Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of the Saturday Show.
Today is 2021.
Uh June
26th.
Now, it's noon, San Francisco time. And
today we are going to do random. So, the
first 10 or 20 minutes is probably going
to be Emacs Lisp coding.
Then I'm then uh whatever you say, if
you have comments, good morning, bots,
post in the chat box, okay? Then I'll
talk about it.
Uh so
with no topic, let's just uh do Emacs
then.
So, um
yep.
Let's do Emacs. So, you are looking at
my Emacs workflow. So, what I want to
do, so add example to replace and
capture pattern, okay? So,
uh go to notes, show in browser, go
down, we're going to do
um
regular expression, okay? So
rejects, okay? But delete that, go to
Emacs blog. In fact, I updated uh my
tutorial, Emacs tutorial, and Emacs Lisp
tutorial about regular expression. So,
you can go to XahLee Emacs blog and you
can see them.
So, Emacs regular expression, a little
bit technical.
Uh so, I'm not going to go over them
unless you have a question.
Okay? So, post your questions, okay? So,
that's uh updated Emacs
regular expression, how to use them, and
so on. And uh some more technical
details on Emacs Lisp regular
expression.
Uh those are just updated. So, close
that, that's one thing done. Then, let's
see what else we want to do, okay?
Uh
add a page about creating a hook. Okay,
so that's again a Emacs Lisp tutorial.
Uh this is about Emacs Lisp, not Emacs.
And then, okay, here's the basics about
how to create a hook.
Um
then add hook. Uh let's see what is that
cuz I HTML auto okay. Uh we don't care
about that. Then write a command to
change one tag to another HTML tag in a
region, okay? We can do that. That's
going to be live coding.
Uh or
add a shift select mark to sub-like
keys. So, I want to do that. So, this is
going to be sub-like keys and workflow
demo.
Or we can live code a Emacs Lisp command
Emacs command to replace backslash to
slash. Now, this is this will be very
useful if you work on Windows if you
code Emacs Lisp and work on Windows
because Windows by default they use the
they use the backslash to be the
separator for file path.
Uh so
you know, sometimes you want to change
them to uh slash or backslash.
Okay, so no comments, okay? No comment.
That means I just choose what to do. So,
let's see what I want to do.
Write a page about creating a hook.
Okay, let's do that. Okay, let let's
write uh so you're going to So, this is
going to be partly tutorial on how to
write a hook in Emacs Lisp, how to
create a hook for a Emacs Lisp function
or command.
Uh how to create a hook. Hook basically
means event. So, this is going to be a
tutorial for that and also it's going to
be workflow. So, if you are Emacs user,
you're going to watch my workflow, how
do I create that? So, let's do that.
Okay, go to talk show, then go to the
notes page, then then then search for
hook. Okay, so basically grab this
Grab this. Okay, show in browser, go to
the browser, you see it's done, cut. And
go to Emacs blog via fast keys to Emacs
bookmark, and add a new section. So,
first we're going to write a tutorial
over here on my Emacs blog. Then I'm
going to create a page the content
there. So, first of all, how to write a
um
Let's create a page, okay? Let's create
a page first.
So, this issue is about how to create a
hook.
Basically means yeah, well, a hook for
function. That means whenever
Emacs this function or Emacs command is
called,
then
it will also call the hook.
And then user can add things functions
to the hook. So, whenever that command
is called, it will call what call
whatever
functions user added to it.
So,
this part will be added to Emacs Lisp
writing a major mode because it's more
suitable here.
Typically, when you
are advanced Emacs Lisp coders, you want
to create a hook. So, this is actually
quite advanced topic. Do we have
comments? No comments, okay? Six people
watching.
Okay, so add a hook. So, let's do this
then. Syntax table and com Okay, keep
comments, okay? Comments on anything,
then we're going to talk about that.
So, right now we're going to create a
new page and add it somewhere here about
how to write a major mod. So, this is
about how to create a hook. Uh
let's see overlay lookup doc. What is
lookup doc? Okay. So, overlay
highlighting. Let's add it after the
overlay highlighting, okay? Copy the
URL. Go to the Emacs.
Go back to Emacs and uh
paste the URL here, make a link, and go
to it.
Okay, search for panel. So, here is the
navigation panel and go to the top.
Uh and you want to add it after lookup
doc, okay?
So, copy that. Copy this line. Let me
show you what I'm I'm going to just do
this quickly. Copy, copy, copy,
duplicate. So, create a new name. Uh
this will be
create hook, okay?
Create function hook.
Let's just say create hook. Let's not be
too specific. That's a tip I learned
in the past 20 years about writing a
tutorial. You want the file name to be
not too specific. So, that way it allows
you the flexibility of changing
kind of a content because once you have
a file name, you have several contents
that's related to it. For example,
creating a hook for a function or
creating a hook in general, things like
that, or what does a hook mean? So, you
don't want to be
If you are not very specific in the file
name, you can be more flexible. So, you
know, so anyway. So, the file the the
topic will be creating
create a hook, okay?
And okay, so
let's copy that, cut it. Call C-h find.
We So, what we are going to do now is we
are going to Wait. Wait. Before we do
that, okay? We need to create this file
first, okay? So,
So, Cocksure
Copy
HTML by link. Do that.
Show in browser. It basically copied It
What it did is that it basically made a
copy of that file into this new file.
So, we open the new file. This is what
you see. And we need to remove the
content. Okay, the first of all, change
the update date.
So, you are looking at my Emacs
workflow, guys. Emacs workflow. So,
delete that. Delete that. Show in
browser. That's That's right. Now,
rename the file so
it's going to be
Elisp.
Create a hook, okay? Capitalize the
words. Do it. Show in browser.
Fantastic. Back to Emacs. Close it.
Okay? Now, what happens is that Now, I
need to add that new page to every
page's navigation panel. So, it will
have the entry here, okay? So, what we
do The way we do that is that we need to
do a multiple find and replace. So, copy
that.
Cocksure Find um
Replace Text. Paste that part there.
Okay, enter. Then cancel. Then copy
that, okay? Then
Cocksure Find Replace again.
Up arrow. So, we want to find this text.
Okay, let's uh Okay, so
So, we want to find this text by
by that, okay? Creating a hook. Uh yeah.
Okay, enter.
So, in this directory, yes.
Regular expression for file name, yes,
HTML. right change to file yes.
Uh fix case in search yes, fix case in
replacement yes.
Make backup yes.
So it's going through about a thousand
pages and you see
you see all these are changes.
Okay, close that. Now if if we go back
in the browser look over here, refresh,
you can see there. Create a hook. There
it is. Copy the URL back to Emacs, close
this page.
Uh what what page were we on?
Okay, yeah, close this page then
paste the link here in the Emacs blog.
Blog,
okay.
Show in show in browser. There it is. We
have blog a new blog entry create a
hook. Right now it's empty. So now move
these contents over there.
Uh it's a draft version of this um
there.
Paste it, show in browser, okay. Now I'm
going to explain how to you how do you
create a hook.
So comments.
Naz says hi. What do you think about
extensions for provide
to a web a dark theme to read it at
night. Do you use any? Sorry my English
is not native speaker, I'm still
learning. Thanks. Okay,
uh about dark theme, I don't like dark
theme, okay.
Uh well, I mean dark theme is
is not it supposed
it's not it's overrated, okay. Dark
theme is overrated. So
let's see.
So
cancel.
Windows key you to get the Windows
settings.
Windows you to get the settings, then
you
to be to be go go to
or you can press Windows I to get the
settings. Then you go to personal
vacation, then you go to colors, then
you can choose a dark theme. Okay,
that's what that's what that is. Okay,
you know.
So, dark theme became popular, you know,
where I'm going to start to
give you a rant about the history of the
dark theme. Since like since 1990s.
Okay, I think I'll I'll reserve that
first.
History of the dark theme, you know,
through the throughout 1990s, 2000s,
then 2010s,
you know, when did the you know, what
what hacker you know, what it used to be
things like that.
Okay, so so let me talk about that that
later. Let me first let's work on the
create a hook.
Okay, so
so we are now talking about creating a
hook, okay? Now let's move here so I can
see those
if there's any new chat.
Now, creating a hook. So, what does this
mean? So, basically
let me show you my
let me show you some Emacs source code
so you see here is a Emacs source code.
There's a lot functions here. Functions,
for example, start user buffer Q. For
example, list matching lines define. So,
you can see
a whole bunch of functions you define in
Emacs list.
Now, what you want to do is that for
example, whenever
let's see. Let's say let's say this
command start copy line or region. Okay,
click on that. You go to the source code
here.
So,
once you write a function in Emacs Lisp
or command,
so people can meta-x and call it. Once
you have a function,
you want it so that you want to add you
want this function to have a hook. That
is you want whenever this function is
called,
it will also call a bunch of other
functions where user can add to the
hook. So, basically, you want to create
a hook for the for this function. That's
So, how do you do that? So, all you have
to do
Okay, let me just explain. Okay, all you
have to do
Okay, let's let's shrink the window. All
you have to do is Let's go back to
uh
Okay, so actually we how to create a
hook, okay? How to create a hook?
Okay, so so
So, let me
clear clear this page and you will know
you will know
how to do it, okay?
Because I basically explained this
already.
Uh
Okay, so
Okay, so like this. Okay, so
Mm.
So, first of all, declare hook variable.
Uh
Declare hook variable. Let me let me
show in browser, so actually so show in
browser, so you can see it at the same
time. So, declare hook variable.
Let's say my
hook.
My function
f
hook.
Okay.
Hook for
Let me Let me uh
Okay, showing browser. So,
you first of all declare a variable
defvar uh with your hook name. So, that
you are declaring a variable. Then, the
default value is nil. Then, here's the
documentation. So, the documentation
says hook for my function f, okay? So,
my function f This is the This is the
convention. So, if you are creating a
hook for a function, you the hook name
should be the function name
uh then  hook, okay?
So, you first of all you create that,
then
then basically just run the hook, okay?
Actually, I So, let me get the name
correctly.
Uh
Okay.
Then, you add that in your in the
function body. So, now
So, now
So, now when
So, now when that that function is
called, it'll run the hook. So, that's
how you do it, okay?
Um Should I give an example? Is this
clear enough?
Um I think you know, so Well, okay. So,
let me show you an example. So, for for
example,
previously we are looking at you know,
this
this sub copy line or region.
So, if I
um Okay.
So, if I want uh uh
you know, this function wherever this
function is called to run a hook, all I
have to do is just
just inside the function somewhere
you know, inside the function somewhere
and uh
just say run hook and that that's it.
Okay, so I but we don't want I don't
want to do it, so
Okay, so that's how you run the hook.
Now,
let's see the comments and maybe let's
talk about dark themes. Okay, dark
themes used to save power and screen in
CRT era. That's correct. With LCD
dark themes consumes more power than
light theme.
Uh I don't know about that. I don't know
if it actually consumes more power, but
I do know it doesn't save energy.
Uh and most of the web and UI is created
for light theme. Using dark theme in
this scenario results in in results in
unpleasant switches from light to dark.
Okay, that's my problem. Yes, that's my
problem with unpleasant switches from
light to dark, but I think it's more
pleasant at least for me a dark theme at
night for reading text. Okay, yeah, that
makes sense, too. So, basically, dark
theme is overrated. So, let me let me
begin
begin my rant.
But before we do that, let me clean
clean up fig uh clear up uh
clear up this uh this part. Okay, create
a new hook. Okay, let me finish this.
So, now add to the atom
add a new entry to the web feed atom
file.
You know, you can see all my pink
windows have all these fancy commands
I've written before. You You search for
it, you'll find the source code. So, I
just press the two keys I press three
keys, it will automatically add this new
entry in my blog into this ISS Atom XML
feed. So, you can see here it is.
You know, so that's how
uh wait, what did I just close?
Uh okay, so close that.
Let's do it again, yeah. Close that.
Showing browser, there it is. Create a
new hook. That's today's
fruit. Okay, so you can see. Great.
So, that's about creating a hook. Now,
let's talk about dark themes. So, dark
themes, okay, that's a
um
So, we got creating a hook. Yeah, so
let's go back to talk page.
Uh
let's go to
copy the URL, close that, and uh showing
browser, talk show. That's right, and
paste the link here. Show. So, this is
what we talked about.
Oh, we I just closed the chat box. Did
we?
Oh, yeah, I just closed the chat box by
mistake.
Okay, so uh let's talk about dark
themes. So,
so
Okay, so
the the request is actually for my
website. I believe you are asking for my
webs- website to have a dark theme.
Uh I can do that, but it's actually it's
not trivial, okay?
It is not trivial
to
actually create a dark theme for a
website. For example, let's you know,
you're looking at my source uh code
website. Let me show turn on the video.
So, turn on JavaScript.
So, for example, if I go to
uh you know, you are looking at the you
are looking at
So, for example, you can see my CSS code
here.
Then
then there is the main CSS code here.
And I can open it.
And it's
right now 195
lines of CSS. Very compact.
Uh and you know, my CSS file is pretty
small, actually. For example, you go to
directory and you can see it's only 10
kilobytes, okay? But today vast majority
of websites, their CSS is like 100
kilobytes or
100 or few hundred kilobytes.
So, my website is extremely compact and
efficient.
So, you know, like mi- minimized, you
know, I mean the
lean, okay? Not bloated.
So, creating a dark theme is not so easy
because that means you have to adjust
every basically every each all of the
color specific- specification. There is
no single way There is no way for you
just to say invert video, okay?
You know, you might think, "Okay, you
just say invert video, then everything
works." Not really, because when you
invert video, lots of a color doesn't
work. So, dark theme, in order to create
dark theme, you have to specifically
design all the colors.
Of course, there are packages. I'm
pretty sure there are packages that
tries to do that. But anyway, it's not
even if I use those package, I don't
think it'll work well for my website
because they
um
Okay, let me let explain, okay? Let's
for example, let's go to Firefox.
Firefox do have a dark theme feature you
can just turn on. So, if you want dark
theme for my website, you can just go to
Firefox. So, we are looking at Firefox
and you go to settings.
Okay, so I believe there is somewhere.
Okay, language and appearance
appearance fonts and colors zoom.
And default font zoom language.
There is color, okay, there. Color,
okay.
Text background use system colors
override color specification.
Text and background, okay.
Okay, let's say text.
Text is white, okay.
Then let's say background is black,
okay.
Okay, now go back to my website. You
see, now it looks like that. Let's go to
let's go to the Xara
website. So, it looks like that. So, you
can see these links does not look very
good.
You have to adjust the colors.
So, anyway, but you know, but so this is
a general mechanism to have a dark
theme. So, you just switch the
background color and foreground color.
But you can see it's not so good.
You know, if it's easy, then the Firefox
will probably just say
it'll just say use dark theme, but it
doesn't have that. So, each website,
whenever you go to a website, each
website, if they offer a dark theme, it
must be specifically designed to, you
know, for every color used on the
website. So, that's the issue with the
dark theme dark theme. Let's see Let's
see if I click on use system colors and
let's change this back to black and
white.
Uh
okay, so background is white.
Okay, that's a default, but I say, you
know, we say use system colors.
So, right now the system colors is
you know,
uh
You see
personalization
colors
dark, right? The system color is dark.
And now I say
in Firefox, I say use system colors.
Okay?
Then
let's switch back to Xara website.
Refresh. It doesn't change.
Wait, is it big too Do I need to reload?
I mean, do I need to restart Firefox?
Let's try.
Oh, actually, wait. We were using uh
update. We were using Brave browser. So,
that's Chrome-based browser.
So, anyway, we were talking about Chrome
Chrome Google Chrome browser, but now we
are in Firefox. Let's try this again.
Settings
Oh, we were using Firefox. That's right.
So, anyway, so you go back to my page,
it doesn't it doesn't change your thing.
So,
So, the first point I want to make is
that
in order to have dark theme, you have to
customize every and each of your colors.
Now, on typical websites, let's say
let's go to Google.
Uh okay. So, you can you see it's still
white. Uh this is what? Firefox?
Why is it
to
Okay, this is Firefox.
Let's go Let's make sure we got the
settings correct.
Colors.
You see, use system colors. Override
colors specified by the page with your
selection above.
Oh, okay. You have to say this, always,
okay?
Do it.
Now, go to Google, refresh, close,
close, refresh.
Uh
it doesn't work.
Go to settings again.
Colors.
So, this is confusing. So, this use
system colors is only
applied to the underlines.
So, text.
Let's try to change text white.
Background black.
Okay. Refresh. What's going on?
Uh now it's getting into some kind of
high contrast [ __ ]
So anyway, you can see it doesn't work
well. It doesn't work so well. So
So the point I want to make so but why
is Google
Uh
why is Google not not um
Let's go to Google.
So right now my system is dark themes,
but Google
You see right now my system theme is
dark, but Google does not
Let's try again. Let's uh use the Edge
browser. You see Google doesn't even
Google does not
uh support the dark theme. So let's try
Google Chrome browser.
Yeah.
Yeah, you see even the Google search
page does not
by default support dark theme. I thought
it
I thought Google would be the one that
does. Okay, so Google doesn't. So let's
try uh DuckDuckGo.
Let's say let's try bing.com.
Okay, bing.com is using the
Anyway,
let me just talk about what I want to
say about dark themes instead of instead
By the way, this is a photo of China.
I recognize this is photo of China.
Um
So
basically in order to have dark themes,
each website have to have its own design
of every color.
Then
uh then the other thing I want to say is
that, you know, dark theme begin become
became very popular about 5 years ago
because of Apple. Apple, you know, Mac
OS Mac OS they in their one of their
version they started to use dark theme
and it's uh it works very well. But how
however, on Windows it it sucks greatly.
And uh I also I want to mention Windows
is the one who created dark theme in the
first place. So,
uh you could say that Apple copied
Windows.
So, for for So, so let's go to So, let's
go to my website suck code and let's go
to user interface. So, I have a section
on user interface.
Okay?
So,
you see
on Windows, if you have dark theme, then
it becomes impossible to distinguish uh
which window is in front or what part of
it what part of the user interface is
actually a window. It becomes hard to
distinguish, hard to tell.
And it happens on, you know, PowerShell.
Uh for example, PowerShell, I open a new
PowerShell.
Go to Emacs. Go to another start another
PowerShell. Then you sometimes you have
a lot text in PowerShell and it becomes,
for example, LS.
Uh
You know, it becomes hard to tell which
line begin which window begin which end
window ends. That's the problem, you
know, that's the idiocy of Windows.
And also
Yeah, so so
So that's a problem of dark theme. You
you you can't just, you know,
swapping a dark theme and think
everything will work fine. You need to
adjust every color, but you also make
you need to make sure every other things
work well. Because if you do not use
dark theme, it's it's better, okay? For
example, let me show you again the
the PowerShell, okay? So you see now we
have, you know, it's hard to tell which
window is what which window is in front.
Is this a window is it's hard to tell,
okay?
But let's switch
uh
Okay, let's switch uh
Let's not use dark theme, okay? Let's
say light.
Then it's actually easier
to tell. Okay, this is not the best
example because PowerShell is using a
back black background. It doesn't matter
whether it's a in front
you know, it doesn't matter you have
dark theme or light light theme. But
anyway, the the the thing I want to say
is that you see the shadow the window
shadow there? With dark theme, you don't
that you don't have that much window
shadows. But with with you see, you
don't see that. But with white theme you
do have a kind you do have this shadow
and this shadow helps you distinguish
window which one is in front
uh
uh to quite some degree.
So a few things I want to summarize.
Dark theme is not something you can
easily do. You have to design every
specific color. So in fact, that's every
website that you go that support dark
dark theme that actually do that.
Uh
there's no automated way to do that.
That's one thing. You have to decide it.
The second thing, not just for colors,
because there are many subtle details in
in the user interface
where
if you have different set of colors, it
changes your user interface experience.
So, that's another thing I want to say.
Okay.
Let me Let me write it down, okay? So,
the problems So, I write it down, so
that makes my video slower, but things
becomes clear.
The problem of dark theme.
Dark theme is
uh
Dark theme is overrated. Okay. Now,
now there are several issues, okay?
Dark theme is overrated, then
there is no automated way to create a
dark theme from light.
You actually have to design every color
on a web on a website or
or
your app, okay? That's the second point.
Show in browser.
Magnify.
Then,
let there's more, okay?
Even if you have the right colors,
simply changing color
set may affect your user interface
usability.
Uh
u s e
Okay, show in browser. So, that's three
items. And when you for example
for example
window border shadow
Beca- because the color of shadow is
usually
black, you know, some kind of a gray
dark. But when you have a white theme,
you don't
I mean, whe- when you have a dark theme,
you don't have white shadows because
that's contrary to experience. So
So, you see how the dark theme is
screwed up an element of the user
interface that cannot be solved by just
changing color.
Or unless you actually try to have a
white shadow, which then becomes kind of
a strange.
So, that's another point. You you you
see you see there's a kind of shadow on
the right side of this window. Whe- when
you have dark theme, that's gone.
Okay?
Now, another point
uh
dark theme is
actually not
is actually more difficult to read,
okay?
Now
you know, the the typical
uh programmer wisdom is that oh, dark
theme makes your eyes easier. Not true.
Not true.
Because the uh dark theme So, George,
one of a group of our people, George,
actually showed an article
that discussed about dark theme.
Let's search for dark theme problems or
search for dark theme sucks, okay?
You'll find a kind of a detailed
analysis on why
dark theme is not good. Okay, actually
there are several of them when you once
you search it. So, dark theme problems,
color theme problem with dark mode,
Windows dark theme problems, editor dark
theme problems.
Okay, my Windows 10 dark theme problem.
Okay, that those are not so good
articles. But, if you look at dark theme
sucks,
now of course many of these articles may
not be good. Some some of them is
probably just garbage rant.
Uh
how to include a dark theme in your
Android, how to get dark theme. Okay,
then it's
So, I'm trying to find the article, a
very good article
that
that discuss the sign you know kind of
scientific or
reasonable
uh give reasonable reasons why dark
theme is not
very good. Because
I don't remember, okay, we can find it.
I don't remember where is the URL, but
we can probably
find it in our Discord.
George from Australia posted, you know,
about that a month or two ago.
Uh
So, quite a few people have requested me
to have dark theme on my website. I
don't think it's a good thing because
first of all it's not easy for me. I
have to spend a few hours to do it.
Practically probably 3 hours.
You know, because I have a lot
you know, 6,000 pages.
Then there's a problem. Then
then there's another issue about user
interface design. Typically when you
want have a user interface design, you
want it to be one choice.
Typically, no customization. That's why
on the Mac, you know, you have a
you know, user interface design
guidelines. So, that doesn't matter
which application you use, the interface
is is the same. You know exactly what to
do to get what menus or command, you
know.
On the other hand, you know, similar in
Windows, but Windows is a a bit more
wild.
Inconsistent. For example, let's For
example, let me show you the example of
a Windows inconsistent user interface
[ __ ]
You know, so look, I'm now turning on
the Nvidia control panel.
And you know, so so for example, you
know, user interface [ __ ] okay? So, for
example, now it's a Windows settings.
So, you can you can see the Windows
settings, you have this use user
interface.
But however, if I turn on control panel,
you can see you have this old interface.
It's inconsistent. You know,
normally, the new interface is supposed
to, you know, the metro design supposed
to be, you know, you have tabs on the
left.
You know, Window
Window user interface design sucks
because you can see you have a little
tiny blue bar that indicates that is a
current, but that's hard to see.
On the Mac, you don't have this problem.
Mac is well designed all over in every
detail. But anyway, so
this is supposed to be the, you know,
the proper interface, the the new, you
know, Windows fluent or metro interface.
But then,
they didn't do that for all their um
you know, for example, you click on that
one, you got this tiny crap, you know,
peep show windows I talked about in my
uh two vi two videos before, peep peep
show windows, im- impossible to read.
And you cannot magnify nor can you uh
enlarge the window. You cannot magnify
the font. I'm getting old. I cannot read
it. I have to get, you know, really
close.
So, Windows like the you Windows user
interface is [ __ ] up everywhere, okay?
But anyway, I'm trying to show you
I'm now I'm talking about on Windows or
Mac or Linux, even Linux, usually they
try to
uh give you a guideline so that every
application have the same interface.
Now, I'm trying to show you on Windows,
even they have the guideline, but the
Windows, the Microsoft itself [ __ ] it
up. You see, you have Now you have, you
know, these two different interfaces.
Uh
then
then then especially the
Let me show you, okay? Logitech.
Then especially the gaming applications
on Windows, the gaming applications,
each one sports their own fucked-up
interface that's impossible to use. You
like you don't know which button or
color it does.
For example, the Nvidia control panel is
one such example. First of all, you have
you got this tiny font, you know, I
cannot read it and you cannot magnify
the font.
Uh
you know, manage 3D settings, uh
whatever. Why is that slow?
Then you have Okay, that's So, that's
one example where the interface sucks.
Then you have the Logitech. Basically,
every gaming software
their interface is one fucked-up [ __ ]
Okay, for example, this Logitech uh
Logitech
you you
gaming setup mouse or
mouse or keyboard is one of the
circuits.
So, let's try
Okay, let's click on that.
Like it's like it's impossible to use,
you know, you you spend few hours just
to see exactly which which one is a
button, which one is actually the
default settings, which one is what.
For example, and you are looking at one
such example, okay? I'm I'm not going to
go to into details, but this sucks
donkey ass.
Uh
Okay, so let's get back to dark themes.
So, we were talking about dark themes.
So, we
So, what is the What's What's the thing
I was talking about?
Uh well, boss says PowerShell has a blue
background. Not Well, that's that's
that's only true if you use the You see,
here's a technical detail. PowerShell
now has two versions. One is the default
Windows version called Windows
PowerShell.
But there's another version called It
used to be called
uh PowerShell Core,
which which is now open source open
source and cross-platform um for Linux,
also for Mac. So,
on the default PowerShell, let's start
PowerShell, okay? PowerShell.
You see, it's it has a blue background.
But if I start
the cross-platform PowerShell, the
default background is black. So, it's
You see, technical details.
Uh anyway, so
So, what uh let's get back to the dark
theme. So, what I was going to say, um
Okay, let let's look at the uh dark
theme sucks. Yeah, I was trying to find
that article, but I don't remember the
article, but let me just
summarize what I remember.
So, human vision, our vision, is
the natural way is actually black text
on white background because that's
natural. Because when you go out, you
see the sun, you know, everything
everything is white. Then things have
color, you know, it's not dark thing.
When at night, when it's dark, you don't
see nothing. That's the true that's the
real dark thing, okay?
But on the computers, you know, people
inverted
thinking that it's better.
So, but but anyway, so so So, in
article, they said, you know, they've
done scientific test
that actually people reads better when
you have black text on white background,
not the other way, okay? You actually
read better.
Okay, that that is the primary thing
mentioned in that article, okay? That's
the primary thing.
And also, I mentioned several Okay, so
let me let me let me type it out here so
we have a good summary of things.
Um
human eyes actually
read better
of black text on white background
because
it is more natural.
For example,
when you go outside in
day.
And in daylight and
they've done
let's say scientific
Okay, so here's we the summary of what
we talked about.
So, human sees better with the white
background.
Now, so what So why is there kind of
this
fashion or fad about dark theme?
Well, it's because, you know,
computer screen is really bright and at
night, you know, uh
it's too bright. It, you know, light
color affect your sleeping patterns. So,
it might be better, it is true. It is
true that it might be better at night
when at night you can
you should have some kind of uh
not so bright screen, okay? So,
that's good, okay? So, so what I'm
saying is that it's not necessarily that
dark theme is bad, okay?
Sometimes it's good, sometimes bad, and
there's also a lot issues about color
design, user interface design. So, on
the Mac, I would say dark theme is
pretty good on the Mac, okay?
On the Mac, you can have white theme or
dark theme. It's pretty good.
But, what I'm trying to tell you is that
don't believe, you know, the fashion and
fad, you know, just dark theme is just
better. It's not It's actually not true.
Uh
and I want to show you
uh
Okay, then then I want to talk about
like the history of black background on
white.
Uh
Let's Let's see what else I want to say.
Okay,
so that's that's it, basically.
Override color specified by the page on
your selection above needs to be set
always for it to work, okay? So, you are
talking about Firefox, I believe.
Uh
Yeah, so text is white, background is
black.
Okay. Uh use system colors, okay.
But
Wait.
Colors
text is white
background is black.
Why is it not Text is white, background
is black.
Okay.
So, yeah. So, we are back in Firefox.
So, you see this is how my website
looks. It doesn't look good.
Unless I start to change, you know.
So, okay. So, um
Oh, yeah. So, here's another thing I
want to show you. So, if you want dark
theme
you know, you you you you you can, you
know, you can set to dark theme, but
but if you want to demand that every
website should have a dark theme, I
think that's a bad
that's a bad demand demand
because that increases the complexity
complexity a lot. And also
I talked about the dark theme is just
not that good, okay.
So, however, the the the primary reason
most people want dark theme is that is
that at night the screen is too bright.
In that case, what you want is a you
want a
you what you want is a Let me show you,
okay. You want a good monitor, okay.
So, so
So, let me show you what where is the
uh
is there.
Okay? So, you can see my screen.
You see? I don't know if uh it shows up
the screen color. I need to show you
some white pages in order for this to
work.
Uh
Okay, so
what you want is a better screen. So, on
my on my monitor a better monitor
display. So, you have the blue light
filter. So, one of the force of the dark
theme popularity is that some kind of
scientific say they say that the blue
you know blue color actually the blue
light hurts your eyes.
And affect your sleep, things like that.
Uh but
that is not necessarily true. We don't
actually know for sure yet. But people
say that, you know, all the websites say
that. So, Apple says, "Oh, so therefore
we're going to have dark themes, you
know."
We don't actually know this for for
sure.
Uh but so what what you can have
So, what you should have is to buy a
good display monitor. So, for example,
you can see I have a blue light filter.
I can adjust my
uh you know how much blue light I want.
So, okay. So, that's one of the you
know, right now I set it to kind of
level two.
So, that's that's what I have to say
about dark theme.
Okay, actually there's more, okay?
Show you So, buy a good display, okay,
which has the adjustable blue light
filter. Now, there's one more thing I
want to talk about dark theme, okay?
So, dark theme became popular about uh
you know, search for Wikipedia.
They They will tell you all about it,
light on dark color theme, okay? So,
yeah, so this starting to be getting
into history, you know.
So, but the Apple energy use issues with
the web, blah blah blah, and and
something and the Solaris, okay? A lot
of people like Solaris. So, Solaris is
the is the
is the beginning of the theme [ __ ]
okay? Solaris, the idiot, this guy
created by Ethan Schoonover. It's
supposed to be based on science, you
know, and they talk about how your eyes
can see better, and so on and so on, and
they created Solaris. This is back about
10 years ago. So, look at 2011, 10 years
ago exactly. This is the beginning of
the theme [ __ ]
Okay, this is actually not the beginning
of theme [ __ ] This is the beginning of
the color theme [ __ ] okay?
Themes and skins is 10 years before
this. All these are [ __ ] You don't
want any of that those those are no
good. And also, because of the solar
solarize, you started to have gray, you
know, gray on white, which is unreadable
[ __ ]
Okay, so so this so so let's let me show
you um
Let me show you my
dark theme sucks, okay? What Not that
page. I don't want to
Let me show you my articles. So, here is
a collection of articles on user
interface design.
So
So for example, you have uh gray text on
black
uh gray text on white background. This
begin about 10 years ago. It [ __ ] up
lots of websites, including Google, you
know, and actually it stem from these
design gurus, idiots at Google or you
know, these at Apple and you know.
And you know, and where did it begin? It
began by Solaris color theme [ __ ] You
know, it's supposed it's supposed to be
like science. This is all science says
this way. Therefore, you should have,
you know, blah blah blah. That's crap.
That's not true.
Okay, so that's uh Solaris, okay?
Uh what else I want to say? Um
There's now a brand new PowerShell
separate from the default PowerShell.
Yeah, that's true.
Uh
Flux, okay? So there is a program called
Flux.
Redshift to inversion. So I suppose
that's a uh add-on, Flux.
Software to make your life better.
That's what the [ __ ] The marketing
[ __ ]
Microsoft Store.
Okay.
You see this all this crap, you know,
they show this crap like a scientific
graph.
The connotation is that this is a
scientifically designed and this or that
you know, this is trash, you know, all
these are like pseudo science trash.
Beginning with the solarized, you know,
pseudo science trash.
I don't even have to read it because I
read this stuff for 30 years.
Every every 5 years, 10 years, there's
fashion fashion and fad come and go. So,
if you are new, I mean, you are here
today, maybe you are young or, you know,
you oh, this is new thing. You need to
do this because this is science. Then
after 5 years, you are no longer in
computing industry or something or maybe
you you got old. Maybe you become a
manager. You don't care about
programming stuff anymore. You don't
care about hacking, you know, the
argument anymore. You become a manager
or you have a family. Then the new
generation, they have another new fad.
We each one doesn't know the others, you
know, like you don't know the history of
the colors on the screen. So, you forgot
about all the nerds are saying what it
should be like
20 years ago. What it should be. Oh, you
should do this. If you don't do do this,
you are idiot. Blah blah blah. Then then
next 5 years is something else. Then
something else. You see? Now they have
flux. Like like today people forgot
about Solaris. They don't they forgot
about solarize like young generation.
They have no no uh concept of history.
They don't know this is this was, you
know, 10 years 10 years ago this was the
hottest thing.
Then then flux, okay. So, ever notice
how people texting at night have the
eerie blue glow or wake up ready to
write down the next great idea and get
blinded by your computer screen. No, I
didn't notice that. I
I'm still I I'm not blind yet. During
the day, computer screen look good. They
are designed to look like the sun, but
at 9:00 p.m., 10:00 p.m., uh
[ __ ] what a idiot.
Download flux, big button. Free for Mac
OS.
Free on Windows for personal use. Oh, so
that means the implication,
you know, hidden in the message is that
you have to pay.
But but you have free versions
downloaded first. Once you got hooked,
you have to pay.
Free for Linux for corporate use and
it's site license. Click, you know,
[ __ ]
The money.
Why do we have all these fad and fashion
that's untrue? Because money. Money is
talking and here is example. Flux. Money
is talking. For corporate use and site
license, click here.
Now, commercialization or capitalism is
not a bad thing. It's a a great thing.
But it's a bad thing
is when you have untruth in marketing,
okay? So, marketing by itself is also
not a bad thing. Because, you know, for
example, I I write tutorials. I write
Emacs tutorials. I need to sell.
Otherwise, I die hungry.
You know, so I have to do a little bit
marketing, you know, so so for example,
Xah Fly Keys. Oh.
Oh my god, they not not now they have
like actually
kind of snippet of my website.
You know, so anyway, you go to my Xah
Fly Keys, okay? Which is something I
wrote. It's kind of like a product,
okay?
And it's I get I Well, I don't make
money out of it except donations. But I
do have a little marketing, okay? Xah
Fly Keys is most efficient than Vim or
any key key binding set in history.
Okay, that's a little bit dramatic
clickbait. But actually
that's kind of true. I abide by that
statement. But anyway, that's that is
the marketing, you know, uh
epigraph, you know?
That's kind of marketing. So, marketing
is not necessarily bad because you want
to, you know, you make something you
want to sell it, you know?
Sell it because you need to survive.
Everyone, you know, you go to work.
You work for someone. People have to pay
you. It's not It's not free. You don't
work for someone for free. People pay
you, you know, whatever you do services
or you go to, you know, you go to mop
the toilet at McDonald's. You got paid.
So,
you know, so it's not a bad thing to
sell things.
And marketing is not necessarily bad,
neither, because you have to
let people know, you know, maybe uh
you know, just like dress. Sometimes you
dress, you know, suit or tie. Why?
Because you need to impress people or
something, you know.
But
but
when you are a corporation, big
corporation, when you do marketing, that
often starting to become untrue, become,
you know, marketing is often associated
with propaganda and spreading untrue
lie, okay? That's what marketing is. I
mean, not is, but associated with. And
we can see some example here, you know.
Blah blah blah, you know, ever notice
how people texting at night that eerie
blue glow? Yeah, eerie blue glow is from
the screen, not have nothing to do with
whether
it damage their eye or what whatever.
So, anyway, so marketing is
uh you know, often
you know, borderline
uh between propaganda and spreading
false, you know, untrue.
And uh
Okay, so that's that's that.
So, I wouldn't, you know, as as for, you
know, I I would actually just the best
solution is actually get a monitor
that can uh uh display, you know, that's
can that can filter blue light or use
the operating system.
You know, operating system today
you have um
you can adjust it so that at night it
becomes less bright.
Uh where is it?
It's somewhere here, okay? I don't use
it myself. I don't I hate those
features.
I don't use it myself. So, using color
filters, color settings, background
setting, you know, somewhere here,
somewhere here, I don't
color filters, okay?
Turn on color filters, magnifier,
uh
there is
there is a feature somewhere
that automatically adjust your screen
brightness according to time
of the day.
Uh Win- Windows is pretty [ __ ] up. You
don't You cannot find where uh things.
Okay, so that's That's about that.
Uh let's see what else I want to say.
You know, let me let me tell you another
story about terminal colors, okay? For
example, you are looking at PowerShell,
you know, a terminal.
Uh
terminal colors, you know, because of
history, because historically
um
let's go to keyboard, okay?
Let's go to keyboard history, then you
see all these uh big ass old
monitors. So, back in the day, 30 years
ago or 40 years ago, this is your
monitor, okay? You have you know, so
this one is VT100
introduced in 1978.
So, that's 40 years ago. So, So, back
then, you don't have color monitors. You
don't even have graphics monitors. So,
oh, so a display like this, it cannot
even display a square or triangle or
circle.
All it can do is display text.
And uh the text is only 80 80 columns by
24 lines. You know, 80 80 characters by
24 lines. So,
So, that would be How large would that
be? It would be something like that,
okay?
Something like that. So, that's how
large that monitor is back then.
And uh
and it doesn't have colors. The The only
has two colors, white or black.
You know, white or black.
And also, um sometimes not white. Some
You You know, sometimes green. So, this
one is a little bit bigger, green.
So, this is uh
uh Apple Ambassador 60 terminal, year
1982. You know, a little bit
improvement, three three years
advancement. The glory of a hacker. Uh
by the way, this is from JWZ's website.
JWZ is a
um colorful character. He's a He's a
hacker, but he's also an [ __ ] He's a
[ __ ] [ __ ]
So,
So, let's go to his website because I
wanted to talk about he he, you know,
his website is
You are looking at the classic hacker
website. He uses a dark, you know,
background. This is before the fashion
of the dark theme, okay? There's no such
word dark theme.
This is the This is the dark theme
before the word dark theme, okay?
Basically, a
black background, okay? So, let's If you
go to his homepage,
uh did he
Okay, yeah, you go to his home page and
then you'll see this idiotic [ __ ] you
know, the Jamie Zawinski.
Because I had argument with him. I
talked about about 5 years ago when
about politics, about Trump, about the
election.
Because I always respected this guy
until that day. He's uh, you know, he
he's not he's he's very
he's [ __ ] kind of guy, okay?
Uh, anyway, so you know,
uh uh
you know, when when we talk about him,
there's endless things to talk about him
because about Emacs, about Lisp, about
Netscape, about, you know, Netscape
Mozilla, the daddy of Mozilla. And all
all sorts of things. So, anyway, he is
the one who still uses the black
background consistently for the past for
the past 30 years. You know, he began to
have a website around 19
uh
98, I think.
About the same time I began to have a
website. I began, you know,
about the same time. 1997 I
1997.
Uh, and I think I I for a month for for
some period, I think, I'm not sure. I
don't think so. Yeah, I was saying for
some period I I I have a black
background as well. But, anyway,
So, let me talk about uh a bit about
history. So,
back then, let's say around year 2000,
you know, year 2K.
Many hackers website uses the black
background just like just like him.
Yeah, and green text. Why why green
text? Because green
because green is the, you know, because
because habit actually, okay?
Why is he using black background? Why is
using green text? Because habit, not
because he thought about the issue and
he has some creativity. No, that's not
true.
Usually, people just follow habit, okay?
When when when when there's something
new that refuse to change, things like
that. So, he's using black background
and green text because habit because
back then
monitors cannot have multiple colors,
just black and white. And the white is
usually green or amber, okay? Or cyan.
Green, cyan, amber, things like that.
So, let's go back to
uh
you know, let's see some examples. So,
here's a white
uh
and here's blue, kind of
white.
I want to see some amber example. Do we
have? Okay, so So, now beginning here,
1980s, this is now you have graphics.
You know, you have display that can
display graphics.
But
do we have a amber, like orange example?
I don't have example here.
Okay, so that's what I'm saying. So,
around year 2K, lots of websites still
have a black
background. And one of the most
uh big website that still have black
background is Ars Technica.
Okay, this is a classic nerd website,
Ars Technica. Uh
in you know, in year 2000s, you know,
you can go to uh
Wayback Machine to see their website
back then. So, anyway, this this is a
classic nerd hacker website. Their
article was usually very good. I don't
know today, but back in 2000s, they they
are, you know, one of the big
nerd website for programmers. But now
they, you know, today they got into all
sort of things. Every website, you know,
talk about politics and crap. So, I
don't know how good they are anymore. I
haven't been, you know, actually reading
much uh Ars Technica
for 10 years, for over 10 years. But,
you know, so but let's go to um
Wayback Machine, okay? Let's go to Let's
see how their website looks like. It
used to have black background.
Okay, so wait, so you go there, Ars
Technica.
And magnify, so you can see year 2000,
so they begin year 1999
after my website began.
So, let's look at year 1999 Ars
Technica.
Let's go there.
Uh
well, there it is. You see, Ars
Technica, 1999.
Black background.
You know, so let me talk about another
thing. So, back in year 2000, now
remember year 2000 year 2000, the CRT
monitor is still very popular, okay? We
most most monitors are CRT CRT like
that, you know, heavy.
Uh you know, like like that.
Heavy and bulky, you know,
uh
most monitors are still like that. LCD
didn't become
very popular until after 2005, around
there, okay? So,
so those monitors
uh so, what I'm saying?
So, what So, basically, the monitor, you
know, what color you use and the font
size
depends on the quality of the monitor a
lot. So, if every monitor in use most
monitor in use is bad quality, there are
certain choices you wouldn't do.
And
And the And the And one of one of the
effect on that is the, you know, whether
you use a
serif
uh font or sans serif font.
You know, because monitor today are very
high quality and crispy and high
resolution. So, we started to see a lot
website they use um
they use serif font again.
You know, but I can show you examples.
Anyway, I'm I'm like rambling over. So,
you can see Ars Technica. So, they use
serif font
only for the title for now. But anyway,
Time magazine, New York Times, you know,
the major news website, a lot of them
today use serif
um uh font.
Why? Because it has to do with the
quality, you know, the quality of the
display, you know, used by the masses.
So, anyway, I think that's it for today.
I I I think that's it for today.
Yeah, so how many people are watching?
13. So, I've talked for
1 hour and 25 minutes. Okay, I talked
for over 1 hour already. So, I think
that's it.
Uh let's see what I want to
Okay, thank you guys. Thank you guys for
watching.
Uh any other comments, questions?
Uh yeah,
uh color is fairly complex, but
but usually as far as software people or
user interface design are concerned,
usually they are just fuss about
nothing.
Um
yeah, but color, you know, a accuracy of
color and human vision is very, very
complex thing. You go to Wikipedia, you
can see tons of articles very and and
they required they require knowledge
beyond
a typical programmer because you you
have to understand human vision, human
color perception system, which is very
different from which is actually biased,
not the same as, you know, the
the color frequency, you know, the the
magnetic magnetic wave frequency
distribution, things like that.
Okay, if you like my stuff, donate.
Okay, don't donate or Patreon me or
PayPal or Amazon gift card.
Uh and buy my Emacs tutorial.
So, could you have to a stream talking
about Chinese politics anytime soon?
Yeah, I can do that.
Uh
usually,
you know, you want you
I would talk much better if you you you
know, we start, you know, if you start
to say something, you know, if you have
specific question,
then I can do much better.
And also, talking about politics and
Chinese politics,
um if I do that, Google is probably
going to censor me,
my video, because once I started to talk
about that, I'm going to
be non-stop, you know, the issues about
China and Taiwan. I was born in Taiwan.
Uh and the issues of, you know, the
relations between USA and
and China, you know.
And once you talk about that,
you know, YouTube might want might
censor you.
Okay. Bye, guys.