hello guys welcome to another episode of
EX talk show today we are going to code
wolam
language wolam language we are going to
continue Advent of code 2023 day 14 part
two which we did three days ago about so
we're going to continue explore that
problem but you don't have to watch the
previous episode because today we're
going to do independent I'm going to
explain the problem it's pretty short I
mean that you know easy to understand
problem so we're going to explore and
see what is going on with this problem
this you know event of code 2023 day 14
part two uh it's fairly you know it's
kind of more complex difficult
problem okay
so well come if you are watching offline
skip around because I ramble and I talk
slowly I ramble a lot skip around and
play at speed
1.5 I think 1.5 is optimal and then
preferably you sit in front of the
computer you skip around you know like
every 5 Seconds 5
Seconds um if you are watching online
live say hi okay so we're going to start
to uh code the this so video check check
audio check check my keyboards ultimate
hacking keyboard that's this one this is
glove
80 glove 80 I have reviews video reviews
on YouTube and this this
fantastic uh this is called Data
hand uh SW board s v a l b o a r d I
also have a review but I'm not ready to
use it yet okay sorry about that so
let's begin coding okay so the problem
is you are given this uh let's let's
start wolam language okay now if you
don't know yet search for SAR wolam
language you'll see the download link
and the tutorial for programmers okay so
here's a problem so the problem
is is that you got this text okay you
got this you know given text this o
capital O they represent a ball a marble
okay so consider this is a board like a
wooden board so this O is a marble and
this dos are empty
spaces and these pound sign are pegs or
wall okay so this pound signs they are
immovable they are just walls so these
marbles can roll around they can roll to
any of these positions of the dots okay
so the problem so you're going to so the
problem is that you're going to teer the
board so there are four directions North
West South and East so when you teer the
board North all the marbles Will Roll to
the north so for example this o will
will will become at that position uh and
this o will move over here then start by
the wall uh and for example this o will
move over here stop stopped by the wall
so that's when you te North all the
balls move to the north okay then
similarly you when you te West all the
zeros or I mean the O moves to the to
the West so this o will end up
here does that make sense if you are
here say hi hi Alexandra finally on time
for stream thank you so uh check check
video check audio check so that's when
you til West then when you til South
similarly all the all move to the South
position for example this one will uh
end up there then there's uh te Eastward
similar thing so the problem is that
you're going to teer the
board North first then West West then
South then East in this
order okay one every time you te all the
all the balls move to that direction
then you te North I mean starting with
North then west and south and east in
that order okay now once you do this
this is called one cycle according to
the problem specification so you do this
so one
cycle then the problem says you have to
do this 1 million I mean one bill
billion times one followed by 9 Z so you
have to do this 1 billion
times okay that is a problem I mean so
what is I mean what exactly is the
problem is the answer I mean what what
is the question the question is once you
done this 1 billion times basically you
want to count in each row the number of
all the number of BS in each
row then for each row you have the
number of BS then you multiply that row
by the reverse count of the index of the
row so if this is if there are 10 rows
total and the first row will be have a
weight of 10 multiply by 10 the second
row multiply the number of BS multiply
by nine the third row the number of BS
multiply by eight you know so you
multiply
each total count of number of BS in that
row by the inverse of the row number
okay then you sum it up then that is
supposed to be the answer so you have to
do this you know you know till them
North West South East that's one cycle
do this one billion times then count the
number BS multiply by their weight and
sum it up that is the
problem the EV of code 20 23 day 14 part
two okay now the problem okay so we we
explain the problem
specification now the the problem is
that so we have a solution you know we
did code the solution okay so let's show
in wolam
language uh you know so the solution is
just so we begin with you know this text
input okay then this this part is
personal input you know it's much bigger
but let's skip it now then we have uh my
solution is you know turn it into a
matrix then then do this replace all uh
uh okay you okay so instead of
using you know this string string o and
string Dot and string pound I change
them to zero and one and three
uh this step is not necessary but you
know so I mean but you do that it's
easier to manipulate so you deal with
numbers instead of
strings but anyway this step is not
necessary so then you get the row count
total row count then you get column
count which actually we don't need but
anyway this is a solution for last time
and here is a function to cycle
them uh so if you want understand the
detail watch the you know three days ago
or four or last week you know we have
full uh explanation that that video
turns out to be three three
hours okay then you just call
this uh F1 cycle which cycle them one
time you supposed to call them one
billion
times okay then you just total like
count the number of BS in each row M you
know then multiply by their inverse of
the index then total them then that's
the answer okay so if we run this okay
so this part actually remove it uh okay
delete it you see if we run this right
now we are just running at 10 raised to
the power power of two times which is
just 100 times if we run it shift
enter so here's a result and and the
solution the answer is 68 very good but
now the problem is asking you have to do
it you know one billion times that is a
problem because if you run just 1,000
times then it will take like 11
seconds okay so 1 billion times is going
to be take days or what was it years I
forgot so the the problem today is we're
going
to continue to do this and see
where exactly how you know how to solve
this uh is this there's some inefficient
code somewhere or is it because we need
to some kind to find some kind of
shortcut you know we are going to
explore this problem okay so you see
right now it's trying to do 1,000 times
I mean 10,000 times and uh it's still
running so it's this is not going to
work okay so that is the situation
okay and then today we're going to just
you know explore this problem
systematically from the ground up
so uh okay let's get warmed up let's see
so let's break break this function so
let's explain let me explain them one by
one
okay uh so actually put them back okay
so let's start a new W FR uh language
code P it there and uh pop it out okay
so this function f cycle is defined by
two components I mean by four
components so you have moved North which
is represented by that
function uh wait I mean represented by
this
function okay that's move north then
move west then then movees South then
move East okay so you have four
functions
now uh I want to Let's decompose these
four functions into each one of them
okay
so so let's do that okay let's just let
me let me just code it so you can see so
let's define North okay so
move uh North okay so that's one
function and it's just um
let me
just so we don't need this so let's see
so this should be one
function you see so okay let's move
north I'm going to explain how it works
in a
bit then move uh so now you need move
west okay
equals to equals to you see the code is
it now the code is final return 69 it
takes like 10 seconds or something so
anyway now move west is a
function uh that's
right
okay okay put a semicolon there so that
it doesn't show the result it kind of
suppressed the output so move west and
then move South Okay so
so constant equals to then this function
now the function the name the keyword
function in wolam language basically is
like Lambda in in Python in lisps
okay or in JavaScript just function so
so here's a function and uh here's a
parameter XX then this is you know then
this is what you do you know the SEC
second argument to the function is the
definition of the body this is what you
do to the to the parameter
XX okay so semicolon then move East okay
so we're going to define a move is a
constant equals to this function
okay now how does this this work let me
quick L explain this move west function
so to move all the zero so you see we we
we change the o to zero and we change
the dot to one dot is spaces so we
change the P sign to three so we work
with numbers kind of more familiar
instead of like strings of Single
Character I mean first of all we turn
the problem a list I mean a string a
giant string into a basically a matrix
okay so the ones are just empty space
three is a wall and zero is the balls
okay so you for example to move all the
zeros to the West means that you want to
move zero if there's one in front move
it to the left so you know you want to
move zero all to the left so let's try
it
[Music]
um for example because now we are you
know we have nicely defined each
individual functions four of them okay
so let's um so then we don't need
this this part anymore okay so we just
got these four functions cut them show
them in wam notepad so you got more
nicely
um uh you know color syntax colored you
know you define four
functions okay so move west how does it
work you see so you got a function and
the function has two arguments the first
argument is just
um you know it's just the parameter
parameter
names and the second part is just
replace repeated we use a pattern
matching so repeat it replace repeated
means that given an expression XX what
you do is you find this pattern this
pattern is the list it begin with zero
or more
something Then followed by a pattern
named
dots and this pattern is the longest
match of
one followed by one or more so one or
more ones so you know like that that
that
longest match so this pattern you know
so you want to capture all the ones
because the ones are like space you call
it dots Then followed by a pattern where
which is named by boss boss then it's
you know longest sequence of zeros one
or more zeros that's represented
by uh this pattern Then followed by tail
tail is like three
triple low line which means zero or more
things okay and the whole thing is in
the curly braces that means it's a least
so when you see this
pattern
then right arrow means change it to
change it to this head B starts tail so
you basically just swap the positions of
the balls and dots you see the B the
dots and both they are the names for the
pattern so once you capture this pattern
you are giving it a name dots that's how
this works similarly the head is just a
name for this zero or more okay so you
for for the X expression XX you find
this pattern then you replace by this
okay and you do it repeatedly until the
result no longer changes that's what
this replace repeated does okay so this
function that's how you move all the BS
to the
West now similarly for the East for the
East you just swap the positions of the
dots and ball now for North and South
basically what you do first is you
transpose The Matrix transposition means
like flip flipped it around a you know
diagonal you know left to bottom upper
left to bottom right diagonal you
flipped it then you do the move to the
left then you transpose again so you
need two transpose you can see this
transpose you transpose it then you
match the pattern to the you know move
all the balls to the left then you
transpose the result back so that's how
you move things to the north so this is
kind of a different approach this is in
wam language using pattern margin
okay does that make sense so we got uh
Steve is uh okay Steve got something to
say we are arguing about functional
programming and O anyway so we we need
to focus on this problem so cut this cut
this and uh put it back and uh let's
modify our
code
so so we
here we somewhere we Define this
function F1 cycle
now
we we paste these four definition
functions you know move north west south
and move East so now we redefine the F1
cycle like to do the sequence of them by
simply calling each one of the above so
so you don't so so that um so we can
start to modify so let's let's see let
me show you okay so actually you need a
function okay so
function uh function let's say the input
is y y so what you do is that so
actually we don't need the rest let's
just delete
it okay so we Define the F1 cycle
by parameter y y then expression is y y
is the argument then post fix
notation
uh what what is a character here okay so
that slash slash is equivalent to the
Unix vertical pipe okay so you pass the
argument y y to move
north okay then
you okay so then you
uh move west then you
move South then you
move East okay so let's
see make it one line so it's kind of
nice so again double check given an
argument you pass it to move north then
result path to move move west then
result P pass to move uh south and east
okay sounds good okay now given this
function now we can actually test this
again so copy all now previously you see
previously when we do it 100 times let's
say 100 times shift enter run it the
answer is 68 okay now let's
copy all select all paste wait let's
do
so yeah so let's say 100 okay then let's
remove this part this this this this
part are just duplicate of the above
okay so copy
all select all paste okay here's the
codeing wam
language now shift enter run it so you
see 68 is basically the same result as
above okay but now now that we have
decomposed the function we can we can
call each one at you know each one and
see exactly how they change the how they
change the board configuration
okay so the inputs okay okay this this
big Matrix this is annoying this
personal input let's remove
them okay so you know
so delete so we
don't okay now it's short
okay uh let's shrink a little bit is it
is the Fone size too big or what can we
do smaller like
that okay so you see X Matrix is our
Matrix okay
so let's let's just run it I mean
doesn't matter okay so shift
enter okay let's shrink this a little
bit so that Matrix shows as Matrix there
so X
Matrix shift enter that's a matrix
then then you
call move north okay and see you can
kind of
see okay with uh you know with now with
numbers it's actually harder to
see
yeah with numbers it's not harder to see
so let's change it back to let's change
it back to string
okay uh let's not have that okay so
let's let's not do this use numbers okay
let's not use numbers let's just work
with string so to work with string
string
so so zero replace all Zero
by by a string of capital O okay do it
do it do
it do
it okay no no do it there okay now
replace o one by
uh dot one is dot okay uh not there
there
there no no
no no no
okay and uh then there's one more
replacement so replace all number three
by the pound sign
uh wait oh okay it doesn't occur that's
okay so copy all back to language select
all paste and run the
code
great uh yeah so yeah so let's see
Matrix uh X
Matrix run
it okay can we can now we can show now
there's a comma there which is annoying
so let's kind of show in Matrix form so
that it will hide the comma so now it's
easier to
see okay so now we do the same now
except now let's apply move to
North okay shift enter so now you can
easily
see you see this zero right here is
moved all the way there
okay
okay so you can see all the balls got
moved to North now let's do another
one
let's
move
west okay north and west so for example
this will be over here let's do it
exactly
so this way we can visually
see our program is working you see so
this zero is now here that's
correct now let's see so the next thing
we want to check you know the problem is
you know we want to find
out uh what actually happens when you
move northwest southeast after one cycle
how does it it
effect so let's try Okay
so
so next so let let me okay let me let's
just do this fast okay I mean let get
become more advanced
so uh before we do that let's
do same thing like before but this time
we do the ccle F1 cycle okay so shift
enter so this is after moving North West
South and East okay so here is a result
now let's see what is the effect if you
do this again okay so F1 cycle then you
do it again F1 cycle shift
enter let's see if there's any
difference there is indeed you see
there's the there are four zeros there
now it's only three why because we can
try to trace it you see first you move
all this four
North yeah so you can
well so let's try something fancy
okay so let's see how do we do this
um what we want to do is we want to see
the effect preferably visually how how
this ball
moves and what is effect of repeating a
cycle you see here's a difference
between two two cycles but
but it's you know we can we can see they
are different
but but we are missing the each
individual steps of of tilting the boat
northwest
southeast
uh do I make sense okay
so okay so
so what do you want to do so you can
what you can do you can kind of do an
animation interactive animation of this
sport so in the animation what you want
to do is you want to move them
North West South
East okay North West
Southeast then northwest
southeast okay
so northwest
southeast
okay then northwest
southeast so you you kind of have this
um uh let's let's just explore okay so
let me
just
um you know show you
what okay move back
make a backup pop out and uh let's do
this okay move
north uh let's create a
list list of moves something like
that uh equals to equals to equals to is
that uh
move north
west
move South then
move East okay that's
one thing uh and we want you know I'm
just hacking so we we want you know like
like at least like
that so
North West South East okay
so so we want some kind of Animation
sequence
Nest so you want to use
fold fold each time takes that then
takes more then takes more then takes
more then takes that that
that okay so I got I think I know what
to
do so you want so let me let me show you
okay so you want
table
okay
take list of
moves each time take X number of
them uh take take just return from the
first element to nth okay the first end
elements that's what take
does tap Edge show you the
documentation okay so yeah good
control
magnify okay
so so that's you know take the first end
but then but God what's going
on
clear clear okay so now but X goes from
one to let's see what what
number uh to three 4 five
six let's say
24 uh 24
okay uh let's say I mean four times
by five okay so we got 20
steps so but what do you do with the
list so once you got the list so we can
actually we can run this so you know we
can show it
oh each one okay each one is a function
wait
uh yeah each one they become a
function yeah but
uh yeah so each one you know these are
functions that's
correct wait wait did I Define
in did I Define them yeah well we Define
them as
functions okay yeah okay so this is not
um well I
mean it's preferable to not show the
function instead instead of just show
the function
names okay but
um Let's ignore it for now okay but
anyway yeah but then you cannot see the
structure of this
table okay so wait so this needs to be
wait did we do it correctly shift enter
yeah it works but now each one of these
is a
function uh they show up as a function
so
okay so what we have to do now hello
plash great to see you so now what we
have to do now is
to plash are you the guy the are you the
Indian guy from s Discord I'm
wondering
um so anyway so so Focus okay so we got
a list of you know function
names what do you want to do
um you know one thing we can do easily
is we can hold yeah
okay so again if you are watching
offline just skip around okay so I'm I'm
just going to go easy easy so let's see
so
um so once you have that you want
to so what do you do with the list so
what you do is you okay let's just yeah
forget
about showing symbols so for this you
copy that paste it okay let's put it
here
so what you do is once you have this
thing this is a sequence starting with
one element then two element and three
you know which is just bunch of this
list you fold you call the fold function
fold is like reduce in python or others
okay you call the fold function you
apply a function first argument is a
function the second argument is a least
and in our case is that least so what
function you want to call you want
to call and then then you need the
argument so the argument is X Matrix
okay that's the input uh but what is the
function you want to call okay you need
to construct a function so let's do it
here so it's a
function this x is one these functions
okay so this getting
into kind of advanced functional
programming so let me just do
it so X is a function you want to apply
it
to uh wait so yeah X is the
argument so this this function needs to
take two argument X and Y
okay uh and what is the body of the
function function well the body of the
function so it takes two things X is
originally this Matrix okay
so uh so let me just and Y is actually
the function the function from this list
so you know why is that so so why don't
we rename in them so that it makes more
sense okay so fold the first fold is
reduced so it takes a function takes two
argument I mean three one the first one
is a function the second one is the
initial input the third one is a
list okay so what the function do the
function will take two arguments you
know we name it AR and FF so and it will
return FF applied to
AR okay yeah
so this so we don't you know remove that
so this is what we want okay so um and
uh okay so actually so this is getting
you know slightly complicated so anyway
but you'll see the result okay now we
don't need we don't want
that semi
semicolon okay so now let's paste this
code okay run it it will give us a
sequence of this northwest southeast
then northwest
southeast sequence of them visually R
it indeed so you can
see now but we need to put them into a
matrix form so it's easier to read so
let's uh so that would
[Music]
be here
okay so we we actually so let's put it
here so postfix
notation Matrix
form okay shift enter to run it great so
you can see oh we got the error
oh H yeah well that's a problem with the
Matrix form because if you call M Matrix
form it became part of the expression so
so then when you do you know when you
call the function on The
Matrix it
doesn't it didn't get the Matrix but it
gets the Matrix form of the Matrix so it
doesn't know what to do so that's why
you got this transpose you know so you
need to remove the Matrix form
here instead you want to apply the
Matrix form to the the hole okay so let
me show you so this this is what we want
we want to map okay map Matrix
[Music]
form a function to this thing okay uh so
let's name this thing
by board
history okay
uh not board uh move history something
okay board history so board history is a
list of matrices of
movements then then you just say map The
Matrix form to the board history
okay good we don't need that okay so
that okay so put a semicolon there so
there okay so
control dot to select then paste okay
shift
enter
fantastic yep
fantastic okay so you can see in the
beginning we got the Matrix all mve to
the north then to the west then then to
the South check correct then then to the
east check correct they all to the east
yes then North again check now you see
now this result is different from that
result you know so when you do a extra
cycle it it became different so this is
north then West seems
correct then
South then yeah South is that correct
yes then East is that correct yes then
North again that now is this North same
as the before
um no it's different I think I think
that was
North so anyway so that North
then West
then South check seems right then East
okay then North
again okay now let's remember this
pattern because let's see when does it
is it different so 0 0 then Gap pound
dot Z 0 on the right side you have a
vertical zeros on the right and in the
middle
okay this is north right okay so in the
middle you got this kind of
configuration like a human coring or
something okay so this is
North
West
South
East okay then North again okay now it
looks like the
same no
okay notice here you got a this
configuration the right hand side four
lines got connected to the left columns
but but not over here see so you can see
the cycle differs okay so then
North
West
South East okay that is actually the end
hm so what have we learned we learned
you know so when you
move every North West Southeast every
cycle the result is actually different
so the question is when will the result
be the same because when it's the same
you when you are sure that every time
you do a cycle the result no longer
changes then you can
stop okay and maybe that's the key to
solve this problem because you need to
do this cycle
one billion times hello German hey
haven't seen you for a while German is a
wolam language
coder okay so we got so what I want to
do so I mean so you know we are doing
kind of trial and error to visualize
this
problem this is a very good problem for
visualization because you are seeing the
boards move on the
board and
uh but if you you know if you really
want to solve the problem you really
actually just think you need to think
about this problem like mathematically
as a
puzzle that is the real way to solve the
problem as a mathematician you want to
analyze what happens through the
boss but we are doing you know we are
you know using computer to help us kind
of
um but it's not the true solution I mean
it's not the true way to solve
mathematical problems because for real
mathematical problems you don't want
just to try out an error and see what
happens it helps a bit but that's
not you know that's not the ultimate
approach because if you do this trial in
error it can you know it it can end up
many hours you know you don't know what
what's going on you know just like trial
and error programming which you
shouldn't do but anyway we are you know
we are exploring the wam language so
anyway we see the visual pattern but
what I want to do is more uh another
trick in wolam language is that you
can you can do the whole thing by Let Me
Show You by a more better visual
approach okay so what you do is let me
just code it
okay
uh uh
wait okay so we got so what is is
mapboard
history Matrix form
okay so B okay manipulate okay both
history
uh so we want to
do
manipulate manipulate is a way to show
animation step by
step which is a very powerful useful uh
wolam language thing you don't have that
in any other language okay so manipulate
takes just like a table takes two
arguments okay
so the first argument is going to be
this for history it's a list okay but we
want to take the nth element okay then n
goes from
one to 24 you know they are total 24
okay let's do this
so and uh actually actually you need the
Matrix form
okay okay so
that paste shift enter so that's what we
want this is beautiful now let's we can
you know so we can go step by step let's
see right arrow no
uh click on
that oh we got what
okay this is not what we
want wait
history manipulate Bard history
n Matrix form so when n is
one when n is two okay what's going
on okay and let's see the
documentation expression um me U Max
generate the version of expression with
control added to allow
interactive okay in step of okay maybe
we want to say instead step of one okay
let's try that again shift
enter yeah okay because before it's one
it's going into real numbers okay now
it's
good so this part we don't want that's a
mistake oh that's a board history
okay so now we got
this
next let's
see wait
uh oh this one uh step
forward
what can you use Arrow I want to use
Arrow key to
control okay we still got an eror
somewhere 11 12 16 18 19 2011 wait
something is wrong so how many how many
total things we have
here oh we got 20 things okay so
actually
let's let's let's make it more beautiful
okay let me show you how to generate a
more elegant way to generate this
sequence of four things okay so instead
of of hard coding this like that
you you just have name one thing you
know
one thing then you use a table okay you
want a table of this thing and uh and uh
how many
times uh let's say 10 okay so you don't
need
X um 10 let's see if that
works yeah okay so
um uh
okay let's
hold so hold means don't evaluate
okay so
hold
uh okay let's do that hold hold hold
okay so make it easier to read
so
that so you
got okay actually don't I mean use hold
form
instead Okay so
that there that's what we want then you
need to flatten it because now it's
nested uh let's see do I want to flatten
it yes okay so now you just say flatten
flat and add add is a prefix notation so
when you have some
symbol add
something that basically just
means that okay so these two are
equivalent for example let me show you
because wam language is symbolic you see
when you run this you know wfam language
doesn't know what is f f FF or what is X
X they are just
symbols so but this is a shortcut for
this so it just become you know it's the
same thing it's exactly the same
thing so that's why we are using at here
so the advantage is that you avoid you
know lots of nesting of the
brackets so okay so remove that remove
that so and here we use flatten flatten
at this whole table okay so so this
thing we can now do
it okay so that's beautiful you know so
this moves so now you know much shorter
Cod shorter you know elegant code than
than than this you know than that plus
we hold the form so so all these
functions they don't become the function
body
itself okay so that's least the moves
but once you make now they each one is a
hold form you have to say release hold
so this FF you need to say release
hold because otherwise it won't work let
me show you so otherwise if you say
that it just um okay remove the
semicolon run
it you see it just shows that because
that function you told it to hold so
it's not actually
applying so you have to say release hold
here okay release hold I'm not sure uh
maybe you need a
paren oh it works okay so let's see the
presidence yeah it works okay so you
need the release hold here
so fantastic okay so now here let's try
this
again uh Bard history now Bard history
what
[Music]
history let's define number of Cycles
okay equals
to
uh
equal how many cycles let's say 10 okay
so number of Cycles is 10 then you just
put it
there then this will
[Music]
be number of Cycles okay
yeah so let's try it again do it do
it run it that's good then we here is
the board
history uh let's double check board
history run it
paste run
it yeah we got uh you
know that's one
Matrix that's a second Matrix that's
right so that's a board history then you
map Matrix form to Bo history okay we
are going too slow then you
manipulate uh and the manipulate then
number of Cycles
okay
so number of Cycles times
four
okay do it do it fantastic
now let's
expand
play H we still got problems
oh we forgot the yeah you need to say in
increment of one
not not getting into decimal
stuff do it
fantastic
play and uh
slower oh now it's beautiful slower
slower slower
okay now let's see so we got 40 10
Cycles one two three
four yeah so
fantastic are this this is a great
achievement for today's you know talk
show are you guys seeing
this
uh you know wolam language you can do
this you of course you can do this in
python or even email like this you know
you can just generate the text and you
know play the text uh it's
fun but wam language lets you do to to
uh do this much easier okay so now let's
look at
this what's going on with these uh
marbles South East
North West South East North West West
South East North West South East
North uh yeah that's fun but it's not
actually solving the problem we need
to stop so we need to actually think
about what's going on now can you use
arrow
keys uh let's see
play now
back can you can you use arrrow
Keys uh no but I think you can but I but
you need to do
something yeah so like you
know I have to look up on how to you map
the arrow keys to make them go forward
or
backward so but anyway so here is the
thing
so okay so now we need to think what's
going on with this puzzle am I doing
good are you guys following hello
juang oh uh German caught my error thank
you so what is going on with this
problem you know we need to do this one
billion cycles one followed by N9
zeros and uh so actually the real
question we want to know is yeah we want
to know what happens in each cycle when
does the ball when does the cycle no
longer have an effect
you know you really need to think about
this
problem because for each cycle there are
four TS north northwest southeast so
each cycle is actually made up of four
steps yeah so you really need to you
know I need really need to start to
draw you know to think about what is
effect
when when does the tilting no longer
change after a
cycle so
anyone but don't don't give me the
answer yet okay Steve has solved the
problem you know so he's warning me
about the issue
but but I don't want to look at the
spoilers yet
so yeah yeah so okay so right now
actually I just need to
think okay so so here is the whole code
so you can
[Music]
see uh let's maybe clean up the
code number of Cycle Sport history and
uh yeah so this is only this is only 10
Cycles
select
all yeah select all paste okay here is
the whole
code shift enter let's rerun
it then generate the board
history then you got this
animation play it
okay okay it's already 1 hour should we
one you know and I'm not anywhere
yet you know so far I've been just
playing with the wolam language but not
actually solving the
problem okay
so move there move them so what about
you know you just call a fixed
point so that it will know when the
cycle no longer has any effect then it
stops but I tried that yesterday that
doesn't work you know it still take a
long time so I I don't know
why uh
[Music]
but you know so really what you really
need to know is actually what happens to
the marbles you know as a math
problem and I don't know what to do now
so okay let me just think about
it we can
you know so far so good we kind of
played with wolam language and we got
into this visualization it's very
good but this
[Music]
visualization
helps but does not directly does not
obviously is the
answer when should you know when the
Cycles no longer have
effect so to really solve the problem
you really just need to think about
that and uh if I do that then it's going
to be me just sitting here thinking for
minutes so there will be no video
content
so what to do so I don't
know okay so maybe we can try to think
about this
problem you know while
I walk you know draw some pictures or
something Juan says I'm implementing
programming language following a book
called crafting interpreters yes I think
we talked about that someone posted that
I think oh
it yeah because I was I remember I was
just reading about that few days
ago uh good for you but
uh yeah that came
from you know so there is this book
called crafting
interpreters and uh which allows you oh
yeah that came
from you know but anyway there's a book
about crafting interpreters it's also
free or you can pay for it but it's also
free online supposedly a great book
which teaches you about designing and
implementing a programming
language in Hall from the ground
up so you have to now I I don't know to
what degree it actually teaches you
about designing a language but however
it does teach you about you know
implementing you know kind of
implementing a language from the ground
up including you know writing a passor
writing a
compiler so anyway so supposedly that's
a good book
yeah anyway so go uh going back to this
problem we want to know when does it
Cycles has no
effects
so the other thing we want to know which
is slightly separate is that why does
fixed Point not work because if
you you know every time you do this
cycle you can tell Wan language to use
you know you call the fixed Point
function which just repeat this until
the result no longer changes
so that
should be a solution assuming that the
cycle will have no effect at some point
so you don't have to do this a million
times as soon as the cycle stops having
any effect the program stops so you save
a lot you know redundant
computation but like I said I tried it
yesterday or today uh you know a day
ago it doesn't stop right away
so but I haven't think thought about why
so one question is why does the fixed
Point does not seems to
work that's one thing maybe it actually
work but it just because our code is not
efficient so we are still have to wait a
long
time so that's one question
we can
pursue but the central question is
really actually the math problem what
happens to the
boss okay let's think about what happens
to the
boss so well I mean in order to do
that it's just mostly just about
thinking okay so but let me try to do
this interactively so think and
explain what my brain is doing okay so
we kind
of so given a board so you you know you
got these marbl when you teer North they
go to the
north okay so you T West Southeast the B
rows uh they keep rolling but what's
what is the condition that for each
cycle the balls no longer moves no
longer change you see in between a cycle
you know every time you te northwest
southeast they will
move almost all the time because as you
know the only condition that when you
tear nobody you know no balls move is
when the balls got Wars on all
sides so when you teer North
and if the balls are already tiled North
before then there's no
change okay that's you know that's
that's one
condition then when you te
West the ball the ball will not move
only when the ball are all kind of has a
western War already or in other words
you already tiled West before
so the condition for each ta the
condition that the ball do not move at
all no balls move is when the balls
already have a you know a wall in that
direction okay but now however when you
combine the T tilting in different
directions
northwest
southeast you see it is possible that
after this
cycle the ball will not move at all but
however when you til in each
Direction They the balls move they will
just after all the direction they just
come back to the original position so
when does that happen for example it
happens when you have like uh let's see
a war there here's a
ball uh let's let's see you know for
example this is one I can think
of you know so let's say a line
here so here is a
wall and here's a w so you have some
kind of
swastika pattern here okay
you know so so this ble when you te
North it stops here then West stops here
south it stops here then then East stops
here oh wait so wait oh
gotcha
wait oh so the end step is East not
North
you see then you move north then it
stops there so oh I think I know the
answer
tricky
miraculously I wasn't planning to really
solve it but this is a simple example to
you know to see how it how the ball
stops moving you see in this case it
will stop moving
because because you know every time you
do a
cycle but you
see it s stops moving only if you try to
move north again then the ball doesn't
change you
see ah you see yes I see so now actually
actually I do
know the solution the solution is to use
a fixed point but however the end you
know the ending segment is not when you
see the end is when the ball are teed to
the east but what you want to actually
check is then you you move to the north
and check okay so I think I know the
answer uh jman says is this related to
cellular automation no not obviously not
in any obvious
way but I but I presume you can turn it
into a cellular Auto automation
though yeah I mean that that would be a
different thing to explore to turn this
problem to or to to to specify this
problem in terms of cellular
automat because cellular automat is also
dealing with Squid you know cells and uh
you have rules
that govern each
generation where the different
conditions of the cells are so in this
in terms of cellular autometer you have
a great 10 by 10 in our case wait one
two 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 yeah 10 by 10 then
each cell has three
conditions either o or dot or pound side
right and then you have a rule to
determine in each generation what the
cell um
changes okay and that rule is will be
very difficult to
specify for one thing if the cell is
already a pound sign that cell never
changes okay but if the cell is a
period that cell will change depending
on um you know it will depends on the
neighboring periods and and O so the to
specify this as a cellular
autom the rules will be quite involved
because it will involve kind of all the
adjacent vertical or horizontal as long
as you know they are dots or zero yeah
so
you know so the rules the rule for each
generation will be fairly elaborate and
it it will be kind of like our code of
using this you know using using the
pattern
maging uh so the rule will be fairly
complex uh but what do what benefit do
you get if you think of this problem as
a cellular autom what benefit would you
get
I'm not sure what benefit you would get
so yeah that's interesting though anyway
so I think I think I know the answer
let's you know why not we try to you
know solve this Advent of code problem
so the pro so we the answer you know so
we can observe this situation you know
so the CYO will stop
yeah only if you
[Music]
compare uh let's see one two three four
wait how does that one two three four so
each cycle is 1 two 3 4 four TS one two
three
four and you want to compare so given
the beginning 1 two 3
4 wait wait wait the end is always
moving to the east okay the end the last
TI is always moving to the east so the
ball would be
here
okay one two three four okay end on the
east
then yeah so if you use fixed point it
should still
work one two three
4 One Two Three
4 right so the end condition let's go
back for you know just see
four one two three 4 One Two 3 4 One Two
3 4 One 2 three 4 let's look at this
okay 1 two 3 4 One Two 3 4 One Two 3 4
Slow Down slow down slow
down one 2 3 4 One 2 three let's slow
down slow
down two three and slow down four
one
3 4 check
3 4 stop check one
4 one okay let's just observe this for a
while I still don't get
it one two
North
West South
East
North
West
South
East North West
East how different you know this is so
interesting getting interesting so let's
increase the number of
count let's see let's increase the
number of Cycles let's say 10 Cycles
let's say 30
okay and then let's put a semicolon so
it doesn't show it
copy or select or paste R
it so 30
Cycles okay is this is only 30
Cycles it's
magnify okay and uh run this okay too
fast slow
down two three
so what I'm trying to observe is the
lower right corner so try to observe the
lower right corner configuration
changes okay let's start from you know
waited to finish North West
Southeast North West
southeast
northwest
North oh they they
changes okay so okay I got you you know
so I started to have new idea so we are
observing I am observing this corner
okay the lower right
corner so you see for part of the
board the configuration May repeat after
a certain cycle
okay but but however for other part of
the board the cycle do not
sink so each part of the board they may
repeat after you know each cycle after
you know after certain Cycles then they
repeat but the period may not be the
same the period period of each local
Regional
repetition may not be the same so yes
but what you want what you really want
is you want to find the periodicity of
the
entire cycle
repetition it's you know this is really
interesting so let's look at this
again lower right corner but it still
doesn't explain why fixed Point not want
work am I making
sense let's see
so look at this part that and that that
that okay so you see so you see it it
ends up in this configuration
there you see
this but
however you see now that pattern is
G you see now it's G
so there okay after 14th Cycle
uh there 20
21 there
25 3 4 there 29 2 3 4 there 33
so uh and but in 37 it becomes something
else
what okay let's let's start from the
beginning
okay
stop start from the beginning do it
again North okay
there three 21 okay
25 29 you see you got this field pattern
there there but now it's missing here
you see now it's missing so they they
mutate into a different stable P okay
now it's four zeros here that's again
different
[Music]
H isy okay
27 okay now it's
missing a zero
here okay
so then it came back to that pattern you
see
so what does this mean so actually
still we don't know the answer to this
this question
so uh okay but maybe I stop
though so let's see the hello well says
a bit sad today your talk show make me
feel better thank
you okay so so far we don't know what's
going
on why but you see the whole pattern if
the cycle has no
effect it will go into a period right a
period ody
SE North West South
East okay so now let's stop this now I
got a better idea now this this
animation is showing each individual TI
okay now let's try to have an animation
that showing just the every cycle not
every
til okay just for fun you know I'm I'm
just exploring this blindly trial and
error playing with wam
language uh but again to properly solve
properly solve this solve the problem
you just need to think about this math
you know like just sit there and think
about this math
uh math issue
so is you know not not just coding and
see the pretty pictures but let's see
the pretty pictures so now we want an
animation where a cycle is each you know
actual cycle till um okay so what you do
is
you list the moves okay so now it's
actually easy to do
um this is actually this is not uh
number of Cycles okay so oh okay so we
can use the same data
structure but here in instead of
four let's see
so maybe that will do okay try that try
that
okay so now it should
show uh slow slow slow down slow
down so now it's showing the north each
cycle
North okay changes
so this is showing each four
TS just fascinating though it's
fascinating you see
so if you each each set of four
TS they they also have a
periodic okay oh you have to find
the psy
oh I get it now I
know you see here's the thing so you
don't want to consider each
tilt rather you want to
consider each cycle cycle here is
defined as you know North West
Southeast this sequence of Tils so you
want to look at at the cycle right right
now we are observing the effect of each
cycle okay so but if you look at this
then you can
see do they ever repeat I think they do
okay so let's look at observe this
pattern even visually it's
it's not so easy okay
so so I think so if you look at the
cycle end result of each cycle
they repeat
too but you know they just they don't
just become stable instead they repeat
there's a period
okay so yeah so there is a
period tricky very nasty you know well a
good problem okay so this aent of code
um day 14 is it day 14 part
two okay 2023 you know a good problem so
you want to know basically you want to
find out the the
periodic of this
function god that that to compute
that oh God to compute that is
not it's not trivial though it's not
obvious you want to find out the
periodicity of this function the
function in question is this F1 cycle
Okay so you want to find out periodic so
that when you so you don't call Nest nor
do you call fixed point because if you
just call fixed Point often times they
actually they never repeat neighbor by
neighbor they you know like they never
become stable the pattern but however
this the pattern become stable in a
sense that they repeat
so there is a
periodic you know maybe after five cyle
Cycles it repeats you know the F same
five frames they repeat over and over
again it may be the periodic may be n
maybe 90 maybe 1 million and one you
don't
know but however once you know the
periodic then you
know when the function is repeated end
times you you know exactly what
configuration it will be without having
to compute
it so you know if the question is asking
for a
billion
repetitions then if you know the
periodic is you know let's say
100 then you you just um you know you
just have to compute 100 times you never
need to compute more than the periodic
number of times
okay right so you just need to know the
periodic
and and
yeah oh okay so you just so the so you
need to find the periodic of this cycle
function and the result
the the result board configuration is
basically the last step in that P
Odyssey
okay okay I kind of got the idea okay
very tricky
problem now let's look up
documentation uh fix Point see if there
is kind of some building option to
detect
py uh
no okay well you got the same text okay
so actually you can use the same test
that is a
key you see the fixed point is a
function that computes a function with a
given input it will stop when the result
no longer Chang
okay then you can give a third argument
that says do a maximum of n
times you know in our case 1 billion but
however it won't work because each time
you run the function f in our case is F1
cycle you know each time you run this
function the result will not be the
same most of the time you will not you
know in in some I guess no they they
will not be the
same because you can see this tricky
thing each time they run they will not
be the same the ball will be moved
somewhere but however they they they
repeat so you need to
find they repeat okay so so the you need
to find the periodic you know know like
how many different board configurations
they will end
up so you find the py then you can apply
this same
test okay so let's see the same test
applies as to successive pair of
results fantastic that's
exactly the solution okay let's check
some example beautiful wolam language
you see they have thought out about this
issue you know when you have a fixed
Point okay well the function doesn't
repeat by itself I mean I mean it never
come out the same however the function
may have a repetition a cycle a
periodicity so you just
say you know you you just say same test
s test and give a number let's
see yeah well the problem is to find out
I mean what so what is the likely Hood
what is the range of
periodic options same test there okay so
stop assume a successive iterations
differ by less than
that okay
differ by less than that
okay successive iteration differ by that
no what about this perform exact exact
arithmetic but use a numerical
comparison function so
no so the same test is a
function okay it let's just
specify okay we we
need right now we need a function that
does does repetition like fix point but
however to be able to detect the cycle
so let's see W language fantastic you
have so many options stability
conditions okay let's look at some of
them our fixed Point gives the fixed
points for a recurrence
[Music]
equation that looks like very
promising recurrence
equation okay
equation then gives the fix points for a
recurrence
equation uh okay so we need to turn this
into a equation what is
it oh God this you know this requires
thinking so we need to now we need to
turn this function F1
cycle and express it as a equation
so and the F cycle you need to also
change it so it takes a number of times
to
repeat that's
easy uh so we you know for example let's
just play with wfam language uh so I
mean I'm
just okay so for example you want to uh
let me do this okay so you
Define F1 cycle
n that means repeat it okay uh let's say
repeat okay so you define that
by equals to uh
Nest uh okay so F cycle repeat uh okay
so let's use a function okay so function
so it's a function then the body of the
function so xn
so the argument is is uh is two
arguments one is X then n then that
means you call F1 cycle begin with X
initial value and repeat it n times how
beautiful this is how you
do so this F1 cycle
repeat
n uh wait
okay so this defines you know you run
the F1 cycle nend times
okay so now this function now you you
have to say so basically if you want to
use this you know fixed Point relation
recurrence equation so you got a
equation if repeat X then n is
is equals to let's say the py
is is five okay then it
means then then uh equals
to A minus 5 something like
that so this is how you determine and
something something like that okay
equation a n and n gives the fixed
points for a recurrence equation so
recurrence
equation wait a
minute you can't I mean that's
not wait F cycle is not a
recurrence equation no yeah so you I
don't think you can do that F1 cycle is
not a
recurrence function because it does not
define what the function is in terms of
the previous one but what about this
wait so F1 cycle repeat
n oh yes then you can so repeat and let
me try that again so repeat and equals
to oh yeah yes okay so you can actually
Define this as a recurrence
relation F cycle repeat and just means F
cycle n minus one
okay wait it it equals
to F cycle
applied to F cycle n minus one
there so here we have a recurrence
relation however now it involves two
functions so it's probably not
appropriate so we need to rewrite again
in terms of one single function because
this is you know this is involving two
functions anyway so that's
oh and this is new
in
14.1 oh this is then I don't think
that's what we want
because when it's very new then you know
it's less
used uh I'm not even sure we have I have
it I'm using uh
what and do yeah up so let's see
r
fixed yeah I'm not using 14.1 I'm using
yeah so in order to know you run dollar
sign version number okay shift enter
yeah I'm using
14.0 so this is new and not likely what
we want
but you know
very fancy and this is not experimental
otherwise your say so this is there for
good uh but however
it's not likely what we
want so our stability conditions also
new R fixed Point D fixed points also
you know also in 14.1
not likely what we want we want what we
want you see this these are like
differential equations and Chaos systems
dynamical systems and Chaos Theory kind
of that's what they that's you know
that's why they have these
recurrence equations you know that's
what dynamical systems is
about like you define a function in
terms of pre previous time you know time
base like the flowing of water or stream
something like that so that's not likely
what we want we want we want a a
function that
determines the cycle of a function like
the
periodicity of a discrete
function okay so you give a function f
every time you call it it returns
something you call F again on a result
then you call F again on a
result but f is such that after you run
a few times it repeats you call itself
it start to repeat like 1 2 3 1 2 3 1
two
3 so you want a function that determines
that takes a
function and determines the periodic of
that function okay so that is what we
want now we think we thought about this
and good we
got you know we got a clear
understanding what what is
needed so the question now is is is
there a function in wol language that DP
that determines
cycle not I know of you know not in my
memory so let's search and see if we
can search for periodic
ah stupid
English p i o d uh it's let's do muscle
memory uh no that doesn't
H search let's just
search not the city okay that is
actually how you spell it periodic d i c
i t
y
period
what p
City PR the city
God okay anyway let's just search for
period and let's see what we
find sampling period geological period
data historical period data function
period
plot let's see function period find Nest
plot find Nest period no that's a
resource function uh we don't want
resource function resource function
means someone has written
it oh
this this is exactly what we want
so this implies there's no building
function that does it so this re you
know this resource function means
someone wrote this
package and
uh and uh according to the documentation
looks like exactly what we
need God
wait what is
that so find Next Period try to find the
repetition period for nesting of a
function
exactly attempts to find the repetition
period
okay yeah but this okay so this one is
written in 2019 by whom let's see
Richard Phillips okay I don't know I
don't think I know the guy
okay but this function should be easy to
write
uh or I can you know we can simply call
this you know the power of w language
you can
actually you know you just paste this
code you you'll
work without having to import anything
you know just call resource function
find Next Period then you work yeah but
that's using someone else is
callede
um I could write this
myself let's see nextest while
[Music]
maybe yeah actually we can just call
next next while so your nextest
while yeah but it still take it will
take some some code to write this to to
to create this
um Fin n period this is exactly what we
want you know you can try to implement
it using Nest while which will Nest the
function with a given condition but the
issue is that you don't know you you
know you have to accumulate at least
each time you have to compare the
previous compare compare to see when it
repeats
so yeah we can do that but now I'm
tired
uh yeah so okay in summary let's give a
summary oh Molina says we t
work maybe
yeah uh let's
see see the documentation for tally
Tally the elements in this distin or
distinct element together with their
multiplicities
yes okay you work but
indirectly because first of all you
don't know what is a period right and
you you have to do this a billion
times uh right now we have no idea what
is a period but I assume it's pretty
small like 100 less than 1,000 probably
because this devious problem you know
this this devious um Advent of code you
know the period but but but but we do we
we have no idea what is a period it
could be you know one or two to to even
a billion not likely a billion
because we can assume they designed the
problem such that if you don't know
about the period thing your program will
run for years you know so so the period
is actually probably something small
like a thousand or 2,000 you
know but still we don't know exactly
what is a period so if we going to use
tally it's it will be some kind kind of
trial and error you know you run it for
2,000 times then you tally then you you
you you get the multiplicities then you
get idea of the you know let's you know
why don't we try it instead of talking
you know we can
um tally okay so Tally what you want you
you just want this table okay actually
board history let's
try and see what we
got
what wait uh
what T
list oh okay again it's a cycle
issue uh wait why does it not work so t
a a b c i c b a so they group yeah so it
should work but oh it does you
see you see this four you
see this Matrix repeated once once once
that's a unique configuration but you
see this Matrix is repeated four times
this Matrix is repeated four times you
see four
times so when when we so after we call
tally then we can then we use the tally
result if they
multiplicity
is is repeated so if we have a lot
multiplicities that are the same then
that is the periodic of the functions
probably something like that so you see
we see a lot Force here then the period
is
four you see we see a lot fours here you
see so the so this configuration
repeated four times this configuration
which is different from that one is also
is again different repeated four times
so you know the the
multiplicity four appears many times so
that means this
you know
this the cycle of this is four the
periodic of this is four 1 2 3 four like
every four times it
repeats okay let's check so yeah the P
okay so let's see so it should be every
four times it repeats
it's hard to see I mean
well yeah anyway so tal idea is is not a
direct
approach and uh even then you have to
guess so I don't think it's
good yes so you have
to you really just have to implement
this find next period is there some
better
way I thought there should be a building
function
because finding the period of function
of a discrete
function is fairly common
uh and you know then we have to look up
his you know actually so let's play with
it let's you know actually we can do
this we can get the source code like
let's just try it okay so you know it's
you know so he's
um resource function uh let's say
FFF equals to this resource function
shift enter you'll go over the internet
and grab that
function okay take a
while uh okay there we have it now
question mark and uh question mark and
FFF now let's see the definition
okay
so and then you click on okay so you you
you click on
that and that gives you the
documentation we want the source
code so what is is you click on
that there it is the source code
beautiful it's so
convenient so you can see the source
code let's magnify
so we are cheating we are looking at
someone
else's but you see yeah you see it's
starting a guess 100,000 times as a
guess for the period because to do this
you need to and also look at he's using
Nest while so basically every time you
compute this function you have to save
the result then compute the next next
nest nesting then comp then save the
result compared to if you know it
repeats any the any of the sav results
so you know you then you have to try
this initially 100,000
times so basically you are just you know
you you just have to save the result and
try it each
time um you know so let's see block okay
so
with then if then if statements you know
if you know then length Okay so no I
don't want
that yeah it's kind of
um yeah okay so this will give you
periodic but um which is what I what we
want so once we know the p other C we
have a so let's say the period is nine
that means that means the F1 cycle has n
distinct configurations for the
board then if you want to do a million
times or a billion times you take the
mod of the billion over the periodic so
billion divided by
9 you get a
remainder so let's say you know what is
it remainder is one in in this case
something but let's say the remainder is
three then you just take the third part
of the period you know the the the third
configuration that is the
answer yeah that's so simple now now now
it's so simple so now you want to find
the periodic of this
function uh this function f cycle right
yeah you want to find the py of this F1
cycle let's say it's n then to repeat
this a billion times you
mod let's try I mean let's write it out
okay let's just you know let's just
pretend this works okay
copy periodic equals
to call that function let's make it
uh full I mean let's
actually let's just make it actually
work
okay so let me try this okay cut cut cut
cut and do it properly over here
okay uh tally we don't want fix point we
don't want okay uh and this we want okay
put a line break and
okay and uh this will
Define
okay X fined period okay so we Define
that function from this resource okay
then then we Define uh
period we don't want that anymore so
period x period equals
to equals to find the period of our F1
cycle
function and uh it requires a initial
input X
Matrix and uh it also requires a
optional uh try Okay optional try Okay
100,000 let's say
okay let's just run actually this will
give us
answer turn
it one okay one is not
correct
what the period of one okay so maybe we
didn't try on enough
well this shouldn't even you shouldn't
return one okay let's
try
10,000 okay
so shift control D break and shift
enter
one uh did we call this function
correctly F expression
n f expression n
F
expression n why does it return
one if the period is not found find n
period return a failure object
okay yeah but it returns one that means
our function F1 cycle has a period of
one which means me it repeats every you
know it just repeats return the same
result which is not
true what what what is going
on what's going
on N list F1 cycle
so so this is the first
result and uh this is the second
result and they are not the same
so why do you say period is
one ah God frustration uh frustration
one after
another or is it because you see the one
of the problem is you see this resource
function someone else wrote
it so you have to trust this guy Richard
Phillips is's a great coder but however
the wolan research function repository
they are curated meaning that everything
you see as soon as you know as long as
they are on wolam function
repository they are verifi to be correct
at least in some way so there's qu
quality assurance otherwise they
wouldn't be on wolam function uh
repository that's by
Design so every function uploaded there
you know as soon as you know if you can
use it that means
it's at least 99.9 correct okay so I
should think that this function is
correct that we you know we are calling
find this
period but however it's giving us
one for the F1 Cycles which does not
seems to be correct
so I used it wrong or
something because the period is not
one uh because each time you call
they return different
answers so what is this now T okay let's
remove this T too
big so again looking back at
this F1 cycle you see the period you see
this board history where does boort
history come from Bo history came from
applying this
function every four times oh God
so okay I don't know but we are
getting close
though we getting pretty close right now
I'm just want I just want to
verify why does this give us a period of
one uh which
is does not seems
right uh
yeah and uh
okay I think maybe that's it today so
you know we did two hours
plus okay yeah good point not
necessarily every four
times yeah okay so I think you know we
stop here this problem is kind of nasty
but so far we do
know I'm pretty sure I'm 99 .9% sure
that you need to find the periodic of
this cycle
function
then you know the solution is the whole
solution is just um so once you know the
periodicity then you just 1 billion
times 10 ra to
9 uh you do a
mod so modular arithmetics so that
divided
by by X
periodic okay that's a number then you
just then you just call Nest okay you
let's you know let's mark up the
function solution you call this
function with the with the okay so you
call this
function with the initial input of
Matrix and you call this number of times
okay so let's see so
that's that is the final board condition
once you got the final board condition
let's write it
out something like that final B
condition equals to okay then once you
got
that then you just tally the I mean the
you just count the
there okay so actually
so then you just do that and uh do that
and that should be the
answer okay so the new code would be
just this and we are calling someone
else's function
uh try to find the
periodic and
uh and it's giving us one which is very
weird uh not
not so we have to figure out what's
going on there then once we got py then
it's
just final condition is mod
divided by periodic take the remainder
and miss it that many
times
[Music]
then then just total okay yeah but okay
that's it thank you guys for
watching anything else
interesting bye guys for today hope you
enjoy the
show uh uh hope you learn some W from
language tricks or some you know or have
some fun watching
me solve this
problem uh if you like my stuff go to.
info code at the
bottom donate to me patreon or Amazon
gift card or
PayPal okay thank you guys guys bye so
we shut down in two minutes or
so oh Steve says great live stream
today thank you
Steve Steve get on YouTube you know get
on YouTube and
uh
uh bye guys hey Dam D Dam sick bye guys