hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we are going to code
emac lisp we are going to write a
program that validate all the matching
brackets may it be cly brackets
parentheses or square brackets or any of
the Chinese brackets or Unico brackets
so we're going to check you know there's
Mis no mismatch
brackets so that's one thing and I'm
going to talk about my keyboards in the
first five minutes five minutes or so so
this is kesis form keyboard brand new
okay I did a unboxing yesterday uh two
or two days ago you you should go watch
it uh and this is my ultimate hacking
keyboard okay and let me show this again
the king of
keyboards so this is uh
SW board data hand s v a l b o a r d uh
this is a fantastic very Advanced
keyboard so I'll be using it down the
road you know not yet sorry about that
so we got the keyboard so the form
keyboard got the trackpad now the
trackpad is not so good you see this
keyboard is Bluetooth I showed yesterday
you know you go watch my video very
elegant very well designed and beautiful
but however the track so it you know you
can use it wired right now I'm using it
wired or you can use it uh with
Bluetooth you have two profiles to
connect to two different
devices
okay but the trackpad when you connect
with Bluetooth on Windows it's it's it's
not so good I don't know if it's because
windows I mean I don't know if that's a
general situation
now this is not just a normal trackpad
you see a normal trackpad is just you
know one position uh and uh you can turn
this into a normal trackpad and I
believe it will work well but however
this is what's soall
multi-touch okay multi-touch trackpad
which allows you to do gestures for
example let's say uh s blog
you know I can two finger scroll here do
scroll and I can use three fingers to
see all my windows you see uh for
example click on that or I can show my
desktop uh not that let's see show my
desktop you see and I can use four
fingers to increase the volume up and
down you can see on the left corner I
don't know if you can see it uh let's
see four fingers okay now three fingers
to show my my windows where do I want to
go I want to go uh yeah
OBS so you can see so this is a
multi-touch touchpad like like the ones
on
Apple uh so but it's not so good because
when you connect with
Bluetooth you know sometimes there's a
bit delay I I don't know if it's a
Windows issue or it's just a general
Bluetooth problem also on the
Mac I haven't tried it on the Mac but
you know according to the documentation
by kesis kesis Form
keyboard uh you know the mac Apple
Computers they don't allow other third
party you know trackpad basically so you
so they don't allow gestures so on Apple
they just want you to buy the Apple
Magic trackpad or whatever Apple touch
pad so which is bad news for this
keyboard because if you are using a Mac
then you know then you don't have the
full capability of this trackpad track
you know this multi-touch Precision
trackpad that's what they call
it so anyways so I'm going to use it
this keyboard for a while okay so but
today we are going to code emac LP if
you have questions and comments post it
and pay me okay donate to me uh PayPal
patreon it's ons.info
so the other thing I want to mention is
that I'm going to read the comments in a
in a minute damic hello damic so I
updated my kesis form keyboard you know
right now so it's like you know 10 pages
full detail complete photos let's see if
I can
magnify so you can see this Isis form
keyboard uh you know I have full full uh
detailed review here including marketing
blug you see usually on my keyboard
website you'll see this section
marketing BL that is the part basically
from the manufacturer you know what they
say
themselves about this keyboard which
becomes import you know usually it's not
so good because it's just marketing you
know my you know our keyboard is the
best keyboard because it's the most
comfortable and so on but so usually
it's not useful information well part of
it is useful but part of it is
just fluff okay
however when time passes you know it be
becomes important historical information
for example if you look at you know let
me talk about this uh just random chat a
bit then we're going to go on to emac
this coding okay so for example if you
go to the history page uh you see and uh
then let's say some of the keyboard uh
let's say this one Macintosh portable
now when you look back you know this is
30 years old or 35 years old you want to
see the marketing blub because you want
to see how it was
advertised and you get lots of detailed
information about what's the you know
ports you know the technical name of the
switches and so on at that time so the
marketing
blub let's go back um let's see which
key by the way I have programed my keys
uh via the power toys by the way this
kesis form keyboard is not programmable
anyway so let's go back to marketing BL
so the marketing blur becomes important
information as time passes that is why
uh I started to consistently add the
marketing blub uh typically from
Amazon so anyway so I did unboxing
yesterday so quick start and all the
liting you know superb quality build
truly uh yeah but the you know the
trackpad is got
issues when you connect with Bluetooth
but however when you click uh connect
with the USB it allows you to um also
connect it wired so you you don't need
Bluetooth devices you can just use it as
a USB it works okay you know it you know
it's a multi-touch trackpad I I
especially like this uh three finger
swipe so that's a issue so if you you
know it wouldn't it it's not for me
because I want the ergonomic you know I
want the fancy keyboard I have many
fancy keyboard but if you want a
beautiful keyboard you know it might be
for you okay that's my kind of my
summary of this kesis form keyboard and
it's fairly expensive like the uh
currently $200 yeah fairly
expensive yeah okay that's what I have
to say about this and also it's not
programmable so this is just for average
you know
people so I programmed it of course if
you let me show you guys
uh you know so of course I Pro wait yeah
scroll up yeah you see the touchpad
scroll is
not is
not good good compared to a actual
Square wheel you see now I'm using the
can you see uh you see I'm using the
trackpad I mean the track ball the newa
I reviewed uh few weeks ago last month
so when you you see when you use a mouse
or
trackball the Precision is very good you
know or if you play a game you know but
if you use a trackpad even you know the
multi-touch it's it's sometimes like you
have to do it twice and you know so
that's the issue with the trackpad in
general I don't like trackpad because
trackpad you rub your fingers all the
time and also you have the pronation
problem like today's most Mouse have
some kind of slant so it's more
ergonomic you want your hand this way
because this way is more natural and
then you have the vertical Mouse like
that typical trackpad and mouse is like
that but with the
typical track ball and mouse is like
that vertical Mouse is like that but
with a
trackpad your hand is like that and you
have to you know rub your fingers all
the time so I don't like
trackpad but anyway so that's that's
kind of uh you know my summary of the
kesis form keyboard okay so let's use
track track Bard much uh much more
efficient yeah also the other issue
about trackpad is that you see it's a
generic uh panel which is not good okay
so let me show you article about that
hello guys a bunch of people hello I'll
answer the questions in a minute so for
example by the way there's an
interesting story about Tesla you know
the Cyber truck that alen musk let me
tell you about that so you go to design
okay you go to the design page um
keyboard design and by the way you can
find S
keyboard okay so you can find my blog
there are over 1,000 articles on
keyboard on keyboard history on design
on key switches on uh on all sort of you
know on keypads programmable keypads
which I use for example this uh my a
ultimate hacking
keyboard and so you have you know track
bad trackpad track
B Mouse programming keys or everything
you need to know about how do you
program the keys if your keyboard is not
programmable you can use the windows uh
for example I want to tell you power
toys so for example this kesis form
keyboard is not programmable but but I
have used power toys let me show you so
show key mapping so you can see this is
my key mappings you know so for example
um caps lock is doing Escape right
now and you can remap a key
yourself so power toys is pretty good
though it's getting bloated it's I mean
it's getting bigger and bigger or you
can use Auto key so I have a you know
tutorial and documentation like over
over on my website just search for auto
H key or S keyboard and you will find it
okay so let's close uh so let's try to
use a trackpad so two finger click is
right click okay wait you see two finger
then close this okay it's kind of much
more slower and then yeah so we we
talked about Kinesis form keyboard oh
yeah so there's a thing I want to tell
you about design about these
panels you see the US
Navy they have a accident they you know
their warship run
into run into some commercial ship and
there's a and you know made a big dent
you know and they try to find out why
eventually is because of
the you know graphical touch screen
interface this sucks this sucks donkey
ass you know although you know why does
this happen because technology you know
made the touch screen right so you have
so much you know touch screen sliders
and all and all that and by the way on
Tesla cyber truck you you have no
control it's just except the this giant
display screen everything is touch
screen that is very bad okay so they
discover this touch screen control
system is what caused the uh you see
what the I made a mistake then it
becomes that you know that's a problem
you don't want touch screen you want
physical wheels and knobs okay for
example here is another touch screen
panel this one is Space X touch screen
no
good what you want you know another
picture of the space uh so what you want
is this is no
good yeah let's go back to mous you know
what you want is like this
classic one Bunch 1,000 wheels and knobs
and Sliders okay that's what you
want okay okay this is what you want
because you can feel it you can for
example Mouse wheel I can feel the wheel
or track B I can feel the ball or or a
mouse you know in in a case of mouse I'm
moving you know you want to be able to
feel it that's what your hand is for you
you you notice that touch you know that
classic uh let's see if you can see
me you know there's a classic art you
know but Leonardo or something you know
human touch that two fingers touch
because touch is the most essential
thing any any any new things you want to
touch it you so you can feel it so this
is so you know so this is come back to
the user interface you want physical
wheels and knobs okay you don't want
the the
the code you know the the the generic uh
touch
screen okay that's about that issue
that's about the user interface design
okay
so and uh you know back to the form
keyboard yeah the form keyboard okay
let's shall we start to code emac list
then or is that enough talking about
keyboard uh did I miss
anything uh
yeah okay so let me answer the questions
and say hi and let's h on to EAC this
coding hey I saw your video how is it
going with the keyboard so far is it
weird using a keyboard that is not
completely split okay
so I mean they this is a feature of
their design so that is simple you know
one simple piece elegant you know I I
actually do like one single piece so
because when you have two pieces then
you got cables going around every time
you go you have to you know and then you
have to move you know like like um foot
you know fidget you know like a fidget
spin you have to adjust position so I I
do like the one single piece anyway it's
their design you know you have pros and
cons if you have two piece or if you
allow tting you know pros and con so
this is supposedly according to their
website kesis you know they say it's you
know entry level ergonomic so it does
provide split that's why so they put the
trackpad in the middle so so you have wi
space you know so you don't have like
you know typical keybords like that you
know you have space in between so that's
the you know that's Design By Design
design and I can use to it I mean it's
you know sometimes I use it on my bad
phone now uh you know so it's it's
better than you know the one piece for
sure of course
alternatively uh alternatively for
example let me go
here so this is all the orgon ergonomic
keyboards you know these are the main
ones I talked about so much for example
alternative design is like that instead
of you know a big space in between you
have
angled so the advantage of that is that
you know then your keyboard becomes more
compact this one is fairly wide you know
so your keyboard become more compact you
know but you don't have you don't you
don't have a mouse with
it
so you know and also for example this is
another alternative design right so
yesterday I was looking for uh and here
is the Kinesis form keyboard so
yesterday I was looking for is there a
Bluetooth portable keyboard with a
trackpad and mechanical
keys so it does not you know I don't
seem to find it
Bluetooth
portable and mechanical keys and with a
pointer device so I don't seem to find
it you know this is Bluetooth but
there's no mouse with it this is not
Bluetooth this is wired okay so so in
some sense this is kind of um well
actually I did find that Logitech oh
yeah so let me show
you I did find a device
yesterday this thing Logitech Kasa po
but it's expensive it's
$180 well I mean but this one is $200
the kesis form so there you have it so
you know they come with also multi-touch
trackpad you know so it's I suppose it's
a
competition um yeah so that's one I
found uh but the key switch is oh this
is not I don't think this is mechanic
mechical
switch yeah I don't think that's
mechanical s switch that's the thing
also for
me uh yeah I don't think it's mechanical
switch and also for me I really want
lighter switches so even this one at 50
g uh is not light enough so it's not for
me for long-term use because I have RI
so greetings from Ukraine
wow how's how's going how's going
Ukraine uh yeah staggered okay staggered
I you
know yeah well I mean of course I prefer
grid but staggard is um you can you know
it's not like a big
deal and hello from Iran
wow amazing people from all over the
world Ukraine and Iran sensitive
locations
uh so hello from and hi Francisco hi I
believe you are the guy from
Twitter uh you know like usually I don't
know you guys unless you guys follow me
and frequently comment or join my
Discord you know then you know you talk
every day then I'll know who you
are um greetings from France oh France
right now
uh oh France okay right now is running
Olympics okay so what are your thoughts
on recent ThinkPad keyboard two well I
don't know about it I have to look up
but I think we should start to code emac
this shall we or or yeah I think
because you know if I put a title emac
disp some people come here they
expect emac disp coding they don't want
you know like you know they they are not
necessarily interested in keyboards oh
13 people so anyway let's let's do some
e uh EAC this then you know this diverse
interest some people watch me for
the for comedy
okay a lot of the forchan people they
come here for they come here to see Bas
Bas are talking [ __ ] you know but some
people come to see me for my emac this
expertise you know they want to you know
they are
emac uh fans some people come watch me
for my programming some people come for
uh for my wolam language
you know wolam
language code and functional programming
and programming language
issues uh and and some people uh want
to uh hear my opinions on politics which
by the way I want to mention few days
ago about last week There's a my
observation on El musk and Venezuela
situation you know Venezuela
the USA United States of America our
country is trying to do a coupe they
tried and tried Coupe
meaning oh God sad
meaning they have to do that to quite a
few people quite quite a lot sometimes
you know Riot on the street that means
people
die the you why because
oilo Venezuela has got the biggest oil
in the world more than Saudi AR
Arabia and uh oh my god when I talk
about politics you know the a lot of
people following me because I'm you know
I'm anti the let's say the Democratic
party the you know I'm I'm anti the
social justice Warriors you know they
want to say man can get pregnant they
want to insist
you know putting on 10 pound in the
bathroom in men men's bathroom you know
this kind of
thing so corrupt to a degree that you
know
it's you know very bad they and they are
trying to force it down your throat okay
so that I'm anti this kind of crowd so a
lot of people who follow me are we can
kind of call them right Wingers you know
they include roughly you know like
different people have different
attachment to the meaning of these words
right wing what does it mean you know to
you it means this to that guy it means
other another thing okay but roughly
they include the you know us let's
narrow down to USA because I'm American
okay I don't know other I don't know so
much about UK or other places so in
united in
USA right wing usually includes the
conservatives the
um Republican party supporters
conservatives Republican party
Christians American
Christians uh yeah including these
people and include anti social justice
Warriors and minorly also include
anti-war people which is like
classically the heppes the heppes in the
'90s
like free speech anti Vietnam War you
know anti-war you know love and peace
and and sex you know that's
Hees so a lot of people follow me are
you know the like the right-wing people
right but there's one thing that's very
annoying that's China you know whenever
you know they it comes to China lots of
these people they spread fake news about
China why am I concerned about China
because that was my that's my blood okay
the Chinese blood flows in me or like
many of you the white people blood flows
in you okay so oh then then there's
another issue you know there's another
race in USA which is like running the
town partially okay let's not mention it
uh well I think maybe we should get on
to emac this coding anyway the thing
very annoying annoying me very much is
that I mostly I follow the right-wing
people and more technically I want I I
follow I follow those who actually speak
the truth you know truth is very abused
word like everyone is all politicians
every politician is like we want truth
but but they they want they want
something
else but anyway
so to speak I follow you know those
people who truly speak what is true or
according to their opinion you know in
other words I follow people who have
integrity okay doesn't matter what their
policy is what's their political view uh
or religion or you know used to say
whatever their Creed or religion in USA
so I want to follow real information
truthful in information or honest
opinions okay I don't want for for
example as opposed to bots or agents you
know you pay me you know you pay me
$1,000 I say good things about you or
about the keyboard or you
know so I want to follow truthful
information and uh and the anti-war okay
I don't want this scop thing you know
the the top leaders coup other countries
to get money mostly forsel like they
it's why are they do that you know it's
it's very very very big money you know
like how much how much do I pay you for
you to do this thing for me is it 1,000
will you do it what about
10,000 but over here they are talking
about billions and billions of dollars
you know if you have you if you are rich
enough to buy a mansion now you can buy
10 you can buy a island that's that's
what they talking about so this you know
when it comes to China many of these not
all but many these rightwing people they
are you know oh [ __ ] China they steal
everything you know like they are brain
they don't know
anything okay we must protect Taiwan oh
Jesus okay I maybe I should um you know
today's episode is not going to be
imagist
anymore I [ __ ] it up
okay so this right when people you know
they they follow all the fake news you
see very interesting when it comes to
the social justice War issue they dig
you know they dig
deep um yeah well let me let me talk
about you see I follow these people okay
most of the people I follow are extreme
good truthful news okay Mike Ben that's
he's a top expert on the on the deep
deep State
okay uh Michael sh shellenberger he
is he is basically telling fact factual
in a factual manner okay I don't follow
any memes for example
Pepe uh MAA M you know the P Mar you
know what what whatever the [ __ ] I
despise those okay or based whatever
based [ __ ] scums they are just they are
there for the you know to get you know
massive followers they get money I don't
follow I don't follow any of those okay
I follow people who really post
insightful and uh rare information
usually you don't see you know which
usually means they have to spend a lot
effort to get it like me talking about
keyboard you know you go to t you know
you go to YouTube typical T keyboard you
know they got 1 million followers hi I'm
I'm Franco today I'm gonna sell you this
keyboard oh it's got you know they talk
fast G like the Linux Tech [ __ ] you know
the
lenus get like they are better they they
know better than you like and they use a
bunch of
Jons you follow typical you know they
they don't know anything deeper about
ergonomics about all the design they
don't know but they make a sale you know
their video is edited in 10 minutes you
know nice equipment nice cameras you
know their their cameras is is 10 times
more expensive than whatever [ __ ] I have
okay so you follow them there no
information
you know is is it's just
commercialization or in other words
capitalism USA style you buy things they
get money you know so but anyway back to
politics so I follow people who
really have knowledge about the things
they talk about for example this Glenn
Greenwood is probably the most famous
among them all some of you know I mean
some of you don't hello Chris uh thank
you it's asking me what's my favorite
Chinese character uh I don't I don't
have a favorite Chinese
character what kind of question is that
what's your favorite color what's your
favorite programming language typically
that's those are asked by beginners I
mean by young people what's your
favorite philosophy are you are you Pro
capitalism or are you Pro communism
which one do you think is
better young people are very much into
this kind of thing are you algebraist or
are you a u a a c analysist you know in
mathematics analysis versus algebra are
you into discret or continuous you know
they young people they like to
categorize like are you a generalist are
are you are you want to be a specialist
you know young people like programming
or you know generalist versus specialist
young people tends to um go into those
things including me you know when I was
when I was younger when I was a h shot
even when you are smart anyway so back
to politics so I don't follow you
know mean posters or anything you know I
follow people with real expertise and I
read them carefully for example let's
say for example this guy I check them
carefully just him every day for a while
to know to find out what is his nature
you know for example the Glen Greenwood
he's a f famous journalist you know for
15 for 10 or 15 years the most widely
known
okay so I I check out the guy know his
nature what area is he expert at what
kind of things he typ he say what he his
area okay and what is the style he says
it okay for example green I can tell you
Glen greenw you know he's a journalist
you know he's also he he's typically you
know not the mainstream I mean he's he's
a re classically so-called today real
journalist he
exposed crimes or misdeeds by government
by those very powerful That's a classic
meaning of journalist so Glen green word
is kind of the the representative of
that word journalist journalism
okay uh but okay and and and I can tell
you more about this guy he's got you
know characters you know like many
aspect you can dive into the person is
he a good person bad person in general
or you know or specifically with respect
to what and you know you know for
example he's gay okay he's gay and I'm
not gay
okay if you are gay you are fine but I'm
not
gay okay so he's gay so his mannerism is
kind of gayish you know you know is and
he for example let's on on the lighter
side of the Glen Green World he's often
he's just whines you know although he
exposed a lot of very criminal and
corrupt Deeds of of uh specifically USA
politicians you know he he for 10 years
for over 10 years but every day he's
just like whining about it like what you
going to do I mean that's one of the
thing
anyway so Glen Greenwood is a classic
journalist and a very good one I would
say so every news every day today you
see on the news for example few days ago
you have
Olympics controversy and then today this
week you have the riots in United
Kingdom United
Kingdom you got Riot so every day you
got news and you can check out green
green wood every day to know what's
actually happening you know I'm you know
you don't have to believe him you know
you know it's not like oh everything he
say is true but you can check it out and
usually it's good information you know
at least in my opinion okay so he will
tell you for example Kamala Harris you
know I'm not sure today you know my
video is going to be banned by
Google 17 concurrent view okay no no
emac list today
sorry you know it's it's really getting
very very bad you know they Google can
cancel my YouTube or you know very bad
so for example kamla Harris she's
running for president
today oh my God you you know I I'm not
going to go into details because then
it's going to be endless but anyway so
that's why that's why kamla Harris is on
the news so you hear the news and and on
the right side is this guy we shall not
mention the name okay it's also on the
news in know for the past two years
every day so my point is when you see
the news you want to know what's really
going
on Glen Green World okay you can check
him
out now as opposed to on Twitter you
know you go to on Twitter or you know
today is called X you know or Elam musk
you know another controversial you know
you go to Twitter or any any red or you
know you have this for You tab
algorithmically controlled then it's
just endless [ __ ] endless like you just
squir you know drama drama fighting you
know not just politics for me mostly you
see because I don't follow this meme
[ __ ] but for other people especially for
you young people you see you see Tik
Tock Tik Tock Tik Tok you see tits by
the so-call
influencers white white girls
typically most of them okay most of them
successful are white girls The Tick
Tock kind of type you know today's
zumas what they do basically girl they
just show you TI their tits okay that's
basically you can see it on YouTube you
go to YouTube YouTube shorts have a it
is these white girls doing their
things a little dance or
whatever okay then you see
then so social network today you go you
know it's just wash washes your brain to
the point that you get jaded like you
don't know even what you are seeing like
our hot dog guy we have a guy on our
Discord his name is hot dog
[Laughter]
you you you know you know you are a wimp
you are a n because you don't dare
because you know today's zumas you are
just a narm you are you are online just
to watch [ __ ] show and you memes you
don't care about nothing you don't know
nothing that's what's going
on and why did why did that happen that
because it's conditioned by these big
people behind the scenes you don't know
okay anyway so back to you know
so today online when you go to turn on
your computer you don't follow I never
follow anything that comes to me
free for example this for You tab I
don't I don't I
don't I never go to the For You
tab if I have to I go to the following
these are the people I actually follow I
never
get any information that just popped
popped up for me comes to my door
free okay like when you go to
YouTube you know the scum
YouTube uh let's
see you'll see you know a bunch of
crap uh do I have to to turn on you know
you have to turn on
okay try searching to get started oh
what usually it pops up I don't know why
today it shows a blank page but usually
just pop up a bunch of [ __ ] what that's
interesting wow this is new
today they don't they don't pop up
things like normally they do what
try searching to get started oh this is
actually this is new I'm not sure what's
going on but uh for example you can go
here you know let me show you the
situation youtube.com
Okay and by the way this web design you
see these gray things that's what that's
that's one I have an article on that you
know this started to do this about uh by
now 7 years ago around 2015 or
so uh oh yeah you need to turn on
JavaScript so Google knows what color is
your
panties oh okay this is new this is
something new Google started to do you
know they they just show a
blank anyway so let's not show it so
what I'm saying is that you any social
media when you talk you know do not
follow whatever information that comes
to you free okay only follow whatever
you actively seek okay so find people
for example for example this guy I kind
of know somewhat because I've been
following following him for by now two
years I know his nature what kind of
things he Post in what kind of style
what his what is his background slightly
at least you know you know so that's
what I recommend you follow people don't
just you know like for you whatever you
know scroll by you don't you don't even
know who's posting what you know who's
posting the thing you are
watching instead go to each person you
follow you can start by a few you know
and bookmark with the browser bookmark
not by not by whatever the social
networks you know save page Whatever by
your own browser okay so each day you
read whatever people you follow pretty
soon you'll know the nature of this
person is his
information valid or to what degree okay
is his opinion usually you agree with or
do not you know you don't you know it's
you don't want always to follow f and
things like things you agree emac is the
best thing K is the most beautiful guy
on
Earth mirror mirror on the world who is
the most beautiful man on
Earth it's
Kali oh yes how true that
is oh is somebody else go [ __ ]
yourself you know so you don't want to
always follow whatever L to you okay for
example let me go back to the China if
you are a white guy you are a rightwing
cons conservative or Christian and white
guy white man and then when you see
China China steal everything from
USA you are so happy you know you go you
know you read one after another another
that's no good okay because you know you
don't want to always do that you want to
actually try to see is
something whose opinion that's
unpleasant to your sensories
okay so you can see so that diversifies
your point of view
okay so that's my kind of advice to like
what you do on social networks
okay stop being a a non you know stop
being a non coward and do not mean
posting and random [ __ ] okay you know
random [ __ ] [ __ ] like the Y the Y miles
CH is one big scum grifter
okay uh I don't follow him okay I don't
follow this [ __ ] this scum he's a right
wing you know scum on the right wing
side 1 million followers okay a scum you
know he just post drop you know he just
suppos whatever attract attention and
you know for
example
ridicul kamla Harris every day and
promote you know this guy this another
this is one another one of another
grifter from the right wi side and uh
you know his name is Nick something I
shall not utter it but whatever Yan post
is basically promoting him you know I
don't have to read it I don't you know I
don't
want something like that okay uh so this
you know and he's posting you know
sometimes violent you know bloody Drama
videos and girls there there it comes
girls girls my favorite thing
girls y mil CH scum okay and one big
scum very popular on the right side on
the right side of
things so anyway so I recommend don't
you know blindly follow get a name be a
you know don't be a non-cow and pay okay
don't you know you know not oh free free
is no good pay for example on
Twitter I
paid this is the receipt did you see
that that you see you see that Mar I
that's my receipt I paid for it why do I
pay for it because I believe Adam musk
even though controversial in many ways
you know he's one of the richest people
controversial in many ways but
overall I think him is reasonably good
guy okay now you you might have your
opinion oh El how can you possibly he's
the worse than whatever [ __ ] you don't
know [ __ ] okay Elam musk although
controversial but overall in my judgment
I studied Elam musk the most in the past
three
years I believe he's reasonably you know
a good
person and more more importantly he
happens to be so rich he's
doing good things for America and for
the entire
Earth Adam musk okay that's that is my
opinion so elus run tter and I
decided yes I should pay so that's why I
paid for
it
okay uh and so don't be your
n and don't follow you know [ __ ] posting
you know comedy and joke are fun of
course my I personally don't enjoy
comedy much because I'm a schizoid
personality so when something typically
it's funny to most people I don't find
it funny okay I just don't you know it
doesn't do anything you know it's not
funny to me okay for for things to be
funny usually it's dark humor or more
involved nerd humor I find it funny okay
most things I don't so anyway and follow
people actually know the people okay get
to know the people gradually
and one last thing don't do anything
drastic okay some people who follow me
they you know I'm sometimes persuasive
you know they believe they think I'm
good person or for whatever reasons so I
made some change impact in their life
which is great thank you guys
so but don't do anything drastic okay if
you are right now A non Zuma you are
[ __ ] posting every day like lots of my
followers you
know lots of my followers let's see go
4,000 followers you know many of
them you know they they don't use real
names they they have anime uh pictures a
lot of them okay so you know anime you
know like oh this is verified wait all
these are verified let's see unverified
okay you know then it becomes small you
can see right away the
difference uh well except this guy okay
this is great this and AutoCat uh guy
anyway so my point is that don't do
anything drastic okay listen you know if
you like what I said keep it in mind
change it maybe slowly okay don't do you
know don't don't oh I'm going to you
know something something
um because it
may you know do you no
good okay okay today is kind of started
um talking about politics randomish and
uh when you talk about that lots of
followers much more than my
usual uh because emac lisp and you know
coding programming is Technical and
usually technical your audience shrinks
by tenfold
literally if you talk about sex girls
gender how to get a
girlfriend oh my God everyone want wants
to know your
opinion that's a common characteristics
of humanity okay nothing special about
that okay and I just hope today's video
I don't get banned by Google you know
Google is gonna
strike uh you know very corrupt
situation today so bad today you know
it's really
bad uh in USA and other white man
countries you know the Canada
Australia and United
Kingdom uh they are
basically you know they are basically
following the USA's
politicians big money big
money The Wheel of Fortune you know but
even when you are the most powerful you
know if you are the let's say the evil
Lord the evil evil Lord that's kind of
the white men's concept especially
American the evil
Lord you know either it's a good guy or
the evil Lord you know the like the
Darth Vader
even if you are the most powerful your
power do not last
forever judging by
history okay
so assuming what I say is true that the
USA you know the top leaders some
are uh you know leaders nominal nominal
some are covert they are lead in the
country but you don't know who they are
okay they are very corrupt according you
know according to me in a very critical
condition right
now so you know they are doing all these
kind of things but the power will not
last forever
okay for certain you know uh and let me
just you know the most important I mean
the most serious things going on is the
war things okay that that's where
thousands 10 thousands 100 thousands
people die innocent people like your
mom your dad your
brother you know but they are you know
but they are not your family they are
somewhere
else you cannot possibly feel their
pain you know like I'm coding you know
I'm I'm enjoying my Starbucks and
suddenly
boom my neighbor
died and I lost an arm that's what
happened that's what's going on okay but
it's not your family it's not here so
you don't know you just we just enjoy
YouTube and we enjoy talking about
genders
is it good or bad to have a t ton in
man's bathroom let's have a
debate Hey Jo
Rogan invite me let's have a debate hey
you know the you know the bunch of you
know [ __ ] debate let's go let's go on
TV let's make money Hey cuz I'm GNA
invent who who wants to come to my show
let's have a
debate this the guy Destiny hey Destiny
come on let's debate whether whether men
should have you know whether men is
women are they equal are they
equality you know so you can make money
you'll be more famous and I can make
money I'll be more
famous okay I think that's it for today
uh pretty sad okay so yeah
so final my final say
is stop [ __ ] around find a goal you
know don't [ __ ] around you know don't
waste
time uh you know try to not to be a non-
coward pay for things you
like uh you know follow people don't
don't follow the The Social Network you
know the the the the streams you know
whatever comes through or door
information really follow make friends
you know follow people you really are
interested or may it be programming may
it be politics or maybe whatever you do
you know try to know the people and
determine what what kind of people they
are you know and also including all new
sources you know New York Times CNN
you know try to find try to find out
what's their nature or what whatever you
know News website you know it may be a
new
one you know and uh and meanwhile I'll
do something that benefit you okay I do
not recommend contributing to the open
source
whatever
socialism you know uh code for yourself
okay
okay so I think that's it so let me read
the questions quickly and we shut down
uh it's 1 hour
today he Rich because the B Financial
Market have you tried going to
therapist uh have you think autism is a
hyperborean
trade so do you think autism is a
trade what is hyperborean in the default
state of all Humanity okay hello YouTube
once again did told me that you were
streaming today oh YouTube didn't oh
[ __ ]
okay
so so do you still plan to have kids
like you
mentioned long time back I mentioned
like last month I believe not a long
time back yeah but I don't have I need a
blonde to have kids okay but right now
my situation is my wife is too old and
and uh I have to go through my wife in
order to [ __ ] a blond I really do want
to [ __ ] a blond
because because the right the white
girls oh my God Jesus they are my they
they they are the love of my life okay
the white
girls uh debate a blue hair feminist
that's good hey
Jan okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching and do not forget to
donate to me of course CH Ching CH
[Music]
Ching now I need to talk about this
topic for one
hour you know other people talk about
pay for like five minutes in their
YouTube today's video is sponsored by
you you go to s.in info and scroll all
the way down and you got this
coupon this free
coupon and uh there's a feature with
this coupon you don't have there's no
code okay you just click this Amazon
gift card
me and uh I sanction you that you are a
good man oh Amazon GI card oh $50 that's
good that's
good bye