hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk show today we are going to talk
about randomish I'm going to tell you
what have I been doing in the past week
update uh it's going to be mostly about
wolam language mathematics geometry plan
tiling uh and uh plan curve
so that's one thing and the other thing
is emac Sly Keys uh a new set of keys
for Oak mod so you don't have to press
control meta in Oak mod okay so let me
show you so this is my keyboard kesis
360 and ultimate hacking keyboard they
are
fantastic okay I recommend you go buy it
okay let me show you my keyboard just
search for for SAR keyboard
blog ergonomic keyboards so I recommend
glove 0 kesis
360 and expose
night
and ultimate hacking okay this four I
recommend uh if you you know two two
videos ago I did a video on this
fantastic input device called Spar board
data hand so I highly recommend you
check it out on my page you have video
reviews of all the keyboards I showed
okay so that's about keyboard now let's
get on to emac and wolam language okay
copy that uh let me post the link here
so we know we have a record of what we
talked about so this is this is s talk
show today hello guys Source if you are
here say hi okay uh if you have a
questions ask me me this is the right
time
hello
Infinity hello I love what you are doing
great work thank you thank you guys uh
reminder donate okay uh donate is a
actual good thing
uh you know donate money okay so wolf uh
so so today we're going to talk about
wam language and emac so let's talk
about emac first
because that's more kind of popular uh s
FL Keys is one of the my most popular
package it allows you
to uh use emac without pressing any
control meta or or keys or window keys
so you can go you know just search for
Sly keys there is a dedicated video for
it uh so there's photos there's a
dedicated video video 30 minutes or
talking about Supply
Keys uh so basically it's a key binding
for emac so so you can see so you don't
have to press control C control
something meta so it's all model it's
just like Vim or VI but the key binding
choices you know which command
correspond to which key is designed by
the frequency of the command and ease of
the key so the most frequent commands
the most used have the most easy Keys
it's a model mod Modo key binding system
software Keys okay and on the pink
window you can see all my command Calles
and the key strokes as I type so you can
see on the pink window you can see the
command names and keystroke I'm using
softly keys and vorak keyboard
layout okay so today we yeah so the main
thing I want to say is that I added a
customization section for o mod so you
can just click on Sly Keys
customization and go to uh go to the
bottom uh set up keys for major mod so
go there so I give you instructions on
how do you do it you know in emac you
have the concept of major mod such as
programming
languages diet or the add show
directories or programming languages for
example uh in emac for example here's a
emac code or python JavaScript goand
rust whatever and uh so and one of them
is ogod ogod is uh special mod
for allows you to take notes have
outline
uh outline feature uh so for example uh
there's a lot of dat so let me show you
OGG mod uh for example there's a OG mod
introduction on on my website tutorial
OG mod introduction o mod is a markup
what is ok mod how do you start it uh
orod is a outline feature so you can
have headings subheadings you can hide
the content just show the headings or
you can move the uh section around the
chapters or sections so so or mod and uh
the keys for and uh keys for Oak mod and
the cheat sheet cheat you know Oak mod
is just like
markdown uh and so many others it's a
part of it part of art is a markup
system so you can have you know you type
special characters to have headings and
B italic underline or order list and
Order list and Link images and data time
stamp and code you know so that's
tutorial about oakmark so what what is
it
so so the new thing I did is that uh Sly
Keys customization for orot so you can
see
here here set up or Keys Fork Sly keys
so you just you just copy this entire
thing it contains all keys of Oak mod so
you put this code in your emx in it then
when you use Oak mod you don't have to
press contrl C you know hold on control
something something you know so there
are about I don't know how many how many
commands are there o mod so many o mod
so let's see so have let's have a look
okay pop it out so they are about
commands in OG mod each one has a key so
fairly complex 180 shortcut keyboard
shortcuts so now you don't have to press
control anymore uh you can use
it uh and you can customize it you know
once the code is pretty simple so you
can you I haven't put any effort to
design the key binding such that the
most frequently used ogm mod commands
have the most easy keys that will take
time I I'm not U I'm not much of a ogm
mod
user so but if you do I know a lot of
people do use Oak mod so if you do oak
mod use Oak mod and if you do use Sly
Keys you can you know put this in your
init start to use it and gradually as
you use it you can reorganize you know
adjust the keys so the most frequent o
uh use OT commands have the most easy
Keys okay and if you did that seriously
let me know I'll update the page I was
thinking of putting this on GitHub so we
can H have some kind of collaborative
thing but usually that's not good
because you know the open source
mentality you know once you put out
there then people is like um then you
you became tech support and you became
you know argument with people who got
nothing to do they're going to argue oh
this should be that it should it should
be that or Tex support they ask you
question why is this and you
know uh which you know usually no
benefit to me they don't donate or
anything so anyway so there it is that's
about emac Sly keys for o mod so next
topic let's talk about the wolm uh
language okay so s ke uh show today's
talk show so I want to tell you about
wolam language now before we do that
there's something a bit more about emac
so go to
emac go to blog there's a huge amount of
minor updates I did in the past week so
for example this entire section is about
how to how to
efficiently added emac dis code so for
example you have you you want to turn on
highlight paren you know the how to
information is so here highlight paren
and how and how to automatic insert
closing bracket you know there
intricacies many
details uh and you can also use this
command which is a bit better than the
default than the electric PIR mod and so
insert brackets then you also have
delete bracket by pair so so you always
insert brackets by pair and delete them
by pair that will get rid of the issue
of unmatched parent that's often the
case so my recommendation is that
whenever you code in a programming
language whose syntax is based on nested
structure such as lisp parenthesis or
HTML you know HTML um is also nested
structure syntax so in any of this
language you always want to
insert the tag pairs or parentheses
together in pair okay so they are always
matched and also when you delete them
for example for example showing browser
let's say I want to delete you know this
you know so I just go you see this is a
unordered list so I just put the CER
here press one key that unold the Leist
is G or undo I I can just remove this
single item go to browser refresh you
see and do go to browser so yeah I
recommend you always use matched you
know DD matched Pair by uh together and
some so you know lots of update how how
do you move CER to bracket what's the
most efficient way how do you jump to a
matching bracket the most efficient way
all these
are you know is it's like my 10 years
experience um you know you can you can
buy it or you can not buy it you can use
for example par edit which is a mod I
don't like I despise I think it's
inferior but that's a mod gets a lot
emac Fanatics excited paredit in fact I
have article on why do I not like pedit
and you can compare yourself you know
you know if if you are cafi Keys user
and
you you read these articles you know
almost all of them are part of cly keys
so you can compare yourself you know you
use the clly key system to work on lisp
code then maybe you came from paredit so
you can use a paredit way you know they
usually they have control something uh
you can compare the
efficiency and you can make a judgment
yourself okay so that's uh so besides
these updates uh let's go back to emac
blog so I also there's a lot huge amount
of updates I added the visual uh section
box so you can see each section is now
has a gray box I talked about this in my
last video too um where we wrote the
this iMac this code to add this section
box in real
time uh so lots update uh okay so that's
update about my emac block okay now
let's talk about wfam language in
mathematics
geometry so let me just show you okay so
let's go
to uh let's show you some pretty
Graphics right away okay then we I'm
going to read the comments uh and uh
let's so this is a package this is plain
Tiding fantastic and beautiful
see so this package can do all these
varieties of Tidings okay or random star
patterns and then this PL curve
package uh also beautiful all things
about PL curve mathematics
geometry uh and both of them are now
free on
GitHub so okay so I'm going to talk
about that and but let me read the
comments first you
are Source says you are economic group I
have given up on control key combos
that's great leavon says hello KAS you
do you still have hand pain regularly
not anymore I'm glad to say I'm very
glad oh yeah so so if you go to my
keyboard keyboard blog you know I have
lots of you know um tons of tens of
article you know the the whole keyboard
blog by now there are over 1,000
articles 1,000 over 1,000 articles just
on keyboard alone keyboard mouse RI
ergonomics how should you type what is
the best layout uh you know and what's
the best keyboard what's the best
ergonomic
keyboard uh what's the
best uh tracko or Mouse and what are
some of the weird you know tracko
controller which uh you don't see you
know they are not around uh L best
layout and keyboard
design key and so layout is one thing
you have quality vak and all that then
you have key binding
layout key binding layout design how do
you judge effic efficiency for example
uh Vim has you know HJ KL is it better
or is it worse than i j KL you know you
study all these issues The Gamers have
WD
WD uh and the Vim you know so so lots of
issues about designing of the shortcut
layout so you not just have letter key
layout uh let's see you know these are
letter key layout qu
Bak they are about arrangement of letter
keys on your keyboard which one is most
efficient what what does how how big a
difference does it matter you know lots
of issues but let's talked about so the
letter layout is everyone is talking
about it you know all the programmers
but let's talk about about is the key
binding design in other words it's a
shortcut layout what is for example in
emx you have over 100 uh for example in
emac you have over 100 keys so let me so
how do you so you just say you call the
command describe key chk
okay so you can see oh not this one
uh uh let's see how do I show all the
keys
okay so you type chb uh what is the
command Des describe bindings okay so
you meta X describe bindings okay let's
try dis describe bindings Okay C contrl
HB so you can
see emac
has 1,00 3,00 th000 key bindings by
default you know basically 3,000 so I
have an article that went through the
entire 3,000 key bindings many of them
are repetitions actually anyway so I
have article if you just search for on
my emac on
MyInfo emac section you can search for
it you will find so I went through each
and every of
these keys and commands
and look at what they are you know have
a overview what what they are why why do
you have 3,000 which one is like used or
what you know most people don't know it
um I mean lots of them are kind of
historical too but I would say there are
about 300
commands that's actually used you know
some of them are less used like once a
month you know occasionally but uh about
300 is is is approximately right 200 or
300 keyboard shortcuts in emac that's
used commonly used okay so in Photoshop
you have lots of
keys um in Second Life Second Life is a
virtual world you have like a few
hundred keyboard shortcuts you know so
and in video audio editors you have then
tons of keyboard
shortcuts so keyboard short shortcuts
are important in fact keyboard shortcuts
are one of the primary cause of RSI
repetitive repetitive strain
injury why mostly because you have to
hold control old you know hold something
type something then release that key
then release the modifier that that is
one of the major part of cause of isi
okay that that particular thing not
typing well typing to but but the the
the M the key key code or key
combination that that is a major cost
okay I talked about this many times but
um so yeah so I wanted to say answer
your question about um yeah do I still
have
isi no because you know I pretty happy
about it because um for example there's
article s's typing experience and
repetitive strain injury this is a
record from you know so I started typing
in
1988 uh 35 years ago when I was 17 on a
electric typewriter then 1992 I worked
as a data entry clerk 1994 I learn vorak
layout because I'm a efficiency nerd so
I read about it I love typing for some
reason and or piano so I learned about
vak and to me I'm a very big uh nerd on
design so to me I cannot accept the
quality you know the the inefficient
system that somehow for histo historical
reasons that just um became the common
you know the standard so I started to
learn vorak in
1994 and so far I don't have RI at all
so the first 15 years the first 17 years
of my typing I type every day but I
don't have a problem with with with hand
pain at all although I read about it a
lot you know so so but until uh
2006 2005 I started to have discomfort
and that is because I use a laptop
keyboard at all
times then then I started to have
isi about every two or three years of
different different causes you know isi
is very strange so anyways the last one
let me show you just the last one that's
um this one okay you see I put a salent
pass over here it's uh kind of permanent
damage
okay this one has trouble about me for
like 3 years but not today you know why
that's why I've been telling you guys
get a linear light switch you want the
mechanical keyboard first of all go run
and buy it now
and you want a linear light switch less
than 45 grams of force or even less 35
okay so if you go to my keyboard blog I
I have full detail like more detail than
you wanted to know so you can about it
so this this problem you know this this
right
here in fact I have this BS so that I
they function as a hammer to to
uh to massage my arm so this this
problem bugged me for 3 years but not
today linear light switch okay that's
important so I'm very glad that issue is
over but but there's lingering you know
issues because once you have RSI usually
it's kind of permanent I
mean it's kind of permanent I mean it's
it's it's it's not as good as new even
if you um recovered from
it so for you young people you know you
might say you might think oh I am not
going to have a problem well I just use
normal keyboard you know maybe they have
a problem you know I heard this this
that guy has a problem but I'm not going
to have a
problem you know you are wrong because
for the first 15
years I don't have a problem at all and
on emac I started to use emac in
1998 so for the first six years I use
emac I use a
default I don't I don't rebind keys or
you need you know fiddling didling with
it no just default and and I use
terminal okay I use emac in terminal for
the first six
years let's
see uh Emax okay so uh no windows system
you see this is emac in terminal
fantastic and uh flag key work it what
fatal error occurred
what there's a bug fatal error
C no why is that oh this is new let's
try again emac no windows
system okay go
to my
blog
huh there's something odd I'm not sure
what's going on fatal errow
so h that's interesting anyway first six
years I use emac in terminal only and I
use um you know no no no special key
binding just just uh the default emac
with vorak
though so anyway that answers your
question uh so several other questions
okay I wanted to start to talk about wam
language okay so let me quickly answer
some of the question
hey when when you going to show us more
about s board okay swab
board uh I'm in love with it okay I'm
you know but I can but so I will show it
for for certain but I'm kind of slow so
there's a lot to explore with SW board
so maybe in two or three 3 weeks okay
I'll do a video I will continue to do
probably regularly do videos and and
maybe after 3 month I'll be using it you
know as my main but there's a tremendous
amount of things to do with this device
okay is the kesis 36 360 back
lit so kesis 360 there are two versions
okay
so
um go to keyboard block kesis 360 there
are two versions one is wired USB the
other version is kesis 360 pro that
version is wireless Bluetooth okay and
that version has back lid okay but not
the pro I mean not the USB version but
actually I recommend the USB
version
uh backlit is not that useful okay backl
backlit is like
useless you know the colors on the
keyboard that's like 99% useless it's
created you know it's it's promoted by
The Gamers team know nothing else you
know because color oh shiny usually you
the cheaper the keyboard the more shiny
and so useless however there are some
extremely use for the backl color for
example on this ultimate hacking
keyboard you see they have a different
color the different color indicate
indicates different functionality for
example
this so the red ones you see they are
remap so for example I press one of the
red key uh for example this one is remap
to control W so it closes the current
tab okay uh let me show you VI I press
that close the current tab I want to
reopen it I press this one which is
control shift T okay you see close it
reopen it
previous previous next next next tab you
see so those are the red ones that's key
remap the white colored ones
are uh they are just the normal keys so
for example this one is actually f F1
but why does F1 do that that's because I
have power
toys
so I have a power toys that remaps F1 to
do okay here's a little bit complexity
but let me tell you the story The the
art of key binding and why do I why why
is it so complex
so this key on the ultimate hacking
keyboard is programmed to be F1 so first
of all let me show you
that ultimate hacking keyboard the best
programmable keypad software okay so you
can
see uh you see there you can see
F1 now when I press F1 it toggles the
window size so if the window is not
Maxim imiz it call maximize window if
the window is maximized it
calls normalized you know window
okay you know the Ed edotic Windows 11
Windows 10 don't have a Target Windows
size instead you have for example
old old space so you can see you have
minimized and maximize but you don't
have tarle so you so so maximize is
windows up Arrow uh let me try that
again Windows is you see but there's no
tarle so if you want to restore you have
window press window and down
arrow so each time you have to know what
state you are in then press choose the
right key so it's idiotic you want a
single key that toggles you see like I
do now so what so I have this
um power toys so let me show you power
toys is a tool for Microsoft keyboard
manager so you can see uh where is it
keyboard manager
uh let me show
you okay so it's not in power toys you
bit a bit complex so but I have this
Auto hard
key so I have to show you
um
okay there is a auto hard key script
called tarle maximize window so this
script we'll get the current state of
the window then determine whether to
maximize or restore you see and it's
mapped to F1 you see so that's why I
have
this
uh so what's what was the question and
uh yeah so I was explain explaining the
key coloring okay so that's this
key uh then so let's see what
else okay that's about that uh for
example I have a article on that so you
go to keyboard showing block and search
for color so there's a recent article
keyboard light light color by functional
category open it so you can see I
explain this this situation you have
blue you have green so green are
standard modifiers for example so this
is the case
when they actually make the color of the
keys
useful okay but for most scammer they
are idiot oh CH Ching thank you Max Max
darling thank you let's let's answer Max
question I've been a fan uh in past two
years and finally switched to emac and
having a lot fun writing emac Le thank
you your site and streams have been
invaluable thank
you
cool yeah okay so let's see next next uh
back light how to touch
type Cano touchpad give you RI yes very
much so so isi came from many different
diverse caes and different people have
different you know issue some people are
posture some people are the habit of you
know ways of typing
um and also very much dependent on what
exact keyboard you have because the the
keyboard they dictate kind of dictate
how you press them you you develop
certain habits so you know again I have
like so much articles written about
it so you can just search you know I can
I can actually find find and show you
but you know then we the talk show is
going to be
endless so so but yeah so one thing I
want to say yeah so for some people it's
a mouse okay some some people it's the
mouse hand you know
they and how do you deal with that
there's article for that okay so uh for
example uh best mouse for programmers
how to avoid how to avoid Mouse hand
pain you know some people it's mous
severe so you can you know for example
you can try your left hand you know or
put two MTH you know so you use either
hand alternatively or you can buy a
trackpad or track ball or you can
use now I have so many devices you can
buy this pen input which is fantastic
but it's but the problem with the pen is
that every time you want to use it you
have to pick up the pen and
uh anyway so there are so
many issues and there are many solutions
for example one of the best solution for
Mouse is that I don't click you know I
almost never click so if I want to
switch window what do I do do I control
T Tab and uh and look oh I want this one
oh mistake shift press shift hold it
down oh idiot okay that's the
idiot so if I want to switch to previous
window just that okay but mostly here
you turn on Hoover click or sometimes
they call um Trail okay this feature is
available on Windows on Mac and on Linux
I have articles on for each one of them
how to do it okay just search for S you
know hover click okay for example I want
to switch window so you know I move my
mouse there can you see my
mouse uh uh no let's show the mouse but
then you cannot see my windows okay
uh okay and let's try this okay there is
my mouse so I move the mouse here no
click so let's put my hand here so you
see I showed this many times in my past
video so this is how I switch
Windows incredible you don't click
anymore no click you know
uh but on Windows they don't
have they don't have actually Hoover
click they they have Hoover to switch
window but they don't have Hoover click
so if you want to select this you still
have to
click but but this this thing already
saved you like 50% of the keyboard click
and besides let me show you another
thing you
know when we talk about keyboard I'm
going to be endless okay for example so
a key here now you cannot see it
uh you see this is the my left part of
the automate hacking
keyboard so I can so this this key is
mouse click okay now let's switch back
can you see yeah you cannot
see this key okay so I for example I
click you see let's see I move the mouse
here okay then click you see so all
these are ways to
reduce the possibility of hand pen with
the mouse and you can also try a track
ball uh keypad keypad is fantastic uh
you know keypad saves you a lot
shortcuts you can um and then for the
mouse I have the spin whe you see I can
just spin it um for example I go here I
go here then I just spring it my hands
are here see fantastic especially if you
browse Twitter and
stuff so so anyway what are we talking
about yeah ways to avoid Mouse problems
a lot of people have Mouse problems so
you can get a mouse mouse
recommendations lots of Articles these
three I recommend okay uh
well depending on the person so if you
really have mou Mouse pen you can also
get vertical mouse that helps uh you
know they come in many
forms and then track ball yes of course
track B is also great uh anyway so lots
of uh
details so let's see
next okay now let's let's talk about
wolam language for 15 minutes and that's
it for today okay it's almost it's 1
hour
today uh wolam language yeah so let me
just quickly so tell you about wolam
language so I wrote this package around
so this plane curves I I wrote around
1990 4 1993
actually uh that got me a job at wol F
research so so in the past month I've
been updating the code you know 30 years
of language changes and so on
so fantastic so now it's up you can
download it on GitHub okay so let's go
to GitHub it's actually
here so you can see get my S GitHub PL
curve
plot you know it's free there
okay so GitHub uh so let me just show
you some
pictures tangent so you can plot tangent
so this is useful if you are a college
students or high school and you are
interested in mathematics or if you want
to be a mathematician or if you are a
programmer but you have some you know
you always you don't know much about
math you want to pick up so plank curves
there's tremendous does
um very much a lot of interesting things
so so this package does illustration
that makes visualization of plank cve
properties it makes theorems or concepts
easy to understand by a glance you can
understand oh that's what it means okay
so for
example for example tangent you know
what is a tangent that's this line you
know this that's that's this line at
that point this line is a tangent to the
sign curve and also this line this line
you know that's a concept of tangent and
what is this one beautiful but but what
is it okay this is called normals so
what is a normal to a point on a curve
it's it's like tangent but
except so a
normal line to a to a point on the Curve
is the line that's perpendicular to the
tangent and also passing this point so
the tangent line would be like that over
here so straight so for this I mean the
normal line okay so for this tangent
line the normal would be there so it's a
perpendicular line to the to the tangent
okay so and in this you can see we have
a parabola and you have all the normals
strong so it forms this so when you draw
all the normal lines on this Parabola
you see it forms this this thing and
that thing that curve is called
um cisoid okay very interesting so
Parabola you draw the normals and and
and it forms this shape okay in math in
math jargon that's called the envelope
of the lines okay or in
other another jogon is that you say the
envelope of the pencils of the normals
pencil you know pencil like you know
like the word pencil but in math it has
a special meaning in um in projective
geometry and in differential geometry so
basically it's a concept you know so
many of these normal lines forms kind of
the shape that's called the envelope of
these lines so this so the envelope of
these lines is this curve this this
curve is called
cisoid and itself has many properties
you know it was used 2,000 years ago by
the Greeks to solve one of
the tri-section of the angle problem
anyway that's another big topic so in
this picture for example you see the all
the normal lines to a
asteroid okay so there's so many so many
endless so you know here you see the
normals the envelope of normals of a
elisp okay and here you see SEC secant
lines okay and secant lines they form
they can they are very useful to show
what's called uh string art so this is a
example of string art which is
uh cultural art form in I don't know
Europe basically you you know you you
you you you you take a wooden wooden
board you draw some curves on it
you Pike Nails into it then you wrap
strings around it it forms these uh
beautiful pictures okay and this one for
example is
costic so this is a uh this is a
parabola Parabola curve has a special
property Optical property that is if you
have a point specific point on the plane
there and you shine a light suppose
that's a light
source then it will reflect of the curve
to form to form lines in One Direction
so this is the principle
of car headlight or parabolic dishes you
know radial you know dishes you know
that's a principle Parabola okay the
optical property called this called
cosics
okay and and so many more okay so for
example this one is the exponential
curve and the CeX of the exponential
curve you get this curve which is a
catenary okay you see the envelope of
this forms a catenary what is a catenary
cat
is um Let me let me let me talk about
this you know about St Louis
Ark there it is Gateway To Heaven oh no
Gateway Arch okay so this is a giant
huge Ark Arch in St Louis USA that's a c
catary so what's special about it well
let's um so let's go
back uh press press press press yeah so
so you see that's a c catenary but
inverted upside down so what's special
about catary kinary catary is the curve
when if you have a chain you hand the
chain around two
points am I still doing good you hand
the chain around two points uh let's see
yeah good so you you hand the chain
around two points the chain will form a
curve that's not Parabola okay that is
catenary that's this
one you see so many properties so you
see a exponential curve is this one
that's e ra to X okay e is the you know
the the the natural base of logarithm
that that's another interesting topic so
all this is part of
calculus uh you know interesting very
interesting things you don't usually see
in a calculus course so you have a
exponential curve now what is special
about exponential curve well it is the
function whose derivative is
itself amazing is that amazing that's
this blue curve okay now if you shine a
light from Top then they reflect they
will form a
catenary which is a curve where if if
you have a chain or necklace or or
string you hang it that shape is
catenary okay not Parabola you see they
looks like Parabola but you know it's
actually different so C catary okay so
so many you know and this one is Optical
property of elisp so you have for
example you have a bilard table you know
American game uh bilad or snooker
Snookers but you have you you you
sometimes you know so bilad you know the
interesting thing about the bilad game
is that you bounce the ball off the
table right so you have to like think
about how it's going to bounce and where
it's going to go and one of the
interesting video table shape is
elliptical like this in fact someone has
build it so let me show
you uh you know all these are like old
math topic you know like recreational
um so if you are into math you probably
have heard of it but if you are not here
is a interesting thing uh there's uh you
know there's even YouTube for example
you know they build this special table
um so why is it this uh for example
let's see can you
uh so why is this interesting because on
if you have a pool table shaped like
that
they the
reflection if if one of the ball is on
the focus on a specific point it will
always go to the other specific point
that's called the focus of the elisp
okay so anyway then you have light
refraction properties on a hyperbola
okay light refraction then you have this
this thing this thing you will see in a
cup okay so did you guys drink coffee
yet so you you drink coffee good morning
and uh
then you put it under sunlight
you'll see that shape can we see it
actually uh let's show it
here can you see it no not
really uh okay so anyway so you go out
you'll see
it uh so actually you know I have I have
taken photos of that so this this is um
you can find
special dictionary
of uh wait dictionary of special plane
curves okay that's my website that's my
earliest project so this website
explains all these
things uh so we want to go to cosics and
uh cardid okay so which is here here
here there it is okay go to cardid this
curve is called
cardioid why why is it called cardioid
what is what does it mean cardid cardid
means the heart heart- shaped
okay so it's invented by
1674 by studied by this guy oay Ro and
blah blah blah and you can generate this
curve by Rolling a curve on another
rolling a circle on
another uh you know so many in special
interesting properties okay uh but right
now we are focused on this one which is
uh I have a photo of it somewhere what
where is my
photo actual photo I
mean uh wait maybe
here there it is okay so you can see a
cup you know with that
shape okay so I think maybe that's it
for today I've been talking you know
this I can I mean this is so long um so
anyway this package is now available on
GitHub free now the other package I
wrote In
this one in
1998 this one is more ambitious this one
is more
complex um then my plan curves so this
one allows you to draw any periodic
patterns in the plane okay so for
example you can design Islamic patterns
okay uh it generates all
possible symmetric period tiing uh all
the possible wallpaper patterns okay so
this package is also now available on
GitHub you can
download so that's you know I worked in
past past month to update this code 30
years very interesting 30 years code so
you let's show the code okay uh let me
show you some of the code for example
plan Tiding okay go to plan Tiding uh uh
so for example this yeah let's show um
you know so let's show for example let's
show you
some you know start wfam
language load the package in fact select
all run name all so this this page this
file is testing the functions that
generates a lce okay lce is kind kind of
a regular grid pattern okay so you have
square
lce uh you know lots of math formulas
and in fact you can make
it you know you can make it type
set you know so test the rotation uh
let's eval let's run it for example you
can rotate the lce you
can and let's make this type set you see
fantastic and one of the great thing
about wam language you see automatic
smart formatting unlike the python the
JavaScript the typescript the goand the
C and the C++ idiot they say oh you have
to format your code you know you you
need a tab here uh how many tab tab
versus Space uh oh configuration emac in
it emac in it I need to conict my tabs
is idiots okay and coding conven
convention style guide
blah this feature in wolam language
Automatic Auto formatting in real time
and not just code okay so you can Auto
format code too for example here you see
ijust you see smartly you know they show
there's no indent here but however they
indent it's like it's rendering just
like HTML browser it renders a given
text
smartly without you actually insert any
tab or any return okay so you
see but wam language has this feature
starting in
1998 okay wolam language Mathematica
version three
1998 and then not just not just you know
plain asky code but you can it will
format this complicated type set code
now observe carefully for example let's
look at this this this part okay obser
observe carefully where does it insert a
indent or return you see it's
smart you see you see this for example
let's look at this unit syntactical unit
you see it cut them in appropriate
places you see now this features is back
in
1998 okay so you know I'm a wolam
language coder so I know about this I
love it but every time I talk I try to
express these two programmers for
example the Pearl people the lisp people
especially Lis
Jesus you know I try to convey them hey
you can you can you know why why don't
we stop worrying about you know
coding you know coding convention you
know coding style guide the tab versus
Space wait we don't TW we can you know
it's possible to make
this you know I can I I try to tell them
they don't understand they're going to
say you are a troll you are an idiot no
that's idiot you must have oh if lines
are too long it's unreadable
extremes idiot so I I try to talk to you
know convey this idea to these
programmers in par in Python in you know
python is especially idiotic because
they they they they baked the syntax
with indentation into the semantics of
the language okay so I talk to them this
you know they they don't understand they
don't listen then they deny they attack
me you know well I don't say things in
the most polite way so they attack
me uh but you know to this day to this
day but it's getting better because 10
years ago Goan started this go format
which automatically format so you don't
have to manually you know or argue about
formatting style anymore at least it's
automatic one single way of format goand
starting with goand then it spread to
other languages okay so right today you
have that in Python in JavaScript you
know and I have other for each one how
to do it and integration with emac just
search for um for
example s emx format okay I have like
you know you'll probably find so format
code okay so for example format python
code so this is a code in emac disp you
can put to your init so that will allow
you to when you code python emx you
press one single button you'll format
your whole buffer okay you don't have to
manually do each line and you need the
python Auto format code so here's
another tutorial talking
about the auto format
code you know uh software you can
install how to use them you know so then
you have also JavaScript you know I show
you the JavaScript and integration with
emac and Goan uh Goan started go line is
fantastic and there's also a version
with Powershell okay so Auto format back
to wam language you see
this so that's why this is one of the
reason you know wolam language is not
open source you have to
pay uh and yeah okay so let me let me
show you guys so you can download it for
free these days
uh so you you know go to s wam Language
tutorial you can download it for free
you can read about what's the
differences wam engine wam script uh
Mathematica and you know you can
download it for
free at least for non-commercial use for
you know if you just want to play with
it so that's why I say wfam language is
just this
incredible design and and why why is it
so good well because the wolam
the Stephan wolam guy he's you know you
know one of these cocky guy who's got a
vision for the world you know
fundamental theorem you know like the
ultimate theorem for physics and stuff
anyway he's got Vision so he you know he
coded wam language you know 30 something
40 30 in 19
1988 okay so he tightly control you know
he's got Vision like he's got so-called
strong opinions on everything so he want
his system to be just this way and it's
it's very good okay so you got this
autof formatting feature you know it's
just just
incredible so has is there any any other
editor that has this autof formatting
feature now let's forget about this type
set you know maybe you'll say oh that's
special for
mathematics but is there any even a
normal just like asky code that support
this Auto format is there
editor as far as I know I don't think so
can you guys tell me have you guys
seen is that puzzling is it puzzling I
mean you can do this right you know
today we have ai and you know all that
and wolam language did
this 25 years ago okay but why is it in
the industry you know the C C++ the Java
the Microsoft you know the VSS code why
why didn't they do this and it's open
source right it's a great oh oh my God
the greatest programmers open source how
come we don't have
this okay that's
um that's what I want to say you know
there's you know
there's uh some issues in the world
that's you know when you think about it
it's kind of
strange so anyway I'm showing you some
of the examples so this part is
generating luses okay different you know
Lattis is is basically regular points on
a on a plane uh this code uh and then so
for example here's a fancy one it's kind
of uh hexagonal lce but actually they
don't technically this one one is not
called lce lce has a specific meaning in
mathematics this one is more of a vertex
of a regular taging not not a latus but
for it to be a latus in a mathematical
group Theory sense it needs to
be in a plane it needs to be generated
by just two vectors so for example so
that's not a
latus this is a lats okay this is a
triangular lce generated by two
vectors but this is
not but it's kind of regular it's I
think you can call it it's one of
the you can call it uh it's a vertex of
archimedian regular archimedian Tiding I
think that's a technical name but anyway
back then you know I was coding this so
I mean if we were if I'm going to redo
this I would have rename this so I call
this star LS star LS but this actually
technically it's not a LS but anyway the
point is that you have this
regular uh grid coordinates in a plane
then you can map a figure to it it
generates a different Tidings okay am I
getting boring uh let me show you
um W Language tutorial and close that
close that
uh yeah so I want to show you uh some of
the
things test okay so yeah let's open
this okay so this is a documentation you
can get from it's on GitHub so it just
show you uh what this package does okay
I think that's it for today hi I know
you all uh talked about and written a
lot about good fonts but what fonts are
you using currently in emx okay yeah I
talk talked about that a lot so let me
just answer your question
simply uh okay so let me show you this
first so this is what this package do it
does
any it can generate any regular patterns
in the plan for example this one just
generate a random a random
wallpaper okay so random
color uh and uh here's another example
so LS we talked about out and uh okay
that's it so this is uh on GitHub free
okay so get it so you know then you have
start patterns uh let me yeah so let me
show you the St St patterns then I'm
going to quickly tell you about the font
what's the best font okay
so you see so this this uh
generates star
motifs
okay some some example so you map these
to the luses then you generate all sort
of beautiful uh pictures I mean
Tidings okay
so okay that's that so about fonts I
talked about many times uh so the best
way is actually just go to so we go to S
visual CSS
and uh go to the fun section fun
family okay F family that's one of the
CSS properties you have these ways then
common web fonts these are fonts that's
available on Windows and Mac and Windows
and Mac and then the one I want to say
is metrically compatible fonts this is
very important concept so the the
question about which is the best fun
for um for programming I so my
recommendation is that you use the
default on Windows and on the Mac okay
so on Windows the default font for for
for the terminal
is uh consolas okay that's the
best uh in fact so for example uh s.
info let me show you articles about font
S
search font so there's a article so
there are 50 articles containing the
world font just search for the best so
best unit Co code f for programmer
that's a dedicated article to answer
that question okay so and what is my
criteria how do I judge you know what is
your criteria for best F what why do you
claim is you know so I I show them here
uh and so for the font
um you know our Microsoft just use the
default that's the best you know after
all these study after the past 10 years
today you know different year the best
dep changes okay so today if you are on
Windows the best font is just the
Microsoft consoler the buildin the
default okay don't first don't f okay
just use that now if you want to if you
are the type you are a thinker you want
to know why then you can read you know
my tens of
Articles if and if so if you are on Mac
the best font is melow meno okay also
build in just use that no fedo and it's
the best of all criterias on the average
you know that is just score the highest
okay on Linux I would recommend
s mono
okay now if you want to go fancy you
know you you can try some of these you
know Julia mono uh but anyway that's my
recommendation okay that's it for today
thank you guys for
watching let's see how many people are
watching so I think that's it for
today YouTube live stream what is this
okay live 13 people watching 11 okay bye
guys that's any anything else okay it's
already 1 hour so that's it for
today uh close close close CU we shut
down in one minute okay so I'm going to
close my things close close close close
my things and put links to my website to
my talk show page
close Okay so talk show page uh we post
links to what we talked about
here thank
you so math block okay we don't need to
talk about
that uh keyboard block yeah let uh okay
font we talked about let's put font
here uh so font articles so
many uh so here that's very interesting
important concept metrically compatible
fonts okay if you guys into design you
should read it it's the most important
concept it's but it's not popular let me
simply explain this one
okay now on website you see uh let me so
for for example you know so if I go to
my CSS here okay and if I let's say I
want to change my font to serif you you
know okay so font size 18 okay let's
leave it B now now font body let's say
serif okay now go back to browser and
refresh oh they become smaller why
is that did I touch font size no and why
why the my font become smaller all
I want is just serif that's a issue okay
so when you web design you know you
think oh font size let's leave it this I
just want a different font well the
problem is the font actually changes
size the size depends on the
font so what what does so what does font
size exactly mean let's look at let's
look at CSS spec you know I'm a I'm a
expert you know on on web dev I'm a
programmer let's go to
www3 or you know let's look at CSS spec
what is what is a font size why does it
happen it turns
out font size is a fuzzy idea uh back
from you know back from there meaning of
font size back from the B from the metal
type set you know font size is just a
just just a design box okay for example
these two you can see one of them is
bigger M than the other but they have
the exact same fun size why because the
meaning of font size is just the
arbitrary box that the designer of the
font created so it has nothing nothing
whatsoever to do with actual font size
it just a imaginary box so so so this
blue box is the font size okay but the
actual word can be like tiny or
sometimes you can go beyond the the the
font size box okay that's how things are
so the fun size you know it's like it
doesn't mean
nothing so what can you do well you know
so this is one of the issue you know you
look at this CSS gurus design gurus the
idas very popular you know 1 million
followers or what what not Hacker News
or whatnot oh I work at Google you know
I'm a guru design grur I design for
Facebook Facebook I'm Microsoft you know
what the what they call the the
Microsoft what they call it uh metric or
know it's uh what what is the word that
designed Microsoft Windows 10 you know
this pretty white boys on stage telling
you about their design their design
jargons bunch of idiots so you look at
the you look around nobody you very
rarely almost none we talk about will
tell you actually this
issues but you know all these
scurs you know that's that's uh that's a
thing okay that's it for today so let's
change back okay change back and I don't
want to screw
up
bye
but