hello hello hello welcome to another
episode of s talk show hello hello hello
today we are going to code wfam language
fantastic Advent of code 2023 day
12 uh hello guys so this is glove 80
keyboard fantastic ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic nulia track boo
fantastic Logitech 502 I think
fantastic and uh this is SW board SV a l
b o a r d superb I'm going to use it but
not yet okay uh you search on my website
search for S keyboard blog you'll see
reviews of all of them and video reviews
okay and now let's just code Advent of
code wam language concentrate we need to
concentrate uh Advent code day 12 okay I
haven't read the problem yet uh so let's
get prepared
uh do we have everything if you are here
say hi if you are watching offline uh
feel free to skip
around and uh let me introduce you wolam
language okay now you can get it free
just search forar wolam Language
tutorial uh wolam script download there
is uh how you where you download it okay
let's copy it close it uh weop it copy
the path and on the pink window is all
my command code and keyboard Strokes as
you see I you know I work on my website
you can
see the other command names on the right
side and key strokes on the left side
I'm using aora keyboard layout and I'm
using Karly Keys Kar fly Keys search it
you'll find it the most efficient key
binding system for emac if you are using
emac and emac is the most powerful uh
text editor if you are a programmer you
won't go wrong you know it's a long-term
investment for 10 years for your Prof
profession for your livelihood if you
are a programmer or if you are anything
technical doing uh dealing with
computers so if you are watching here uh
say hi hello Dam
dam hello Dan hello yes thank you hello
d uh just started using soft like is
fantastic okay so let's begin wolam
language code okay wolam Language
tutorial you you can and learn the whole
language download it and uh free and use
the whole Lang uh learn the whole
language from the ground up so you
there's not uh you know if you know one
programming language such as python
JavaScript or even cc++
Java then this is good for you because
then you know you know already know
what's a variable what's a function
what's a loop then you don't you know I
don't tell you what's a variable so but
otherwise there's no prerequisite so you
can learn from the ground up and why wam
language because is the most advanced bi
a magnitude than all existing industrial
languages including you know cc++ Java
that's we already know so lisp
closure scheme Lis common lisp no
comparison to from language uh uh you
have Julia you have mat lab you have
hascal you have OK camo you have F no
comparison no comparison at all like
there's a big gap That's The Power of
wolam language but of course there's a
flaws that's because wolfen language is
not uh designed for industrial kind of
programming for example if you are
program if you are going to write an
operating system you don't use Ram
language if you're are going to write a
um uh uh networking protocol
implementation tcpi
you don't use wam language if you're
going to write a microprocessor you know
some some kind of know you know uh
drivers you know video Mouse drivers
keyboard drivers you don't use wam
language okay but it's the most advanced
um if you are doing mathematics if you
are physicist if you are engineer you
know you have to design rocket rocket
for example Tesla or design the Tesla
you know or uh uh uh artificial
intelligence in intelligence machine
learning you want to explore all the
possibilities you know one single line
of wufan language is equal to 100 lines
of python okay things like that so wfam
language okay the most powerful
especially of course it is known for
doing mathematics calculus linear
algebra integration derivatives you know
but that's that's well no that's you
know but I'm not doing it I'm not using
it I do use it for math but I'm not but
my tutorial is mostly not for that okay
it's for uh for just just like a python
or Java okay string regular expression
number
arithmetics uh you know uh true false
spoling this you know so that's my
tutorial
so uh if you like it donate to me okay
so let's begin uh let's start to uh
begin the uh Venom code let's just code
it quickly I heard that from Steve from
s Discord Steve has done lots of these
problems he told me uh day2 is kind of
hard or tedious okay so let's let me try
to do it quickly so you finally reach
the hot springs State 12 okay you can
see Steam rising from secluded areas
attached to the primary something as you
turn okay so let me uh move this here so
you can
see so as you turn to enter the
researcher stops you wait I thought you
were looking for something something oh
sorry something something you look in
the direction the researcher is
something pointing something something
idiotic verbos
verbosity you know I've seen Advent
people finish the problem in 10
seconds before before I can read one
paragraph they already finished in 10 10
seconds or 20 something you know if you
search YouTube you'll find some of those
people you know those are so-called
speed coders okay there's speed coding
competition but it's not a useful it's
not a um it's not a uh it's not really a
valuable skill you know in real life or
in history the greatest coders
mathematicians they are not known none
of them known for like I can do it f
fastest speed coding you know it's not
valuable just like speed typing you know
this it's no it's not a valuable thing
anyway anyway so there's just one
problem many of the Springs have fallen
into dispair this this dis repair so
they are not actually sure which Springs
would be safe to use okay wor yet their
condition
records which Springs are damaged your
personal input okay condition records of
which Springs are
damaged that's your personal input are
also damaged okay you'll need to help
them repair the damag record okay so
this starting of the problem in this
giant field just outside the Springs are
arranged into rows for each row the
condition records show every spring and
whether it is
operational by a DOT or damaged by a
pound sign okay this is uh you know so
here is the input that's what Advent Cod
like to
do so a DOT is operational pound sign is
damaged okay so this is a part of the
condition records that is it s damaged
for some Springs it is simply unnown
question mark okay whether the spring is
operation or damage okay so I guess here
is the toy person input let's just copy
it
now okay we want to try to do this uh
quickly okay yeah
so uh code
uh Toy
input okay so you got a operational is
dot damage is P sign and unknown is
question mark now I don't see a question
mark here uh but anyway so however the
engineer that produced the condition
records also duplicate duplicated some
of the some of these information in a
different format after the list of
springs for a given Row the the size of
each continuous group of damaged Springs
is listed in the order those groups
appear in the
row for a given Row the size of each
continuous group of damaged
Springs is listed in the order those
groups are those groups appear in the
row what does that mean this list always
counts for every d Dage spring and each
number is the is the entire size of its
continuous group oh okay I kind of uh I
think so that is the groups groups are
always separated by at least one
operational spring okay so pound pound
pound Pound would always be four never 2
two okay so contiguous contigous
something so condition records with no
unknown spring conditional conditions
might look like this so this is one
example input
so pound pound and three pound so that's
113 then then you got one pound one
pound and three of you know of their
grouping here is 13 1 six 13 1 six okay
checks out however the condition records
are partially damaged some of the
strings conditions are actually unnown
for example
so oh okay so you got this so 113 is
still there but you you just don't know
what's the question marks okay so second
row
113 okay so second row
113 uh 113 okay third row 1316 oh okay
so you got like this kind of thing 131
six okay okay I kind of get the idea got
the idea equipped with this information
this is your job it is your job to
figure out how many different
Arrangements of operational and broken
Springs fit the given criteria in each
row so in each
row on the right side they give a list
of
numbers on the left side you have this
question Mark and Dot and P
sign uh basically I think you need to
figure out what is this question mark p
sign do
configuration by removing those question
mark So for each question mark you want
to replace it by a DOT or a pound sign I
think okay so in the first line question
uh you know question mark 31 okay so
let's hi so I can show you so there
uh there ex there is exactly one way
separate groups of one one3 Broken
Springs okay in that order 113 okay can
appear in the in that Row the first
three unknown Springs must be
broken the first three unknown Springs
must be broken then
operational then broken okay pound.
pound okay making the whole row pound
dot pound dot pound pound Pound okay
let's double check yeah so given 113 and
given this string I mean this string
this there's only the one way to replace
the question
mark So such that it fits this you know
this description okay that's a condition
so so let's start with think about this
problem so given a line you split it
into two parts the right part is the
numbers the left part is a bunch of you
know dot or question mark or pound sign
and basically for each question mark you
want to replace it by either a DOT or a
pound
sign and the criteria is that is that so
that in the
end the in the end if you split this
string
scen by a DOT
then the count of the pound sign will be
these numbers the the sequence of
numbers you get okay so that that's kind
of the algorithm so this given this
string you want to replace all question
marks by a DOT or P side such that in
the end if you split the string by
dot then you count you know the group of
pound signs they should be you know the
these sequence of numbers
okay okay so that seems to be okay the
so it continues to explain so let's see
the explanation the second line is more
interesting uh so here uh question that
that that could be total of of four
different Arrangements
okay one two three what uh could be a
total of four different Arrangements
last question mark must always be broken
to satisfy the final continuous group of
three broken groups uh string uh yeah
whatever and each question mark question
mark must hide exactly one of the two
broken strings okay nether question mark
question mark could be both broken
Springs or they would form a single con
contiguous group of
two nether of the question mark question
mark could be both Broken Springs okay
uh broken means a DOT okay so
yeah if that were true the numbers
afterward would be 2 three instead yeah
yeah since each question mark question
mark can be either uh yeah p sign dot
dot P sign there are four possible
arrangement of the strings
okay so basically what is saying is that
the last sentence is saying that there
is no sometimes there may not be a
unique solution okay on which question
mark you replace
with the solution may not be unique okay
now the last line is actually consistent
with 10 different Arrangements okay
because the first number is three so
what is the last one okay 3 2 one okay
all question
mark so there's you have lots of
possibilities do dot dot whatever okay
so it's saying that all these are
solutions to this line
okay yeah so you have you know many
possible let's say 3 2 1 yeah so there
are many possibilities okay okay got it
in this example the number of possible
arrangements for each row is oh you want
to know the possible Arrangements you
idiot okay so basically you want to
count the possible solutions okay so the
first line is one the second line is
four possible solutions the third one is
one then 1 4 10
okay adding all these possible
Arrangements count together produces a
total of 21 arrangements for each row
count all of the different Arrangements
of operational and broken Springs that
meet the given criteria what is the sum
of those counts okay I got the problem
let's get my personal input copy it copy
it and
uh and new file save it XX today's state
aoc2
- one let's just say temp temp file so
this is my file 1,000 lines 1,000 lines
okay let's uh scan it quickly okay yeah
so you see so the first problem for each
line you want to split them by a space
is that
right yes now I don't remember the
problem says that maybe because maybe I
skipped anyway so you split it by a bace
so you get two parts the string part and
the number sequence part okay then you
just
um uh you know start to find the
possible solutions okay so so very very
simple okay uh W language got a lot
functions that do combinatorics so maybe
it's just one single line to solve the
gist the problem in fact the whole
problem is just one single line okay no
more than 120 characters I'll tell
you so this is the input so let let's
make it you know so we got the input
there uh so this
solution solution for this to problem
close that is uh what is this 21 okay
let's copy
that uh solution for toy problem is
okay let's just um W
okay
what text okay code
okay there we have it okay so let's
start a wolam language and begin to
code okay we got uh I'm using San mod
for example
table xx1 29 run
it uh it takes a while to start up the W
so there is a result one two three four
okay
so um okay let me show
you so there is a codei mod You Can Get
It Free open here's a source code about
3,000 lines but most of it is the is the
wolam language keywords you know wolam
Language by default when you open the
box there are 7,000 functions build in
you don't have to load libraries you
don't have to load any Library unlike
typical programming languages oh you if
you want to use regular expression you
you need to load you know rejects if you
want to uh manipulate files you have to
load the system IO or something okay
nothing like that 7,000 functions so
building and function is all you do okay
just functions because it's a functional
programming language okay so here is the
my website for Wam mod so it allows you
to code wam language in emac okay
so uh open that file copy the file path
close close close Okay and uh put this
back and let's put a
link
okay there it is
okay so now we can let's start wam
language Also let's start the notepad I
mean the notebook format oh where's my
drink let me get my
drink okay we already spent something
like 20 minutes cheers uh this is orange
juice
start
table
x five let's just say five of them shift
enter to run it okay now let me magnify
this and put this up
here okay so that is our today's you
know so we start to code it okay
uh okay so hold on a second so I need
the inputs I I need the toy
input
uh okay here's a to
uh input equals to A String there it is
uh
so let's pass the input okay well uh
string
split spring split input let's try to
code this
quickly if you do that then uh by
default it's split by y space so
including the new line and also includes
the space which is not what uh actually
we can use that yeah let's just do that
uh what is this x
input string or list of strings is
expected
what string split string string or list
of strings expected at position one so
yeah that's oh yeah so I need to Evol
the whole buffer not just the single
line evolve the whole
buffer there it is so uh once you do
that so you all you have to do is
partition
now so you know basically here we got a
list of things so it's a string sequence
of numbers string sequence of numbers
the sequence of numbers is also a string
okay so let me show you this partition
uh partition we will just group them
into um let's say uh let's let's say
two
uh okay uh I want to code this quickly
so let's not worry about you know all
the I just so let me just show you the
easiest way so I can also uh so you guys
also understand what I'm doing so okay
so so
uh result so partition you want to go
group them by two
okay then uh then let's just say let me
just do this quickly actually if I do
that you don't know what I'm doing so uh
equals to transpose
uh transpose okay transpose X result
by uh uh just transpose okay
so so once you transpose you got um
should you transpose no uh let's say
see uh so
partition so you so here the result is a
list each element is again a list and
the first part is the string the second
part is a sequence numbers of numbers in
string form
okay uh
then then you want to turn this string
into actual um uh into into actual
numbers so you know for example turn
this 321 as a string into actual numbers
you can do split again
um okay uh I'm going to code quickly
okay so so map let's just do map
function and write it in a way so you
guys understand so the second um um so X
is the input you map to each uh element
in the list and you want the second
part okay so that's the second part and
you
want split string uh not sply knots okay
it's some f fancy mathematic mathematics
m not Theory so you want string split
okay uh you want to string split this
thing by a comma okay then you want to
turn it into a number okay actually this
is inefficient but let's press on two
expression so two expression will
turn uh so what uh so what uh so let's
see so
so here you got the
list each element is a single number in
string form okay then
[Music]
you yeah then okay so you map so you map
two
string
uh two expression which
turns string two number to each of these
this element okay so you can see
I don't know if you guys find it
understandable so uh we don't care about
the so so what do you want to map this
to so you want to map to uh X result
which is a result above
this okay
so so I think uh that so that you can I
can we can show the result okay so print
H okay so if we run the whole thing
you'll run okay let's let me let's show
it okay so we got uh What uh why is it
saying
print oh yeah we on what uh oh yeah
capital okay so let's run
again so there it is so the result let's
let me show you so the result is like
that okay we got we got a
um and here what is this part
so uh let's see what exactly is
that we you see the second part the
second element should be is a
Leist but very now
now I'm not sure it's a list or not so
let's try to run this again let's
see oh yeah it shows no because
um good afternoon hello dong and hello
D1 six pound hello
LC question about your wolfan language
setup if if I
may uh let's see what
uh let's magnify this so I can
see in emx are you calling into from
script presumably using your own mod yes
and all the embedded w language engine
uh I'm calling wam script okay
now you know when you wolam script and
wolam engine is free when you download
wolam engine it comes W uh with wolam
script wolam script is like bash it g
basically is a shell like interface to
to to wam language to the wam Engine
Okay so for
example did like just close it okay let
me show you okay
quickly so for example here is shell uh
where do I put it let's see
well okay so wam
script uh uh okay we don't want that you
know let's start wam
script uh let's say
three + 4 and enter you know seven so
this is wolam script when you download
wolam engine free it come with it a
shell interface to the wam language okay
so it doesn't show Graphics or it
doesn't show nice uh
mathematical type set you know type
setting like x squ uh Power Roots you
know it doesn't show that it shows in
asky way but anyway so I I have lots of
video if you watch my YouTube there's
lots of videos introducing demonstrating
wam script okay so anyway wam engine wam
script you can download for free but if
you buy like me actually wolam Lang you
know wolam research they sponsor me so
they you know because I've been coding
wolf language since
19902 93 because anyway so if you have
the wolam Mathematica or whatever
Mathematica or wolam desktop product
then
you the wolam engine is called wolam
kernel okay so basically wam language
you have a font end which which is which
is usually the notebook or the wam
kernel or wam engine which is what
actually does the whole compiling and
computation so wherever I type something
here or in the notebook it sends the
input to the wolam engine the wolam
engine sped out output then the front
end the notebook or the wam script
prints a result okay so your question is
about do I call the wolm script or do I
call the uh you know that's called wolm
kernel IO wolam script okay now the
basically they are like exactly the same
thing but I mean the the technical
difference how they what's the
difference between the wolam kernel and
the wolam
engine you download it free
exactly I'm not too clear but it's not
important okay and and it's not they are
basically exactly the same so it's not
like oh if you download free some some
feature are disable there's nothing like
that okay let's get back to this okay
so so let's see the result let's get the
first item then the second item okay
let's just run it
uh uh you have to activate because you
know I need to
quit
the wam script otherwise it doesn't
allow me to run it twice you know
because so anyway run it
again embedded engine where uh via the
dynamic mag Oh you mean you mean the um
you mean yeah the so wam language they
commun Comm unicate the front end and
kernel they communicate via a
protocol which was called
uh math talk but but now they call it
something
uh let's say Wan uh it was called math
talk
okay uh not walk talk I believe it was
called math
talk and no it was it's called um but
anyway the front end the engine and the
front end whatever it is they
communicate via a protocol so I guess
your question is am I using that Pro
Protocol no but I would like to because
then because if you because then you are
always connected just like the wolam
notebook you know you don't have but for
my emac every time I I you know run a
code it starts the wolam engine I mean
the wolam script then the wolam script
talk to the wolam kernel the engine okay
so it's a bit less efficient but it
works for now but yeah so but you know I
have to implement that wolan protocol so
well since I'm talking about this why
don't why don't I
show you uh what is that
uh I'll just search for Wan
protocol okay it's called Uh thing yeah
there it is now it's called wam symbolic
transfer transfer protocol okay that's
how the front end and the back end how
they talk okay and I'm not using that in
my CAA
mod for emac uh but it would be better
to use that but you know I have to look
into so they have language support for
cc++ for rust for Java for net uh and
other languages you know so I haven't
looked into
yet so anyway
so but in in my wam language mod is I'm
just calling it like a sh command so
it's you know it's much simpler anyway
so let's get back to this so I want to
let's run it and's see what's the result
um yeah no so because
uh well if you run this in wolam
language it would be much easier so
let's run it
so you can see the result is that now
what is the so
shift percentage sign means last output
so percent six means the the output
number
six
um so I want to see what is that
uh so is that a
string uh
oh so that's a string so this two
expression this part is
incorrect
function you
map this function so you map this
function to the result and uh and and uh
and uh so first of all you take oh okay
so so you map the function okay
so
uh you split the
string yeah okay so let's
say
X2 then oh you forgot to assign the
result that's
why forgot we forgot to assign the
result here okay let's assign
it that's why so the result three equals
to that okay now result three
evaluated oh yeah okay
print
evaluated uh one okay so one is not
right so the first one and
uh let's just print the result three
okay okay so the result three
is incorrect yeah so yeah I kind of
know yeah so you
need return a list and uh the first part
is H what is this emac shell no uh the
first part is the first part then the
second part is this okay
okay so I don't know if you
um okay so you got you know this this
will work let's just run
it yeah so you see this is what I mean
so this is the desired output
okay like that so
okay let's copy the whole thing go to
the wam language and paste it
there and uh we don't need
print
because whenever you run in some kind of
notebook or
interactive form uh you don't need print
just like python or or shell or any
other language so there we go there you
know here is a desired output okay so we
got a list each element is a list of two
things and the first thing is a string
and the second thing is a sequence of
numbers
okay uh yeah so we wasted a lot of time
like 30 minutes on on this forgot to
forgot to name a variable I mean assign
it so now we have to start to think
about how to solve the
problem uh the about algorithms so let's
see the algorithm
so so you got the
string you you got the string you got
the sequence number so you the question
is you need to F out the question mark
so actually this is not the input the
input is with the question
mark okay so yes so the input is
actually with a question mark okay go
back to so let's fix this here as well
so
there showing browser here is today's
code okay here's a sample input and
here's our code
okay uh so let's go back to
code make a backup
okay so
now and so now so algorithm so what you
going to do with
this you want to replace the question
mark okay so oh okay so let's we have to
run this again because that's the wrong
input shift
enter now it's better okay so
yeah so
now okay now we need to
think h a bit tedious
so so given the Stream So wow wow how
you going to solve
this oh God this is a bit tedious so you
know so you can start to do like
backtracking okay lthm
or you know there's a so you can do
backtracking meaning that
you you just start to replace each
question mark by a DOT okay so you find
the first question mark you replace it
by a
DOT well okay so you find all question
marks then if each question mark can be
either a DOT or a pound sign okay so you
just
systematically try all possibilities so
for example the first line you got three
question mark so it can be dot dot dot
dot dot pound sign
dot pound sign pound sign or pound sign
pound sign pound sign or or dot pound
sign dot you know so you you you
generate the list of all the combinate
combinatorial possibilities then you
just try each one you know so once you
got a possibility you feel the question
mark out then you see then you split the
string
by uh by a DOT to see if you have that
113 group okay this is fairly
inefficient because you know for example
this the 113 it's not possible to have
for or question mark to be dot dot dot
so if you're going to try that you
you're wasting your time you know it's
inefficient but this is the systematic
approach oh in fact oh yeah the in fact
the
question is asking
for the count of all
possibilities so you do need to actually
know all the possible solutions okay
that's
interesting so you do actually need to
know all the possible solutions and
because you want account of
it yeah so the problem is not just find
one solution you do need to know find
okay
so you need to find all the possible
solutions so what what is a gist like
what what is like some kind of core of
the problem that you can just attack
there and get get the
solution instead of instead of you know
trying trying dealing with the strings
and you
know is there some kind of gist okay so
you this thing oh God this needs
thinking
so you need to know
actually just a count of them
so finding all possible solutions for
filling out the question mark is
actually not essential you see here's a
kind of a Twist I don't know how
important this
is the essential thing is merely to know
to know the count of all possible
solutions so you you it's it I don't
know if it's possible you even
skipped you you can skip finding all the
actual possible solutions but all you
need to know is the how many possible
solutions are there
okay okay so this gets into you know
more like like you have to think about
it it's not just you know this this this
is this is a
problem this is a anathema to the
cc++ Java idiots because they cannot
just start to code and trial and
error um so anyway
so is so is it possible to know how many
total possible solutions without act
actually trying out you know finding all
the actual possible
solutions uh you have to
think okay God it's going to be another
hour I don't know I don't know
so so you want to find the groupings so
grouping is the key here one one
three so what you can do is first of all
you take the string and split
by the dots okay then you get okay so
okay algorithm
exploration take the
string and split by
dots okay then what you
get
is a group pin number okay for example
this first line if you split by dots you
get two
groups then you know you see the
solution requires three
groups okay
so let's say G okay
you check the grouping count
of um okay we need some jargons what's
the Jon they use the sequence of numbers
what is uh what is it called continuous
group of damage
Springs so is there a name we need a
name to describe these sequence numbers
for the sake of you know discussing the
problem otherwise it's starting to get
very
confusing uh but I don't
recall there any particular name they
are they are using okay so there's a
possible
Arrangements
uh okay let's just um let's
describe some
description for each
line there are two
parts
one the string
okay uh let's use a proper name the
let's say stream mask okay that that
stream mask is the left side of this
thing
okay
two okay on the left side is string mask
on the right side is how shall we to uh
call it
grouping
sequence sequence
count sequence group
number uh sequence of numbers grouping
sequence grouping count grouping count
let's just
say grouping
counts uh grouping list
something grouping number list
okay grouping numbers okay now that's
maybe that's a better
name so you got the stream mask and
grouping
numbers okay
then okay then
algorithm m
so you got stream
mask and grouping number okay so so take
the string and split by dots then what
you get is is uh is
um SP by
dots
count the length of the Le
e then
what so the length of the
least
uh let's say G
okay that's a grouping number okay
that's
the that's a tentative grouping number
okay
so you split this string mask by a by
sequence of dots then count the length
of the Leist result you get a 10
tentative grouping number let's say
G uh okay then you
compare the length of grouping
numbers
is let's say n uh well that should be G
okay
yeah let's that should be G then let's
change this to
n uh n two
okay what what
uh let's say TG tentative grouping
number okay so that makes
sense
so count the length of this tentative
grouping number it's a tentative
grouping number okay now compare so you
compare the the TG with that
n if it's
equal oh
God now compare to TG with
G if
equal if
greater if
lesser what happens
okay
so if
equal that means
that means you don't need to change the
length so that
means oh
God we are going nowhere
so but if it's greater is it possible
for the for it to be
greater
no so is it possible for the left hand
side to be greater the count you know
total number of
them no
if
lesser if lesser than sum of the
question
mark
means sum of the question
mark needs to be split
okay
so so something like
that okay lesser greater okay so most
likely it's lesser so but if it's equal
no need to change
length oh God this this live stream
doesn't seem going well
because too much thinking of
this truly require a lot
thinking
uh okay so well
so for example let's
say let's say this line this line the
left hand side is just
one because you split by a DOT there's
no dot so you just get one and on the
right side the grouping number is three
because you got three of them three
groups so this is less than three that
means some of this question
mark oh there so there difference so on
the right side is three left side is one
their difference is two that means there
are two
places on the left hand side side you
need to split like insertion point
Breaking Point okay
uh
and G minus
TG diff equals
to okay
and uh diff is the number of places you
need to
split to you need to replace by dot in
question
mark uh okay let how do I how can we
this is this is the heart this uh
oh OBS
problem uh how can
we phrase this
precisely so when the difference let's
say the difference is
two then that
means that means two of the question
mark two of the question marks needs to
be replaced by a DOT is
that no not necessarily because you have
the issue when the question mark is at
the
beginning
um so what we do know is that you need
to split this string further by Two
Times by
um okay so if the difference the diff is
the number of places you need to
replace question mark by
dot
okay
and they can not be
consecutive so you
replace question mark by dot but the
next one
must be
not as neighbors
okay okay so let's move on so what if
they are equal so if they are equal then
no need to
split further okay
if it's
greater oh greater is actually possible
if it's greater
then oh God if it's a greater then
some of the consecutive question
mark or needs all be
replaced by
dots oh
okay so what so what uh so so far
what we have we have this
analysis and but it's this is not
algorithm yet so I
mean so the question is how many
possible solutions right so this is not
a solution yet so suppose if lesser
then then
so any anyone else is watching I think
you know I'm kind of
getting oh n people okay so I think I
think you just have to sit and you know
do something else
because this problem
I cannot keep talking you know and
trying to solve it I just need to think
like for five minutes you know because I
keep talking and writing about it it's
not it's going to be three
hours so so let me just think about it
so you're just going to stare at my
screen okay because otherwise we can't
finish so
so you need to find you need to find all
the possible
solutions so and what we have
is you need to find all possible
solutions okay but the way we are doing
it is first
analyzing what kind
of we are analyzing the what kind of
split maybe this approach is wrong uh
but
okay so even so if you go with this
approach then you have the three
cases so if it's lesser that
means some of the question mark
string sequence needs to be
split okay so you need to split by this
count okay
yeah but also but once you do
that also first question is you don't
know where to split okay you don't
know where so how do you capture this
split thing how do
you what is the phrase to describe split
just means the essence here is
that basically you want to replace the
question Mark by a
DOT that's what it basically means but
however if you want to split it at two
positions then the two dots cannot be
consecutive because the if the two dots
are consecutive you only got one split
so another way to say is that you want
to split them sequentially end times you
know the diff number of times
okay okay suppose that then but there's
another question where do you split
it you know that's
another kind
of not simple question for example you
got this bunch of question mark there's
a question where do you split it you
know there's only certain place you
cannot simply for example replace
the well you you you can replace the
first one uh but it doesn't make sense
if you replace last one in this
case so how do you capture that well it
basically means if you have a pound sign
sequence before
it then you can
split okay if you have a pign if you do
not have a pound sign sequence
before it then it doesn't then any
splitting in the first question mark
does not
work okay this is
two okay now maybe split by dot is not
the right answer maybe you want to split
by well actually you do want to split by
dot because ultimately dot dot is what
determines the
separation okay so once you so okay so
uh you split by
dot then you so our
approach yeah so you know presume we use
this approach but then what's the next
step you got a bunch of question marks
you don't know you don't really know
where to
split okay that's the next
step because in order to know where to
split exactly you have to look into this
sequence of
numbers very very
annoying uh
okay remember you just need to know the
total Solutions total possible solutions
let's let's let's rethink
overall so total possible solutions you
got a stream mask you got
a you got a stream
mask you got grouping
numbers you got stream mask you got
grouping
numbers and uh dot means the
separator so and your problem is to fill
in the question mark by either a DOT or
a pound sign and uh uh and so the first
step is you
can is it proper should
you split the string the string mask by
the dot is that something you should do
yes because this step is absolutely
essential doesn't matter what you do I
think so so you split by the dots then
you get kind of some kind of grouping
for example here we got one two three
three
groups uh and uh you know so these three
groups cor correspond to the the
grouping
numbers I mean the count of grouping
number G so length of grouping
numbers so when they are same okay so
the first so the actually the easy way
the first the simple simplest case if is
is that when they are equal so when they
are equal you don't need to split
further so you all you have to do is you
oh yeah this is the simplest case so all
you have to do is for each
group for each group that contains the
question
mark oh okay so you know you got three
groups and you got three numbers so each
group has you know has a given number
how many uh pound sign there is okay
so oh God so
okay so so for example the first group
is one pound sign you got two question
marks so there are two possibilities so
it's about position so you got two
spots and you need one pound sign so
there are two possibilities okay in the
second spot same thing you got one pound
sign you got two spots so you got two
another two
possibilities the the third
group question mark p sign P
sign oh then you start you need to count
the number of pound sign then the three
then you got another equal or greater
than or less than
case um in this case two P sign but
number three so you you got one
possibility so the total possibility
here is just 2 * 2 * 1 is 4 four so line
two the possibility is four is that
right
yeah
okay so so far I think our our kind of
algorithm approach is still pretty good
because did we waste in anything that's
not necessary I don't think so split is
necessary split by the DOT
okay so you split by the dot then you
got the grouping number for the string
mask you compare that grouping number to
the total if they are the same then it's
just
the then the the possibility for the
solution is just
the product of each
possibility
of of filling out the pound sign okay
just the
product now that's the case when they
are equal okay now what about the equal
and
greater I mean lesser and greater so if
it's
lesser save it close it reopen okay so
what if it's lesser then then uh then
you need more splitting to do
okay
so so you need to do more split but the
question so you know so how many times
you need to split that is g minus TG
okay this count minus this grouping
count on the left hand side so let's
suppose that's two you know you need to
split two more times okay so do we have
a
case one two three one two
three okay we have a case here this this
is
just this is just one okay this is one
and this is three okay so that means you
need to split two more times
right but here comes the question how
many possible ways to do that so that
each each position of split is still a
correct solution at the
end
um so we actually need to dive into
about when you want to split this where
can you split it I mean like you know
where is the
what is the algorithm to precisely
describe the conditions and restrictions
where can you split
it in other
words we want to find the possible
possible ways to split this string such
that you know such that after you split
you can still fill out the pound sign
correctly
if if after you split you cannot fill
out the pound sign according to the
number given then that split possibility
does not count okay so this
is uh complex okay
so you want to figure out the
possibility okay let's maybe let's look
at another way so you got given 32
1 32
one yeah it's it's hard to separate them
into two
issues because you have to fear out with
the pound
sign maybe our approach is is incorrect
so but anyway so the less lesser
case how many possibilities to split
you can split by so split just means
replace a question mark by a DOT so can
you replace this by by a DOT the first
one
no no that doesn't work because on the
edge it doesn't work you still get one
group so basically Bally if it's on the
edge it doesn't work now what if it's on
the edge adjacent to a pound
sign I don't know I'm just playing with
this uh
so what if it's adjacent to the pound
sign if you spit there that
works if you spit
here that may or may not work depending
on like yeah so you can just you have to
consider the hole you can just think
about where to
split okay so that's not the right
approach
okay so that's the Lesser case what
about the greater
case some of the consecutive question
mark needs to be replaced by dot okay so
if this count is greater than the right
hand side do we have an example like
that no actually we do not have a
example like that one two 3 3 1 2 3 3 1
3 so you got 2 three 3 3 1
4 3 3 3
3 1 3 there is no case in the to input
such
that the stream mask it can be spit more
than more than in
that yeah but you see but the problem
does not preclude that
possibility because when you go to the
input let's say this all
input now is there a possible case where
left hand side has more numbers than the
right hand side very
possible three
so so basically you want to count
consecutive
dots so for the left hand side greater
than the right hand side numbers means
you got to have a lot separate dots on
the left hand side okay do we see a lot
of separate dots
no so we got one
two three
4 yeah so it's always less than the
right hand
side but though still it's possibility
though so
alternatively there it is you see the
tricky Fu the Advent of code you see
this line line
55 on the left hand side you got three
groups on the right hand side twoo so
the left hand side is greater
than the right hand side we have let's
go back to
yeah yeah so that's one example the left
hand side is greater than the right hand
side okay in that
case you need to reduce one of these
group meaning that reduce
all question marks in in the group to or
dots just replace them all by Dot
uh yeah so okay got
it so anyway so our approach here we run
into some some fairly complexities that
we don't know a solution
yet the equal case is pretty simple the
if the left hand side is greater greater
than right hand side it's pretty simple
but if the L I mean wait
yeah equal case is pretty simple if
the left hand side is
lesser then it's it's it's it's fairly
complex we don't know how to resolve it
yet but if it's
greater that's also relatively simple
because we just replace any
group of all question marks in it by a
DOT basically elim that
group and uh we just had have to do that
uh
oh but then the question is which group
can you eliminate you can
just okay God you see you can just
eliminate uh you see here in this
example we got three
groups in this case is we can eliminate
any group that will
work okay but that may not always be the
case there are some cases where there
are only certain group you can eliminate
so
that so that the pound sign you can
actually fill in and work yeah that is
true for example in this example you can
eliminate the first batch of question
mark
however if this batch of question mark
is only one question
mark then this patch of question mark
must be the one to eliminate otherwise
you you cannot eliminate the second or
third because that does not create a
solution
okay so this thing
so this in this case exactly which group
we can
eliminate
depends on
the grouping
numbers as yeah
but how exactly does it depends we need
the algorithm so this is also not
resolved yet okay so this
our approach so far doesn't seems uh
getting us
far now let's just think
about like the standard normal approach
of trying to
find trying to find all solutions
okay you know you you can you can try
you you know so like we said before just
find all possibility ities of the
question mark question mark upon sign
find all their
possibilities then fill them out each
one of them then check if it works out
if it doesn't it doesn't count if it
does it counts as solution then just
total the solution in other words we
find all possible solutions
by Brute Force okay by Brute
Force
now if you do that the major problem is
then is when you have a lot
questions okay so if you have you know
let's say if you have five questions so
each question mark is two
possibilities so how many possibilities
you get that's five raised to the I mean
two two ra to the fifth power okay so
and that in increase is quickly so 2 to
the e8th power is 256 that's
small but it's exponential okay that's
basically two to the N nth power so
quickly you become exponential now again
you have to check advant of code you
know they don't have many question marks
you so so far actually we can actually
Brute Force this so for each possibility
you just check all you know check all
possible solution I mean check if it
works out so in this
case there are 10 question marks that's
two to the 10th power that's not too big
that's five uh 12 that's only
512 so the AOC because if you
are really careful thinker mathematician
you waste your time while the brain l
stas they they work out you know they
but if you you see their personal input
doesn't have you know for example I want
to
see if you have one single line like
that okay let's just say to okay then
all the idiot idiotic no thinker no
brainers they stuck on that you know
it'll take 10
hours to to to to to run their
program but Advent of a code
well I mean he's not a bad guy but he
but you know he his problem this you
know this
problem you know this this kind of
problem is bad because it punishes those
who actually
provide 100% correct and efficient
answer if you do that you know like me I
tends to be that way okay I'm slow but I
provide 100% correct and efficient
answer you get punish it punished
because there's no input you know that
deal with you know the the case you are
thinking it doesn't say that case
doesn't happen you know this is the case
with the ven
code so
anyway uh let's let's put uh let's put
let's just say that
okay yeah if you get one of these then
the possible solutions is kind of huge
you know how
many how many um
51 so you know 51
this mod exponential what is the name of
the exponential function exp I think
228 okay let's run
it uh R number exponent
what what the oh that's natural
exponent okay maybe it's always very
annoying yeah you know the you see
this is a common problem among
programming languages about the naming
of the power function or exponential or
the natural like the E the natural
number e raised to something so this
this is actually doing e raed to 8
okay that is Computing e raed to 8 okay
and what we want is actually this one
okay there it is you
see you know 256 so what if you get 10
that's still small okay 10 is 124
okay uh but okay let's copy that let's
just put it here for the sake of fun
because you know I'm kind of stuck so
I'm starting to you
know do the easy thing of just rent and
so anyway so what so how many for
if we have a case like that how many
characters 51 characters okay let's
see 51 that's still within normal range
because you know not many characters but
what is the
result okay so here is the result okay
stupid
okay so basically you have to try this
many times for each you know you have to
try this many times to verify
uh to verify the solution matches the
number given on the right hand
side right so how many how many times is
that yeah this can
easily I mean you can still finish in
few minutes I
suppose so that's uh what is number
this so here is kilo Mega G
Petra
wait k wait so something
kilo Mega Giga Petra two okay Petra then
EXA two
EXA
times uh if you take one second less
than second so you know I don't know I'm
not sure how long that is but anyway
okay okay so something like that 51
question mark okay yeah so you
got okay
so so but what so what are we going to
do then I mean should we finish yeah we
shouldn't leave need to finish because
I'm sure other people finish in one hour
a lot people I mean yeah a lot the you
know
the fast
coders so if I don't finish this problem
is it doesn't it's not so good you know
doesn't look good for my
YouTube so
okay so we analyzed so
far uh uh we got
this yeah but so far we don't have an
algorithm yet yeah so we are now we are
thinking of just try
basically okay so I mean let's write it
out did we write out
yet
so
simply put Force replace all possible
replacement
of question mark by Dot and
check if it works okay this is a Brute
Force
way uh let's think about let's do if we
do Brute Force how easy it be you know
how easy would it
be you know of of course BR Force then
you run into you know this
this
problem you know then you run into this
case uh but anyway so but you still
finish in a few minutes I suppose
something but so if we do Brute
Force which I believe is vast majority
of
solutions because that way is the least
brand required
okay so if we do the Brute
Force then
um
then how easy is that I mean can you can
we quickly start to code it BR Force so
BR force is that
you so for example here is
113 you still need to know
uh yeah you you still need to like split
first
then okay so for example let's say this
if you do Brute
Force oh yeah I'm sitting on this chair
for too
long I think I need a
break so can you see this is like
ergonomic chair this
is this is my kneeing chair yeah
actually I'm
pretty I need to walk and prevent as Rod
you
see usually every day I sit on this
chair for a few hours then I switch to
that
one uh you don't want to sit on one
chair all day because I sit in front of
the computer like 10 hours a day
so and typically every two hours I walk
around so now let's sit on this
chair but actually I need a break okay
so if you do boot
Force you still have the split problem
because you need to first of
all okay but let's forget about
splitting let's just real boot Force you
know simply just
replace uh okay how do you do it though
so you got question
marks question marks and a bunch of
numbers uh if you put
Force so what do you need to
do you need get you need to get the
grouping right okay so the the most
brainless brute force is
simply you know get the number of
question marks and find all possible
feeling of the question mark by either a
DOT or by a
pound so if you have here one two three
four five five question mark yeah so
it's to raised to fifth
power which is small 128 or you
know fifth power yeah that's not much
128 or 60 602 or
something 32 64 yeah
so so you have 64 possibilities then you
just then for each you
just then you know for each you sped the
string by
dot then you count each group the number
of P the number of pound sign in each
group then you check if that matches
that if
so then that's one possible solution
okay so you just compute all possible
solutions okay this is a pro Force way
now the Brute Force
way okay replace string question mark
um well I mean so I mean the question is
is it very easy to code if it is you
know if we can code this full way in one
minute then wow then who cares about you
know it takes how much time it runs you
know we we solve the problem but the
Brute Force way
[Music]
you you need to find all
possible yeah the first way is not too
hard but
still so you got one two three four five
five question mark so basically you got
you know end spots each spot can be
possible of two things one or zero let's
say then you just get all
possible you know binary
sequence then you take that sequence
then you take that string then you just
replace each question mark by if it's
one it's you know pound sign if it's
zero it's start
right so the Brute Force way first or
you count the number of question marks
okay the
most putot Force
way is to count number of question marks
in the number in the string
mask
then say
n
then you
have two ra to n
ways find all the possible binary
sequence
okay
then map a function to the stream mask
to
the uh as a least
okay okay then map a function to the
binary sequence l h
time replace
question
by if it's one
else replace by dot
okay
then split the result string by
dot
count for each group and see if it
matches the grouping number
okay this is the proof Force
way the
problem so anyone is still actually
paying attention say hi okay concur
viewer six maybe you are doing
something okay but we are kind of
making progress
okay so the most Brute Force way you
know actually I want to quit
because anyway the most beautiful way is
this way okay can we do that can we call
this how long does it take to call this
the most brute for
way uh let's see let's think about hey
hey wimbo hello oh someone is watching
me still thank you
so the bo the boot Force how long does
it take to do to implement this most Bo
Force
way
uh 20 minutes I
think so you got the stream mask you
simply count the number of question
marks okay then you generate a sequence
binary sequence of that number of
question marks you know you got binary
one 0 1 0 0 1 0 one of length n okay how
do you do that that's is very easy in
wfam language one single
function okay then you just map a
function to this binary sequence for
each time you replace this
you know you replace all the question
mark according to whether it's one or
zero
right uh yeah so you get a string you
get a new string then you just split the
string to check you know the pound sign
grouping Matrix set
okay yeah so if we do this way it how
long does it take 20 minutes 20 minutes
to C this
is that what shall we do you
know I kind of you know should we you
know yeah it'll take 20 minutes
10 20 minutes you know maybe 30 minutes
actually because then I I go you know I
explain things
and but you know I myself will take 10
minutes 20
minutes to implement the boot Force way
but the Brute Force way
is insulting you know because
[Music]
then what am I here for you know if you
want watch you if you want to watch The
Brute Force way I think all the
solutions out there are the BR Force way
basically I'm pretty sure 90% of
solutions I mean V of
code I think few people a lot of people
does day one part one you know or part
two or day two or day three but for day
12 it it's exponentially rare okay so
you won't see a lot people I don't think
you'll see a
lot you know we can we can
check let's just search quickly see you
know do we get a lot
Advent of code 2023 day 12 900 a.m.
Wednesday in Magalia California
idiot oh there it is hot springs YouTube
know Jesus he solved in 12
minutes uh actually it would be
interesting to check you know so there
is advent of code day 12 solution
s uh day 12 part two okay oh okay this
guy are persistent Advent code 200 23
day 12 House Spring in
C how long does this take I don't know
this one uh rust this
one you know they did it
so let's see how long did it take
them so this one is 1 hour
okay this one is uh 42 minutes okay
reasonable this one is 33 minutes
fantastic yeah but actually some of them
are smart you know if they are all doing
Brute Force then it's not really
interesting
because 30 minutes for br Force way uh
you know that's
reasonable
but it's you know it's real
interesting oh
I talked all this time sorry about
that oh yeah so I was looking at um you
know other people how long do they
take
so oh you know so anyway so you
know so this guy is taking one
hour in C this guy is taking 42
minutes in Rust this guy is taking 33
minutes what language what language is
he he
using uh language actually matters
wait so what language
uh coding programming Advent
code 600
views uh what language it doesn't say
this
guy let's see
oh def part one def C uh looks like
python okay python the most
mainstream 33 seconds
okay so these people now if they solve
this problem by Brute Force 30
minutes uh I think that's
not that's normal I mean it's normal
it's not too impressive okay but if they
if they solve
that uh
by by very efficient you know like dive
into the heart of the
problem then that's more more
interesting okay so for
me uh
God I'm thinking what to do so I don't
want to do it Pro Force
because but if we go back to our to my
analysis we partition it it first you
see the the thing here is that you don't
really need the
solution you actually just need to know
how many possible solutions there
are so if we go back to our this
original analysis
exploration this may lead to that answer
yeah I think
so you don't actually find a solution
okay maybe I should I should I should
continue this but if we continue this
way I don't know how long it'll take one
one more hour so you don't actually find
the solution but you just find all the
possible
solutions so we you know we get the you
know we
get the two parts The Mask string and
the uh grouping
numbers we split the Mas mask string
mask by dot to see how how many group we
get then we compare if it's equal to the
uh grouping numbers or less or greater
so if it's
equal then the possible solution number
of solution is very
easy you
just you know we we we talked about this
before you just
um if it's equal you just find the for
each group you count the possible ways
to do it which is you know which is you
count the number of question marks by by
the pound sign required for that
group uh well minus the exist existing
number of pound signs so you you got a
difference so basically you got a number
of pound signs so number of question
marks and number pound signs how many
possible ways to feel that then you know
that then that's the total possible ways
for one group you do that for the second
then you multiply all of them together
okay so you
don't you don't
even actually obtain any solution you
just directly answer what the problem
wants okay but that is that's the
simplest case if the grouping numbers
equal now if it's lesser
if it's if it's lesser I'm pretty sure
you know there are people on YouTube who
solve this
way within our okay I'm pretty sure
there's always a lot smart people out
there anyway so if it's
lesser
then some of the question mark
stream sequence needs to be split okay
um
for example it's a case here
so yeah but God okay I don't
know okay I want to quit
uh so if we do this
way but we still we don't have the
algorithm yet you know we haven't
finished this may you know I don't know
how long this will take we don't have
the
algorithm if it's lesser then you some
of the question marks sequence needs to
be
split
then you know so we know how many times
we need to split
it
um
okay uh however
however we have't you know however you
cannot simply split it
anywhere there is you know these
restrictions so let's think about
this there are these restrictions so how
can you maybe shortcut so there are
these restrictions 13 one six
so you know in this case you know the
number here is four four counts the
number on the left is one so their
difference is four minus one three so
that means this string mask needs to be
split three more
times
okay now here is the question how do we
know
which are the possible split is it
possible I mean you know first of all we
know we cannot split on the
edges okay because when you do that you
know if you replace those question marks
by dot it doesn't do anything it so you
can only
split by replacing a question
mark to a DOT only if that question mark
happens not on the edge of the current
group okay that's one
thing is not
on the edge of the
group that's one of the condition
okay so you
look then okay that's one of the
condition the
then then if it's inside because for
example can you split this
one
yes but can you split this one and not
those two not whatever com in from no
because the first group must have one
pound sign so if your first split is
here then you don't get the possible
solution
okay so given a string mask you know
they must be
split three
times in other words you know there must
be three separators in three dots in
between okay so instead of looking at
this way kind of sequential you have to
look
at so what you know is that you need you
need to have three dots instead of
saying split you just need three
dots inside this this mask okay not on
the edges but three dots inside but also
where do they but not just anywhere so
the you know you you cannot have the
first start here because then that does
not solve the problems okay so in order
to
determine where where you can place the
dot is to judge on the pound sign okay
so here is the case you need to
split by question
mark uh no yes or
no well may anyway but I mean so this
question mark three of
them needs to become a DOT the problem
is you don't know
where so if you look at the pound sign
the first one is needs to be
one so you can another approach is you
just look at the pound sign oh that's
more direct because this sequence of
numbers grouping numbers directly tell
you you know how the pound sign I mean
they they specify about the pal sign
so the first one must be one then there
must be a
group okay
so so they specify the pound
sign grouping of the pwn sign
okay so basically this problem is that
you got a
string okay then you have these
groupings okay the groupings can split
can so think of a kind of a
like a cable or a wire okay then you
have kind of Abacus on it you know like
children's toy you can push it
around okay let's you know let's just
random talk and
dig yeah kind of like
that you know so you got a
toy yeah f
Fu
you know you gotta you got a toy
like that I don't want this I just
want this picture yeah you going to to
you like that so think of each row of
this thing of the stream mask what that
you know so you got these speeds you can
push around form groups so the the
real you know the the question is just
about
this grouping and and uh
uh and question mark okay
so I mean and they
specify so what what is another approach
you know our approach here is getting
too too
hard is there another approach you know
so you basically you are given a string
of certain length
the length is always fixed okay and you
just want this possible pound signs with
a
DOT oh okay so this another approach
okay so in this approach kind of new
approach the
problem new approach ignore the input
simply take the fixed
string
simply for each
line consider
the length of the fix
string on the
left let's say stream
mask okay so that's a length for example
example I mean this one is seven
right
then uh not you know I mean simply for
each line consider length of the stream
as uh let's say
n then the
sequence of grouping numbers
okay uh let's say seven okay so this is
seven and three
okay let say something like that
okay so this is seven and uh this is uh
one
one3 and uh
total uh length is three okay
so for seven so
so
consider
binary
string binary number of seven
digits okay
then then you just compute
compute possible
grouping of
one in
this binary number okay
then once okay then it needs to be three
one3 okay
so
so okay so you actually if you do this
approach uh this is not so good then
because you know you want to consider
all the possible combinations of
consecutive ones in a binary digit
binary number of seven
digits but then you need to and then
consider
suchar
groupings of one three
basically oh yeah
okay but
then
minus but you see your binary string
still needs to fit into this given
mask because the pound sign is like one
okay the dot is like zero
so your binary string cannot even though
you find all the possible such binary
digits with grouping
113 so let's say you have one
1,000 but you have to consider the
problem given is that the rightmost
three digits is
one so you have to minus the
so you have to minus the given mask
okay okay that's not
good too much you
know so if we do that so is this is this
approach any easier at all
oh okay so so why don't we minus mask
the mask
first yeah so we only the you know the
the part we don't know is just the
question mark
part I mean back to our problem so the
just the question mark part so given
this specifically placed question
mark so yeah again we we are thinking we
we want to think about this
problem from the beginning again so
given a like a binary
sequence certain slot we don't know we
want to feel it so
that so that you know so we want to know
the total possibilities
okay we just want to know the total
possibilities of doing it but the con
strength is that we are given this
mask okay the mask on the left hand side
okay you know
so you know I got nothing to do
now so
let's let me just do this
so these makes it more easier to see
somewhat so the left hand side is the
mask
string how do you do it no how I mean so
we are
not is there a way is there like much
significantly simpler
way because this problem is a
combinatorial problem okay if we capture
the G gist then we can solve directly
this combinatorial
problem you know we can of course do the
Brute
Force yeah but you know that's the most
boring Solution that's I think that's
what people do I'm guessing but I mean
maybe they are
smart but there was way too many age
cases I didn't think through ahead of
time at first it seems to day 12 will be
relative easy okay so problem solution
problem solution part one part two oh
they did both of them
and oh chat GPT
well I doubt I doubt chat gbt can solve
the
problem you know correctly they can just
give like
suggestions so this guy using
rust okay uh I live stream this on which
on Twitch I can occasionally weekday
morning okay my R
Solutions okay my question is did you
sol it Brute
Force whole afternoon after work for
this problem and couldn't solve it I
thought I can use some combinatoric math
to solve it but was but it was the case
for me then I found your video your
dedication to the problem as well as a
sound you make we love we uh we we make
we you sol it just give me more
energy to revisit okay thanks
Uncle okay no I'm I'm the Granddad
then this was impressive I Brute Force
part one then worked on part two for two
hours two hours before I had to start
work then in the evening I did another
two hours before setting aside again
finally my third session I managed a
similar but less elegant the WR solution
okay so it seems this guy did uh did not
use brute force you know if it's Brute
Force it's not really interesting
because if it's SP Force then then the
interesting part is how do you use the
language okay the programming
language I simulate okay so oh his name
is Uncle scientist this guy Uncle
scientist that's why he's Uncle I
simulate being smart by taking four
times longer to think about things than
normal people oh okay like me I spent
two days studing on paper trying to
reason my way through a solution before
the second half of this video
started okay so they didn't solve
it on the
spot okay they they had some
preparations I
guess SP spent two days doing on paper
trying to reason my way through a
solution before the second half of this
video video
yeah so they you know they they this is
not real
time so what about this guy twitch using
python did you boot
Force how did you do today you are
finally posting about it amazing great
explanation thank you
you know you can you can see the code to
see if they are Pro Force right
away yeah this high low
resolution go index plus index left lse
M index pound index go index looks
like line in input calculate Line Print
total
okay pretty short program line split
then cach go index index left
index return one return zero index
links
number Define go okay total zero M index
dot
dot else if equals to Z equals to
that looks like BL
Force oh okay so he's still coding
it so that's his personal input I guess
okay any comments okay maybe I
stop so let's let me think about this
again
uh now it's 2 hours and 20 minutes okay
so you got it's binary number of mask
you got a mask your problem is filling
out the question
mark your problem is filling out the
question mark by either a pound sign or
by a DOT
so you know it's much more familiar if
we just think of this as a binary digit
of certain length the pound sign is just
one the dot is just
zero okay the question mark is
is the part you have to decide whether
it's one or zero okay
[Music]
then so grouping given so first of all
given this
grouping uh certainly there's a
combinatorial possibility so first of
all if you know the total length of the
grouping numbers then you already know
what is the total possibilities okay
once you know how how many grouping
numbers are there you know how many
total possibilities okay then but but
then you see it's not just about
grouping total number of
groupings but the each number in the
group matters
okay so in other words yeah so actually
yeah so like I said you know there are
two parts given a binary number of
certain
digits and given this grouping number 32
one you already
know let's
see you know you already
know how many possibilities are there
but uh but
um so given this binary sequence this so
you so the problem is actually you you
you really do want to split by DOT
first then like like we like our analy
analysis here then you do want to split
I mean then you focus on
each sequence of the question mark
because uh well
then then you do not know if you need to
yeah actually our problem analysis here
is good you know you have three cases
equal to lesser or greater then
uh I'm not sure what to do I need to
walk so you need to so
you you have the
situations yeah so this is a good way
way to go first step then you got equal
lesser and
greater cases so the equal case is very
simple the Lesser case it's more
complicated because it's lesser group
you need to do more split so for example
like this one we talked about you
need three more dots
oh oh okay it's either dot or a pound
side so if you if this you know you need
three more Dots
here then you know the rest is going to
be pound
sign yeah obviously but where but the
question is where do you put the three
dots how do you know how do you what is
the algorithm what is a efficient
algorithm to place three dots you know
that it cannot be on the edge of the
group
um so that's one condition what are the
other conditions so we we need to
continue to think about
this H
uh so you cannot be on the edge and
uh it cannot be too consecutive you
cannot put two dots consecutive because
otherwise there's no
split so okay so consider this case four
let's
say you know in this case we can only
split
once it's not possible to split it
twice that's right that's
correct so
if you want to split once you know it
cannot be on the edges so you only have
like two possibilities now what about
more question okay for what about this
one so this one let's say it's required
to split it twice two more times to
obtain total grouping of three
parts okay so we know already it cannot
be on the edges so that leaves that
then okay so we need to spit so and we
know it cannot be consecutive so you got
so this the first one here this can be a
DOT then the dot just can be
anywhere
okay but then the dot can be this one
beginning with this
character so but how do you
what is the exact condition so you got
two dots you got bunch of
spots
split so what are the possible ways
to
split okay I think I
know I think I know okay
I I think I started to know
okay so once I know this yeah I I kind
of started to know so I mean first of
all you know you cannot it cannot be on
the
side yeah so we got you know we just
basically got a bunch of question
marks and uh
well but that's not the total condition
the also another condition that mean
it's not just about split because once
you
split you know this you need to
fit
this okay I think I give up uh this
problem it needs more
thinking uh needs more thinking you
would
be you know if we did the brute
force it work but uh but we didn't do
that it's
already two or three
hours so if we
continue to force this mathematical
way uh more thinking is required you you
just need to think about this
problem it's some kind of binary number
mask
problem uh and this
problem it is my
guess is well
known me not I mean maybe obscure but
this
problem
is somewhat common I mean not common but
I mean it must have came up before in
Engineering in computer chips
design because this is you
know and uh it's uh it's it's kind of a
math problem it's basically just about
mask
binary numbers a efficient way
to to have a sequence of binary digits
such that the groups of one the group
the groups of Digit
ones forms this pattern and you just and
and also given this mask you need
to yeah very very very combinatorial
problem yeah now I now I get more closer
to um to understand the math
aspect a very clear combinatory
combinatorial
problem you you you know you you got a
sequence of binary digits of fixed
number of digits and you got a fixed
positions of ones and you want to find
the total possible ways of such binary
sequence such that this you know this
pound sign already
one uh and uh you
know yep
so so definitely this is the approach
definitely but you just need to think
more about
it uh and you know look at the cases for
example this one one one one
yeah yeah so you see so first of all
about the possibilities one of the most
important thing is how many digits are
there how many groupings are there
that's the most important because once
you know that you you kind of
eliminated a lot possibilities in all
possible binary sequences
so that's one important thing but the
other important thing is that the
existing ones that also eliminate a lot
of possibilities
okay so to approach this problem you can
approach it either from Pure I mean I
mean we are approaching you
know in this combinatory or binary
sequence way which is mathematical
analysis okay so forget about
actual you know forget about the actual
coding you know trial and error and
Brute Force okay because this Brute
Force way is never going to fly because
then because this Brute Force way if you
have you know let's
say binary digits of 100 digits all
these bruit Force they they
fail yeah they fail you you want a
formula okay so the problem the the
solution the most efficient and correct
solution to this problem is one single
formula okay it's not about manipulating
strings you
know it's one single formula this
formula tells you how many possibilities
given a fixed number of string a binary
Ary digit a fixed number of binary
digits and this grouping
numbers
and okay that's one thing but and also
you know where specifically so you know
these slots are already one okay then
the question is just the combinatorics
okay yeah it's yeah so
so I need to solve it you know I need to
think about this some
more uh it's sequence yeah so you know
you can just magically came out with a
formula uh the also it's not a pure
formula formula because you already have
certain positions filled so the formula
needs to have some some kind of encoding
for these field
positions
now the
exact pos position of this one Ur it
does not actually is flexible okay it's
again it's actually
flexible
uh for example let's say this
one uh
I mean I mean there is um you know what
I'm saying is that given this line you
know we know there's a solution right
let's say n
possibilities now what I'm saying is
that given this
number they are more
than I mean there there are
um there may be different fixed position
of the pound sign that also have n
possibilities something like
that so in other words this input is not
unique you know not necessarily
unique you know so for for each of these
line there's another number another
number that is a total possibilities
okay so we got three things one is this
fixed Mass stream mask the other thing
is this grouping number and the third
thing
is total possibilities okay so what I'm
saying is that if the grouping number
and total possibilities are
fixed
this stream mask is not
unique neither okay so again this is a
combinatorial
problem uh so I'm just making progress
on and talking about it and uh so but
okay so but we need to actually
pursue how do you solve it okay
so okay I I'm gonna stop okay so I'm
gonna
stop we we failed you know I'm going to
I'm not going to continue
uh but I will
continue and finish this
problem uh and do a live stream you know
probably tomorrow okay so I will think
about
it um so that maybe tomorrow or maybe
after tomorrow I'll start the live
stream and I'll start to code instead of
you know thinking I'll tell just tell
you guys to how I think about this
problem
uh pure combinatorial solution okay
there there would not be stream
manipulation there would be just um yeah
but not I mean so let's look at what
other people I mean is this guy also
doing the pure
combinatorial solution
no you know you look at his
code you know you got this which for
Arrangements size iteration count
restart length matching on regular
expression I
guess this is while loop which self no
this guy is not doing it's basically Pro
Force okay uh let's see the next
guy this guy Advent of code in C okay
let's let see what he
got Arrangement pattern length group
count pattern index pattern length
length equals to smaller than that
pattern lengths plus one okay that looks
like
another uh root Force for pattern length
for else if if if if patter length count
equals to one Arrangement yeah F
Force so we
so three quick web search it seems like
they are all Brute
Force
okay uh now
read
it let's see you know
so you you see this guy I tried to use
combinatorial to solve today's puzzle
but failed my brain burned out in the
end I just used brot
Force okay I don't care about that code
2023 day 12 share your solution berley
edu oh berley berley atre they got smart
people uh you need JavaScript
on why is it not
opening okay this is a threat to discuss
day remember it is very important not to
write any public spoilers oh
Community software Swift Forum
event of code 2020 three Swift Forum hi
Swift
Community okay so they are coding in
language
okay so here's some
code uh location group point so part
number A P part number what is this
initial table grid count grid is this
actually okay that's not I don't think
that's not day two puzz two okay
something
uh okay so so here's a thing guys uh I'm
going to shut down
today not having done the problem uh but
so you guys look around and comment
okay uh hello you EU morning from
Ukraine hello so i' I I kind of failed
during today's problem after three hours
so this is uh so let me wrap up okay let
me explain what's going on on in
the okay today's talk show uh this is
advent of code
2023 day 12 okay so I read the problem
in the past
about uh three three hours I think two
two and a half hours or
something two three four yeah close to 3
hours I analyzed the problem and uh
didn't actually actually didn't really
code anything except you know that's
just passing passing it okay so we
didn't code but we I you know I went
over trying
to
find ways to solve this problem in a
efficient
way but so we so one way one approach is
simply brute
force and eventually you know I I you
know search the web it seems all these
people are just doing brue Force now
brue force of course solves the problem
is it will be great I didn't do uh it
will take me I think 20 minutes or 30
minutes to actually write the code to
brute force it but brute force is not an
interesting solution because if you do
BR Force well you get to learn how to
code in that language in this case wam
language or python or C or rust you
know uh but you just learn the
programming language but however from
our analysis this problem is basically a
combinatorial problem about binary
numbers you know bin kind of like a mask
a binary sequence you know given a
fixed binary number fixed number of
digits and
certain digits are one already and given
that they are grouping count of ones
consecutive counts of
ones you want to find how many
posses uh you know what how many
possibilities for such binary sequence
okay that's when you want to fill out
the question mark each one is a binary
digit you want want to replace it by one
or zero so that this consecutive ones
count uh grouping
numbers is satisfied okay so this is a
combinatorial problem so ideally the
solution is simply a mathematical
formula okay you don't do you know Loop
if check you know like you don't do that
ideally the solution
is a combinatorial I mean a math
formula like two rais to the power
something plus something and uh if but
if you do that each of the you know
binary sequence they need to be encoded
some in somehow you know which position
is one which position is not it actually
can be just a string just like
that so anyway the solution should be a
very
simple mathematical formula
and uh as far as my guess you know I
guess this problem is already known it's
a known problem okay maybe obscure but
it's a
known
problem uh in binary sequence okay so
that is how where we are today I didn't
finish it so I think next time maybe
tomorrow but maybe not maybe I'll do a
video live stream on something else on
emac or on politics or something
or on keyboards but we all come back
next time I come back to this
problem you know I will have already
thought out and give you guys the
solution how to code it okay so that is
the situation for
today thank you guys for watching uh too
bad no Solutions today like like uh okay
that's it bye guys