Good morning guys. Welcome to another
episode of talk show. We are going to
code advent of code. Ad event of code
2025 day one in wufam language.
Now if you are watching this offline
we're at 1.5 speed minimum.
If you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. We got six people. So,
starting Wufam language, the most
advanced programming language, a new
notebook.
Okay, so we are ready to go. Let's
magnify
3 shift enter to start the kernel.
Okay, so comments. Okay, advant of code.
Uh I haven't read the problem yet but
let's do so we're going to read at okay
so you got needs to be here this idiotic
advent of a code dark theme stupid and
you cannot resize it the window so they
have hardcoded their website
uh their website layout which is idiotic
advent of code
um okay so anyway we're going started
and let's see how far we go. Okay,
comments.
So, the VM code. So, um let's see
today's talk show. So, we're going to
use Wuam language introduction. If you
don't know, search for Wufam language
for programmers. So, you got a complete
tutorial from the ground up for
programmers and uh oni.info
http nos. Okay. And you can uh then you
can download Wuang language for free. It
began free about four or five years ago.
Okay. On this link uh and uh I have like
over 100 video tutorials on wam language
in the past. Okay. So go back to uh
today's talk show and you got kasaw
wufam mode which allows you to code wam
language in emacs. So anyway let's
begin. Okay.
subwoofer mode and soundfly keys. That's
what I'm using. I'm so I'm using Emacs,
the most advanced uh editor for coders.
Okay, let's put it back there. Put it
there. Okay, let's read the problem and
let's see. Just have fun.
Okay, event code day one secret
entrance. The elves have a good news and
bad news. The good news is that they've
discovered project management.
This has given them the tools they need
to prevent their usual Christmas
emergency. For example, they now know
that the North Pole decorations needs to
be finished soon so that other critical
task can start on time.
The bad news is that they've realized
they have different emergency. According
to their resource planning, none of them
have any time left to decorate the North
Pole. Okay. To save Christmas, the elves
need you to finish decorating the North
Pole by December 12th. Collect stars by
solving puzzles. Okay. Two puzzles will
be made available on each day. The
second puzzle is unlocked when you
complete the first. Each puzzle grants
one star. Good luck. Okay. You arrive at
the secret entrance to the North Pole
based North Pole base. Ready to start
decorating. Unfortunately, the password
seems to have been changed so you can't
get in. A document taped to the wall
helpfully explains.
Ah, tedious babbling. You uh then due to
new security protocols, the password is
locked in the safe below. Please see the
attached document for the new
combination. The safe has a dial with
only an arrow on it.
Around the dial are the numbers zero
through 99 in order. As you turn the
dial, it makes a small click noise as it
reaches each number. Okay, 0 to 99.
The attached document, your puzzle input
contains a sequence of rotations, one
per line, which tell you how to open the
safe. A rotation start with L or R which
indicates whether the rotation should be
to the left
towards a lower number or to the right
towards higher number. Okay
let's see wait 0 to 0 to 99. So
according according to this the 0 to 99
is arranged counterclockwise
supposedly I'm not sure. So let's see uh
then the rotation has a distance value
which indicates how many clicks the dial
should be rotated in that direction.
Okay, left or right.
Uh and the and the number of clicks. So
if the dial were pointing at 11, a
rotation of R8
would cause the dial to point at 19. So
11 + 8 is 19. So okay, after that a
rotation of L 19 would cause it to point
at zero.
Okay, so far so so good. comments. None.
Because the dial is in a circle. Because
the dial is a circle. Turning the dial
left from zero one click makes it point
99. Okay. So, yeah. Exactly. So, the
numbers are arranged in counterclock
orientation.
Similarly, turning the dial right from
99.
One click makes it 080. So zero suppose
is at the top and uh to the right of it
is 99.
Okay. So turning the dial left from
zero. That's right. Okay.
So turning left means you rotate it
counterclockwise. Turning right means
you rotate it clockwise. Just like
common sense. Okay. So if the dial were
pointing at five, a rotation of L10
would cause it to point at 95. So let's
see five
L 10 which means rotate left
uh and which also
okay so L is actually
so so you know it says decreasing and
increasing but
>> [sighs]
>> So let's see how do we model this L10.
L10 would cause it to point at 95.
That's right because
let's see five rotation of L10 left.
So,
[clears throat]
so if it's five and see
five
so essentially it's 0 to one uh 99. So
you want to do modular arithmetics
of 100.
So
So five
L. So L is negative or positive. L means
um
let's see let's get this right. That's
the heart of solving the problem. Okay.
Rotation of L10. Let me just think about
it. Comments, guys. Comment.
Woohoo. Maybe make a drawing. Yeah, make
a drawing would be great, but then it
takes time. So then it's going to make
my video like from one hour to two hour.
But but it's uh it's always good to make
a drawing. Okay. So let's start a
drawing. So let's see.
Uh so basically you have something like
that. So
zero 1 2 3 4. Okay. So this is 99
98 and so on.
Uh
L10 means move leftward. So let me think
about this. So L basically means minus.
So if you are at five,
if you are at five L10,
[clears throat]
I got a cold over the weekend. So the
whole body aches, so it's pretty bad.
And coughing, but now I'm better.
So L10, uh, it's I'm pretty sure it's
minus. So 5 - 10 would be neg -5.
Then you + 100
means 105. Then you modulide by 100. The
remainder is five.
So L10 cause it 2. 95. Wait, that's not
right. So um
let me see.
So if it's point at five let's say if
it's pointing at five so
five six so something like that suppose
five six
uh wait
yeah yeah it increases on the on the
left five six 7 8 Okay then
four 3 2 1 zero. Okay. So if you rotate
it by one to the left
then it's going to be four. So left
rotation means minus that we can be
sure. So five rotated to the left by two
get you three. Okay. Now five rotated to
the left by five get you zero. Five
rotated to the left.
So it to the right of zero is 99. Now
five rotated to the left by six is 99.
How do you arrive at that? Because 5
minus 6 gets you -1. -1 + 100 because
there's 100 of them. So 101. Wait. So
uh
[snorts]
so this this is uh involving signs. So
so if we uh five rotated by six so 5 - 6
get you -1. Now -1
-1 + 100
+ 100 is 101.
Wait -1 + 100 is 99. That's right. -1 +
100 is 99. That's what you get. That's
correct.
Okay. Then um then 99 is less than 100.
So you don't need to do anything. All 99
divided by 100 is still 99. Okay. So
left means minus rotate right means
plus. Okay. So modular arithmetics
that's a key which means modular
arithmetics is a operator that takes two
numbers. Basically it's the remainder.
So one number divided by another number
then you take the remainder. That's what
modular arithmetics means. Okay. Okay.
So, we got that. Close it. Save it.
Okay. So, so the day one problem should
be easy. Okay. So, if the dial were
point at five, a rotation of A10 would
cause it to point at 95. After that, a
rotation of R5 would cause it to point
at zero. Okay. The dial start by
pointing at 50. Okay. So, so there is a
beginning of pointing 50. You could
follow the instructions, but your recent
required official
North Pole secret entrance security
training seminar taught you that the
safe is actually a decoy.
[sighs]
The actual password is the number of
times the dial is left pointing at zero
after any rotation in the sequence.
Okay.
Okay. So there's a trick.
So you got I suppose you got a bunch of
instructions left something right
something left something right something
and the key is it begins at 50. Okay. So
left, right, left, right. And so what is
the problem?
The actual password is the number of
times the dial is left pointing
at zero after any rotation in the
sequence.
It's stupid, idiotic
phrasing.
Okay. So the actual password is the
number of times
number of times the dial is left
pointing at zero. What does that mean?
Left pointing at zero after any rotation
in the sequence.
You see this is idiotic English because
this is not logical. So the number of
times okay I got that. It's a number of
times it occur. Now, but what's a what's
a circumstance?
Well, the circumstance is the dial is
left pointing. What the does left
pointing mean? You see, you got a dial,
you got a pointer. What the is left
pointing?
The dial is left pointing at zero.
Does that mean after a left rotation
and it results in pointing at zero? Does
that mean that the dial is left pointing
at zero after any rotation in the
sequence?
Well, then what does it mean any
rotation? So, it could be also right
rotation. So, what is the Oh, okay. So,
the dial is left
pointing at zero. So this is English
ambiguity and the idiot
of the advent of a code writer. He
doesn't know the ambiguity about
English. He doesn't know how to write
English. You see
the actual password is the number of
times the dial is left on.
You know it's better if you say on. So
after the number of times the dial is
pointing at zero after a rotation. Okay,
that's a better phrase. The number of
times basically the number of times it
is pointing at zero. Okay, let me
rephrase the question. So you got a dial
and you got a se uh then you got the
instruction. It begin pointing at 50.
Okay. Then you are giving a bunch of
rotation left and rotation right. Okay.
Now after all that the number of times
every time after rotation the dial is at
zero
the number of uh times. So that is a
number
and that number is the password. Okay.
So this is the stupid phrasing. Okay. So
for example, so let's verify. So he's
gonna give you an example.
That's right. Mocha says the correct
analysis. So ignore the word left. It
doesn't refer to direction. It's like
left as in I left it there yesterday.
That's correct. So there is ambiguity in
English.
I mean because left could mean the left
hand side
or my left hand or another meaning is
it's a state it was so there are two
meaning in English the language of the
word left but however when you describe
this problem this problem involves left
hand side left rotation and right
rotation uh but so It's it's ambiguous.
So if you want it if you are writing a
technical documentation or if you are
writing a puzzle, you should avoid
phrasing like that.
But you could argue that the guy
intentionally phrased it that way. So it
kind of like add to the confusion of the
person. That's not good because the
quality of a ple is about the essence of
the puzzle itself. not about your like
style of writing. I mean you could make
it elaborate like Shakespeare style but
still
um anyway so this is not very good.
Okay, this is like a flaw. I you know I
find a lot of flaws of the advent of
code.
[sighs and gasps]
Yeah. Okay, let's go on. So we going to
you know probably going to take two
hours just to finish this. Okay, let's
move on. For example, suppose the
attached document contain the following
rotation. Okay, so this is kind of your
input I suppose. Can you guys see it
actually? Yeah. So you kind of can see
it but let me move it here. Oh stupid.
Okay. So let let me let me let me think
about this. So
0 to 999
and uh you got so start at 50.
So 0 to 999 start at 50. Then you can
rotate left or right. Uh then you want
to know the number of times.
So every time you rotate there's a new
pointer, right? So you want to know know
the number of times when that pointer is
at zero. Okay. So you given this bunch
of rotations the following following
these rotations would cause the dial to
move as follows. Okay. The dial start at
point at 50. The dial is rotated L68
there. L68
then it's at 82.
Let's compute it. 50 - 68 is -8.
-18 + 100 is 82. That's correct. Okay.
Then you do L30.
Double check. L30. Okay. L30. So 82. L
is minus 82 minus 30 is 52.
Okay. Is it less than 100? Yes. Okay. Do
nothing. Then 52
do r 48 that's plus 48. 52 + 48 is 100.
100 is equal to 100. So you do modular
arithmetics. 100 divided by 100.
Wait let's see. Um
52 + 48 is 100. So 100 you want what
what uh what is the modular ariththmic
you want to divide it by 99 not 100.
Okay,
wait. Let me see. So, this is off by one
problem. I mean off by one likelihood of
uh kind of a problem, a trick. Uh so 52
+ 48 is
and uh when you got 100 what do you want
to do this here? So,
so modular arithmetic uh you you have
100 items divided by 100 is one then you
want to minus one right every time you
divide it by 100
you got
right so you want to minus one okay now
remember that so that's why you got zero
let's try again so zero L5 is -5.5
+ 100
is 95.
Okay, 95. So I think we got it. Okay, so
just remember
uh every time
you add 100 and you divide it by 100,
then you want to minus one. Is that
right? Let's see.
Yeah. M minus one because there's 0 to
99.
Uh right. So if you minus one. So
yeah, I think it's right. Okay. So
anyway, so let's go on. Let's move on.
Because the dial points at zero a total
of three times. One, two, three. During
this process, the password in this
example is three. Analyze rotation in
your attached document. What's the
actual password? Okay, so we got this
number. So let's start to code. Okay, it
should be easy. So
showing browser.
Okay,
start a wolf language pad code. Pop it
out. So you got this
uh kind of input. So now remember this
is just a sample then you have to deal
with your uh puzzle input. So let's copy
it. Select all.
Copy.
Uh let's see. Paste. Okay. So there's
got it's got 4,500
items. Okay. Let's um
let's make it one line.
So how do you want to present this? Uh
you can
in Wufam language you can leave them as
is symbols or you can turn them into a
string. Um
so let that uh so you see
Okay. So this
select or
copy. Okay. Select or paste. So 450
4,500.
So you can process them as symbols. So
process same as strings.
Let's turn them into strings because um
because strings is more universal. So
okay. So let's do them.
Okay. cut
goes um and uh
input.ext.
Okay.
AOC
day one.
Yeah, I'm too slow.
Yeah. [clears throat]
So, let's let's just make them at least.
Okay. So,
save it. Copy the file path. Close it.
Paste it. And wait.
Copy the file path. Okay. Make it
underscore.
Close it. Close it.
and do [clears throat]
paste a link there.
Open it. That's good.
So,
so let me think what to do. Okay. So,
first of all, generate a list of 1,00.
Let's just do it
easiest as possible. Let's forget about
efficiency and elegance. Okay.
range
0 to 99. Let's just generate that.
Does wam have modular types like ADA?
What does that mean modular type? Uh I
think you mean some kind of ring. Okay.
But wam language can do lot can have a
lot of way to solve this. Okay. So for
example, you got a range a list of uh 0
to 99. You can do rotate left. Okay,
rotate left. Okay, let's say uh x list
equals true. Okay, so you can run that
0 to 99. Okay, then that's output. Then
you can rotate left and the X list.
Okay, let's say two. Let's say two.
Okay, run it. It'll just rotate the
list. Uh wait, uh nonatomic nonatomic
expression. Okay, you need to evaluate
it because it doesn't know what is x
list.
Okay, so now run it. Run this.
So you see this is original and this is
the new rotated left by two. So you can
do it this way and uh the current index
is the first element two. Okay. Or you
can do uh modular arithmetics. Okay. So
you can do either one. Uh so let's see
what we So every time you get in uh
input
uh so let's make this list.
Okay. So
x input
equals to okay let's suppose that's a
list.
So yeah the easy way to do this is let's
just start to code it. Okay,
by definition it's not pointing left,
it's a pointing at zero. Still it's
confusing. Does W have modular? I would
take the file in as is. They may make
you do more with similar input later.
Uh yeah. Okay. So anyway, I I I just
want to finish this quickly because in
the past I start to you know be
efficient, be elegant, then it's like
two three hours and we still didn't
finish. [laughter]
So you know so for live stream just show
how it works because you know show the
basics of wam language. Okay. So you got
the list um
then you got this is a example of
rotation then you got the input. So what
you do is you
so every time you do this transformation
this rotation every time you do it you
want to check if the first element is
zero then you want to count. Okay. Now
there are many ways to do it but I want
to do it in a functional way. So let me
think about functional way. It's going
to be just one line. Okay. For the whole
solution.
So if you do the imperative way or
procedural way what you can do is that
you you know you do a for loop and you
do operation. You do one operation. Then
you check if zero is the first item.
If it is, you add a counter. You know,
result equals to 1 +
uh 1 + plus plus, right? Then when you
finish, you check what what is the
result. That's your answer. That's when
you do a for loop.
Um
okay. But but in
wuam language is predominantly a
functional programming okay uh
functional programming uh way. So how do
you do this functional programming way?
Okay, so you want to
do this process.
You want to do all of them. No exit.
Okay. So you can use map
then.
[sighs and gasps]
Okay. So let's go look at my wam
language tutorial. Okay. So not to do.
So let's go to Wuam language uh tutorial
and wam language in depth and let's go
to the section string comment print
string number pooling list variable
expression um conditional function loop
and iteration. Okay, create a table. So
you in this case you uh want to find
membership.
There are many ways. Okay, let me just
uh quickly show one way so that this
works.
There are many ways to code this. Um,
one says it's day eight, not day one.
What?
What
am I on day eight?
Oh, wait. This is day one. What the
you talking about?
>> [sighs]
>> Okay. So anyway, am I on day one, right?
Day one problem. Yeah.
Okay. Um, so yeah, let me just think
about this. Okay.
So you you you you got this list of
process. Um
so you got this you want to apply that
each time you want to know how many
account it happens.
B
Hold that.
Hold at least.
Yeah, I kind of know
already
one of the way. Okay.
Uh, but it's going to result lots of
memory usage data. So,
so another way, do we actually the do we
actually need this list?
Uh, I don't think we do. Do we actually
need this,
you know, a list of numbers? No,
because we can just use modular
arithmetic.
When you use modular arithmetic, how do
you know,
right? You don't need to know. You just
need to know what's the current number.
So, you do not even need to rotate
the list. You can just use modular
arithmetics.
So, if you use rotate left and right,
it's actually inefficient.
[sighs]
Uh uh okay coding is always
okay. So so then we realized we don't
need this uh list
but we need to get to work.
So if you don't use a list then
let me just quickly show how this way
works. Okay, let me just quickly show um
so let's do fold.
Let me just show you guys how it works.
Okay. Um bold
bold
list.
Okay. What what is the what is the
parameters? fold. Here's a wolf language
FX list.
So
you need a function.
Okay. Function. Um
this
so what is the first character of a
string? Do we have uh first character of
a string?
So wait. So you can do string match.
Okay. So let's just say
let's look at the documentation string
and pattern. Okay.
String and the pattern. So what is the
pattern? Uh let's use regular
expression. Okay.
Okay. regular expression is L
uh
anything okay L beginning of string okay
so if we run that it'll be true
uh false
string match regular expression
L start with L why is it force
What?
No, that's not right.
Oh god.
Ah
very annoying. So we got lots of tedious
problems. Let's look at regular
expression. Okay.
Regular expression pattern. Regular
example of regular expression. regular
expression or you can use string
expression. So regular expression
um
ignore case ignore case is true.
So this is regular expression.
Okay. So you got a pattern string
captured pattern regular expression
reference. Do we have a do I have a
reference?
Uh no. So let's look at the wam language
documentation.
I believe that that should be uh
beginning of string. So why is it not
the beginning of a string there?
So do you guys see it?
So did did we get the order incorrect
string match Q string pattern? What? Why
is this force?
God,
that's a capital L, right?
10 capital L.
So this is true.
Wait. So
run it again.
Boss.
Why is that? Oh, okay. Now I understand.
Right. So the problem is because in wam
language they this regular expression
needs to match the entire string. Okay.
So, so in this case if you put the dot
uh dot and plus that means anything
then it'll be true. It needs to match
the entire string. Okay, that's one of
the tricky part of regular expression in
any language because sometimes
if it match p part of the string then it
returns true but in some other
circumstances
the expression needs to match the entire
thing. So you see that so that is the
issue. Okay. So we we so we got that.
So,
so we uh what do you want to do if if
this uh if this returns or another way
to do it is you just say
string equal
Okay. So you want to extract string
string and give the nth character. Okay.
So for example
string part uh in fact string start
that's easier even
so we are showing several ways. So
string part one
that will return L.
Okay. Then you can say
same Q that
L. Okay, that returns true. That means
rotate left. Okay. Or another way is
string start
l.
Okay. So you can see we got several ways
to uh match your string. Okay. So cut
it.
Let me just go here. Paste it here as a
tutorial.
different ways to
check first
char. Okay,
like this would be uh good for
beginners. Okay, so different ways to
check. Now, why don't we just use that
one because
the string start because that's um
so that's what we want. So, if
string start then rotate left.
So a function rotate left X.
Okay. Then otherwise otherwise rotate
right.
[snorts]
Okay. Now the X you know you need to
extract the number. Okay. So let's write
another program to extract number.
Oh god.
So given a string like that we want to
extract the number. So
let's say two expression.
So we are showing some
wam language specific. Let's see if it
does.
So it returns a symbol. No.
Uh so we want to get the 68. Let's see.
Uh no two expression. No. Yeah. Got it.
So tedious. A little problem.
So let's now
to extract
the number inside string.
There are of course many ways. So let's
look at it.
I don't know of hand string string
length
string split
uh split a string to a list of strings.
I don't think so because um
list of patterns split a string by a
list of patterns. No. Okay. So string to
list of characters.
Okay. Not exactly what we want. String
functions substring by index. We can use
substring.
Yeah, we can use substring. Then we can
turn the string into a number. Okay,
that seems the most intuitive.
Um,
get substring by pattern. You can also
uh get substring by pattern. No string
join, string insert, convert to string,
string template, string match, string
replace. Okay, string. Okay, let's just
stream take. Okay, let's do this.
Okay,
do I make sense? Is that am I making
sense?
So, string take uh
stream take two.
Oh string take uh what what is the uh
string negative n m through n so
give characters m through n in string so
let's see
two and one
that should be 68 okay then string to
number
There's no string to number there's here
actually we need to do two expression
okay
that will give you 68
okay so for example you can minus min -
8 that will give you 60
right okay okay so
okay
Okay.
So that takes it apart. Now fold
bold takes three argument. Okay. So
x input. Okay. So the first argument is
a function. Now what does the function
do? The function will take x.
x is one of these l or r something.
Okay. So first of all
split it into uh so this is a number
part. So if string
okay so
so if string is l rotate left
rotate left but what is the least?
So the function takes two argument when
you want to do fold the function takes
two arguments. Okay.
Okay. Rotate left
Z list then uh then
okay is this clear
rotate left of this list by by this
number. Okay. Uh and this X this L68
is the X. Okay. So we can actually turn
it to X. So rotate right will be
something similar just rotate right.
Okay. So
so this is the thing
actually we can run this. Um
okay. So let's
let's uh yeah
so let me double check one more time. So
fold
fold is the fold takes three arguments.
A function. The function takes two
things.
X list and uh
wait.
So what is the fold
FX list? So begin with the list.
Ah, let's just run it. Okay. Tedious
thing. Okay. Here is the code. We paste
it. So, you can see this defines the
range, the list. This is the rotate left
example. Actually, we don't need it.
And here is the input. Then let's just
run it. See what we get.
Okay. Something is not right.
Oh, we got a comma there. So
where is this extra comma two
expression?
Okay, this is not right. That's right.
So copy that again.
select all paste run.
Okay. So,
so instead of fold, let's say fold list.
So, it shows all results.
Okay. Not that's not right. So, what is
it return though?
Uh oh, we got this wrong again.
Select or copy or paste. Shift enter.
Uh
okay. Incorrect.
What do all the Q means? So in Wam
language when a function ends with a
capital Q that means the function either
returns true or false. Okay that's it.
So such function is called predicate. So
in emac this for example by convention
it's lowerase p. So a function ends in
lowerase p.
It means it always return either true or
false. In the case of lisp it returns t
or neo but in eac lisp is not
consistent. There are some functions
ends in P but but it's not uh predicate.
So but anyway in Wuen language it's just
capital Q stand for question always
return true or false. Okay.
Uh there is from digits. What does f do?
Uh fold is just reduce. Okay. Fold is
like um
fold is like JavaScript reduce or
Python's reduce. Python reduce. they
removed in Python 2. You have to load a
library in Python 3.
Okay, let me just finish this. This is
getting tedious and we are not doing it
correctly.
Uh God.
So
God. So let's say
okay we actually these two got reversed.
Let me explain uh later. Okay let me
just do this first. Let me explain
later.
So this imp waits.
So this actually input should be there
and uh this should be empty. Okay.
So this is input
and uh the beginning.
Okay. So this is not good.
Uh what does fold do? Fold is just
reduce. Okay, let me show you both these
F.
Okay. One,
one, two, three.
If you run it,
it's going to this is the result. Okay.
Um,
so it's just reduce.
Um
right. So
so one way is to use fold but we are
getting
God.
[sighs]
Okay. I really actually I need to think
about this instead of just
typing stuff.
Uh okay, let me think about this.
So the input the input is this bunch of
L right L R LR. So every time you feed
one input so this is the input. So this
should be input list.
Uh so you go through these operations.
Okay. Then then the function um
the first argument is a function
and uh
wait. So, where do you get where but
where do you get the uh
That's
So you got rotate left and rotate right.
So this rotate left.
So but where do you get the initial? How
do you get the initial Z list?
Um,
so the function takes two arguments.
So the first argument the function takes
two arguments.
Oh remember to start at 50
sh.
So rotate this. Can we can we do a start
50? So actually
50 uh
50.
So that's that's that's kind of um
that's that. Okay.
So I'm not very happy because
this trivial thing I got stuck.
So I need to think about this. Okay. So
so bold takes two thing at a time. The
function. So here is a function there
and here is the input.
The input is a sequence of operations.
So every time the function
gets operation but there's but the um so
the function takes two things.
Oh god.
Function takes two things. The function
the function has um
this is very bad. So let me just look up
string tank. So regular expressions.
So iteration
so every time you do this step it
depends on the previous state. So every
time you save a state. So what is the
initial um
what my current problem is that is that
how do I get the initial
list
Or you can use recursion.
Let's see.
>> [snorts]
>> Fold
takes this bunch of steps.
Yeah. So this is very bad. Or do we use
nest
I do think it's must be imperative. No,
I don't think so. Okay. I think there's
a I'm stuck somewhere.
Uh that's what we are doing. We are
computing. But let me let me just get
this to work. Okay. So um
let me just get this to work.
So the function takes two arguments.
One is the current state. The second
argument is the operation.
So the current state. So operation.
So the current state you need to add uh
wait
this is not right because you are not
getting the current state. It's
something simple I'm missing. Okay. So
select all paste
return. Yeah. So I'm missing you know
there's something simple I'm missing
string or list of string expected
position of string start.
Okay. So something simple I'm missing.
So
oh yeah so this is n
this is actually this is
x operation. Okay.
So
that
so the function takes two arguments.
Okay. So,
so this X is that.
Okay, now it's better, but it's still
not correct.
Uh, because we still have the problem.
Oh, that's right. All we have to do is
to add
right we need to add the initial state
here. So something like this. Okay.
Yeah. So I know I know what to do. Okay.
So wait a second. Hold on a second. So
yeah we will write in the beginning we
need put X
list there. Okay. Something very simple.
So let's try a select all paste it.
Shift enter.
Okay, it's better. But something is
wrong. Okay,
so what is the problem? String start no
l. So we got a new somewhere.
So the function
So that's a function
and uh
starting with x list.
What?
>> [sighs]
>> That's right. So, what is the problem
here?
So,
select all paste shift enter. Oh, you
got the extra comma there. You see red?
So, that is why. So there it is.
That is got extra comma. Okay. Now
select all again. Copy. Select all.
Paste. Shift enter.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
So this is the final result. But however
we want to we want a list of all steps.
So we use instead of fold we use fold
list. Okay. So, so this here is just
example. Let me put it back. Let me uh
for educational purposes. Okay. This is
how bold works.
Uh so for example this list uh let me
just this this is what confused us
before. So ABC
for example ABC
run it.
Okay. So that's the result. So let's
uh let's
indent it so it's uh easy to understand.
Okay. So this is how bold list works.
Now fold just return the last item.
Okay. So for example, let me do it
again.
Okay, that's fold
for list just return all steps make make
them into a list. So similarly
bold
returns that which is just the last
item. If you do fold list it returns all
intermediate steps. Again fold is just
like reduce
JavaScript and Python. Okay. So now put
it back syntax color show in browser. So
we explained string match same and
string start and we explain fold. And
now our code.
Now our code this works. So let's do it
again. copy all select all paste shift
enter. So it returns a all intermediate
steps. So now we just want count in this
big nested list how many of them
start with zero in front. Okay. So you
can see there's one zero.
Go down there is two zero. Go down there
is third zero. Okay. So we just now we
want to count.
Uh so this is a result. So
result
equals true. Now let's count. How do you
do count? So far so good. Answer my
question without seeing uh them. Good
intuation.
Yeah. Show or state. That's right.
Uh can you do the f to the f list? Yeah.
So okay. So now let's uh just we just
all we have to do is count. So let's see
wam language count. Okay. So wam
language recursion. Now let's um hold on
a second. Let's copy show in browser
today's talk show and let's copy all the
things we talked about. So recursion
uh and make a link so later on people
can easily
better see what we've been up to. So in
regular expression
paste it there and uh get s substring
by index
paste there.
Okay. and uh close and uh then
and then then we need to go to wuam
language tutorial again. Now we want to
count of a list. Okay, so let's go to
the list section list and introduction
to list and then we got list position
nested list this level list operations.
Okay, we want some kind of count.
So, get parts, add elements, delete
elements, change elements, check
existence, join, union, intersection,
difference, minimal, maximum, filter,
sort, flatten, rifle, rotate, left,
padding, list, partition, reshape,
split, gather, transpose,
iterations, scan, uh, fold, loop. So,
where's the count? [laughter]
Count. Okay. So, count or tally.
So,
so where would that be? List minimum
maximum. No. Create. Get. So, count
uh check existence. Okay. Maybe that's a
check existence member Q count. Okay,
there. So count
expression and pattern. So count count
by pattern. Okay, so let me let me do
that. So uh today's talk show search
pre.
Okay. So let's uh do a example. So let's
count
uh
okay count at least let's say 0
1 988 okay by a pattern now what pattern
pattern would be that
anything
uh dot dot okay I think that would
return true
uh Wait. So, so
count a big list. This is one of them.
This is two of them. Let's say start
with seven.
And let's say another one
start with 88. So, we got a list of
three elements and count by this
pattern. It
syntax invalid. Okay. So this is not a
valid pattern. So now we need to go
check pattern pattern matching count
level spec. Um
yeah so we need to check pattern. So
let's go to the pattern.
Uh yeah zero. This should be uh zero
zero [cough]
means zero or more. Okay, I think that
like that. Delete that. Run it.
It returns one. That's correct. Now,
let's try again. Now, let's put one more
here. Let's say three. Okay. Now, it'll
return two.
Corre correct. Okay. So this is an
example of count
and uh if you don't know you click on
pattern you can see all the pattern
syntax. So we are using
three low lines. So three low lines
means zero or more. So you can see uh
let's see literal expression pattern any
expression pattern which is one low
line. Uh then you got blank H means any
expression but with a head edge. Okay.
Then you got a pattern uh named pattern.
So given a pattern you can name it so
that when you do replace when it matches
you want to do some replacement you can
refer to the name just like regular
expression. Okay. So then sequence of
one or more expression that's that's
double low line. Okay. The full syntax
name is blank sequence. Okay. Now
sequence of zero or more expression
that's triple low line. The full name is
blank new sequence. Okay. So we are
using here triple low line that means so
we got the list
then it's zero or more you know we just
care we only care if the first one is
zero. Okay so that's how count works.
Syntax color showing browser. Uh so we
got the count example. Okay. We got some
something extra there. Let's remove
put it back syntax color. Now go to our
code.
Now you just want to count this result.
Okay. So count
uh count. Yeah.
Count this result and pattern is zero
followed by zero or more expression.
Okay. So select all.
Select all. Paste it. Shift enter.
So three. The answer is correct.
Finally. Okay. This is kind of
inefficient but quick very fast. You
know this got just three lines.
Okay. So
result is three. That's correct. Now we
need to um do our uh our user input um
you know our
let's do this again. So but now we got
our code uh input.
Let's see day one input. Okay. Open it.
Select all, close it,
and uh then go jump out to our code.
Then um
then the input is this. Okay,
put a semicolon. So it suppress the
output so it doesn't print a bunch of
thing. Okay, so they delete that.
Okay. And uh this this original list we
don't need. Put a semicolon. Okay. So
this is the input list. I mean this is
the the lock 0 to 99.
Here is the input.
And next
and next result. And we can run the
whole thing. Okay. Copy it. Go to wuam
language. Select or paste.
Shift enter.
1135.
Is that correct? Let's check. I'm pretty
sure it's correct. So, let's go to the
advent of code.
Paste 135. Submit.
That's the right answer. You are one
gold star closer to decorating the North
Pole. Okay. So,
oh my god, that's horrible. Sorry, I got
a code.
So, so we finished this. [clears throat]
Answer my Yeah. So, we finished this.
How long have they been? One hour
exactly.
Oh, 90 minutes, actually.
So we finished coding this um in kind of
the the most intuitive way. We didn't
even use modular arithmetics.
We could
you know but the actual when you start
code it might take an hour but in
principle it should be just five minutes
because when you use modular arithmetics
you don't need to keep this list of 0 to
999 and also our our approach is very
inefficient because we generated
the entire list you know this this 4,000
4,000 times. So we have a list of 4,000
to99.
So it's, you know, it's uh very
inefficient, but it's it's the actually
the most intuitive.
Um should I
optimize it? No, because I realized the
advent code is, you know, they don't
care, you know.
So I think that's it for today. Then
there's part two. Let's let's do it some
other day. Okay.
Any more questions.
Well, part one. Do you think you could
explain how it works? I think I
understand, but but functional isn't my
my uh native.
So, well, I mean, okay. So, let let me
let me try. Okay. So, you generate a
list from 0 to 99, right? and you rotate
it so that 50 is in the front. That part
is clear, right? Then you got a list of
input. This are rotate left, rotate
right, you know, a list of operations,
right? So one is
x list and the input is x input. Okay?
So you got two things there. Then what
you do is you use the fold operation.
Okay.
So fold.
So so so
this fold
takes three arguments. The first one is
the function. What do you want to do?
The second argument is the original
input list 0 to 99 starting at 50. Okay.
Then the third argument is the input is
this is this operations.
So
fold let's refresh. So fold you should
understand what fold does is right here.
It's also in JavaScript and also in
Python. So if you don't know about
functional programming you should master
fold also known as reduce.
uh there's a lot of tutorials
because it's also in Python and
JavaScript. Okay, that uh fold is one of
the it's a fundamental
general purpose way to do any loop. So
in other words any loop whatsoever
however complicated imperative loop for
loop you can write it using fold also
known as reduce. Okay. And that's what
we did. So fold you know the in the
simplest form
you know you give a function the
function will takes two arguments and
each time it takes one thing from the
list
then return a result then the function
will feed that result as the first
argument then take another thing from
the from the list of input. So in a
sense it's keeping a state. So the
function every time return a state the
state of the loop then take a new input
from the from the you know list
then it returns another new state the
state is fed to the function as first
argument then it takes another item from
the loop you know specific input in the
loop. So every time it just
take the previous state and take another
new input returns a new state then the
function take that state again and take
the new argument. Okay so that's
essentially fold or reduce
and in warm language spe it has
something extra it has something called
fold list. So instead of just returning
final result, it returns all
intermediate steps. So every time a
function takes a state, it returns it
adds its one element in the list. Then
take the state and take another new item
return a thing which is a state that's a
new item in the list. So f list is just
like the history of the fold. Okay. So
here's theam another example with the
initial value you know so so if you are
not familiar with fold or reduce you
should spend time okay now if you
understand fold then then our problem
becomes easy to understand
so we are using a fold list so that
returns um
all steps okay and and okay so God, this
you know th this slows down um this long
line slows slows down Emacs
very very much. So let's let's make it
Yeah, this way is much faster because
otherwise when when Emacs has a long
line every time you move cursor it takes
a second. So now it's much better. Okay.
So anyway, so
so I'm just returning um all steps then.
So it's a huge list. Each element
of the list is one of the 0 to 999.
Okay. So you can see
so okay so it returns this huge list.
So four 4,500
of them. So this is the first element in
a list. So you can see this is how we
start 50 51 something. Then show more.
Let's show more second element in a list
after one of the rotation operations. So
it's this one.
And uh so are you still here? Do you get
what I'm saying?
So then another step. So you know there
are 4,500
items.
So once you got this huge list then you
just you want to count them which one of
them start with zero.
Yeah. So that's um so you got 1,35.
Okay.
And this is not efficient but and but
you know we get the things done.
Okay. So this this count is another
interesting thing in wolf language. It
uses pattern matching. So again it's not
procedural. When you do procedural you
do a for loop. You know you do a for
loop on each you know then take the
first element. Check if the first
element is equals to one. If it is you
increment a counter you know uh counter
plus.
Then at the end the counter is 1 1335.
Right? So but in functional programming
you you just have this single function
count result and and use a pattern. The
pattern is whatever list starting with
zero and followed by zero or more items.
So there are three of them. Okay. Thank
you guys for watching.
Uh thank you guys. So if you like my
stuff, go to kasali.info.
Okay, I'll talk to kasali code.info
http nos and you go to the bottom, you
go to lots of stuff. You go to the
bottom, you can Patreon me, PayPal me,
Amazon gift card me. Okay, thank you
guys. Bye guys.
go over the function. Well, the function
are you are you late because we I mean
we went over the function.
So the function is just this this
function. Okay, if you take it apart it
becomes easy. So the function the first
of all is got two arguments. The
function takes two arguments. So I name
them list and I name them operation.
Okay. So the function so this is like a
lambda in in this or in Python this is a
lambda okay it takes this is a function
of two arguments okay now then is simply
a if statement
if
string begin with l you know the string
the x operation is a string right it's
one of the l or r so if it begin with L
then you do this line. You rotate
left of the list which is the previous
state. Remember you see
uh you see that's a list and that's the
operation you see. So if it's beginning
with L then you rotate left. Then how
many times two expression string takes
operation from second to last which is
what you get is a number. So you just
rotate left that number of times. So if
it's L if it's not L then you do rotate
right exact exactly the same thing. So
the function each time just you know if
the input is L22 it just rotate left 22
times. So it's very simple.
Okay. Bye guys.