good morning guys welcome to another
episode of castle talk show today
September 29th 2019 Sunday
and so what's up guys what's the topic
today let me go to the let me set up
2019 September 29th so September there
are 30 days in September and welcome to
another episode of saw life's scream
so let me get the live YouTube set up
there we are so George says come Oni
George George says George says I'm
surprised I didn't find a page on your
website about Ted Nelson Xanadu now he
is a guy who invented kind of the HTML
like the before HTML something like that
let's see if I'm alive yes yes right
am I correct so Bartholomew says 13
critique of OSS cloud solutions critique
about OSS cloud solutions what does OSS
stand for I don't think I know much
about that topic I the only thing I know
is I don't want crowd okay no crowd no
crowd no nothing sabatham you know
George Sanne do Sanne do ho
okay let's you know Sanne do Sanne do is
like a tient topic you know I know that
in in 1990s of not that Sanne do is a
film but it's let's see what what is the
Xanadu and Ted Nelson yeah you need to
type the name Ted Nelson so I think you
know projects on ado yeah that let's see
what that is say okay projects on ado
was the first hypertext project yes
founded in 1960 by Ted Nelson
administrators that projects honor to
have declared it an improvement over the
world wide web which mission statement
today's popular software simulates paper
the World Wide Web
another imitation on paper
realises our original hypertext model
with only one way ever breaking links
and no management of versions of content
yeah I read about it but I don't know
much about it it's like mystery you know
this is history when you are not there
it's like total mystery to you so this
is 1960s I didn't get I didn't start to
use a computer until 1989 and 1991 is my
first computer so and I did study a lot
Computer History mostly AI and Lisp so
back to 1980s basically and I don't even
I mean the history is such that if you
are not around there it's very hard to
for you to get any sense of it you know
so so for example today if you guys
don't know so eras
UNIX systems you would not you know oh
this you know you would not know well
it's like Linux okay but you don't get
the idea
you know what's it's like in 1990s the
Perot days and so on and similarly you
know I began in 1990s but I've read
about operating systems you know this
machine's several things I read about it
but you can't really know much until you
know you have to unless you are
dedicated to studying that subject for
example let me show you
history keyboard history so you see many
of these old terminals and teletype
machines cells keyboard for example sale
keyboard cell stand for Stanford AI lab
and see sale stand for something
computer something okay hold on a second
let me close my door my roommates
so anyway this machine keyboard you know
this is back in these days so this this
this keyboard is this keyboard runs on
pdp-10 19 okay this this keyboard is
basic basically invented by john
mccarthy the same guy who invented lisp
so is there is a lot interesting history
about that about this machine
keyboarding i did a video on this
machine keyboard so anyway this is the
Grand Daddy of lys machine keyboards
okay this is even before before the very
famous
space-cadet keyboard you see you can
read about them but you don't know much
you know what what is really like what
is pdp-11 computers are like how do you
you know use it you know so so yeah I
heard about Xanadu but I'd you know I'd
read about it but it doesn't doesn't
make any sense
so who asked that George you know
typically this is kind of the thing that
the hacker community and this was they
sometimes they mentioned you know like
when I was in comp comp dot land our
Lisp new scoops like you know today
today's people they don't know what the
[ __ ] is new scoops and and sometimes I
run into like someone on YouTube okay
someone on YouTube mentioned mentioned
mentioned me you know mentioned one of
my website page I forgot what age
network anthropology I think net Turk
quote
anthropology okay let me show you that
page good morning
who can sue so I have this page as I
think there's a girl okay a woman on
YouTube she she did a YouTube and she
mentioned one of my page I think it's a
male there's a very popular page the Mia
was okay let me show you
Mia was is supposed to be the greatest
flame war on the in a history of
Internet okay I don't know nothing about
it but I happened to you know read this
story and I you know me wrote on my
website from another website that's long
time gone so here is a miaow story that
one true history of meow is supposed to
be the biggest frame war and the army of
trolls this is in 1980s I think on this
new scoop ode fan car maiden knows you
know anyway it's a very interesting
story about trolling and flame war back
in 1980s I think so so so there is is
this girl who did a YouTube I think she
mentioned this article I found it and
you know then she tried to describe what
user net is you know she didn't know you
know she is young right
so she didn't know what use used you
know you scoop so you know uses Usenet
is so she tries to describe it then
she's it's it's very very funny to hear
how she says it
you know she says oh it's like it's it's
I think it's kind of like a reddit forum
and so on so yeah so if you are not
there it's hard to understand history
okay so let me read the comments and so
hank saw and
chant hexane chat Kimani Matt and George
says so George I don't think you are
very old right I think maybe you are
20-something or 30 something I forgot
how if you ever mentioned that come on
interesting morning Quinn tech to Russia
Justine in Canada good morning George in
Sydney Australia
no not Sydney Perth good morning Pablo
in Spain so let's see so I'm gonna do
critique of OSS cloud solutions yeah
what is OSS o open software open-source
software cloud solutions what to say
about that you know you don't want crowd
you know if I'm gonna talk about that
I'm gonna it's gonna be a giant brand
giant vent again it's open source again
you know because open source you have
open source that means people cannot
make money even though you know
technically according to the you know to
the Bible of open source yes you
supposed to be able to make money
it's just that in it needs to be open
source you know or the free software
free speech you know versus free be free
beer you know supposedly you can you
know you can sell your software you can
make money by edit you know by the way
did you know that Richard Stallman used
to sell Emacs like you know you send me
money I send you a copy of Emacs he's
doing that and it's allowed you know by
he's a coding he's free software you
know ideology but the fact is you know
that's you you cannot make money you
know that's just a lie you know like I
mentioned before the moment Linux is not
free as in free beer the entire open
source of free software foundation we
all die within you know within like few
months you know disappear the concept we
are entirely disappear the moment the
moment that that you charge you know
let's say $10 for Emacs or you know $50
for Linux you
entirely die but the open source
phonetics they don't you know they don't
you know it's it's like we when you are
in your coat or when you are in a
political party you don't see you don't
see it
for example the open source phonetics
they are you know when it comes to you
know economics when you talk about
economics or sentence things like that
they all say oh yeah but you can make
money it's allowed you know it's you
know you can make money but in reality
you can because it's open source other
people will just copy it you know copy
it sell cheaper and and and another guy
will just copy or sale cheaper you
cannot make money that is why they went
to the crowd because crowd is as a
service you know so that's why they they
take your data or you know put your data
in other people's computer it's not your
computer so in my in my view open-source
kind of helped helped the the rise of
the cloud okay I'm going to start to get
into a giant huge rant about open source
so let's not go there you know I did
this many times so bartholomew says you
always say you think crowd open source
solutions are stupid yes well it's not
stupid okay it's like this crowd crowd
is kind of a in effort ability okay
because when society you know we are
progressing you know people want the
communion convenience such as for
example let's talk about credit card
credit card whole payment systems that's
one example you know in sci-fi you know
Arnold Schwarzenegger movies you know in
sci-fi query in the future you go to
Mars or whatever it you don't use paper
money anymore or you don't you don't
write checks right that's kind of stupid
I mean as technology progress is
progress is obviously it's all digital
so so credit card is the father of that
you know in a sense credit card you know
you just swipe a card you don't carry
cash because you carry cash
you know people will rob you things like
that it's got problems so he's so
digital because it's convenient so cloud
in the same way crowd you know your
phone you know you you stole you know
you you store your photos or whatever
information on the crowd and you can you
know you can access it at work at home
or if you travel you know that's kind of
in a sense that's inevitable because
it's convenience you know that's what
technology does it brings convenience to
you so cloud is kind of inevitable but
however it is the open source ideology
okay
the open source and free software of
fanatism that that give a big hand
a giant huge help to the rise of the
open source I mean a crowd okay because
with open source you cannot make money
like everyone you know has the ideology
if you make anything not open-source
they they will heat they will punch you
like many of you
you know opens those phonetics [ __ ]
where they will punch the day or two or
everything they can to to destroy you
you know like me you know they call you
a troll they ban you you know things
like that when whenever you have any
opinion that's not you know open source
this is like politics you know people
and a lot of people they are young
people they don't know you know they
just think oh open source is grateful
you know help help humanity you know
share you know like communism okay and
today you have social justice okay it's
like that a lot young people you you
cannot you know it's almost like you
can't you are helpless because they are
huge and and then there's evil
corporations those powerful they they
they indoctrinate people you know things
like that you know so so yeah so I I
would blame you know love it a lot of it
you know so I'm saying that open source
and free software foundation they
they helped the they quickened the rise
of the crowd okay
not just that they made it evil because
of you see open source and free software
foundation the I the idea the concept is
not bad okay it's great that we share
okay but it becomes bad when it becomes
a ideology where when you have any
opinions that's not like that people
don't like you you know it's it's become
like that so I'm not you know III I
rendered about almond sauce in so many
of my videos so let's not do that today
it only makes sense that people running
a service not the customer you know so
crowd I'm saying is kind of inevitable
okay so so what so you know so I'm
saying in my point of view crowd is
somehow somewhat inevitable and I'm
saying that open source it is the open
source and free software fanaticism okay
remember it's important for net ISM if
there is no fanaticism
then it's good because you know this
this kind of things there's no like we
don't know the answer we don't know
should you know commercialization
proprietary software is that system
better or is it open source way that we
don't actually there is no one answer to
that to the whole society because it's
very complex so you be it's it would be
great that you know some people advocate
you know some people some sees some part
of the world or some you know some it
would be great that they coexist okay
but so but what I'm saying is that the
open source and free software foundation
maybe they has become a ideology you
know like brainless ideology you know
people just chant chant it and follow it
that kind of like us the word democracy
you know like for example you know I
know
most of you guys are not again is the so
show justice right and many the newest
medias are run by social justice people
you know American left so for example
let's go to Washington Washington Post
okay we go to Washington Post Washington
Post is one of the major publications
now you you see that you see that you
see that it says democracy ties in
darkness why do they say that of course
they are saying that they are directing
that at Trump the current president
president of USA and two most of you I
know you don't like it because you it's
totally just it's just a lie it's just a
lie you know a [ __ ] subscription I
want to go back you cannot even go back
you see how I'll have the [ __ ] this
this you cannot even go back like I
quick go back it refused to let you go
back your [ __ ] [ __ ] open source and as I
mentioned before in my other videos the
software the the social justice today is
in part because of open source you know
because of the the the basic the
fundamental idea is the help you know
the obsession about helping you know you
just need to help you know like share
and help help others this this this has
become twisted you know so anyway you
see you see that democracy ties in
darkness half American half of American
people will not agree
you know what the [ __ ] what what do you
mean basically they are meaning you know
as I do what they mean is that they
don't Trump you know we we voted Trump
as president that's democracy but they
are saying democracy dies in darkness
you know and same thing with New York
Times the number one publication in USA
and around the world you know that's
that's
that's no good so so why am i mentioning
this because I'm saying you know it's
like like the word democracy it becomes
a chant you people don't know what it
means anymore you can just say you can
simply say democracy dies in darkness
when you don't like the current
president you know so in the same same
way I'm saying this is happening you
know the democracy becomes say you know
just chant what it lost meaning same
thing with open source and free software
you know foundation people don't know
you know this massive number of
phonetics young people they don't know
what it means like you know but they
just know it's good they must you know
they must have open source and free
software green deck says how does it
connect to Trump
yeah well green deck you are in Russia
so you don't know well that's my guess
because in u.s. politics you have the
you know the Democratic Party okay the
so-called Democratic Party that's left
us a left then you have the right wing
which is Republican Party okay and they
are fighting the you know they are
fighting becomes worse and worse so that
so basically an questioned term post is
a Washington Post most of the major news
media are learned by by the leftist by
the Democratic Party okay in USA in USA
so Washington Post New York Times you
know so they say why do they say
democracy dies in darkness because they
are it's kind of it's there because they
want to they mean they mean Trump you
know they don't they hate Trump they
think Trump is a hitter you know so so
they just put that phrase there you know
we USA we know what it means you know a
lot of people so that's what it means
and and you know you are in Russia all
right let me ask you have you heard that
you know USA
if you heard you know everyday the
leftist okay like the Washington Post
everyday they are saying
Russian Russian is meddling with us a
Russian elected Trump yeah they say you
guys you know poutine
you guys in infield traded you know they
you guys the Russian made American made
Trump the president you know that's sort
of what they are saying you know today
every everywhere I don't know if you
heard of that you know or not you know
so let us know what you think okay so
you don't know yeah so anyway so so let
me check the comments George George II
31 okay we like to hear rents okay yeah
I did too many of that a lot I choose
number 10 how compiler works Hawking sue
Soho can sue to about three days ago
saw talk show saw talk show three days
ago
how compiler works so this is September
24th I did a video on that and they went
it's pretty bad because I wasn't able to
give a good tutorial yeah Justin says I
contribute to open source but I don't
expect ever to make a penny yeah George
says I found out today Richard Stallman
is still in charge of the new project no
longer know I think he I read yesterday
he says no he's no longer in charge of
the green project because he just posted
in his blog that he's effective
immediately he is no longer you know
he's out of the new project store
Richard Stallman okay Richard Stallman
blog okay let's see yeah he said that
Richard Stallman personal page it's such
fun oh and you see wait where okay
somewhere here I just read today oh yeah
Oh yesterday you have to go to Pollock
political notes okay
magnify magnify search for know
anyway where is it
I don't know I I think I'm pretty sure I
read it like today or yesterday Tami
well 10 hours ago 20 hours ago he says
that he is no longer running as well so
he is no longer associated with MIT he
is no longer the president Free Software
Foundation and he is no longer running
no the head of new it's somewhere here
he is you know he is just out of touch
everything huh I would say including
politics he's just he's just completed
he he become like I showed you this
article I showed this in my video before
I talked about it
I think actually I talked about
yesterday even he's looking for a room
so there is this magazine okay
this magazine I mean this article
studies what happens to commune what
happens to commune gulps okay hold on a
second why utopian communities fail now
utopian you know there are several
utopian communities who are thinking you
know in this community we will not have
hierarchy you know everyone is equal
everyone makes exactly the same about
amount of money everyone there's no
leader okay
nobody is you know higher than others
you know there are communities like that
you know for example hippies some some
of the hippies groups and in such
communities typically you have a leader
you know and and many of these
communities believes in green you know
no factories they believe they grow
their own stuff you know things like
that
and this this guy you know Yvonne
Morrison go study these scoops you know
visit them see what actually happens
it's pretty the picture doesn't look
very good you know it's pretty bad so
typically in this utopian communities
you have a leader you know the founder
just like Richard Stallman actually
Richard Stallman is exactly one of such
people you know and typically he is the
one who makes all the money he makes the
most like you know however because in
such communities you cannot talk about
money like you cannot talk about oh I
work harder so I make more than
you you cannot talk about that because
everyone is equal
you know you know the equal outcome the
idea of equal outcome like today's
social justice so you cannot talk about
that but however you created a lot
problems so the problems become such
becomes like basically a struggle you
know political struggle like what can I
do so that I kick you out or you know I
get more than you things like that
except the the the the leader you know
like Richard Stallman so Richard
Stallman you know he you know for the
past 20 years he just sit there he just
preached his ideology and he makes money
you know he don't have to worry about a
living not like you or me you know I
make you know I do open source I get mom
no money and I tie okay but he is
different because he don't have to worry
about that he don't even have any been
coding for at least 10 years I would say
probably 20 years he he he have not
coded you know he don't know it I mean
he's asking yeah I talked about this a
few times you know he like completely
out of loop he don't know what coding is
like you know even ten years ago he
haven't coded but but however he's
giving opinions you know so anyway in
the past 20 years you know he just seen
the songs of free software go around
preach you know give lectures and and
also you know let me show you my you
know you you go so I I wrote this
summary of what happened about Richard
Stallman resigned from free software
foundation you know I and here is
another article
Richard Stallman speech requirement okay
two articles on my Emacs website so this
article I summarize what happens Richard
Stallman resigned from free software
foundation 2019 September 16th okay so
this collection of what happens what
happened in screenshots and who are
trying to kick him out and you know all
the the document the screenshot as a
record you know what Richard Stallman
said he said he resigned and things like
that and after resign what did what did
Red Hat says you know what did Steven
Levy says you know Steven Levy is a
[ __ ] he so he's a sold out he is a
he is a kind of a tech journalist for a
long time you know since 1980s he write
you know I read so I read a lot of list
history oh you know software history in
the 1980s from him you know he's one of
the old journalists and now he just
showed up Thomas spoon shel he is a guy
who wrote new heard the operating system
he you know he began it for for like 10
years in 1990s then he got kicked out by
Richard Stallman and he so he also wrote
a commentary about about you know which
was some and being kicked out you know
so he's I don't think he's good so
anyway so I have this collection of
articles and who support him it's here
so anyway that's one article then in a
process in my so-called research I also
found this article this is the title is
Richard Stallman's speech requirement
you know since around 1998 when the open
source become popular be due to do to
Linux Apache and Perl okay due to these
three most
when opens and and also Netscape Nest
Netscape is the first one that released
browser the commercial entity that
released their software as open source
okay so so in this article you this is
written by Richard Stallman
it's very long it's like seven thousand
words
okay seven thousand words this article
he describes his requirement like if you
want him to give a speech he discussed
you know what you need to do like like
what you know like the process seven
thousand words and the cursor to the
bottom of Nalco he becomes crazier and
crazier you know so it turns out you
know when he's giving a talk of course
you have to pay him at least you have to
pay the airplane tickets the hotel
whenever the travel fees you know and
also you don't pay you know he
specifically request that you don't pay
you don't pay to the free software
foundation okay
you pay you write them you know you pay
him Richard Stallman directly so I read
this yeah and then I then I realized
that's kind of nasty you know that's
kind of nasty that's how he makes some
money you know so he's you know so he
becomes like we were talking about this
we were talking about this where's the
article we were talking about let me go
to the Holika okay utopian communities
okay we were talking about this article
where this you have these coat like
communities and typically always almost
always they have one founder one leader
you know one the top guy other than him
everyone everyone else is supposed to be
well it's supposed to be everyone is
equal but actually not so you get you
got these spots you know usually who
lives in comfort and everyone just spout
to him
like today we have it this situation
today like everyone you know you you you
talk to people on reddit or you you'll
see people oh oh these are so many so
god you know they will like every time
you have some negative opinions then you
will have like an army of people
defending Richard Stallman typically
young people they don't know like they
don't know oh they know he said Oh
Richard Stallman is a guy you know it's
like a legend okay we just did we did we
got a God you know he's a god you cannot
attack him you are wrong you know
because yeah so that's what ideology
means you know ideology that's that's
what it means you have this you know you
have these cool people like communism
you know all the people believe it so
Richard Stallman you know he gave a talk
you know it's nasty you know he give
talks and he you know the it's not you
know he big request
you know he he make it him he he he made
it in writing that you pay him not the
free software foundation you know that's
kind of nasty okay so that's you know
you so you learn how that's how he make
money you know and you know and the the
it's like that because he's this God
kind of thing you know creature so
anyway that's about that anything else
at you know put comments to me okay and
I can adjust it so green deck from
Russia says we laugh we laugh at it most
of the time but we definitely like Trump
more okay that's about you know Russian
collusion
you know Russian elected Trump okay so
let's see what else let's see how long
I've been talking 37 minutes 10 people
watching okay
so if you have questions put it to me
okay
yeah I don't think Regis DOMA is in
charge of new you know check check check
his blog because I'm pretty sure I read
it yeah I I just can't cannot find it
right now on his on his blog somewhere
ok somewhere here you will see you
so anyway so Matt says so do people
really base their decisions on using new
software on IMS and the recent
happenings yeah
yes Pablo says the messages were retired
today already
so Justine says probably we allowed to
eat lean on Simeon until you saw his
work yeah that's the easiest room
shrimp derangement syndrome yeah that's
that's what we like to call the the us
the right-wing like to call you know
that left people the common well a few
days ago but not anymore
so the comments were very suspicious
because they were repeated over several
days without change Oh
so Pablo says Pablo says so Richard
Stallman is still head of new I mean
co-leading a group project it I got I
got a tip from male cat you know one of
my follow a friend who says that Richard
Stallman website has been hacked but I I
didn't find any evidence possibly
because by the time I checked it's
already fixed so Matt says it might be
unsafe to bring up this topic but what's
your thoughts on the whole climate
climate change
oh yeah crime climate change I don't
really know much details about that I
got yeah let me tell you so what I you
know my experience about that my
thoughts so you know I'm I I came to USA
in 1989 arrived in California okay from
Montreal so I was in Montreal and
Vancouver I was in Vancouver for half a
year and but most of the time in
Montreal Canada so this is between 1986
to 1989 okay so I lived in Canada for
like three years mostly Montreal I was
about 16 around 16 to 19 in Montreal
so I came to USA in 1989 in California
and since then I basically all my life
now I'm 50 so for the past 30 years 40
years one-third thirty
I lived in California now California is
a very left
Lefty's state you know the Democrat
Party you know or basically it's a very
progressive you know the Democratic
granting party so so oh my adult life so
basically I'm exposed to all the
democratic views and basically I'm
mostly I'm almost you can say poor
democratic you know I'm I'm in crime my
views are inclined towards the left for
example things like green okay green
planet we global warming we need to fix
you know we want green we don't want
pollution we want to recycle I'm so much
heat to recycle you know it's is
fanatics so I believe I believed all
that you know recycle and for freedom of
women you know feminism and for equality
all that you know it's you know all my
life but but it began you see it I
change I changed in beginning in 2016
when the social justice scan when they
rose and in you know the the the
Democratic Party of American Left they
they changed entirely around 2016 okay
they started to have things like you
know safe space and all kind of you know
this is LGBTQ and all kind of weird
stuff and they started to they did you
know they just lie and they beat people
you know things like that so they are
entirely different today so anyway so
what about climate change so all these
years you know basically almost thirty
years before I believe in global you
know I believe in green planet so I'm
very much for I'm very much for solar
panels you know the renewable energy
system and also and also I'm not a
religious person I don't believe in God
so you know back in 1990s and throughout
USA is mostly ruled by its heavily
a God believing country you know like in
god we trust' any money if I can show
you a coin yeah let me show you a u.s.
coin
so here is one dollar bill and can you
see in god we trust'
right here in god we trust' okay and
here is a quarter let's see you get old
you cannot see there is also in god we
trust' i don't know if you can see it
but yeah this camera this logitech
camera is very bad you cannot see it so
anyway so I'm not you know I'm not
Christian or Catholic I'm not a god
believer so I don't believe you know I'm
pretty much a agnostic so I don't
believe me region so these kind of
things very annoys me you know these
kind of things and and so basically what
what I'm trying to say I'm trying to
tell you all my life I'm rather inclined
towards the left ideas you know the
Democratic Party I'm not I'm rather I'm
also a libertarian I believe individual
freedom the most okay I want freedom for
each person I want small government okay
and most of the time through our 1990s
and year 2000 you know up to 2010 owed
so us you know the the American left the
Democratic Party is compatible with
libertarianism you know individual
freedom we don't want big governments we
don't want war you know we don't want
war but now it's so entirely changed
okay so so what I'm saying you know back
to the climate so I was very much
worried about for example whenever they
you know for example throughout 1990s I
watch PBS you know people you know many
of the PBS station PBS okay let me show
you what that is Public Broadcasting say
servus okay this this logo PBS then then
okay this is a non-profit nonprofit
organization in USA okay so they they
publish videos and document a document
on commentary about global warming about
space explorer exploration about science
about history you know kind of like
educational Channel PBS and this also
you know so for example back in 90s
1990s everyday I I go to the library
every day
okay yeah basically every day I borrow
you know the videos history history
history channels and and all that you
know so I watched tons of them about the
ocean you know dolphins whales all kind
of creatures in the ocean today you can
watch them on YouTube you know there's a
lot for example look at this one you
know octopus you know something like
that you know so I I'm very much
you know progressive you know are you so
about you know global warming
I very much into recycling and you know
clean energy and all that and I believed
it that's the thing I believed you know
I was I believed it but now it's all
changed since 2000 16 since 2016 I
started to see you know all the social
justice you know the rights of all these
crazy social justice facts then you know
they are started to look into you know I
started to look into the you know I
started to you know because these social
justice there ideas you know they are
just crazy okay they are just they are
just bad you know they are just clearly
clearly bad and they are then they are
saying women are there's no difference
between men and women okay it's a
[ __ ] [ __ ] you know this it's a
[ __ ] completely complete lie okay in
every way in every way they got lots of
problems on one hand
they say there's no by personal this is
what they say okay there's no biological
difference between men and women no
biological difference then they say then
they also say there's no sex at all that
I mean they they are like 10 sexy that
you have women women you have trans do
you have genuine none you know
non-binary then you have queer that you
don't think you have dinosaurs then you
have Dragons you have you know you have
all that now so then then then they say
okay so it's a complete mess you know
they the the today is left you know the
social justice the extreme left okay
they become you know they just say
whatever they say whatever if you
disagree they're gonna beat you up
that's what they do so so be this began
around 2016 actually when it began
earlier you know 2016 is when there's a
you know presidential election then in
2017 Trump you know Trump got elected in
2016 so anyway around 2016 oh you know
beginning I will say 2010 let's say 2010
the social justice rose then you started
to see all these weird things you know
then they're talking about safe space
hate speech you know free speech they
want to ban speech you know things like
that they do violence they burned you
know buildings not building so that they
burned cars and stuff so so this is all
like shock you know and so I guess you
you know you started to naturally do you
look you started to read things look at
what when who are these people why are
they here so today so today on the issue
of global warming I'm not sure anymore I
use like before okay before to that
before 2016 I'm pretty sure you know
whenever there's a vote for example I
would say yeah I want you know I would
vote for
something that will fix global warming
it's important you know today it's like
not sure about that
well yeah it's I think it you know it
should it should be important but I'm
not sure that's the thing
and also okay so about global warning my
opinion today is that I'm not really
sure what's you know I'm not really sure
what is true okay because there's a lot
lies going around and I've seen people
you know who are professors you know who
I really respect but he's like he's got
the Trump you know the syndrome like he
just say anything hateful about Trump
and he is one big global warming guy you
know he's you know he's you know he
thinks that's critical okay so he think
that's critical and he's you know a
mathematician I respect but however then
when he mentioned Trump stuff you know I
looked into that's just totally [ __ ]
that's not true and also he's you know
he's in this group where they they they
say you know the patriarchy you know the
the patriarchy that omens are evil you
know so he he's like he he doesn't
really actually say them but he seems
impressively he is you know supporting
the social justice can kind of people so
when you see he dude does that you know
when you when you see he does that then
you are not sure anymore you know
[ __ ] go [ __ ] yourself with your global
warming go [ __ ] yourself so in other
words he is doing he is having when it
comes to politics you know he's having
the opposite effect on me you know he
wants people to believe that global
warming it's really critical I can't
believe it you know because it's
something you you know if you fix it too
late then
it's too late you know you have to you
know you have to fix it fix it and I you
know rationally I believe that's what I
believe too but meanwhile his increases
support
this patriarchy thing you know this man
equals women this kind of thing they I
don't want to believe him anymore that's
the thing so on global warming I'm not
I'm not sure what what exactly that is a
situation okay I don't know
on the other hand but I what I know for
sure recycling
okay recycling that's that we have been
lied to for the past you know 20 or 30
years recycling that's a lie that's
actually recycling is just a lie you
know if you want look into they are a
lot YouTube videos for example recycling
let me tell you this you know we recycle
in USA right and what we do you know we
think you know things you know goes to
recycling center and they do recycle and
they make new things with it that's not
true and tree the USA and Canada you're
just think you know right I treated
about that I mean you I mean you agree
right I mean so so we actually we ship
we you know we we you know a citizens we
recycle things but actually all these
companies they they put them in a truck
they shipped it they ship it to China
ship it to Philippines so you got this
huge amount of garbage sent to China and
Philippines and let them deal with it
and in the past few years
China China refused okay they are not
taking your recycled garbage anymore
Philippines you know they refuse so now
you got a problem they are you know
YouTube videos you can watch published
by CBC you know the Canadian
Broadcasting Corporation I think I've
seen it for example let's go to YouTube
so we so we psycho turned out it's a lie
it's a huge lie why do government lie
about it why do American government lie
because because they can they benefit
they can make tax money or something
like that I forgot what's exactly the
details
but but you go to youtube and you follow
you know mainstream chant channels this
is not even conspiracy you go to use
search for recycle okay recycling okay
and for example maybe this one I'm not
sure I trust this one now this this
company now this is kind of leftist and
Vox box is also it's extreme leftist
recycling is a scam okay I don't know
who is this guy but you might you know
check out that but but basically if you
try to look watch a few videos you will
see you see Philippines or South Asia or
what whatever country I forgot let's see
recycling let's say China basically many
countries they don't want they don't
take you know the recycle stuff sent to
them anymore so you can then then that
becomes a problem because you cannot
throw them a way to ship it to China so
you know anyway there's also by this guy
I trust who is a couple of guys who do
shows like magic shows what's what's the
the you know one tall guy in one short
guide the short guy named almost never
talks what's their name anyway they did
a show Pantera
yes exactly paying Tara yes so they they
did an episode on recycling you know
watch them they expose all the lies yeah
now I remember
yeah Pantera
it's it's just such for their video I
watched the video pen and Tara TL area
okay recycling yeah so they you know
there are some click clips and but there
is I I remember the Food Show is also on
YouTube you know they may pirate it
don't you - but anyway so you can watch
you know so it it's just it's a lie you
know they expose the day yeah so you
know so in the past 20 years I didn't
know until until these social justice
can rose up then I started to learn I
started to learn a lot of things about
how the Democratic Party you know they
you know they are always for women for
the blacks for the minority and so on
and and one of the reason possible very
possible reason plausible reason is that
they they are for also for immigration
you know for the immigrants for the poor
and so on one of the reason is vote you
know they they get all your black people
to vote for them actually they are
they're doing bad so I learned a lot of
things you know and one of the one of
the thing is about recycling is just a
huge it's just a lie you know so in the
in the past 20 years I didn't know I was
like it was for recycling yeah we need
to recycle oh my god we need to recycle
help the earth look look at the ocean or
the turtles and whales they are you know
they are dead because the plastics that
is actually true I mean but but you see
the the thing is you know when something
is true how you report it you can you
know add color that's that's today's
news they are all twisted
they are tricity because that way they
can make more money you know they can
benefit this government group or that
cooperation you know yeah so there's a
lot you know in a modern society if you
are normal people I mean I I haven't
been watching TV since 19 since since
since year 2000 okay
but but even even even so you still get
brainwashed because everything you hear
you know the it's almost like anything
everything you can you can start to
doubt then you start to do research on
anything any of your beliefs then you
start to do research and you'll find
it's likely that you are find is you
know what you believed is just not true
yeah is yeah one one you know in the
past few years I learned that that's
almost true almost it's almost like for
everything like anything you believe
like you know you might try to do it
think of something you really hate you
know you know you don't even think about
it but then you try you know try to
actually to look for the truth you know
try to research then you'll find you oh
you will find a lot of things you don't
know and possibly you'll change your
mind you'll just change your mind
almost almost about anything about
history and and stuff okay so I think I
hope I'm not remembering too much I've
been talking for one hour so yeah that's
that's about that recycling about crime
and change and I noticed recently it
seems
what's your country Matt it seems you
know they stopped using the word global
warning global warming instead they say
climate change is that true I mean
what's the deal about that like you know
I I just noticed it there seems to be
something going on within the past one
month or two is it looks like there's a
trend to not use the word global warming
anymore instead instead they say you
know climate change I'm not sure what's
going on
Oh Matt is from Germany okay so just
Justine says in Canada is a big topic
because we have a lot of natural
resources logging oh yo and there has to
be a balance between jobs and in ending
economy and not changing the climate but
a lot of people are done and screaming
about the world ending in ten years
George says I feel sorry about the
Swedish girl
yeah that's Swedish girl that's that's
you know that's a pony there's a video
actually I should show you you guys
should watch that video Twitter you know
that's what so I learned you know like I
was I was you know a progressive but now
I learned it's you know things are
entirely different okay not not what I
used to believe so there is a video that
shows that even 20 years ago the
environmentalist you know the political
group for political reasons they have
another girl who is actually I learned
later on who is the daughter of David
Suzuki now David Suzuki actually I know
him because I yeah I think I in Canada I
used to watch his show he's a science
show you know a science popular Raisa
David Suzuki so it turns out he's his
daughter so anyway so back in 1990 so
okay so they have a girl just like today
that girl that quake something you know
go on to un and and give a speech like
12 years old girl and say how you know
how environment is important and stuff
it's all just a lie you know it's a you
know you especially girls you know
whenever you you know it's typically
they they take girls to do that because
girls has the power they attract you
know our attention
let me show you that video okay then you
can just this one okay this one let me
open the URL so you guys can go watch it
okay so this girl hey later on I'd you
know I did some research after I watch
this after I watch this and I started to
look up who is she she turns out to be
the daughter of David Suzuki by the way
Justin do you know David Suzuki have you
ever watched him so this is packing like
1992 you know she's talking almost like
the same style like the current Gretel
thing you know in this greater girl
she's got psychological problems you
know she's like anyway
longer than a month because in some
phases it actually gets colder what do
you mean okay so anything else I think
maybe we stopped in five minutes
so Pablo says my doctor says says that
if I don't answer exile events free
software then I'm cured
about what then you are cured of
fanaticism oh okay Pablo says if you
want a real fight I can invite you in
IMS to my house for a session we can
stream it don't worry we have universal
healthcare here in Spain oh that's great
Richard Stallman what am I gonna fight
with him I don't you know he's I'm
pretty sad you know he got kicked out
for he's got you know he got kicked out
it wrongly you know I'm certainly for
Richard Stallman but however meanwhile
in the past 20 years I don't think he's
doing good you know he's so I you so I'm
finding it you know I'm not so
enthusiastic to fight for him you know
but yeah I don't have fun funny so
anyway okay so me that's about it today
I think
so a test - good morning - Chile Chile
attached - says there is a strong
movement trying to modify the Free
Software Foundation from inside
like what like you know I don't trust I
you know I don't think we can trust free
software foundation anymore doesn't
matter what happens I don't think we can
trust it
yeah so yeah so Coraline odda yeah she
is a very extreme Evo guy you know they
want to create a new license they want a
license so that they can say who is not
allowed to use their license you know
Evo you know it's like they this social
justice people I can tell you what you
know they are basically they are almost
like a militant military group okay they
are philosophy everything they do is
exactly designed to be a coat and tube
to expand themselves to get themselves
more and more power exactly because I
study coats I study Scientology you know
Scientology they are rules and their
philosophy I talked about this you know
in in my videos they they have a you
know they have waste disciplines you
know they have rules how should one
behave and many other code organizations
I've studied they have like rules what
you can do or cannot do or how should
one respond you know how should one
behave they control your thoughts so
anyway I studied you know their
philosophy what you can do what you
cannot do what you should do things like
that
they are just they are just like you
know the social justice group they are
just like that okay
it's almost like every every of the
internet is designed it's specifically
designed so that so they are group you
know their code will become more
powerful more powerful and they're you
know they are rules their way of to do
how to do things is to eliminate their
enemy enemies okay
for example for example among the social
justice one thing they they often say is
that you have to do something okay
that's you know like they tell their
friends or people you know may it be
feminism's related issues or about
choice you know versus you know for
choice of
life about any any of these
controversial topics about anything they
they have a chant they have a like rule
like you have to do something it's not
okay it's not okay just to talk about it
that you have to they tell their friends
you know that you have to do things you
have to actively do something about it
if you do not then you are the enemy
that you know that's what their
philosophy okay so for example about you
know was about for example about Richard
Stallman the way they kicked out Richard
Stallman you can read you know before
he's kicked out the the day that girl
you know wrote that blog there are many
you know all the social justice warriors
on Twitter are responding to it okay so
one of their you know they actively name
the Free Software Foundation Board
you know the Board of Trustees you know
the organization something that they
active actively picked out those names
you know like Twitter if they are on
Twitter they you know tagged them and
they say you know you should make a
choice you know they tell them you need
to make a choice things like that so
what I'm saying is I so this social
justice can people they have you know
their philosophy or rules alternet so
you know mantra or things like that it's
specifically this designed you know
almost in every way so that they grow
and they eliminate the cue of their
enemies for example one way they grow is
to they they always you know they say
you know you have to it's not okay you
know you are just be be yourself you
know it's not okay you have to actually
do something if you don't do something
you are considered an enemy okay now
that is one way they grow because now if
they if there is some issue
controversial issue I for example for
example if I don't have a opinion if I I
cannot just say oh yeah I support
you know I cannot just be neutral no
okay I simply say oh yeah I support you
know social justice I support women
that's not totally okay you have to do
something they want me for example they
want me to actively start to do
something then they can accept me
otherwise I'm still enemy you see so now
I becomes now if I read that oh I it
becomes I now have to have to make a
choice you know that either be them be
part of them or become the enemy because
otherwise they're gonna attack me so
that's that's what they do
you know that's others that's one of the
you know that's one of the way to grow a
coat you know the you can see this in
Scientology in Falun Gong in other coats
you know I've you know it's one of my
thing to study coats you can see similar
kind of rural same tactics the members
you know so in my opinion okay they are
kind of like criminal now okay welcome
back bathroom um oh I'm pretty much done
for today so so yeah so that's what I
think about social justice people the
social justice warriors now I I know
some of my friends you know white people
okay typically white people they are you
know they they have money they live in
comfort a lot of the Emacs people I know
you know some of them is this your
follow me okay so but I kind of I kind
of can tell that they are they are under
anti-trump okay they are kind of the pro
the social justice Google people you
know many of them they don't explicitly
say it you know they don't say it he so
it's kind of a problem okay it's it's
kind of like you know you have
your friends you know we all have our
friends and family but but then civil
civil war is on the brink of you know
starting a civil war and when see what
happens you have no choice you're gonna
you know be one side or not you're gonna
stab a knife into each other into your
family members into your friends you
have no choice when see what when it
really breaks up so what I'm feeling is
that so you know I have these
acquaintances and they are kind of like
you know sofa is still okay you know
this you know but but it's still it's
already pretty bad this you know this my
you know some of my white acquaintances
in the Emax community for example I you
know some of them I see them sometimes
tweet out you know things again it's
Trump and I feel like you know I want to
tell them stop that you know stop that
because that's not true you know I want
to show I want to show them oh you
should you know maybe try read this
article instead but you know but I'm not
sure you know because this is very
controversial this is a serious problem
it's getting very serious you know and
yeah
is it's hard to say what what can one do
okay and and you don't know exactly
what's their intentions your friends
among your friends or acquaintances you
don't know exactly what their intentions
may be you know maybe they are extremely
for social justice extreme like if once
they know you know they like they are
ready to you know beat you beat you up
possibly there's that there's that
possibility but meanwhile they don't
quite say it yet they are you know they
are now still too public maybe that's
like that maybe you don't know you have
no idea but maybe they are kind of in
the middle they are really not sure
what's going on they are not sure they
you know they they are not sure
you know oh maybe you know they I think
they are all good people but maybe they
are you know they don't know the fact
yet they don't know that they just don't
know because today all the news media
are left leftist news media the New York
Times in Washington Post for example
this this one
you know democracy dies in darkness such
such such a countable phrase you know
that that's kind of like propaganda you
know if you are not sure you believe it
you know
oh oh yeah democracy dies in darkness
look look at you know so anyway they
read these articles every day they don't
know what is actually you know true you
know so you know so so so you don't know
what's your acquaintances or your
friends what well you know what's their
situation you know so it's a it's a
problematic it's it's a problem when
civil war breaks out or not you know
let's let's not be traumatic things are
bad enough today you know USA
I see USA is like stagnating you know
there's no not much progress I mean if
you like look at China you you most
Americans don't know if you look at
China you know the cities the trains
much better you know even ten years ago
it's on YouTube okay if you really try
to look at it all the cities and train
so that you know it's much better than
USA so I feel feel like USA might be
stagnating and you know you it's kind of
I kind of worried you know what's going
on what's what will happen anyway so
that's it for today so today is about
talking about politics global warming
and stuff thank you guys for watching
I'll see you guys so next week I think
next week tentatively probably around
same time now o'clock you know no car
gets breaking my back
it's disrobe disrupting my sleeping
schedule see you guys