good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 201st
may 4th and today we are going to do
emacs
i'm going to create a emacs um
emacs distro okay because imax distro
and today is mostly just going to be
emacs
i'm going to create a xl emacs distro on
the fly
so it's going to be a competitor to doom
emacs
and spacemax
so yeah so that's what we are going to
do today mostly emacs and if you have
questions ask me questions okay post in
the comments good morning george good
morning new off good morning
emacs enthusiast we have uh
new people because it's a different time
frame
okay so so uh voice check let me check
my status
voice check video check i'm good to go
fantastic
fantastic chen guo hey chiang guo
good morning uh
first name last name is uh yeah so sorry
i have
i had to schedule today reschedule today
so okay so emacs distro let's create
acce max c straw so let's write it down
okay create uh date okay
on the pink window you can see all my
emacs command
cores such as whenever i press a key
you'll see the command shown on the pink
window and you also
you will see the key shown there and i'm
using soft light keys
so i'm going to create
a e max distro so this
this is going to be your emacs package
you can go to github
and download it and you have everything
set
you know i did this like 15 years ago
starting with urban emacs about
12 12 years ago 2008 also and i did that
for about eight years
uh so it's uh okay so let's do some
image system so why
am i doing that you know i can do that
easily but
for example let's go to my emacs init
for example you can see here is my emacs
init and the init file okay let me show
you okay so
here you see here is actually my git
directory so
if i go to dot emacs my dot emax d
[Music]
so you can see this is my dot emacs d
and you can see dot emacs
dot emacs not dot emacs the init.ell you
see
this file and if you open that file it's
basically one single line
okay uh where is it this one single line
load file load file and given a
directory so this is actually this
is my main init file the custom set
uh variables those are created by emacs
itself i don't actually i don't want it
i don't need it
olan olan helm powershell go
mod smix okay i don't really need any
anyway
so dot emacs
dot d directory then you have this init
file then you open and basically this is
the
this just this one single line that's
significant
okay then we open that open that
then you can see this is uh this this
directory
is my main init file and my main
need file is this one emacs init
so it's kind of some kind of redirect so
all my emacs init files here
and you can find them on github uh so
normally
you know this is what i do but when i'm
so you know this is one you need file
and what does this
enable file do this init file the
main init file open it will basically
just load
a bunch of other unique files so first
of all
uh depending on you know whether i'm on
e-max
you know call emacs initiate if the
version number is less than
27 because in imax version 27 there's a
new
uh uh package initialization mechanism
that does not require you to code
package initialize
but before emacs 27 you need to call
that that's why
we have this line then require i do then
basically then
okay then this this code okay this code
is just
loading relative directories kind of a
fix
but anyway so this may you need file is
basically a load a bunch of
uh packages and any other unique files
for example first of all load emacs
settings now this settings file if we
open it
it's ending in dot er okay so let's
shrink back
so you can see the pink window so this
file if i
open it let's open it dot el so this
file is about
font is about
setting up font setting up uh lots of
fun phonician
egyptian hand you need to do that if you
are using those characters especially on
windows
it otherwise e-max is going to be slow
usually
depending on the version i'm not going
to go into detail so anyway
so this ini file uh emac settings
is all basic the most basic
settings that does not require any
external package
uh for example uh after you set font
then you set desktop mod that means
whether
when emacs restart it's gonna reload all
your open files
then you global auto revert mod true
that means whenever a file is changed
outside of emacs
emacs will automatically update that
file
when when that file is open in a buffer
so so this file is all the most basic
setup
you know blink cruiser no blink i don't
want blink
column number mod that's uh that's show
the position of the
column of the cursor you can see on the
mod line over here
uh you know all the basic ena files so
that's this file so
so back to my init file so you load the
basic settings you load my abbreviations
let's look at abbreviations for example
you have
i have lots of abbreviations for example
the most used
english words uh
second minute about after
because between cannot you know actually
some of them i forgot so i don't use
so this one are i use often for example
let's
see you let me type you are okay so
let's uh oops uh what what's going on
uh go back go back
uh wait yeah okay
where are we uh a brief fire so okay so
you see i'm going to type new buffer
y r okay i mean you are
so if i type u r space
it becomes yours if i type u space
it becomes u y o u if i type
r it becomes a ie
okay that's a that's the abbrev uh brief
a brief is the most useful thing
the most for efficiency reasons of
abbreviation the most uh useful thing
you want to do
anyway actually i need to we i i need to
go uh
much faster than this but you know
because today
i'm supposed to create exact emacs uh
distro
so so it's kind of um
you know i can do it myself but you know
so it's
meanwhile you're watching me doing
creating some emac cistro meanwhile you
are
watching you are basically looking at my
emacs workflow you know that might be uh
uh useful for some of you like for
example
how do i open a file uh you know i can
open a file by calling this command
uh you know how do i go to a directory
i can just press two keys and i mean uh
you know i'm back to a directory
of the of that file is in
so you're looking at my workflow or
whatever so
so okay so i want to yeah i want to
start to
um create a xr emacs
distro uh okay let me let me explain let
me talk about why do i want to do that
you know so i've been using you know so
i started ergo emacs digital from 2008
to about 2012.
uh you know once you do about 2000 yeah
2006 or something you know about five
years
when you do that you become the tech
support
you know because inaudible you know my
ergo emacs digital is especially
designed for window users
because for emacs in the emacs community
the window
users are the ones left out you know
because
all the emacs are geekier one geekier
than the other
one is superior than the other one is
more elite than the other
they all focus on uh on linux
and they are trying to they all trying
to show which one knows emacs better
so the windows platform is typically
left out
but you know i but i want i want emacs
to be
uh powerful on windows as well so that
was
uh the main focus of ergo emacs
uh i can i can show you some links but
anyway it's it's old okay it's gone it's
you know it's not i'm not doing that
anymore so
so i did that for five years and the
main issue is that you spend all your
hours
every day for several years working on
it
and people just you know you become a
tech support
people just use you know they you know i
i don't get you know i don't get much
money
and they ask you questions all the time
uh you do get thanks now and then you
know people thank you oh thank you
so this is so uh great uh but
you know thanks doesn't do much you need
money donation
okay so so if you like my stuff buy my
stuff or donate okay
so uh so what's uh is there any question
they finally finally yeah finally i'm
here so i started to talk a lot
and we haven't started to code yet 12
minutes okay let me continue
now let's just chat why not i'm gonna
you know so so ergo emacs distro
and one of the you know what you know
it's
focused mostly for windows you just go
to the website
you download one zip file and you
uncompress it
and you are ready to go you don't need
to worry about you need config
you know because it's all set up for you
and you have
python mod you have javascript back then
javascript mod is not part of emacs
so you have all that mod you know you
you don't need to install the music
you don't need to you know look oh which
one is the better package for javascript
uh search for that things like that save
you lots of time
so that was ergo emacs mostly focused on
windows one zip file
and there's another focus that is ergo
emacs key binding okay so
let me show you other emacs keybinding
so if you just go to xymax block you go
to the keyboard emacs keys
then on the side you can see emacs
keybinding how to
then key tips
then issues about emacs pinky
then you can see xrflight keys
this is a emax key system very efficient
a model system for emacs
but before flight keys i
spent about 10 years working on ergo
e-max
mod and i call it you know auger emacs
keybinding a ergonomic based keyboard
shortcut system
so this is this is uh this is the main
show of ergo emax distribution when you
install ergo emacs
you have you know you have the ergo emax
mod and what it is primarily
is is that it redesigns it's a
keybinding system for emacs
so that you don't have to press ctrl key
as much
instead you use the old key most of the
time
to navigate and to navigate to delete
words and things like that
so this is the ergo emacs mod this is
the main part of ergo emacs distribution
uh but as around 2012
2013 i kind of stopped working on this
for reasons because i was having
problems in life
so uh so matt took over so matt
fiddler you know so he is now
maintaining
uh ergo emacs
where is the ripple it's wait i'll go
e-max yeah okay here
ergo e-max distro okay so this is the
uh it's i you know i think it's still
still
fairly popular so in this keybinding
system
the primary the design point the design
philosophy is that
you do most things by by holding down
the old key with your
thumb so that it's it's uh it's
more efficient it's more ergonomic than
using your pinky
to press the control and also all the
move move cursor forward move closer
backward
and up down and and delete characters
and things like that
are designed so that the keys are on the
home row mostly you know so it's
it's basically these two these three
fingers your primary fingers
on the top two rows so you can see on
the right side you have up down
up down left right and on the on the
left you have delete words
uh left and right things like that so
this is ergo emax
mod still still fairly popular
maintained by matt
fidler now for 10 years now and also by
the way
this package ago emac smart is now part
of
gnu e-max alpha so
we had to sign papers very very
very tedious we have to sign ikesaudi
assign all my rights to this code to
you the free software foundation
[Laughter]
and he also did that and also david
capello
david cappello was the main guy who
worked with me who helped me
do create the ergo e max distribution
david capello is the is a
c and c plus plus expert
and he is also a windows programming
expert
and he is the author of a sprite
okay yeah so you can see let's go to his
website so a sprite
so a sprite is a software for window
on windows i believe it's i'm not sure
it's available for mac
or linux i think it's also available for
linux but it's a
software designed to for design for
retro game classic arcade style game
developers to create sprites
so that's right fairly popular so
i would recommend you support him you
know buy
buy his software uh so where is his uh
he's a sprite uh can you click on that
no website okay so david capello a
sprite blog
a sprite uh let's go to us a sprite
website okay
so let's see
javascript not available oh twitter i
don't want twitter
but let's go to a sprite website okay
a sprite faq
a sprite okay so this is the
you know david capello he's also
he you know he and me too we supported
open source so a sprite was open source
however just like i mentioned before
when i did organ emacs you know you
don't get
much pay you don't get paid and
meanwhile you work all day and night
so a sprite was open source until you
know he has to survive so
one day he changed the so he changed
the license such that
you can still download the source code
but it's not like the
you know the normal open source i
believe so but you have to check the
details
anyway so that's a sprite david capello
he worked with me together we
made ergo emax and with
you know with some other help from other
people you know patches some
sometimes things like that so that was
kind of the history of ergo emacs
and ergo emacs mod
so that is why you can see my website
you know
saudi.org i mean the
if you just search for orgo emacs you
can see ugo emacs and
evil mod you know people are trying to
to do comparisons
ergo emacs users out there the study of
people's efficiency in their working
uh so my website you see
my website my emacs website is the
domain is still ergo emacs
uh meanwhile you can see the ergo emacs
quick start guide you know that that is
the ergo e-max mod
a key binding system for emacs okay
that's over
max that's uh so i had to stop i stopped
working on urban emacs because
no money and i'm you know i'm i need
food
that is why
uh okay so let's see what else for
coding deja vu mono so any comments no
comments okay
so history of over emacs uh
okay so yeah so i
stopped working on google emacs because
i need money
and then
yeah so there is a big problem in my
life
and now i'm much better and after
after a while i for reasons you know
because i changed my keyboard for
reasons i stopped working on ergo e-max
mod
too so david so the the mad fiddler
just took over and he rewrote the engine
he went
in his philosophy of direction he
you know he he he leads ago imax mod
but after a few years i started to
happen i happen to
think about key binding because i've i
was suffering
uh repetitive strain injury right now i
still do
like here i talked about that several
times
uh is a minor pain constant
so after you know after i stopped
working on uber emacs but
then after a few years i thought about
key binding i thought about the
moto mod system like
evo mod like vim like vi and i
and that you know uh
i think you know the model system is
actually more efficient
in the sense that you actually type less
your number of keystrokes is actually
less when you do programming
when you use a model kind of a system
because you no longer need to hold
control
something or or something wherever you
want to run some command
so model mod so then i decided to
create a soft light keys okay uh
uh the i guess you okay so like uh let
me show you okay so
so that that is uh that is when i
started to work on
sapphire keys which is kind of a
mix of ergo e-max mod
ergo e-max mod which is a very efficient
design the choices of keys
i mix that with a the idea
of model you know so you have a command
mod
you have a input mod you no longer need
to
hold down hold down old key anymore
so that is kind of the history of over
uh
supply keys so this
so when i created stuff like keys it was
2013.
now it's seven or eight years ago
and now i feel like i'm in a position
to create a uh xr emax distro again
you know but i don't i don't want to do
tech support i'm just going to create it
if you like you know for any people
using it if you like it
you you know you pay me you you donate
uh you know things like that so how long
have i been talking uh
so today i'm mostly doing the talking
i'm not actually
creating the pack you know
so who who else is watching seven okay
so
talking so should i um so so let's see
what i want to do
okay have a drink this is a energy drink
power drink
so starfly keys i'm pretty proud of
starfly keys because you can see it's
very efficient especially when you watch
me
do workflow okay so actually close that
close that
okay so i need to increase the window
otherwise you don't
yeah that's better so close that one key
press
uh yeah so meanwhile let me show you my
keyboard
okay so you are going to look i'm gonna
show you my keyboard now then
so you are looking at what is this
so you are looking at kinesis advantage
two keyboard okay kinesis advantage
to lf l is linear so i got linear
uh cherry silent red
switches and on top of that this
is the ultimate hacking keyboard that's
just one part of it the other part is
over here
uh you know so so so one part is here
one part is here i'm using it as a
marker keypad i showed that in many of
my videos
my wife is gonna sleep so i'm gonna just
show you my keyboard then
not not showing you my face
okay so let's just i guess that way
okay yeah let me do add so
this video is spawned sponsored by xrd
[Laughter]
so why is that you just go to my
keyboard blog
uh so you go to my keyboard blog you
click on logo emacs
ergonomic keyboards and you can see my
reviews
of the kinesis advantage 2
and also my reviews of ultimate hacking
keyboard
and in fact if i just press a few keys
you can see the software
for ultimate hacking keyboard which is
one of the greatest
software yeah the most great you know
the one that and you can see
all my uh keyboard markers right now
okay that's the ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic
split okay so you like them
go go to my website buy it
okay so now next
what's next what we're gonna do next i'm
going to
create a sardi distro yeah so
close that um
okay so create let's let's begin to do
it
then okay so let's see how long have i
been talking
27 minutes okay let's let's begin to do
it
so uh so okay just watch me okay
so here is my git directory and let's
create it where do we create it here
let's create it here okay
xr emacs
okay so you can see i've created xl
emacs
okay so open that so it's empty uh
wait so it's empty split the window
now we're gonna uh so what do we need
yeah the first of all you need
you need a unique file so
okay open a new window
shrink and let's go to my emacs init
file okay
so here is my emacs ini file directory
what we need to do is to
okay let's just start working so any
comments
looks like cloudy's sake sake
oh oh yeah so this is
uh this is actually some kind of a rose
rosy
you know energy drink
i believe it's monster
uh so what what else my concurrent users
okay so so let's
let's uh begin creating the xsa emacs
distro okay
so first of all open a new buffer type
something
save it emacs dot e l
um
what should i name it let's just say
init.er okay
so we have that file close that that
that okay so let's actually move that
here so
so open the init file so okay let's just
start to do it quickly okay
so open my init file my copy the whole
thing
paste it here so let me actually the
best thing uh when you do a video is you
need to explain because otherwise you
have no idea what i'm doing
so let's uh in order to before we expand
we write down uh what we are doing
okay so this is the
main init file for
xr emacs distro okay
and in this file it's going to uh
in this file it's going to
load packages load
a bunch of other innate files
first of all load a
settings in it that
does not require any packages
first of all load a most basic
settings in it okay
then load other packages
okay so we need this line
and by the way you also you kind of need
the first line there
that is called um
i forgot what's that code that's a bit
basically this
this format you are looking at that's
the
emacs convention
[Music]
you know first of all you see it's a
comment then you do
dash star dash this kind of format
that's the emax
convention for loading variables
and values so in this line you can see
there are two variables
one is coding that's a that's actually a
e max variable
then the other variable is lexical
binding
so the value for coding is utf8 the
value for lexical binding
is t t means true in e-magnesis
so when you have this format by the way
this format is also
adopted by by python and also by
ruby okay uh yeah okay uh let me show
you okay digression so let's let's go
through my ruby
uh tutorial and show in browser
back to emacs let's go to my python
tutorial
showing browser magnify okay so let's
look at python first
so search for
uh unicode okay so the in this page
is all about unicode you need to know if
you code in python
so so first of all for python 3
everything is utf-8 for python 2
you need to begin your file
with that you see with this line and why
because that
that tells python that your file may
contain
unicode characters encoded in utf-8
then it will the com the python compiler
will load it properly
so it's required for python 2.
so you can see so this format you know
it's a common
in python but then that that that's a
that's from
the emacs convention adopted by python
now if you look at ruby same thing okay
let's click on unicode you see this
is a ruby source code and also ruby
adopted this emacs convention
so now you know if you are a python
coder or ruby coder
next time you have cds oh that came from
emacs
so back to uh yeah back to back to back
to the
uh um where are we doing so uh
close that close that yeah so we were
explaining the first line so
so then okay that we explained require i
do so
um okay i don't think i'm gonna i'm
gonna going to be able to finish this
today
so i'm just going to type a lot um
well i'm i'm going to um
well let's let's let's keep going
because
loading custom commands and functions
okay let's do that
and get full path so given a relative
path you want the full path that's what
this function does
because e-max is not you know e-max
indeed is not e-max
um should i explain it because i
uh you know i explained the thing here
in detail
uh anyway so
so what's the next what's next we need
to start to load
files emacs settings emacs abbrev
okay uh so i'm creating excel distro
right
so why am i creating a casa emacs distro
because
actually it's a very convenient because
whenever
i need to switch to a new machine
i have to like essentially go through
every
file of my init file and kind of
recreate
it in the other machine uh
it usually does not work if i just copy
all these files over
because because they have
they depend on for example they depend
on some
directory structure i have my machine on
mac
but two months ago two months ago i
switched to windows so i have to kind of
do or do do this all over
but if i do have exci max distro
i basically just download a entire
directory on the you know from gib
gib from github git clone
then i'm ready to go so
emax distro is actually convenient even
for myself
whenever i uh want to use emacs on a new
machine
so that that's uh that's part of the
reason
uh it's useful to me not just to other
people
uh but i've heard other people want it
to be you know
i i've heard some of you guys want it so
i'm going to
i'm going to create it okay so so what
else
so um so i need to focus on here so
so right now we have this one single
init file
and in this cni file we
we load a bunch of other ini files uh
first of all
load the settings file and okay so let's
do that
okay so settings okay so now go back
here
search s-e-t-t okay so copy this file
over
basically copy the whole file
okay open a new buffer paste it here
and back to this window go to diet copy
the file path
close it back to this window save it
paste
save go to diet you can see
there we have it okay load the settings
now back to the ini file load up brief
okay
agree is important actually so let's
open uh a brief copy it over
so another way to copy over is instead
of instead of opening
opening the file copy the whole thing we
instead of doing that like we did before
we just uh this time we just switch to
switch to this style directory so
you want to copy this file to
this directory so we do it this way
press capital c yes
done okay so you can see it's there
now open the ini file again what's the
next uh
add the of this file to load path
okay so yeah so this means
add the current directory to the emax
load
path load path is
load path is the emax variable you can
see
by calling described variable load path
you can see here's the documentation for
load path it's basically uh
a list of file path where where emacs
will
search those directories when you are
loading a emacs package
so okay so you want to add the current
directory to
load path you know the current directory
being
being you know wherever this directory
is
okay then getting your selection yeah
you need that
okay so um okay so we start to load
packages okay so why don't we
why don't why don't i why don't
i show you you know a few of them
so you get the sense of how the whole
thing works
we don't need to go over all of these i
guess
uh but i do want to show you how to get
stuff like keys okay so anyway let's
start okay
let's start you have to start somewhere
so let's start to load this package
start get thing or selection okay first
of all
open it so it's um
yeah so how do i how am i going to do
this um
let's see okay let's just copy okay open
it
copy the whole thing close it back to uh
back to here
back to this directory split the window
new buffer paste it back to this window
copy the file path save it
there go to diet you can see get thing
okay
uh so what does get thing do well i'm
not going to explain okay so
yeah yeah
um all these are on github by the way if
you just search for it you'll find it
uh these are kind of utility emacs list
utilities
okay so okay let
next we need to do this uh okay open it
uh open it wait uh
yeah open the directory open this file
copy close switch to here new buffer
paste uh back to here
copy the file path save it done
go to diet and you can see
here okay now back to this window close
now you need to now you need this one
emacs list utility okay open it
do the same thing copy switch here new
buffer
paste back to diet copy the file path
here save paste
it is ut go to diet
you can see there okay now we'll go back
here close
close uh next okay now so far we have
basically created
a structure that loads these
files yes but however we need to change
something here so you see
over here it's going to load the path in
a git directory but
no we don't want that
because because split the window
you go back here you can see uh
you see the get thing here
is in the directory itself it's not
somewhere else
um
yeah let's let that be that okay so
later on you know after today you know
later on when
saw emacs digital grows you probably i
probably
need a new directory for packages but
right now let's
let everything be like very simple
okay okay so back to here
expand the window send center it
we don't need this line and we don't
need
this line okay so simple okay
now next i need to load sapphire keys
this is the most
important this this is going to be the
primary show for
sar emacs distro okay so i
again open the file emacs
supply keys is one single file copy it
close it close it
uh open a new directory i mean a new
buffer
paste it okay then save it
supply keys dot e-l okay now go to diet
refresh you can see it's there okay now
close it
close it so
this section is all about loading stuff
like keys
okay so in this in our case in our new
distro we don't need this line
because the file is just right there
okay then require
then okay set keys layout
we comment that out because we want
other people to choose they are not
necessarily using orac
okay then turn it on then start fly
command yeah then we need to install
smix okay
uh let me let me let me tell you how to
do that we need to do that
then run current file
okay let's not do let's not install smex
for now because we need to
uh do this quickly okay uh
then let's leave that so okay that's
like
that's um
leave that okay okay so
so far so let's forget the rest of it
and let's just uh try it see so far
it's working correctly or not so you can
see
yeah okay so save reopen so you can see
this is basically now this is the
content of xymax distro
and this is the main you need file so
let's open it
we covered all the code here so
basically we load
basic settings we load the brief then we
do we have the brief file yes okay
then we load
a few packages okay these three packages
then we load sapphire keys that's the
main thing
okay save it now i'm going to
restart emacs okay it's restart emacs
and use this as my
um uh
use use this init file as my you know my
init file
you know suppose people you know
you know i'm going to upload this to
github so when people clone
it they go they are going to get this
directory then um
then then
okay so so let me hold on a second let
me show you
back to my face
okay so 13 people watching
am i doing good alpha beta good morning
alpha beta
first name last name looks like cloudy
streak okay
okay so so okay let's
i'm going to i'm ready to restart emacs
uh
but before we do that we need to put
this in the emacs directory okay
so let's go to hold on a second so let's
show the pink window let's go to
my emacs dot emax okay
so you can see dot emacs d go up one
directory so you can see
i mean my home directory uh dot emax so
this
is not emaxd i'm going to
make a backup of this directory
yeah so let's do it rename underscore
date save okay
so i basically renamed my emac star
directory
now let's create a new directory
emacs.d
okay so you can see i created a new
directory
open it it's empty fantastic
and
so what do i do next should i
move all the files here into it or
should i
um
like right now i'm thinking about
basically the directory structure
of emacs distro
uh you know one thing
one simple thing i can do is just move
everything into it
like that but
this is not going to be good because
once people
yeah because
once people you know clone chrome
package
it's going to
[Music]
you know you don't you don't tell them
to just copy the the files into your
emacs dot d because emacs.d
is emacs init directory it will create
lots of other things
emacs will create lots of other files
here temp files and cache files
so it's no good to mix them so okay so
let's move them back
okay so what so
so so what would the
directory structure be e max okay
another solution is simply
[Music]
okay let's do this okay let's just for
this video let's do this
exact emacs just move the entire
directory there
okay so we are done so you can see up
refresh
so we have emacs so basically
when people get clone they get this
emacs directory
then i tell them to move this directory
into dot emacs then
you need another init file create a file
uh save it init.el
so tell them to create a unit.er and
this init.er will we'll load
load this one okay load this this thing
okay so what how do you do that what's a
syntax you can see
the syntax is here okay
copy that paste uh
we don't we don't want the full path
okay
so basically like that that that that
that okay so wait
uh at this point you don't even have uh
you don't want that there okay so
because at this point people
do not have this function yet because
that function is defined
remember we defined it here
so we want to just
load okay load uh
wait so load file name
okay so um this is gonna be
tricky i think
so basically right now our job is to
modify
this line we want to modify this line so
that it does not contain
it doesn't call this function however it
should do
exactly what that function does uh so
so we can actually do this
yeah i think uh let's hold on a second
let's
uh
so load concat concat stream
file name directory okay hold on second
file
name directory
file name directory
okay yeah file name directory so so this
will give you the
full path
yes let's try it okay evaluate that line
and you can see in the message buffer
you can see that that's correct
then when you concat that
with that you get the um
let me show you okay so you get the full
path that's correct
so this is correct okay we don't need
this anymore
okay so i just tell people to do that
okay
so here okay that we are done so the
whole file
is just this single line okay
yeah so so this init we will load
that and we'll load this file so
actually that's it okay now we are ready
to
we close that we are ready to uh close
that
where we close that
close that close that
okay now we are ready to
uh restart emacs okay but but now
instead of restarting
we are going to uh cd home directory
powershell okay
powershell let's magnify
we are going to start emacs
okay
okay so you can see once i start emacs
it will
it will load the
dot emacs file in my home directory
which is
here dot emacs.d let's magnify okay
open then you upload this file
open you see that file so
let's please let it work
if it works then we are done fantastic
so actually i you see now i have some
flag keys
actually so you can see you know this is
sci-fi keys
two keys to go to the uh directory
fantastic
and uh let's go to the message buffer to
see if there's any error
so actually so how do i um
yeah so yeah there's no error fantastic
so that's it
actually so let's close this emacs let's
close
um
wait why is the
why is the close window doesn't work
oh save desktop it asks me do i want to
save desktop
uh no okay
okay so that's it that is uh
you know let me summarize okay what
we've done today today we just created
this directory
emacs and the directory content
is just these uh six files uh
so you have one init file that's just
uh it's just a few lines okay for
example if i
you know there's lots of comments here
if i remove all those comments
you know that's that's it that's just a
few lines basically load some settings
load the brief file
then load several packages that's it
and then the rest are you know settings
a three file
and four packages and this whole
directory
is the xa emax distribution
so now so now i can do you know now i
can like call git so let's go to ishow
so let me show you okay let's yeah do
the complete thing
so now i go to isha i say git um
get new repo i forgot what's the command
okay no
okay no problem let's uh let's go to
um
the git tutorial
okay then you go to git basics
uh wait what what am i
okay so actually i want to go to firefox
hey wait this is firefox okay let's try
it again okay
exactly get tutorial
okay so you can see git basics so to
clone
a project or to get in it
obvious get in it
okay then get status
okay then so yeah okay it's fantastic
then get commit
oh git add so we could add
then git commit
uh what why is my
uh
why is my uh command memory doesn't work
git commit i should have
oh yeah because of course because you
know i was trying to use the e-shells
uh backward search feature because i've
called git command
commit before but however it's not
working
it's not working because i just swapped
out my
emacs.d directory you know the git
ripple um you know the initial
history is saved
you know in one as a file in that
directory but now i don't have it of
course
so git commit git commit
m message uh in
first commit emacs
distro okay let's say
let's just say emacs distro first
okay committed now go back to the
directory
refresh you can see we have a git file
so the next step is obviously just go to
um go to
uh go to git and github
and create a new project let's see if i
can do that
sorry
repositories okay click on that
new
oh emacs already exist on this account
uh i guess that's my exci emacs
init i need to change that okay
so actually i need to change
oh wait a minute there is xr emax
because private yeah because
like uh almost a year ago i i thought
about creating it so
i already have a repo emacs
so we have to do yeah so anyway that's
about good
so i'm gonna i need to go so
so basically that's uh emacs distro
after a few days or a week you'll see it
on github and you can use it
and we're gonna shut down in three
minutes okay three minutes
okay no comments okay i'm gonna shut
down uh we are done today
i have to go
anything else any questions
yeah so we talked for one hour precisely
one hour
thank you guys for watching if you like
my tutorial
go buy it okay uh so you have i have
emacs tutorial
supply keys you can you you know you can
find
my
tutorials easily thank you guys for
watching
bye