good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sat up shop today is 2019
December 24th the eve of Christmas
Tuesday 2 o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time how are you guys so
let's get on business so we gonna talk
about a bunch of things we gonna talk
about Emacs demo weekend I'm going to
show you a demonstration of Emacs of a
fantastic most efficient command then
I'm going to do eMac this coding live
coding first tutorial I want to modify
that command because it's got a minor
problem
so that's Emacs and eMac B's then then
I'm gonna tell you something then
basically we're gonna chat random
something about there is a subject a
topic about hermit mathematicians or
hermit programmers typically they live
in poverty
kind of like me and you guys you know
they are French okay but but they are
great mathematicians and programmers
then we're gonna talk about sundry other
things and George and Alan
Georgie and Alan stuff so Lee actually
so let's begin with George there's some
initiative
ok created by George and Alan thank you
thank you guys so you know you don't
know how hard it is to do a live stream
okay you guys you guys try to create a
live stream channel and do live stream
every day for an hour and you see how
hard it is it's not that hard but it
does take a lot of time let's see wait
am I talking we muted no in in my life
yes I'm alive okay that's good so you
have to check on that you as you do live
stream you get more
on these modern technology [ __ ] you know
these tricks and knobs and you have to
make sure they are correct or something
went wrong and audios and videos but ok
so so so and join discord ok the
wonderful and fantastic discord you see
Emily's here is Emily alive om it's not
ok and so let me show you something ok
my body I have a body you have a body I
have one body and you have one body
everybody has a body this is my key to
the apartment
this is nerds way of key so I don't get
lost so George began good morning to
Australia George George began a
programming challenge and and looks like
it's it's a success
so the the the forum in charge challenge
here is that first of all you guys need
to join this code ok for those of you
don't know discord you go to you go to
ok you go to you just such sorry discord
you'll find the link okay but let me
just paste it so this code there you
join and vibrant discussions colorful
nerds and bright people okay joining
sorry discord
okay so George and illustris member of
our community
he created a programming challenge
channel so here the basically the issue
the problem is that we're gonna post
programming problems and then each of us
can go and code it pretty
you know we can use your favorite
language javascript' Golan Perl Ruby
Python or Java or closure or Lisp emag
miss or Common Lisp or skim this or
racket or fancy languages such as
Haskell Oh camel Idris Elm Earl and all
languages you can use your favorite
language to code this problem and so
George George has began posting a
problem about generating English words
generating new words ok and we already
have a solution
I was surprised by kittens in Ruby okay
so so join discord and look at the
problems and its coded okay and we also
so Alan is going to do a goal and
solution did okay so it looks like okay
Alan already done it okay so the plan is
that I'm gonna going to look at the
solutions and run them and you know but
I'm hoping that I'm not going to be the
only one doing this because you don't
know how hard it is to do these kind of
things so I was I'm hoping someone some
of you George or Alan or any one of you
will you know sometimes when some coding
problems you will be the church like
what you gonna do so you cannot look at
all the solutions you cannot run them
you're gonna compare them like how how
creative they are which one is incorrect
which one is good elegant code things
like that then you're gonna you have to
run them compile it if necessary if it's
C or C for us first for example so and
you know then we talk about it and we
have fun like we we are going to have
prices the price is one banana okay yeah
so things like that so this is a
programming challenge and I hope you
know
I don't know how it's gonna be done yet
like maybe once a week or something in
the beginning I guess I'm going to come
and I had no other programs I can I
cannot burn all the programs because you
know when you do this you have to let me
know let me tell you let me complain
about the work you have to do you have
to know you know if you're gonna church
if I'm going to church this program
solution service first of all you cannot
you cannot ask people you know so George
already did it you have to talk to
people to get them interested so they
cannot code if you just post a problem
oh I think this is a great problem let's
code it nobody is going to do it you
have to like instigate people to do it
then once you all the solution comes
many of them they'll you know if you
what don't worry carefully you know if
you don't shape you know talk to people
then you're gonna get lots of solutions
that doesn't work that doesn't compile
or missing libraries oh you know things
like that so you're gonna spend hours
you know just just then you're gonna -
you have to find you have to tell the
person oh your code is problem then he's
gonna say oh no it runs on my on my
computer
thank you you know you got a problem
basically you become it's you're gonna
spend hours on creating this solution
saying you have to talk to people then
then okay then the other thing is you
have to download each programming
language you have to compare it so it's
it's not it's not you know you if you do
it once you know why I was great but
it's is it does take some time to do it
so I'm I'm hoping somehow you guys
cannot run it as well we can have you
guys go on to your own YouTube stream if
you if you want to create one or
something like we can talk together like
I I could it's possible I give you my
live stream key so for example next week
you cannot win the show you can talk
show you know you're gonna lead it so
and I'm gonna just be I'm gonna be
watching you so and also you can do it
on your own
on YouTube
stream if you want to that would be fun
so that that is about the programming
challenge and also you see I know you
know because I'm old so I know a few
languages I know Python Ruby pearl Java
I can run I can compact compile although
I cannot criticize it too much I don't
know Java aware so yeah you know I know
if you close your goal and Java Script
emag bees for example but I do not know
olan I do not know Haskell
I can barely know Oh camera ok so but
but people here you know once you post a
question all the also the programs were
coming so what you're gonna do you're
gonna install you have to install them
you know so I cannot do that all that I
can I can just do this you know this
this five also for any languages I
mentioned the other one so I can simply
usually what I do is I just post on my
website okay here is another solution of
Haskell and let other people who read
the page search it or run it you know
things like that so anyway that that is
about the programming challenge
interesting problems okay so that's on
this code so I think maybe we're gonna
talk about this today is Tuesday so
maybe on the weekend we're gonna talk
about it and also you know we have we
have interesting people here Susan he
codes Cobo I got Cobo okay cool guys he
code Kobo now do you see so we have
interesting collection of people here
let me show you his COBOL code okay wait
I need to get connected to people so
what what things are you saying let's
pop out the chat okay keep the comments
coming okay so let me show you the Kobo
code can you guys see it let's see okay
yeah so Kobo so let's see so we did this
live stream in in December 21st
okay em time which is number systems in
crack system you want to convert 24-hour
clock into a 36-hour crack system 36
hours 36 minutes for our 36 seconds per
minute then you have to write that in a
hex in a 6mo notation or hexamer or
scenario tation so this is actually not
that trivial problem you know in theory
it takes 10 minutes to code but never
none of us take 10 minutes even Emily
who has written her who has programmed
her clock in this notation and in fact
all the solutions are incorrect all the
solutions people gave are incorrect
until we had to fix it a couple of times
so anyway here is a COBOL code okay so
this is Kobo I've never seen Kobo code
before and I haven't run it yet you know
I need to install it so but anyway
there's a COBOL code season season is
usually not on my live stream chat or he
maybe he's looking but he is on this
code and he's also we got this weird
COBOL code so that's about programming
challenge okay so that's one thing and
the other thing difficulties about
creating a live stream the way I do is
that I go on every day almost every day
I talk you know I talk talk shocks are
talk show talk talk I talk for an hour
and usually in a haphazard way so there
is no coherent structure or topics
usually there's there's like two or
three topics but it's not you know it's
not precisely segmented so one of the
problem with my talk show you know I'm
not getting popular most other people
when they do a YouTube you know
youtubers they have a goal and they
after year they have 10,000 followers me
after year I have
thousand followers okay they after year
they're you know they got five hundred
thousand followers and then 1 million
followers in two years many of them in
two years you got 1 million followers
I'm not getting into that because I kind
of know why because I don't I don't have
a like I'm I don't I don't end for that
anyway so each video I have like 100 or
200 views but what's my point
okay my point is it's actually very time
consuming so one of the things I would
like is to have time stamps so that
people can or I can or you guys can feel
free to do it you know create a clip of
two minutes or three minutes or five
minutes well you know I I talked about
some topic for example many of the
popular YouTube youtubers they have a
separate channel that is made that is
clips of the cream of some interview or
something so in modern society we are
all busy we don't know who the [ __ ] they
are you know you just go on YouTube you
don't want to see - oh this this video
is one hour you are not going to watch
it but rather you want you want a click
wait when you see all girls boobs then
you click on that that's that's that's a
condition of us created by corporations
so anyway so you have clips you know
five minutes on some particular topic so
that that really drives traffic and that
is actually I mean I mean that's part of
a communication that's a you know it's
like books you have chapters and
sections that's the purpose of you know
organizing them so that that would be a
good thing but so what I need is to have
time stamps a lot of people have asked
me for that on my video because I talk
for 90 minutes is you know so people
want time stamps like at this time I
talked about Richard Stallman at that
time about my ideas about the world
affairs things like that so we need that
so if you watch if you are watching my
video if you are watching my video a few
of you you know do I would like
I would appreciate if you you know post
the timestamps and Alan has created a
github for this precise reason so Alan
Alan Thank You Alan
so Alan watched a lot of my videos and
helps me doing things so Aaron has
created this kid hub page that is the
ideal situation is that we gonna have a
index of all my topics like you can
search by topic and see let's see what I
say about that
okay so Alan created this kid hub page
and you can go there and help out ok
yeah you leave YouTube comments yes and
if you watch off-hours yeah leave
youtube comments on time stamps on
things you find interesting or you can
you can contribute to this github web
page as well so the link is going to be
on my youtube description actually in
the youtube description right now you
can click a link then you will see
you'll see my today's talk show page
like I have a corresponding page on my
exodia dot info website which is this
page for today's video so you can go
there and you'll find Alan's link here
so that's about that so that's about who
I mean challenge and then about the
timestamp of videos okay that that's
true thing what is the next thing the
next thing is I'm going to get money in
my pocket okay so I talked about this
yesterday and to this week of before I
so I bought this drive so external hard
drive actually so because I went to
Costco with my roommate you guys know
what what is Costco it's a great giant
warehouse
in United States come on in Justin Scarr
fight just since traffic you know you
sent me an email is yesterday can I talk
about that Justin and so because that's
interesting very interesting
things you've done so anyway so Costco a
lot of people I mean if you are outside
of USA you don't know what these Costco
so Costco let me show you okay it's a
giant warehouse in USA where you go
there and buy stuff they have a race of
a race of food and and other wonderful
things in life okay turn on JavaScript
Costco I want to see pictures let me
show you pictures okay so Costco it
looks like that that's a store up that's
the outside that's how it looks like
cost Costco we're wholesale okay it's so
things they are usually cheaper and let
me show you inside okay so this is USA
United States of America you see right
this is actually small you know it's
bigger than these arrays of arrays of
food and other things and fantastic
fantastic Oracle yeah you have racks and
racks and arrays in a race of them and
they're a race beginning at 1:00 okay
just like mathematicians not zero
stupid programmers with the zero C
simple purpose some of ucnc purpose
hackers so cuz I had to turn off
JavaScript yes indeed
so Costco so so my roommate you know we
went there and so I you know and they
have these hard disk so I just bought it
you know because I being one I need a
backup drive for for that for a year now
so I just what a heck I just bought it
so you can so you can buy it but but
today I think you guys are probably more
interested in flash drive which is
faster okay so I tested the speed of
these which is you know there's one
thing interesting anyway so if you are
transferring a giant fire like the movie
movie movie files like one gingka by 2g
gabite to these from your for my Mac the
speed is 130 megabytes per second that's
about the maximum well however that you
see the interesting thing about this is
that about this external drive aside if
your files are small like programming
files like you have thousands of them
ten thousand hundred thousand of them
your speed is gonna be like hundred
kilobytes a second oh yeah that's that's
an interesting issue about transferring
speed you know so anyway so they also
have external flash drive so you know
this is going to be the future more or
less fast drive instead of the spinning
disk and they are three times four times
five times faster than then the spinning
disk okay so you guys go by it okay so
let me post the link some talks your
index okay so actually let's go to
today's talk show
then we're gonna do Emacs and I guess so
you can find the link there just in
scarf I are you see oh they're like you
know talk answer so and and you know
I've been looking at you know these
drives you know past 30 years you know
I'm a nerd technical just like you guys
so I observed the technology of hard
drives how they change you know and I
buy them of course this when I had money
you buy them every year every every two
or three years you know they upgrade you
know over the past 30 years the the
interface change then us us became up
around 1999 by Steve Jobs okay that's
another innovation from Apple Steve Jobs
and not just from Apple from Steve Jobs
specifically once Steve Jobs is gone
Apple is like you
it's basically no good Steve Jobs so he
introduced the USB and there's a
firewire and in lots of you know the the
connection technologies so I observed
them you know then USB becomes you have
USB to then USB three then you have USB
you know the plugs you have USB C plug
which is today you know other changes in
technology is exponential growth that's
what it is so so one of the interesting
end and remember the in twenty years ago
it used to be writable DVDs you buy a
stack of writable DVD side CDs I don't I
have a CD somewhere here okay so you buy
a stack that's how you store stuff but
anyway with flash drive one of the
question I have is is if you want
storage for archiving purposes is is the
flash drive more permanent then the then
the hard disk
you know the magnetic electromagnetic
drive and so I did some reading or
research as you call it and I think the
answer is that it depends okay there is
no absolute answer I mean a question is
if you're gonna store if you want a
storage that you cannot you're gonna put
away for ten years which one is better
spinning disk or the flash drive so the
answer to that is it depends there is no
absolute question though it's not really
a technology issue it's rather about
much of many other details so so which
means you can buy and Trust a flash
drive today I think it's gonna be you
know the hard drive is kind of it will
go away sooner or later in five years in
ten years it's gonna be your dead
technology
somewhat okay not actually not that's
not totally true but so anyway that's
about drives so let's see what's the
next topic okay so should we what's the
next topic should we start - okay so
there are two more topics one is doing
Emacs demo and eMac based coding and
tutorial or the other topic is I'm gonna
talk about some hermit fringe or poor
programmers and mathematicians they live
on the fringe of society but they have
done great work so which one should I
talk about first so I need you guys
input like I need interactions say say
it in the chat so we got 11 people
watching ok it's type in the chat which
topic next so I know that I'm alive and
you are alive and you are listening okay
so Costco closed it
George says hermits okay great great
George permit okay so let's talk about
Hermits Herman mathematicians some of
them have done the greatest work more
specifically mathematicians okay so let
me show you two of them actually this
this guy I talked about one or two times
before a good morning Matt and who else
is here parties yoga morning parts
ammonium active - good morning -
Nicaragua
Matt Pye says it tastes it tastes better
than it looks one of my favorite thing
to do around this time is torment people
with my food pictures my foot pictures
good morning Ripper in good morning Bart
shrimpo
says Ella Graham Shambo Ella Graham says
hikes ahh do you follow Taiwan election
love to hear from another nut on that
Taiwan election no I haven't followed
Taiwan politics so I was wrong in Taiwan
I grew up there until I was 14 I have a
bad family kind of very chaotic family
and it's so messed up
and I basically Taiwan I have been
alienated oh I a lien a tit Taiwan
politics you know there's a lot politics
well part of it is because politics part
of it because my family you know so I
don't haven't read much about Taiwan and
well politics you know Taiwan is is very
is is I would say used by USA okay so
anyway so it's a hard thing to talk
about
so do I followed her on election well
the the one election I know is about 10
years ago sensor idea
okay that guy who is you know turns out
he is corrupt and steal money hundred
millions old you know hundred millions
and he is in jail and that's basically
that's the only election I've kind of
know a bit about and now I heard so
Taiwan's is got this female president
just like just like the USA's chanting
of it anyway so I don't know I don't
know much about Taiwan V there is one
thing I know that of a great Taiwan P
person and you I need you are in Taiwan
right he said yes I want I wanna tap
Tadros liao dr sua tree switching paid
eager than so so there is this guy whose
name is Leo okay so for you far eNOS you
wouldn't know much about it and there
he's got a Wikipedia entry but a
Wikipedia entry doesn't have much
information so his name is Dr okay so
let me show you he is I would say the
greatest heat historian the greatest
Chinese historian in the entire history
of China of the 3,000 or 5,000 years
history of China he is the greatest okay
that is my opinion that is also his own
opinion you know he's this kind of a
braggadocio guy so he write you know
he's also the most prolific probably top
10 in the entire history of China the
most prolific writer and the primary
primarily he's his historian so this guy
is one of let's say one of the three
greatest writer I respect in my life or
greatest author including English or
whatever whatever language so he is one
of them the other one would be Bertrand
Russell and Camille Paglia more or less
okay you know it's hard to pick you know
precisely what's your top three but but
basically these three person
Bertrand Russell logician and the
pacifist and also a writer okay
Bertrand Russell the British guy and
Camille Paglia who is still around you
can see her on YouTube Camille Paglia
who is the greatest in my opinion you
know I like her okay so basically these
three are my most favorite authors I
respect the third one or what well one
of them is vrdr he doesn't write in
English so all his writings is in
Chinese so so that's that's what I know
about Hawaii I don't know much about it
now
so okay so you can read on his Wikipedia
you know you know this English version
they don't have much information you
know you know it's like if you believe
what I said he is a greatest historian
in an entire history of China but then
on his Wikipedia English version you got
you got just three pages three screen
that that's not you know because you
know why I can tell you why because he
okay this is gonna be about politics you
know now now my video is gonna be more
popular because once you talk about
dramatic stuff people all the people
drama you know
let's do creeks mate okay this states
Jewish it's to rent in creeks Bates the
condition of the [ __ ] traitor created
Saudi are so so so why why are in
English literature you don't hear much
about the yah
let me tell you okay let me tell you my
own perspective which is anti USA with
respect to this topic by the way I'm a
I'm a I'm a USA's US citizen okay I'm
America so you know America America
wants to control you know the America
control we control all the world we are
you know some would say booties
especially today the social justice
warriors this can this group they you
know you they don't like American flags
you know they they they they are this
extreme group so but anyway one of the
you know one of the things I say is that
USA which i think is true okay USA you
know you being being the the greatest
bully in the world in the past 100 years
you know we we bomb or we do whatever
you know we can to control other
countries in the Middle East in in China
in Russia we do whatever you know today
the democratic party every day is like
who Russian Russian is trying to affect
our election give me a [ __ ]
crap gave [ __ ] those democratic [ __ ] USA
is measuring with all other countries
every day
you know so one way of the hot topic is
Hong Kong you know USA been sending
perience literally billions of dollars
to Hong Kong to to to to to to people
who doesn't agree with China government
okay so USA is doing that
why because USA want don't you know it
would be great if China split into
several countries you know so so USA
remains the most powerful that is why
okay that's that is the issue period you
don't know this you know I can I can
give you a lot factual information you
know you actually you just go to you
know all these political things most
people they don't they don't pay
attention they don't they don't want to
look for it they just want to believe
you know in fact for most Americans they
just owe us a democracy Oh China is no
democracy therefore we support Hong Kong
that's what they do they don't really
actually care to look forward fact or
truth anyway so there's this
organization you can you know you can
look okay I'm not going to give you
details about it but if you really want
to you already know these details okay
so anyway so USA is for democracy right
human rights democracy we want that
everywhere okay now in 1990s in 1980s in
1970s when the when when Taiwan is ruled
by coming down
okay comenta Kuomintang English you say
coming down okay that is the party who
nationalist you know you coming down is
a Nationalist Party again it's the
Communist Party China so they lost the
Civil War they escaped to Taiwan so they
hold the Taiwan and they control all
Taiwan right which act with this which
is where I came from my dad and my you
made my granddad we my granddad is part
of the Kuomintang a soldier you know
kind of general of some sort so but we
lost the Civil War so we escaped to
Taiwan and we control Thai what but you
know it's not democracy democracy my
as you know the Gua mean down control
Taiwan and they rule the apparently
they've done bad things to the Taiwan
people now Taiwan people is a very
complex idea okay so you like you have
natives like the American native India's
that's Taiwan people then you have
Taiwan people which is not the natives
but but who lives in Taiwan okay then
you have the people from China who moved
to Taiwan like me
we are also Taiwan people so when you
say Taiwan people is kind of means of
out of things and also on Twitter or
online forums when the when heated
debates you know the people don't know
what they mean you know they do just
push for whatever you liked it to be so
anyway so so the coming down took over
Taiwan a they controlled then they've
done bad things to whoever who disagree
okay they because they want to control
Taiwan so Li Li AO okay this guy D are
the greatest historian Chinese historian
he again is his organist
you know he this is not right this is
not democracy the owl says we want we
need democracy you know you you
government you know the Taiwan
government is doing talk things you know
putting people in prison you know you
cannot do that so he stand up here ah
he's he stood up he published books he
got put in jail jail for you jail diao
okay Cho and USA is for democracy right
but what did USA - nothing nothing not a
[ __ ] thing
[ __ ] the USA government again the
government in the USA government and
ignore and many ignorant white people
they think you know this is bias you
know it's a natural bias because you
because you are that you know I'm also
USA citizen but however I have a Asian
skin so I see I have you know I see I
have different biases then the typical
white American you know spice so anyway
so democracy so the yogurt got put in
jail
four times three times in total of six
years or something the USA is doing
nothing why because USA wants you know
USA's in is impaired with the coming
down party they want to fight China who
cou cares about you [ __ ] democracy do it
you don't care
you see USA is only doing things for
democracy when its benefit USA that's
what happens okay so that is a story
that's that is my complaint okay that's
my story of the yah and that is my you
could say one of my reason I you know I
am against the typical of the media
controlled American USA thought okay
democracy democracy my ass he fought for
democracy
he put jailed USA did nothing meanwhile
okay I can go on endless okay okay me
meanwhile USA has this you know CIA
organizations split off from CIA because
to evade law okay no the USA law says
you cannot do that so see is split in
two different organizations they send
money to control other countries in the
name of democracy like there's a name
okay
anyway so USA you know every day they
are chanting or China is putting people
in you know the Islamic people in in
concentration camps okay I'm I'm going
to get banned by Google starting to talk
about this you know media they are
controlling information you know so
anyway so what you hear among typical
white Americans that democracy is
democracy this or that basically they
just it's just a media copyright control
they brainwash you and you know with the
concept of justice you know human rights
record my ass okay basically the end
result is that you just you just help
yourself you know help yourself to
become more powerful and kill other
people so you get better you get a
better life and the name of that is
called democracy and human rights that
is my opinion
for example USA sent billions of
dollars you know Nobel Prize Nobel Prize
winners Western society Nobel Prize
winning Peace Award Nobel Prize peace
goes through the Dali Lama you know
which is which is a region a plateau
like like one mile above sea level
who was controlled by British government
and and so on you know a big history
that I am NOT going to get go into big
but anyway the Western society give him
Nobel Prize and give to Obama Nobel
Prize and give to the what you know the
oh okay mister do I'm not going to give
the full name okay mister do not one of
the Nobel Peace Prize about ten years
ago in China because why because he
rebel against the Communist Party
so USA's you know the Western society
well why are why does why does all this
happen
power power struggle you know you do
whatever you benefit yourself that is my
opinion okay so that's about that topic
so we are in deep waters of politics and
you know that gets me that's you know
usually politics you know you when you
talk about politics
you get people riled up including
yourself you know when you when you're
talking about politics so forty minutes
so we have we can do ten more minutes
about mathematicians weird hermit
mathematicians let me show you which are
they are the fringe of society they do
not accept you know the institution's
the mainstream you know the institutions
the way the system they do not accept it
but however many of them are great
geniuses and have done great work okay
one example is this guy well no he okay
he is considered considered by many to
be the greatest mathematician in
entire history of human animals
alexander quote Gotland dick okay
Alexander girth and dick this guy it
looks like obi-wan
so he's considered by many to be you
know if we have to pick one of the
greatest you know it's kind of dramatic
to say you know you are the greatest in
math or something like that because it's
really hard to define what is the
greatest how do you measure it exactly
but anyway you know as drama goes as we
you know but he's reasonable you know
101 of or the greatest mathematician
okay that's him and he lived life very
weird okay he's a hermit he became a
hermit and he he he is also a pacifist
you know he got fired or he quit because
he is against he is against Vietnam War
okay when Vietnam War is going on
you know u.s. is bombing you know
fighting the Communists you know car you
know among human animals in the century
of 19th it arouses to ideology one is
the communism one is the capitalism so
these two idealogy among human animals
we have these two giant groups who fight
who kill each other literally kill each
other
so I'm um I'm on the USA side well I
physically at least then then there's
the communist group who are led by
Russia Russia and China okay
so doing around I don't know what what
was it nineteen you know 1960s nineties
1970s 1980s you have Korean War
you have vietnam war so USA is bombing
in Vietnam you know fighting with the
Vietnam government why in the name of
freedom democracy okay so so when the
Vietnam War is going on this guy
Alexander Groban dick he he went to
Vietnam to to the place where the bomb
is going and he
he start a conference there math math
conference he went there and start a
conference that's this guy so he's you
know a pacifist as you co-ed pacifist
he's against war and he you know then
then he become a hermit he he just
disappeared one day you know you know
after that then he just disappeared from
math community entirely not even his
close friends know how to contact him
just Buchan God disappeared and it turns
out we know he died he died like five
years ago four years ago five years ago
he died five years five years ago so it
turns out he went to this little village
in France okay now actually we have a
Wikipedia article of this town in France
this town is called Lhasa ray a rage
okay this is like nobody knows this town
but since because now we know he lives
there then people started to create a
Wikipedia article on that town so it's
over here
so he went there and lived there become
you know it like you know he's like no
he become as he just went there and
lived by himself you know and with local
people farmers or whatever and he is
considered the greatest mathematician
okay in human history so that's okay
that's this guy that's my introduction
okay the other guy this is this guy I
talked about a couple of times he he's a
Russian okay and he doesn't like the
institution he doesn't like the
establishment okay he said he's he so
what he has he done he solved one of the
difficult problem called you know
millennium problem okay there's a
problem by the clay math Institute they
created seven unsolved math problems
that these seven
problems are considered the most
important the most critical problem
today okay so he day so this institution
created seven such problems published
and they say anyone can solve this
problem you're gonna get 1 million
dollars
okay well media and this guy solved it
and then the institution is trying to
give him the award you know with 1
million dollars and he and he says no go
[ __ ] yourself ok that's this guy and
he's living in with his mom there are
some videos ok you go to my website you
can see it you know you go through
Microsoft Hawk show today there's a link
you can find it his name is gregory
parham on guys
he saw this one medium problem so he's a
hermit he lives with his mom in russia
so that's two of the interesting guys ok
so let me read the comments try to do
the text not show in Chinese on bdbd
though you know politics I think there's
a chance to make some money there also
ok yeah someone hand surgery sounds or
just made cheek way yo you got panel
champagne would yeah just Reba DVD she
knowing that's the Tony Hsieh ones and
tayo tayo need Nagar Shoji Hama
well Mayo so G so email so G hama say
you're the improve ambience we are just
long say [ __ ] she's hung cafes agenda so
yeah it's a session I'm a no say
Hanzhong she's and shondo pbbt so shrimp
ow are you so you are on so I was
talking Chinese about opening a China
video account you know China has their
own version of YouTube very popular one
of those website is Billy Billy well let
me show you okay so you english-speaking
people get a glimpse of what's going on
in
okay biddy biddy okay I don't go there
much PEP the video okay so you can
search that by just type pbbt video very
popular that that's the website okay you
can there's also Wikipedia there it is
so you can read about the website
Wikipedia if you want to and then you
can go to the website so this is a video
just like YouTube okay basically this is
like a YouTube
China's YouTube and you guys take a shot
I'm turning on JavaScript okay so BBB
you know so I'm thinking you know I want
to open a account on BB BD so I can talk
about Chinese I mean I can talk in
Chinese to my Chinese followers in
Taiwan in China in Hong Kong and many
other Chinese abroad so I want to do
that so yeah so that's Wikipedia about
you know China you know learning a
different language is a great thing
because once you know the different
language for me for example I happen to
you know Chinese is my native tongue
okay I grew up the first fourteen years
of my life I speak Chinese then when I
was 14 I started to learn Spanish in
English
okay so English is not magnetic so the
interesting interesting thing is about
languages that is that once you know a
foreign language you really can see a
lot different perspectives of the world
okay it's actually a great thing you
know not not like you know you high
school everyone is required to take a
Spanish pass that that doesn't work okay
that you know you have to have an
interest in learning a language to talk
to people that that's the thing so and
then you
reading you know in that language
especially a language that's very
different from English for example if
you want to get into different
perspectives you can learn Japanese you
can learn Chinese you can learn Russia
you can learn Arabic you can learn
Persian okay not that common
Oh German Oh Dutch Oh French or Spanish
that's that's that's common that's
unthinking well it's still good to learn
okay but if you really want a complete
complete different view of the world of
all the things you know you're gonna be
you cannot relearn them again because
they're their culture they don't speak
English they're gonna have a view point
of view entirely different from yours
on everything okay so if you learned for
example Chinese you know you really why
am I talking about this because I'm I
was going to tell you I you know I dug
into the Chinese community I was on a
Chinese chat forum just like this code
okay Chinese has their own versions so I
mixed in with with programmers in China
for like two years every day every day I
was there for four hours or something
four hours six hours every day for two
years this is this is around 2004 2014
or 2015 around there okay so I get to
know people you know I get to know what
Chinese programmers are thinking what
are they doing what language they'd use
you know what and how well do they know
English you know you talk to them you
it's like you dive in and much become
one with them you learn you know it's
it's quite fun too because you know you
notice you know for example in
english-speaking world we have lots of
slants means jargons you know 4chan you
know jargons memes you know there's a
bunch of crazy things then you have to
go to you know the the urban dictionary
to know what they mean you know if you
are not in a group you know the game of
Camus talk low tech you know low kick
and you
huge amount of others hundreds you know
means you know the frog kept the Frog a
know that in the same way China China
has their own you know so III beat and
speak Chinese right but however I don't
know what this means
did you look at them some of them they
are really truly extremely funny just
like just like the English ones you know
you see the you you kind of see the word
you know lots of puns
you know the etymology how sudden phrase
arose because maybe because politics of
course China has lots of that the
politics they criticize you know so you
have your Chinese Chinese their own
memes and Internet slants you know lots
of that's a lot fun and so you dig into
for example I saw you know I was when I
was in with we're talking to the Chinese
people you know so I learned I learned
about all these different website you
know and I watch them you so you see a
different it's like different it's like
it's not like oh this is just YouTube in
China no it's not like that because the
entire culture the way they talk the the
kind of material the reaction is
entirely different from what you see on
YouTube okay and and you know that's
fantastic okay so you have all sort of
things you have you know see weird
things you have funny things you have
lots of anime stuff you know you can for
example you can learn how Chinese people
they how they how they we got you know
Japanese animes for example in USA here
we know we know that oh yeah so there's
these usually young people you know we
call them weep weep so we bow yeah we
have a MIMO slang for that we bought in
then they do whatever the Japanese
speedos or whatever go pillows or
whatever so in China they have their own
you know talk or their thoughts about
you know a bunch of things so so anyway
that's interesting about knowing another
language and dive into okay that's what
I like you know so you know I don't like
the main
Stream News I'd like to talk to people a
regional regional people you learn
things from them
and you don't like for example if I have
a political question about Chinese
people for example in USA we hear
everyday Oh China government they are
suppressing you know the no freedom of
speech and all that crap you know total
blatant lie okay propaganda you don't
know it so how do I know you you dive
into a Chinese community you know the
people who live in China you you go into
there you dive in then you see whatever
what they talk every day use you you you
you you see what common people talk
every day not not some some [ __ ]
China China standard news okay not not
some big corporation China sees V you
know news they talk about what they what
they're people like not not that not not
new New York [ __ ] times
[ __ ] the New York Times [ __ ] Factory in
you know CNN [ __ ] [ __ ] the MSNBC ordered
media big media okay you want to dive in
into people and and you you look at them
what they talk about you don't even like
like for example I want to know for
example I want to know what to change
Chinese people you know what they think
of the the you know the Chinese
government you know I know many of them
hate it that's true that that is true
okay but you see that's not the way to
get the answer you don't you don't go
there and ask them hey what ha ha what
do you think of the the current you know
the leader of China that's how that's
not how you get the answers if you do it
that way all the answer you get inspire
senses you know but rather instead you
just go there and and mix with them talk
about everyday things whatever they
talking about you you you know you chat
then you gradually you then you pick up
what they are actually thinking the real
you know the real thing in their minds
so that's so that is what I recommend
okay so that's so that is my story you
know the interesting thing about
learning a new line
which and how you actually learn the
opinions of other country things like
that okay
so are you guys still here are we done
today these notifications I don't want
any notifications I want my life to be
controlled by myself I don't want no
nothing [ __ ] notifications okay so
let's see I got sixteen people here
still and we've been talking for one
hour now so would that be it for today
so so XO we talked about two
mathematicians who are weird and who and
these two happens to to be successful
you know these two great mathematicians
they they are very successful and we
also have programmers like that okay and
some of them by the way it's not like
everyone it's not like oh if you're just
gonna drop out from high school or
college and you just study hard and you
are gonna be successful like them no
they are there are a lot mathematicians
around like me who mop the toilet at
McDonald's you don't hear them they die
a lot okay that you don't hear them
because all the media the hacker news
[ __ ] the reddit year they control
information the Twitter and Facebook you
get just the mainstream the the
mainstream thought the mainstream you
don't you don't you don't get you know
your thought is totally controlling you
don't even know it and especially lots
of you open source and free software
foundation phonetics you don't even know
it and everyday you are just helping
Google you are just helping Google and
Facebook you are helping them become
more powerful with your chant about
open-source because because you don't
know nothing about you never thought
about anything because all your opinions
are just following the mainstream like
you go to hacker news so all the hack
all the tech all the nerds are saying
this there for me open source is good
you you do because this happens to you
every day for 10 years for 20 years
since you were born
okay so so there are a lot other
programmers I want to mention some of
them I talked to several of them they
have done great things in math and all
programming but let's see so yeah so but
I don't know if I should talk talk about
it I don't know if I should complete
talk for 10 minutes about that or
something else by the way so there is
this guy who is kind of a hermit
programmer and he is also a success
story this guy George showed me so it
says you know cottage computer
programming poor by poor letters so
apparently he lives in a hut you know in
in a forest something like that and he
wrote the most popular program which is
the Apple writer so this is 1990s early
1990s Apple writer the word processor so
that's that's interesting so and and I'm
I was going to talk about there are a
few others so this guy we a friend okay
we emailed each other you know over the
years and he died in 2008 it's too sad
you know but he it's he's a fringe okay
he's a fringe he is not that your
typical mathematician but how
he has done great discoveries in this
particular niche thing about this thing
is called zonal hydrants okay zonal
hydrants and his name is Russell tower
you know he doesn't even know calculus
because I remember one one time we were
email each other you know because we
both programming in Mathematica we wrote
you know we write each other and you
know I was ask him so he doesn't know
calculus ma'am you know so you know we
have here a mathematician who don't know
the basic of not modern mathematics like
calculus he doesn't know it nothing he
doesn't know a thing about calculus but
however he has done great work in this
thing about Zhanna Zhanna hedron's
there's a Wikipedia you know you can go
and read about it on Wikipedia and
Stefan Wolfram Stefan Wolfen also wrote
a eulogy about Zhanna hedron's about
that kind Rousseau tower instead of
Stefan Wolfram's you know the great guy
so he wrote a I was surprised because I
didn't know I didn't know Stefan Wolfram
knows him so Stefan Wolfe and wrote
about his death and he you know so it
was a great meet for me so there it is
this guy was so tower you know and he
lives actually not far from here in
California somewhere yeah but you know
why so I wanted to meet him but back
then I was I you know I was like him you
know I was like in poverty I was you
know so I never got to meet him so
that's one of the you know fringe
mathematicians great guy and and there's
other another guy okay this she this
girl this woman
marriage acquaintance she is in UK I
know her since 1991 we you know on
CompuServe math forum and he she she is
also a great mathematician and also he
is she is one of the great expert in
toss okay the toss operating system and
the low-level of the Intel CPU at the
time she is a great master of that and
she she also died kind of she's she's
you know these people are longest loners
like me and like many of you guys
they are loners so anyway I just learned
I learned you know she died in 2009 yeah
I one day I just found out oh she died
yeah and she what has she done she has
solved one of the challenge a math
problem in published by this journal
okay published by there is this journal
seeum okay this this is a very popular
journal I don't know if you guys heard
of it it's popular among mathematicians
or engineers s I am applied mathematics
okay
so one day this magazine put journal
published a problem and I think there's
a competition to solve it something like
that so she solved it and she won the
prize anyway that's that's you know one
of another interesting mathematician and
programmers she's also a programmer and
this is her website back then in 1990s
so anyway that's - that's you know
that's some of the mathematicians I know
and there is another one wrong
eva's oh okay I know this guy we also
exchanged exchange emails quite a few
times you know in the 1990s the Mac came
with a
latest graphing calculator which is just
graphing the name is just called
graphing calculator it's bundled with
every Mac Mac OS around 1995 - tuned to
2001 okay before they created Mac OSX so
it's it's bundled with Mac but this guy
he's by the way he's still around he's
still working on the graphing calculator
because I get sometimes I get emails
from him so he's a so he is another kind
of hermit mathematician like he so he
hears his essay talking about how he
created it by the way so at the time in
also he was not a Apple employee okay
he's actually not an Apple employee he's
just like someone living on the street
or something and he just program and he
went to the Apple building he don't have
a badge but people just let him come you
know let him come he okay
that was you know that was so that's
this guy he saw he's got great story and
he created this graphing calculator is
which is the best cracking graphing
calculator ever probably to this day
okay best interactive graphing
calculator I mean if you just such that
like such for you you'll find it okay
search for his name you know he's got
pictures and galleries I'm not going to
show okay calories okay so it looks like
that okay it's the best interactive
graphing calculator okay he wrote it
himself but in you know this is very sad
in 2002 when Mac OSX came out they
replace this by another one they call it
graphing calculator and that and that is
the one of the worst crap possible to
this day to this day Mac still has that
graphing calculator okay let me show you
the the worst application on the Mac
the world's cracking Kevin eats a crap
okay this one now they called guava in
2002 Apple we placed that graphing
calculator by this one this is crap okay
no actually I haven't you tried it for
ten years I don't know if they changed
much but I think it's the same one okay
yeah you know that logo let's see this
is a worst [ __ ] possible there's so it's
you know so why why did this happen you
know you see Apple had the greatest
graphing calculator interactivity free
bundled with Mac but then when when when
they switch to Mac os10 they ditched
this okay completely they'll be faced it
with one that's ten times as lousy that
is a crap okay it's a crap crap why did
that happen
because well politics institution
structure you know when you are a French
you have you you you know it doesn't
matter how great is your software you
can't you can't just you know get your
program to be part of you know the Mac
goes things like that so why is why is
it great because it's got interactivity
interactivity with the most intuitive
interface you know I have to show you I
have to talk about it to do justice but
anyway I have article okay let me show
you
sorry math you go to my math blog and
after so we're gonna talk about three
more minutes and I'll be it okay so you
go to my math block you go to math
graphics gallery okay you scroll down
then you go to this arco geometry
requirements for a visualization system
for 2020 okay by the way before this
this is written in 2007 so before it was
named
you know requirement for a visualization
for 2010 it didn't happen then I renamed
it to 2020 I don't think we have it yet
we didn't happen so I'm gonna to change
the name to 2030 requirement for a
visualization system for 2030 so what is
this article about because I do a lot
math visualization programming you know
so I on this article I showed I tell you
what are things we need you know and and
I talked about what is a great user
interface and what are the things we
need in GUI what are the programming
framework the system we need to help us
easily create these interactive things
for math for geometry visualization so
this is my essay my opinion I don't
think to this day we have it we don't
have it we have what we have is by this
programming odd facts like OpenGL [ __ ]
you know where you two programmers
rotating cube requires 1000 lines and
10,000 hours to understand what what are
these pipelines in [ __ ] ink in float and
float textual maps that this [ __ ] ok
program created by this C C prosperous
this this this this type of programmers
this kernel CP you know the open gr this
low-level this these idiots why did what
they do things like that because they
have no no experience and conception
from the math background they don't know
nothing they don't know nothing about
math they have no experience so what
they create is this in this industrial
you know the sea like the CLC processor
first are the epitome of examples they
create things such as you have float you
have int you have this memory management
like rust rust idiocy rust the
programming language rust who is fast oh
you can control memory [ __ ] [ __ ] these
people so they have no conception they
don't understand no experience about
okay so that's why these programmers
they create this raw kind of thing like
UNIX like the UNIX philosophy [ __ ] UNIX
Camila is all [ __ ] up [ __ ] and get
like the get you know get
incomprehensible [ __ ] why so they create
this type of people they create things
that's like tightly bound to the CPU
you know they like to the every school
every every dip switch of the CPU that's
that's what they create okay so they
don't understand they don't understand
the the abstract kind of the
higher-level CPU or application
interface they don't know they don't
know these things and in fact they are
against kind of these things because
they they prefer they want the low-level
you know the more difficult you know
it's part of the code the more difficult
things are the better it is so that's
why you have all these people loving oh
oh you're a Linux Linux FreeBSD command
line you know a bunch of crap
incomprehensible [ __ ] that's what these
people love so II quit and like Emacs me
Emacs and VI Emacs versus VI every day
you hear it every day non-stop for 20-30
years that's that is why the that's that
is my opinion and my regards to this
programmer this this this nerd you know
these hacker types I despise them okay
so anyway back to this article so I hear
we don't have this system today we all
we have you know then we have open Gia
we have WebGL today I know it's I know
it's easier to use by zero [ __ ] okay
it's not like that okay so anyway what
I'm saying is I so I wrote this article
which which explains your list what are
what things are important the GUI things
we need and the system we need to help
us to create this kind of visualization
interactive things so if you read this
article then you understand why that
graphing calculator is truly one of the
greatest software ok this this software
okay that that is my grant that is my
rent for today okay so let me actually
there are several a few other people I
haven't talked about you know some weird
programmers there's one more guy okay
this guy anyway okay let me read the
comments we're gonna shut down for two
three minutes two minutes
Alan says do you think Hermits lifestyle
is often associated with Passover season
getting away from state can violence yes
it is often associated with that
pacifist ISM that is true it is so often
associated with hippies
you know the hippie movement but I think
those homemade type of people mostly I
would say half of it is from their genes
it's it's personality okay it's a
personality that creative these people
like like me okay it's a personality
thing you will pong with it you know
different person are born with different
personalities different inclinations so
I think I think this hermit type are you
know half of Eddie's because they were
born that way well the other half reason
or the or the other reason is because
well night like like what they say not
nurture and culture so they grew up at
time you know with the hippie movement
for example so that's what I think you
know actually Richard Stallman is one of
these type kind of and by the way let's
not forget that people are very complex
okay so when I say this type is kind of
general
so in fact we are you know of course we
are sometimes very different
and I know a lot of my followers like
that you know we we share similarities
so you guys are following me and
especially we can see on this court we
are you know most of us are not
mainstream for sure
so reaper says we versus long piece is a
term for the unprecedented historical
period following the end of world war ii
in 1940 in 1945 to the present day o
long piece the period of the Cold War
1945 to 1991 was marked by the absence
of major wars between the great powers
of the period the United States and the
USSR such a period of relative peace
between major powers has not been
documented in human history and since
the Roman Empire I am not sure about
that well what about Korean War and
Vietnam War I don't think so either
I don't think I agree with that what
about Korean War Vietnam War Iraq war
you know and yeah so so you are saying
well it's the greatest long peace you
know so you are saying from 1945 to
today if you look at history everything
then this period current you know in the
past 70 years is like the most peaceful
I'm not sure yeah I don't I don't think
I agree with that because there are lots
of things you know I mean if you you
know if I'm gonna comment on on that
first why don't I I'm not sure I do I
don't know I don't know for sure but I
don't think so I don't think first of
all factually I don't think it's a long
period of time where we have what we we
have less Wars I don't think so
and the second second my second reason
is that I think if we look at history
today you see we we it's not like we
have longest piece because we cannot
start wars today we cannot start major
Wars you if we start major Wars it's
gonna wipe all of us out you know
nuclear weapons so you could say oh it's
because you know well if if it is true
that we have the longest piece period in
history in human history that doesn't
mean much because well the reason we
have longest piece is because we got
nuclear bombs over you know what once
marking we are dead you know you don't
call that longest you know it's not
really peace it's like you know oh
alternatively we already dead 10 years
ago
we waited we've if the you know if the
nuclear war happened so I yeah and also
today because you know we technology we
we can you know it's not like in the
past when you have war people go with
your knifes or whatever you kill people
or guns not machine guns you kill you
know by next year everything is back to
novel no more you know not like today
today you have you know these bombs and
you know you kill millions of people in
mass so Dion says once we'd almost all
modern mathematics is based on something
that came out of Reuben Dick's brain
yeah I think that's that's I think that
I think that's somewhat true okay I
cannot I don't think I I cannot say for
sure because actually this guy's work to
understand this guy's work basically
means you have to have a PhD
overland you know degree in math to
understand his work yeah so I yeah
also be really interesting to have
English video that reviews a Chinese
internet sites lots of interesting
features that are hard for English
design does to appreciate you know one
of the very interesting thing in this
Chinese video site is that they have
what you called bullet screens okay like
this is very funny okay
this is fantastic funny like if I watch
a video let's see which one to watch I
don't really you know they have lots of
you know crap and you know they like or
things Phi one thing though they don't
have politics right that's true you know
China they don't allow you to criticize
you know the the country that is true
but not like the typical American think
okay but anyway let's watch them let me
show you the bullet screen it's this is
truly funny okay I don't want install
nothing wait why is this refresh you
know one one thing interesting is that
they have this bullet screen okay I'm
not sure I can play it here is it
playing sometimes some some movies
you're gonna watch you cannot watch in
USA because they forbid it maybe I have
to go to Google Chrome I don't any
anyway so they have basically on YouTube
you have comments right at the bottom
but but in Japan and China people can
type comments that just fly through on a
swing at that moment so when you watch a
movie you can see all people's other
people's reactions and some some of them
are extremely funny so that's called
bully swing you if you search you're
fine Wikipedia articles about that
okay so I think that's it
a lot of game I using different math
physics to make the game work lots of
hack not necessarily one way in one
physics or even do you still hear that
Java is the devil do you still use
closure no I don't use closure okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching bye guys bye my stuff and
sponsor me PayPal and all that PayPal
and patreon and Bitcoin and whatever on
my website you find the link didn't have
creeping problems so crippling problems
is why self-driving driving costs scares
me goes to show only comic would be
allowed to write game okay okay I'm
gonna shut down when I shut down the
comments we also shut down so
bye Merry Christmas everyone