good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
so today I'm going to talk about
something something random topic I don't
know what yet but I'm hoping for people
to come out and direct me you know ask
questions and stuff and meanwhile
there's no nobody watching yet and I'm
just going to oh hi green deck good to
see you so so today is going to be
random ish do you have any questions
like okay I can talk about first of all
technical topic or non technical topic
tech technical meaning I can talk about
Emacs emag Lisp or teaching about Emacs
Emacs lips or programming JavaScript
goal and programming languages and so on
anything technical or mathematics yeah
that's my that's my true love math and
so among the technical topics I can do a
very focused like you know you might
call it professional meaning that for
example I'm going to teach you a max
Lisp you know so there's no commentary
about Emacs culture about Richard
Stallman and so on you know I'm just
going to teach like one subject you know
like a like a like like a professor so
that's technical topic now on the other
hand okay zero watching now on the other
hand I can talk about I can talk about
random random random ish stuff random
ish stuff gonna be
let's see when the random ish stuff is
gonna be literature philosophy social
happenings commentary on YouTube on
futurology you know that advancements of
future can you tell us something
interesting about your work experience
in programming or something oh yeah sure
well I haven't been working in a
industrial in you know in the
corporation for the since about 2004
okay but okay let me give you a short
amount of my programming history you
know employment you know with so my
first job is is at Wolfram research
Wolfram research you know that's the guy
who makes Mathematica Wolfram language
Wolfram Alpha and I worked there in 1995
for half a year technically I'm an
intern you know but you know the guy
asked me to stay but I decided not to
stay it you know and because I was going
to Berkeley UC Berkeley but I think I
end up not going anyway so 1995 is wolf
I'm you know wolf I'm research that's in
Illinois Champaign Capanna cabaña
Illinois that's a small town in Illinois
then in 1998 I joined a start-up now
that's you know the Bay Area Silicon
Valley startup crazy
that's when internet just began and all
the companies are making stuff on the
internet so I joined a start-up I'm you
know one of the three the first three
for fourth employee let's see ya the
first three the third one so you know so
that company is called let's see it's a
job hub so what is it and the name dream
power okay
actually if you let's see if that the
domains Steve
there but you know obviously the owner
is is someone else brainpower calm let's
haven't looked at this for ten years
this see okay so the domains gun I mean
nobody is using that domain so it's
brain power calm and that is a job hub
meaning it's like monster or dice
monster como dice calm or whatever is
today's you know monster and dice are
two of the biggest you know back then so
yeah so you know our company you know
which is three programmers including me
he's spring power calm we you know we
create jobs you know job listening so
corporations they want to hire
programmers they come you know they post
their you know advertisements on site
site and programmers you know come to
our site to look for a job so and I
remember back then I wrote a book
database entirely by myself of course
but database in Perl like written in
Perl four thousand lines of code now I
don't I think I still have the code
somewhere if I really want to find it I
think so but it will take some bit
because you know my there's a period of
time few years ago you know I was about
to die you know my cousin I don't have a
computer I don't have a money to buy a
computer like my computer broke down and
I was that you know the you know I was
you know that's it and so I lost lots of
data you know but typically I'm the type
of a guy who keeps everything I've ever
written all my emails like I pay
attention I like that keep them you know
so but that you know that hasn't been
happening in past ten years because my
life went bad and you know it's just you
know
but you know actually look at the guy
Steffen wolfin he wrote a blog recently
interesting I met him in 1995 and he I
liked him you know as you know let's see
and you know this guy is spectacular in
many ways now okay so he saw so well
first of all yeah I mean actually I
share many of his outlooks and
philosophy the approach to math of
Sciences the way he think about things I
shared many aspects you know I you know
I look at things very similar way he
does about anything like technology AI
computer science but anyway let me get
back to the okay so he wrote articles
seeking the productive life some details
of my personal infrastructure hero
usually writes like okay yeah we have to
click on that so click on that each of
his blog is like 10,000 words you know
it look okay so let me show you one page
page wait hold on a second let me
magnify so you can kind of see it's a
one page I'm Paige Paige Paige Paige
Paige Paige Paige and that's only like
one fifth of it you know you can just
keep going but basically what what he
does I mean he's a pack rat you know so
called pack rat that he keeps every
documentation as a record but also he
also keeps a record of his life like
personal life even happy great you know
how many hours he sleeps
you know since since you know 30 years
ago
you know whenever possible with
technology so he's kind of like that and
and you know just in the recent few
years he started to write about
them so you know I didn't know until
until you read them and I'm actually
kind of like that when I was like 14
years old now you know today by the way
if you guys have any comments
keep them coming okay keep them coming
because then I can see I'm talking to
people you know people are listening
find it an interesting or something so
you know it's like when you speak to
audience you can you can see their faces
you know you know how how good you are
doing if you're not you know like if you
are not you know if they are doing you
can see it you know right in an
expression when they when you are
talking about something that catches
people's attention you have to then you
see it in their faces they you know
intensely looking at you and stuff but
you know via video I cannot see you guys
and also I was going to talk about how
to achieve how to do that how do how to
be a good speaker but we are getting
into a nested topics but anyway let me
go back to so so this guy Stefan Wolfe
I'm so he keeps a meticulous record of
everything he do I mean in a spectacular
way it's not just like oh you know
writing Diaries every day oh okay I was
talking about so when I was like 14 in
Montreal Canada you know today you have
a [ __ ] fit you know those watches that
you wear that monitors your heartbeat so
I bought that watch back in like 1986 I
don't remember how much maybe it's $200
or $500 Canadian back then 1980 around
1986 so it's a Casio watch that monitors
my heartbeat and I have to wear wear a
belt like Electra belts on my chest so I
was worrying it all day like I mean
continued continuously like 24 hours for
like almost kind of you know I tried to
wear it at all times but
it kind of went on and off for five or
six years so you know even so back then
you know I was doing that nobody you
know nobody else is doing you know
there's no even I mean the the the
watches that monitors your heart rate
only became you know somewhat popular
ten years ago and it's not and you and
you have to like put your finger there
to measure a B but but today you wear
those you know Fitbit swatch that they
measure your heartbeat by they actually
have two optical sensors like they they
shoot light pins into your skin and they
have cameras so they they watch your
skin and your blood vessel when the
heart beats you know the blood vessel
goes so that's how they monitor you know
how that's how they can see your
heartbeat but back then you know 1986
the my watch the heart monitoring watch
is I wear a belt on my chest and the
belt has electrodes you know so called
electrodes which is basically Robert
electricity transmitting rubber so you
have two contacts on my chest and they
they they they are electrically
connected and each time the posts get
through it sends a radio signal to my
watch so that's how it works so so yeah
I was you know I was when I was when I
was younger so I had that and I was
going to become a like a I'm going to
become a cyborg you know because I'm so
much into technology so much into
technology and take and you know
computer science well well yeah
technology and you know stuff so and and
my personality is such that I'm I'm very
technically I think I'm you would
classify as a schizoid personality so
let me type it
that's technically called schizoid
personality disorder that's another
topic but basically it's a it's a
personality of loners you know you know
some guy who talked with who doesn't
like to talk to people I mean every in
every other aspect the guy is normal
except that he you know he's a loner you
know there are a lot people like that
you know you say you know in English
word you have long wolf you know like
you know you are kind of cast aside from
society not not because they cast you
aside because you just I just don't you
know I don't like to mix it you know
it's just your personality you know you
don't mix in so they are of course
there's a degree of it
you know most nerds are like that you
know most most nerds you know they
aren't a social you know they don't do
well in a social situation they feel
nervous when it's about people you know
the old people they don't know and so on
and on the other hand there are extreme
other side extroverts you know and on
the other extreme there's there's a
personality disorder called dramatic
theatrical borderline okay that is
called borderline okay that's kind of I
think that's the one borderline
personality disorder
this odd I've met people who are like
that actually so the borderline
personality disorder is such that they
are very dependent they are they like
they always need someone's approval they
always want constantly need your
attention
you know let's see borderline
personality disorder is a long-term
pattern of abnormal behavior
characterized by unstable relationships
with other people no okay okay I'm not
talking wait wait I got I got it wrong
this this is not the one I'm talking
about the one I'm talking about is a
okay schizoid is here anyway for a
period of time I have studied all the
personality disorders you know I was
wondering if I'm you know maybe
depressive or bipolar or you know or
so-called today is fashionable to call
someone a HDD or something you know you
know attention deficit something
something it's almost like fashionable
so anyway
Oh histrionic there it is that's what
I'm trying looking for histrionic
histrionic Personality Disorder now this
disorder is the opposite of schizoid now
this type of people they are they are
always dramatic and theatrical you know
they constantly they like I mean to such
a degree that's why it's called disorder
that they need I mean if they don't do
that they they shrivel they you know
they they crumble down they cannot live
you know they cannot function they have
to like constantly you know so let's
read it histrionic Personality Disorder
is defined by the American Psychiatric
Association as a personality disorder
characterized by a pattern of excessive
attention seeking emotions usually
beginning in the early
hood okay yeah so that's the one that's
the opposite of the schizoid personality
disorder which is longness you know
people who don't like who you know so I
you know this is huge topic I can talk a
lot about it my experiences you know
there are people I actually know who are
like one of these actually on Twitter
I've known people who have told me in
private chat they are histrionic
Personality Disorder and usually you can
you can kind of tell you know the people
are when people are abnormal you can
kind of tell from there you know
interactions and anyway so personality
disorder is a you know big subject you
know it's a by the way why is it
disorder by the way it's a it's it's
kind of like a SPECT spectrum okay it's
not like so I mean each of us have
different personalities but in the case
when your personality is to such a
extreme degree that you are unable to
function normally in society you know
you are unable to get a job you are
unable to work with people you know
that's when it's called disorder you
know that that's how you know that's how
it's defined I mean that how it
functions you know the that's when it's
called personality disorder otherwise I
mean I mean what everyone has different
personality so anyway so back to the
topic so I was saying yeah I was you
know I was kind of you know the loner
type you know I was ready to become a
cyborg but you know or become like tied
into the network I mean become part of
the computer you know in Japanese
animations in Japanese science fiction's
they are huge amount of these concepts I
mean Japanese they they actually the
anime you know the you know American
actor Commack now anime like but anyway
the Japanese stories they yeah
japanese sign fires you know unique
expression in there and you know
animations they they are quite they are
very good I mean of course Americans got
different style but the Japanese is
quite you know very good you know so
many so for example ghosting in a shell
you know ghost in the show is about the
story where anyway keep the comments
coming okay
did I answer the questions so let's go
back to you know let's go back to the
topic so so yeah I was kind of into very
much into sciences and you know it's
like almost ready to become you know
type into the computer become part of
the network for example that concept is
also in Star Trek and by the way in Star
Trek there's an episode called the
schizoid man okay
Star Trek the piece or it men have you
guys seen it type it type six person
watching say something guys yeah Star
Trek The Next Generation the schizoid
men okay so let's see the pictures I
want to see the pictures Google I don't
want to use Google Google is like evil
empire you know incredible evil empire
today it's so sad
I want to see images that's what yeah
that's the one
so this guy and this girl is beautiful
oh my god that's the wait so anyway this
is this guy's kiss old man anyway he
ends up you know he ends up when he died
because he's got a terminal disease I
think so he he made you know he input
himself into the computer so he become
part of the I think enterprise computers
I mean oh his memories his person you
know but any by the way that is also a
topic we can talk about for a long time
like you know in science fiction you
have this concept where you can a person
can just transfer I mean just become
part of the network like oh you're you
know your brain your memories your
thinking's you know your soul you know
become part of the computer program you
know but however you know whether that
is the possibility of that is of course
it's open actually you know nobody knows
it's like it's like the debate about
singularity about whether you know AI or
the machines will one day become
sentient or become you know like you
know acquire self-awareness and and
maybe take over you human animals anyway
so back then so I was you know that type
of guy anyway so back to so Stefan
Wolfram in back to I was my my
employment my programming experience now
I'm limited to just talking about
employer-employee programming experience
in the corporate world so so in 1998 I
was with brain power but after one year
brain power
didn't you know had problems we didn't
succeed funding yeah we ran out of
funding so then I joined another startup
company his called web order it
see if the domain still web order comm
okay it's it's it's run by some domain
squatter
but not web oder dot-com is big we are
the biggest so what we do we are
creating a online store you know you
guys know about Yahoo stow measure of a
man yeah I think that's also yes that's
the episode measure of men where data is
you know ingot Rio okay so great thank
you green deck so I was okay let's go
back so 1998 so 1999 I joined a company
called web order calm we all start up in
trading mountain view actually it's the
only nearby where I live like if I walk
there it's going to be one hour walk you
know walk one hour from where I live
right now so web or dot-com what we do
is we create online stores like we
create a server and software and
influence online stores and merchants
you know whatever you want to sell
usually small to medium merchants you
know you go to our website you can
create a store then you can sell you
stuff your stuff you know of course with
your own domains you know or without
your own domains you know it's like
yahoo store but even today I'm not sure
people know about Yahoo store anymore
because that's back in 2000 Yahoo store
so Yahoo still actually came after us
you know I mean it happens after we had
it first and so web order calm it was
that was big because anyway so we're
border calm but in 2001 around 2001 we
got bought by a company called natok
here you might have heard Natalia by the
way it's owned by Motorola
so I mean things change you know
companies come and go and or bought by
this company and then but by another
company and merge with another and so on
you know the ownership changes and
that's how capitalism works so not hope
yeah let's see I haven't checked these
these domains for like 20 years
okay not hope here site cannot be
reached let's see if I can find some
logos of not no topia okay I probably
gonna it probably is going to turn out
to be a bunch of unrelated things not
hope here yeah not hope here router you
know they we used to make routers well
let me explain not then not not any of
these these are unrelated actually now
they're here here here is our you see
this image in partnership with NATO Pia
now that was the what this image this
logo on the right there was I mean even
that you know that's not our internal
logo but I think that that was our
company but all the others yeah this
this router we make but anyway sona
Tapia part spark but web order around
2001 for huge amount I don't I don't
remember but I didn't make much money
out of it but you know they were but I
mean you know some of our money you know
back then because of stocks and you know
and I basically just lived off that but
you know it cannot last forever I lived
off that amount of money for like ten
years and live in a very very very cheap
way you know you know just barely
leaving a car so anyway not Hopi about
web order calm so not hope here was a
company that does they they they yeah
they make routers and other things I
don't remember now it's been you know
twenty years but my brother is one of
the thing they make and also they I
think they they merged with another
company called Timbuktu now do you guys
remember Timbuktu on a Mac the name is
team back to I think they spare it that
way but Timbuktu is you know today you
have screen sharing applications
you know like on Windows you can you can
admit remotely like you can log into
another person's computer and see the
whole screen same thing on the Mac and
Linux got you know its own things so
that's that's popular today and that's
actually part of the operating system
but back then you know that's like a new
technology nobody does that but think
Timbuktu yes like like TeamViewer but
Timbuktu is like the earliest you know
the earliest the granddaddy of them all
on the Mac it works on a Mac so if you
have a Mac and you know I have a Mac I
can I can log into your Mac and see your
whole you know Mac screen remember this
is back in 2000 you know to 0 0 0 year
to K and actually Timbuktu is like you
know very popular in the 1990s hi
Matthews so solid so by the way Matthews
in any anyone coming here you know to
keep the comments coming you know keep
ask questions or you know if you want to
change change subject just let me know
I was going I was talking about my
programming experience with cooperations
so anyway web border part
why bother I mean the Natalia sometimes
earlier I think they merge with the
company that made Timbuktu I don't
remember who makes Timbuktu but anyway
you can all based information I believe
I'm pretty sure it's on Wikipedia so
let's type it Timbuktu
let's see if I can yeah I'm pretty sure
it's on web on Wikipedia you can get
there no not this one no Timbuktu yeah
no let's go to the top here then
yep Natalia was a company headquarters
in Emeryville California that produces a
variety of broadband products including
modems routers gateways Wi-Fi devices
the company also produced MBBS servant
as well as Timbuktu there
Timbuktu remote administration software
now let's go to that page so Timbuktu
you know how they still have a stable
release in 2013 it's interesting nobody
is using it man yeah do you have
TeamViewer and you have you know most
mostly I suppose you know it's people
just using use the building in the
operating system okay so no tophi about
butters so I don't know topia or at web
order I mean we are huge okay we I
believe back then our Perl software is
the largest pearl software in a world I
mean just lets Mac that was my guess
because nobody can know the details you
know how many lines of code each company
wrote you know but back then it was my
guess that we would you know let's say
top top five or top 10 biggest pearl
source code but anyway the technology we
were using was actually I mentioned this
in another live stream before but anyway
we were using Solaris operating system
made by Sun Microsystems we were using
Oracle we were using Java which is a
main server and we were using Java
servlet what's called a servlet back
them it's like Tomcat Tomcat is one of
the but we were not using Tomcats but
Tomcat is a similar idea we we wrote our
own servlet then we use pearl pearl main
application software so you know the
Apache servers you know they deal with
you know traffic comes in then the Java
runs you know handles name then it's
passed to Java servlet kind of Java
servlet then Java servlet talks to our
Perl software so that's the architecture
the Perl software is the actual part
that does the business logic you know
you know creating a website you know
like remember the business is Web Store
so much and can create their store and
buyers can to go to his store and buy
things put in shopping cart you know
remember shopping cart like Amazon
shopping cart so ours is the one of the
first web order so my so I joined web
ordered my superiors you know the
company boss they made money they they
made a lot money anyway so but I left I
was actually laid off by NATO Pia in
2002 October I was laid off and that was
you know because you know back then at
that time there's huge amount of led
lay-lay of studying in 2000 you know
huge amount you know that's why they
could dot-com bubble you know like every
company is laying off he go and you know
people feel sad so in my company a lot
of people get laid off you know I didn't
happen to me but then eventually you
know they laid me off
building a well yeah you can let me talk
about okay so let me finish about my
story with my experience with companies
okay but actually that's it
that's the end so after nutopia you know
I haven't worked with any major
corporations no I did you know I you
know I did come as a contractor on and
off basically well and and basically I
started to work on my website so you
know I have a website you know I have
several domains now like five domains
and I have a total of some ten thousand
HTML articles manually written page by
page tag by tag by me you know over the
past 20 years in Emacs of course with
the help of Emacs command email is
command I wrote myself so here's a
question about how about I show a
guideline into building my own major mod
yeah but I can talk about that but
that's a big topic
I'll show you so I won't be talking
about that today because that by itself
is going to take one hour just for a
introduction of course because you know
it's a project it's a programming
project but anyway if you go to my Emacs
blog so such folks sorry
Emacs I show you where to find an info
ok I give you the guide like I talk
about it a little bit for you know a few
minutes and you should be able to follow
it and and start to write major mod so
such folks sorry Emacs and you go you
you arrive at my Emacs tutorial now go
to the practical emag list now here's a
here's a Emacs tutorial you know
practical email is where I focus I used
I've
emphasis on the practical aspects like
how to instead of is instead the you
know a theory of you know howi'm at
least the language works
so anyway read the first two boxes you
know that will get you started on Emacs
Lisp the you know read the first two
back two bucks okay then after that you
can decide where you want to go because
in Emacs there are so many ways you can
write a major mod you can write a shell
you can write something like tired you
can write again you know there's a
Tetris in Emacs many people have showed
that so I'm not going to show it you can
see YouTube tetris such for tetris Emacs
made several other games like snakes as
well so you can write all these things
in Emacs they are fairly diverse so you
know it depends on what you need you you
do what you want you go you know you
learn the part you need so if you want
to write a major mod that you know
typically I assume you are writing a
major mod for programming language then
you go to this one you see you see here
on the Left panel very the major mod so
you click that then you got you know
basically to navigation boxes then just
follow at them you know starting with
the first one you know read a couple
then you you'll know how to do it it's
not hard if you actually in fact if you
just begin with this article in one hour
you will have your major mod for syntax
highlighting at least so Matthew is
salsa so is that is that good so I mean
I'm going I'm running live stream you
know every day like yeah I'm doing it
every day now so just the next time you
see me you know just I mean you know I
tell me you want to see that then we can
talk about yeah that's a good topic to
cover so I'm you know I'm going to do
one live stream about how to
a major mod okay by the way if I
pronounced anyone's name incorrectly
just say so so I can see it in a comment
so Sam all people just use SSH well not
really
yeah people use SSH but mostly Linux
people you know they do that but not
necessarily yeah well that's a you know
that's an interesting question by itself
you know there's always the question you
know the debate about command line
versus GUI you know command line is
always precise and very especially you
know text terminals you know text only
command line for remote computer or sex
access you know that's very efficient
because you are just transmitting text
whereas if you are transmitting images
or video that's you know ten or hundred
times more bandwidth required however
you know terminals you got a major
problem you because you to do that it
requires you to land huge that you have
you literally have to have like one or
two years of programming you know or
system in experience to actually know
what you are doing you know one wrong
command you crashes your server I think
that's you know when wrong when wrong
command
RM - F slash you know wiped out that
yourself
Matthias Matthews okay okay so anyway so
yeah but on the other hand GUI graphical
user interface that's that's what you
know the word to describe that is
intuitive you know any moment pop can do
it and if you are you know a program you
can just follow you know the menu and
you can carry your job you know you can
carry things out that's why Microsoft
micro Microsoft
thrives in many aspects in this way by
the way okay so but the problem with the
GUI is that okay from the geeks from the
Nerds perspective most will say oh you
have to use the mouse I hate it you know
we hear it all day day and night every
day you know buddies linux geeks but
they are yeah there are several issues
let me explain okay first of all you
know if you don't want to use the mouse
you don't have to okay you can use
keyboard shortcut like entire you can
you know at back at you know Microsoft
Windows actually was designed so that
you can operate the whole operating
system without the mouse okay
unlike the Mac the Mac always I mean
Steve Jobs he's the idea his vision
requires you to use the mouse you cannot
operate a Macintosh without using the
mouse now today with you know today I
think you can but not probably not
entirely because you know technology you
know it's been over 20 years
you know things improve but anyway Steve
Jobs he he requires you to use Mouse but
Windows actually is designed you don't
have to use the mouse you do everything
just by keyboard and it's actually quite
efficient you press the Alt key the menu
pops up then you just press other keys
that invokes a shortcut so it's a
combination of commit of key press but
so it has the advantage of key press
only yet it also has the advantage of
giving you the context like what command
you are calling so it's a it's almost
like a hybrid so it's very there was an
extremely great idea but these days I
think that also rotted away because we
need because you know the cell phone
interface came you know became popular
you and then you have tablets you know
using your fingers so the the original
idea of using odd key to invoke all
commands that kind of like disappeared I
mean like in browsers like you cannot
you know they stopped you know even
showing in the menus on top in browsers
so you know you don't even see the menus
it's instead of it's hidden with on the
right side with three bars and it only
has a limited amount of commands and
usually they don't have a shortcut
corresponding to it so it's crap you
know but but well I can tell you why
it's going that way because again it's
because you know vast majority of people
they don't know what a [ __ ] you know the
heck is owed key you know keyboard
shortcuts they don't know they don't
even know the concept shortcuts so
anyway so I was talking about menu
actually I wrote article I want to show
you so menu versus command line so in
this article I talk in detail yeah GUI
versus command line a unified design so
I was you know this UI user interface
kind of things
it's one of my obsession so I study it
you know over the past 10 years
you know casually but you know I always
it's it's like programming language
design you know everything related to
design I have a some sort of obsession
about it so I kept thinking about
command line versus you know UI which is
better why it is better you know you
know then you know and the history of
them or and what could possibly be
designed you know to cover the flaws and
so on so anyway in this article I
discuss I come up away such that command
line and UI is unified so you have the
both you have advantage advantages of
both and by the way when you are
obsessed about some subject I mean
typically we all think you know
especially the hacker geek types
programmers we think we know everything
I mean this is saying you know suffer
[ __ ] sophomores suffer most likes means
second
year in college and there's a comp a
satire satirical Rob less ASAP or more
means suffer more Remini say my [ __ ]
actually I think that is neat etymology
of Safa more it literally means say my
[ __ ]
because you know once you are a teen
then you went to college then you
learned about something you know
something about Sciences of philosophy
or history then suddenly you think you
know so much oh yeah yeah yeah I know
about the stuff I know history you know
but then they say you know people
usually say the more you learn the less
you think you know that is actually true
I mean yeah that is true in general so
you know then then the history and
science is also huge I mean
imaginably huge okay they are just they
are beyond a person can ever learn any
little things about it you know this
like beyond you know so anyway so so
anyway back to this topic so I was you
know writing this article but however
you know way in in my in my wondering
about all these different topics in
philosophy and you know Sciences you
just notice that many things you know
there's a huge history I mean the more
you learn you dig up history and you
have you seen in many cases you know
people have actually covered it you know
they've they've thought about it you
have they have they have created a
system of that but you you don't you
just don't hear it you like you'd you
you will not hear it at all in the
hacker news [ __ ] yeah you know in
order popular you know forums you don't
you don't hear those things they are
just buried buried in history but they
are there if you really you know study a
lot you see them you know almost every
subject math notations history of math
notation
history of programming languages you
know maybe you have you are into
programming languages right then you
think oh you know about it but actually
there's a lot more I mean not just
ceased I mean this so much more in
history I mean for example I know well I
know about this I know about history of
Haskell I know about history of ML F
sharp or camel you know like the whole
history of functional programming but
not really because this you know this
like how deep you go it's almost like
bottomless you can spend your whole life
just study history of foreign languages
just just that one topic nothing else
like you do nothing else in your life
you know so anyway let me get back to
the command line versus GUI so so
apparently there's this guy Jef Raskin
he's actually picked a fairly popular I
think you know for anyone who is
interested in GUI all the designers you
I you know might have heard him in
anyway so he have designed kind of GUI
stuff and I read it it's very good you
know but but they just never picked
picked you you they never they failed
you know that's you know essentially
they've you know so many technology many
good was really good ones they fail
because well simply because it's
actually not supposed to be surprising
because you know the success or the
popularity of technology is almost never
about how how good it is technically net
is almost never about the merit of the
technology it's it's 99% due to social
causes you know you have to market it
you have to have fund you have to have
someone to you know things like that so
many things
so anyway that that's what okay so I've
talked about my history of employment
with tech companies then I talked about
how to write the Emacs major mod a
little intro they are talk about GUI
versus command line I talked about
dot-com bubble what so what else I've
been talking for 50 minutes now so let
me read the comments hacker culture
oh okay so let's see okay so there's a
question about hacker culture first of
all let me bring up the challah call now
the hacker culture article is actually a
index of of many articles like hundreds
of articles so easier a particular one
you are talking about
oh is it this article are you talking
about but anyway so there is that
article then netiquette anthropology now
this article belongs to the index of
netiquette anthropology that's you know
people regard me as a troll edition back
back in the 2000s they regard me Astro
you know some say I'm the great you know
I'm the greatest troll because I can
tell you why because I'm I'm none
I'm a nonconformist okay me I don't
conform
I don't conform to social norms well all
of these has to do with you know they
tres you know everything anyway else to
trace this back to the personality so
that just happens to my personality okay
and I'm a schizoid you know basically a
loner
you know I'm an introvert I'm a nerd and
a fairly extreme case I mean there are
more extremes you know they are crazy
you know people but I'm fairly you know
extreme because all the acid I sit in
his chair like more than 10 hours 10
hours a day statistically I'm talking
about statistically not oh I think I
woke it you know eight hours a day no I
you know almost like basically
statistically sit in this chair for ten
hours a day on average for the past ten
years and what I do I read and you know
Wikipedia let me show you let me show
you this article
encyclopedia my experiences so there are
several articles you know I of course I
have like thousands of articles you know
you can you can like read about it
offline you know these are several
articles they are almost ten years old
old written when Wikipedia is still like
like not as well as accepted today I
mean today everybody refers to a video
oh look just look up Wikipedia but back
then you see this is 2003 this is 2007
Wikipedia is still sometimes
controversial you know people say you
know don't trust Wikipedia and so on you
know so you are you know I'm absolutely
observing the the the growth of humanity
the history I mean observing the society
how technology changes it oh you know
like you know you observe it and you
make a record of it so so here we can
see now you know it's 20 years since
Wikipedia began it didn't begin just
like Oh Wikipedia are great everyone
start to use it no but you know back
then they are still printed
encyclopedias like Britannica and
Microsoft Encarta but eventually they
died because of Wikipedia so so what
we're talking about yeah I was going to
show you an article where I have like
I have like thousands of links to
Wikipedia let's see sorry in Emacs let's
go to my Emacs website because on that
side you can find it oh for a change let
me show you my code then sorry movie KP
do
okay I have to wait it's here
emag list
script examples right grab find string
insert HTML validate matching brackets
generate link report that's the one so
this is a him at least script you can
run and that will generate all links I
have to Wikipedia from all my websites
and wait yeah
and the page I want to show you is a
[ __ ] where's it
yeah I can just show you the path man I
can just show you this way I can sorry
org Wikipedia links so I'm gonna show
you the page you can see on the website
as well but I stopped maintaining this
page so I have so back in 2016 I have
seven thousand links to Wikipedia from
my websites and since 2016 I actually
stopped linking to Wikipedia so but
anyway so you can see this page is you
know these links so each one of this
page is a link has has one at least has
a link to Wikipedia articles some other
go on Wikipedia so and by the way I also
stopped linking them so you cannot just
click it to go there because I stopped I
stopped linking to Wikipedia and I
stopped maintaining this page because I
don't you know I don't want to I don't
want to promote we keep Wikipedia
anymore
well for for quite a few reasons but
anyway so I have 7,000 things but like I
for each link I have read you know 10 or
20 more articles of Wikipedia so so
anyway so okay so okay so anything else
yeah I'm going to answer
[Music]
so okay hi Michael Michael DeSimone e
hexa random question I am a new ovum
user I am considering the switch to
Emacs yay
would you recommend it of course
everyone designing interfaces be they
may be new actually yeah first of all
okay yeah of course
obviously I recommend you know moving to
Emacs in fact there is a new of him yeah
well in fact there's a YouTube
youtube.com there's a YouTube video
where this guy is a beam user for like
10 years and he switched to Emacs and he
talks about it he you know he like once
you switch after month you get you know
you you know how to use Emacs and you
never switch back like you become like
so excited about you max so anyway so I
thought you are Emacs users so Michael
so is that Michael Michele yeah so Emacs
from rim so that maybe maybe we'll see
it there yeah this guy so very popular
video Eva mod or how I learned to stop
worrying and love Emacs
by the way do you guys hear the video
are you guys hearing the video
okay so you have seen it well it's
really up to you
you know so from if you are a VM user
and you want to switch to Emacs there
are many okay thank you
Mathieu so if you are you if you came
from VI or nee ovum you want to switch
to Emacs there let's say there are three
options you can you can just go to space
my space Mac you know that's one option
space Mac is Emacs distribution meaning
that it has all the essential packages
bundled with it so you don't have to
worry about oh I need to install this
smart I don't you know because I want to
I want to have a good Python IDE and so
on you don't have to worry about that
everything you know this bundle then
setup and so that's space max okay so
that's one way to go then you can just
use plain Emacs with the evil package
now evil package is a key binding for
Emacs so when you are in Emacs the most
most of your keys is is VI keys you know
so you can switch mod inside my command
mod so that's another option and by the
way when you use evil key binding in
Emacs they are there there's always a
little friction between Emacs and you
know Evo key binding because same thing
with space max because each of them they
try to change entirely how you work with
I mean entirely they create entirely
different ways for you to interact with
Emacs so this you know there's always
some you know pebbles yeah well you know
what what you call you know the little
creatures you know but overall you know
a lot of people use them you know you
can get used to so sly smack
Eva ma Eva mod oh you can you just use
playing Emacs you know just download
from canoe Oaks website the plain Emacs
playing new Emacs once you do that you
know read the tutorial actually well
read my read my tutorial my tutorial
teaches you everything
so you read my tutorial you know you
spend a week you know reading one page a
day or something then you get you know a
good idea a good feel of how the whole
thing how it works then you can
gradually add packages yourself you know
add one packages add another two you
need file start to get into the habit
you know knowing you know you know how
to set up your unit you know like little
email is snippets you know you you start
to you know on the road to Emacs that's
everyone does that on you so so three
options space Mac Evo mod or start with
playing Emacs good new Emacs okay now I
want to add if you are using GNU Emacs
you know you should avoid using the
default key try my my key okay try stuff
like he's let me show you now cut stuff
like this is a key binding package for
Emacs and that is like like him it's
modal meaning that you have a command
mode and insert mod in command mod each
key is just a command in instrument you
know you you you you know insert
characters so it's very efficient
however it's different from vim because
the choices of the command and the
choices of keys the mapping is is based
on the frequency you know statistical
frequency of the command and ease of the
key press it based on economics you know
the science science of ergonomics email
okay that's because I wrote this so
obviously you know that's my point of
view you
it may be biased but you know judge for
yourself
so space Mack Evo mod with Emacs Oh
start with playing Emacs and possibly
use sapphire keys now let me say this if
you use space max space max everything
is packaged so you don't really actually
learn much okay that's that's true in
general you don't actually like learn
learn the way of Emacs much because
everything is set up just like when you
use and microsoft visual you know visual
code or whatever it's all set up you
don't learn much but if you really want
to go into Emacs in fact if you are
Emacs user and eventually you will like
start to learn in Emacs so so anyway if
you really want to get into Emacs you
know faster then you probably should use
start with a playing Emacs that way you
know you learn about how Emacs works you
know the basic concepts and structures
then you start to add your own stuff now
if at some point you know let's say
after three months then you think it's
too you know it's too much of a mess you
don't want you don't want to you know
you don't want to be a fan of Emacs you
are not willing to spend like one hour a
week just to you know do things with
Emacs stuff like change key by yourself
then you can always switch back to space
max oh oh
at that point you probably are not you
know Emacs is not for you
so anyway so okay so that's my
recommendation for that free-foam okay
so the other point about you see it's
actually
okay yeah so there's there's a book
called the design of everyday things
that's hugely popular back in the 1990's
I remember my friend at Wolff and
research Robby Vegas he yeah I think he
recommended it and he bought you know he
but he died he killed himself liked it
like about ten years ago it's pretty sad
and he is a nerd he is very much or not
like me but he's also you know he's an
expert he's very technical like when he
does something he's very focused on what
narrowly very specific thing anyway so
anyway so there's this design of
everything book the design of everyday
things okay the design of everyday
things it's written by this guy called
Norman something yeah it's got a teacup
with the tea kettle it's got a tech
kettle but with the handle and the
speakers on the same side but anyway
these days I kind of I actually never
read this book and this day so I kind of
I don't feel that you know intern
why because but okay here's the thing
this guy no man Donald Norman okay he
he's pretty old now I think he's
probably 70 something I think 83 you
know it's kind of sad you know a lot of
people I mean when you learn about
someone usually they are pretty old when
I was younger I felt that way like you
discovered someone you really like you
know maybe you read his books or
whatever oh my god is you know they
exist these people you really you know
admire him you know you want to meet him
but then usually
you know they are 17 years old you know
yeah and you know I'm getting old myself
you know I you know I well what can you
do
life goes on you know it's just that's a
perpetual complaint you know throughout
history I need an elixir I need an
elixir so I can drink and be young
forever
so anyway yeah okay so down no man
Donald no man he one day I found an
article by him and that turned turned me
off about about him that is let's go
through sorry
keyboard I'm gonna show you the article
so sorry keyboard blog layout keyboard
layout then go to okay go to
let's see hurrah for acting ah yeah
they're myth of Corti versus Warrick
when you're talking about keyboard
layout there's lots of myths you know
just like is Linux better than Windows
you know the GUI extremely idiotic the
Linux phonetics I'm sorry guys you know
I know a lot of you well because I'm in
the Linux UNIX community and the hacker
you know I'm the hacker types you know
but I always like tend to you know
criticize the you know groups of my own
because well actually that's actually
natural because that's what I know but
you know you know so anyway Cody and
Warrick there's always you know myth
like people are spreading false ideas
like then stop like they don't die you
know force ideas fake you know just true
patron to reinforce they don't die they
just keep calm so like every time people
want to learn vorak or work yeah mostly
you know for act they they will start to
they will run into or someone will you
know show them an article about how
Barack is actually not efficient you
know that is like saying pigs actually
to fly you just never see you know it's
my god you know it's like flat earth you
know and sometimes you wonder you know
to do people actually believe Flat Earth
you know of today we hear that a lot you
know a lot of it is I don't think a lot
of people actually believe that but I do
think it is true that there are some
people ok very you know very small
number people they actually believe that
it well it's kind of think of this way
it's like religion okay you know you
know so many people who believe religion
right there's a god now if you are
religious that's totally I'm totally
fine with that and there are different
religions right in you know
is Christian and many branches of
Christian and they are not friends with
each other you know it is there's you
know killings in the past you know
fighting in fighting you know with
results of hundred thousands you know a
hundred thousand death Millions
okay this Christianity there's Islam
Islamic of course there's also different
branches in this Buddhism there's
deviant you know Buddhism you know Tibet
Buddhism out let me just say that okay
if you are a white person person you
probably you don't know what you don't
know what I'm talking about but you
probably think oh Tibet Buddhism is good
you know we we must respect it because
all the Hollywood stars are into that
but anyway so so I mean like religion
okay so in many religions they believe
you know a deity you know yeah anyway so
okay so this religion then this also
coat you know you heard about
Scientology you heard about Falun Gong
and many many others I mean quite a few
if you start with look into code I mean
if you start to study a channel code you
know you can you can read it for years
you know you can start by going into
Wikipedia so and each one of them are
typically I mean for big religions you
know like the Christianity and Islam
they are like billions of people who
believe it in them and obedience of them
they are devout I mean they actually go
to church every day some kind of church
or mosque or whatever or temples you
know they like in Taiwan and Japan every
day you see it on the street you know
every one every two blocks you will see
some kind of incense burning for the
dead you know or you know other things
in temples you know I mean if you if you
are Western Western I know it's you know
will be interesting if you go to you
know China or Japan to visit but anyway
so so anyway so you have these religions
then you have this
Coates and they are they are they have
millions of people follow us you know
not not like just you it you know you or
just me
they have like very sizable people and
they believe you know quickly crazy
things so the point I'm making is that
you see the human mind you know the you
know what for example what is the
meaning of life that's a perpetual
question we don't know and we wonder
about that all the time is deep inside
us it's deep you know even though you
don't you may not talk about it but that
that question I mean the the mystery of
the universe you know the purpose you
know of your life you know that's that's
very deep within you so so what I'm
saying is that so what do you believe it
can vary it can vary a lot and in fact
if you look I mean you could a lot
people actually someone you could live
in within your certain belief and never
in your life never possibly knew or
imagined there are something else
different from you you know if you look
at history you know did you know the
great history of humanity is recorded
history since maybe four thousand years
ago you know of course nobody can
actually know even a little bit about it
but you know you you try to read history
and you get deeper and deeper and you
you you start to see that you know you
can see that you know obviously clearly
many people beat billions or millions
okay they just they believe him maybe
one thing and they never thought of it's
possible that there are other things
different from there you know belief you
know so so so what I'm saying is that
the human mind the questions of the
Cosmo you know it's like in modern
society we think you know especially
like technology you know we are
intellectuals so we are or at least we
are literate and we are you know we're
talking about computer science and stuff
and we think oh we see the world is like
oh it's just like that we'd like you
know everything you know oh yeah there's
history yeah I know about it you know
the history the the the whole world is
like okay there's philosophy as history
and and Sciences and you know I see it
yeah everything I know yeah I know about
it all but it means but so what I'm
saying is it's it's not it's not like
that actually I mean just so the human
mind you know you so even take us for
example it's okay let's put it this way
it's still possible for us you know for
me for example that there's some
thoughts I mean it just never occurs to
you and that and that's thought if it is
exposed to me right now
it kind of you know turns me upside down
like it made me like question all the
things I know I mean it's very possible
I mean you don't know I mean you can
like it's it's not like the the human
mind and the universe things it's not
like it's not like a finite set where
you know the whole thing is the ER it's
it's just a matter of where you look
it's not like that but it's rather like
you don't know how big it is it's
infinite first of all it's like you
don't know you you can't possibly
explore things you don't know so anyway
a [ __ ] by the way there's a link with
linguistic theory and kind of
philosophical linguistic theory you must
have heard of you know the saberwolf
hypothesis
you know you might look up but but it
but it basically says the language
influences your thought or in the
extreme case languages limit what it is
possible for you to imagine so you know
for example I speak Chinese in English
and maybe you're know a little bit
others you know but
so if that hypothesis is true then that
means clearly there's so many other
things I don't know anyway so anyways
and by the way that hypothesis may not
necessarily be philosophically valid by
the way that's another perspective
because in philosophy in many of these
know math things when you have a
question the question itself may not
make sense because the question may turn
out to be just a linguistic loophole for
example does God exist you know you know
many arguments oh it exists or it does
not exist but however there's a you know
particular philosophy called began led
mostly by Bertrand Russell that that is
called positivism and but basically did
it takes approach that what does it mean
does that does God exist first of all
you have to define what do you mean
exactly I mean define in such a way that
we can say we can say ok so when this
happens then we can say it's true
it exists well when this happens we can
verify then we can say ok it can exist
it's not true otherwise maybe it's just
a linguistic tautology you know God what
do you mean by God exactly you know like
you know anyway so
yeah so if you tried space Max and you
not happy with it right away then yeah
take my then go okay let me say just you
know go with the playing good movie Max
and you know maybe start with my
tutorial and see how far that goes for
you that you know see if that works for
you okay I'm gonna read a few questions
and that's gonna be it for today
okay I think where is he
okay I think I'm kind of lost the thread
in the comments
okay what's the issue with quote you
versus versus fullback well you can read
the article you can read my article here
but I think that's it for today because
you know I've been talking for one hour
in twenty minutes
or actually you know why why should I
put a limit to you know the talk show
because after all these five people
watching oh okay yeah I what I was
talking about Norman article oh yeah
that's it okay thank you for reminding
me so yeah so yeah it's so high vote oh
you know so yeah so Norman here's a
quote look wait yeah so there it is
here's the one so okay so there's a myth
about corty ok but basically that
basically a lot of people says says that
Barack is not more efficient they say
quote is actually well they just keep
saying Barack is not more efficient than
quote e ok and ok so here I quote
something on Stack Overflow i believe no
on the Cora Cora website which is a
question answers and that's the one I
found so it's that's posted by Donald
Norman the guy who wrote design of
everything every day things okay here so
here it is he says wrong quali and Kohan
perpetuates the false belief that quote
he has that Cody was intended to slow
typing in fact it is one of the fastest
keyboards around and he continues
there's not not there's not enough space
here to explain fully but I have done
experiments and published a lot about
this quote he was designed to prevent
jamming of keys back in the days when
everything was my mechanical blah blah
blah so that's from him Donald Norman
the guy who wrote
design of everything now I'm picking
this kind of out of context because I
mean it's why I'm I don't mean out of
context but I don't have the food detail
of exactly what's the topic you know
because it's very short you know someone
asks someone asked on Quora is the Kody
keyboard layout the most efficient one
or are there better ones so someone just
asked that out of the blue I guess and
he just posted you know one paragraph
you know saying you know basically
basically saying something to the effect
that Kody is good you know quality is
sufficient and that you know I see this
you know as you just turned I so I I
have lest I have less respect I have
less trust of his opinions because of
this because this you know first of all
what he says you know the things he said
here it's been said 1,000 times and you
know and also notice he's not giving
exact specific details like here's the
history and from this article and you
know from this historical document or
something like that he's not doing that
well he just you know and he gave you
know general kind of fuzzy undefinable
answers to the question you know and he
claims that you know he claims that
quarry is I mean this is the most
idiotic expression in fact it is one of
the fastest fastest keyboard around well
maybe he means it was the facet at the
time you know at the time when when when
they are the way there are lots of other
mechanical typewriters that are by
different design you know weird is not
even like you know typing is like maybe
a circle or whatever you know and and a
lot other weird layout maybe that's what
he means you know in fact is one of the
fastest keyboard
around you know it what a flag you know
so I don't like the I don't like he's
coming and this is because this is funny
because this is just a huge myth about
corty like people just like to mention
why let me tell you why because Barack
is a efficient layout far more well
efficient more scientifically absolutely
more efficient than work then corty
period okay Barack is more efficient
than quarry absolutely period now
because of these however Barack is not
popular you know what is popular Kotick
quarries you know adopted by the whole
population because you know most people
you know you don't have a problem with
quality because you know mom-and-pop you
use the computer for half an hour a day
that's it you know the encoder is fine
you know it's really it's fine
but however if you are a professional
programmer or typist or use a computer
or novelist or writers bloggers you have
to type all day you know Corey is very
bad it's it gets you a hanpan you have
to see doctors okay
now however when people hit first foot
when people hear about Barack for the
first time for example you okay any of
you
you start we have hand pen because you
type too much then you start to look for
solutions then you heard about Iraq okay
this vlog is more efficient then you
start to learn it then oh my god you got
first frustrated because it's actually
very difficult it's very painful to
change your muscle memory and also in
general it's very painful to deviate
from your habit you know just try to
change your habit you know people say
okay they want to lose weight they want
to you know stop drinking they want to
maybe change to a more active lifestyle
but it's hard because you have a habit
you have condition you have your family
or whatever context it's hard to change
habit but anyway for changing from Corey
to Barack is also hard as
especially if you already type on Cory
so you you're running into this big
problem you know you didn't want to like
on one hand you are suffering your hand
is you know hurting but on the other
hand you find it extremely painful to
learn vorak so there is a psychological
and a psychological reward or kind of
some kind of a psychological push for
you to believe that virag is actually
not more efficient you know in your
process of learning all right then you
will see some articles talking about is
well act really actually efficient then
some one point you know these some other
articles about variation article about
varrock is not actually efficient and
then someone think up some histories
about you know oh you know the the the
the studies they've done is in the past
is actually bias because the guy who
invented more Aggies is that why is that
way you want to believe it oh then you
say oh hi oh my god Morag is actually
not more efficient I don't want to learn
it anymore that's why that and in a
nutshell that is why with this myth
nonstops Pop softness it continues on
you know anyway
ok I think that's it for today thank you
maisha
king can you can you treat tell me how
you pronounce your name and you know ask
me you know questions I'm gonna answer
your questions on Twitter or some other
another livestream tomorrow maybe
tomorrow you know I'm going to live
stream every day okay so that's it for
today thank you guys for coming and also
I want to mention you know I'm okay put
money in my patreon okay so you can find
it here on my website any you know on my
website go to my blog you will see you
know my patreon link my paypal link my
Amazon you know you can buy something
from Amazon and send me Amazon gift that
would be appreciated thank you
so I see you guys then bye