hello welcome to another episode of xan
talk show today we are going to do
Advent of code day 7 in wufam language
live coding okay like coding and uh
yeah so uh day seven the problem is a
bit difficult I heard uh so we are going
just going to focus on the on it and try
to get it to
get the solution okay language let's
begin
uh if you don't know you know I have
from Language tutorial just on my
website just search for Saudi wolfam
language complete tutorial so let's
start the Wolfram language engine okay
let's uh now let's magnify
sorry uh okay so there it is
so yeah let's begin open language and
this is expose
keyboard one of my favorite my top three
favorite okay exposed keyboard you can
find reviews on saudi.info go there
click the search and you'll find it
almost everything I talk about you know
the emacs my mod whatever you can find
on saudi.info
okay let's begin so let's begin the
Advent of code problem seven uh let me
show you what's the problem okay let's
start the Wolfram language code and
that's begin coding here so this problem
this problem day seven
basically I already read it so basically
you are given a this is your input a
string
which is basically like Unix directory
list okay so for example
let's start Powershell actually I'm
gonna try to go fast and less of random
talk for example you can oh yeah I don't
want emacs to Temp so for example yeah
let's start the Powershell
turn this off and magnify this so for
example you can you can say LS that's a
Unix directory Unix command LS okay that
list all directories and you can see the
dot dot to go up one directory and you
can do LS again so these directories or
you can cd2 sound talk show
oh okay so
uh what what is the directory name let's
see
yeah talk show okay noxa
CD talk show you know go into a
directory and you can list
okay so you know
so the input
the input is this string let's copy it
okay that's like the Unix prompt
Unix command uh prompt so today's top
show here so let's put it down
okay in Emax so we can easily see it so
you are giving this input essentially
you want to build a tree you want to
build uh generate the directory
structure from this input okay so okay
so let's start to code it actually so
let's go to Wolfram language X input
equals to a directory so first thing you
want to do is split the string okay
split the string
okay so uh stream
split okay split by the input and split
by a
new line character okay so once you
split it let's say X1 equals to
equal sign is always problematic to type
maybe I need to remap the keys
I have this a brief EQ or eqq
and I used to have a brief for typing
equal but I removed it anyway so here's
the input
okay you split it and so
every line that start with the dollar
sign is the
input so let's think about how do you do
this so given this input you want to
generate the directory your tree
structure you want to build a tree
structure
okay
and let's write it out
given this input
build a tree structure okay
and this input
um
those starting with
yeah
dollar sign
means it's a command okay this is
important
and uh you know so once you see your
dollar sign in front that means it's a
command okay and the possible commands
are
possible commands are CDLs
okay let's see let's see CDLs CD okay so
it's something like this let's do it
properly CD uh
name okay that's one case
and uh let's do it here then LS
how is don't don't have a name okay
so let's see
okay so CD this matching noise CD CD
something
and uh so the uh CD name or
CD slash that's a special case Okay uh
Slash means root then you have LS CD
name lscd and you have this special case
okay that means go up one directory
okay okay that's it that so that's the
possible command names okay
showing browser there it is okay so then
the part then you have the output so
anything else is the output so let's uh
yeah so let's let's analyze to see what
type of the output lines are okay
so that's how I go about solving this
problem
uh so let's uh narrow to region uh
these matching lines include a dollar
sign
okay do it again this matching lines
backslash dollar
okay and remove those lines okay did you
imagine lines okay so here is a possible
output
we analyzed you know to see what type of
it is okay so the possible case is
the
name
then
number
name okay they are all separated by a
space yes okay the name number name okay
uh
number number
name number name
wait
wait what what is this I
584 I
okay uh what
LS 584 I
I is a fire
let's see let's see uh
inch I
yeah so I is just a file
Okay so
yeah so number I yeah number
let's let's put the file name let's put
the D name okay so
file name file name yeah that's the
possible output okay now let's
um
expand uh both uh okay let's
it's
let's make these uh what
yeah we did everything in front by
mistake
what
oh we forgot we we didn't expand
correctly so now it's back okay
so possible output lines that's these
two okay
and uh yeah so let's show in browser so
that's what we have now
okay so we got we got this input uh okay
let's magnify the browser font size is
probably too small
okay so now it's better so
video check audio check if you are here
say hi okay
uh yeah so let's
video check audio check Okay so
okay so that's the input and possible
commands are these types so whenever you
see these
okay so let's why don't we add a dollar
sign in front let's see yeah so there is
a dollar sign
okay
foreign
okay so possible commands The Impossible
output either the name or number name
okay and so you start to read you know
you split the line
and basically you want to do a loop
uh
you want to Loop through the lines now
Loop is typically a procedural style
programming but in Newfound language is
you know you too functional so
let's see how what can we do
Okay so
uh you go through for every time each
time you see a dollar sign you it's one
of these possible cases you
and is it true that always you always
begin with a CD slash that's important
because that's a root you know
um so let's see the puzzle input okay
yeah so you begin with that that's
almost a given implicit
given uh you know uh so let's write that
down here so let's uh day six yeah today
is day seven
so let's write down here
okay
I'll save it paste it when the code day
7 input
okay so now that's today's day 7 input
yeah so let's see 1000 lines okay
so you
so you always start with the rule let's
let's look at how um because they are
basically traversal directory so
implicit
is that you the first line is always
that you start with the root then
then I think I assume it's also another
implicit K implicit case that you you CD
to
every directory
for the problem
yeah obviously because the directory you
don't see these two uh you know doesn't
matter
and your goal your goal is to basically
your goal is to construct this tree in
some some kind of data structure and the
actual required answer is that you want
to find all directories
whose size is less or equals to
100k
total size okay total size including
subdirectories directories themselves
are zero size so you count the file size
in a directory and or its subdirectories
so if it's less than 100k
then you then calculate the sum of their
total sizes okay
so
that means you know given a directory
you may have lots of subdirectories that
that that is less than 100K but
but basically you want to find their
parents
the topmost parents that that's that is
less than 100K okay
you know the wording is not phrased in a
very precise way you know
uh
to begin find all the directories with
the total size at most that that means
less or equals to that then calculate
the sum
of their total sizes you see this is
ambiguous
so for each directory it comes with a
size okay but when you say you calculate
the sum
does that mean for example this
directory a
let's say it's less than that size
but let's say
then obviously all the subdirectories
uh below a
is also less than 100K so does that mean
you just sum a itself the size of a or
to use some a plus you know it's
subdirectory so I find this is
ambiguous statement
in the example above these directories
are A and E okay and the sum of their
total sizes that that that that as an
example the pro this process can count
files more than once okay
there's some A and E the sum of their
total size A and E A and E
yeah so you know so actually it wants
you to count
including all sub subdirectories so if
this file
wait this file
[Music]
yeah so the directory e only have one
single file and this file is less than
100K of course so you would count e
and you would count a as well and you
sum the size of a and e
[Music]
you know so and the sum of their total
okay and this process can count files
more than once idiotic
so find all the directories with the
total size at most 100K what is the sum
of total sizes of those directories and
this means you repeatedly count
uh you know you know subdirectories so
it's not a good question
because it's unrealistic
because the description says you want to
remove
you know
um the the disk size is full you want to
remove supposedly big files
so anyway
so first of all still we need to build a
tree okay so let's see what is this uh
input remove the delete that so go back
to the code
so you build a tree uh then so
two so
let's see whenever you see your list so
you must have a intermediate
variable of Contour
okay something like that
okay whenever you see that let's just
write up some notes
then say that
okay then
then
let's see the structure then after CD
it's almost always LS is that true let's
see
let's see okay so after CD
it's almost always LS let's check that's
true that's true true
oh wait that's not necessarily true cdcd
so
after CD
it may be another CD
then and then if the end of the sequence
of a CD is an ALS is that true yes okay
cdlscd CD here so this osls so let's
highlight the ALS to be green power of E
Max
Okay pink so now it's easier to see this
yes yes yes yes
yeah so after CD the last CD there's
always LS okay go back
after the last CD then there's an LS
okay
so
okay so that's basically that okay so
whenever you start to see LS then you
have either two possible
um
to possible
lines okay
so
so you have two possible lines okay
uh then after that
then again it's CD and LS okay
so okay that completes the analysis of
the input okay now let's see what we're
gonna do so we start with a CD
then
um
so we want to build a tree
okay and what does this tree
this tree each node of the tree has a
has a name
that's a directory name okay and so this
tree
each nod has a name that's important
because you need to put this somewhere
so
this is a common problem when you build
a tree whether each nod has information
attached or not
so in this case yes each naught has a
name
and each nod also has a size okay let's
write it down
okay
each nod
and then leave
okay and each
Leaf nod has a
name it in the size okay
so
okay
so then
this is idiotic presentation because it
you see it uses a dash to signify an
item a nod
okay
anyway so
each no leave so we are thinking about
how to build a tree each
then Leaf nod has a name and size we saw
we need to store that somewhere so what
kind of structure we we want we we want
to use a tree so
so each tree
let's say in wolfam language
um
so a nod name size
not meta info okay name and size
and uh
and also type Maybe
so
not name size type
uh
okay so how do you
can you you can do this as either key
value pairs a list of a nested list of
key value pairs
such as python dictionary or JavaScript
object
um
in Wolfram language you have
associations Okay so
Association which is
key value pairs
Okay so
these oh yeah Association where is it
graphic Advanced Graphics uh pattern
matching functions data structure
Association there
Okay so
so how do you want the tree structure or
more common is just the nested list of
least so that let's just do let's write
them out so suppose
suppose the first element of the least
is
meta info okay
then the second element is whatever
the first element of
the least is the meta info
yeah I think I preferred this way
uh maybe not let's see so the first
element of the tree
so we're gonna so for example
let's write it down Okay so
two ways to represent a tree
how do we want to
represent the tree
two
major ways okay
a dictionary
or
nested
or nested Beast
where first item is meta info
now if you use a dictionary
which is a key value pairs
how do you represent meta info in the
key
yeah that's a problem too so
um I don't think I want to use that
I want to use nested Beast okay
so the meta info
is a list
for example
um
there
name size type okay
so for example we have
name
size
type
the
Okay so
So Meta info is at least and meta info
is released
name size type name size type okay
type is one of
the
file okay a stream
so that's an example and here is another
example
okay
and the file a file doesn't have any
other things
okay
so yeah
so this is not
not looks like that
children is a list of knots okay
for each
nod
the first item is
okay
so this is meta info
for each knot the first item is
meta info okay that's essentially
that's a spec of our tree
okay uh yeah
okay yeah that's uh that's our tree
structure we want now
uh now
okay now let's write the code now let's
put this into talk show
okay
so now let's go back to the code
okay now
let's start to read it okay once we
split
oh this is gonna take a while 30 minutes
already
hello laser
Lassie Nasi
kaiman
okay so so now let's start to read that
speed of the tree then okay
so we want to process each line one line
at a time
so we can use a map or a do Loop let's
see
let's write out the algorithm
if it's a command
okay if it's a command
what type of commands are there so if
it's a command CD or LS so there's
always CD first
uh
set
second and
[Music]
oh God this is gonna be
it's okay let's think about this
set the current uh
so
so we don't have the size information
ready
but we do have the The Meta info the the
name
and
the size is not ready and we do have a
type
so
each time we can start to build a
okay so each time we can start to build
a meta info about the nod
uh so let's look at the input so CD
slash so you can build the meta info
but without size okay then you
LS
is the children of that nod
okay yeah CD is always the last city is
always followed by LS so once you got
the ls you got the children of that nod
okay
then
use CD again
you then you see to a
okay so you can so let's see
so now you have an issue
or maybe you don't of building a tree
bottom up or top down
so top down approach would be
you know you can just get all the CDs
first
so that you you know all the directories
directory names
and uh
and you can also get all file names
and their size first okay so this is not
sequential but you know you you get all
the directory names then you get all
file names in their size
then
you look at
yeah so you still need to know what's
the current directory whenever you do LS
okay so that approach is not good
probably
uh it's probably better to build a tree
as you go so
uh maybe let's just start to do it okay
so CD
so if it's a directory so you CD to a
directory
then you
eventually do a LS then you got the
children
little children
and that children
needs to be added
so let's let's mark build okay
so first of all CDLs so you got the meta
info
um
let's just say meta okay
So Meta equals to
slash
size we don't know uh we can leave it
near or something and then type okay
so we got that then
when you see LS
shouldn't of last
okay
pseudo code okay pseudo code
let's say the pseudo code
okay then when you see LS add all lines
to the children of last counter
how do you do that
so current does so to begin
to begin
so you do that
then append
method to
prepare meta to
three
oh that wouldn't
so temp Dutch temp third tree
okay so Global tree
the tree
tree
meta
okay then prepend
uh yeah that's how you build okay
uh well yeah so then you
then when you see LS
append or two
children of
can the tree something like that
something like that
so yeah so let's start with the global
tree okay then
so let's start the loop how do you want
to do the loop okay
let's see let's go back to
um
so we want to map to a list okay so you
look for map function to a list you can
use map or scan map is returns a list
just like other languages scan
does not return anything
okay otherwise it's the same so we can
use scan
are there a better way okay I don't I
mean are they are they a better approach
to build this tree
oh God this is uh this is this problem
it's gonna take two hours
so if we use map or scan that means we
have to write a function and what the
function will do it's not going to be a
you know functional programming function
but rather it's going to be a the
function is going to be a procedure
of doing these things
you know so
Okay so
okay sorry I have to think about this
so you can use map or scan if we do it
this way
um
yeah the you know we map or scan if we
do it this way it's procedural oh
Okay so
so
um
map or scan so the function needs to do
a bunch of things
uh
okay so let's start to write some
more pseudo code
a more pseudocode possible commands
possible output okay let's start to
write code
if
fly
equals to
and if the if the first character of the
line
um
let's see if that works
okay so you cannot use that for string
you need to use Stream parts okay
okay stream star Q
okay let's do that
f equals to dollar sign
then
it's a command otherwise something else
okay
okay and what kind of command are there
CD and CD and LS okay
so now
c d o l s okay it's either CD
or it's either LS
okay now if it's CD
okay
so we got nesting so let's do switch
statement okay let's do switch or which
that will give you clear cleaner code
okay
switch or which so this is a condition
so condition you go to Boolean
conditional which or switch there are
two
uh inputs okay test expression form
oh yeah so switch you start with the
value then after that comes with many
pairs then you compare the value to each
of the key of the pair
uh while which is just these are pairs
each pair tester condition so that's
what we want so which
Okay so
uh a b so these are pairs okay
things like that
so the first one
is
okay so actually
so we can do it this way
Okay so
so again how many types uh how many
types are there
CD
-o-l-s okay
so if it's a CD
then what you do so when you see a CD
you need the temp directly you need a
temp
um
variable okay let's use the temp
variable
okay so it's like that 10 variable the
temp variable is gonna be
not info okay not info
current okay
then uh
and maybe current tree
not info couldn't uh kinda tree let's
put size there whenever that
Okay so
if it's a CD
uh
the name okay so now you need
not name
okay so actually you need a line
that's the current line
so
if x line is already there so if the
line is that
maybe you can split the line first
okay so what are the possible yeah very
simple two items or three
wait
okay here line info so
so
we can just say
Okay so
CD or LS okay CD or LS so it was if it's
a CD there's always three three items so
not name equals to
three
okay
and
so that's one thing
so if if it's a CD
let me just code it okay
hey man how's it going going good
uh stream start
okay strings start with um
yeah pattern Okay so so if that is that
wait that's not right yeah
okay
Okay so
not type
clean them up cream my stuff up okay as
I go so
so lying info split the line okay
and not type equals to
uh
my info okay if we start with the dollar
sign then it's the
um
and uh
and
so
we have line
parts
not type so
and otherwise if it's a command
otherwise it's a file size
Okay so
so let's see
so name
way into command the extra info is the
name
okay so we need to command the extra
info is
is always
the okay so the type is erased and you
got a name otherwise name
okay I'm getting
more clear and clear but this will take
a while to code
um
how's it going everyone
let's see where is my uh
check yes you're going
this is gonna take a long time this is
gonna take a long time so let's focus
so
so if it's a command or it's an output
then when it's a command
so you either it's a command or it's a
output and Windsor command
you
you have so this part you need to do for
sure then then if it's a command you
have
you have
not name
okay so there are several issues this is
not name there is then
LS you can almost ignore it just
signifies yeah LS you can almost totally
ignore completely
uh
so if it's
n type
so maybe
okay so let's start to put stuff here
that's
one two three
so dollar sign or Not dollar sign okay
so yeah
and this code is all wrong but let me
just code it okay
so here it means it's a command
then
when it's command you have a name and
you have
you have a name okay except when it's
dot dot okay
yeah this is a lot
complicated things going on so
okay I'm not I I I'm I'm gonna not talk
too much I'm just gonna focus on coding
it
foreign
strange starts with
if he start with the other side
if start with the dollar sign then it's
a command then there are two types then
[Music]
okay there are two types
then okay maybe it's better to just
okay then process fire okay so if it's a
command
then if
then if the
if the second part is CD so
if
you can do that
you need to split the parts anyway yeah
doesn't matter which one it is so you
need to split the line into separate
components
so so that's why this this thing is
there first
okay this ignore for now okay so now if
if the line the second part is is equals
to
CD
okay so if it's a CD the second part
so it's CD or ALS okay
now if it's LS
okay
but if it's a CD then you have the third
component Okay the third component
that is the
the name okay the name so let's put the
name
so if it's
if
it is a command
then the second part is CD
then you have a name
except it's
dot dot
Unix
okay so you actually maybe so it's it's
a CD
and if
if the third one
is equals to
is not equals to dot dot
then
the name equals to that
but every time you do CD you have to
change the two
hey
uh
you have to change the current
so
if the third part is not that
then
okay another second
then you have that
and
God you need to build a counter
you need to so current there is a string
so basically you need to append the
current name into that
kind of string
oh God this this is say gonna take
another hour at least I think
I want to
take a break and stuff
okay let's look look at this problem
again is there some easy way
so
you know
it shouldn't be too difficult
but actually it is not trivial I mean
it's trivial
um
you know this is this is like real world
coding
I mean it's trivial in a computer
science sense
but to actually code this
I wonder if the chat GPT can
just spit out a solution a program
so okay so let me think are there other
ways to do this so so one way you can
get all the names and uh
then you look at the last changed to
directory then you add their children
so the first scan you know one way is to
do most multiple scans of the input so
the first scan will get all the
directory names
uh then the second scan will get all the
file names in file size okay this is
kind of logically simple
once you get the so you have a table of
the names you have a table of file sizes
okay then you do another scan where you
scan for the last CD
statement you know the last CD statement
you know this one and then
so you get the last CD statement and
basically then then it's followed by ALS
then you get
you get in between the file things a
bunch of files so that would um
okay first scan get all directory name
second scan get all file names
and their size third scan
is actually to build a structure
so for every
last CD
so all the all the sequences every chunk
of sequence of CD
is to obtain I mean the critical part is
to obtain the current directory okay the
current directory so
so you need to pass this dot dot
uh you know into a the path
okay once you get the path
once you get to the path you can
okay there are so many ways to do this
you see so for this one for this example
this these files are children's of the
directory d
okay
so how do you build the tree
you know so if you already have a tree
so far you need to add these children to
that particular particular nod
which is not easy because you already
have a tree structure you know then you
need to find the position add this to
that knot so that's one way the other
way is to Simply build
a list of all directory paths
that would be easy
yeah that would be easy so
so uh you know just like
just like in the
um let me show you okay
just like the Unix
so what do you do is you
you
got that
the
you know the so you can you have cd
so the because
uh
because
a filter
tml
right yeah do it okay so
actually cancel this is no so what you
want to do
what do you want to do is that
then
uh
this is Powershell
yes this is what you want you'll be you
want to build a string like that
okay once you got this list of strings
then you need to turn this into a tree
hello Juan
so which way to go so we can build a
tree as we go
or we build a list of paths
as we go once we got a decent path then
we turn this little path
into a tree
okay the problem actually requires file
size you know summation effects
problem this is okay this is not a
simple
so okay so you get a
you know so even if you get this file
path like that
you
you want to turn this into a tree
structure
and that is actually
a problem by itself
yeah so
is the easy way is there a easy way
where you just got the list of file path
and turn it into a tree structure
well there's no easy way no so let's so
instead of doing that that's you
actually want to build a tree
just by each step
okay so we back to here so
so you want to build a tree in each step
you know I'm sorry I just have to like
think about this you know
cannot just start to code it I really
just need to think about this
so each time you encounter
um so yeah so actually we are on the
right track it's just very tedious and
lots of thinking
um
so if
it's a command
then
if it's a CD
then you want to update the current path
and stuff okay
so if it's a CD then you got
then
think
okay what is the current Uh current uh
beginning with the Slash
I mean in the beginning you get a slash
so
update the current
okay but the current uh is actually
supposed to be a position in a tree
okay this is
not so good
this problem
you're just gonna see me struggle and uh
let's see
three people
two people
uh not so good this is not fun
you know I'm probably just going to be
mumbling for the next
Allah
like like right now what I'm doing so
I'm thinking actually just chicken out
stop the video
and uh I will for sure get it to work
offline
then
but if I do that
you know that then that loses the point
of me doing this live you know then this
video is wasted okay
okay I will not stop I should just
continue
but
I should just continue so
so you want the current directory so I
have to think I just have to think about
it
okay and actually let me take a break
okay
okay I'll be back in five minutes
yeah you know when when the whole thing
is done it's going to be one single line
I'm gonna tell you yeah but okay be back
in five minutes
foreign
I'm back
you know so
so we can build a tree as we read the
least another way is we build the list
of file path
like that then turn that into a tree now
I wonder if full fan language has a
building functionality to turn this Lisa
path into a tree uh so let's look at
that
because that would be uh interesting
feature of wolfam language Okay so
so that that let's look into
maybe there's a
feature of doing that another way is
that we don't build a tree at all
instead we get this list of file paths
and for each list for each item for each
path we make it a pair you know which is
the file path and the size
you know so if it's a file
uh then you have a size and if it's a
directory
let's see do we have a
uh we don't have a directory so
filter
so we don't if we don't filter then we
get all sort of
um
for example let's see
that's cd2e Max okay because otherwise
it's huge
CD to Emax
and it's not it's cd2
okay let's do it there
so
so now if we list the directory
you can see
some of them is a directory name you see
this is a directory name
and a bunch of files
and you know some of them are directory
names such as these so if we get this
file path like that and then for each
item for each file we add the file size
like make it a pair and also for the
directory we make it a pair
then we got the size because the problem
asks for computing the size basically
so
so this is one approach get a list of
path and add a file size to each item
then we can compute the directory size
by
by those you know the files in that
directory once we have that
once we have that
you know so it's possible is it possible
to turn this this path into a tree in
wufam language using some building
um
functionality Maybe
because wufan language
has a lot of tree functions graph and
network okay so let's see where they are
you know this feature is kind of new
you know since year 2000s so I never
used these
computation on graph graph and network
overview okay let's look at that
so you have graph object with vertex and
Edge properties grab data okay
a complete graph okay random graph h a
Json graph
highlight graph okay
graph object with vertex vertex and Edge
properties so if you want to represent
the directory structure as a graph
then
okay Edge Let's see
okay so this is how you represent
a triangle a graph you know a graph is a
generalized tree you know three trees a
special case of graph three is defined
as a graph such that there is no Loop
you know they don't come back you know
so
tree is a special case of graph and in
the Wolfram language graph
you know function
it you know this is a data structure
that represents a graph any graph so
if you want to use this to represent a
directory structure then
the edges you know each element is an
edge of the graph so
you would have for example a directory
so each Edge
has is two elements
each element represents a nod so if
we're going to use this as a directory
structure then the nodes will be on the
left side it's uh on the left side is
always a directory
so in that case it might be a string of
the directory name okay so on the left
side is a string of a directory name on
the right side it's again a string
um
yeah it's again a string
yes it might be a directory or it might
be a file Okay so
for each element is a string to string
okay so this is how you can
represent the graph
now
to use this you know we are thinking the
possibility of using this to solve our
problem so if we use these but we also
need to represent the size and
so for each node you need a meta info
right so each node will be your name
either directory or file but you also
need the meta info to indicate that it's
a directory or a file
so
so if we use these on the left side or
the right side it's going to be a pair
so on the left side for example it's
going to be a string directory name
but
but also a size on the right side it's a
directory name or file name and with the
size so it's a list of pairs
and
yeah you can do that
okay so that's one way to do you know if
we want to use this but what is the
advantage of using this
I don't know because it's it can get
very complicated graph and network is
there a way to
um
I mean we are trying to see whether it's
suitable to exploit this movement
language graph data structure to make
our solution easier
okay so you can
highlight graph highlight elements in a
graph so give given a graph you
highlights the knots a that can be
vertices Edge edges or sub graph of G
Okay so
so basically this allows you to
visually represent the tree okay that's
not what we want
it it's not useful to us
so we can represent the graph then this
graph data curated collection of
theoretical empirical graph okay that's
like cities and stuff
cities or Earth
data let's see what then what does it do
huge
yeah
so we need let's go down
okay grab data yeah so it this is a
theoretical graph you can just give a
name
of a graph you know a known named graph
then you just
creates the data for you and you can
visualize it okay so that's what this
graph data does okay that's not useful
to us so we can you you can represent
the graph you can
uh
generate a graph by a given graph name
then you can highlight graph then you
can plot graph
properties and measurement graph
distance
show this path okay now these are not
useful for us so this is mostly graph
Theory
yeah that's not useful to us Boolean
computation
yeah so okay we don't want to use graph
uh now but okay so now is there some
kind some kind of function related to
directory structure that
I don't think so I mean there are but
it's just like typical programming
language
where you can get file size the size
total the size and things like that
where would that be that would be
data manipulation time related
engineering computation
uh recent features scientific okay it's
not
okay so you you go here language
overview
uh you know there are 6 000 functions
so it's not here so instead you want to
search for file okay directory
so there's a tons of functions related
to directory
directories and directory operations
okay let's go there
yeah but I don't think it's helpful for
us because these are just like typical
programming language
uh directory set directory
this is like
a current kernel directory set directory
okay
then you can get Parent Directory
directory name
so how does this work Parent Directory
gives the parent of the current working
directory oh okay
so apparent directory gives the parent
of directory done okay this is useful
this is when you have a path
basically it just returned the directory
part
okay so just like typical other
languages
yeah
so they yeah so they may be useful
operations on file names directory and
directory operation
construct a file path programmatically
okay that's not
that's not interesting that's just to
construct the file path okay so it's not
useful to us so let's go back
uh file name join split uh yeah so this
is not useful you know because our
problem is not really about
manipulation directories it's it's
really about
building a tree
so
okay so that made us think of another
way to solve this problem so when you do
this you can you know you can actually
create a file
of that on your file system
this is very interesting you know just
yeah you create a file so you
essentially you use your file system to
create this directory structure and for
the each size particular size file you
actually create that file but that's not
good
that's well that's that's one way to do
it but you actually create a bunch of
files that's not efficient
you know that's kind of going around the
problem
the problem really is to build a tree
okay so again there are several ways you
know so you can build a file path
then then you add the file size for each
each so then then your problem becomes
working with a list of path
which you can do but it's not efficient
okay that's that's again like going
around the problem
yeah you can you can get a diesel files
I mean file path with their size then
you can find the directory's total size
yeah you can do that
but it's actually you will be
inefficient and
inefficient and also
kind of going around the problem
the proper solution is truly you need to
be on the tree
you need to build a tree that represents
this
you know this input okay so let's go
back to so we
yeah I think at this point we go back to
truly we just need to build a tree
it's not you know
try to be try to go around the problem
so we need to build a tree okay which is
not so easy okay so to build a tree okay
we decided we want to undo that we
actually have to build a tree and also
we decided the tree structure
uh yes we we decided so there are two
possible ways one is uh nested
dictionary nested key value pairs
but we reject that solution we reject
that representation of a tree using a
nested key value pairs because for each
nod of the tree may be a directory or
maybe a file which is the leaf of the
directory for each nod of the tree
we need meta info such as the name and
the size
so if you use key value pairs
you know typically the key would be the
directory name or file name
but where do you put the size
so that's a problem
unless the programming language allows
you to say attach a property to the
string
or to the key or you use a list of pairs
as a key to your dictionary
but if you do that
that kind of
um let's see
okay so you can use
key value pairs to
yeah so you can use a key value pair
as the key of your tree
so each nod or the key of a dictionary
the key would be your pair
a name and the size
okay but
but the point is that you do have to use
a pair for your key
to represent the nod and what is the
problem with that well the problem with
that is that your dictionary your nested
dictionary is now not simple because in
vast vast majority use cases of a
dictionary or hash table your key is
always a simple string
you know just a string or or a symbol
but now you you you need the meta info
file name and size so I mean the size so
so now your key is gonna be your pair so
we we can do that because the Wolfram
language
[Music]
um
you know the wolfam language Association
data structure which is
what python would call
dictionary
allows that you know your your key can
be arbitrary expression
yeah we can do that okay
okay so that so right now we are
thinking about how to represent the tree
revisit this is
so you can use Association or also known
as Association associative list also
known as dictionary in python or known
as hash table in Ruby or Pearl or also
known as map
in JavaScript and Java okay so you can
use this basically key value pairs to
represent a nested key value pairs to
represent a tree okay
okay so that's one way another way is
just
pure nested list
where the first element is taken to be
the meta info about
yeah so
yeah so we can do that the first element
would be the meta info
Okay so
hmm
in either case
so okay so again we have two
possibilities okay we are thinking of
which one to choose
a dictionary a nested dictionary or a
nested
least
now if we use the list then the first
element of any nod will be the meta info
and it will be a name
size
and type the or file
the type we can actually skip because
the leaf nods are files always you know
the files are always Leaf nodes so if
it's not a leaf knot it's a directory so
we can actually skip this we just need a
name meta info our name and
size
okay is that right yes
okay So Meta info name and size okay so
two ways uh dictionary or necessary
dictionary or a nested these okay now
let's think about which one is easier
which one is easier so
so the problem you know given this
you know we have already decided that we
want to
go through each line one at a time and
as we go through we are going to build a
tree we already decide on that
as opposed to scan this list multiple
times get the directory name first get
the file names and size first then
build a tree then you know
so we decided we're gonna just go
through and as we go through we are
going to be on a tree is that possible
yes okay now so what does it involve
so so each time when we start to do a
ALS we get a children and this is when
this is when we need to add these
children
to to our tree to the main tree
okay this is when this is the birth of a
new
nod Nots several knots so
yeah so so when is when when do we start
to add a nod you know we begin with a
empty tree you know so
we add a not when we
uh when we
first encounter a CD
and and when we
yeah so that's the question when do we
so whenever you have a CD with a name
okay whenever you have a CD with the
name that's when you add a new node
okay and whenever you have LS that's
when you have a new bunch of knots
children knots to the current nod okay
yeah so we can yeah so this is yeah okay
so
the point here is that we need to add
knots in this process we're gonna need
you know and it happens when you know
okay so we are going to
add a nod and how do we create a nod
well when it's a CD name case
we
build a nod so
yeah so we need to build a tree so
when you create a nod
okay then you need to attach this to a
tree to an existing tree that we have
built already okay and there is a
problem of where
or
how you're gonna attach the tree attach
your new knot to the tree
okay so let's look back to our two
possible ways one is Association you
know a dictionary a nasty dictionary the
other one is next at least
so let's think about Association case
first so suppose you have a nested
dictionary
and now
you have
a current directory
with a bunch of children you want to add
to your nested dictionary
okay how are you gonna do that
well what you need is the
you need you need the actual position
of the nested dictionary to add to
you know in other words you need a
specific way to
you know
um
so you need a bunch of
key names
in a specific order that indicates how
they are nested
then you
yeah so then you create a new dictionary
under that
dictionary
yeah you insert a new dictionary into
that dictionary
so if you use the you know dictionary or
Association you need
let me let me let me explain okay for
example let's say python let's say
python
so
so let's go to python
so for example python you use a
dictionary right I'm using python to
explain it because that way people
understand
uh because wolfam language is
you know probably new to you guys
so Association you get key get value or
delete key or add key for example this
is how you add
add a new key into Association
but in Python
let's go to dictionary string
arithmetics Boolean conditional Loop
data structure uh
iterators dictionary okay so here's
python dictionary
but what we need
is nested dictionary so this is how you
add a entry you know add a key value
pair to the dictionary
but
that's a flat you know that this is
assuming you have a flat dictionary so
when you want to add a key to a nested
dictionary you you need to
get the position so you need something
like this okay in Python you need
something like key one
like that okay so you
yeah so this key one two three
you can call them indexes
so you need a sequence of index to add
your key
oh yeah that makes sense now so so each
of this key will just be directory names
then
okay now it's becomes clear much clearer
than before
yeah each of these key will be your
directory names so you can so when you
go through this problem
uh when you go through this problem
each step you build you have a value of
current directory
you know which is a path like that
so when you are ready
to add a new
nod into your tree
so you start you know you have the
current directory which is a path
then
each part of the directory name becomes
a key
so this is how
this is how you can add
okay so yeah okay and I think I got I
got this is uh very easy way to do it
yeah so let's use a Association list or
key value pairs you know this is
yeah because the key is just to be
directory names
yeah so this is a easy way
to
represent the tree
at least for the directory structure
using a nested dictionary
okay
what about now let's go back to the list
nested list if we are using nested list
how we how we add a tree how we add a
new node well in that case
you need to need you need the numerical
indexes of your tree so if you have a if
you have a list it will be something
like this okay this
uh
it would be like that something like
that okay if you are using a nested list
to represent the structure
okay
who who is who is uh pinging me
a lot of these people come here watch my
videos
uh how does it compare with Google in
terms quality results
these people I have a lot young people
following me
uh you know many of them are teenagers
um
so
hello we have a gender selection box
hello or flamio
no we are working on a tree okay um so
yeah so so now we have
we have the two possible data structure
a dictionary or we're gonna use a list
it looks like dictionary is better
because if you use a list
then there's no direct way
of a given uh there's no direct way of a
given file path
to
the positions of a tree
that's right
uh so you need to keep a current value
of the indexes and that's tedious that's
very tedious okay so we don't want to
use that okay so we want to use the
dictionary to represent a tree
where each nod is a key and it's a
string okay but now back to another
question how do you represent the meta
info for example
so if the key is a directory name but
how do you represent size well
in that case we can create a separate
list
to represent the size that's right okay
yeah we can create a separate you know
lookup table
to represent where you're given a file
path we can represent
you know we have a value of its size
yeah
okay so we decided
necessary two ways to represent the tree
nested nested dictionary or Nest at
least
if we use sticked then it's easy to
represent the position we want to add a
new node
and that's just a list of keys
or the names okay like that
but
if we use a list
then
we need a list of position
corresponding to the
current
okay
like this
it's
this is hard because we need to maintain
each
we need to maintain how the names
corresponds to the indexes
Okay so
so this is the problem of ways to
represent the tree
so so far we decided we're gonna
represent by a
nested dictionary okay
let's write it down here actually let's
just put it here so we have all the
information
uh about how to solve this problem
okay here
okay now
close that we open back to
back to the Wolfram language code okay
so now we decided
with clarity
that we want to represent a tree using a
nested dictionary
okay
yeah
now there's a
problems of
of
storing The Meta info
such as
name file or the name and the size
okay
when using a
next it tick to represent a
we can have a separate
list
[Music]
separate dictionary
where keys are
file path
okay and value is size
this way
we can easily
find any knots size
that's right that's how we solve this
problem
so finally we decided we're gonna use a
nestic dictionary to represent the tree
and the problem of how to store The Meta
info
corresponding to each knot is solved by
using another dictionary okay
good now we have clarity
instead of a blind you know instead of a
trial and error
okay
so now okay so now we're gonna use the
nested dictionary and now yeah so we got
a lot of the info here we need to redo
yeah it doesn't
okay now let's back to
I'm gonna solve this problem in this
video for sure nobody nobody is watching
I think two people who are you
uh okay so
so yeah use the dictionary okay use the
dictionary okay now let's go back
um
let's go back to uh code okay so here's
the input
split the input into that then
we process each line one at a time
and build a tree as we go okay we
decided this is the optimal
instead of
scanning
the least multiple times one time to
build
order
names
another time to build or file names then
build or path then build a tree from
list of path
okay that's one way to go but we decided
um
we decided
that's not
oh actually now that way also can work
out because now
this is how you add to the dictionary
so now it's easy Once you have a list of
file path it's actually quite easy to
to turn them into a nestic dictionary
that represents the same structure
yeah because each I you know each part
of the path is just a key
that's right
fantastic so which way to go so should
we
should we be or at least a file path
first or should we
directly be or the the you know three
years we go
um
let me think about it
Okay so
so if we have at least let's look at the
file path again so if we have at least a
file path
can you actually build
a nested dictionary easily
yes
okay or flamio say speed of the list of
file path first
okay I'll take your suggestion because
the other way
you know uh you know uh
optimize later okay good yeah I'll take
that it's fantastic optimize yeah that's
a good I mean that's that's a good
advice yeah I mean let's let's finish
the problem first okay okay so we build
a path um
we build a
at least a path
first okay
Okay so
then turn the paths into a tree okay
fantastic and this comments let's just
forget about it
okay let's do that okay now
now start to get into the detail so if
it's a command
uh then we need to several things we
need to do okay first of all Global tree
now we know it's a Association now uh
not the least anymore
so
so it's gonna be your empty Association
yeah okay let's start to
oh wait so we don't wait let's not worry
about that first because we are going to
build a list of path first okay
okay that's what we're gonna build a
list of strings okay start with empty
now let's get to
let's get to starting to get
um
okay so let's see what is it if it's a
command set con directory Okay so
this we
let's let's those are things we were
thinking before but let's start fresh
Okay so
start with the path list that's empty
and we split you know we split the lines
okay so X1 is lines
okay
let's rename them so it's better okay
lines
so
each one of these is one of that then
you need to map
okay map
okay map map to the lines
and the
you map this function to the lines at
level one okay
so Line Parts
so now this is a list of
line parts list each one
each one is like let me show you okay
for example each one is going to be like
okay
okay you know I'm going extra miles to
because
okay so anyway so so people can
understand so so now we have each line
part of this thing and actually let's
run it so actually we have a example
let's run it I mean so you can actually
see
so far uh
there okay
yeah so this is line part list you know
at least like that okay
so next
next we're going to
so we're gonna go through this line part
list okay now it's uh more clear okay so
now
so we want to map again okay map to this
list and the first level okay and we
need to map a function to this list okay
and this function will be
um
okay actually this is going to start to
process it this is not yeah this is
starting to actually build the final
path okay
yeah we can you can we can still do one
function
but it's going to be a big function
okay
let's just say result
and it's not yeah that's I mean let's do
it yeah so
um so what is going to be so let's
forget about
foreign
we need some things here
okay so let's get
okay let's start here so it's going to
be a function okay now the function uh
we let's write it out
four
um
okay function
function something expression okay the
input is just
Line Parts
okay
and and what does it do here is a body
okay so the body is gonna be a bunch of
if statements okay
we're gonna purify the code hold on a
second so
let's you know you move from language
you can
purify the code
fantastic okay so now
so Line Parts
right we we gonna map this function and
map it to this list okay now a function
okay now what does the function do so
it's a bunch of if statements okay
a very bunch of if statements so first
of all if it is a
if the line Parts it's not just say line
parts let's say
bye
okay
bear with me
and simpler
foreign
list
should be lying Parts uh okay
let's just sxx
okay it
Okay so
if okay now if string that's not do that
so now let's say so if x x
the first part
is
equals to
a dollar sign
okay that means it's a command okay
okay
so if the first part is a dollar sign
so we see we analyzed here before
if it's a dollar sign then it's a
command then we need then what we do is
so it's a command then if it's a
and where is this nested if expression
neces if expression
confusing so if it's a command
let's see
wait where does it end
yeah here okay so if it's a command and
here is
line is not a command
okay so here is what happens when it's
not a command
so here is weapon uh is a command okay
so if it's a command then we do if it's
a CD
right yeah so if it's a CD then what we
do and
yeah if it's a CD
[Music]
one two three one two three
one two okay
okay so anyway so if it's a command then
there are two possibilities it's c d o l
s okay
foreign
something like that so
so if it's a CD then what we do what to
do well we have a name
we are not necessary we have a
so we have uh CD name us or dot dot okay
CD so there are two possible cases a
name or dot dot
so if it's a CD
um well
well okay let's think so what are we
gonna do so
name so once you get a name
you want to append to the current
directory
I mean we are building a fire path okay
uh yeah so CD or name append the current
directory and if it's a dot dot then
remove the last directory okay
so yeah so okay
so CD so you first if it's a CD then
there is two possibilities
and what what the is where is this
connected uh
if it's a CD then we build the path okay
now
now let's put this here temporarily
to make here clear
yeah okay so if it's a CD then we build
the path now let's create a current
path okay let's create a temp variable
let's say Okay empty okay cut the path
so if it's a CD
we and
okay so something like that okay
so if it's a CD and
and depends on start dot or not so
if
third element
is equals to
dot dot
okay then that means take off the last
um
actually this should be at least
let's make it because this is easier to
work with okay
okay this is easier to work with Okay
begin with empty okay so if it's dot dot
then then drop the last element of the
list okay
I'm pretty sure that's that's what um
drop negative one that means delete
uh that means delete last element
okay
so if it's dot dot means goes up One
Directory so the current directory will
just drop but otherwise
otherwise
otherwise you want to append
that with
with the
the third part
okay fantastic we are going somewhere
going somewhere
after two hours of coding we are going
somewhere
two hours of analysis
now we are like
on the in the flow
okay and I can guarantee you the final
solution is gonna be one single line
more elegant than any other
in a universe you know you look online
rust solution go land solution
JavaScript python Ruby bash whatever
language this Wolfram language solution
I would say it will be shortest
in terms of you know the character count
you know I can shorten the function
names later but and this is the shortest
it may not be the most efficient but you
know you cannot compare with C but it
will be the shortest
including Haskell and this okay let's
back to the code okay so if the third
party started then you
you drop the candle list okay you you
set the counter to that
otherwise you set the counter to that
and now there is a shortcut because this
you see this line let me show you this
here this year you can actually improve
it by since you're gonna assign it
anyway so put the assignment here
okay
so this line you know it would be
equivalent to this line functional
programming okay
so current path so CD so if it's a CD
then you change the current directory
okay yeah so double check double check
you need to double check I need to
double check
instead instead of you know later on
learning a code you don't know where it
went wrong so a pen give the expression
with element appended that's right
okay
okay we don't care about efficiency
right now you know you know I I just
want to finish the problem otherwise I
typically stuck for n hours in my videos
that's not good
okay so okay
so we got so so so what is going on now
so we got the
we processed you know so after a bunch
of CDs we have the current directory
path that's right
now
the ls case
okay now it's the ALS case
what do you do with the ls well
uh wait so
um
so and you need to do one more thing my
friend one more thing
once you got the current path you need
to push it to the
to to the current path list okay
push and shove push
wait what
oh okay so yeah wait
oh wait so you need a
yeah push here path list okay
each element is a doe or file name so
you need to push to there okay
so path list okay so push in Wolfram
language you don't have like
like push instead you say the proper
English a pen prepend okay no push no
push and pop what the does that
mean can mean anything like I'm gonna
push you
you know I'm gonna pop your cherry it
could be any anything but the idiotic
industrial programmers they are used to
this push and pop and where you know
such as
where something something or in the you
know SQL something something where where
where is it you know confusing ambiguous
abuse of English
push Pub where and and let you know in
in in in this you have let let something
what what let what let let's let's go
crazy let
idiotic industrial names okay and you
see it's worse my luck and what the what
the
so Papa English a pen prepend okay not
push
okay append to this path list and append
this thing
okay
uh yeah a pen two okay let's actually
let's say append
two yeah
you're gonna use a pen two
other so that we don't have to assign it
actually that's a sign no and it's not
because yeah okay let's just do this
okay
so
um yeah
yeah
a pen tool path list kind of path list
okay
yeah so every time we encounter a CD
we append to but only when it's
it's not
dot dot okay okay we need to modify this
spot
so okay so yeah you need to modify this
spot so put it here so if that is that
then that otherwise you
okay so now we need to yeah okay so
let's redo this
okay
so then you also do this okay so if it's
dot dot do that otherwise you do this
okay
okay does that make sense let's see
I hope that makes sense code condemned
77 hey we are making progress to this
problem day seven
build a directory tree be on the tree
actually nothing with nothing to do
actually with directory because it's not
about a fire system
rather it's using the concept of file
system
to induce a problem
of actually about building a tree so
this problem is about building a tree
it's not really about directories or
files
and we are going to hit the heart of the
problem actually building a tree not
you know doing work around of using path
we are we are building a final path list
first then we build a tree
okay so so current directory path list
equals to that okay if it's dot dot
otherwise
uh
well these statement needs to come after
so
uh okay so yeah
okay so we have appended to the path
list
that's a major achievement basically
essentially that's gonna be
corresponding to adding a nod okay now
what if the command is a LS okay
if the command is LS
we
all right let's see so command is CD we
do that we do that then we add it okay
if it's LS we do nothing not a thing
how do you do nothing new okay in
Wolfram language null represents
nothing
okay
yeah so
so we start to read the next line
okay
now the next slide which is when a line
is not a command okay so what to do when
the line is not a command
children of course
you're gonna start to add a bunch of
children
oh okay
okay that's
then but each children has also a
H okay so then you need another
dictionary
children's list of children's okay I
mean you know the size file size table
size lookup
okay and it's this is going to equals to
Association
which is Association list okay which is
a dictionary
in
python speak
so in Python speak it's called
dictionary in Wolfram language speak
it's called Association in lisp speak
it's called associative list
okay
so um Association key value pairs that's
right so Association they are empty okay
okay that's size lookup table now
that's all um
yeah so so that's a procedure okay next
so what if it's LS
what
what you gonna do when you see your
nails do nothing
okay next
when the line is not a command what
you're gonna do well we're gonna add to
the current
at it as child to current
it's what that's what he's gonna do so
the current
yeah what wait
wait we are not building a tree yet so
we actually just added to the lookup
table
okay
so add to the lookup table
then it's gonna be two parts
okay key in value
value is the size okay
and the key is gonna be the path okay so
what is the path well the path is the
is the um
the path so
let's see
let's group them so that we can actually
have some
easier syntactical unit
to work with because I can you know
press run key and get the whole
syntactical unit
Okay so
so look up size so what the key what is
the Key Well it's
the you first of all you have to create
the current file path so the current
file path is gonna be I mean the file
right so if it's a LS
okay so so if the line is not a command
it means
size and file name okay
we add to that table okay so it's size
and file name so how do you get the size
and file name of course you need to
split it
where is our speed
XXX okay so x x
x x x x
1 is the size okay
uh okay
two is
file name okay
so what do you do you first of all so uh
so you want to
yeah yeah so file name is here
file name
you
you append to the current uh
path list right that's right
you append to the current path list
and you also need to do that okay
so current uh path list you appended
then you
you know actually you don't want no wait
hold on a second so
so you
so let's let's write some
temp variable okay
let's get this right
okay let me show you how to do it uh I'm
sorry if this is I'm babbling but but
babbling is good for viewers because
then you know what I'm doing
file size that okay and the file name
okay now it's easy to understand
okay so with this with expression
that means
like this led
in this case it's constant okay
so then then
you can move this inside okay
so now
so append current path list that's
that's just a
okay append the file name to it which is
here
okay then you append
to the Past list of that okay so
that
uh and uh
yeah so that's one thing you need to do
actually there's another thing you need
to do
tree
um
yeah let's do it here
file path
equals to that okay now it's readable
because we are using variables
so you add the so we are you know
encountering a line that is not a
command so which means it's a two things
file size and file name so we got the
file size we got the file name and we
need to get the file path and the file
path is of course
um
that
Kunta with the file name added okay then
so after you get the file path you need
to append your file path to your Global
file list
because it's a file we are building a
list of paths right yeah so we do that
okay so actually uh wait I want to use
this
yeah so that's one thing to do we add to
the global file path list and then we
need to add yeah to add we need to add
to the file size lookup table okay how
do you how do you
um add an item to a dictionary to a
um
to a
Association
you know so let's look up let me show
you the association documentation
so you can add by
and let's look at let's look at my
tutorial
because I have
better understanding yeah in a different
style so my tutorial so you want to add
a key value pair to a existing
Association so let's see add key
so that's all you have to do there so
that's Association
that's the key
ah my back hurts I need to like take
another break
I was hoping I was you know today I
didn't do any video of my mug shot so
you don't see me
so but I'm stretching I was thinking
because I need to be really focused
that's why I don't include a headshot
so you focus on my keystrokes and stuff
but it turns out you know this is gonna
be three hours but we we're getting
close okay
so Association key value pair this is
how you add it
okay uh
or you can use associate two okay let's
use associate two
because I don't like the you know the
imperative
okay Association variable is that and
now you just need a rule so the the way
you write a rule is like that okay let
me show you this rule here okay so the
key what is the key
well the key is the file path
uh actually should we turn that so right
now the file path is actually your list
of strings each string is the directory
name
so you should return this actually into
a giant string or should we just um
so that's so you know the code is not
readable right now let's see what you
guys are saying
condemned 77 says some short words what
makes
some short words what makes Wolfram
special I just found that wufan got
interviewed by Tim ferries I need to
listen to it you know wolf and Stefan
Wolfram got interviewed by lots of
people for example lexed Friedman
he has interviewed Stefan with at least
twice
and I mean if you search YouTube you'll
find quite a lot interviews of Stefan
wolfen over the past
15 years on YouTube so and he also goes
around to different universities to give
a lecture so you'll find a lot of his
videos
and you know if you have watched my
video I have also done quite a lot
talking about the language about
so I recommend
if you want to learn the language
I recommend you watch my videos
uh
you know they are quite there are some
not many other YouTubers that teach you
full-time language but I would say
you know if you trust me
you know I'm one of the major source for
teaching wolfam language because I've
been coding it for 15 years plus mostly
in 1990s okay so but if you want to know
more about Stefan Wu from the person you
know he's also a physicist computer
scientist he wrote wolfam language you
know
and uh so yeah so and he's uh founder of
the field of cellular automata which is
kind of very interesting especially for
you guys programmers say the word
cellular automata you know a giant Book
on a new kind of science
let me show you so sorry
new kind
so I you know I went through the book
multiple times it's a huge book you know
that's about hunt uh 1000
200 Pages something like that very heavy
so you know I I went through you know I
read them
since when came out 2003 or so
yeah so if you want to know about Stefan
Wolfram you know he's you know he's got
his website and blog so you can read
them or videos you know if you want to
learn about Wolfram language you can
start from my
tutorial okay
so that's a digression now let's get
back to the code okay
uh so I hope that answers your question
I don't know who is Tim Ferris actually
who is Tim Ferriss
I'm starting to digress a lot American
Author entrepreneur I hate that word
Angel invested okay yeah
maybe he's good you know I don't I don't
really trust this type of people
the four hour work week for our body the
four hour Chef no okay
okay interesting but
I am not sure about that
okay so so that's about wufam okay and
so familiar says I didn't notice you
didn't go to face cam until you
mentioned
is also on YouTube yes indeed but you
wouldn't notice that because YouTube
doesn't push up his videos often enough
oh team fairies is the four hour work
week guy I see okay
okay back to code
you know because I'm I'm a nerd so and
I'm I'm a programming nerd and I'm a
nerd in general so I my my main interest
is also mathematics artificial
intelligence that's my in philosophy and
some Linguistics you know but yeah so
these are my
things that I have obsessed in my life
so I don't
uh care much about those
entrepreneurs except except Stefan wufam
and Steve Jobs these two person I admire
and also Elon Musk you know typically
when you talk about these super rich
people I I don't like them I despise
them but these three persons is
exceptional they have a huge I would say
huge influence
in my life and high Heidi I personally
highly respect them
and I can see I synchronize with their
View
from in different aspects Steve Jobs
Stefan wolfam Elon Musk you know these
three persons in different ways I very
much like their View and I like what
they did what they have done and I like
how their integrity that's one thing I
pay attention the most the Integrity of
the person
does the person lie you know like most
politicians this is a person like doing
questionable things make a lot of money
like like you know 4chan Reddit like
Facebook you know these people
are they do you know what did they do
you know are they you know you look at
their lives events history are they
always see something controversial
okay so anyway these three persons are
highly respect I admire I respect and I
also associate with the way they a lot
of the way they see the world okay
anyway back to the code let's back to
the code
now the LMS guy you know of course he's
today the richest person so you'll have
a lot of different opinions about him
you know and many a lot negative
but you know I I but you know if you ask
for my own personal Judgment of course I
judge you I look into a lot you know I I
carefully you know I don't
you know it's very hard but it's very
it's almost impossible to get me to like
someone okay so when I say I like Elon
Musk very much
you can be sure that at least I put a
lot of effort to look into you know and
he's you know elements is is not paying
me so I got nothing to do with Illness
but I find him just great okay that's
that's my opinion okay
so yeah so if you um yeah anyway that's
right let's let's get back to code okay
we'll find language okay so we
we make it made a lot of progress a
little break that's good for me uh I
need to take a break to ease my back
okay so this this part okay let's finish
this part so let's so now
so when the window command let's go back
to code let's put my mind back to code
so when the command is encountering a
line of file what you do is you get the
file size you get the file name you get
the file path which is the list of
directory names okay then you
um then you
appended to the global file list that's
right then you
uh yeah then you add an entry to the
size table size lookup table okay and
the key would be the file path okay so
here the key
should be a string not final path wait
should it be string or final path let's
leave it let's see leave it to be a list
of strings where each string is a
directory okay let's not do optimization
now you know it's
okay
okay so so far so good let's look up
let's look at our overall structure this
thing this
um
copy let's see if it let's go back to
Fan language let's see if we did we
screw up the syntax no this is a
complete code nice looking now if we can
can we do it that way yeah
okay back here and let's put here let's
see yeah it's much more cleaner okay now
we're gonna delete this part to see
efficiency
okay so here
uh oops okay so now make a backup now
what do we do next
uh
okay so so far we have covered when the
line is not a command okay we covered
all cases already
when the line is a command CDLs
when the line is not a command oh oh we
missed one part here you see when the
line is not the command you have the
possibility of a duh
okay more things to do okay
uh okay
okay so now now we need the if statement
another if statement okay
okay so we need another if statement
God
so you can see this with uh
if statement
what you're gonna test yeah you're gonna
test if the first part is a
you're gonna test if the first part is a
number
no do you just you're gonna test the
first parties okay so let's put the if
statement inside
and we can because you know these file
size okay so we have to put the if same
here so if
if the XX
first part
is equals to a duh
then it's a do okay then you just do
whatever the you have to do otherwise
that
okay so so if I install you do something
there okay
yeah okay so what what happens if it's a
duh okay it should be simpler
if it's a duh then we um
so let's do a width again so
okay so if it's a duh then the first
part
the second part is the name okay
so the second part is the name okay and
this we don't need
[Music]
we don't need
okay very easy all we have is the name
so what you're gonna do when you get the
name well you're gonna
um
yeah you can you you're gonna
um add
so this associate we don't need
you need to add the name to
yeah you don't care actually if it's a
directory
what you gonna do with it you don't care
you can know it
oh yes
that's right
because
we can just ignore it
Because unless later on You CD to that
then you maybe do something because if
you if it's a and you don't CD to the
that means you you don't get files in it
so you can ignore it
so if it's a duh we just ignore the
whole thing
okay
no
so okay so actually let's let's uh our
code is complete let's run it
for so the first for the rest we can
like delete them now okay delete
do we actually need the the things we
were trying to
um yeah so actually we don't
needed to lead the
is meta and
okay delete the fact so now code is just
just that
okay so now what if we run the code
right copy it
back here
select all
okay paste
please no arrows please
oh fantastic wait something is wrong
okay let's look up our
uh let's look at uh global
path list let's see
okay so you can see
we have some error there so you see this
is this
path
but let's Let Me Show
yeah and then
okay
yeah
can we do that okay so yeah so we can so
that's our path list there's some error
because we added
you know so yeah we added CD to the
twice
okay but let's look at the current path
list
see what we got
we don't care about that actually
because that's temporary now let's look
um wait let's
make sure our name is
one one single R okay now let's look up
uh what's uh size lookup table
okay size is incorrect
it should be file size okay
so no size but file size copy all let's
do it again paste it here Eva
Okay so
so what is the
size lookup table
okay so we made some mistake that we
have repeated the names in the path
okay we need to fix it
can
uh
so we have to fix
we somehow added the names twice does it
always and also we have the file name
wrong because you know it should be an
actual file name not
that
so
yeah so yeah so it's not good
okay where do we get the file name
file name okay
fail path
now where is file path defined
I'm getting tired and we're not gonna
finish the problem
and I'm hungry
um
found and this is idiotic
so file name
so line is not a command it means it's a
size in file name okay add two size
lookup table okay
yeah
so if it's a directory ignore it okay
now but otherwise
you have the file size but first of all
the path is wrong
here the path list so let's fix the path
list first so our path list
okay here
okay so path list
rename again let's rename our things
this is too long current
okay
it makes uh code much easier simpler to
see
okay and uh
then our path list let's just say paths
okay
each element is a
and uh
so our X path is incorrect because
uh because if X3 equals to that
this this nice V formatted
thing is not semantic
so if X3 equals to dot dot so we need to
command and if it's a dot dot
means a command and it's a dot dot you
what you do is that current
equals to you drop it
yeah you drop it otherwise current or
equals to append current that okay
Okay so
so this is if it's a city okay
I don't know so
um
you know I need a break and currently
actually I'm thinking maybe
actually we can rewrite this in most in
more uh understandable way because right
now it's a bunch of if nested if
so oh yeah wait we forgot uh wait this
is a function right okay
um
nine parts
Okay so
it's still good you might feel good yeah
I'm still good
I couldn't uh is a job
if if that's if it's that
current equals to
oh wait
what see what the is this if
structure now
so if that
it's
command
okay
otherwise
otherwise this part is
yeah so this part is a command
okay so if it's a command what you do
so and if it's a command
is CD
so if it's CD
backup
then you
if it's CD then
if it's a CD
then depends on its dot dot or not
okay so you actually don't want this
nine okay so if it's not that then drop
current by one that's right if it's not
dot dot
then
then you append
wait this repeated here what the
what
oh yeah we forgot
yeah that's why that's why we had it
twice because we forgot to
delete it
yeah because we were trying to modify
the code
to make it into this way and we forgot
to delete the old copy okay so now it's
better
so if it's not dark and then turn the
drop otherwise kind of append can't uh
yeah a pin two actually you can see
yeah so now let's do again
select all paste
run it
no better
let's see
we have
C
better
we don't have the repetition anymore the
repetition is just editing mistake
now but we still have repeated paths
you see
we need not sure if I'm lying is a good
tool for this task so oh it seems to me
a bit more complicated than you should
the important is have fun and learn
isn't it
yeah well
I'm not sure
I would agree with that statement you
know this is not suitable for Wolfram
land
uh
yeah but it's yeah it's complicated you
know
it's getting yeah this doesn't look good
this doesn't look good
but anyway yeah yeah let's get let's
keep going okay so
so where does this file name
came from
so when
if
the first part you know so if the line
is not command it means it's a size and
file name
oh
and file name okay
if the ignore
hip file add to size lookup table okay
so if it's the ignore so but if it's a
file
in the first part is not a
so if it's a file then we add
the first file file size the second part
is file name right
yeah
then the third part is the file size so
why is this file name
what is this a pan counter
final path
a pen couldn't do
the file name
you know file path okay
so let's print these
yeah we you know this is not
uh
but it's
I think in other languages you're gonna
get similar complexity
uh
so final path what is final path let's
print
this is
this is dummy's way of debugging
why why the is that the way why
does it just print file names
so file paths oh I see yeah because with
the Wolfram language yeah I know that
when you use the with statement you know
this is like this lead but it doesn't
you know when you have the value the
later variables does not know the value
of the previous variable so over here
the file path will get the literal file
name
so it's idiotic so what you want to do
is you
here's what you want to do okay
so
just move this here okay and move the
variable here
or you can say this is xx3 okay so
anyway
so let's just do it here so well
yeah so remove that copy all
select or paste run it again
we will file past this look of your ass
sheet now another problem is that
because when you say this
then you cannot use width because width
is temporary constants
for each one of them they must have a
value
okay so let's change it to module then
okay copy all
single paste run it
back in recursion depth what
recursion depth exceeded some our code
is wrong somewhere
what
why why is it recursion oh because we
forgot yeah we forgot the semicolon okay
but
let's move back this
okay let's just put that there
and
move this back here
remove that semicolon and change this
back to width constant okay
now
Sergo paste
eval
okay
fantastic finally we are seeing actual
file names okay I mean yeah file names
you see so now let's see path
uh X path
fantastic and beautiful
you know we're getting some videos so we
actually this correct
there's a repeat it's a repetition no
correct now the other thing to look up
is size lookup table
fantastic and beautiful
we going somewhere
next pinball he says I was searching for
good keyboards and I ended up on your
channel thank you I'm glad I found you
thank you
so today's live stream so far it's been
three hours I think three hours and 16
minutes we are sobbing day seven and uh
uh
you know and so we I spent three hours
and it's not done yet but very close you
know we're getting closer and closer so
far this is correct and this is correct
all we have to do now is to turn this a
list of file path
into a tree
and we can do that by
we can do that by as we explain here by
just um you know create a dictionary of
a key key each of these key is just a
directory name
you know like
like uh like yeah each of the key is
just directory name
then we have a tree
the data structure of nested dictionary
that represents the
directory structure okay so it's easy to
do that means you know so far so good I
think we are good close that don't save
quit Wolfram language
restart
so we have you know we clear all the
variables
and in Wolfram language is again like I
talked before is this system
so
and everything is a symbol now when a
disadvantage of this system including
images and common disk is that after a
while you have a bunch of symbols
that's you know you you know you can
clear them but usually you don't do that
you know if you clear a symbol by
mistake
you have a problem so usually so so the
the the the point is that with this
system including Wolfram language
oftentimes you just start over like quit
and restart
you know actually that's true for emac
this as well
so in fact for me I quit every day I
create and restart emacs every day
I mean normally if you just use emacs
you don't have to you know you can use
emacs for a month
for a month or no or more which I used
to do like you have 300 several hundred
or a thousand open buffer you know files
but but if you actually start to code
emac beasts then you have to restart
every day because that because you have
to clear you know all your local
variables you know you you have to clear
the symbol table basically
so that's one flaw with lisp kind of
system
you have a symbol table and basically
it's like it's kind of like Global so
all the symbols you ever used are stored
there even if if even if it's some
symbol you you use by mistake so what
I'm saying is that if you are this code
the e-macblo you do have to restart
almost every day okay
so far so good so we have our code and
so here is the code the full code
I I I'm gonna take a break okay so
here's the full card
evaluated
and we have let and we have built the uh
basically that's a list of file path and
then we can build a tree from that now
let's let's go to Let's pop this back to
today's talk show
so today's talk show now let's take the
actual input and see what we get okay
the actual input where is it
right
what where's the actual today's input I
thought I saved the file
what
close that
Untitled close don't save close close
yeah oh
start a new window then
okay so now we go to talk show
we go to talk show
today's talk show we drop to the
directory
event of code seven
so here is the input close close
paste the input here
application in browser there it is
today's input okay now denying this
somewhere search for the current
directory
yeah so it appeared
twice
wait it appear only once okay anyway so
copy the input which is 1000 lines and
go back to Wolfram language let's see if
that works okay
so you want the so here is the proper
input let's see what kind of things we
get
a minute
okay so lots of directories and stuff
and videos
[Music]
let's go to the bottom
okay so it says three thousand your four
thousand items now let's see the path
Astic
so each one of these list is the file
path and each subpart is a directory
name
you know you can join them into a string
if you want
so here is a file path let's join them
into a string okay
so we are making progress let's do that
Okay so
you want to map a function to each one
of that and the function will be stream
drawing
uh
okay so map that function to the path
then each one of these is a string okay
and huge then we say
go the down go to the bottom we say the
last output
and show them in column
okay
oh when you join the stream you need to
add a slash Okay so
okay
so when you join the string you need to
add the slash let's go back to our code
and X path
okay
uh you want to stream
join okay argument
showing by slash
slash had a ampersand
to make this a function okay and the
slash at means map this is a shorthand
operator so you are mapping this
function to this path okay so copy all
and we add semicolon here to suppress
the output
suppress the long output okay so
semicolon semicolon semicolon
semicolon okay copy all
select or paste and
and let's open the
the input
huge input okay
evaluate the code
yeah we still forgot somewhere
why is it not putting the
oh yeah the last part yeah that's what
we want
let's you know
oh what
wait did we do it correctly no I didn't
do it correctly what
let's look up join string
stream join it's okay
string join
at least
so why is this not correct
so let's get the last item
the last item is that let's try string
join
okay
the last output and we want to join by a
slash
what is what the is that
let's let's try and let's try it again
so X path let's get the last item slash
slash last
Returns the last item slash slash is the
post fix notation like the Unix pipe
okay so then
then you do that let's see what
what
oh you wait no there's no that's mistake
okay so do that
wait what
so where is uh Slash
let's try use some of the character Plus
oh you want to map to not
that's right
and string join
concatenation
wait how do you add the extra character
in between
uh okay that's not string showing
stream rifle
oh yeah so you want to use stream rifle
instead
string rifle
uh yeah so stream rifle
you want to map string rifle
with that okay let's do that
now it's much better you see each one of
these is a string
yeah
okay
so we got you know this looks correct is
it you know does it look correct
yeah let's use uh slash slash column
yeah what did I do that's legal
delete
so
paste again let's paste this
paste that yeah where's that
call
paste slash slash
column
show them vertically so this is correct
oh except we got double
uh why is that double in the front
anyway so we got a list of path
now we need to turn this into a
nested dictionary that's easy well
easier said than done to do this maybe
another 20 minutes
okay I'm tired
um this video is already
3 hours and 30 minutes okay I'm gonna
I'm gonna get up in a walk
okay so let's continue let's okay let's
just do something let's oh first of all
why why do you have the double slash
okay let's go take the the input let's
not
you know one thousand lines that's not
too that many okay let's just search for
CD it's truncated we want more input but
we don't want this many okay
so let's say up to here
okay so that's our input okay now go
back here replace input by that select
no
select or paste
run it
okay that's more manageable
okay but now we got a problem of slash
slash
who is the slash slash
came from
because almost every one of them got a
slash
so
let's search for Slash
okay
then
stream rifle so we don't actually
contain any slash anywhere
so
so why is it oh okay
so because the Unix command when you do
the Unix command you can just CD to the
root multiple times
right
so the when you have a that's that's a
special case
so the reason is that where is it where
is our talk show page
so the reason that when you see d
you know normally see your name but when
you CD or slash that has a different
semantic than name
because normally the name is the current
directory I mean the relative to the
current directory but when you have a
slash that's a absolute
um
you know
directory file path so it's not simply
your name but so there's a special
semantic attached to it so we need to
add that special
another special case here you see
so if it's not DOT
so if it's not dark then do that
otherwise
otherwise you can just add another if
statement you know change this into
another if statement if
okay so this is inefficient because we
are doing the XX third part multiple
times
so anyway so if it's a slash
well then it depends on whether slash is
the first time you encounter stash or
not
idiotic you know
or we can just cheat you know once we
got this result we just remove or double
slash
let's do that
yeah the good point wins
um you know
that's that's kind of cheating you know
it's kind of cheating
so
so let's see what is our next PATH how
do you fix this thanks
oh wait no wait this is actually correct
it becomes incorrect when we join them
that's when the extra slash uh oh
logic is like
we are logically analyzing
incorrect logic anyway you know we are
trying to give excuses to why we are
wrong
but anyway so
this is correct
it's just that when we Join one of them
together
that's when the logic is wrong when you
when you join them together you add a
slash in between
but you shouldn't do it in the beginning
of the thing
and the reason for that is
okay so here actually so this is
interesting so this indicates
that the traditional Unix way is
actually logically inconsistent
because if we consider slash is a
root name of a directory
and slash is also used as a directory
separator
so when you have a root something you
should you really should begin with
double slash
so yeah so this so this problem shows
that the traditional Unix way is
actually logically inconsistent the
traditional Unix file path
yeah and what about Windows I don't well
I don't know let's not think about too
much about other things anyway so we got
that so we need to turn this into
into a um Association let's do that
let's do that I need to take a break
though
okay so how do we add Association so go
back to you know you know we want to
turn each of this line into a nested
Association and we can do that by
uh by just let's look at my
My wufan Language tutorial
Association
you need to turn this list of strings
into a
into a nested Syntax for Association
okay so Association add key
okay so that syntax is actually
so
God
so essentially we wanted to become
[Music]
where is our code
XPath
or is a tree
where is our tree
we don't have three yet
so we need to oh he uh wait
[Music]
the tree okay third tree is our tree so
so what we need to add is that
over here
we want to we don't need that part uh
actually so we want to turn this this
path into
a
a tree so
each one of that is gonna be
each of the elements is going to be
something something like that
[Music]
so again we map a function
to the list of path
and
and the association variable is just a
tree something like that okay
uh so you need a function here
so let's let's write out Maps so it's
easier to understand
okay we don't care level one it's always
level one so you want to map a function
here let's let's write out the four
uh function name
okay and you have a bunch of variables
and the function body so basically it
needs to do something like that
not easy
um
so each of the elements will become the
key key I'm going through for a rest
good stream okay we'll be back tomorrow
thank you for watching bye
yeah I'm gonna take a break too in fact
I think
um
stop it yeah
you know
yeah let's stop it so we didn't complete
we do it tomorrow then
four hours
okay yeah so thank you guys for watching
bye guys