Hello guys, welcome. Hello guys, welcome
to another episode of S talk show. We
are going to code Emac Bisp. We are
going to demonstrate this fantastic
command change
brackets. Okay. And if you are here, say
hi. Love to see your comments. If you
are not here, play at 1.5 speed and skip
around because I ramble. Okay. Let's
begin. Uh my keyboards glove 80 ultimate
hacking keyboard and this fantastic
thing called swallow board SV A L B O A
R D I have a video re review of all of
them on YouTube. Okay, so let's begin uh
Emacs lisp coding. So this fantastic
command. So am I ready? Hello feel. Uh
video check, audio check. Okay, so is
everything good? Yeah, let's go. Uh, I'm
using Sfly Keys.
Uh, I'm using Sawfly Keys and, uh, I'm
using a Vora keyboard layout. Uh, and,
uh, and Emacs, the most powerful editor.
Okay. So, let's show the bracket
commands. So, this command is fantastic.
Let me show you. Okay. So, let's say
copy that. So I want for example
sometimes you know let's say I want to
change all these brackets to paren. So
uh what's a key? Uh let's see what is
the
key. Uh I forgot what is a key. So let's
just call the command by name meta
xar change bracket pairs. Okay space rh.
Okay do it. and uh change square
brackets to paren do it. Fantastic. You
see, if you're going to do this
manually, it's going to take a while
because you're going to do uh find
replace of left parent and then the
right parent, you know. So, I can also
change it to let's say call it again
space RH do it. uh let's say now pen to
let's say some fancy one totto
brackets you see fantastic and it needs
not to be one line you know you could
have
like you know thousands of lines so
uh close
reopen put the cruisers somewhere in the
block it change bracket pairs do it uh
this time toto bracket to uh lenticular
that's another Chinese bracket fantastic
okay so that's a demo of this command
and so you have you know if you you know
pro if you want to port a program from
one language to another Python wolf lisp
or if you want to you know sometimes
it's
template or curly quote or markdown
markdown quote or Emacs quote or mod
quote quote you know so you can change
to all of them or you can remove them
let's try it again so change some
brackets now lenticular brackets lentic
uh
wait change brackets pairs do it
lenticular do it to none so it removes
them all so fantastic okay so that is a
command command close. Okay. And uh now
if you want to use that command just go
to this website just copy it. The code
is
here. Okay. That's one
topic. Now what I'm going to do next is
that I'm going I need to modify make
some modification of this command
because right now the command it works
fine. It works perfect but I want to
change part of the
interface. Uh so this a bit it's more a
bit uh esoteric advanced EMAC topic
involving the interactive interactively
uh interactive core of the
command and also involving the command
parameters the arguments their
interaction. So it's some kind of
esoteric advanced design issue. Okay,
for most of you, you know, just grab the
code and use it. That's it. Okay, but
now I'm going to talk about this
interface related
thing. So, okay. So, all
good. Hello,
Rice. East Coast. Fantastic. New York.
Is it New York or MIT?
Massachusetts or Maryland, you know, or
men, you know, the eastern part of USA,
these tiny states, a bunch of
them. I never been there though, except
Maryland. Yeah. Uh, hi Theo. Hi, Dam.
Hi, Fio. How to learn this like you? You
just to be have to have
a willing and able. Okay. Are you
willing to do it? You need to have a
desire. Then are you able to do it? Yes.
Because learning a programming language
is fairly easy unlike learning
mathematics proof theory that takes some
some brain. Okay. Programming you know
if you are watching my channel you can
learn it. So you are able to do it but
are you willing? How willing are you?
That's a key question for you. So if you
are really uh willing you already um you
know my tutorials or ask bots or you
know the thousands ways. So let's get on
to the to this issue. Okay.
So let me start to uh to do the thing uh
I want to do okay which is make some uh
interface changes. Okay, let let me let
me start to explain this a bit
complicated.
[Music]
Um, so the command is uh R space RH.
Okay, that's the key is space RH. Let's
go to the source code. So the source
code here, copy it and let's work here.
Okay, so make a new EMAC lisp block.
Paste the code here. Pop the code up. do
it. So there is a code and the code is
let's make it longer. Okay, the code is
100 lines, 110 lines. Okay, a little bit
a little bit involved. 100 lines. So
what I need to do
is how do I uh explain this?
You see you can call this command. So uh
how do I how should I explain this? You
can you know in like normally okay
normally in a programming language
Python or something function name okay
you call a function by function name
paren uh three you know let's say add
you know so normally in a programming
language let's say Python or whatever uh
hold on a second let's start the Python
let's start a JavaScript actually so
JavaScript you can define
uh arrow function. arrow uh function.
Okay.
Not I forgot what's the
keyword. I don't want function. Okay.
Uh yeah. FN. Okay. So constant arrow
function. Constant.
Okay. Function. Okay. So let's say this
um let's define x add define a function
and two arguments x and y and all you do
is just x + y. So in this case you can
just say x plus no plus no plus no what
where is the plus key? No.
Uh okay there. So there is your function
and then you can just say
uh we are kind of digressing but let's
say add three four. Okay print it and
the
eval fantastic seven. So you define a
function and you call a function just by
put a bracket behind after that. Okay.
So, so in EMAC bisp pretty much the
same. Let's do a EMAC bisps. Yeah. So,
okay, I'm talking it about this issue in
a more interesting way, but it's it's a
bit more to get to what we want to do.
But let me show you. Okay. So, let's say
add in eac list. You define
uh x add. Let's keep the same name. Uh
let's uh add and uh how many arguments?
Let's say two.
Okay. Uh we don't care about
that. Add two numbers. Okay. And uh then
you say then you just uh
um plus x y.
Okay. That's it. And you call
it
by this is uh 34. Okay. Now evaluate
that. So now Emacs knows that. Now
evaluate this part and insert the result
here. Seven. Fantastic. So you can see
let's pop it back. You can see we did
you know here is
JavaScript here is emacisp. Okay.
Now in JavaScript you define a function
then you call it just add a par after
it. In eacisp you you put a par on the
hole. Okay.
Uh northern Carolina. Oh
okay. Diego Brazil. Fantastic. Okay. So
let's uh well let's just for fun let's
add some Python. Okay. Python variety
idiotic Python. Python most idiotic
language. So you
define function. How do you define a
function? I forgot. Uh in Python
what? I forgot how to define a function.
Dev. Okay. Dev X add XY. Good. Add to
num numbers. Okay. Then just return x +
y. So in Python you define the function.
Now what is this? Oh, am I using tabs?
Fascinating. I'm using
tabs. Contrary to the kido vonome idiots
convention. Okay. So you want to call
the function. Okay. Call it uh call it
just say uh three. You need a comma for
and you need to print it. So print that.
Okay, I think that's
it. Now let's you know I can call this
command. Let's do it. Let's see. Please
make it work. Yes, it works. And uh
let's put the result back here. So call
this
uh do that. Do that. There it is. Seven.
Fantastic. So you see I'm using using
kasawa python mod
uh not pia but
uh kasawa python mod and uh kas
javascript mod and of course eac this
mod. So that's all you know fantastic
the power of learning emac this you can
do it too. Okay. So anyway, here is the
Python code. Runs fine. Fantastic. Put
it back. Syntax code show in browser. So
we got examples of defining a function
in JavaScript, in Python 3 and in
eacisp.
Now, now let's get starting to talk
about the interactive thing. Now in a
normal programming
language you you don't you cannot call
this command interactively a function
you know and you don't you know because
they are not like
emacs you define it then you call the
function by you know the function name
par whatever same thing in eacisp
however you see in eacisp because it's a
editor you have the feature of
interactive interactively be calling the
command. Okay. So, let's let's let's
Yeah. Okay. Great. So, let's uh work out
this example. So, Emacis, let's do it
again. Let's now this time make it
interactive. Pop the code out.
So, so what you do is you have uh you
have to
um let's see uh let's
see let's see okay so
um so control u first then meta x then x
add. So we are trying to call this
command interactively. Okay. Enter. Uh
it won't work right now. You need to add
something. You see but it shows it
proves a point that is you can call any
function by just meta x. But when you do
that there's a question. How do you
actually tell emac what is the argument?
You see that's a thing.
So that is in fact what this interactive
part is
for. So for example uh so okay am I am I
doing good? So for example let's say
let's
say add three and four. Okay this new
function it just return three and four
add them together uh
without requiring any argument. So if
you evaluate it then you can meta xar
add three and four. Okay do
it. Okay it did it and uh go to the
message buffer
uh where is the result. Okay, let's say
the ins. Okay, let's say
insert insert
uh insert that and you need a number two
string. Okay, number two string. Okay,
fantastic. Put it inside. Pify the code.
Okay, let's try that
again. Evaluate that code. Now go here.
Meta
X add three and four. Enter. You see it
got
seven. Insert it here. Okay. You can
insert in any other browser. Okay. Let's
see a new buffer. Call it do it seven.
You see it could be anything. It could
be today's date. It could be the result
of getting a website. You know,
whatever.
So the point here is that we are we
defined a function and we are calling
this function interactively by meta x.
Okay, you cannot do that in JavaScript
in Python. Well, you can, you know, in
Python for example, then you go to the
shell, then you have to, you know, you
have to interact interact with the
shell. In JavaScript, for example, you
then you interact with a browser.
Okay? But then you have to actually code
it specifically. But I mean the thing
with emacisp is that it's designed so
that you can trivially make any function
in eacisp to be interactive to just meta
x. Okay that's that's what this line is
for. You know when if you are new to
Emac this you might ask you know what's
this interactive you know that so when
you have
this line right after your doc string
that means that makes this
function a command that means basically
you can meta x and call it
okay now but the when you call a command
interactively there's a question how do
you pass the arguments okay so There are
many ways. So the easiest way is just um
one of the most general
way is you add a
list you know we we Okay. So I um so
let's regroup. Let me explain a little
bit. Okay. Let me type it. So far so
good. What's your question? I've been
Emacs for six months. I've been using
Emacs for six months. Hi Pio. If I want
any function, I ask chat GBT and most of
the time you give me what I want.
Fantastic. After binge watching your old
streams, I'm fascinated by h how fast
you walk. Thank you.
Fantastic. How fast you are and how cool
your way of manipulating text is. Yes,
Kasafly keys. Thank you. For example,
cycle cycle hyphen lowline space is
really useful. Yeah. So, for example, I
go here. Uh,
wait. Press the wrong key. It close the
buffer. Reopen. So, cycle. You see
cycle cycle. Uh, you know, hyphen space
to uh whatever. Uh, actually we don't
want you can do it here.
Um something in the water does not
compute not
keypass
compute cycle psycho cycle. Fantastic.
Okay. So that that command is um
describe key. Press the key. That
command is cycle. And uh it is here and
you can get it. go to this URL and you
can grab the code and you'll have it.
Fantastic. Okay. But but now let's get
back. Yeah. So let's regroup. So in
EISP you
uh Okay. So wait uh define a
function. Okay. Uh
what? So this is define a
function called the
function. Okay, that's one thing.
Now in EMAC
listp any function can be trivially
that's a keyword
trivially turned into a
command and call and user can call it
by meta x okay which is
uh normally o
Odds plus X.
Okay. Let's uh let's make it okay.
Uh you can do this by
[Music]
adding right
after
the dark
stream. Okay. So there is a example.
Okay. Uh
now, okay. Uh next.
Now if your function has
argument you can
make you
can I if your function has argument you
know there are many so there's a
question there is a question how do you
pass the
function
argument when you call it interactively.
Okay, that's a
question. What do you do? There are many
ways.
There are many ways depending on the
function. Uh for example, so for
example, one of the way is you just ask
people simply and naive way is to simply
prompt user like like what do you want?
You know what what's the argument for
example like this? Okay. So
uh so you want so you want so
uh so let me explain this. Okay. So
instead of working on my problem, I
started to do a tutorial on the
interactive
thing
because you see my problem is is about
the interplay with with using you know
coding interactively and the
design the fun and the function design
of the functions argument the functions
signature
um you know but I can't explain that
without first explaining the interactive
you know the nature the you know the the
two ways to call the function. So so
right now I'm just like doing a tutorial
about this interactive thing.
Okay.
Hello. Am I doing good? Like am I can
you hear me? Can you see me? Sometimes
I, you know, like three years ago, I did
a whole uh stream like one hour
talking, but my my video and uh uh and
audio is not
on. And then two days ago, I did the 15
minutes stream stream live stream coding
a function. When I'm done, I realized
the, you know, the star stream is I
didn't click it.
So okay I'm I'm
autistic. Okay. So so we uh so we are
explaining the you know define a
function call the function then in
eacisp you can call any
function interact
interact
interactively when you do that that
function is called command. So this is
good to know that's a difference in
Emacisp it's a that's a difference of
command versus function
okay when a function can be called
interactively by meta x that function is
also known as a command okay now to make
a function a command you just add this
interactive clause
okay now by the way okay if you just go
to my emac blog Then my Emacs entire
1,00 pages Emacs
tutorial. Then you go to practical EMAC
list. Then you go scroll down. You can
see um search text, text editing, mark
and region. What are they? What are
they? Copy paste cut paste. How do you
do that? Get buffer string. Work with
lines thing at point. Uh get user input.
Then the first thing is interactive form
that this page is what I've been
explaining in past 10 minutes or so.
Okay. So uh okay copy that go to talk
show and paste it. Okay. So that we got
some kind of like um
record. Okay. So we were explain uh
explaining that. Okay. So wait, close
that. Now close that. Now go back here.
What is this page? Emacs block.
Close.
Uh, okay. Back here.
So for those of you already know Emac,
this Emily, you know, like this is
boring, but anyway, let me go on. So
there's a question. How do you pass the
argument? So,
so, so what do you do? Um,
uh, hold on a second. Okay. So, what how
do you pass the
argument when you
call a function uh interactively? Okay.
One easy way
Okay, let's play that. The the simplest
way is just simply pump
user and put the ars inside list inside
interactive. Okay. Uh like
this. So list. So let's say this uh so
we let's go back to this function.
add xy. So instead of fixed argument.
Okay. So add two numbers. So
interactive. So you want you you want to
give a list here. So if you say three
four let's demo.
Okay. So you see this interactive is a
clause by itself. Then here you just say
x y. Okay. So now we call that we
evaluate this command then call s add
okay do
it it insert seven why seven because
when you said when it's called
interactively just pass this value as
argument
so the function gets three and uh three
and four therefore result is seven and
four okay but this way is still fixed
because every time you call the function
you just get seven. That's not good.
Okay. So now you want to ask user. Okay.
So
um here is how to ask
user for
arguments. Okay. So instead of these
three and four hardcoded you ask user.
Okay. Uh
uh for example, you can call read
string. There it is. Okay.
Uh enter number. Okay. Then the rest we
don't care for now. Okay. Enter a
number. That's how you ask people user.
Okay. Now uh enter second number. Okay.
Enter first number. Okay. Prettify.
There it is. Okay. Now evaluate the co
code. Now meta x add do it. So we say
enter first number. Let's say nine.
Enter second number one. Uh one.
Enter. Uh wrong type of argument. Oh
wait. So you know we want number. We
don't want string. So let's change that.
read number is what I want. Okay,
there's data type differences. Okay.
Evaluate meta x add. Enter. Enter first
number. Let's say nine. Enter. First
number one. Enter. You got 10.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. Do I have a shortcut? No.
No. So, okay. So, that's how you
um prompt user and pass them as the
argument to the interactive when you
when this command is called
interactivity. Okay. I end up doing a
tutorial for interactivity and uh maybe
that's that's going to be the topic
today. Uh but okay so here is get user
input. So you can ask for file name, you
can ask for directory, you can ask for a
string, you can ask for regular
expression. Why you can ask for a
number? Why are they so many different
ways? Because for example when you ask
for a directory it can just navigate the
directory and do uh directory name
confusion. Same thing with file name and
you know so if you want to ask people to
type a regular expression it will check
the syntax you know so that's why you
have different you know uh ways to ask
user so that is explained on this page
let's go to talk show and paste it there
merge these two list show in browser
there it is okay so that is kind of the
basics
of the interactive form. Okay, that is
for you to
um call a function
interactively by meta
x. Okay, so in EMAC you can easily do
that. All you have to do is act
interactive. Then if you want to add
arguments just you know just say a
list then the items you know you can
prompt user or there are other ways okay
but let's not go into that okay here's
that's a
basic okay that's one topic
now let me
explain what's going on you know what
what is it I wanted to do about these
change brackets you Let me just
quickly explain the problem. Okay, then
I'm going to work it offline because
it's about the design issue. So, let me
explain that. Okay, so so here's the
code. So, so far so good. Uh, put it
back. Syntax show in
browser. Here is the code we did
explaining the interactive. Okay, now
the code change brackets. Okay, now
let's go there.
So here's a code of change brackets. You
see when you here's the issue when you
write a
function. So normally if you don't call
the function
interactively then you just have to
design your parameters which is also
important by itself and somewhat
complex. Uh for example, for example,
you you probably are familiar with Unix,
shell, spash, bash or uh git or you
know, for example, let's go to
git. You know, git is the most worst
lousy design [ __ ]
uh because you have all these commands
you know like following the tradition of
Unix
incomprehensible like you have no idea
what you know like very
complex and for example the the the most
uh
ex popular example classic example of
the argument design [ __ ] the is the
Unix PS command which list processes
Okay. So in so Okay. So let let me let
me explain this. Uh let's go to Linux.
So Linux uh do I have the PS example
there? I don't think so. Oh, there it
is.
PS. Okay. So px ps is very complex. You
have all these cryptic arguments and uh
and then you have two different version
of Unix. For
example, classically you do on Solaris
is PF
um
uh text mod. Okay, let's say shell
mod shell script mod. Okay, so PS uh I
have my um
psuwx. Okay, that's the classic argument
to type on on Solaris 30 years ago. You
don't even you don't even need a hyphen.
Okay? Why? Because a means or U means I
forgot what W means make it worthy like
verbose. But two W means make it more
worthy. Then X
means X means something I forgot. Okay.
But you can you can you can ask gu these
days. Okay, let I'm talking about the
Unix history here. So let's go to
GU. What
is this on Solaris? Okay,
paste
psWX. Okay, that's a classic most
common. Okay. On Solaris, the command
psauwx is a way to display detailed
information about processes using BSD
style syntax. There you go. Typically
executed via you know user UCBs Berkeley
version and so on. The A lip means all
users. Okay. Uh oh yeah all users,
right? And U means user oriented output
format. Okay. W means wide output
meaning verbose. Okay. Uh by default PPS
limit output to 80 characters. The [ __ ]
Unix they silent the truncate lines.
Okay. So W extended typically to 132
characters is they cut off the lines.
The [ __ ] Unix. We I talked about this
like a month ago. the the extreme damage
by the Unix [ __ ] and today they are
in
Linux. Um and X means includes processes
that do not have a controlling terminal.
Okay, background process.
Okay. So that's what you know that's a
uh Berkeley version but but typically on
HPUX or you know other uh Linux is
PSF kind of do the does the same as
that. Okay very complex [ __ ]
Okay, let's ask a work now.
Explain
ts-f. Okay, if I remember it correctly.
[ __ ] Unix on Solaris. No. And well,
okay. On Solaris and many Unix like
systems, the
PS-f commands is a system v style.
That's right. System V. Okay. Back then,
that's the two major differences. System
V and BSD.
Okay. Uh, wait, no. System V versus
what's the other? Anyway, E display
information about every process on the
system. F specifies full output. Okay.
So, anyway, that's you see that's the
two major incompatible [ __ ]
But the the the
the you know one of the glaring [ __ ] is
this
auwx without hyphen in front like
typically by the Unix shell standard you
have a hyphen in front of a command
right I mean argument but not so here so
so this is one example out of the
thousands out of the you know tens of
the Unix [ __ ] Extreme [ __ ] you know,
Unix and C [ __ ] They don't care,
you know. It just works. It just works.
So Unix and C
[ __ ] So in Linuxes, so what so
what does Linux do today? They they
basically combine both. Okay. So it's
more complex. Like the story of Unix in
the past 40 years is it's [ __ ] to begin
with. you just pile another [ __ ] on top
of
it. That's the story of uh Linux. Okay,
now let me get back to why am I talking
about this? Because this issue is about
functions argument design issue and the
syntax you know in the case of whether
you have dash or not that's part of the
syntax but let's not worry about syntax
there. There's a design issue about the
you know like like what kind of argument
do you need when you want to list
processes
right what we talked about here is
incompatib in incompatibility of two
different designs but let's just focus
suppose we just focus one you want to
think about what what kind of argument
do you want what if one argument is
dependent on your on another for example
that happens over on Unix for example ls
you know the the Unix [ __ ] you know
LS- you know if if you have L exist L
means uh L means long format okay like
some argument will turn off other
arguments so if you have this argument
on that overrides another uh ABC if but
if you have Z that overrides B but if
you B on then it overrides C and D and
[ __ ] that the [ __ ] Unix. Okay. And some
sometimes argument is just true or
false. So you don't have to say you know
so sometimes you have say argument true
argument false or the true force is
omitted simply whether you have that
argument name if that's present that
means true. So it's like entire [ __ ]
the [ __ ] you next. Okay. So I'm talking
about this because this is about the
design the semantic not syntax. Okay,
syntax is about other things like the
whether you need a dash or not. We are
now talking about the design of a
functions
parameter semantics.
Okay, design a function parameter. Okay.
So let's let me summarize uh let's
regroup and summarize so that we don't
um so we don't lose track what we are
doing. So hold on a
second.
Uh so we talked about Unix PS
um uh practice close. Okay. Uh put it
back. Okay. So, we talked about PS
AUWX. We talked about
PS-EF. Okay. And we talked about
LSA. So, let's make this uh
shell. Okay. Actually, let's make it
bash. Okay. Then we let's make comments.
The design
the design of
function
arguments. Okay, that's one thing.
Design of the semantics of function
arguments. That's one thing. The other
thing is
the design of the syntax of functions
argument. That's another thing. Okay,
separate. They are separate. Now
remember now you know I don't know if
you guys understand what I'm saying but
we this is like critical. This is not
just in Unix in any function in Python,
Pearl, Wuam language, F you have to
design this in
PowerShell. You have to you know like if
if you are going to write a function a
shell commands or Python it it it this
is a broad concept. Okay, the design of
the semantics of a functions argument.
Now the design of the the syntax of a
function argument is usually part of the
language. So if you are doing this in
shell you follow the bash you know like
it's like fixed okay kind of if you are
doing this in Python in PowerShell the
syntax is fixed you know you you
know okay so let me let me let me type
them out. So we we we have a clarity of
what we are talking about because it's
getting
complex. Uh one thing of
concern is the design of semantics of a
function arguments. This applies to any
language Python, Pearl, Ruby,
JavaScript, uh
Fuam language. Okay. Act
uh closure, Hascal,
Java and
PowerShell. Okay. Now the other
thing is
the design of syntax of a function
argument. This aspect is usually just
part of the programming language syntax.
you no need to worry about much. Okay?
Because whoever designed the language
has already designed the syntax for you,
right? Because we looked at for example
we have
seen uh where where is today talk show?
Yeah, you we have seen defining a
function in JavaScript, in Python, in
EMAC. you know how you the syntax of of
the argument is already fixed for you
already designed. Okay. So this is the
second thing.
Okay.
Now here what are these? These are
illustrations. Here are
illustrations of the complete Unix
[ __ ] [ __ ] Okay, in both the
function argument
semantics and syntax.
Okay, this example, for example, the PS
without the dash, that's a syntactical
violation. [ __ ] the Unix.
Now you know this repeated argument you
know WW that's another [ __ ] you know
like like almost in no language you use
you you repeat the argument just so so
that to make it more you know like that
like this WW which happens in Unix a lot
you know like sometimes it's dashv if
you give v and v again it means more
verbals you
know okay so These are the demonstration
of
the of both you know uh [ __ ] up okay the
Unix [ __ ]
up persist in in Linux 2 all over okay
all over it just the PS is more
pronounced now now when you design a
functions argument okay when you design
the semantics of function
argument this is a very
broad
topic and uh you need to you you need to
learn and think about. Okay. If you you
know if you code software you start to
write a lot of functions then you start
to
um need to pay attention to this. In
particular if you are designing a
function
that people
use often.
Okay. Okay. Anyway, so that's about the
things uh topics.
Okay. So, let's
uh so hold on a second. So, let
me Okay, put it back and put this back.
Uh let's put it this this
this. Okay, we have written
out the some of the things. Okay.
Show in
browser. Go down. Fantastic. So we were
talking about the design of semantics of
a functions argument. Okay. The design
of the syntax of a functions argument.
Okay. Then we have some illustration of
the Unix [ __ ] and uh okay. So let's
clarify. So let's
um then that's a different topic here.
color show in
browser. Okay.
[Music]
So, so
now we are getting close to what I'm
trying to do about you know my issues.
So now let me show you a example of
documentation that explains the
complexity of designing the semantics of
a functions argument. This is this is
particularly important if you are
creating commands in shell languages
because users needs to type it every
day. You know if you have conflicting
arguments you know this this means
depends on that that depends on this and
some you know boolean argument you know
you have 10 ways to write it you know
that's no good.
So there are documentation that let me
show you example that that gives you a
guide how to do this in PowerShell.
Okay, that would be
um where where are we? Semantics. Okay,
now so
here PowerShell
uh
PowerShell
function
argument. Okay, then I let's find it.
Uh there's I don't want I don't want
this any of these
pajit websites you know or you know
idiots you know how can you tell when
some website on programming language is
low quality they got a picture you know
they got this funny irrelevant pictures
whenever they have a photo or picture is
a [ __ ] website you know this practical
Five stack stack overflow. That's pretty
good. But today is died because of the
bots, the AI bots. So also we need to
um copy this.
Okay, let's make a screenshot of
that and
uh and then explain
that EF.
Okay, screenshot and let's copy the URL.
Okay, we are going full documentation
and write and writing a tutorial. So,
you are looking at my workflow. Copy
link. So back to our talk
page. Uh we Okay. So here's a link. Make
a link list and uh screenshot put here.
Screenshot put here. Uh these are
PowerShell. I mean these are bash. Okay.
So for example, look at it. This is
about the
uh the Unix PS command. Okay. Uh so
let's rename the file talk
show Unix PS. Okay. Copy it. Rename
it. Okay. Fantastic. And this is also
Unix
PS. Do that
there.
Okay. Okay. And uh this is Gork answer.
So put Gork answer back in here. Okay.
And now cut cut cut those
two. And uh let's put here there. Okay.
Then go up then show in browser. Go
down. So we got design of the semantics
of a functions argument. Then design of
the syntax of a functions argument. Then
the explanation the example of the Unix
[ __ ]
Okay. So, let's put a
header. Refresh. Example of Unix
violation. Okay. PS. So, now let's go
back to the PowerShell question.
PowerShell function argument. Uh, let me
show you where. Okay. That article gives
you a guide on how to design functions
argument. Okay, about functions. Let's
go there. Uh
functions Microsoft about advanced
parameters. Okay, let's
see parameters. So, so these are
about actual these are about how to code
it. But there is a page that gives you a
guide on how do you design functions
parameters. Okay, let's turn on
JavaScript.
Refresh and PowerShell you know there's
annoying they
don't. Okay, so you got switch
parameters which are boolean parameters
then you know PowerShell is pretty
complex. There it is. Okay. Switch
parameters design considerations
uh you know so you can read about the
guide. Okay. Now I
believe then you can add attributes to
parameters. Okay. So this page is very
long. Oh yeah. So
here then you got Yeah. So then you got
positional argument. Then you got named
argument. So how do they interplay?
That's another somewhat
complex issue.
Okay,
like you know do you guys know what I
mean? Like normally when you define a
function it's all positional parameters
you know when you add two numbers but
sometimes you want a named argument
which is like the shell dash something
so you know you
can you know so that way you don't have
a you know 10
arguments which are orders are important
you know you don't know which one is
which so if you have named argument then
you can you the order doesn't matter
because each argument parameter always
have a name you know like color
something red uh you know
something so this positional argument
then named argument now what if they
intermix
especially this happens in shell so you
gota you know especially in powershell
so powershell is very well designed so
anyway the so this page is a guide about
functions argument are very complex.
Okay. So, some arguments can
accept values from a pipe. Um, yeah,
this is a large
argument. No. Okay. A large document.
Okay. So, actually function advanced
methods. Function
advanced. Okay. What is this about
function advanced parameters? explains
how to add parameters to advanced
functions. You can add parameters to the
advanced functions that you write and
use parameters attributes and arguments
to limit the parameter values that
function user
submit. Now I don't remember if this is
specifically the document I'm looking
for. Uh I don't think it is. There is a
specific document that talks about the
design of arguments. Okay. Switch
parameters switch parameter design
issues.
Um runtime define parameter type very
complex. Okay.
So, how long have I been talking? Uh, an
hour now already. Okay. So, I think
that's
it. But we haven't we are very close to
what I'm going to uh need to do. Okay.
So, uh 10 more minutes we'll be
done. Uh about function argument
completion. About function argument
completion.
Um, go down, go down, go
down. About tab expansion. Go down, go
down, go down, go down.
Okay. Uh, about functions advanced.
Let's try
that. Okay. Let's close that. Wait, not.
Let's not close. Let's copy it first.
Okay. Let's
paste this. So this is Microsoft
PowerShell function
argument
design guide. Okay, that's what that
that is. Okay. And also this URL I don't
want the
um I don't want the you know the version
or
whatnot. Okay. Microsoft PowerShell
function argument design guide. Now now
what about this one?
Um about function advanced. Okay.
Yeah, somewhere. Okay, somewhere here
about advanced parameters. Wait, is it
that
one? About function advanced
parameters. Yeah. Okay, that's the one
we are reading. Okay, so anyway, that's
about the you know the complexities of
function argument design.
Now let's go back to now let's show this
in browser.
Now yeah.
So, so the problem I wanted to solve you
know this saw change bracket is that you
see this function first of all it needs
to take a beginning and end
position like you know when when you
want to change brackets you know you
need to know what region you want to
make this change to or do you want it to
do with the whole file whole buffer
right so you need a beginning and end
position If you are writing this
function now but if you call this
function
interactively usually you don't want
user to say what's the beginning end you
know because you have to you know it's
very tedious for example what is this
position this position is position
6,221 you know you don't want user to
find that out you know so by default
it'll just work on whatever the current
block text block you know for example I
can do this So if I call this
uh change bracket pairs then if I say
you know this greater than and change it
to let's say uh lenticular bracket do it
you see this you
see so you don't have to say which
beginning so if you call this
interactively you'll automatically
figure out but if you call this function
typically you
want the argument you know you want to
have a argument to say begin end right
so but right now I don't have it
because you know my my code depends on
whether region is active so that's why
it's a bit complex to explain so I want
to add a beginning end okay but if you
add beginning end of course then
interactively you need to figure that
out you know like by default just use
the current block
uh you know the current block separated
by blank
lines. So anyway, I want I need to add a
beginning and you can't just add it
because then you need to change the
interactive you know also interactively
you know you offer a list of
menus. So that that's that's the thing I
need to change. Okay. So it's all
related to about the designing of
function arguments.
uh and in in the EMAC case you have the
inter interreation between calling it as
a function or calling it as a command
interactively and once you dis so you
have to first of all think about this as
a function you call it as a function
what are the arguments then you need to
think about when you call this as a
command which argument should be
automatically ly
supplied. Okay. Yeah, that's a key.
That's a summary. That's the
issue. Um, yeah, that's it. That's it
for today.
So, thank you guys for watching. Go to
kasali.info. Okay. Go to
kasali.info. Go to all the way down
Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal me.
Okay.
That's it. I'm going to answer the
comments and see what you guys are
saying. And that's
it. Get alternative. Not really. There
is a good alternative. Someone wrote a
academic paper by now like five years
ago, more than five, eight, 10 years
ago. Someone wrote a I think PhD thesis
or something or master thesis
that
that clones get but without the
complexities of the git
idiocy. So if you try to search it, you
you'll probably find it. I I might have
it on my blog somewhere but it's buried.
I don't remember where. So someone wrote
a PhD a thesis.
Okay. They created a simpler like the as
still as powerful but much simpler
syntax. Okay. I don't remember what's
the name or what. Uh I like magic but I
also use regular git. I don't like
magic. Okay. Magic is sh Oh Nick. Hi
Nick, I have a random magic. You know, I
ran it on live stream for more than once
once I think. So if you just go to my
Emacs blog, search magic. Mi gi T. Magic
is
[ __ ] So first of all, there's not, you
know, tutorial about. So magic, if you
don't know, magic is a emac mod.
So to interface to git so you don't have
to you know for example typically what I
do is for example cd uh up git status
this is what I do today you know so you
can see there's a new picture oh talk
show new picture unix
PS okay so then I say get add this okay
then get status you he uh didn't add
that that okay those are in other
directories but um okay but okay I can
go to talk show but anyways that's what
I do I don't use magic
anymore but yeah so if you let's look at
magic
um that's a
tutorial and uh it's a funny Richard
Stman in 2014 to you know magic get
begin in 2008 or something 2008 and by
2010 it's so popular it's you by 2010
you know back then there's
a repository tool war you know git
versus murio versus another you know
versus two or three others there's a war
eventually git won because github you
know Linux tovert famous you know Linux
wrote git the guy who wrote Linux
So he's seeing you know he's this
powerful you know great programmer and
then he somehow the GitHub you
know website turned off and I think it's
mostly due to GitHub that made Git won
the
[Music]
um the version control system get Wong
okay back then it's there was a war um
so so everyone just adopted git. So by
2010 everyone already like adopted git.
But
then in 2014 Richard Sman what's magic
you know because this is funny because
Richard Sman is being out of date you
know he's like living in a cave more
cave than me you know he his his cave is
more deeper than me. He don't know
what's going on in the world. He had no
idea like he he asked people what what
is
magic. Okay. You see by then 2014 you
see you got 3,000
packages Emac packages on on on
um mail you
know. And there comes Richard Roman. Oh
uh what what is maggot
maget? Okay that's funny.
And
then here is my article magic problems.
Okay, you know, magic problems. Uh, I'm
not going to go into, but anyway, the
guy is nice. Okay, I know the guy since
like 20 years ago. Magic. Magic is
created by this guy. What's his name?
You know, he lives in Japan.
Um, wait, what? What? Yeah. Yeah, this
this uh Jonah Spanoli, okay, he's he's
very nice, very nice
person, but but I had I had a few
argument with him about the good
technical issue about
magic, you know, and he refused to
change. Then I say [ __ ] good. [ __ ] [ __ ]
magic, you know. So I stopped using
magic.
alternative is this version control
command building in Emacs VC D which I
use some some you know for example I can
do diff let me show you uh press this
key no change between working and
revision okay close that press this
key so it says you know change you know
this is today's talk show close it show
in browser you see talk show before I
again. Um then you see show the
difference. So I'm calling the
command VC diff. Okay.
So, so you it it'll call um I don't
remember what it calls maybe it calls
get diff behind the scenes but anyway it
so it shows the you know the difference
like in the past hour the things I just
added to this page talk
show okay so so that is that article
okay version control
um that's built in VC VC um VC something
the command. Okay, that's it for today.
So, I'm shutting down in one minute. So,
now I go to talk show and just paste all
the links that we talks about talked
about. Okay. So, this version control
command uh Emacs blog uh today's talk
show. This is Richard Storman making
making a scene of his ignorance out of
date. And here's uh here's a basic
tutorial for magic. Okay, close it. Uh
search close it. Thank you guys for
watching. Bye. And this PowerShell we
talked about a guide on designing
uh function parameters uh practical git
in one hour. Copy that. This is my
tutorial if you don't know git
recommended. Okay. Practical git in one
hour. Linux by command line. Uh yeah. So
Linux processes that's my Unix tutorial
which is good for beginner.
Okay. Uh so you know Linux process is
get undo close. Okay. uh rejects. We
already have that link, I
believe. Search
user.
Uh there it is. User
input. Bye,
guys. Oh, we don't have that link. So
cycle cycle low line space change
bracket we have that's what the topic
softly keys fantastic
by any comments on canonical plans to
replace the existing co with the Rust
implementation. Oh, I didn't know that.
That's interesting. I'm going to like
look into that
drama. They're going to, you know,
Richard Strowman going to be
replaced. Totally agree with Git. Yeah,
there was Murio. It was much more
straightforward. Yes. Yes. I like Magic,
but uh Nick, hi Nick. Uh but I also use
regular Git. Yes. Uh yes. Okay. So let's
see next. This annoying thing always
pops
up. Find file at point. Do I use that?
Well, yes, but I have my own version. So
for example, in HTML I want to find file
at point. I just press enter because
this is s HTML mod. But if you you know
if but if you given a you know let's say
a new buffer and let's say uh text mod.
So how do I open that? I call this
command because I open file at
kusa. So let's look at source code. So
why do you have your own? Well because
when you call find file at point it's
very annoying. Find file at point. Okay.
Fap. It asks you, are you
sure? Wait, why is it not running? And
okay, it asks you, are you sure? Is is
this the one? Please confirm. [ __ ]
annoying. Okay, if I call my version,
just do it. Just open the [ __ ] thing. If
you cannot find, then pop out the arrow.
You know the the Emacs find fire 8
point. Are you sure this is the
one? That's why I have
open file at kusa and not you know not
at point what the [ __ ] point and find
file you know those are harmful Asian
emacs jarens you
know to open a file in EMAC is called
find file you have to find and the
cursor position in emacs is called point
so that's why you have find file and
coin. So that decreases the popularity
of Emacs, you know. So, you know, when
you know takes time to learn all these