foreign
we are going to continue from last video
writing a
HTML validator in emac bisp okay so good
morning everyone so if you have
questions comments about emac be posted
okay so we're gonna focus on emac bisp
and we're gonna complete the task you
don't have to watch yesterday or the day
before video fantastic uh because I'm
gonna cover it um
okay so let me show you my keyboard This
is Ultimate this is the glove 80
keyboard and over there is Ultimate
hacking keyboard just search for xali
keyboard blog you'll find like reviews
including video reviews okay so now
let's go start to code let's show
today's page
um
okay so let's start so we did we we
started to do it yesterday that's 90
minutes very interesting I mean I I
explain as I go but today we're gonna
continue that task okay so first of all
so I'm using I'm using soft light keys
let me show you okay I'm using emacs of
course and I'm using all my custom mods
you can see CSS HTML emac Beast goal and
uh HDM you know all my emacs code and
the key binding I'm using is kind of
like keys so there show in browser so
you can download download it and use it
it's a key binding system for emacs so
that you don't have to press Ctrl key or
uh
meta key match
almost none okay so stuff like this and
I'm using a vorac keyboard layout so you
can see vorac okay and on the pink
window is all my command core and uh
uh and keystroke on the left okay that's
on the pink window so what I'm whatever
I'm doing for example select that delete
that you can see the command I just
called size HTML select element okay
undo
okay so let's begin immortality hello
hello
[Music]
hello you guys so emac Beast okay so and
I'd like to thank uh uh I'd like to
thank this person uh actually I don't
know this person Cliff okay he's seen he
you know he's got 100
000 followers
every time he treats Retreats my treat I
get tens of um
uh notifications and uh and some new
followers so thanks to Cliff
so he retreated my you know emacs live
stream and now it's 2 500 views
usually it's just 100.
okay so and I'm I'm on Twitter so follow
me on Twitter and also I'm on Discord
just search for Sardi Discord okay so
let's begin coding the real stuff the
coding okay so first so we need to go
back to yesterday's get the code so here
is the yesterday's pageant talk show uh
I mean two days ago
so here's the code let's grab it so
so get that code let's just work on
these yeah let's just actually let's
create a new one so copy it close close
Okay go to today's talk show and uh new
buffer paste it in the copy the file
path
uh actually save it okay save it let's
say XXX
dot e l for now okay so just run the
name copy it close it paste the link
here link if I
so we have a record of the code so later
on you can grab the code
so we continue to write a HTML validator
now let's create a new buffer and let's
insert some HTML
you know HTML template so we can
test on validating that
HTML so
what is that so there it is a template
okay
so this is the template we're gonna work
with
yeah so uh we need a slash here so okay
so this is a sample file so we write a
command we can meta X call the command
and it will validate you tell tell us
if it's valid you know or not you know
uh Miss mismatched tag or missing tag
and so on so yesterday so you can you
know we I always write documentation so
here's the documentation so if you are
late you can watch you know you can read
uh there to see what we are doing so so
the command yesterday we did is this uh
this one okay
validate buffer okay let's add today's
date a new version
[Music]
um
okay so let's get let's begin
okay video check audio check yeah good
to go
uh yeah
so okay so
let me briefly go over what we did
yesterday so so here is the code let's
hold on a second let's clean up okay so
let's remove the parts that
that we don't want okay so
uh
remove that
and
and this one we can actually also remove
we are using it there anyway so yeah
so yesterday's code
let's
uh can you see yeah you can see it okay
so
it's a trading slash needed for self
closing time okay yeah you were here
just yesterday are you because we
covered that yesterday so in short in
XML
if you have a self-closing tag that is a
tag without a closing tag so this that's
called self closing
you know you can call it self closing
tag the technical name is void element
okay uh why don't we repeat that okay so
you go to
um
you know just search for JavaScript in
depth and click on HTML then you have
you go here self closing tag so these
tags they don't have a closing tag
sometimes they do have a closing tag
it's optional so
technically they are called void
elements
you know it's it's kind of uh confusing
you know so in XML you always need the
slash okay whenever you have attacked
then
that tag ends with a slash
uh Red Bracket that means it's
self-close okay but in HTML technically
that slash is not allowed but however
because you know over the past 20 years
because the mix of X you know XML HTML
HTML5 xhtml it's one [ __ ] up [ __ ] so
so today in HTML you can also have that
slash but in XML that slash is required
okay so that's that's that's the bottom
line
we talked about that yesterday it's it's
XML it's much better because it's uh
because you can purely via syntax you
can judge which tag is sell is close is
you know is self-closing but in HTML you
cannot
so anyway so we so that so here's the
sample HTML file we're gonna have
validate and then
um then we start to code yeah so let me
go over yesterday's code Okay so
so first of all we have this function
PSI is self closing it takes a string so
so basically like that you know it takes
a stream of attack
and if the last second to last character
is a slash then it's a selfie closing
tag so this function just returns true
or false you know we do back
checking the substring
okay so instead of closing so that is
the um
that is that function now let's go to
the main body let's let me go over to
show you what we are doing so we so this
side HTML validate HTML buffer it will
just validate the current buffer so
first first thing it does is go to the
beginning of the buffer go to chart
uh get then get the current cursor
position find the next angle bracket
position grab the text in between
and that's one tag and push it two
stacks so go to the beginning of your
character and we do a while loop here
then okay let's magnify so while loop
then we search forward for
left or right bracket so we go to the
beginning search for word for left or
right bracket
there then if that character is the left
bracket then we set
The crucial position
to xp1
you know which is right here the
beginning of the tag basically
if the first if the angle bracket is not
a left bracket then it's an arrow
because we have a situation like that
you know then that's the error right
away so you just stop the program and
report it so let's uh we can run the
program and try it okay so run it
and copy the file uh command name meta X
sound validate XML buffer do it you can
see at the bottom it says error found at
position three
so it caught there
and that is uh
caught by this line okay so once we
found the left angle bracket we search
for another
angle bracket and if that is a right
angle bracket that means we found a tag
we found a tag so then we
buffer substring no properties we grab
the text between the two positions XP X
P1 xp2 then we check if it's
self-closing
if it's
if it is do nothing otherwise we push it
to a stack stack in here a stack is uh
in in lisp
stack is just a list okay
a list of items you can always add items
to the front or remove items from the
front Okay that's uh that's a
implementation of stacking lisp that's
just a list okay the the most natural
implementation of a stack data structure
in computer science in lisp languages
okay except closure closure has
something else because closure is based
on Java data structures underneath
so anyway so we pushed to the stack okay
when it's when the when the tag is not
set of closing then we push to the stack
uh then the code prints the stack and
that's it
you see that that's that's it that's
that's it of yesterday's progress
uh and we if we call it here let's
remove that you know so let's call it
call it and you go to the messages
before you can see here is the stack it
printed so we
open a new buffer then we paste it then
we make it each of those items into a
line by itself
so you can see that's a stack we have
now the next thing we want to do is you
know we check each one
so you know the bottom one is the is the
bottom of the stack so you go by
you know for each
item in the stack you check the next one
for example right now suppose we are on
head opening head then we check next one
that's also opening tag title so
whenever you see your opening tag skip
it go to the next item then whenever you
see a closing tag check to see if that
close intact matches the previous
tag in the stack if it does then just
delete them you know like remove them
because it's it matched it means well
formed okay so then you repeat so at the
end if the file is valid then your stack
will be
of nothing of no items okay so if
otherwise then you got an error mismatch
tag so that is the algorithm that's what
we did yesterday so today
so yes so so far
so close that okay so yet so far our
code
didn't do much you know our code the
only thing it checks for error is
something like that you know the
mistyped
angle brackets but it doesn't actually
check any
stack yet the you know the matching tag
for example we copy the HTML paste it
again here so it's repeated it should be
invalid so but the code doesn't do
anything yet because it doesn't check
the stat yet so today we are going to
continue the code so it actually checked
the stack
okay so the okay so now undo to remove
the duplicate uh well let's leave it
let's leave the duplicate HTML there so
today we are going to check the stack
okay
uh
so check the stack so
so we pushed a lot of things to the
stack yesterday you know but
but actually you know one of the most
important thing to validate the text is
that you want to know it's opening or
not
okay so you want to know
opening tag
or is it a closing tag closing tag
always start with a slash Okay so
you want to know it's often integral
closing tag the other one most critical
thing is you want to know the tag name
because only the same tag name can match
okay otherwise they don't they don't
match you have to keep going so the two
most important thing is the tag name and
it's opening or closing so let's write a
function to do that Okay so
then we push the information to the
stack so the stack instead of just a tag
name
we push
several informations we push
the information we we like to have is
the beginning position of the tag the
end position of the tag and whether the
and the tag name and whether it's
opening or closing so we find all this
information and push it to stack as one
item okay and so let's do that today
so uh
so we want so we have a self-closing tag
so we we want a function
is
opening tag Okay so
we can write it
or
I already defined it before I already
defined it in my HTML mod so let's let's
find let's use the existing code so we
don't have to waste so so much time so
so let's go to
this keystroke gets me to psi HTML mod
enter to open it here's the source code
then list matching lines okay let's show
the pink window
then these matching lines we want to
match for open something open tag
okay so here so here is a function
HTML opening tag p
any function ending in p
means it's a protocol predicate means
it's a function whether it returns true
or false
okay that's a emac
this convention ending in p means it
returns true or false okay so this so so
we have a function here
uh wait
yeah so we have a function here Excel
HTML open intact P true or false return
true if tag is opening tag or self
closing okay
okay else return Neo okay
now
now this function takes a position in a
in a buffer okay so attack begin the
parameter the argument must be on the
left of angle bracket okay like that
okay so we already have a function let's
just let why don't we grab it here so
copy it close it close it close it okay
so we have already have function let's
paste it there
fantastic so so all we have to do to
call this function is let's just start
to do it okay
so let's go back to our code here
so let's add a variable
is uh X is open okay by my my variable
naming convention always start with the
X so that they are highlighted all the
variables okay so X is open
uh
so let's
let's before we set tag let's see where
do we add this
so yeah so while we find so here is a
tag uh
set
is open
uh so
so before we sew this function opening
tag true I mean whether it's opening tag
it takes a cruiser position
okay not the tag name but we can also
it takes exclusive you know there are
many ways to go about you can make it to
take a stream which is the most simpler
conceptually or you can make it take a
cruiser position
which is more efficient because that way
you don't have to actually grab the
thing as a string
so this function right now takes a
cruiser position okay let's just do that
so now we need to first of all we need
to move closer to
uh yeah the cruiser position is xp1
because we remember we search forward
for the bracket and if it's open then
if it's a left bracket then we set it
the position to XP one so
so it's open so we can just call
here is how we do so call this function
give the argument XP one okay that will
return whether the tag is open or not so
that's one information
and uh and uh so that tells us the tag
is open or not then the other thing we
need is a tag name remember we need the
tag name so
to get the tag name
we also have a function already written
so let's go back let's open the HTML
file then here is the function
HTML get tag name okay
we're gonna use this function okay so
why don't we copy it
copy it close
and we also defined here okay
so these two functions let's move it to
the top
let's move it to the top
these are
self uh
Standalone functions you know these yeah
these two functions are Standalone
functions so this one gets a tag name
copy it now let's now we're gonna use it
okay so first of all let's Define a
variable
tag name okay so let's move here
okay so tag name now let's set
tag name to be
call this function then
then what is uh then then you need to
pass the position remember yeah so
it the position needs to be to the left
of the
left angle bracket so that would be also
X1
xp1
okay now predify the code so
so now we get the tag name we we get the
tag we get the tag name we we get the is
it open
okay and uh
yeah so that's what we want fantastic
Okay so
so first of all
okay so this this we need to
so if it's self-closing tag then we
don't push to the stack otherwise we do
push to the stack so
so first of all what we're gonna push to
the stack is going to be a vector okay
so a vector
in emac this Vector is a data structure
in lisp which is similar to Python's
Tuple okay or two C's array essentially
it's a list of items
of fixed length you can never add to it
you cannot remove item from it fixed
length
uh list essentially a fixed length array
okay typically it's called array so
that's what Vector is in emac lisp so so
here we have a vector and the
so what we want the stack item to be so
we need to be X is open
oh we got the
did we get the hearts and I saw the
heart how does that work
so
so Vector so Vector is open and the tag
name
so we want to vector
first item is is open then type name and
beginning position and position okay so
beginning position XP xp1 where the
let's Square the tag begin then xp2
that's where the tag ends then
then tag name then is it open
wait how does that hard work
fantastic
okay a message am I doing good comments
okay video check audio check
great fantastic heart
um okay so here is the thing we want to
push okay so
beginning includes the position and
close the position tag name and is open
okay
and we push it to
um
we push it to the stack right so
so
we check if the attack is self closing
if it is do nothing otherwise push
this to stack okay fantastic
okay that's our code that's that's
pretty good that's
um that is our code pretty good so
yeah so
so now our stack will be reach is gonna
be rich now so let's see
so is self closing okay let's
cut this move to the top
okay
so describe list matching lines
different so right now we have this
function defined the first three is help
functions this is the main thing so go
through there so there it is it's only
about 40 lines okay so now we eval the
buffer now emacs knows about the whole
list of functions now we
meta X
sound validate XML prefer to it
fantastic now we
open the messages buffer copy it
open a new buffer then we
make them into a line by itself make
each item
on the line by itself so here's our
stack
oh fantastic so wait
tag name is open fantastic this is now
simpler so we got the
you see so here's the the first tag is
HTML beginning position and position
then tag name then whether it's open
intact true open okay so this is open
this is open open close close tag new
scroll stack fantastic now we got the
push to the stack
thank you
okay so what um
so now fantastic now now it's it's great
I'm doing good thank you CEO uh okay so
so what's the next thing to do so those
comments we don't care okay what is the
next thing
let's move it
that's some comment from yesterday
yeah so we now
now we need some code to check the stack
okay
uh so remember
here is a while loop
this while loop
you know is going through
you know by searching the
brackets and each time
push your attack to the stack
now
we can you know so after the whole thing
is done we have a bunch of stacks
we can check it
you know all
or we can check it as we go you know
before we even you know like
we can check it after the whole Loop or
we can check it check the stack
while inside the loop
so
so uh which one should we do so
so here is the thing we need to think
about
we can check the stack
during the loop or we can should we
check the stack after the whole
uh
if we check the stack after hole
it's less efficient because suppose you
have a huge document let's say 10 000
lines
now you know the error occurs on the
10th Line
so if you check the stack while doing
the loop you'll find it right away and
the program can stop you know then this
error
or
if you wait until the whole Loop is done
it has to read all the you know ten
thousand
tax
Okay so
okay so so
it's it's it's better it's probably
better to check during the loop but the
other concern is which one is easier to
write uh to implement
because if you have the entire stack
then the way you validate it is by
you know you go to the last
item of the stack
then you
then you check if it's matching the
beginning
if it does you
you have to remove both so you have to
actually operate from both sides
you know our stack is at least
data structure so with a list data
structure
it's efficient only if you add or remove
the first item you know the top of the
stack if you want to remove or change
the bottom of the stack it's very
inefficient
so that means if we want to wait until
the whole Loop is done then process the
stack
that means the least data structure is
not suitable
because it's going to be very Innovation
efficient so
um
so yeah so right now we know it's
probably better to check the stack
during the loop within the while loop
okay
so
automatic automatically launched the
heart is that is also
you are doing good important to time
yourself while coding time sorry I'm
bugging you but would you be able to
provide results to detecting AMD
identifying a key log
on Windows 10 operating system
no I don't know I don't know anything
about that so you want to detect is is
if there's a key log on on Windows no I
don't know how to detect that or you can
do all I can recommend is you download
the virus checker
otherwise I don't know dude that's
another topic we can talk about another
day
so so we want to check the stack during
the loop okay that's more efficient
but how do you do it okay so
so you
yeah so so here's the stack suppose we
are here
and we just suppose we are here and then
we just one more Loop we read one more
stack so we are here
then you want to check the
Stacks so
so if the current stack is closed okay
so if it's open ignore it
so we move on to the next Loop if the
current tag is a closing tag that's when
you need to do something okay
if it's close in tag then you check the
last item on the stack
if if that's the opening tag and the
name also matches if so you remove it
okay that's the algorithm
fantastic
thinking does it
so let's write it out if the current tag
is closing then
check the last item on the stack
if it's opening
and tag name match then
remove that on stack fantastic
that's the way to go
that's the that's what we're gonna do
okay so
so now let's refactor the code a little
bit
so here if it's self-closing tag
okay let's let's move this code
to here okay so to make it more
efficient
so if it's self close intact do nothing
otherwise
we're gonna do something okay otherwise
otherwise okay let's move the code here
okay that does that make it simpler so
get a tag name
if it's self-closing tag
do nothing
otherwise
actually we don't even need the tag
yeah so we don't even need the tags you
see the only reason we need the tag is
because this function is self-closing
this function we wrote here
that takes a string the tag stream
but we but I already have a function
that checks if something is self-closing
without
needing the text string
so
so you see if itself closing do nothing
right
otherwise get the tag name check if it's
open then push to stack right
so
but however the attack the entire tag
you know opening or closing the tag
itself is
never needed you know it's never needed
anywhere except by this function
therefore we don't need it
the only we just need to know if it's
self-crossing or not we don't need to
actually grab the tag okay so now
let's replace let's let's get let's
write a cell you know
self-closing predicate function
that do not require a string the text
string okay so let's go to yeah so let's
go to my HTML mod again
to find the function because I HTML mod
so we want to find self closing okay
these matching lines self
closing
uh
so here is a function
jump to it
search for it there it is okay so here
is a function
html text cell close p
and it checks by whether the tag name is
is in this list
let me show you okay so here so you see
here is a bunch of self-closing tags
okay so now we just grab that
grab this function
okay close close go back here we paste
the code here and we don't need this
code anymore okay
and uh so now this is a new function
now let's go down here self closing
we don't need so we need a new way to
check
and this function takes a
tag name okay so actually it takes a tag
name
oh so
so it takes a tag name
so now remove this line
now attack name
so you need to set the tag name before
you see it's called here so you move
this line to here okay purify the code
and this tag we don't need anymore
that's right so
remove it okay so we got the tag name
now check if it's self-closing
if it's true do nothing otherwise
do this okay so
if it's not self closing then check if
it's opening tag
okay and now
check if
if it's open
do nothing new okay otherwise we
let's put a comment here otherwise we
we need to check the stack okay let's
predefine the code
so get the tag name
if it's self-closing if it is do nothing
otherwise
is it opening tag
if it's true
okay so set is open so if it's opening
tag then do nothing otherwise
check the stack okay so otherwise now we
check the stack
now
so so let's put a comment here now we
check the stack
so
so if it's a closing tag
now if
X tag now we got we need to get the
element of our stack did we document no
we didn't document it so
let's document the stack
okay it's document our stack here
stack is an empty list to begin with and
the least
each element is a vector
and of this form
position Cruiser position cursor end
position
tag name
is open okay that's a vector
stack is a list okay
each element
is a vector like that okay so that's a
document of the stack okay now let's go
back to
here
so
uh position position
name is open
Okay so
if
so we a vector we we how do we get the
so we need to get the
vector
Vector is zero indexed
uh
and uh
so we want to check the name and is open
uh
equal okay
so
if something okay so if
string equal
tag name
equals to
the item on the stack
so here you need to
get the last item on the stack
so you can so you can do that by car
okay so car extag X tag is actually a
list so car X stack gets the first
element
so
so if that elements
string equal attack name so that element
is a vector right it's it's a vector
like that
so that element so now we need to
extract the tag name from that Vector so
that function is a ref
so a array is that an index is 0 1 2 2
is the tag name
okay
so
if that is equal
and
we need another thing we need to check
Okay so so now go back so if that end
if the last
item on the stack is a opening tag
that means
opening tag that means
t
Okay so
and
let's see
uh
okay so let's
so the last item is
zero one two three so third item
so if the third item of the
of the last element on the stack
is t means it's open
okay so the name match and the last item
on the stack is open then
then we okay clean clean up the code
then we
pop remove the item on the stack okay
so if that is true then
pop
pop the stack
otherwise push to the stack you see now
it's all clear
otherwise
push to the stack fantastic
okay does that make sense
so here's the code to check stack we
already did it clean the code
uh
no too much nesting okay but still
okay
does that make sense actually I think
you'll walk one shot coding
I'm out of coffee
okay so let's double check okay
so
get the tag name
get tag name
uh
so let's look at our file
so we
we get the tag name
then
check if it's self-closing
if it is
do nothing
otherwise
check
if it's opening tag
if it is
oh if it is we need to push to stack
right
so if it is we need just we need to push
to stack
otherwise
we otherwise we check if it's a closing
tag
I mean otherwise it's a closing tag we
check if it matches the
the tag on the stack
the attack name is the same or not
and
the last item on the stack is open
if so remove the last item on the stack
otherwise push okay I think that's it
are you gonna show live memory run
for the runtime no we don't care about
that that this little very little memory
okay even if you have 10 000 stacks
that just means at least of 10 000 items
and each item is gonna is a vector like
that a vector of four things so even if
if you have ten thousand of them it's
like trivial micros one few micro
seconds you know because today's
computer are very fast unless you are
talking about one gigabyte file or
something
it but that's not practical but because
it uh you know most HTML files you know
team Mega by Max okay yeah you know
you are not going to deal with one
gigabyte HTML file so you know it's
uh shouldn't be your concern so we focus
on
okay so practicality okay so this code
works I think I'm pretty sure let's run
it okay it's already run
uh you see run current file so emacs
knows the new code now let's let's let's
test it on this sample file
quit
do it
okay so what happened oh
let's look at the stack oh so now the
stack is very short
actually that's correct you see because
remember we have a duplicated
HTML tag you see so that is why
that HTML tag remain on the stack
because it's never matched
but what is the what is this empty
string that that means attack without
the name
what
uh
yeah so that so we
it's working fantastic now we just have
some bug
so
so what what is the uh
so this mysterious mysterious thing oh
okay so it's number you see position
three
there I think that's that one
yeah I think so so
position three to eighteen so if you can
now you can call describe chart
and emacs will tell you what position
your Cruiser is on you see 18 so
position 18 is right here so
so that means this line
you know this element
is this thing
now that thing should be considered
that's a dark type
technically it's not a tag at all it's
just one decoration
technically you know according to spec
that's not a tag you know
but for for our purposes we can consider
that to be yourself closing
but why is ourselves closing time
doesn't match that let's see
uh get tag name is opening tag self
cross intact P so let's look at the
variable Okay so
HTML self close tags okay
so this should be there
self close tags DOT type
you know because we consider that to be
self closing
now
now maybe the tag name
or tag name I'll get tag name
function is incorrect so let's look at
it describe function jump to
um
yeah okay
and actually
okay so why is it not getting oh there
it is that's why because it doesn't
consider the
exclamation sign
to be part of it
that's why it becomes zero so let's
check
uh tag name
so how does this code work so it takes
an attack beginning position
okay then
looking at then
go to chart tag begin forward chart
looking at
if looking at
then for chart so if it's
the tag name start with that skip it
otherwise
set point
so skip chart forward yeah so you see
that's a problem so
the code stuck over here so that's why
you get an empty tag name
but here you should include
you know this is one of the this is one
of the you should include the
explanation here you see this is one of
the problem of The Irregular syntax that
creates you know suppose if you have a
clean XML not even XML but suppose you
have a XML
where
the syntax of the
language is
there's nothing special because right
now this dark type is considered special
so you can say you know that's even not
a tag you know it's declaration it's not
attack but you shouldn't but if
everything is just attacked then it's
regular is much easier to deal with so
anyway so to solve that problem all we
have to do is add a
exclamation here I'm pretty sure so we
can try it again evaluate the buffer
go here go ahead do it you see now go to
the messages buffer so you see
now we got just one item because that is
the
duplicated HTML tag
here see
fantastic okay now let's do something up
let's remove this
um
remove these
remove this remove this because all
those are defined in my HTML size HTML
mod so let's just go to
size HTML mod then
[Music]
um
then you know we don't have to
duplicate them
so wait
evaluate the buffer close it so what is
it that we need
attack name yeah so
get tag name so describe function jump
to the source code
we need to add a band here
band okay
evaluate the code
at today's date modification date
okay
evaluate the code go back here
evaluate the buffer go back here expand
call the function do it fantastic
now uh
now that's it we done with the program
one more thing to do okay to make it we
pull the error okay so here we don't
even need to print the stack
so all we have to do is
if
length
of Stack
zero zero let's hold on a second let's
try equal yeah
so if link of Stack is zero then
done
perfect
[Laughter]
you have perfect code
okay it's
otherwise
otherwise print stack
well otherwise let's see uh well yeah
otherwise
otherwise print stack but before you
print the stack you also want to uh go
to the last position
so car
a ref
so get
get the last item on the stack and
and
go to char
uh last item of the stack in the the
zeroth index that is the beginning
position of the
tag
and then you just say go to it
go to
go to char okay go to char there
one
okay
so if the stack has nothing then done
you have perfect code
your code is perfect
otherwise
go to the last item on the stack
get the position put a cruiser on the
beginning of the tag of the arrow
and also print stack okay eval the
buffer go back here now let's say let's
now let's put a cruiser here okay let's
let's say in the code command do it
fantastic
[Music]
you see it puts the cursor right on the
face
you know the the first error that occurs
fantastic okay now again let's do some
pretty uh thing let's say
error okay uh messages
error
you [ __ ]
[Laughter]
it says then we have to say
uh yeah those Arrow yeah okay so
also
uh yeah so Arrow
here's the stack okay
then
then also
make sure the program if the program if
it's valid should return true Okay so
so let's do that
t for true
actually message I think message returns
true
yeah it returns a string yeah okay
so when it's valid this function should
return true in case you want to call
this function in this code otherwise it
returns new okay
that's it that's it for today you know
lots of talking and but
one hour we did it in one hour perfect
so total of two hours we did it
let's go to message buffer yeah fact you
fact here is a stack okay
correct now let's remove this at HT this
remove this duplicate okay now let's try
again call it do it
done you will call this perfect
thank you guys for watching if you like
my stuff pay me okay uh you can buy my
emacs tutorial okay lots of
you know go to
you know just search for Sally emacs
tutorial the most popular
emacs tutorial on the website so you can
PayPal me there's a link there PayPal or
patreon me so thank you guys for
watching any questions
yeah so we did it fantastic so for those
of you watching you know later you can
get the code offline
so let's uh hold on let's let's clean up
the code okay so and put the code back
to the my page
so pass region so we don't need that
anymore so here is the code glorious
code
59 60 lines 60 lines plus we used three
building you know three
functions I have written before so a
total of 120 lines something like that
100 100 lines
validation of XML and HTML code
fantastic now let's make some arrows so
let's
you see let's hear
let's make some Arrow here okay let's
say
some
some okay
bold okay now let's call the command do
it your code is perfect okay but now
let's put this in bracket
through here okay call the command do it
Arrow so now let's look at let's go to
the error you [ __ ]
here's a stack
and uh
it should put the cruiser right right
there so let's do it again do it
No it didn't
because
it didn't put the cruiser at the right
position because the way we validate so
you can we can look at the stack
uh the way we've added date we um
because
yeah so
okay here is what here's what happens
what happens here is you have two
hmm
oh that's an interesting error so you
can't
you can't
the question is can you discover this
error while you are doing the loop
uh can you so the question is well
so we found the opening tag then we
found the closing tag well actually you
should be able to
but what is the mathematical
property to know this is error how do
you know this is error
I mean we know it's Error because our
stack they don't cancel out right so we
know it's Error at the end
but technically you don't need to go to
the end
um do you
uh no because as soon as you have an
opening tag
you need to expect it to close
okay so we have an opening tag H1 then
we have an opening tag B
then we close the H1 at that point
we know it's Error
already
but how do you find how do you know in
code how do you What is the
mathematical Essence how do you express
you know we humans we know it's Error
but how do you express
this
this situation
that makes it error from a mathematical
point of view because once you can do
that then you can turn it into code
so opening tag opening tag
so close so whenever you close the tag
so when whenever you encounter a closing
tag
that closing tag must must have
a matching opening tag before right
right before the the previous the tag on
the stack okay that's the thing
so whenever you see a closing tag which
is here
and uh
that that and the
that tag must have
a opening tag on the stack otherwise
it's Error right away
so we just have to modify the code here
somewhere but that's it that's that's
done today so
fizzler fisler freeze says I got an
expose after your review it hasn't
arrived yet but I'm excited thank you
I'm happy I'm happy I finished the code
today it's it's basically good so expose
I highly recommend it you know they I
that's one of the keyboard I love very
much I so so much enjoy it every time I
use it like every because I have so many
keyboards so I cannot use all of them
for as my main so I have to you know
either use this one or that one but all
these you know ultimate hacking keyboard
glove 80 Kinesis Advantage 2 and expose
that any one of them I can use full-time
no problem
but the Xbox is flat so that's a bit an
issue if I use it long term
okay thank you guys thank you all pay me
okay remember donate that's because
that's the most important you know
if you like my work you know donate
something
okay bye guys
uh by closing down in one minute let's
just put a code let's put a code into my
page
uh I think a backup close it
close it
close it showing browser okay that's it
bye thank you