hello guys welcome to another episode of
c talk show today we are going to do a
advant of code day 10
2023 okay uh let me show you my keyboard
so this is glove 80 this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard and over
here is the SP board data hand SV a l b
o a r d okay I have a review on my
website and on YouTube search it you'll
find it and let's just begin coding
wolam
language okay stop that voice check
videos check uh am I alive yes I'm alive
so coding wam language I'm using sofly
keys in emac so this is emac this is
class today's talk show and the Ping
window shows the Ping window shows all
my command code names in emx and the
keystroke I'm using V keyboard so let is
let us begin so uh so the Advent of
code video resolution whatever Advent of
code can you see it yes okay event of
code we did last time uh year 20203 we
did all the way to day night so today is
day 10 and I heard it's um it's going to
be a bit involved I heard from Steve so
day 10 uh yeah Advent of cod day
10 so let's let's begin to read the
problem okay am I ready yes ready and
coffee at hand this is uh coffee and
milk and honey actually maple
syrup if you have comments questions
post it okay so day 10 so I'm going to
try to be as fast as I can okay I mean
well I'm not going to push it but I'm
going to try to uh not talk random
stuff okay uh let's see make sure I'm
ready okay day 10 you can read it and
I'm ready to code emac ready and wolam
language is here uh yeah okay before we
begin let me show you the wolam language
how how do you uh get it so wolam
language is free search for S wam
language in depth and you can download
free from the wam language website
wm.com download wam engine and uh you
know I have a food tutorial
here okay let's begin Advent code okay
so let's see copy that close uh copy
that today's talk show okay
let's begin coding okay um okay day 10
pipe Ma
okay so let's look at problem pipe maze
okay so you use the hand glider to write
the hot air from Desert Island blah blah
blah you wander around for a while but
you don't find any people or animals
however you do occasionally find sign
posts
labeled Hot Springs pointing in a
seeming seemingly consistent Direction
okay the landscape the landscape here is
alien even the flowers and trees are
made of metal okay scanning the area you
discover that the entire field you are
standing on is densely packed with
pipes okay a weird place full of pipes
it was hard to tell at first because
they are the same metallic silver color
as the
ground okay the ground is also silver
color you make a quick sketch of all of
the surface pipes you can see your puel
input so the puel input is all the pipes
you can see the pipes are arranged in a
two-dimensional grid of
tiles okay it's a
tile uh maybe a tiling problem GD of
tiles okay 2D tiles so you got this uh a
vertical pipe that is a vertical pipe
connecting North and South uh Dash is a
horizontal pipe connecting East and West
L is a 90° band connecting north and
east makes sense J is a 90° band
connecting north and west okay J seven
is a 90° band connecting South and West
okay okay so you got all these L symbols
basically f is a 90° bending connecting
south south and east
okay south and east okay
F period is ground there is no pipe in
this tile okay it doesn't connect to
anything okay and S is the starting
position of the animal okay whatever
that is starting position there is a
pipe on this tile but but your sketch
doesn't show what shape the pipe has
okay apparently you have a bunch of
tiles in a plane
and the pattern on the tile is
connecting neighboring tile tiles
okay uh and most connect two okay so
north east west north south or east
south or you know any of the yeah you
got you you got all the combination of
connection like like that that and uh
that that and that that okay one two 3 4
5 six six possibilities let's see 1 2 3
4 five six indeed and plus one that
connects to nothing okay based on the
Acoustics of the animal scaring you are
confident the pipe that connects
contains the animal is one large
continuous
loop okay seems like you need to find
the animal uh starting position of the
animal okay oh God my alarm clock
so for example here is a square Loop of
pipe okay so here is the let's see where
is the puzel
input uh okay so it looks like so there
are some examples let's begin to copy
it okay copy okay let's start a wolam
language okay and let's start a uh input
so paste the
input so here is the problem let's
see so that's a description for example
here is a
input one of the input uh B bad and okay
so okay so the p period is is simply
used as a
blank okay so in this pattern you have
basically a square that's right it
connects a square so if the animal had
entered this Loop in the northwest
corner North West corner from the okay
from there the the stretch would instead
look like
this okay what what they mean by Stretch
uh I didn't read the problem
I mean I didn't read the story
Prelude okay
[Music]
so okay stretch is basically the
starting position I suppose uh your
stretch doesn't show what shape this
pipe okay so uh this is the
stretch okay in the above in the above
diagram the s tile is still 90° F Bend
okay it's just that you don't know you
can tell because how the adjacent pipes
connect to it oh okay so you can tell so
you can
infer the s tile by
adjacent well I mean the assumption is
that they all the all the tiles connect
okay unfortunately there are also many
pipes that aren't connected oh okay to
the loop so this sketch show shows the
same loop as above so here is another
example in this example oh God this is
okay so s is here s is the
starting um
tile okay so this doesn't connect North
it doesn't connect West this connect to
the right okay and it does connect to
the South so connect south and east
but not north and west okay so in this
example in the above diagram you can
still figure out which pipes form the
main
Loop
yes okay because some other tiles they
don't connect you see F and seven
connect seven and this connect but that
but not these two okay so so you can
still figure out pipes form the main
Loop so so maybe there's one always one
Loop they are the ones connected to S
okay pipes pipes those pipes connect
to what pipes those pipes connect to and
so
on okay what weird every pipe in the
main Loop connects to its two neighbors
including s okay which will have exactly
two pieces connecting to it okay and
which is assumed to connect back to
those two
pipes okay including s which will have
exactly two pipes connecting to it okay
okay and which is assumed to connect
back to those
two
pipes okay not it's not too clear okay
but
um
okay so here is a sketch that contains a
slightly more complex main Loop
so assume we assume there's a main Loop
and the main Loop will always contain
the s tile so let's look at this one the
S con Okay so s connect to right and
bottom okay and this bottom connects
here okay so oh God this is a bit
complicated uh so what does this J
connect to J connects to the F above the
F connects to the J to the right uh wait
does
it
yes okay so actually the proper way to
draw the tile is like um anyway these
letters are a bit uh visually confusing
okay so F connects that that and
J
okay so now so that's one example then
here's the same example sketch with the
extra okay so I'm a bit distracted let's
see
uh well I'm con anyone is here
three people okay say hi okay so let's
go back then we we want to uh finish
this okay
so so here's the same example sketch
with the extra nonone men Loop pipe
tiles also shown okay so there's main
Loop but there's also possibly non main
Loop okay God this problem is going to
be hard I
suppose uh okay okay so so you got this
example where this is s so let's color
the S okay let's
magnify uh let color s okay let's
say
yellow so in this example if you want to
okay so it says in this example there's
a main Loop so
SJ FJ
and there's two possibilities oh
God wait no there's only one possibility
F and seven then go back here then go
back here then seven then down then that
that that that that that that okay so
this actually forms a
simple snake
so what is it saying you know here's a
sample here's the same example sketch
with the extra N Main Loop pipes N Main
Loop pipe tiles okay what does that
mean so let's see let's go here here
here here here here here
here here
here here here here here here here
okay uh I don't know what it what does
it mean non main Loop pipe
tiles so it's a same it's not the
same oh okay before it uses the dot to
hide some tiles
now in this one it doesn't you know it
doesn't use a DOT so it's actually more
confusing okay so now let's see if you
want to get out ahead of the animal you
should find the tile in the loop that is
farest from the starting
position
oh so you want to find a tile in the
loop that is farest
farthest the most far from the starting
position okay how do you determine
distance I suppose each tile is one
distance okay so you want to find you
want to find the tile in the loop okay
so the problem is find the tile in the
loop uh because the animal is in the
pipe it doesn't make sense to me
me this by direct distance
what instead you need to find the ti
that would take the longest number of
steps along the loop to reach from the
starting
point regardless of which way around the
loop the animal
went you need to find the tile that
would take the longest number number of
steps along the loop to reach from the
starting
point regardless of which way the around
that Loop the animal went
okay
U you should find the ti in the r that
is a far is from the start okay so
basically the same problem it just you
know use useless information so you want
to find the tile that is the most far
away from the starting tile by number of
steps okay so in this case there's a
even odd issue so let's say if the tile
is 1 2 3 4 so 1 two
3 4 so let's say the loop is foral four
tiles then the farest is that one of
course simple now if the loop is 1 2 3 4
5 six wait one two so one start counting
at one okay 1 2 3 4 five six right and
the the the farest is that one so that
what step is that uh okay so one step
two step three steps right
so the most far tile is half of the
number of tiles but is it possible for
the loop to have seven
steps uh let's
try Okay so one two let's say 1 2 3 4 5
6 7
8 uh so let's try again one 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 11 12 okay it looks like the loop
we always have even number of
tiles
so so you just divide it by two so let's
see 1 2 3 4
so okay so there is like off by one
issue here so the easiest way is that
you always start counting with
one so if you move one step you consider
that two tiles you know instead of just
one so the the distance the far the
farest away is basically half of number
of the tiles so if the loop has four
tiles the the the the the most far away
tile is
two you know half of the total now if
you want to count steps then just minus
one okay so instead you need to find the
tile that would take the longest number
of steps along the loop to reach from
the starting point regardless of the
which way the loop the animal went
so in the first example with the square
Loop okay the most simple kind of let's
count again 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 okay so the
the max
distance is four and if you want to
count count steps is three so the the
most F tile is this one so step is one
two wait 1 2 3 4 correct
okay so you can count the distance each
tile in the loop is from the starting
point like this okay so it's you know
repeating my
analysis 0 one two so 0 one 2
3 four
what oh wait so how many total 1 two
three one 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 right eight
tiles total so max is
four so one two three uh
What uh so on second one two three
four five wait this is a bit different
from what I
thought so how many total 1 two three
four
so 1 2 3 4 five 6 7 eight eight
divided by two is four so one two three
four okay so wait I was wrong
before uh let's say one two three 4
okay oh yeah I was I was right I just
said you
know I explained it wrong okay so the
steps is half of the total number of
tiles
okay so let's continue on
in this example the farest point from
the start is four steps away that's
correct 1 2 3 four half of the number of
tiles here's a more complex loop again
so let's let's try to count so start
from well start from zero then okay so
one two wait let's see first of all
count total number of tiles so 1 2 3 4 5
6 7 7 8 9 10 11 12 13
14 15 16 so 16
total count of tiles so the max steps
would be eight half of that let's try
that so one step one 2 3 4
five 6 7 8 okay supposedly supposedly
okay
so so here so here are the distance so
here is the solution 1 two 3 4 uh wait 1
two three four five six seven wait six
seven yeah that's
right uh how many total 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 10 11 12 13 14
uh God I'm confused
again okay anyway I got the idea
so
she
16 right so if you want to count steps
you minus one is that is that right
again so let's try the
square one
two three uh one two
three yeah is a square you should but
anyway if you have a square 1 2 3
4 that's total of four
Tiles 4 ided by 2 is two so that means
step
one
two okay step one two that's right so
the max step is half of the number of
tiles okay so now let's try
this 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
13 13 14 15 16 16 total so the max
number of steps
is
eight 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 okay so here are the distance okay so
find the single giant Loop starting at
s how many steps along Loops does it
take to get from the starting position
to the point farest okay so that is a
problem yeah we got the problem so here
you
know we got the
problem finished reading the problem and
that
took what 30
minutes what the
13 minutes oh 25
minutes okay reading the problem 25
minutes now let's
uh I'm going correct yeah I'm going yes
so we got the problem down we understand
the problem now the next step is
to so the for the to input the solution
is eight
right the for for this input for this
input this one is a input tot input so
the tot input is this
one okay so this is
the sample input
solution is eight okay that's the answer
so now let's get my personal
input click copy
copy uh now
let's here is the person input let's see
okay
um
see 140
characters 140 by by 140 okay not not so
bad now we need to save it uh Advent of
code let's
see day 10
okay day 10 input okay let's say day
10 oh okay so select all delete and uh
copy and uh paste it so there it
is save copy the file
path go back here and uh here is the
user
input showing
browser okay we that's the user input
now let's have a
look so 140 by 140 so so you need to so
so first the problem is that you need to
find s first of all find
S yeah okay so there it is there's a
unique s start from
s and
uh oh God this is a this is a problem
I don't know if I can finish in one
hour so you find you found the
S
then then this starting position forms a
loop okay so you need to go through this
uh maze you know you can call it a
maze so you need to start to Traverse
the maze you need to
exam the left right and up down
characters the neighboring characters
okay and uh you will
find you will find two tiles that
connect to it
okay so for example here is north and
south okay then what you do is uh let's
magnify okay that's not so good too big
okay so you you you find the next so you
find two neighbor
characters then you can pick one let's
say start from one of them then you find
the next connecting characters okay
right and you basically you repeat
this you repeat this until you are back
to
S that's right it's supposed to be
guaranteed you will uh return to S okay
now which direction should you choose
first uh does not seems to
matter okay so you so once you Traverse
once you reach back to S you want to
find out count how many characters are
there total okay then divided by
two and that's your answer
okay right so the the main the hard of
problem is just to Traverse this text
file
um oh God this is tough yeah this this
problem is kind of tough so the main the
problem is to Traverse this text file
okay am I going yeah so the main problem
is to Traverse this text
file so let's think about how to do so
you get this s this text file can be
represented as a matrix
okay there are many I suppose there are
many efficient ways but let's say you
know it's a
matrix then
you yeah it's it's fairly tedious now do
you have a situation where you go into
the edge and no you don't have that
situation because you know from the
context you don't have that situation so
you you simply just follow the character
so for
each each entry in The Matrix you want
to
find the
neighboring entries that is
valid and uh you can assume there's only
one besides the one you came from so
basically given a matrix you have three
other
choices and one of them is valid okay
then you just go to that one so each one
you found a valid item you put it into a
you push it into a
list so once you reach your character s
again you are done you just then you
count the total number of uh the
tiles okay so that is essentially the
algorithm so but first well well first
of all you need to find the S
entry okay so I think this is this is W
god
um today is the wrong day to do this
problem I'm kind of
tired
so so I'm not sure I can finish
this in 1 hour from now
so here is the S uh that's
right but can it be I mean let's not be
pessimistic I mean let's look at uh from
a optimism point of view it's pretty
simple given a matrix you can you want
to find the neighbor so it's easy you
know given a matrix it's
easy
to well it's not well it's very tedious
to get the
neighboring
entries then you just you know so you
have basically three other choices three
or four if you count the original so you
have four the possible choices minus the
where you came from so you have three
other choices
then you do some kind of condition to
find which one is the one how do you do
that well that depends on which one you
came from so for example if your current
character is
seven oh that makes it much easier oh
wait oh okay so once you conf from a
character you AR arrived at the tile
there is only one direction so you don't
have to do a condition the the current
tile will tell you which one is the
next oh so so easy so you have so each
tile each tile will point to four
possible directions the tire will tell
you which way to go okay so you analyze
the current tile you know it's seven for
example it's either west or
south you analyze the tile
then each tile will give you two
directions you know the one the the
valid one is one that's not where you
came
from okay so given a tile you can find
you need to find the next two possible
choices which is the column and the row
index row and column index so a tile
will induce you two indexes in The
Matrix okay and you need to pick one of
them you need to pick the one that's not
the one you came from okay that's uh you
can do that yes and the index is for the
Matrix always unique of course column
and uh I mean row and column
okay so each time we will give
you two new indexes you choose the one
that's
new okay then you go to Next Step okay
now it's more
clear let's write it out so we need to
write this out um
God oh God just so
okay so something like um so for
example put the
input into a
matrix that is array uh nested array
okay
then each
array item is is a tile
okay find
the one find the stting tile
s okay s is the one
um each array item is a
tile and it is a single
character okay find the starting tile
s find its
row uh find it in what find its index
row and
column row index and column index okay
then given given a
tile
it gives two other Matrix index
is the tile connects to
okay so let's put that there that's a
Prelude
information okay so now you begin
algorithm by find the starting
tile
s find its index
okay
uh uh TI is
identified
by
uh by row index and column index
okay we can call it
ID okay so find the starting tile find
its
ID then
find the two ID it connect to okay let's
say TI
okay push so find the starting tile push
the ID to a result list okay then find
the two ties it connect to
pick the
one hey
wait so starting tile s okay starting
tile is kind of special starting tile
s okay God you know the starting tile
you need to
exam all its neighbor in t
FES right because you don't know what s
is like connecting
to look at all the neighbor tiles of
s okay so what got how do you do this so
you you look at all the ne neighbors of
s
well and you have
to take care of
edges something like that so you you
look at all the neighbors east west
north south of s then you
check you check then one by one to
see oh it depends on the tire position
too so for the East
tile you check if it
connects to the
West ah
God
something something then you arrive
at next tile then you do this okay then
you know that's that but the the
beginning is actually harder
than
um okay I cannot finish this in 1
hour
just we haven't start coding yet any
comments Michael hello if you need to
configure a Q qmk keyboard would you use
VR software yes absolutely VR software
okay VR software is the best user
interface graphical this extremely easy
to use I have I have you know for qmk so
anyway I'm not going to talk about
keyboard today xiaomi phone hello good
morning uh focus on the problem okay
let's do the you know algorithm today
let's talk about this at the end of the
code I don't think I can finish it today
because my wife is coming back in an
hour uh and
uh so this is this doesn't look
good oh God this
is so starting you find you you you want
to get all the neighbors okay so get all
the
um get all the neighbors
NE tiles of s then you need to exam each
one of them why because you you you need
to
find so you have four
Neighbors at most four neighbors four um
okay it has four neighbors or
less when s is on edge okay or corner so
that's a special case you need to deal
deal
with so
um
so look at each
one uh look at each one
then you need to find so for the East
neighbor it should be one of these
characters okay so let's see if we can
go back to um this humongous file
so 140 is actually not too bad 140 I
mean yeah I can I can finish coding this
but not in an
hour so but um I mean the it's just
tedious there's
no you know it's not it's not it's not a
really a hard
problem but it's fairly
tedious
so so we we you know we know what to do
now basically we know what to do and if
I have to explain them in detail and
write it out it's going to take another
20 minutes or 30 minutes but I know you
know I know what to do so now that you
know what to do so for for example you
look at each tile in the beginning for
the East tile
only some of the characters are valid
for example Dash is a valid because it
connect east and west and J is valid
because it also connect to West and
there's another one valid so for for
each tile for the E tile there are three
possible value tiles so one is dash one
is J one is like uh seven okay 7 J dash
on the east side or that
valid okay similarly in other directions
you also have three possible valid tiles
so so you look at all the neighbors and
the when it's invalid you ignore it when
it's valid the end result will be there
there will be like two valid
tiles basic basically yeah there will be
two value tiles that's NE 2 s
okay uh let's write it out for
example for the East
neighbor three possible tiles are
valid okay
they they are uh they are Dash J and and
uh
seven
okay
similarly for each
Direction you have
three possible valid
charts that makes the
tile the path valid
okay but in the end by the Assumption of
the problem
there should be two tiles connected to S
so in other words you'll find two value
tiles that's the neighbor of s okay
then
then then you can
pick you know either one of
them and begin
Traverse okay so the Traverse
steps is
that when you arrive at the
tile find two tiles it connect
to uh pick the one that's
new okay
repeat this
until you reach a t that is
s back to S okay so that is
algorithm so we so now we have a
complete anal analysis okay but now
let's think about okay so you know let's
show um you know show this so it's
interesting Okay so oh
God this doesn't matter how you format
it
is are there anyone watching this
problem give me some feedback okay so
well okay so but we got this written
down basically that's the steps okay now
let's think about possible tricks to
make it
make this easier it's very tedious
problem is there some kind of trick that
will significantly make this algorithm
easier to
implement for example so is there any
dot there yeah there is dots dot dot is
basically a
wall so when whenever you see dot you
can like eliminate so for example you
can first of all scan all the elements
all the tiles whenever you see a DOT you
put that that Dot's ID the row index and
column index into a dead end
zone okay so whenever you need to check
a tile you check the Dead End Zone if
you know a hash table or something if
that you know if the neighbor is one of
that you know already it's it's uh it
doesn't you know that's not your
choice but but if we do this it's no
more efficient than just actually look
at each
tile so that is
uh okay so okay
I well I don't know if I'm going to
finish or I don't even know if I'm going
to start coding this maybe we'll have to
code it tomorrow
tomorrow uh and uh this weekend I'm
going to do I think I'm going to I need
to you know start to do this swab board
so that by the way swab board this thing
is using is using um qmk I mean that V
our software so it's going to be
fantastic fun so anyway the
problem is there any shortcuts let's
think about about
this
[Music]
so you know so we got
this tire
thing is there any kind of like shortcut
to
um start with
s and so s is here
so there's
140 140 by 140 what about if we just
start you know we just go through each
element in the Matrix is that does
that work out is it going to be easier
uh I don't think so because 140 * 140 is
a lot to go through but if you just
follow the loop there's less number of
um
tiles to look
at is that right I don't know but you
know is there some trick let's see is
there some
trick now there is a visual trick if you
just turn these characters into unical
symbols you know like
um I can you know for example let me
show you
you see you can turn this seven and you
know J
into these Unicode
characters then yeah so for example
replace seven
by replace seven by that character
box drawing heavy down and left you know
and
replace dash you know Dash is easy to
see what about J so replace J by this
character box drawing heavy up and
left
then then you will immediately
see the
loop let's see if we follow this let's
see we can try to follow is go up that
that
so
one so counting s okay one two three
4 wait
what one two 3 4
six 7 eight oh God tricky 9 10 11
12 13 14 tricky look at
this yeah so yeah you can
see yeah but can we easily see the
pattern no not
really yeah but if we replace all these
characters by by the unic code we can
easily see
it shall we do
it yeah that's Excursion that's not
solving the problem but
um uh but
um but it is fun to do so we can
actually see the pattern let's why not
do
that okay you
know is there any opinions there's no
comment
okay okay so
um okay so that's one thing we can do um
but
so that's one thing we can
do okay but but anyway you got you got
this
Loop you got this
Loop and
[Music]
uh so what what's some other
tricks we could use
so this this tires this
maze so we know for sure there is one
Loop okay that connects to
S there is one Loop that connects to
S now basically the problem is asking
you to identify this Loop
Loop so is there some kind of like
carpet sweeping
way to identify this
Loop you know identifying this Loop just
means you find all the indexes you know
in The Matrix so is there some kind of
sweeping way instead of we Traverse each
one by
one okay
uh yeah well so you go you you go row by
row and uh you can for example let's say
identify all the vertical
lines those entry connect to the
following uh but not if they are not for
example here they
don't so if you look at them row by row
then you know if the tile is like
anything
horizontal then that's
invalid
okay well not necessarily because you
know it's invalid going down but it may
be valid going side to side so you can
have like go inside and then go down
so
God so again you need to identify this
Loop this path in this
Matrix is there some simple
way you
could okay we know the loop connects to
s so so far it appears the easiest is
actually just starting from
s so we start from s and we
Traverse how difficult is it you because
you have to find all the
neighboring indexes then extract them
from the main
Matrix so potentially you have to do
hundreds or tens
of row and column ex extractions extract
the element and you have to do them so
much so so
frequent uh and
uh okay
so that is
not can we write an AI algorithm to do
this yeah but we need a lot training
data that's
right
uh and uh it's not likely to be 100%
solution yeah this would be interesting
as a machine learning
thing uh but
yeah but that doesn't give us faster
solution because
to you know then you get into the
problem of creating this m maze you need
to create millions of
them which is uh indeed an interesting
thing to do to write a artificial
machine learning solution for
this but it's going to take you many
hours
okay 10 hours at least uh more than 10
then because then you need to deal with
you know uh the neuron net yeah that's
and I'm not experienced in
that but you can feed it to wam language
just feed it you know lots of
input yeah but anyway that's not
a practical solution to solve this
problem at hand
so it looks like you just have to
Traverse each
um you just have to
Traverse from
s okay so today's live stream is just
analyzing this problem okay then we're
gonna shut
down maybe a silly idea but what if you
replaced each chart with a function to
go in a direction then you just execute
the symbol at each location oh that's
interesting I missed the beginning
thought so I uh only get what you are
doing
so so that's an
interesting thought thank
you so you replace each CH with a
function oh that's interesting yeah you
actually that's
can be doable so when you want to
exam a
tile instead of doing if statement you
know for example on the east side of you
know a Eastern neighbor you have to do a
if
statement if that TI is certain
character then it's valid otherwise
no and uh three Poss characters are
valid for each neighbor in a particular
direction for each Direction the
possible valid tile is
different so you have to have some kind
of table look up
too so first of all you have like East
Easter neighbor okay so for Easter
neighbor these three characters are
valid for Western neighbor then another
set of three characters are valid right
then eventually you determine there are
two neighbors that that's that's valid
path right so from your suggestion is
that
you once you encounter a
tile you you have a table too you map
the tile character to a
function uh
then the function will tell you which
direction to go
um so what the function does is
just basically push I mean Traverse
Traverse the tile just means
push the current tile to current push
the tile the value tile to the result so
I'm not sure that
I mean that that just translate to the
actual
code so I don't know if that
um so uh is it can we do something like
yeah I don't
know so the
tile you so the tile each character in
the tile can represent the function so
for example
F just means
going so if you get a f what does it do
exactly this function the function
will
return is in South I
suppose so if you has the function on
argument that is a current tile position
then it can return
the the the Matrix ID the index that the
tile connect
to so for example you will return that
row and column and you'll return that
row and column right
so
each letter can represent
a
function okay the function so each
letter each letter basically returns
East West or you know two of the
directions
then if you feed the letter combined
with a coordinate then it can
return two
coordinates right so something like
that
[Music]
um yeah but that's um yeah that would
be that would be part of actually
writing the
code but does
it does it somehow help
you in a higher level sense skip some
steps
uh I think maybe that does in the
implementation
part yeah I don't know how to so far
that's a interesting
idea okay so uh
that reminds
me instead of doing if statement check
or switch or conditional you can use
pattern mag
so because wam language is good for
pattern maging so you can
have similar similar to this idea
function
so let's say
l uh so what you going to do with
pattern magine so let's
try so if
a so let's write the function let's say
go
something you know I'm just making this
up I don't know how it will
work so if you have a go to or something
like
that so if the function is given an
argument L and
uh row
index okay and uh
then something like column
index so the function is given so if
that so for example we can define a
pattern matching so whenever we see
this
thing it becomes then it returns
it returns two more indexes something
like
that meaning those two indexes are the
valid uh something uh something like
that so instead of saying index let's
just say coordinate
and make it
simple coordinate means a row and column
index so if you see that so if you see a
string
L with a particular
coordinate then you get two
new okay so not just two but
um so sometimes you are at the corner or
Edge but at most you got two new valid
coordinate so but sometimes
one uh you so so
all so you know or just one of
them but but something like that or just
one of them you know
um yeah but how
um okay so right now I'm doing nothing
I'm just trying to avoid actual coding
of this problem I don't think I'm going
to do
it
[Music]
um yeah but okay so let's just go with
this fantasy so so let's
say so if a pattern can can we yeah can
we somehow
like can we somehow make some kind of
like magical
sweep that just get the answer some kind
of magical pattern matchine or
something this is related I believe to
the day three in 2003
there is a
problem
um the V of a
code day three yeah there's a day three
which is kind of similar you got a you
know a two-dimensional text that forms
some kind of pattern and you need to get
the neighboring uh
numbers okay so this is a ad Advent of
code 2023 day
three and I spent a
week so you look look at the code this
is complex I spent a week on this
because I was trying to find some kind
of like a magical solution that can see
the whole pattern but eventually I
cannot do
it yeah eventually I can I can can do it
so I end up with this
solution yeah it's yeah
actually the
solution
um
so so we have a similar situation
here can we can is it possible to have a
pattern somehow
uh I don't
know
so so what about this idea well this is
actually just
this is actually just coding I mean this
is actually this it's
not
something meta level this is actually
just dealing
with you know this is just actually
using patterns instead of using IF
statements um but for example this
actually return nor uh North and South
okay so if you have L it basically means
that but if you with L with
coordinate
um for example we can write it like that
then it it gives you
coordinates
okay so this is uh kind of Nest you know
curing anyway but um so we can start to
write this pattern for
example
uh for example Dash actually this this
you don't need
that and the
coate and
actually oh actually we can start to
code this now so this coordinate Will
[Music]
be actually the coordinate is easier to
write
row column
okay index so row and column are indexes
so once you see that then you just
get uh to
possible so uh once you see that you get
row row plus one okay
so
row
plus
one uh wait row stays the
same column + one okay that's one
coordinate then the other coordinate
is is row minus one okay so
row minus one and column remain the same
so that's going north and this is
provided that your row and column is not
on the edge because
otherwise because you don't have
a
toodo
plan
um but actually we don't have to worry
about this because if we are
following you know if we are following s
you know we if we are following the path
from s then we won't have a problem of
going beyond the real you know like
hitting
a a wall on the edge of the
Matrix
so then this code is actually
valid so whenever you CL l
let's say tile so not go
to okay something like that so now this
is becoming more valid code so when you
see a l tile
l so when you see tile L it basically
returns south and
north and uh
so what about order should we should we
have a canonical order of
the east west south north yes let's go
let's go
counterclockwise so North first then
South so in here it should be in this
order North
first so North is row minus one
then then column Remains the Same that's
right so this is kind this is valid code
but yeah but what you going to do with
this uh okay so yeah so we don't care
about
that so that's kind of valid code and uh
let's let's give it another example
let's say tile
Dash so tile Dash is is east and west so
East
first okay
[Music]
then yeah but then if you give it
coordinate then row +
one uh row actually row doesn't
change
East so column Plus one so column + one
then West West equals to column minus
one that's
right so this this is this is kind of
valid code but
um I'm not sure how it actually applies
so we kind of actually started to code
this so we have to do this for all the
possible characters
uh possible characters
are Dash vertical
line so actually it's easier if we draw
it
uh you know if we start to draw
this it becomes easier
to do
we don't want those that those we don't
want those are the
same so that we don't want that we don't
want we don't want
monsters monsters okay so all the
possible so we already have that
you see so we can see all the possible
characters so how many passle one two
three four five six let's see 1 2 3 4
five six yeah so this uh wait there's
six
possible six possible characters
excluding the dot okay the dot is the
dead end so for the path there are six
possible characters so we can then we
can write it
f so this would be F this will be Dash
this will be vertical line uh
this will be vertical line this would
be what what is
this seven okay this so this is
seven this
is L I think
L and what is this this is J
okay so these are the
possible okay so actually now we can
write them out so yeah now it's
clear
that vertical line Dash vertical line
F7
LJ 1 two three four yeah six possible
characters okay
so we so now we have like two
possibility yeah but we are not doing
you know this is
just this is just if condition
basically uh we are so this this they
are using pattern maraging but it's
basically just doing if statement you
know in a in a different way but it does
not actually
somehow make the problem super
easy yeah I don't know so I'm thinking
of stop here today so what uh what you
guys are saying I thinking so like L
would execute the function at the
coordinate so it would become sort of
recursive B tree style problem
[Music]
okay thank you Ringo Tingo says hey I
just wanted to say you inspire me to
learn and keep coding really appreciate
your work thank
you yeah coding is if you are into
coding you know I'm I'm into coding many
people are not but if you know if they
are not they they do other things things
that they are you
know good at but if you are interested
in coding coding is you know I you know
I would say one of the thing that makes
a lot
money you know relatively compared to
other jobs you can make a lot
money uh you know just just
coding as compared to you make I would
say reasonable it's like low like a
lawyer or a doctor and coding has a
bright future you know it's not going to
go away a lot of people say oh AI is
going to kill coding no actually not AI
is is going to increase the value of
coders okay there are many programmers
they will say oh AI is going to kill
coding you know actually that's
completely they don't know what
they talking about I'm starting to rent
because I'm not doing this problem so
it's easier for me to just say my
opinions so but that's my opinion
coding is you know it's going to be more
and more valuable okay than anything
else um so anyway so as far as this
problem
goes we have analyzed it and we
we kind of know what to
do but the the the devil is in the
details you have to actually code
it you know instead of so only when you
actually have a program and it runs then
you can say we got
it yeah but I don't I don't have it and
uh I'm not going to code it
because it's going to take more than 1
hour
uh for sure so let's you know I I think
maybe that's it for today just random
chat get him give him money yes
money okay anything else I think I'm
going to close so uh maybe we'll do this
continue
tomorrow is Steve here
yeah I'm going to go have
dinner in 30
minutes how many people nine people what
you guys
doing uh well since we are doing nothing
I can actually just code you know just
so
you know so there are total of six
possible characters we can finish this I
mean yeah but what does that give us not
too
far so and first of all we have to
search for
S well first of all you need to turn
this input into a
matrix now there are several ways either
you turn it a m into a matrix then you
refer to each item by a row index and
column index
or you can kind of take the whole thing
as a string then you have to refer each
item by some kind of accumulated index
you
know either way you know both way are
more it's like tedious like you know
like like the number three day three
problem we did
before
um where is it yeah this advantage code
day
three so what did I do did I do a stream
position yeah I didn't turn into a
matrix but so with a
string
you then you have to consider the
efficiency actually we are not worried
about efficiency because you have to
consider the efficiency of extracting
from string versus extract extracting
from a 2d
Matrix because you need to do that a lot
like hundreds uh
times um but that's not our concern Our
concern is actually find some kind of
higher level algorithm for this
problem
and and so
far it doesn't you know I don't have any
ideas
and this idea about using a function
to
uh so each character is a
function
then then
recursive would execute the function at
the co
inate okay what does the function do so
it would become sort of recursive B
tree okay so I would execute a
function okay so I mean if that's you
know if we're going to do that then then
this function will be named go to and uh
it will actually
return it will just return one single
tile one single uh
coordinate uh okay some something like
return a
coordinate which is a valid path but
then you this go to you will need let's
put it here you will need to also
feed
it the current tile that's right the
current tile okay
so you need
it
uh you know we so I think we actually
just have to code it instead of talking
abstractly because then because in order
to do that what does the function I mean
does the function takes a
input if the input is
L it can do much you know you know if
the input is l it just return North and
South that's the maximum it can do it
also needs the current coordinate so the
function will
become we'll need arguments you know the
the current
coordinate and the new tile the new tile
coordinate and right so it needs the
current coordinate the current
tile yeah but so you see you see it gets
complex you see you can
just you know um function represent L
represent the
function
because because for the in order for the
function to actually do something useful
such as return the next valid
tile that function needs the current
coordinate right and it needs
right so if it if that function needs a
current Corner then that function can
represent L you know it's um so I mean
we have to work this out so yeah to
actually code and see what I
think um yeah I think so
so so what are we doing so so first yeah
so first of all represent you know we we
are kind of start coding you know we
can't do nothing without actual coding
it so actually we can start with a
toy uh Toy
input you know so the toy input is
uh where is it so the total input is is
that okay
then then we start to
find so the first question is do you
want to turn this into a matrix or
not if you want to turn it into a matrix
you just do a split on new line then for
each line line you do another
split by a empty
string then you get a
matrix now if you don't want to do it uh
in a matrix then you then you just
um then it's more tedious then I mean
it's in not intuitive because then you
use basically modular arithmetics you
have to determine how many lines are
there each
index you know you you the index become
total number of
characters uh
so which can
be you know which can be turned into
line number and column
number yeah but so so but every time you
get a new index you have to do this step
of turning it into a line number and
column number so that's not intuitive so
the easier the more intuitive is
just start to string
split yeah but then we started to then
is just starting to become TDS
coding okay string input then
then
split yeah okay so but suppose we got
the
Matrix then okay once you got the Matrix
then
uh once you got a matrix then
you go
through
what what
okay go through Matrix
find coordinate of s okay then then
you push s to a
result path so we Define a path uh this
path will be empty
list and each
item
each
item is a string okay something like
that I mean it's a
character uh wait is it character or
wait it should be each item is a
coordinate
okay uh yeah then then you run into a
problem you know then it's deter then
then you you need to find all the
neighboring
coordinates neighboring tiles they
coordinate then for each coordinate you
have
to find what letter it is then for each
letter you need to check its valid over
there yeah
so uh
okay okay I'm going to check out I'm
going to shut down uh you know because I
cannot finish it it's going to take
another
hour um so that's it for today we shut
down in 3 minutes we already spend
almost like two two
hours chicken out
check which is a bad thing to
do uh okay we shut down in 3
minutes at the end of code TDS
problem Advent of code let's you know
let's search let's see who did Advent of
code usually day 10 not many people do
it uh now I will finish this for sure
just not today tomorrow yeah tomorrow
maybe if we are if I'm not busy tomorrow
uh I will solve this either this or I'm
going to start to to do the SM board
because I really need to get on
it I'm going to plug in and just you
know just live stream
it uh you know then that's first step
then once you start to do something you
will start to um do
it so day 10 oh you need to Advent of
code Advent of code
day 10 let's see what other people oh
there it is look code on redit 2023 day
Solutions okay oh here is
a what is this uh Ruby or python
open. read. split lines that's um
Ruby I think that's Ruby solution no
this guy is F
Jesus
so so here is
the open input read split lines okay so
it's split lines and
dictionary
zip wait this is python I think so
zip so and something t c
1 plus J 3 you know there's a lot of
smart people out
there yeah quite a few
Solutions okay bye
guys Elixir program okay now I'm curious
I never searched is there a wolfan
language solution
I never
searched Advent of code Advent of code
solution in wolam language what year is
this 2021 oh let's see this is from the
wolam
people oh okay not not an employee butal
solution in the wolf language
2021 now how many
what problem does it
solve does it solve just one problem or
what call Solutions in the wam
language oh it's got a bunch of problems
say1 2 3
4 okay but this is 2021
oh wait this is 2020 Advent of code now
2020 I don't think I start to do
it let's see announcing winner of one
liner announcing the winners of the 2023
oneliner and get visual
competitions yeah okay so I don't think
there is
so this is advent of code 2020 do we
have
something more
recent code 2021
Solutions
okay
uh who is solving Advent code 2000 there
it is advent code
2023 Online technical discussion groups
should we cheat and look at their answer
okay Samuel you know there's a lot you
know these people are smart people let's
see uh let's on JavaScript Advent recode
2023 day one part two oh he's got he's
got it all
let's see day
two part two day three oh he solve it
all now you know
I'm I'm excited to compare my solution
to his solution this is you know because
in the same language then you can see
which code is more efficient and shorter
oh look at okay day
four let's quickly look at day 10 okay
day six part two day eight part one day
nine day 10
wow this is the best solution for our
problem so day 10 so he Define north
south okay coordinate okay that's the
addition so you add that to go into that
direction pipe encoding wow pipe
encoding
oh and then original uh input so that's
the input original array pad okay so he
creates a
pad so he turns it into a matrix and he
also padded it so that you don't get
into the edge you know problem and start
position first position original s
4057 execute
movement and get pipe and uh then length
minus one to okay
fantastic okay that's it that's a
solution uh wait can we copy the code
does it work yeah let's let's just do it
let's yeah I mean why
not
uh yeah let's let's run his code so copy
it let's
see let's forget about our
code okay
so we didn't do it that's okay
uh oh God so
wait okay this is
problematic yeah we don't want
that so can we copy the whole thing copy
let's go to w language paste there there
it is
okay now that's his code part
one let's run it and's see what
he it worked
7086 that's his uh
solution for his
input okay so
great okay that's it that's it for
us so who is this
guy oh he actually generate wait he
actually generated
a part two method one he generated a
graph for it fantastic
amazing wow this is really good so this
guy I can really trust
so he uh for part two he actually
offered two
solutions so then there's day
11 day 12 oh my God day
13 so who who who is this post does
anyone day 21
wow okay bye guys let's go I want to
check Samuel
Martino post it five months ago let's
check G to watch this guy this guy is
good in Quebec
Canada okay he's got a
website okay bye guys