Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. We are going to code Wuam language
advent of code 2025
day two problem one. Uh let's see. So if
you are here say hi. If you are
um watching this offline play at 1.5
speed.
Okay. So what is this analytics?
Uh
okay so let's begin. So Wuam language
uh
wam language advent of code day 2 2025.
Okay. So can you see my screen? Check uh
today's talk show. Check check check
video check audio check. Okay. So,
advent code of a code. Okay. Day two
gift shop. So, we're going to do this
slowly and have fun. Play at 1.5 speed.
If you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments.
Uh, showing browser. Okay. So,
so can you see it? Uh, this stupid.
Okay. You get this inside. You get
inside and take the elevator to it to to
its only other stop, the gift shop.
Thank you for visiting the North Pole.
Gleefully exclaims a nearby sign. You
aren't sure who is even allowed to visit
the North Pole, but you know you can
access the lobby through here. And from
there, you can access the rest of the
North Pole base. As you make your way
through the surprisingly extensive
selection, one of the clerks recognizes
you and asks you for help. As it turns
out, one of the younger elves was
playing on a gift shop computer and
managed to add a whole bunch of invalid
product IDs to their gift shop database.
Surely it would be no trouble for you to
identify
the invalid product ID for them, right?
They've even checked most of the product
ID ranges already. They only have a few
product ID ranges your puzzle input that
you'll need to check. For example, this
okay, this uh this is one single line
uh several bunch of numbers separated by
comma. The numbers each number is like
two numbers separated separated by dash.
Okay. So this is your input
the ID range. So each each uh item is a
range two numbers.
Uh okay. So so the ID range are wrapped
here for legibility in your input. They
appear on a single long line.
Okay. Stupid advent of code hard
formatted page.
Uh they appear on a single long line. So
you you get one single long line. Okay.
So you need to split strings something
like that. The ranges are separated by
commas. Each range gives its first ID
and last ID separated by a dash. Of
course
technically that symbol is called hyphen
not dash. Okay. Uh the zuma generation
idiots but um but the guy who wrote a
vand of code is not a zoomer.
So
since uh I think he is like um Malay
genen since the young elves since the
young el was just doing silly patterns
you can find the invalid IDs by looking
for any ID which is made only of some
sequences of digits repeated twice.
[sighs]
looking for any ID which is made only of
some sequence of of digits repeated
twice. So 55 5 6 4 64 that's 64 twice
and 1 2 3 1 2 3 would all be invalid ID.
So you
okay so uh okay some of these numbers
they have basically
sequence of digits repeated twice.
None of the numbers have leading zeros.
So 0 1 01 isn't an ID at all. Okay. One
is a valid ID that you would ignore.
Okay. because it's valid. Okay, your job
is to find all of the invalid ids that
appear in the given ranges.
Okay, in above example, so 11 to 12 has
two invalid ids 11 and 12.
Okay. So basically a sequence of
numbers. Uh so starting from a minimum
to maximum I presume you know it's not a
given. It doesn't say so but I presume
let's presume you know from minimum to a
maximum. So among these numbers
inclusive including the minimum and
maximum you want to find all numbers
such that they are
uh they are basically
a sequence of digits repeated
once. Okay. So, so first thing you
notice is that if
So, first thing you notice that if the
number of digits is odd, then that
doesn't count because it is impossible
for odd number of digits
to be the result of something repeated
twice because when you repeat repeat
once, you know, um
the digits going to
uh odd number the total number of
digits. Okay. So 11 12 has two invalid
digits. 11 and 12 both are the both have
even number of digits.
Okay. Uh then before even we understand
we probably already understand the
problem but let's go further. So if the
total number of digits are even you
exclude it. Wait if it's odd you exclude
it. So you only consider
numbers whose total number of digits are
even then for those
if they
you know basically you split the number
into two then uh in fact this problem is
probably easier if you deal with the
numbers a string. So you basically match
string. So in fact if you do that this
can be done as a regular expression.
Can it be done as a regular expression?
Yes, I think so. So if you do it as a
regular expression, it basically
automatically solve the problem.
Yeah, you don't even have to filter even
odd the total number of digits. I think
comments. Okay. So 1112 then 95 to 115
has one invalid digit 9 99. Okay. 988 to
1012 has one invalid digit one zero 1
zero. Okay. Then this big number range
has one invalid ID 1851 185.
Okay. Then this range has one invalid
invalid ID 22 two22.
Okay. Then this contains no invalid ID.
Okay. So this bench no invalid ID.
Now sometimes if you use the drawing pen
as a mouse it's uh it's not good.
Okay. So then then this has invalid ID
446 446 and this range has invalid ID
3859 3859. The rest of the ranges
contain no invalid IDs. Okay. So it says
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8. So it's saying eight of
them has invalid ID. But how many total
are there? One, two, three,
four, five,
six,
7, 8, 9, 10, 11. Okay, so eight of the
ranges has invalid ID.
Okay, so adding up all the invalid IDs
in this example produces that.
Okay. So, what do you get if you add up
all invalid ID? Okay. Let's get my
personal input. Select all. Copy. Go
back. Close it. Go to Emacs.
Uh, so open a new new save. So, this is
uh advent of code. Let's just say xxx
for now. Okay. And let's get the proper
name.
Uh so copy that. So search for xxx.
Let's rename it.
Rename it. This will be a rand of code
day two.
Okay. Copy. I mean make it so. Okay.
Open this. That's a personal input.
Close. Close. And uh today's talk show
uh start coding here
personal input make a link make a list
then
uh move the file
into
the I directory. Okay. Open it.
Fantastic. Okay. So close it. So that so
showing browser. So we got that personal
input. Now the default input let's copy
it.
Copy.
Copy. And let's begin to code
wam language. Paste it.
Okay. So here is the input. Let's start
wam language.
Now if you don't know, watch my previous
videos. There's hundreds of them. Uh uh
wuam language for programmers complete
tutorial from the ground up and
and where to download wam language for
free. It it began uh free about five
years ago.
Then uh saw wufam mode. This is for
coding wam language in Emacs. Okay, you
can get it on GitHub. It's free. Thank
thanks to wu frame research.
Okay. Now wra language three shift enter
to start the kernel and magnify.
So we got this is our work sheet.
Okay. And uh so and I'm using softly
keys in EMAC. The most efficient key
binding system in the universe more
efficient than vim or neoim. but for
Emacs. Okay. So, um there's like
hundreds of videos I talked about these
topics. So, anyway, so wam language
begin. Okay. So, here is input. So,
let's just say input equals true.
Now, uh normally it's a string, right?
Uh separated by comma. So, uh
space without space. So let's just make
it so
uh
okay now let's double check is our input
without any space that's correct
okay so now
so that's input
so first of all
string split by default it uh so let's
Say x input
split by comma. Okay. Then
splitted input
uh.
Okay. So we can do this select all paste
in language. So you can see evaluate. So
now you got a bunch of a list of
strings. Now for each one of them you
split again. So but uh so let's see
11 and 12. So let's pick one. Let's say
this example.
Okay. For each range they only have one
invalid number except the 11 to 12.
Okay. So but but okay. So anyway, so now
let's try this example. So
let's just try to uh work on this
example.
So you got a range of numbers.
Okay. So if you want to use regular
expression. So first of all, let's test
regular expression. Okay. So for example
this number
uh let's say
xx equals to this number
test
rejects. Okay so that's a regular
expression uh you uh string match.
Okay. So here is a documentation for
string split
and uh here is a documentation for
string match string match pattern. So
let's say xx
uh in this example let's just say
directly that number. Okay. Then pattern
pattern there are two ways to specify a
pattern. One is regular expression. The
other one is string expression.
Uh
so let's just use regular expression.
But meanwhile let me show you what I'm
talking about. So you go to
today's talk show wufam language for
programmers search for it you will find
it on kasadi.info
http known as kasali.info info. Okay. So
here you can uh stream and regular
expression. Okay. So you go to stream uh
introduction to wam language string.
Then you got string functions you know a
list of all string functions about 100
of them. Then uh you can get substring
by pattern uh delete substring and so
on. And the one section is regular
expression and string expression.
Regular expression you are probably
familiar with. It's a string pattern.
Now but in Wuen language you also have a
string expression which is basically
like regular expression but alternative
syntax.
[clears throat]
uh basically uh you know just
alternative syntax of regular
expression. In fact, it's easier to read
but less familiar to most people because
most people use regular expression in
every other language. Uh for now let's
use regular expression. So string match
match your regular expression. What do
you want to match? Okay. So in regular
expression if you want to match a number
that's uh back slashd
now uh back slash d plus okay so wait
back slashd plus uh
means one or more.
Now to be sure let me check regular
expression uh wam language regular
expression syntax.
Okay. So here is woofam language regular
expression.
Do I have the syntax example here?
Regular expression syntax. Am I going
say hi? Okay. Say put in a comment. Uh
string expression. Regular expression.
Wait, string replace. Uh, so let's go to
the reference.
Wait, why don't I say
example of regular expression ignore
case replace string by captured
patterns. Okay, now
I don't have a page of regular
expression syntax. So we need to go to
wuam language regular expression syntax.
So here is a summary of syntax. So
double backslash d for digit 0 to 9.
Right? So you need to double backslash
because
backslash is a escape character.
So if you want backslash d in string
that then that's going to be double
backslash. So this is not very good.
This is like in EMAC lisp and also in
common lisp in scheme lisp you only have
one string syntax.
So every time you have a backslash you
need to double it very bad. So anyway
regular expression uh d then you want to
you want to say this is repeated once.
Okay. So,
so um let me show you. Okay, so
basically you want the parin
parane is for capture and uh you want
you you don't want you you want grouping
you don't want actual capture. So,
um let's see question M.
So, we want to capture. Okay, we want
group but we don't want capture. Treat
upper case lower case. Okay, that's a
case. Uh that's that's these are
normally flags regular expression flags.
Okay. So we want to capture but
without actual capturing
repeated between m and n times. Okay. So
okay so I think it's just that then uh
then
one or more then repeated twice. Okay,
let's double check.
M and repeat it between M and N times.
And then
you want to say then you want to put a
anchor that means this must be beginning
of match.
Uh wait,
not that.
Okay. And over here it's end of match.
Now, do you need escape for the for the
braces? Uh this escape is uh usually
very annoying. No, you don't. Okay.
Unless you want literal braces.
Okay. Comments, guys. Comments. Do we
have like anyone watching? Four people.
Okay. Just say hi. So, am I going? Yeah.
Okay. So, that's a regular expression.
We can run it. Let's see how Let's see
if it works. Okay. Run. See what's the
result.
True. Fantastic. Now, we just try a few
uh try a few. Let's say 223. A A3. A a3
run it
true. Now let's try something false.
Aa3 zero
true. So we got fact. Okay. So this is
tricky.
We don't want that. Okay. So this is
this is also true. So that is incorrect.
So
you want this to be
repeated twice.
So can this be done with regular
expression? I'm pretty sure.
Hello aspiring Windows com compositor.
Hello functional programmer. Uh
I think you are uh
combinatorics guy something. So anyway
so so back to this. So why is this true?
So this means a digit
one or more
and uh
string match.
Now string match does it needs to match
the entire pattern or not? I think so.
Um
let's try. Okay,
this should return false because that's
not the whole pattern. That's right. So
in that way we don't even need the
beginning and end. Okay,
try it.
Uh it returned true but it shouldn't.
Why is that? A A3 A A3
string match digit one or more.
Okay.
Insta problem.
Why is this true? We don't know.
Uh should be fine. Let's go back to the
regular expression thing
P MN T repeated between M and N times.
So we say exactly should be two times.
So there's no way that returns two, you
know. So
the shortest consistent string that
match, we don't want the shortest. Okay,
it's a question mark, right? And string
matching the the sequence P1 P2. Okay.
So the following represent classes of
characters. That's right. Digit.
Okay. Then the following named classes.
You can use named classes. Okay. The
following represent positions in string
beginning and end. Okay.
So backslash backslash is literal
characters.
So back slashback slashgn
is the um
captured pattern
represent the captured pattern.
Okay. And uh if you want to actually
replace you use dollar sign in.
Okay. So we got that. But now
we have this bug
string match Q. Uh we have this bug
that's not
Uh we don't know why this returns true
because we say
true Cool.
Oops.
So, let's try this one. Paste.
Let's try this one.
Paste. Shift. Enter.
Why is it true?
I know understand.
Let's just
try some some fancy ones. Uh
copy
paste.
Let's say
three [snorts]
three. It must repeat it three times.
It's even true.
Now if you remove the paren what
happens?
Okay. Nothing to repeat in regular
expression.
Okay. This 33 I don't understand
why is it return true.
You know,
why is this returning true?
Let's think about again. So, digit
So if you do that,
that's a digit true of course. Now if
you remove the paren
that's true, of course. Now uh are you
sure that's a digit? What? What the
is going on?
slash D unknown string escape slashd
that's right
so if you have double D then it's a
digit now if you put a number that will
not match because
string match needs to match the entire
thing it'll be force let's try it
that's right force
>> [sighs]
>> But if you put dot anything
then dot anything then a digit somewhere
it'll return true.
That's right.
So we make sure this digit this D is a
digit.
uh and but this repeat got a problem. So
why can't we let's let's say
ttxxx
okay and uh let's say
this pattern let's make it simple
let's say
txtx
okay tx repeat it
twice. True. Now if you say one one,
would it still return true?
False.
Okay. So here is TX repeated two times.
True.
Now txtx but repeat it once false.
So this repetition seems to also work.
I mean the repetition syntax.
So if you say three,
it'll return false.
That's correct.
Unless we actually add another TX there.
Now it'll be true.
Okay.
Now, but then why is that this digit
should
get us into problem?
[snorts]
I wonder
why. Why is this 83 a3 a3 then we got a
zero
right? What? So if you just say
one two three would it return true
still?
So we got something wrong. Something
seriously wrong.
I don't understand. I don't understand.
So this digit one or more
must repeat at least twice minimum and
maximum.
Digit one or more.
So plus means at least one. One or more.
Repeat it at least twice
and no more than two times. Exactly.
Repeat it two times. And the input is
one, two, three,
but it returns true.
Uh, like what the is going on?
Okay, there's something I don't
understand. There is something I this I
don't get completely.
Why is that every time we code there is
some problems?
Now can can this can be because in
Python we can try Python.
Let's put it back. Okay. Um
for example in JavaScript uh okay Python
paste
uh Python how do you match regular
expression? I forgot. Let's go to Python
tutorial. Search for it.
My name X A H L E Python tutorial you'll
find it string unic code then there is a
regular expression somewhere string unic
code string string string string string
uh
module miscellaneous regular expression
regular expression check if string match
research pattern string flags okay So
let's try Python.
Copy paste.
Uh so Python the text is going to be one
two three and uh the pattern we want to
search is
uh basically is this. Okay. So yeah got
Python ro something something. Uh okay.
So let me
so raw means there's no special
treatment of backslash. So so that in
this case you just need one backslash.
Now do
so digit first
then text. So text let's remove it.
Let's just make it simple. Okay.
Run it. Yes.
So in Python this also matched.
Okay. Something something
fundamental
that I'm getting wrong.
Wait. Why? Why is that something
fundamental? Um
something fundamental about regular
expression I'm getting wrong
and uh
and uh this just um
uh print. Okay.
It matched
spam
span span 03.
Wait, what?
something fundamental about regular
expression syntax that I'm not not not
getting correctly. Let's see regular
expression syntax. I wrote a tutorial.
This is like 15 years ago
or almost 20 years ago because I have a
fight with the Python people.
I um anyway that's a long story. You can
read about it somewhere somewhere in the
article. Okay. So, so but we want to
know why is even in Python this returns
this returns true
uh this let's make it the other way it's
easier to understand okay yeah this so
it returns yes so it matched
so a digit one or more and repeated Oh,
I see. You see I got it. You see this
digit you captured you know this this is
digit one or more. So
there's more tricky. Okay. So it doesn't
needs not to be exact the same digit.
Uh but still in this case I don't
understand why it's true because there's
odd number of items here.
uh in this in the case of Python you
need to put uh that if you put
beginning of the string and end of the
string then it return false.
Oh, it's still true.
Okay, there's something I don't
understand. But anyway, I I I got part
of it because this this means it um
this is not very specific digit sequence
of digit. It could be any. So one is a
sequence of digit two one or more and
two is a sequence sequence of digit one
or more. So therefore one two is
considered a repetition.
uh but in this case I don't know why if
you say three
in this case why is three matching
I don't know
so anyway so there are now two issues
one is that figure out why is these
three matching the other issue is go
back to our problem and uh make that
digit a specific reference.
Okay. So,
can this actually be done with regular
expression?
Sure. But why is this?
Okay. So now let's go back to Python. So
Python rejects functions. We want the
one.
We want uh one that um
let's try this.
Yes. Okay. It returns yes.
Okay. So, there's something really
tricky about slash digit one or more.
I don't understand why is this returning
yes.
Okay, that's a question. So, let's not
use that. Let's use this.
Yes, also yes. Okay, so
what so what about that? um
regular expression functions. Yeah.
rejects functions then
[sighs]
rejects syntax
backlash d is digits. That's right. And
uh we want to know about the repetition.
Repetition quantif qualifiers. Okay.
Then you got these exactly m copies of
previous rejects.
Okay. Now let's just try one single
value.
Not two. Two, just two. Run it. It
returns yes.
I don't understand.
Why is it yes? Because we have this
boundary.
We have this boundary.
Okay. So that has to do with the rejects
function.
Okay. So this is about either
the pattern should match the entire
string or
it can be just part of the string. So
let's look at rejects functions. So
match start at the beginning of string.
But so if you use match and you use the
dollar sign
to signify the end,
why is it not
so dollar sign?
So, you need to um
dollar sign matches the end of the
string or just before the new line.
Okay. So,
so the multi if the multi-line flag is
given then it also matches before any
new line. No, I don't want the
multi-line flag.
Oh god.
Question. Okay. So, let's ignore the
Python for now.
Let's go back to wra language. Okay.
Now, we know
this. Um, let's try.
Can we can we do
can we do like like that
true? Okay. So you can just have a
single
number
you see false. Okay. Now let's go back
to wam language.
Uh wam language regular expression. You
see it says here repeated between m and
n times but it did not give a
it did not give a single number
specification here.
Take notes, regular expression, special
characters. Let's see. Take notes. Yeah,
take notes is like too elaborate. You
see there's no single M example given
which is kind of
uh this is doesn't seems good because it
seems to also support
this
single number. So take nodes string
expression
Okay. So, let's look at my tutorial.
Yeah,
okay. So
God why why is there always this little
problem? Is it true? It supports that.
Yes. Because if you say
that it return false.
Yes. So this single
braces number
syntax works.
However, it's not
well documented
here.
Is that right? So, is this a valid
point? Did I find a valid
bug in the Wuam language documentation?
I mean, is that did we spend all all
this time? Is that true? We found a
valid criticism
or incompleteness or imperfection of a
problem in weren language documentation
because we want to know this repetition
syntax but with one
single number there but it's not
mentioned here. However,
we test it seems to work.
You see these two. So,
so I think there's a valid criticism of
the Wufam language documentation. It's
not
mentioned
uh scope
basic constructions
and see
basic constructions. So there's a
repetition two three
but um
compound constructions okay more
complicated
you know they don't have much
you see they don't have much
examples. They should have a lot more
expan examples
but I think they focus on their string
patterns
string expression uh which is their
alternative syntax for regular
expression
which is more readable
anyway. So we didn't. So anyway, so I
think that's a documentation problem. So
now can we go back to our problem by uh
trying to
fix this so far? Is there everything
clear?
No, because
we still don't understand why
this works. True.
Uh, for example, let's make it simpler.
A9
A98.
Okay. A97.
Let's say 1 2 3. Run it. It'll return
true.
Yeah. But why is that?
because the string match requires
matching the entire expression.
So
the
back slashbacks slashd plus
matches one.
Oh, I got it. So
it matches one, then the rest matches 2,
three. So is it repeated twice? Yes,
because one is a sequence of digits one
or more. 2 three is a sequence of digit
one or more. So they got repeated even
though the exact numbers are different
but they but they they are they are
indeed a sequence of digit repeated. So
that returns true.
Now I understand that. Okay. Now that
also explains the Python case.
You see
it matches one.
Uh let me let me write down
one as first sequence of digits.
It matches 23 as second sequence digits.
Therefore
result is two is true.
Because the pattern
backslash
the backslash the back slash D plus
is repeated twice.
Okay. So that is why this match
Okay,
now we know why. Okay, now so now go
back to wam language. Now let So now we
know why
uh we can uh we can rework out rework
this uh to be what we want. Okay. So
what this needs to be let's see if this
can be done by regular expression at
all.
First of all, you don't need the dollar
sign and uh
because
you don't need the dollar sign because
um because in wam language the string
match cube requires to match the whole
thing.
[clears throat] Okay. So, but you need
to refer to this
Okay. So instead of that, let me show
you how. Okay. So let's say let's say
uh let's say let's just say A8. Okay. So
so first of all you have that. Then
you have you don't need the dollar sign.
Okay, then you then you just say
back slashbacks slash one that refers to
the previous capture.
So this should return true.
Okay. Now to test the contrary,
let's say
one, two, this will return false.
Fantastic and beautiful. We are on
track.
Now let's test more. Now let's say aa99.
Uh wait that that will return false.
Okay. So now but let's try a8.
It will also be false.
That's right. Now let's try a uh a9 a9.
That will be true.
Beautiful.
So now we can we we we made one progress
milestone.
Gerard. Hi from the other side of the
earth. Hello.
Uh hope you enjoy today's talk show. So
we made a progress. This can be indeed
be done by regular expression. Okay.
And uh and what what about so let's try
this number. So this number. So
copy
cut
uh run it should be true.
Okay. Now but if you add a little more
number there it'll be false.
Perfect.
Okay. So this can be done by regular
expression. Um
what about alternative ways? So to solve
this problem, you split the the string.
Then you got a string of
a string that is a syntax specifying a
range. Then you need to split them
again. So you got two numbers. Then you
need to turn the string into a number.
then generate all the numbers in
between. That's the easiest way to get
all the numbers. Okay. So then you got a
list of numbers. Then for each number
you need to turn them back into a
string. Then you do this regular
expression match.
Okay. If it matches
push it to a new result list something
like something like that. Okay.
Okay. So we can we can um
now we know what's the problem. Okay,
now we uh we now let's
have a break. I mean let's uh clean up
our stuff.
Let's clean up the Let's clean up our
stuff. All this testing code. So yeah,
let let me just clean up
Uh
so the question is
let me comment up.
We don't need the anchor.
Because
string match requires
what
the hole
the the pattern
to match entire string.
Okay. So for example,
uh ABC
uh then you let's just say
uh let's say ABC
post
right so you need to have ABC
then that's true
and
you don't need to say begin
and end that will be also true if you
put it there doesn't matter. Okay, so
that's one issue.
Now the second issue is this this um
this return there's something odd. Let
me show. So here here is an example.
This example
return true
because
The pattern
is
one or more digit
but not specific.
So
the first
match is
one.
The second
match is
23.
Therefore the
non
specific
digit sequence
are repeated
twice.
Okay, you see that's true. So that
solves the puzzle. We puzzled over it
for like 20 minutes all these examples.
So now we can remove it.
Okay. So,
so that should clarify syntax color show
in browser. Today's talk show notes. Uh
there's a Python example wra language
example
explaining the string match tricky
parts. Now back to our
actual code. So now we want to do this.
So,
so we know regular expression should
work. Now, let's double check on the uh
say hi. Okay, say hi here you guys. Say
hi. Say hello. If you code weren
language before, say hi. If you came
from Python or whatever, say hi. Or if
you are student, say you are a student
something. Or if you are a
mathematician, you know, say something.
So we we back to this advant of code
2025 day two problem one. So it asking
uh range of numbers if they repeat and
also if the digit begin with zero it
doesn't count. Okay. So there's this
digit begin zero. But
is it actually possible to have a digit
begin with zero? Uh let's see the input
search for zero.
No, you know why? Why would it uh let's
see
comma replace comma by comma
new line. Okay, do it. So is there any
actual number sequence that begins with
zero? No, we just look at the input.
So the restriction you see this
particular restriction telling you that
that none of the numbers have leading
zeros is just to prevent you
from generating this sequence by using
strings. So you might get a zero in
front of it just to make sure that's
why. So you know that's that's what it
is the actual so in fact so in fact this
needs not be part of the specification
because
it already says this number these are
sequence range number range. So by
common sense number range does not begin
with the zero. It's not strings. It's a
number range. It's not string range.
Okay. So that is actually redundant. So
that's a criticism of this vein of code.
Sometimes it oversp specify. Sometimes
it underspecify.
So anyway, because none of it numbers
actually begin with zero.
Okay. So we got it. So, okay. Close it.
Close it.
So, what we do now? Yeah. So, we
um
we start to code it. Okay. Let's just
start to code it.
So split input then we then for each
new
input list. Okay.
Uh new input list equals to
map.
So for each of those split input you so
you got a number like that. Okay. So
map a function. So you just say function
uh function that's a string. So you need
to split string again.
Okay. You need to split string this time
by a dash. So you got two
numbers. Okay,
so space string
X is the input. You got two numbers.
Then you say range. Okay, so you just
say range. Um
that will turn it into a sequence of
range. Now that's a shortcut. What this
actually do is I can show you. Okay. So
let's say
um
so let's say 95 to 1115.
So that's one of the number you can see
at the top. So if you run this it's
going to be a list of 95 to 115.
Oh wait this is there should be a uh
comma. Okay. Run it.
You see? So and so what is that add at
add at that is shortcut for apply.
So when you have apply a function
then
uh x can be written as
okay.
So this f add add is just the shortcut
for that. So when you want to write
range so so so this is just shortcut for
um
that. Okay so let's not use the shortcut
because the shortcut people get
confused. So I mean
So let's here range but it's much
simpler you see but if we don't use the
shortcut then it's going to be
apply
apply the range function to
this. Okay. So these two lines are
exactly equivalent. Okay. So,
so now let's make this part into a
little um example here tutorial. So, so
that people can understand.
So in fact if you run this it's going to
return that. Okay they are exactly the
same thing. It's a short uh shortcut. Oh
wait.
Oh wow. Yeah. So if you apply f2x
and if those are symbolic you just get
um
you just get
yeah I'm not going to explain be u well
because it apply to the argument it
doesn't apply to the list so do you see
what I'm saying um
okay nobody's commenting okay So,
so let's uh so let's just put here so
people can see that example.
Uh let's say
3 2
11.
Okay.
Simple example.
Uh and uh what did what did I want to
explain here? Well,
yeah. Okay. So, wait. So
you know so actually this explanation is
not so good because
because the reason it returns that is
actually because range can also take a
list.
Uh no.
Well,
okay. Let me let me let me re let me uh
so this basically when you have apply
f then x the shortcut is actually
f
x
right. No,
no.
Right. So apply applies to the argument,
not the least.
Right. So,
so,
so if you have that then you get f(x).
That's right. So apply this the second
argument and the rest should be
are actually the functions arguments
any anyway let's not let's not
go uh let's not uh be stuck over this
okay
uh the detail
about that thing we can Find
do we have actually have a apply
tutorial apply? Yeah. So there. Okay. Oh
yeah. So the shortcut is add add. Okay.
That's right.
So you can read about that there. Okay.
So but now let's let let me go back to
uh what we want to do.
So what is this? Yeah. Talk show
like keys. Let's add the link there.
Then
then go back to our code. So let's just
write the without the shortcut so it's
easier to understand.
Okay. So we
we map a function to this splitted input
and apply a range. So, so each so we got
a nested list
uh and the result is uh let's
actually so let me show you the result
there.
Okay. So you got that? Then if we do
this, let's make it. It can be one line.
Actually, one line is not so good. So we
then if we do this, you got
list of le. Okay. So you got uh
Oh, you forgot to turn them. You need to
turn string into
uh string into number then you can apply
range. Okay. So here you need a
function. Okay.
Function.
So let's name this y. Okay. Then don't
get confused. Function
range.
Uh
range at
wait. So,
so string split,
you want to turn them into um
strange split. You got two numbers. Uh
you want to turn them into uh
list and two expression
space string
by that
space string. So you got a list of two
strings.
Okay. So here that's what we want.
Yeah. So if we evaluate it
there. So you can see this is the output
and let's format it better.
Okay. So
okay so you can see let's uh put now
this this error let's delete them
okay and and also we can run this in wam
language
select all paste
uh in fact we don't we don't want the
comments okay so
delete so here's the code shift enter.
So you got list of ranges.
Okay. Then what's next? So did we save
the input? Yes. New input list. List of
ranges. Uh list of uh list of list of
numbers.
So
So what is the problem? So you you want
to find in the invalid ids. Okay.
So you can go through the invalid ids
adding up all the invalid IDs.
Okay. So you can apply cases.
Those are numbers. you want to turn them
back to string. Okay, so here is cases.
Okay, let me show you.
Cases return all
cases is like filter. It returns all
elements in a list that satisfies some
pattern.
Okay, we don't want cases. You want uh
select. Okay, select use a function.
cases use a pattern. So select
select is like a filter. Okay. So data
is a list criteria is a function.
Uh so when you do this you apply this to
every number each and every number.
Okay. So let's do that.
So what we can do so let me show you an
example. So for example here uh let's
say let's pick let's pick a list. Okay.
So select
here is that your data then uh then we
want to use our regular expression
function that so criteria criteria needs
to be a function. So function and the
function basically the body will do the
string. So but first of all it needs to
turn this each this number into a
string from number to string. So
do we have two string? Yes. Okay. Two
string x. So here's a function of one
variable x. Then you turn it into a
string. Then you do string match with
this regular expression.
Now if it return true
then that item is selected. Okay. So we
can run this. Let's say let's run this.
You'll filter it out. So there is one
result. Okay. So that's your function.
Now you just want to apply
this select to this entire
new input list. Okay.
So map the all powerful map the map we
want to map to new input list and by a
function the first argument is a
function the function will be something
like like that. Okay
and the third argument uh the third
argument is a um is the level. So so we
don't we we we we want to apply to the
nested list. So that's in level two.
Okay.
Now if you don't know what that is, uh
if you go to my wuam language tutorial
apply the uh then the list section
basics common print string number
boolean list. So introduction to list
the most powerful data structure in UF
language the most important. Then
there's a section on uh level that tells
you the idea about level nested you know
when you have a nested list each element
has a depth. So a specific level of of a
of a data list means specific set of the
elements you see. So this is level one
this is level two. This is level three.
Now in our case, we got this bunch of
nested list. So we want to map each
element. So those are level two. So this
is kind of novel idea. You don't see
this in Python or JavaScript
because they are map only map to level
one. That's it. But in woofer language
you can map to like specific
elements at specific depth of a nested
expression. Okay. So that's what we are
doing here.
So we map this function to this new
input list which is which is you know
the this and uh and uh at level two.
Okay. And then what the function the
function needs to be something like
that. Okay. So we need to say here it
gets complex. Okay. So delete that. So
the function will be
uh so the input will be
x number. Okay. Let's just name it that.
So select
oh actually so this actually so we
so in fact we we don't select we um
let's see uh we can just okay let's re
regroup
In fact, select can be placed on a
uh level. Let's see. Select.
Let's see. Select.
Select. Does it take a level? No, it
just work on flat list. Okay.
So let's not so let's not do this. Okay,
let's just level one use a normal map.
Okay, so uh
this will be number list. Okay, so
that's your input the functions argument
parameter. So that's number list. Then
okay then you you select then inside
that you have a function
string match to string x regular
expression. Okay, that that okay
that's it.
Okay, let's let's try to run this in wra
language. Okay,
select all.
Select all. Paste.
That's our code. Go down. Go down. Go
down. Shift enter.
Fantastic.
So the result is just sum of these.
Okay.
Total
paste.
Okay. Least of unequal length. Okay. So
then we can just say flatten
flatten the whole thing.
Okay. So, 1227775554.
Uh, no, exactly correct.
Okay. Nobody comments it. Okay.
122777554.
Fantastic.
Okay. So, let's just uh then then that's
the result. So let's just say
then total
total at fatten
at
map. Okay, that's our solution. So
is it beautiful?
Uh
okay, that's it.
Um
so that's the code. So let's if you
select or paste shift enter then you got
that number which is the solution. Now
if your input is your user input can we
try that? Yes. Okay let's try that.
So put it back.
Syntax color showing browser. So we got
today's code. Wait, did we?
No, we didn't.
Oh god. So open it. Put it back. Coling
browser.
Yeah. So that's today's code and this
let's move this out so that
uh that's just testing right.
Yeah we let's clean up. We don't need
those.
Okay. So go down. Let's clean up this.
We already solved that puzzle.
Okay. So, here's the code. So, now
put it back. Cut. Paste. Make a copy.
And uh
and search for
input.
Copy that. Close it.
Syntax code.
Then just and just let's
so now the input the new input.
Okay. Select all.
Select all. Paste.
There it is. Let's remove um
let's remove the the the examples so
that
so that you just see the input.
Let's remove the like all the sample
code.
Okay, that's the solution.
Copy all. Select all. Paste. Shift
enter.
Oh, it's taking a while. So,
Anyway, here is the result.
Can we run this in here? Yes. Run it.
Okay. Huge result.
Okay, now we just all we have to do is
just put a
semicolon to suppress the output.
Run it again.
So here is the answer.
Copy it. Go back to advent of code.
Answer.
Paste.
Submit.
That's the right answer. You are one
gold star closer to decorating the North
Pole. Congratulations.
So fantastic. We done.
Is there anyone congratulating me?
Fantastic. Okay. So now let's put the
code back.
Okay. And now let's just do some cleanup
so that this becomes a tutorial for
those learning wam language. Uh yeah. So
here is a stepbystep
output so you can see what's what is
going on.
Uh and this select example let's move it
out so you can kind of see.
Okay. So
let's let's make it you know so this is
clear.
Okay. So thank you guys for watching.
Hope you like it.
We did how long does how long did we
take? One 90 minutes something like
that.
The solution is elegant. We can make
this uh we can like compress this into
one single line like lots of these are
redundant but
and there are alternative solutions but
uh you know we so we are using regular
expression we can you also use string
expression which is wam language's own
syntax for string pattern and then
alternative alternative solution is not
to use any string pattern. You deal with
number directly.
In that case, you you take apart the
digits. You do digit manipulation. Okay.
So, let me write it out. Okay.
So, summary,
we solved the pro the problem
By using
reg
regular expression
we can
also use wra
string
expression
which is basically
alter
native syntax.
Wait, do don't we don't I have like sing
tax
or
regular
expression.
Okay.
Or we can
solve it.
Another way to solve it
is by taking the
digits apart.
Okay. And the wuam language has lots of
functions that takes a number and
returns the list of its digits and do
all kind of man manipulation on the
number on the digits.
So anyway that's it. Thank you guys for
watching. So if you enjoyed my show my
programming stuff go to kasali.info
kasali.info info
http nos and uh go to the bottom pay me.
Okay. Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal.
Okay. Thank you guys for watching. Bye
guys.
[snorts] We shut down in one minute.