good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
today is 2021
november 15th
so
uh
do we have a topic so i'm thinking so
i'm thinking i'm going to this is going
to be a work session
i'm going to work on my saudi website
and lots of to do so you're gonna
learn some coding
uh so
wufang language or powershell so let me
ask you guys a question answer right
away okay
right now uh do you want me to
use wufam language or powershell answer
that question right now
okay so let's go to to do so i'm going
to work on my website uh and lots of
coding it's basically live coding so i'm
going to do basically i'm going to um
let me explain what i'm going to do so
okay so you go to
uh
logo emacs okay
you go to my
emacs blog
so
search for
uh
yeah so you can see
there are a lot of links to xrd.info now
that is fully qualified domain name
fully qualified url okay so you can see
this is a link to uh here's the woofing
language tutorial so let's show in
browser search for
ufram
so i'm blogging you know october 31st
i'm talking about now coded wufang
language for several months now i think
i revert at least opinion
uh you know certain technical details of
about emac lists
uh about emac these symbols okay you you
can read that okay so this is my emacs
blog okay
and on this section i have links to my
wolfram language tutorial for example
click on that
uhfun language tutorial now
go back now before
my emacs blog my practical emacs
tutorial
is
hosted on the website ergoemax.org
but a month ago as you've seen in my
live tutorial i have moved it into
saudi.info you can see in the url so now
it's all on saudi.info
therefore
therefore this link is to a local
it's in the same domain so it's so i do
not need the fully qualified domain name
so let me show you for example
now you see this text block
now by the way on the pink window you
can see all my emacs command call the
command names and all my key strokes
such as moving cursor or any keystroke i
type corresponds to a emacs
command
and you can see the command name there
okay so let me turn on global high line
highlight
mod so you can see my current cruiser
position so anyway so you see this text
block or paragraph now i want to extract
all the urls so i press a key
done you can see the command is html
extract url you if you search that
you'll find the source code probably
or just use
html mod pay me okay pay me and you'll
get it open source
uh so
i extracted you the url in this
paragraph now i go down here paste it
you see fantastic now i can make a link
you see it's a link now oh i can make
the whole thing into a list with local
files linked
okay so do it
there you see it you see fantastic now
you can see
this paragraph and this paragraph are
actually the same
you see it uh well almost the same it's
you know they link to the same file so
but over here it's using uh relative
links so i can press enter to see to
open it show in browser there it is
woofing language syntax in operators
okay back to emacs close this page same
thing for this page
enter to open it show in browser wolfen
language tutorial back to emacs close
that now same thing here except they use
the fully qualified url domain name so
if you if i press enter it's actually
going to the saudi website
so anyway so since
so i want what i want to do
for
2000 files 2000 html files in my
you know in my saudi
domain name so you can see you can go up
you can see this is saudi domain name
now
hide the unix thing the unix crab so
study domain name directory then search
for emacs there's the emacs directory
lots of files hide the unix then this
emax
what you see so 700 files then there is
miscellaneous
200 files so basically
about a thousand files
in this you know about 1000 files
every link
that is linked to
xrd.info using the fully qualified url i
want to change those links into
the related links okay so relative links
like here
and also
you see
change the link text into the title of
the
into the title of that page
okay that is the task now the question
to you guys is that should i do it in
wolfen language or powershell
let's see comments like sorry hey ufo
sounds interesting okay
pajamas says okay
then raghav says what are your thoughts
uh co-pilot okay that's crap okay that's
a [ __ ] co-pilot you know the today's one
of the fad they announced you know
github or whatever they say oh you're
gonna we are going to have a i code code
the code for you that's
crap that's completely [ __ ] okay
that's just marketing
it's not going to do [ __ ]
except it's going to do uh enhanced
completion that's about all it does
okay so let's do wufang language then
two people say sufam language advice q
good morning so okay so let's do firm
language now this is going to be a kind
of big task it's going to take one hour
so before we do that let's have a cold
brew
coffee
enjoy the elite life in america
[Music]
to harmony and prosperity
peace for the world
i injured my finger i talked about in my
past few videos
cold brew coffee supposedly to be better
but i'm not a coffee connoisseur i don't
know the difference
uh so okay so
uufam language okay so this is gonna be
a hard topic uh okay i mean
we're gonna so this this is going to be
a uh live session a work session coding
session live coding session okay
so
so let's write down what we need to do
for each html it's magnify
file in a
now if you have questions comments post
it okay i love to see your comments your
comments gets me
that gets the flow gets the talk show
uh so for each html file in a directory
find all
links of the all links
that uses fully
qualified url
of xsa li dot info
of http
colon slash slash xli.info
change them to
relative link okay
so that is the that is the task okay
showing browser you can see magnify for
html file in a directory okay so let's
go back to emacs
blog so let's show an example copy that
here to do that close that yes
paste it here
and uh
okay let's um let's let's let's let me
just work on this so you can see
the workflow show the pink window so you
can see what i'm doing so you can
see showing browser there are two links
one is the fully qualified domain name
one is relative link
so
example
ex
example okay
where's my
for example
change this
to this okay now show in browser now
it's you see the html is better better
than org mod soft like keys
with great keyboard kinesis advantage to
keyboard this one
this fancy batman keyboard and this is
ultimate hacking keyboard i use it for
macro so marco keypad you see that
new tab close that we don't need that so
you can switch tab backward forward
close it reopen it things like that
and
emacs bookmark jump to xa keyboard blog
you click on here and you go there buy
it okay
now let me mention so kinesis advantage
they are going to have a new
uh keyboard up so a little digression
okay
let me show you
kinesis twitter
javascript is not available okay let's
turn on javascript then you want
information i'll give you information so
kinesis
advantage you know the this maker of
kinesis keyboard this one fantastic my
favorite
they
are coming out next year sometimes next
year with this new
uh model you know after
after now by now uh
20 from 1990 so kinesis
first came out in 1994
something something around there
so after 25 years now they have a new
model so this this is how it looks like
okay
so you can go to their website
uh they you know they have a photo it's
not out yet and i'm going to review it
okay i'm going to give you guys a review
of this new keyboard next year
but now for now you can go buy kinesis
advantage
on you know this model right now they
have a thanksgiving discount 20 or 15 i
forgot and also you can use my
uh code okay
what's the code okay let me let me type
type the code okay so uh digression a
little digression add uh
uh
okay copy the url here paste it
linkify
by discount code discount code okay
xah
okay so you go there you go to the
kinesis advantage website you can give
them a
discount discount code xah and you'll
get 15 percent off or 20. i forgot and
and plus today you know thanksgiving
they have a discount so i'm not sure
my discount applies over the over the
thanksgiving discount but anyway so keep
the comments
in flow okay keep the comment incoming i
want incoming comments
keep it flowing guys six persons
watching not much
okay so
that's about the kinesis advantage
keyboard so they have a new um
yeah so they have a new one so they
let's close that
uh close that so now let's go back
talking about what what we are doing
today so you can see
change this thing to this link but let's
let me do something else okay so let me
show you so i want this i want the i
want the
browser to show the actual html code as
you have seen on this emacs buffer okay
so how do i do that
okay watch
so i add a code
so this is html code you can see showing
browser now it's empty html magnify
magnify let's see the complete beauty of
the font
so now it's empty now
copy that
paste it here okay show in browser
okay that's not still not the source
code so now i do this
do this
there it is now showing browser
you can see now this is the
actual source code
yeah
you see that's what i want to do so
so now we don't need this part anymore
so let's do the same here
so html and syntax code go to the
browser refresh there it is
so change this
link links of this form to this form
okay let's do a wolfram language my god
uh ufam let's begin this is gonna be one
hour
because i haven't done much text
processing tasks
in wufang language let's say one plus
two enter three good
magnify the font
okay wolfram language we're gonna code
this today
so
okay so working session okay there's not
okay so i have to um now i have to think
okay
so
so for every html file in a directory
you want to you know traverse
get every html file's content in that
content open it in that content find
links find all text of this phone you
know you can use a regular expression
then
change it to a relative link okay so
let's
so this this is going to be a walk this
is going to be a lot work
so um
so it's um ufam language okay
okay
let's see uh notes okay
okay so um
any comments questions
how hard is to type on conventional
keyboard after you get to use kinesis
one it's uh same thing there's no
there's no
uh like
stumble i mean what you know so for
there's no there's no i mean once you
learn the kinesis advantage
so
normally you might think okay once i get
adopted to this consensus advantage
keyboard then when i switch to laptop
keyboard or normal pc keyboard i'm going
to be clumsy because the keyboard is all
different no that
actually that does not happen okay that
um
a little bit maybe but for for example
you know because once you go back you
know it doesn't okay so it doesn't uh
happen
that's i mean that's not a concern don't
worry about that what you want to worry
about is
for example if you actually use a
different keyboard layout such as vorack
qwerty comac
then
you might worry about that because once
you adopt
vollrack then you cannot touch type on
quality unless you keep practicing both
similarly for comac walkman and all the
other
keyboard layouts okay that that sense
answers the question now let's get back
to the woofing language coding so let's
focus on this okay
uh wolfram language coding so
you you want to open every directory so
um
coding notes so let's write some kodi
notes okay
what
so you have some coding notes so
let's let's so so how
so
we uh the the directory we want is let's
start to code okay wufang language now
i'm using um let me show you i'm using
wufam language mod in emacs okay there
are there are two ways to coding wufang
language you can use woofan language
notebook
you know you can you can buy mathematica
or you can get a free i talked about
uh just just just um just um
sorry wolfham search for it
you can go to okay so all these are my
websites you know all these are my past
tutorials lots of videos you know about
wufam language so you click on that ufo
language tutorial there's uh you know i
still work on i you know i work i i make
better months of this tutorial every day
so i highly recommend that you know let
me repeat this
watch my past tutorials i've done more
than 10 wolf i'm language tutorials then
you have a wolfram script what it is and
let's turn on javascript so you can see
there is a refresh you can see my past
videos what's the difference between
wolfram engine will find
mathematica uh ufm script and where do
you to download where do you download it
for free you can buy a
raspberry pi it's bundled with raspberry
pi free or you can just download the
wolfram engine free okay and then you go
to the top the home page so i have
tutorials i have several you know lots
of videos some you know many of them
it's not shown here it's on youtube okay
so that's
language
so now we want to for example let's you
know usually i use my own tutorial so in
wolfram script
tutorial section
i have a collection of kind of idioms or
functions that you want to call when you
want to do shell related tasks such as
getting you know traversal directory
find and replace those kind of tasks so
i have collected the function names so
so first of all let me
let's start to code
root okay
rule directory equals to uh uh file path
okay let's so file path questi
let's limit it to emax okay let's get
the
root here so file leak sorry dot info
emacs okay let's just try that directory
okay that's a root directory then
then i want the
function file names okay
so you see i'm coding wufam language in
emacs using some of them mod you know if
you like what i do buy it
support me so let me show you
describe key
press the key for invoking wolfram
language mod then you can see here is
the mod name sao wolf and mod and here
is the source code
press enter to go to it there is a
source code 2
500 lines of code go to the top you can
see there is a url home page
open it showing browser
will find mod search for it you'll find
it and pay me you'll get it okay so
because
coding in wufang language uh it's much
much more efficient when you work in
emacs of course because emacs is
designed for it i mean the woofam
notebook is
allows you to have interactive graphics
and uh play sounds
you know all sort of that i'm not not
going to show it today
so okay wolfen language mod okay so
great go to here
open last closed copy the url back to
emacs go to talk show sas talk show
and paste link
make a note so we have a record of what
we talked about today okay so that's
woof and language mod okay so now
and
close that
copy that already there
so what's uh emacs log okay copy the
emacs blog
paste here
make a record of what we talked about
copy that url
paste it here
and
[Music]
close that go here
copy that back here
conjoin the lists okay show in browser
you can see
here's today's topics okay back to
coding wufong language now
you go to
open this file we were coding that so
so file name
you want
file name takes three arguments okay the
first argument is star h
star html that's a string that means i
want all
star html files okay file names ending
html okay then
the second argument is the path okay
so
put it here
that will list all files in that
directory okay so let's try it in here
you can try it run it
okay uh wrong what what
why is it not showing off
okay file names not file name okay thank
god
file name
oh there's there's a different function
okay so what is uh
so far so what does file name do let's
show
let's go to
[Music]
our file name is actually illegal syntax
wait
but why is it
okay that that's a bug in someone mode
let's fix it
okay
go to the source code
list matching lines list all lines that
contains the word file names okay so
there it is
now why why is there a file name
okay so anyway let's let's go to find
mod
and see so that's illegal syntax yeah
okay file name is there's no search
function file names okay
so you wanna
so how did i get this
uh must be my mistake because um
ufo language functions okay
okay
make a backup
go to the directory go to the directory
you can see
here is all my packages delete the
backup okay here's all my packages so
emacs packages you can buy them again
support me
git
status
git add
git commit
okay that you know we just made a change
to woof iman okay close that close that
close that close that close that okay
now file name file name
snot file name okay
copy the code go back here select all
paste
run it you can see
tons of files
thousands of files okay go to the top
okay so that list files file names then
oh yeah then you want recursively yeah
so because the third argument is how
many levels of directories you want to
go to so if you just say one
how many directories you want to go to
so let's give it uh you can say actually
infinity
let me uh my infinite infinite
infinite future what does infinite
future do
let's look up documentation infinite
future returns a date object expression
representing infinite future in time
fantastic
this is what stefan wufram likes to talk
about how wufang language is symbolic it
has a simple representation of
just about every notion
so
you know that you you have a notion of
future right i mean if
you have the notion of a future so in uh
language you have a symbolic
a symbol or function that represent that
notion
so when you talk about future there's
immed i guess there's an immediate
future and infinite futures
so you got
you know it returns a date object that
you know it returns a date object
expression that represents infinite
future in time so why do you need this
for example when you do
when you compute daytime calculation you
know there's a like
you know tens of uh functions on date
okay date interval date uh absolute time
date winter queue
date within queue date overlap queue so
tens of functions on date
so when you compute with dates just not
not like average typical languages you
know
at most they give you date differences
like
given to date you can calculate how many
days between them that's almost the best
they they can do the most advanced thing
about date they can do but in language
i tell you you have infinite futures so
you you know for free i can tell you for
example time you got date object time
object dating turbo okay so if you click
on date object
it can give you because i was looking at
this yesterday you know let's turn
javascript so we can
see the full glory of the website so
you have date object then you have all
these different formats familiar to most
of you you know date month you know i
iso format and and so forth
but
but then you also have calendars you
have like
all possible calendars
encoded in wolf and language you can you
can do it easy okay
that's a bit digression but you you know
you see from julian date
then you have time series
event series current date
day round unix time from unix time
julian date
from date stream calendar convert okay
like when you specify a date you can say
what calendar yeah i mean even absolute
calendars egyptian calendars and all
that
so you know i you know i was looking at
uh that's the nature that's that's the
nature that's a characteristics of wufam
language they
they embody everything they essentially
that's what they say stefan wolfer likes
to say
it's the it's the you know computing and
knowledge combined you know all human
knowledge all algorithms it's you don't
have to code it yourself there's a
function already does it
so that's a digression okay so let's go
back here so um i want so so here is all
the files
okay lots of digression so let's go this
let's
continue this okay so this is not
infinite future i want infinity
so infinite future infinite infinite
line infinite past infinite plane you
can you can have a plane in geometry you
can you can have a code that represents
uh infinite plane not just uh you know
typically finite
so i want infinity here infinity
if infinity represent the recursion you
know like recurs the directory okay
so now let's say files
equals true okay so so
we got a list of files okay
then
for each file let's see file map okay
for each file we need to do something so
map
there's also file map hey
file system map okay file system let's
see what's the difference
usually you can just do
map two files okay file system app hello
tiago says have you ever tried
sage
yes i have so what do you think about
that's a common frequently asked
questions
sage compared to sage compared to
mathematica sages crap okay the worst
magnitude not just the magnitude you
know if you compare primary languages
let's say haskell or something some some
good programming language pascal closure
julia okay those are
very high quality programming languages
a magnitude better than c c plus plus
okay
f sharp
haskell
julia
closure
you know for example these are the best
languages or you can come skim this if
you want okay
now these space languages compare to
mathematica mathematica is
a magnitude beyond them okay
one line in mathematica equals to 100 or
10 000
or
yeah literally one hundred thousand
lines of these high score whatever
but when you compare sage sages worst
crap okay
that's open source thing that's open
source thing yeah sage is free you know
go download it you know then then you
spend hours trying to do whatever [ __ ]
you know i can show you right now but
it's a
digression you know that's that's that's
why i blame you know i don't that's why
you open source phonetics you don't know
nothing
you know you you yeah anyway so that's a
digression siege
uh
just use uh just
you know if you want you know i
recommend wolfen language but there's a
competitors good you know
competitors to wolfram language to
mathematica for example maple okay
i can recommend you know if if you
really want if you want to be a
mathematician or physicist you want to
focus on your
learning on knowledge on your career to
as a physicist or whatever or engineer
you know like
mechanical engineer chemical engineer
science scientist or engineering not
programming okay if you are an engineer
scientist
you want to
get a tool that helps you do your stuff
focus on your career or whatever
learning okay or solve problems solve
equations
or even matlab okay
i i would even recommend that matlab
then say such crap open source [ __ ]
so you want to focus so
yeah but if you want
if you if if you like open source if you
are open source phonetics you know unix
philosophy unix linux you know open
source titling window managers you know
if you are you know if if you think your
life you know you want to be your open
source proponent open source activist
yeah go ahead
you're gonna you're gonna waste your
life on that you know
with no benefit
do it you know go ahead go ahead try
sage
uh
yeah actually i recommend you try it
yourself try it you know don't trust me
go download wufang engine free go
download sage first of all
try to see
how long it takes for you to start to
write your first line of code one plus
one okay try sage you know download how
long it takes for you to
see what's going on
okay so that's a digression open source
phonetics [ __ ]
idiots
so back to a system map so i want to see
what file system map uh
uh actually do you know at this rate we
cannot finish um
uh
so many digressions at this rate we it
will take two hours for me to finish uh
how long have i been talking uh
15 minutes okay so let's continue
so i want to know now i want to know
what's the difference between file
system map you know normally i would
just say
normally i would just say here's what i
would do okay normally
map a function to files
process
okay
process file okay so this is a function
we have to define process file for
example let's define okay yeah
process file
equals to
a function
okay then
uh
path
file path then
do whatever let's see let's say print
okay
not principal components
print
okay print print path okay
so here is a function definition and i
can then i can
map this function
to
the files you know files is we
files all these files right this is what
i do normally
and here
here
the body of the function we open the
file and find all the links with the
sari.info url and
and find and replace them then
make a backup and save the file that's
what this function will do okay so so we
can we can start to document this
function so process file this is the way
you document it
i believe okay so i um
i forgot what's the syntax so let's go
back to
wolfram language tutorial let's see
what's the syntax for
function documentation so search for
string function okay
so this is my tutorial these two
functions okay so
let's search for documentation okay
let's search for
docs string okay so this is how you
write dot string okay not message usage
okay copy it close that
so this is actually what you want
not message but
usage okay
so
delete that
i'm gonna um documentate document
documenting this uh
process file function
open the file
change all
links to
the
info
change your links to
to auxiliary http colon slash slash
exactly info
to the relative link
and
of
a file at path
and
save
make a back up okay
so that is the that's too big a font so
let's shrink a little bit
okay that's that's the documentation for
the for this function okay let's put the
documentation in front okay
so
now we can map the file so that's
normally normally what i would do
map this function to all these list of
files but what is the
file system map let's look
okay final system map
f root okay gives a
gives an association whose keys are the
names of files in root
okay association which is a hashmap okay
which
in python is called dictionary so
or in perl ruby is called a hash table
so it returns a hash table
or dictionary whose keys are the names
of files in root
okay so the keys is the file name
in that root
directory and whose values are the
result of applying f
to the full names of these files
okay so f will returns
something okay
okay anyway it returns a hash table
that's not what we need
uh that's okay that's not what we need
map is what we need okay map
so you know right now we can actually
run the code so select all paste it
let's uh that's too big okay
that
that will actually um you know
you see that will um
that we that you know that just prints
the file path okay
so you see um
yeah it prints a lot file path it just
prints them
and
[Music]
so why is the slash in backslash there
see
yeah it returns no because
when you print the function returns new
okay it just printed but it the return
value is no so let's go back here
so actually so let's not say print let's
say
the path let's get the file name part of
the full path okay so how do you do that
go to
wufang language tutorial go to wolfram
script tutorial
so you have list files current directory
dd directory check
check if it's a file or directory
check file directory existence
directory path file name file existence
file extension okay that's what we want
so we want
file base name okay so this is a
function file base name
so instead instead of print here
we want file base
base name okay
okay so copy that
select all paste it
okay put put put the semicolon here okay
copy that
select or paste it run it
fantastic now you just got at least the
file names you see
now it's just all these the file names
you see
fantastic now we are getting closer
okay now open now
open file
you know one of the big one one of the
tasks you know we
the way i code is that i logically
dissect
the problem
so now we have basically the the
structure
now
we need to refine the process file
function so what we will do
first of all it needs to open a file get
the file content okay so how do you open
the file get the file content
so there is a
tutorial here
get file date
date and time
okay file size print file content there
it is file print okay but except i don't
want to print i want just the content so
read string
there it is read and get file content
so
okay read string now let's look at the
documentation press the key you'll jump
to it show the ping window
reads the complete contents of a file
and return it as a stream so
yeah so
so you can give it a fire path here
okay so we are refining our function
here
now here is the function body
now we want let me show you something
else okay module
okay so what does what modules do
module is this module function is a way
to create local variables so in this
that is called let
in commonly scheme this emac this you
have the function let
the purpose of that is for you to
declare local variables
so in language
that's module okay so we can put the
code here
so module so you want to so what local
variables we want uh
file content okay
okay file content then you can say file
content equals to
restring
okay so in fact you can define here you
can define it in one shot okay
firebase name we don't need
so file content so now we got the file
content okay now you want to do find and
replace
oh my god this is gonna take long time
this is gonna take another hour
uh find replace okay so am i doing good
how many people are watching
the paucity of talk show nobody is
watching six
say something
so
so now we want to do find replacement
okay
now write to file
okay so there's several things need we
need to do this these are the things we
need
write string right to file
okay
comment it out and string replace we
will need soon
but right now we need to
yeah string replace actually we need
string replace
so content so string replace
the first argument is a string
right so
string
okay the second argument is the part you
want to replace now before we do
replacement we need to know
before we do replacement we need to know
for example with excel talk show
let's go to talk show
your explanation so far is excellent
thank you
thank you for the yeah
for the comment so
you see we want to replace let's magnify
okay so we want to replace text of this
form
by this form
and
so first of all we need a regular
expression to match that
once we found the match
we need to generate the relate relative
link
now in order to generate a relative link
you need a path directory of what
relative to what is it you know relative
to
so you need the current file path
so let's write down what we need to do
so
wait what
so you know my in my wolfram
mod i don't have
i don't have the indentation uh so
so what we need to do we need
need
current file path
current file directory because we need
to calculate the relative to the
to the directory
then
current
current h ief value okay current i
current rh
current hief value
should be the that domain name
you know that full domain
path okay
so we we get the current
so this is actually fairly complex so we
get the full domain name
we need to turn the domain name into a
local full path okay
then then we can calculate the relative
path okay
uh
convert
domain
path to
local to
full file path okay that's what we need
to do
okay so there are things we need to do
so
so there are several things we need to
do here um
you know my my my emacs
my exactly woofer mod is you know
there's no
um
no um
indentation so it's hard to read so
let's go back to wolfram language copy
or paste it so now here you can see much
better
um
yeah but then but then you know the
comments got screwed up
let's try it again yeah it doesn't work
okay so
you know com comments in wolfram
language is
problematic because it ignores all the
line breaks and and then that
okay so but
[ __ ]
let's do this okay
select or paste
okay that's a little bit better
so let's do it one that one one thing at
a time current file path we already got
this is the that path okay let's change
it to full path
okay so that's a one that's current file
path
let's rename again let's say current
file path
so now we have the name current html
file path why do i use the elaborate
name because later on it's going to be
fairly complex because you have the
current file path confounder
href
stream value stream the domain name then
the file path of that domain name so you
need the names to be
clear clarify them
so current the let's so how do you get
the current directory so how do you get
the current directory so let's see
um wolfen language tutorial so what is
this to do close
so wolfram
script tutorial
yeah we don't want that
uh oofam script local file yeah so how
do you get the current directory so
i mean not that you want to get the
directory part of a full path okay here
um
file name drop okay
file name
drop
okay
actually
we got
okay actually all these things should be
inside module
so
it should be all here so
so file content okay file content then
the path
current path
okay so that's how you get current
directory path
so current file path we have current
file directory path we got
then current
current href value so
just joined in
okay so we are coding yeah so let's see
module is a local
variable so these are the local
variables so we got the file content
we get the file content current
directory path we got the current
directory path
then you got a you need to have a
current href value so how do you do that
so now you need to do find and replace
so okay so
so the actual part is the find replace
string replace
string replace replace this text
this string
so now now you need a regular expression
now you need we need a regular
expression to represent
[Music]
these um
these things so let's
let's
so there's a lot to do
so we need a regular expression to
represent this so how do you do that
yeah
now i haven't i haven't used wolfram
language uh regular expression before
now let's go back to so let's go back to
woofam script tutorial
uh find replace okay so where do you
find the documentation for regular
expression let's clean up the code a
little bit
so you look up
you look up the function documentation
for replace string
string replace okay
then
then it will point you to
uh regular expression documentation in
language yeah let's do it quickly so
wolfram language
string pattern
they support
two
methods
to have to to represent more than two
methods to represent a pattern in stream
one is regular expression
just like every other language golan
javascript python pearl
or
bash grep
you know you regular expression you are
familiar with but they also support
their
symbolic pattern matching based syntax
to represent
patterns in string which is
i haven't looked into detail but i
believe it's far more powerful than
regular expression because it can
represent string patterns that involves
nesting
regular expression by definition by the
original you know automata you know
linear grammar definition of the history
of regular expression by the
very definition of regular expression
it is
designed to
match
patterns that's only linear
linear languages no nesting so regular
expression is this you know that's why
it's called regular expression if you
have a language whose syntax involves
nesting such as lisp or any kind of
brackets
then
that's not
you know the the language you use it's
not it's called not regular not regular
i mean
something like that i forgot the detail
i might get the jargons wrong but anyway
that's what regular expression is for
for linear languages only no nesting so
when you have nested syntax such as
parent or bracket you cannot or html you
cannot or json you cannot use regular
expression to
you know to to get to match them
it's only good for matching linear
grammar
so wufang language supports regular
expression let's let's look at some of
them instead of me just talking
the superfine language supports regular
illustration but they also support
wolfram
uh symbolic pattern matching based um
pattern okay so the syntax is obviously
different so there are so many
documentations so let's begin here okay
uh there it is so you see
this page is a guide on string patterns
now this page is talking about what i
was talking about string expression so
this is a more generalized um
string pattern
you know more far more powerful than
regular expression so they show you what
the syntax here is
now i never used this before so let's
not use this let's go to regular
expression here okay so before we do
that let's copy that go to talk show
good morning west
uh and go to talk show and paste some of
the
um
documentation here we talked about okay
so click on regular expression copy the
url back to emacs show pink window paste
it here linkify
combine them into a list showing browser
so
here
ah
mobile debug they don't update the url
let's refresh now okay now the url is
correct [ __ ] vavaldi we we talked about
that yesterday
so let's do that showing browser so you
can see
there's a link to string patterns then
there's link to regular expressions they
are all patterns of a string but one is
the traditional regular expression so
now click on regular expression
so this is how you represent regular
expression in language now this regular
expression i know so well so i don't
need to read the documentation for it
let's just go to it
so let's start to write very regular
expression here
okay
so
the bracket
then
what is the
what is the pattern you are trying to
match the the pattern we are trying to
match is this okay
copy that
okay so
let's
so the pattern we are trying to match is
this okay so
um
so let's do it one thing at a time so
ignore the
ignore the link text let's just focus
focus on on replacing fixing the
domain name okay so here's the pattern
so let's copy that pattern
now we need to escape the quote because
we need to put a quote outside of it so
there is a key
there it is okay now put a quote on the
whole thing cut it
now
put it here
okay
so here is the pattern now
now that's not
done yet okay so here over here it's
gonna be
you know let me let me let me show you
okay let's copy that
let's uh copy that here so
so here is going to be
[Music]
anything
anything and capture it
okay
any character
that is
not
double quote okay
one or more okay
yeah
so we want to capture this pattern you
know that begins with
a href equals to then quote http info
then whatever
then
up to
up to the double quote okay that's the
cap that's the
that's what we want to capture then the
file access date we also need to capture
okay so we need to
the date okay so we need a date for
we need a regular expression
[Music]
syntax to capture the iso format update
okay so let's do that
so i already have a shortcut
date
t so that is the
you know that's the emax agree if you
haven't learned emacs of brief you
should okay so just search for exactly
emacs a brief so for example i can show
you right now so search for date
so
there it is you see that line
that so i just type date t that expand
to the regular expression for the iso
format date
okay
so we got this date now this state needs
to be placed here
okay
so that let's double check now we don't
want the
we don't want the backslash
parentheses because that's e max thing
that's the emax
toothpick syndrome you don't need the
backslash before parentheses
yeah because in regular expression
parenthesis
means capture in python ruby javascript
golan
java
all languages
except in emac list
parenthesis is literal so you want if
you want to capture you need the
backslash in front in fact you need two
two of them because backslash by itself
is is a meta character so
emac regular expression emac circuit
expression is a pain yes
so anyway so we got the date
pattern
uh then
then let's remove that okay so that's uh
that's our regular expression okay
cut it
let's go back here
let's go back here now the replace
string there it is so replace string
takes two argument
then
the second argument is first is going to
be a regular expression
and and then you need a return i mean
the replacement string so replacement
string will be
okay the replacement string
will be
um you know and i know regular
expression well
the replace
okay here's a complexity the replace
string
needs to be computed
because
the regular expression captured the
domain name but now we need to convert
that domain name
to a full
file path
then we need to con convert that full
file path into a relative path
so we cannot
we cannot have a replace string right
here so instead of we need a function
in order to do that i need to look up
how to
um
yeah so this is actually the problem is
not so simple
god i think i'm gonna stop
gonna
chicken out and stop here because
yeah because now
in order to do this what i have to do
now is first to
you know we are gradually getting closer
but
in order to do this i need to first of
all write a function that returns that
takes a domain name returns a full path
okay so i um
so let's let me just put in a template
a function
that takes a domain
url
change it
to
local
file full path
and change it to
relative path
and return
that here okay that's what we need to do
so
copy the whole thing go back to the
woofing language
from notepad
select all paste it so maybe you can see
better the
so far our code
again the task is the task is about you
know i said you know it's mentioned here
for each you know anyway you can read it
so back here so now we need to
write a a bit digression uh like a small
job write a function
write a function let's let's write it
okay so
write a function
let's write it here okay
domain
url
to
relative
path okay
takes a url
return let's write two functions okay so
the name url to full path okay
return
a
corresponding
file
full path
okay that's one function
now we need to write another function
get relative path okay this is already
probably building
so relative path
take a full path and return
a
relative path
okay now it takes two arguments one full
path one
the path okay return a relative path
a full path relative to
the path
okay so we need to write these two
functions so let's write the first one
so the first one
function
argument
x
path
body
what the body will be okay so the body
will be
replace string okay
string replace okay the body will be
not stream repeat
okay string replace
okay stream replace uh
the first argument is a path
the second argument is
okay
let's
clean this okay
so string replace the first argument the
string you want to replace that's a path
then
then you want to
replace by regular expression whatever
that
okay not even regular expression you
want to replace
http
just delete that okay we don't need that
so replace this part by
there okay
so let's see
so again
woofer mod doesn't have indentation i i
need to
you know so the code is hard to read
okay copy the whole thing back to woofam
notebook paste it so you can see we
defined this function domain url to file
path and we defined it here
this is the docs string
okay so let's see function path take
function takes a path and do a string
replace
okay replace path by
use a regular expression actually we
don't need regular expression it's just
a string
okay so not not regular expression
just a string okay
copy
paste
okay so
yeah so that
let's let's run it see if that works
okay oh wait
yeah okay i don't know what the code is
doing this is the interim code you know
so anyway but that we can take we can
test this function by itself so let's
try it
let's
try to call this function
and give it a path oh yeah sorry dot
info
okay hold on a second so copy that
okay so
domain url to file path
now
let's see
for example this is our domain
i mean this is a
domain name
uh wait
for example that's a file it should it
should return a file path let's do it
fantastic
is it correct
yes
yep that's fantastic so we verify this
function works at least
okay so
um do that okay so this function works
now we need to um
now let's write a function that
gets relative path so
given a path file full path you want to
you want to get the relative path now
that function
is already built in so let's just look
look at my
uh ufam script tutorial
so you want to find the relative path
search for it
there it is
expand file name okay that's not
uh okay where is related path
file name take file name drop expand
file name
you want to
given a full path
and given a directory
you want to get the relative path
yeah okay so i don't know
so regular expressions let's so let's go
to
close that let's go to find
documentation
read stream
date object let's copy that to our talk
show because we didn't before
there
okay
so restrain date object document not
found um
[Music]
you now i need the relative path so how
do you find the building function for
relative path
what are we doing are we
sure
yeah we given a full path
and given a directory
you want to find the related path okay
so
we so right now we need to find the
function
so to find a function all you have to do
is to find a
sum function related related to file
so
because then or you can just go to the
wolfram
[Music]
uh not there
documentation center
graphics math functions images knowledge
representation sound and video
graphs and networks graph theory
symbolic and numerical computation
no data manipulation no core language
okay machine learning maybe in code
language text and string
okay maybe there click on that
wait system operation and setup okay
let's say text and string stream
manipulation working with templates
uh text manipulation text analysis okay
now we we what we want is uh functions
related to file manipulation so
um core languages
parallel computing external operations
import export file names there it is
external operations
okay
then file names okay
here
then you go down
then there's related guide file
operations okay then files okay let's
click on files
read string right string
read the content of the file uh read
byte import export release find these
file names
uh read write read line find get put
we need relative path okay file names
okay that's not here remote file okay
go back
now let's see file operations
rename file delete file
absolute file name
click on that
you know the easiest way is actually to
search
relative just type in relative
related path there it is
oh wait this is uh
this is one of the library
yeah
so this one
you know wufong
library
you know in typical programming language
libraries per python java's
per python java ruby a library
is usually
a bunch of functions
but in wufan language they have a more
refined notion
so you have a single function as a kind
of library so they call it wolfram
function repository
so
they also have libraries but but you
also have one single function function
repository
so i can right now i can you know
act you know i can call this remote
function by
you know but um but i don't like that
because
so anyway this function related path is
contributed by a wolfram research
a programmer at wolfram research i don't
know this guy richard hendergan
so i i would trust this code but however
i can write it myself you know i can
write it myself i don't want to
use um
but in any in any case i don't think you
need a
external function i'm pretty sure it's
building
it's just that
what's our search result let's go back
okay
let's go back search result
i would be very surprised
if the related path function is not
built in in some shape or form
at most you'll just require like two
function calls something like that
hello science friends hello alan hello
uh
you know i think i'm gonna shut down
it's um
this coding problem is
fairly tedious i think i'm going to shut
down so it's been an hour now
wait uh how long has it been
an hour and 20 minutes
so right now we are trying to find how
do you get the relative path
in language
well
the
very existence of this function in
repository that probably means
this function is not building i'm i'm
amazed i'm
yes i'm amazed about i'm surprised by
this
so
but however this function can be written
[Music]
in just you know two lines of code one
line one single line of code
so i'm i want to write it myself i'm not
going to
you know use a cloud or import it
so but
before we write it you know it's pretty
simple you know
it's very simple
but
can we look at the source code of this
uh is there a
source called
detail and options okay examples example
notebook
source notebook oh you can actually
[Music]
yeah there it is so you can actually see
the source cover there it is
um
yeah i'm not gonna use it and you know i
can i can define it better
let me show you how i i mean that's a
stupid remark i shouldn't say that
but
but you know um
okay i i don't want i don't want to look
at it okay so let's let's
okay so let's
let's do this let's write a relative
path function and and that'll be it for
today okay
so let's write a related path function
and that'll be it today so
so relative path you're gonna write the
function now
equals to
function
okay
then the function argument is a two
arguments okay the first one is the full
path
the second one is the path
okay
then
what is the body
so here is the body of the function
now
so we're gonna write this function but
but before we do let's go back to um
let's go back to some saudi website so
we get a sense of the
path arguments so for example here is a
path
uh
so for example that that's my um let's
use a
let's use the emax block path okay
okay so now let's open that and let's uh
go to some other path okay let's see
this one okay
okay so that's the example of true paths
now
so
example weight
example of a path
example of input path
example of the
okay
the relative to okay
result
result should be
let's see what the result should be
the result should be
so this path really himself so
so that should be the result should be
right so this is uh
input path relative to
to that
okay
so the result should be
dot dot
dot dot okay
yeah so here is the result okay
yeah
so given that
in the directory the result should be so
what you do is you
body moment what
what is body moment
so what is the algorithm to get the
relative path actually thinking about it
i don't think i've ever coded this
because in emaclis in python in perl
in golan i don't know about golem but
python pro emac lisp they all have a
building function that returns a
relative path
so
so anyway so
yeah so i don't think i've wrote this
before but anyway so given the path and
given a directory
you want to return a path that's related
to the directory
so what you do first of all
is to
subtract sub subtract
the same
beginning part of the string
uh yeah
okay so let's write down the
so notes
so
find a common find a string that's a
common beginning of full path in the
path
okay that's a one of the first thing to
do
then
then you have to count the slash in
the path okay
common root that's a string
so level root is a count slash in common
root okay
then
level the path
is current slash in the path
and level
input path
okay
level input path is kind of slashing the
full path
i'm getting distracted it's taking long
time and now i'm losing
okay so what do you do what what am i
doing with all these uh slashes okay so
you want counter slash
so you count the slash then
example of a directory
oh god now i want to look at the source
code
it would be much faster if i just look
at the source code
um
okay let's
i want to finish this
i hope too
uh but okay so i have to think first of
all i have to think so
so the input path
so the example of input path
so let's not name it full path
input path they are all full path okay
example of input path
example of the path okay
so input path for example equals to
the for example equals to
the results
for example equals two
and this is the example algorithm notes
okay so
so input path the path
so given directory
so given so if the
if the input path is a subject
subdirectory
of the the path
then
obviously
the relative path
is whatever
the input path minus the path
okay that's one idea
then just
input path minus
okay that would be the answer
now if input path
if
now
the other case if the input path is the
[Music]
no obviously not
so the input path
so input path is a sub directory okay
now if they are the same directory
now if input path
and the path
are the same
the
then
then result
is file name of just the file name part
of the input path
okay
wait uh
okay that's one case
that's the second case
now if the input path
now the third case
if the directory path is a scepter of
input path
then
then there is problem then you need
to add dot dot slash to
get
to the
same
level
as
input path
then
add the best of input path okay
that's essentially the algorithm
the algorithm okay so this
these three these three cases
you know
basically we we we want to count that's
why we are counting the level
of uh
of the
so let's rewrite this part okay so
input path
level
com slashes okay
so we need
the path level
okay count the slashes
then
[Music]
level
difference
equals to
minus
okay so we know the
level difference then
then we can then we can find out which
case is what
ah i think i i'm gonna i want to stop
now because now it's gonna
longest common subsequence that's uh
is that a wufam language function
what is this
safari
no that's not a wolfram language
function but
oh there it is
longest common subsequence find the
longest continuous subsequence of
elements common to strings
biomolecules sequences yeah okay that
yeah that can work actually you know i'm
getting tired and i'm getting this
problem it's not solved
but um
we talked almost like 90 minutes in two
hours i think i'm gonna stop
uh github co-pilot is no good okay
that's a marketing crap
i talked about earlier i commented
yeah too long i gotta go i have to go in
you know i have to go in today i gotta
uh learn some errands so that's it for
today the working session in kind of
incomplete so let's close in five
minutes let's summarize what we did
today
so let's uh
make the code clean let's clean up clean
up our code
so that we have a nice summary of what
we did today okay so copy that
copy that
text processing using woofam is for the
brave actually i think it's uh
very good
uh you know
wolfham language for text processing
it's just that i haven't
used it to do that so this is what the
code we did today
let's double check if the yeah so this
is a algorithm
comments what we need to do so actually
um
so the movem command is a little problem
let's do it again select or paste
yeah wolf i'm common they just uh
you know there's no line break unless
you
unless i add line break myself
let's see
select or paste
did we actually run the line break
result equals to
no it does not respect the line break
yeah that's common you know that's who
i'm comment because
and if you
call them into standard form or whatever
it it actually remove the comments for
you it just removed the comments so
so the comment in wolfram language is
actual real comment i mean like
it's basically ignored ignored and when
you reformat the code it delete them for
you
so wolfham common is not reliable
i mean it's not persistent the comment
in the wolfram language
so
anyway that's digression i've been
trying to find some other way but i
don't think there's another way
but anyway so
here's our code so let's
remove that here
syntax code
show today's talk show
so that's what we talked about today
show it
this is the problem we set out to do
and we did not complete
and so far our code is like that
we have code to
get all files in a directory of html
files
we have
shown how to write a inline
documentation
how to write a function
how to do string replace
yeah this worked
and how to
uh and how to
you know open the file read the contents
and how to
you know get the directory path of a
full path
uh how to use regular expressions
we also explain how to
you know you have
more advanced string patterns than
regular expression
uh yeah that's what we talked about but
we have not finished coding this
task
yeah that that task is actually not not
easy to do because i've done that in
emac list let me show you
you know
it takes
half a day
of these today's tasks because
the you know
then you need to get file name of a file
of the html title of the file
you know it's a bit involved because
the com the
the heart of the complexity is that for
thousands of files html files you open
each one of them
and for every file
you
check using a regular expression for
every you know you check the form once
you got it you want to replace it
and you cannot directly represent the
replace string because you need a
function to compute
compute the domain name in order to do
that you need the current
file it's processing
you know
conceptually it's not too complicated
but it actually takes a whole day to
code it half a day or quote the whole
day
so let me show you my
emacs this code for example let me show
you my emac this code so go to where do
we go to so let's go to a cassar
directory
so let's see so one of these
no not that one
okay let's go to to do okay show in
browser go back here
see
so let's uh search for xx
yeah so it's in emacs package okay so
it's this code okay
uh wait is it
because html no no it's not that one
okay let's go back to casa brief let's
go to sign in it
then search for
site there it is
okay
emacs site
site map site
site move
this file okay
let's open it yeah this is the file so
this this file is written in 2012
when i did a massive
migration of my website into different
domains i split saudi.org
7000 html files into six domains
so when you do that you move thousands
of files into different directories then
you need to recompute all the
relative links depending on whether they
are in the same domain
if they are in the same domain then you
just use relative links if they are in a
different domain you need to use fully
qualified url with domain name in it you
know http
slash
blah blah blah
so this emacs script is written in 2012
when i did that
and it's working
but over the years something broke you
know so this is only you know 250 lines
something broke you know and it took me
a long time it actually took
took me a month a week or a month to
write this because
in when doing this there's a lot
complexities
uh so anyway so here's the emacs code
the
you know so
that does
basically what we are trying to do today
um
and you can run this
script
by giving it a list of files like
thousands of file names where they are
moving from and moving to
and run the script you'll change you'll
fix the links automatically
so this is actually much more complex
than
what we are doing today for example
this is a very old this is agent so for
example this line
that means there's two parts the first
part is the original file path
so this is the file path
bad girl thumbnail bad girl drawing
and the second part is the where it
moved to
so you have the origin
file path and destination file path then
this script will move the file and fix
all the links in that file
a very
involved
code
so here is a function
site fix html links you know takes a
host file path
move from to list
from
moved from path
and right to file
okay that's it bye guys