Morning. Welcome to another episode of S
talk show. We are going to do I'm going
to explain JavaScript object system.
Okay. So, can you see my screen? Yes.
JavaScript. Okay. So, let's show my
page. JavaScript the object system. It
is a fantastic wonderful simple system.
But however because JavaScript tried to
become Java to look like Java and
therefore it become completely screwed
up and very complex. So you got keywords
like new you know new object instance of
this keyword prototype property and
constructor property
uh uh prototype key. Yeah property.
Yeah. So it becomes extremely complex to
this day. And then in 2015 they created
the class keyword which you know they
are trying to help the situation but
actually completely made it worse. Okay.
So that is today's topic. I'm just going
uh to explain that. If you are watching
this offline play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble a lot. Uh if you are watching
here live say hi. Hello Sarath.
Sarah, is that uh are you a guy or a a
girl? Okay, so let's talk about
JavaScript. Okay, so JavaScript object
system, you know, a short history,
JavaScript is created in
1995 when I basically when I started
coding coding in 1994. Uh okay. So
created it. So I watched it grew up
along with
HTML. JavaScript, Java, Java was also
born in 1995, 1994. Java language and
Ncap the browser the internet the entire
internet grew up uh starting around that
time uh and CSS wasn't born yet. CSS
cascading stylesheet was born
uh around 1997. Okay. And it wasn't it
wasn't practical until uh 2002 let's
say. So CSS you know so so anyway. So
JavaScript object system is very simple.
Okay. So it's called prototype based
system and it is based on the language
is modeled after the language called
self. Okay. I don't know that language
anyway. So how it works? What it is is
that you have a object. So first of all
what is object? What object is uh kind
of like Python's dictionary or Ruby's
hasht or JavaS map object or uh you know
so it's also known as dictionary hasht
or map sometimes known as association
list. Basically it's a collection of
items. Each item is a pair a key and
value. Okay. And this this pair is
called property. So again in JavaScript
a object is a collection of properties.
Each property is a key and pair a key
and value pair.
Okay. So that is object. So you you know
if you code in uh Python it's you can
think of it as a dictionary. Okay. So
JavaScript object is kind of like
Python's dictionary collection of pairs.
Now um now but however in JavaScript you
have the prototype based object system
meaning that every object any object may
have a parent associated parent. Okay.
So you got one object it may have a
parent. So this is a daddy of that
object and that object can also have a
parent. So you got the daddy you know
like ancestry you know chains of dead
daddies. By the way, this is called
prototype chain. Okay. So anyway, any
object can have a parent, a dad, and
that object can also have a that and so
on until then you have the root
object. But it is not necessary every
object always have one parent. Okay?
Some you can create object that has no
parent at all. So for example, the root
object no doesn't have any parent. So
JavaScript in JavaScript objects may
have a parent. Okay. And only one
parent, you know, dad or, you know, call
it mom. So only one parent. So you got
kind of the object tree. Okay. So and
anytime you can change you can you can
set the parent to be some other object.
You can do that anytime or when you
create object you can say okay I'm
creating object and this other object is
my parent. You can specify that when you
create object. Okay? Or you can change
it anytime anytime you want and anytime
you can add a property you know remember
object is a collection of key value
pairs. Each key value is called a
property. So at any time object has lots
of properties you can add at any time or
remove it. Okay. So very simple. So you
have uh functions to change the parents
or create a object when you specify a
parent. You can add properties or you
can remove properties all very simple
and function and works. Okay. So if you
want to understand that by the way I
have a JavaScript inepth tutorial
written um written starting in 2005. So
that's like 20 20 years ago. Uh so I
read the spec version of spec I spend
like a lot of time writing this okay
JavaScript in depth and uh so if you
want to understand the prototype based
object system in JavaScript you can
there's a section okay prototype and
inheritance okay very
simple so you can you know you can you
know you can the prototype chain you
know you know parent of object and the
parent of that object and uh you know
and you can you can query what is the
parent of this object you know get the
parent or you can set the parent change
the parent to be some some other object
okay uh so anyway anyway so very simple
okay or or when you create object you
can say you know my parent is this this
is how you do it you know object equals
to objectreate and you specify a parent.
Okay, that's how you create a parent.
One of the way to specify a parent
object very simple. Okay, so it's
fantastic. So that is the basis that's
the entire basis of
JavaScript object system. Okay, but
however that's you know this this is
great. This is all you need. In fact to
this day today's JavaScript doesn't
matter it's a Google Amazon you know any
JavaScript you code is based on this
prototype based system okay that's all
you need create object set parents add
properties or remove remove properties
okay but
however the JavaScript language became
much more complex than
that so we come down to you know history
of JavaScript
constructors and class complexity. Now
remember before when we talked about the
prototype based object system there's no
mention of class because there's no such
there's no such concept in
JavaScript even today there's no such
concept okay but however you know back
in
1995 there is there was this language
called Java okay Java is meant to be a
competitor with C++ so Java is
originally it's a very heavy language
you know it's requires a you know like a
a real programmer you know you needs to
be heavily invested writing originally
JavaScript is designed for writing
embedded systems such as you know the
code in your microwave in your mouse in
your keyboard in in TV in anything in in
your you know you know or or in space
satellite whatever
Java. Okay, Java is created created
around
1995. It's a competitor to
C++. So C++ was very popular even today
and also back then. So there's new
language Java. We're going to challenge
C++. We're going to you know and Java
Java the slogan was write it once run it
everywhere. So anyway that's Java. Okay.
So Java was created by the corporation
called Sun Micro Systemystems. It was a
big
corporation. It died in around 2006.
Oracle bought it. Any Anyway, that's
history. So back in 1995, Semicro
Systemystems created Java by the guy
named James Goslin. Very interesting guy
by the way. He's also one of the
original creators of Emacs. Okay, James
Gosling his, you know, one of the or
original first Emacs is by James Gosling
and he accuses Richard Storman stole his
code part of it. So James
Gosling is the founder I believe he's
the founder one of the you know founder
of Smicro Systemystems or was it he
original founder? I forgot but he's a
big you know CEO uh CEO or tech tech guy
semicrosystem and he created Java the
language okay so it's a Java is this
huge language you know so it's for in
industry use it's heavy you know heavy
uh duty language Java
uh so Java you know 1995 some micros
system you know trying to advertise it
they spend millions, you know, millions
of dollars. And then, you know, the web
began, you know, the Netscape back then,
the the browser, there's only one, like
almost only one, Netscape, the browser.
So, they collaborated with some micros
systemystems. They, you know, they say,
why don't you include Java in your
browser? Okay. So, they agreed, you
know, but then also, but at the time,
they also are creating JavaScript. So,
so why are you creating JavaScript?
Because back then the HTML is static,
you know, nothing like today. Today you
go to, you know, it's like interactive
JavaScript. So back
then most HTML are written by like
non-coders like you can you just type
these tags and showing a website. So
they want some kind of
interactivity to you know to manipulate
you know the HTML so it becomes dynamic.
So for example the first thing you can
do uh let me show you the first thing in
JavaScript that you have is let me show
you some example the first few examples
in JavaScript.
Okay. So, one of them is
um is this
uh image row over. Okay. So, do I have
that somewhere here? There you see
that's a image you mouse over it becomes
different background. That's the one of
the first JavaScript made thing uh back
in n late 1990s. Okay. It's like
everywhere. The other very popular thing
so that's dynamic HTML you see without
JavaScript without you know with just
HTML you cannot have like this you can
but then you you send it to server is
you know too slow so image rollover is
one of the first thing in JavaScript you
know kind of the
effect and the other thing is this uh
raining effect. Okay. So, let me show
you.
Um, so boom image roll over. Okay.
Stopwatch uh fader elements snowing
effect. Okay. Like
that. So, you see all these things
falling down. So, this is around year
2000. You'll see you know some website
have this uh so this is JavaScript you
know that that's like the cutting edge
back at the time. So anyway, JavaScript
was created to be
um to be to allow HTML to be dynamic and
it's supposed to be a simple scripting
language for those people who just write
simple HTML. They are not really most of
them are not professional programmers
back then. They are called web monkeys.
Okay, web monkeys like they know some
technical you know thing like you know
the tag or markup but they are not
actually programmers like C or C++ they
are more
like designers and writers you know they
or scientists you know scientists are
not programmers at least back then you
know scientists they they they you know
they research rocket science or physics
or mathematicians
they don't know how to code you know
they don't know how to write you know
Java or C++ or C you know so but the web
at the time there's a lot scientists and
engineers they need to talk so they
write HTML you know so you can that's
original purpose for scientific
communication
HTML so anyway 1995 there is this Java
programming language going on and then
you know they want they they are
creating a JavaScript language for the
browser so it can be interactive. So
Java is a heavyduty programming language
competitor to
C++. JavaScript is designed to be like
easy for nonprogrammers. Okay. So 1995
they they you know they collaborated
with some micros systemystem to have
Java bundled in in browser. So they
thought they thought you know it would
be a good idea to um make JavaScript
look like Java so that you know it feels
like they are together you know because
JavaScript was originally named Mocha.
Then it was named
Livcript you know before it was like
Livcript is in the in one of the beta
version of of Netscape browser. So they
wanted them to be kind of similar. So
they they they tried you know one of the
goal is like you have to make JavaScript
look like Java and kind of like you know
similar to Java. Okay. So they did that.
So that is a big mistake. Okay. Because
the
JavaScript programming language which is
modeled on the self you know programming
language you have this prototype object
system you know like we talked about
object has parents. You can change it
anytime, you know, and you have
inheritance, meaning that whenever you
look up a object's property, if the
object doesn't have that property, it'll
try to look up that object's parents to
see if that has that property. If it
does, then it's good. If it doesn't, it
tries to look up a that object's parent
again to see if that has that property.
Okay? Until you reach a parent that has
no more parent. Okay? And if you don't
if you didn't find any property of that
name then you don't have that property
otherwise you know it looks up. So this
is called inheritance that's what it
means okay inheritance. So you got this
prototype based system fantastic and
simple but Java the language they have a
classbased object system. You know this
is typically known as objectoriented
programming. So when people talk about
objectoriented programming they mean
Java. Okay that like the JavaS way where
you have you know you you write classes
that can specifically
inherit other classes. Okay that's a bit
complex to explain. Uh I'm going to skip
it now. Okay. But anyway, you have a
class-based system that's Java. And that
system is used also in Python, in PHP,
in Ruby,
um in C++. Okay. So this the so-called
objectoriented programming that system
is based on the Java is is is is based
on the JavaS class system or C++. So,
Java, C++, Python, PHP, Ruby, they are
all like that. Okay, that is class-based
system. But now because marketing they
say you need to make JavaScript look
like Java. So that becames all the
problem. What pro and and what made it
worse is that the whole JavaScript the
whole JavaScript is created designed
implemented in 10 days. Okay. So you
only got 10 days to do it and it needs
to look like Java although you are like
you know you you are not Java but you
have to look like Java with the syntax
and all that. So that's that creates all
the problems. So today when you talk to
a JavaScript programmer or if you know
JavaScript so every day almost every day
you you use the new you know like new
keyword instance of this keyword
prototype you know something prototype
you know and
constructor. So this why do we have that
that because these are created so that
JavaScript looks like Java because Java
in Java's class system you have the idea
of new you know the new keyword new
something you have the idea of the
instance of some you know something so
and you have the keyword this so I have
a
Java I also have a Java tutorial but
it's not very good. It's, you know,
because I haven't coded in Java that
much. But if you want look at that, if
you uh are a beginner, you know, if you
want just to simply understand the Java
programming
language, you know, I have one
on.info Java tutorial. So, you also have
like this keyword, you know, in Java,
which is entirely different thing from
JavaScript. Okay. So, by the way, I
created a Java logo. This is my own logo
created in 2008. The original Java logo
looks like
that. Okay. So, and then they change it
to look like that. Okay. So, in 1995,
it's like this. But then in 2003, they
simplify, they try to simplify it
because Java is a very kind of
heavy complex language. Okay.
And Java's got a mascot, you know, this
this thing called penguin. Yeah. Java
penguin. Duke. He's got a name Duke.
Okay. That's history of Java. So Java.
So So what happens is that they they
want to make JavaScript to look like
Java.
So that's why you got this new instance
you know and it and it is extremely bad
extremely badly done as well. First of
all, you know, it's very bad idea to to
make it look like Java because one is
prototype based system, the other is
classbased. They are not
compatible. But they are trying to force
it. You know, you you got to make it
look like Java because we are like adver
because there's a billions dollars of
advertising for
Java. So that's a big big mistake. But
then they they try to do it in 10 days.
So it's entire up. Okay. So if you
want to understand the JavaScript new
instance of this keyword it's all in
this chapter. Okay. So this binding uh
you know you got this binding you got
constructor the concept of constructor
which came from Java. Okay, Java class
constructor. You don't need it in
JavaScript because every
object, you know, you can create every
object just by by by by just by the
braces, you know, when you have a
braces, that's an object. There's no you
don't need a constructor, you know, but
they added that. So it, you know,
because Java has it. So you got this
constructor idea, then you got this
prototype property. Every function
magically has this prototype
property. Magically why? Because well
because in Java the class system you
have you need inheritance. Therefore
this is the way you know to tie them.
It's very bad. Okay you don't need it.
So in fact today if you are coding
JavaScript this entire you can you know
you can
never never ever use the new keyword
never ever use the instance of keyword
never ever use this keyword and all the
others and your code will become
actually simpler to understand simpler
faster more efficient. Okay, that is a
situation but unfortunately that's not a
situation in the computing industry
because you you look at the JavaScript
code you know the frameworks you know
they are using these why because people
they don't know because they habit you
know habit and confusion so that's why
they keep using these so for
example who does not use like I said you
don't you don't have to you do not need
to any to use any of new this in your
code to achieve exactly the same thing.
Exactly. Okay. For
example, Douglas Quford who is who made
JavaScript very popular. He's one of the
top most um expert of JavaScript. He is
in fact responsible for making
JavaScript respectables. you know he
wrote the book JavaScript the good
parts around year 2005 Douglas Quford
okay so let me show you and he's also
the creator of JSON format you know you
probably know Jason is now very uh you
know it's standard
so so Douglas qu okay Douglas qu that's
a guy okay he's a I highly respect him.
He's a very he's one of the guy who um
study programming languages and I highly
respect his view his point of view on
programming language design. He's now
pretty old. So I think he maybe he's
about to retire. I don't know but he's
pretty old but he's still kicking. Okay.
He's like I don't know 60
something.
So you know so you can go watch his
videos. So I I got you know so he also
wrote JavaScript the better parts and he
also wrote a new book. So let me see if
I can. So anyway my point here is he is
the one you see if you watch his
talk he stopped using the operator new
like in his code you not see it not one
time at all he don't use he he doesn't
use even object.create create he never
uses this key binding I mean this
binding he doesn't use no you know so
there's bunch of others okay some other
uh javascript complex comp
complexities he doesn't use okay so
anyway the main point is he doesn't use
new he doesn't use this binding okay so
you can take it from Douglas Crawford
one of the top JavaScript
expert okay so That's I'm showing this
to support my um my what I'm telling you
that you you know you can totally not
use any of the
um uh the other things you know this new
and this uh new and this keyword. Okay.
So last part of the story so that so
that's a JavaScript. Okay. JavaScript
let me let me summarize in one minute.
JavaScript created in 1995 is based on
two
languages
self where it took the prototype based
object system from and it's also based
on scheme lisp the programming language
which is a kind of like this like
functional programming language okay
that is why JavaScript is very kind of
known as functional you know programming
language so it has a very simple
prototype system. But however, because
of social reasons, marketing reasons,
they try to force JavaScript to look
like Java. Therefore, you got a syntax,
the JavaScript syntax become like Java.
Then you got these new words like new
and this.
Okay. So, actually I I should reverse
the order of these two. This should come
after new. So let me do that. So new.
Okay. So let me put that new. Okay. Show
in browser. New and this. You know those
those two are the most popular keywords
in JavaScript. So you don't don't use
that. Okay. You can like don't use them
at all and your code will be simpler,
better and more efficient. Now last part
of the story. So they so they created
they try to be like Java. So they become
all this complexity and but people adopt
it you know people use them because back
so
why why is that you know you have so
simple system you don't need this
complexities but however you do have
both in the language but and but most
people started to use this complex you
know construct instead of the simpler
why is that good question okay that is
Because the prototype based system is
not well known you know like nobody
understand what that is especially back
in 2000s. The reason is because you know
because most people are like programmers
are industrial programmers they code C,
C++,
Java and they consider
those you know they are familiar with
that classbased system. So nobody
understand you know not many people
understand what is prototype based
system. So that's why they are familiar
with you know this they they think of
that them like Java you know so they are
used using that those but they use it
wrong because it's not a class-based
system. So that is why the coding
industry all the JavaScript coders they
are using kind of they are like using
this. Okay. Now last part of the story
and and I think that's it for today.
Okay. So so in 2005 you know JavaScript
got lots of problems besides this this
object system problem. Uh so in 2015 the
people tried to make it try to overhaul
the language. So they they started to do
you know they they did a big giant
overhaul of the language. But meanwhile
they tried to make it backward
compatible. So they added a lot things
to fix JavaScript. For example, uh for
example, one of the big things they
added is if you look at variables, they
added the let keyword. Fantastic.
Because
before before you have the var which is
very complex and very bad. No no scope.
Like whenever you use v the glo the
scope is global unless you are using it
inside a function. So you cannot declare
local variables you know very bad
extremely bad. So after 20 years they in
2015 they find they added the let
keyword. So now you can have local
variables. Okay. So if you put it inside
the braces it's local in that braces.
Okay. That's one thing they added. They
added like a whole lot of things. So let
is one thing they added. Another thing
they added is for example, let's go to
JavaScript in depth. Let's go to
functions. Uh functions arrow function.
Okay. So now you can actually write a
short function like
that. Am I good? Say hi guys.
Okay. So error functions. Fantastic.
Okay. So again remember JavaScript is
based on a functional programming
language scheme
lisp. So they added that and lots of
other things. But however they try to
remain backward compatible. So they are
not removing or deleting anything that's
bad. They simply create new things. You
know use these new things just don't use
the old things. But they they are still
there. So they didn't you know they
didn't say okay we're gonna remove the
new keyword we're gonna remove this
keyword. No they didn't do that. Okay
but however they added a new thing
class. Why? Because most people when
they call JavaScript you know they are
using this complex and unnecessary new
something something this something
something.
Then they thought why don't we just
create a class keyword so people
actually can create a class just like
Java you know again just like Java but
the entire object system is not Java at
all but they just you know let's pretend
we are coding Java so they added this
keyword class new in 2015 very bad okay
it's it's it's bad in some way it's good
in some way okay It's bad
because you are trying to pretend you
are Java but you are not Java at all.
You don't need you don't need this class
keyword at all. You don't need new you
don't need this. You don't need class
and you can do exactly the same thing
which with with simpler syntax easier to
understand and more efficient code.
But so but they but they added the class
keyword. So that's bad because you don't
need it. But why is class also part
three good? Because because people are
doing this new and this and prototype
thing that's very complex. So now they
created a class
keyword which is kind of this this you
know new instance of class you know
prototype function.prototype and
something it makes it kind of simpler.
So it kind of like make it simpler for
those people who are like using this new
this keyword. So that's why they created
class keyword in 2015. Okay. Uh I think
that's it. That's a kind of the short
story of the complexity of JavaScript
object system. JavaScript object system
is prototype system. Prototype based
system is fantastic and simple. However,
they made they added a bunch of crap
unnecessarily for marketing
reasons but pe and people adopted them.
Then in 2015 they added the class
keyword which is like a necessary and
you know that's a short story. So if you
want to know the full detail about all
these things the this binding
uh the constructor the prototype
property every function magically have
this prototype property. What does it
mean? And if you want know to know the
you know the new operator very complex
this new operator you know exactly what
it does it very
complex so you can understand all these
instance of operator you should never
use okay because it's not reliable it
doesn't you know it they they pretend to
do what it does but actually no
sometimes it doesn't work some you know
depending on the situation you know
things like that depending on whether
you change the parent or
So you know you shouldn't use any of
these. Okay. Then you got magical
constructor property meaning that
there's a property whose type is a
string like that you know and the name
is constructor like magically like
whenever you have a um yeah whenever you
create a function it creates a whenever
you define a function you know function
some
function name parameter body whenever
you define a function it magically
automatically behind the scenes means
creates a function f.prototype prototype
you know by magic and that prototype
magically has a object and this object
magically have a constructor property
that's how complex it is okay so you got
that then then whenever you do new so
what does new do do exactly very complex
okay so here is a detail so you can read
it and you don't need any of these okay
so for example um you can you know So
you don't need any of them at all to to
create exactly the same thing. Okay.
So so you got this confusion type of
instance of constructor very
confusing. Then 2015 you got this class
thing. So what does the class thing do?
Well here I try to explain them in terms
of the basic object and prototype based
system. Okay. So you I try to explain
that you know class system. Okay. So uh
then you got of course you got the
static keyword borrowed from
Java. You got the extends keyword also
2015 borrowed from Java. Um you know
then you got the super keyword from 2015
borrowed from Java.
very very complex. Meanwhile, all this
is pretending, you know, it's using the
JavaScript prototype system, but
pretending it's like the Java
system. Okay, that's
it. Uh, thank you guys for watching.
classes make it harder to know the
structure of an object. Yes, exactly.
Uh, ironically, functional functional
programming is bit greater than object
oriented programming. Yes, but some
people do not believe it though. So,
it's not totally u you know widespread
yet
accepted. Okay. So, bye guys. If you
like my stuff, okay, don't forget to
donate to me, okay? Just like, you know,
if you like my stuff, go to
um go to go to
kas.info, go all the way to the bottom.
Uh you can Amazon gift card, click the
link, go there because I cannot accept,
you know, German, Germany's Amazon or
Japanese or French, you know. So, you
got to click the link and copy paste my
uh email and pay me or use PayPal. Copy
paste my email or Patreon
me. Thank you
guys. Bye.