good morning guys
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show today is 2019 November 8th
Friday it okok San Francisco time 8 8
o'clock in the evening
San Francisco California and today I
don't have a topic I think we are just
going to do Emacs so I'm going to do
some Emacs yeah let's do that let's do
some Emacs coding and if you have not
already joined this code
okay this code is a lot people it's fun
a lot of different people from different
places from UK from Germany from Czech
Republic from Japan so lots of people so
join this code ok and you can find a
discord if you just go to my websites
our talk show and discord here is the
link so join this code so good morning
Pablo and good morning Lokesh Lokesh is
from ireland so well slow gesture says o
else you could do more general video
like how you could approach your problem
based practice to follow while coding ok
i'm that's a broad topic so the question
is how general video about how you
approach a problem best practice to
follow while coding so yeah so that's
two questions
two very broad questions and I think
there is no ultimate scientific answer
because each person is different as for
how to approach a problem my you know
I'm typically very logical logic
oriented logic you know logic and
analytic
the methodological so systematic I said
sets approach I tend to take so when I
have a problem it doesn't matter it's a
technical problem programming math or
social I tends to be analytical you know
systematically you know get information
like what to see what's the problem
you know that's what I tend to do and
the best practice to follow while
programming again so I am kind of
logical so I tend to be first of all so
if I have to code a programming problem
first of all I want to know the problem
in detail so I think about problem like
I try to understand the you know the
like the the core the problem the
mathematical nature of the problem then
then I start to think of a solution then
the first thing I do is I write the
documentation so so this is this
approach is very different from any
hackers programming hackers a lot of
people they tends to they just start to
code you know they they do it they they
have to do it that way they cannot you
know they you know so it's a opposite
approach you know they have to start you
know just write code then you know then
they start to correct parts of it or you
know improve from there so on but me I
tend to I don't start to write code I
have to think about problem I think of a
solution I think of how to solve it you
know maybe different approaches you know
I then then then I start to write code
and typically before I write any code I
write a documentation first like this
function is gonna do you know what
function I'm gonna have that that's
that's kind of my approach so so what is
the how why do you have that question
like what is your background like what's
a concrete example of a situation where
you have that question
Lokesh so answer that piece and I'm
gonna I'm just going to I think we're
gonna do like 30 minutes you know a
short video just to keep me keep in
touch and Pablo so Pablo is five o'clock
in the morning how are you doing
so I'm going to yeah let's do some I'm
gonna to code some emag bees okay so let
me show you emag beeps this thing Emacs
so exhaust art command log mod okay so
on the left window you can see all my
comments and Lokesh how did you find me
were you reading my blogs before or
Lokesh answer so on the left window you
can see all my Emacs commands I call so
I'm going to create a new page so Kassar
talk show magnify today state then a new
page okay that will create a HTML page
then link link it and cut it put it here
so here is the page showing browser okay
close that cut that open it again paste
magnify so that's the one thing I'm
gonna talk about and close that let's go
back to the topic spring so saw talk
show you go to this bunch of topics
topics print and we're going to I'm
going to do eMac this modified because
our new page to add the title so that's
yeah that's what I'm gonna do
let's do that then
select Lokesh says thanks answering my
question
getting back to questions I had come
across a situation to develop a custom
XML parser and I was so confused how to
approach this problem I have following
your blog for a long time but it's quite
spectacular oh thank you
so you want to write a custom XML parser
okay so have you written a parcel before
like if you have not then how did you
get that problem you know so I'm
thinking because if you have written an
XML parser before then you know what to
do custom XML parser like yeah so I mean
you have to know if you have written a
pasta before I'm guessing you know right
I don't know okay so I don't know what
is your situation I don't know if you
are student or you have been programming
for a long time like I have no idea so I
mean if I'm guessing so if you have
written a parser before then you know
what to do you know develop a custom XML
parser so and what do you mean by custom
I mean so so I'm thinking you know if
you know have written XML parser before
you know what to do
parser you have to but otherwise I mean
if you are new to passes then XML parser
is not difficult you know actually I
don't know how to write one so if I have
that problem to read you know to try the
XML parser that's one of the things I
have to do that I want to do I have not
done yet
so basically you then you start to you
know study about passes so for example
so passes they are quite a lot of
tutorials on the web about passing you
can start to read them for example okay
so I have actually sort of I can well I
know a book that's a very that's
actually the best book on passes okay
this is this
is the best book on passes any
programming any compiler expert will
agree this is agreed-upon basically this
is the best book on passes now Wikipedia
has a turn of articles on passing but as
usual Wikipedia as tends to be very
confusing because this got tons of
information you know it's got tons of
information and it's not suitable for
beginners and it has 100 links you know
two different passes because they are
different algorithms for passes you know
so passing or syntax syntax analysis or
syntactic analysis is the process of
analyzing a string of symbols bah bah
bah and you know then he starts to talk
about natural languages computer
languages data structures so it's you
know that's that's confusing
then it's talking about linguistics you
know but for programmers we are just
concerned about parsing program
programming languages not you know
natural languages and all other stuff so
Wikipedia is very confusing unless you
already read a book about parsing then
we havea is useful but otherwise it's
you know because I've spent days I've
spent days to read quite a lot of the
Wikipedia articles on passing so so for
beginners of course I don't I don't
recommend Wikipedia but there is a book
I can show you for example on this page
you can see my notes this is my learning
notes about different you know my notes
it's not coherent or anyway but you know
there are so many different techniques
for passing you know I'm trying to learn
and classify it I understand what what
are the different types why are they
different you know what what's each one
good for things like that so that's my
notes but I'm going to show you a book
that is the best book on passes okay so
that book is
this book passing technique passing
techniques by big gun okay so this book
now you can buy it on Amazon now this is
basically universally agreed this is the
reference book for pasta it's also it's
it's it's it's suitable it's also
suitable for beginner because it starts
from the beginning assuming you don't
know nothing about passing so comments
okay look Lokesh comments like you know
when you know give me some feedback you
know let me know where I'm going so so
this book I don't I don't know so is
this book would be something useful to
you or do you already know passing so
forth so this book is a great book okay
very expensive one hundred dollars or if
you can buy used is $32 I think
paperback back ok paperback hundred
seventeen dollars hardcover $72 Kindle
version 32 to one hundred dollars why
they have different versions of Kindle
anyway so very expensive but however the
previous version of that book is free
online if you can go to his website I
talked to this guy
dick gran I emailed with him you know I
asked him question a couple of times and
he's very helpful so here is the table
of contents of his book you know so this
is kind of that like the comprehensive
book on pot passing okay so and you so
you go to his website and you will find
you know so here is his website passing
techniques
okay second edition okay and
[Music]
now I now this is the second edition but
the first edition is free online and you
you know you you just go and find it you
know it's on his website the first
edition is free Oh a beast was free I am
pretty sure it's still free
okay for example I have it a copy I have
a copy here somewhere in my directory
PDF anyway I was planning to I was
planning to put his I was trying to put
his book ok possible I was planning to
put his book on my website but I I
didn't finish you know it takes a long
time so anyway here is his book wait
yeah so here is the book this is a first
edition and it's free so you should find
it on his website and that's that's a
good book that's a serious book though
you know you will have to spend one hour
a day or two for a month to to really
understand it you cannot scheme you know
that would not be good because I mean
passing is a deep subject and you have
to you have to be constant you know pay
attention to it okay so great I've
already been written a wrapper around
some open source XML parsers have been
limited by shortcomings yeah so I don't
actually know that this subject so I
cannot tell you what to do I don't know
so I'm learning the stuff so passing
yeah so I mean like what like what do
you mean by passing HT
like you know so like the you know like
we when you would write a compiler when
you create a new language okay like you
when you create a new language Cola and
JavaScript things like that C or Perl or
Python that's a you know that's a those
are languages and you then you have to
write a parser that's a real pasa
because basically you have to write a
program that's what parser is so pasa is
a it's a program that you basically you
have to write a program that beats every
character of some of some file you know
basically a giant stream that is a
programming language source code so you
have to write a program that beats every
character of this you know file then you
have to analyze it basically you have to
find that you know you have to determine
the structure so it sounds very complex
in fact it is you know that's that's
what parsing is about so you read it you
and you also you know you read the
source code you also have to be the
grammar fire grammar fire is kind of a
specification for for valid syntax of
this language so a passer you have to
read a grammar file then you take input
a source code a big giant string as
input then you your program output sort
of tree a tree structure which
represents that source code according to
the grammar you know oh oh if the source
code is invalid like according to the
grammar it's invalid then your parser we
are up would say oh this is not valid
that's that's what parser is so this is
the real you know meaning of pasta real
pasta but most people when they talk
about pasa they may not mean that
because for example I want you know if I
have a web you know if I have a file I
want to get all email addresses in the
file so what do you do you just you
a regular expression so you can get all
the email address in the file you know
and some people you know that's also
passing that's also passing in some
sense you know but that's not so that's
not but that's not be your thing that's
not real pasa so but in programming you
have a lot of tasks that's kind of I
mean in average programming in the
industry nobody actually needs to write
a parser like because it's already
written Python you know or program Oh
programming languages they all have a
parser because you need a pacifist then
you need to compile it that is generate
the machine code or translate to another
language like JavaScript you know so all
so so basically in general nobody you
know you never and you know most
programmers like 90% of programmers you
will never need to understand know to be
able to write a parser at all you don't
you don't need to okay like I've been
programming for 20 years I don't need to
write a parser there's no need
you know well actually I've done some
there's some tasks I have done some
tasks that requires passing but that's
that that's a special project but in
general you don't need to know basically
you're most programmers you don't need
night like 90% of programmers in your
life you know you don't need to write a
passes so anyway that's a real parcel
but however most programmers but you
know there's a lot tasks for for most
programmers where you need to get email
addresses in file you need to like miner
like you know you might call it miner
passing like I don't know what so hey
you know it's hard to think of example
at the moment but get email address is
an example but so so what I'm saying is
that maybe that's what you mean because
because XML you see XML is a it's a very
simple XML the line
which has a very simple grammar actually
done the full grammar is very complex
like like tens of pages or even hundreds
the video you know I'm so so there are
so many meanings to it
for example XML let me get let me try to
explain one by one okay just just my
opinion that what I think about this
topic okay so yeah so when we talk about
XML you know very simple right so you
have tags and you have closing tags but
actually if if you are writing like XML
such that you need to you need your HTML
file to pass certain XML spec then
that's not easy at all because the x8
XML spec you know you go to read XML
spec you know then you start it's like
hundreds of pages of technique there ok
X XML specification let's see if we can
find it so what I'm trying to say here
is that XML is very simple okay yeah I
mean practically speaking we all every
program we understand it what it means
okay I mean basically it's very regular
so you have a first line that declares
what XML it is what yeah like that okay
so you know the first line declares the
version of XML then basically every
thing is just you know this nested tags
you know that's that's it that's the
syntax of XML that's you know every
programmer understand it because it's
you know it the very nature is very
really simple but however so it depends
on what you mean however if you want to
write a XML that pad that for some
reason needs to pass the XML validation
then you need then you you can see that
so here is an XML spec let's see
extensible extensible markup language
fifty titian
okay so you see so then you can see no
not now this is a very long
documentation and this is not even
aspect yet entity declarations yeah so
entity external entities yeah so so when
you want a real XML you know like
passing some standard you know tests
things like that then it's not easy at
all it will take you you know you take a
dedicated expert you you need to work on
this for years to to actually do that so
you see so that that's you know so they
are different kind of meaning when when
people say XML you know I mean this is
related to passing you know like we when
you are saying if you are saying you
know if your boss or someone tells you
you need to read a XML parser what did
they mean what does that mean so I mean
if you like if you don't really need to
pass some you know spec then it's not
it's very easy actually actually you
don't even need to read the passing book
you don't need to read this you know
this passing book because you can just
hack up a solution because XML is pretty
simple you can yeah you can kind of you
know you just for example you just write
a program then you first of all you use
a regular you know you read the whole
file then you use a regular expression
to split every right angle bracket okay
so so you so you you read a whole file
as a stream then you split the string
into a list okay every element of the
list should be you know you split the
stream by the but basically by that
greater than you create a greater sign
greater than sign so you got a list of
elements each element should be just
tagged okay then you started to
BTW gentlemen in order ok the first one
should be some kind of you know this
version XML version SPECT okay so you
read that ok then that's it you know
like you use a regular expression to
check you know if it begins with you
know like that XML version equals true
you know it's like that then then the
next one is attack you you use again you
use regular expression to see what tag
name you know like sometimes you have
the attribute so you you can you use the
regular expression to get that you know
so you got a tag name you got an
attribute then you got an attribute
value okay then you read the next one
okay so each time you read you know one
of the tag you push it to a stack so you
push it to a stack then you read another
when I'm pushed it to the stack and
every time you read a new one you check
if the previous the last item in the
sack has the same tag like if when you
pick pick for example once you read the
question ending you know the closing tag
you check if the last tag in the stack
is the opening question tag so if a
match you can remove that from the sack
you know so because it you know because
you found the nesting you know you can
remove that so yeah so you do this for
the whole for all the elements in the
end if your stack is empty except the
first line then that means this X XML
file is valid okay
basically you have written kind of a you
know sloppy way of checking where the
XML file has you know matching text
that's you know that's that's one way to
do a sloppy way so like so what do you
mean by passing like maybe you're
passing job requires you to
determine if some tag is nested you know
another another tag or something like
that like what you need to do like so
that's that that is a question you know
on the other hand if you really want to
write you know a full XML parser then
that's really complex then you you know
then then you have to read this stock
this stock is like hundreds pages then
you know the entities you have to deal
with entities you have to you know it's
very specific then CD data and all that
so loquacious I so I have some so I have
experienced what you said about grammar
language of language I have come across
XML schemas which is like hundreds of
pages that book will really be useful
okay yeah so I guess you are doing
something serious so I don't know the
answer yeah check out that book I should
get on to read that book so actually how
long have we been talking so I'm
thinking maybe we so do you use Emacs
look load Lokesh so I'm thinking maybe
that's it for today because you know so
unless anyone else is here ask me a
question okay Pablo where are you
wait I remember I see Pablo they are
there Pablo in Spain okay so you don't
use the Emacs ok so yeah so so ok so any
anyway so I'm thinking maybe that's it
for today pauses yeah very interesting
topic this guy by the way this guy Guan
he is the he see he you know I found out
later on he is actually the author of
CBS the CBS is a version control system
are they what's the full name CVS
content version system you know CVS
anyway that's a you know version control
system before get before SVN so we
talked about that a few days ago so dick
gun is actually a author of CES I think
so he say old UNIX sky so dick one yeah
so he's got a Wikipedia entry
oh my god so he's videoed he's 79 years
old so he is a dutch computer scientist
and university lecture best known for
inventing and developing the first
version of concurrent version system yes
that's him haha you know he's a he's a
pioneer
he's a pioneer of UNIX CVS goon was
involved in the construction of Arco 68
compilers in those 1970s yeah so he's
very you know he's a computer scientist
a renowned computer scientist he also
gave the name to gnome sort a sorting
algorithm invented by Hammett Sabah's
EES add who originally published under
the name stupid sort wait they wait this
arc oh did I mention his passer book
assured oka did selected publications
okay dig run and and and Savio's Serio
JH Jacobs so they they you know so they
wrote that anyway it should be more I
mean this article only has one sentence
of it in selected publications but
actually it's more because this book is
considered be considered to be like
basically the classic that you know the
number one book for passing because I I
know it because I read a lot Wikipedia
articles on passing your you will
sometimes you know come across
references to this book
so Pablo says how do you manage Emax
creation of your web pages it is code
templates okay so let's do that and that
so let's do that and that'll be it for
today so I'm going I'm going to show you
so how do I create a page for example I
want to create a new page let's say name
new saw okay so you can see my commands
on the Left panel so so for example so I
have a command I just call some new page
okay that's okay man so I enter that
will create a new HTML page with that
name and with the title of that you know
the title is derived from the file name
in a current directory in the directory
where this file is set so that's a
command so if I open the file you see
it's got all the you know showing
browser so it's empty and but it's got
its got all the you know doctype your
headers meta stylesheet googles you know
web tracking stuff for their statistics
like how many people's viewed this page
headers you know so so that's that's
kind of how I do it that's the template
and okay but the question is how do you
actually so how do you actually write
the command so let me show you the
command so let's delete this page we
don't need it okay so refresh it's good
right remove that so let's go to our
talk show today's talk show so let's
show you the command so sarni page okay
so I call describe function I go to a
new page and here is the source code
here is a source code so I open it
okay so anyway so so here is the file
yeah there is something let's let's see
what how are you gonna do this okay so I
quit let's create a new file let's
create a yeah let's create a dis let's
just create it here okay so here's a
file you can see now in my browser and I
I split it into a window and let's
remove that okay so it's better that way
so so here is my here is a eMac risk
code that that creates a new page and so
what it does so what I'm thinking what
to do because - because you know I can
start to explain this file how it works
the this emag this function basically
the way it works you know it's not the
best example for a tutorial the way it
works is that first of all it finds out
what directory I am in the current
directory because on my website
depending on what domain you know what
what website you know I have several
domains like oh go Emacs or English comm
or cardstock or sorry down info I have
several domains and each domain you have
several directories so when I want a new
page in that directory for example let's
say Golan okay so : for example here is
my goal and tutorial now if I go into
that directory you can see that's my
goal and tutorial so when
when I am for example one of my tutorial
page on goal and constants when I want
to create a new page that new page must
be based on one of the page in this
directory so it's directly dependent and
domain dependent so whenever I call this
create a new page command I need to find
out what directory I'm I am in and in
that directory I there is an example
file that is used for as a template for
that directory so for example when I
mean if I'm in the colon directory then
the template file is this call and run
so let's look at it let's go to colon
and goal and run so this is the template
file I use to create new pages so let's
open that look at that you know it's a
it's just one of the goal and tutorial
page so once I you know so I I find out
what that directory I mean then
basically I find out you know I there is
a file that's that's used as the
template for that directory so that what
I do is that then I just make a copy of
that file rename that file then open
that file then remove all the video
content in that file so what's left is
just headers and footers and whatever
you know the ads the Google trackers
that's like that and that's it that's
essentially what this code does you know
you find out the directory you are in
find the templates in a directory copy
that and modify it and that's how it
works so this is not a great example
because well it's it's it's a reward
real world example you know you know as
opposed to I mean on the other hand you
you could write a program that base that
is based on templates like you have a
bunch of
strings you know maybe in a hash-table
that's a template for each duh but
anyway this is the approach I take
because it just happens to be useful to
me so what are you family that's not one
of this directory then you know then I
just modified this command to create new
a new a new you know directory with the
template you know that's what I do this
is you know so this is this approach is
actually the practical approach because
I don't need you know so far I haven't I
don't need to create a file in in order
Ector II that's not one of these so this
is one way I'd read a new file but there
are so many other ways ok so this is one
way I create a template so so Pablo yeah
so your question about yeah so yeah I
don't know if that address the question
because there are so many things in how
I created create my website like the way
I create like basically it just began by
writing manually writing HTML that's how
it began like 20 years ago
okay cool yeah so yeah and I preferred
to ever be a pliable rehabber BOGO
template you know so so this case our
new page is actually pretty new you know
I just actually created like NASA you
know so for you know because used to let
me show you another way because used to
you see my website the way I create them
there is no master plan in the beginning
it just evolved you know from 20 years
you know whenever I need basically in
the beginning I just manually code every
tag you know like when I need the new
file i just opened newt buffer then I
just start to type like H you know HTML
that's what I did like back in 1997 you
know I just start to type it you know a
paragraph and something you know and and
then save it for example the ensuring
browser you know so that's how I
beginning it but but but not you know
but now is that after 25 years you know
so I've got lots of eMac beast code and
techniques and you know and also HTML
has become so complex so I have CSS
files that's thousands you know that's
hundred lines lines many CSS files in
JavaScript file you know it in google
tracker so it becomes complex and also I
have templates for example today for
example let's delete that okay so do
that so today if I want to create from
scratch
I can type for example HTML H that is a
brief that just insert the whole HTML
template so in showing browser you see
and this is how something okay so press
a key h1 okay let's do it again some
press a key h1 then you have that then
show your browser you know
then this and that and Alice in
Wonderland okay then I can call the
command like that that that then I have
three paragraphs you see I have three
paragraphs then I can add a style sheet
if I want and okay so let me show so
style so now I have a style it's okay so
I want let's say all paragraph to be
read so I can say P P color red okay
show in browser now it's all red now
let's make it 100% let's say I want to
make text bigger so I have a lot of
techniques you know
so the I mean right now this way I'm
showing is technique when I want to
create a new HTML file from scratch so
and you can create you you know there
are so many tips you know one of the tip
I recommend the most if you want
templates is brief Pablo so I highly
recommend that for example for example I
showed you before I can type HTML H then
becomes you know the whole thing I could
have a footer I don't actually have one
but I could have for example let's do it
so if I go to my HTML page you see at
the bottom there's a footer you know so
I if I show this in browser you see this
footer that's created by this slide now
I don't have a template for that because
I don't need to but let's say I want one
so I want to brief for that let's create
that so I copy that
okay so I go to my a brief page my
bookmark just open my a brief ire
and then I just say I just say here okay
I paste these and I want to escape the
quotes basically here's what I need to
do okay T X this is what you need to to
do you I want to add this line like that
what this means is that when you type T
followed by space of punctuation it will
become whatever here so the the thing
here will be this line but we need to
escape quotes because in Emacs you
cannot have you know the double quote
you need to escape so I have a command
called saw escape quotes okay so that
does that so cut it move back here paste
it that's it so let's say I want to name
this a briefcase a footer okay that's it
now I avow the buffer okay
give out the buffer go back to go back
to our previous HTML file and at the
bottom I just say type saw food tour
enter you see it becomes that so this is
this is what I recommend a brief Emacs a
brief is the most powerful template in
show it show in browser you see that you
see that now it's not showing up like
that because we need CSS we can we can
add that let's let's add that but let me
tell you so I did a video I did like one
or two videos on Emacs a brief so if you
have not seen it check it out you know
just go to my YouTube search for Emacs a
brief you'll find it so a brief and also
I have my tutorials very useful
let's see so I think actually I think
that's it for today so Emacs of Brima
tutorial that's my tutorial you can read
that's all you need need
okay very very easy and the most
powerful a brief is the most powerful
I know Emacs a lot of people also use Y
snippet or others that's okay
you know I mean that's good but I don't
think he's it's necessary so I would I
don't I stopped using my snippet as I
used Y snippet for like five years in
for like 77 years then I stopped a brief
is just simpler and more powerful not
not more powerful but you know it's
simpler and good good fast and also I
have a brief on youtube so tutorial so
let's search it and see so let's turn on
JavaScript and it's search for sorry max
a brief and let's go to wait okay do you
need to wait so it's such okay you know
the dr. ko is very annoying when you
have JavaScript off because it doesn't
it doesn't show the images and videos
and stuff you need to turn JavaScript on
and research it start like firms over so
Emacs a brief tutorial so there's one
that's ten minutes yeah so I did several
talks related to that anyway so you
might check that out so Pablo you are
working on a keyboard right how is house
going so that that's it for today thank
you guys for watching so so Pablo how is
going with your keyboard
okay so that's it thank you guys I'm
stuck on stm32 okay okay thank you guys
for watching see you guys bye Pablo bye
luggage ask me
yes disco channel channel you haven't
seen it join join it I mentioned it many
times in my video so join it you can
find that this code you can find the
discord in Mike's ad-hoc show page and
elsewhere you know it's like over so you
can find it and join because I like you
guys join it you know and and quite a
lot interesting talks by all these geeks
and nerds keyboards the places people
live you know keyboard modification on
this coding on programming in general
heat on vim or Emacs and very
interesting you know the worst people so
actually so this page let me add a CSS
okay so let's let's not let's not that's
that's it for today then that's yeah bye