Hello guys. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show. We are
going to talk about Emac list and I'm
going to you know teach I'm going to
code actually I'm going to show some
emac list updates on my website and you
know uh teaching something about EMAC
list generic map functions. Okay, Emac
Lisp is the topic and uh if you are here
say hi. If you are watching offline,
play at 1.5 speed minimum because I
ramble, you know. Uh 1.5 speed minimum
is perfect or faster. Okay, so video
check, audio check. Am I alive? My
keyboard. This is glove 80. Fantastic. I
have video reviews. This is ultimate
hacking keyboard too. I have video
reviews. Uh newly track ball mouse uh
track ball and you know I have video
reviews. Search for YouTube, you'll find
it. Okay, let's begin today's topic. Uh
let's see. Uh yeah, yeah, yeah. So, Emac
Lisp. Okay. On the pink window, uh is
all my command calls and keystrokes. You
can see them. Command name co uh command
name on the right as I type and
keystroke on the left. I'm using a Vora
keyboard layout and keys. Okay. So,
let's see. So, first of all, keys news.
So safy keys as you know it's the most
efficient key binding system for Emacs.
So this is mostly for writers and
programmers. Mostly for programmers if
you are vim user or neo vim you know uh
safely keys beats them it's more
efficient. Okay so it's a key binding
system for Emacs text editor. Okay. So
here are the key bindings. So there's
some news update. So let me show you the
news. So the you know the update it's on
GitHub. So now insert date. So let me
show you. So show today's page. So let
me demo um remove the todo. So let's say
press press you see today's date. So you
can see the command insert date and the
keystroke is space EU on Vora keyboard
layout. Okay. So if you call universal
command first then type the key then you
got a bunch of varieties of options
format for the date. So you can have ISO
date which is a default
and you can have let's do it again. Uh
you can have USA you know USA convention
September 4th 2025
and you can have other you know quite a
few others coder format. So this is
popular for coders. So you got ISO date
underscore then uh that's hour. So right
now it's 20:00 3 minutes and 21 seconds.
So
that's a command. So and a new one I
just added is the started version. So
let me show you it started version. So I
started to use you know starting today I
started to use this this syntax this
notation for version so for software
version. So first of all let me show you
the safely keys code. Okay. So uh that
that that that there is the code safely
keys in this file. So this is insert
date. So go there. Go in. So here's a
source code. Not too long. Uh about 50
lines of code. So uh let's see.
Uh let's say insert date. Uh what's the
key for insert date?
Uh I mean what's the key for uh show
line numbers? So I forgot because
recently I changed it display uh display
line numbers mode space and space D.
Okay, space and space D. So you can see
the command name on the ping window and
the keystroke on the left. So there it
is. And uh let's make it s e emac smart.
So you got color. So uh space and space
d. So there are it's only 37 lines of
code and you can see. So close that go
to the matching paren and you can open
this URL. So this code is on my
website.info.
Just search for emac insert datetime. So
you can grab it and use it for yourself.
Okay. Uh hello hello Cortez. Long time
no see. Cortez
I want to say something more but I you
know not sure it's personal or not. So
welcome uh welcome back. I I suppose
contains great to see you. Uh so
insert daytime. Okay. So this is a
command you can grab and use it. Okay.
Put you know you can use it. So let's go
to keys source code. So uh space and
space d show uh line numbers. So there
are 4,000 lines of code and you can uh
so and uh what I want to show yeah the
new version uh format I'm using. So now
it's like that you know uh based on date
so year date I got the inspiration from
Mac OS. So Mac OS. Okay. So let's search
for that because in the latest version
coming version of Mac Mac OS they they
decided instead of naming it you know
Mac OS 10 10.5 10.6 you know they they
just going to name it 25
stand for year 2025. So this this this
uh what's the current version? So let's
go to um
you know Mac there Tahoe you see before
it's Mac OS 14 Sonoma and 15 Sequoia and
then 26 Tahoe
oh I thought it's 25 it's 20 version 26
so they name they they they started to
name the version date using the date so
I got inspiration so that that's a good
thing because you know like when you
want to download some software. Oh, it
requires version seven. But but then you
have to to wonder like what what year is
seven? You know, sometimes it's, you
know, two 10 years ago or 20 years or
one years ago, you don't know. So with
the version date, it's much more, you
know, when the version number is
actually contains the date is much
easier to see. Whenever you download
software, you know, you have to check,
oh, it's not compatible with Windows 7.
When was Windows 7? I I don't remember
you know
so so that's fantastic. Okay. So,
version date. So, so that's why clo
close. So, I that's why I added this new
option. So, let's try again. Press press
press press. And one of the one of them
is uh dotted version. You see dotted.
Fantastic. Okay. So that's demonstration
of um
that's the demonstration of insert date
and that's part of fly keys news. So
there's that and there's some other
command I change extend selection. This
is also a good one. Okay. So in in EMAC
or you know when you code you want to
press a key then you'll start to select.
So,
so in my case, I just press a single key
I on my left hand this finger. So, right
here, you see right right here. Can you
see? Right. So, so switch back. So, I
can so cancel deselect. So, if I want to
select a word, let's say fly, press a
key, it's selected. Press again, it
select the whole line. Is that
fantastic? Press again, it select the
next line. So that command is called
kasar extend selection. It's part of
kafly keys and you can get the command
too. So go to the source code keys and
here's the documentation and jump to the
URL open in browser. There it is. So you
can copy it, grab it for your own use.
Okay, that's uh that's that.
So fantastic. So safely keys news. Let's
see uh what else are new. So extend
selection there are minor changes use a
buffer. Okay. Next use a buffer. So let
me show you. Okay. So in EMAC when you
have right now for example I have
several files or buffers open. You see
how do you switch to the next one? Press
a key. So next next next. So let's say I
open uh
programming blog. Okay. back to Emacs
and bookmark. Open another JavaScript
blog. Open. Fantastic. And open another
let's say uh Emacs blog. Did I do so?
Math blog. So math. Okay. Showing
browser. So you got math blog, previous
tab, webdev blog, previous tab,
programming blog, previous tab, stuff
like keys, news. Now in Emacs, you can
do the same thing. Switch. Sweet. Next,
next next previous
next, previous next
previous.
You see? So that command you can see
right in the ping window. SA previous
user buffer and
next user buffer. Okay, that's a superb
fantastic convenient command. Okay, of
course you can get a key. I believe so.
Go to fly key source code. Is there a
URL there? Yes. So, open it. Show in
browser. So, you can grab
the code. So, it's my gift for you.
Okay. So, let's copy the URL. Go to talk
show and uh go here and paste the link
because I don't think I have the link.
Okay. So, paste paste. Okay. And this
date make it list showing browser. So,
that's what we talked about stuff like
keys news. Uh yeah, we covered that. So
the there are also update like a week
ago. So I constantly code code code and
non-stop
uh for your benefits. Okay, if you like
my stuff, pay me. Go to all the way to
kasabi.info
homepage and all the way at the bottom.
So pay me Patreon, Amazon gift card,
PayPal.
Okay. And this you know when you click
on that you you know it's not
automatically you know you have to type
my email address because I like that
way. So you are you know you are
actually paying me. So pay me you know
if you have a job if you work you know
as a coder you make a lot of money you
know pay me $100. Thank you very much.
Okay. So soft uh so that's pay payment.
That's today's sponsor. Okay. And let's
go back to uh go back to what we talking
about. So
uh so let's yeah talk show. So we talked
about uh insert date. We talked about
extend selection code. We talked about
next previous buffer switch to the next
uh and let's move them. Let's join the
list and uh and uh
and uh let's see and uh keys news. Cut
it. Move the to the top. Join the list
and cut the entire list. Move to the top
and uh paste it here. And there's a
duplicate. You can see you can show all
duplicate links. There you go. Yellow
means the first first occurrence. Green
means it's a repetition. So remove that
and join this two list. Show in browser.
Fantastic. That's what we have talked
about. Okay. Then uh next thing let's
talk about this. This is more technical.
This is for Emac this programmers
generic map function. So a month or a
few month ago we talked about that in
Emacs there's a new library actually
pretty old by now from 2016. So they are
it's a library called map.el E and uh in
the library it contains like about 10 15
functions that's for hash table for
association list for um
property list okay so all these data
types so these are data types so this is
very technical okay uh for eag coder so
all these association list property list
symbol property list and hash table they
are all data type of key value pairs. So
they are all collections of
items. Each item is a key and a value.
Okay. So
before this library in order to you know
extract a key you know get get the value
of a given key you have to call specific
functions. But now this map.el E library
is a gen gen generic. So you can call
these functions for any of these data
type. So what they call uh the C C++ the
C++ and Java people they would call it
generic functions uh generics uh which
is a very idiotic name. Okay but anyway
so that's what they are gener generics.
Okay, general purpose functions can you
know for key value pairs data structure.
Okay, so you got these new ones uh they
but they however they are not documented
in EMAC this manual. Okay, so there's no
actually they are not officially
documented. The only documentation is
the inline documentation. For example,
let's call describe function map length.
Okay, enter. Then you can see map length
is uh you know blah blah blah in map
eel. Uh this is the syntax map length
map return the number of key value pairs
in map. Okay so you got this inline
documentation but there's no official
emac documentation.
Do you know what I mean? Uh let's see uh
let's see
for example let's look up regular
expression. So we are looking at the GNU
Emacs manual. So you can go up
you go you go up you know chapter
section 35.3 regular expressions you
know lots of documentation. So then you
go up that's part of the chapter 35.2
search and case searching and case go up
searching and string. Okay, let's go up.
Um, go up chapter 35, searching and
matching. And go up and we are looking
at emacisp manual. Okay, so that's about
1,000 pages. So that's official
documentation for emacisp the language
close. But however, it doesn't have you
know this map functions are not
documented.
Uh what is the reason they are not
documented? I'm not too sure. Uh, but
this library being around since 2016.
Okay. So, fantastic for you Emac these
coders. So, I'm starting to write a
tutorial for them. So, let me start.
Let's let's write one. Okay, let's do
one. Let's say map filter. A very useful
function. So, right now I don't have a
documentation. So, so let's do it. Map.
And maybe that's it for today. So search
for filter. There it is. So you first of
all you look at the documentation. So
copy that
and uh okay let's just say so let's
start a code emac this code. Paste it.
We're going to do it later and first and
say here filter a map something. Okay.
But actually what we want is look at the
documentation. So describe function
there. Okay, so it says return a an
association list of key value pairs blah
blah blah the default infl. Okay, so
copy that, close that and paste it.
Okay, so here is a syntax. Now let's do
some markup. So it shows on my tutorial
as red you know like syntax coloring
that you see you see you see this green
that means those are variables
red means literal. So you know you have
to type paren and map apply. Then green
means
uh variable. So so this function is
whatever your function you know that
it's not literal. So let's do the
markup. So right now if you show it uh
you know let's say field refresh you can
you see it's ugly. So now we have to do
some markup. So delete that. So let's
say so let's call
capital cap uh bracket
capital uh wait bracket capitalized
words okay do it you can see it adds
this French quote fantastic and press
the key they become HTML markup so all
these are because I'm using HTML mode.
Uh you can search it, you'll find it.
You have to pay me to get it. Okay. So,
but anyway, so now put a make a
paragraph of that then make a paragraph
of this. So, let's say return a
association list. So, let's show in
browser first. Refresh. You can see now
it's much beautiful. Now,
a list we want to make a link. So
association list uh
there copy the file path close it paste
it and linkify. So there so return an
associate association list of key value
pairs.
Okay, I don't want to. So you see this
is my tutorial. So I want to word it in
other way. So filter. So let's say it
should be filter a
map.
Filter a map by a
by by this function. Okay. predicate
by a function uh
function uh not file name function
predicate.
Okay. So
markup. Okay. Filter a map by by
function predicate. Okay. And uh if
predicate return true
the
item is kept something like that. So
that's kind of wording thing
then return an association list. Okay.
So let's say so delete that that okay
show in browser. Let's see which version
is better. This is involving technical
writing. So one way to say it is uh
return an association list of key value
pairs for which predicate key value is
nil in map.
Okay. The alternative way to say it is
filter a map by function predicate. A
predicate return true the item is kept
return an association list. Okay. So
that is the style I prefer itemized,
concise,
simple, you know, instead of the, you
know, the grammatic grammatical
complexity, you know, return something
for which something parenthesized
clause is the neo and this the
neo just say true. Okay, n is a emac
tradition to indicate true because this
why do they say n? Why don't they just
say true? Because in immac there's
actually no boolean data type. There's
no true and false. So you either have
neo which is considered false. Anything
else is considered true. So when they
want to say true, they don't say true.
They say the neo like every time you
read it, you have to think about oh you
know what what a that is. So this
is a little about technical writing and
human cognissance.
Okay. So, we got a comment. Simple
postman. Hi, I think I remember your
name long ago. H I'm learning your uh
safely keys. Fantastic. Thank you for
being a patreon of that. My that's my uh
best thing I've done in my life kind of
at moment. Great design. We'll pay you
when I get some income. Fantastic. Thank
you. If today's uh uh today is about
this Yes.
So I'm interested in your opinion about
cop list that compiles into uh C. Okay.
Uh is there another new list? I haven't
heard of it.
Okay, let me get to the question. Okay,
so but this is off topic. So let's just
quickly look at look up cop lisp. You
know it's kind of related to today but
because we are talking about lisp. COP
is a statically typed list programming
language designed for real time and high
performance applications.
That's novel. Notably targeting digital
game development. Oh, okay. The language
borrows its syntax from closure. Okay.
Uh and oh and mention Rust and to and
are closer to those ML or Rust. ML is
fantastic functional programming
language. is stand for meta language
which we have the family of Okamo and F
and F is the best language okay so it's
you know it's a it's a it's modern okay
let's look at the website so this must
be something new that's interesting you
know uh statically typed list oh that's
interesting with oh without a garbage
collection That's up for real
time applications. Okay. Well, for real
time usually they don't want garbage
collection. But I think you know in my
biased opinion that's idiotic. You
always want garbage collection. Okay.
Unless you are doing assembly unless
unless you are doing microchips. Okay.
Like even Goland is garbage collected.
So so-called garbage collection that
well. So what does garbage collection
mean? What the is that? The is
that? This is C C++ jarens. It It means
automatic manage memory management.
Okay, garbage collection means automatic
memory management. But why why do people
keep saying garbage collection? Garbage
collection. Why don't they just say the
more clear me automatic memory
management? Why? Because they these nerd
That's part of the code.
Because when you say garbage collection,
it's like dramatic. Oh, garbage
collection. What is it? Like every
people start to ask. So you become more
popular. Garbage collection. Oh, you
know the science, the art of garbage
collection. So that's from the C and C++
and Unix idiots. Okay, the garbage
collection. If you just say memory
automatic memory management, it
clarifies everything. And then a lot of
the people who don't know better, they
will suddenly realize it's a good thing.
Okay, you always want garbage collection
today, especially today, you know, the
in in our this AI artificial
intelligence edge age. Okay. So anyway,
so cop I don't I haven't I I have not
heard about it before. So, let's turn on
JavaScript so Google knows where you
live. And let's look at is there a date?
Let's see when did this start. Oh, four
years ago. Okay. Uh, it kind of began.
So, so all these are five five years
ago. Is this dead? Is this project dead?
That's the question.
So, uh, so answer so simple postman. So,
is you know, so what's going on?
failing, failing, failing. Okay. Is this
project dead?
You don't know. So, you know, anyway, it
seems interesting.
But is there a major corporation
support? Because that's most important
because otherwise
lots of these most of these languages
are one man show. You know, I'm going to
create a language, you know, it's just
like very few uh users maintainers.
Okay. It's kind of like
okay Eric
it's created by Erican
and uh okay so I don't know about this
project it's new to me so sounds
interesting but you know a lot new
programming language languages sound
interesting but it will it be popular
you know you need to be very robust so
you know it looks But you know this uh
for real time application looks very
good but look look at the date you know
it doesn't seems much updated it's like
five years old
and uh so you need to be robust but most
importantly you need major corporation
sponsorship like you you need to say
Microsoft is sponsoring Google or
whatever Facebook then you have a chance
like you know otherwise it's just one
man show like scheme like scheme this
bracket is you know for 30 years they
are like tail recursing in Mars like
nobody knows
cop list this okay good luck
okay so ACP have a question do map
functions modify the map in place or
return a new map that's a good question
I think most of them return a new map
because this is part of the new uh
generation of libraries you know when
where you know in past 15 years
functional programming became more
popular so I think most of them return a
new I I I think I'm pretty sure okay
that's my guess but I haven't really uh
looked into I think well yeah I don't
know that that depends because
um
well let's see because we are working on
filter So we can just try filter. Okay.
So let's see. Map apply return the
result as a list. Okay. That return.
Yeah, usually they return a new thing. I
think some return association list. Some
return some others. Some return uh
others. I think it depends. Okay. So
let's keep working on the filter then we
are done. So let's see map filter. Okay.
So let's continue. So we are missing
something here. we need to say
uh what argument the function takes.
Okay, the function the function
predicate takes two ox
uh key
vow. Okay, something like that. Okay. Uh
okay. So cut that that that that that
that that that that that.
Okay. And delete the first part.
Okay. Refresh. Filter map by function
pelicut. If predicate return true, the
item is kept. The function pelicut take
two arguments key value return
association list. Okay, that's good
enough. Now let's start coding. Let's
make a create an example. Okay. So, uh
create a example. Let's we need a
example. Let's say we need a hash table.
So, let's just copy that. So, that code
uh delete that. Delete that. Delete
that. Delete that. So, this part create
a hash table and let's work on that. So,
map filter. I don't have a a brief I
don't have a template. So, let's
manually. So, map filter. So, what is
the documentation again?
filter predicate map. Okay, so you need
the predicate first
lambda and you need the
xx the map second. Okay. Now what is the
function for the lambda? Well, it takes
two things. So let's say key and v.
Okay. So
let's say so return. So okay. So if
so let's key let we we we we will check
the value. So if the value is odd we'll
keep it. Okay let's say that. So so we
don't need a key. So use underscore.
That's the convention. If you don't need
a key name it underscore which is a
allowed character in variable name.
Okay. So if
if
this is mode okay well so what wait
what's the difference between percentage
and mode
extra question okay I forgot but anyway
let's quickly code this first okay so if
value
modular arithmics that means divided by
two and so mod means a value divided by
a number and it returns the uh
remainder. Okay. So if this equal let's
say let's check okay equal works on
number. So if that
equals to zero then return true else
return. Okay false. So predefine the
code. So are we good to go? So let's see
lambda key value if zero mod value two.
So that means even keep okay otherwise
okay so let's let's run this and uh so
first of all run that then run this and
uh paste the result here. So press press
press
fantastic is it correct? Yes. So you can
see the command call on the pink window.
Okay. So this is the result. Fantastic.
So let's
put it back.
Syntax code show in browser
and uh Okay. So let's see. So fantastic
and beautiful. Okay. So does that double
check work? Yes. And let's update the
last update date. So press press press
press. showing browser September 4th.
Correct. I think that's it for today. Uh
and I'm going to have wife noodles.
Simple postman says it's a oneman show
basically. I hope that it would be
something as useful as elixir or odling.
Oing cop doesn't have any corporate
support. Yeah, that's too bad. you know
this one main show
um usually they go nowhere you know you
know it it's not it's not necess because
the programming language is no good it's
just because you need corporate
sponsorship you need you need somehow to
make it like have a big sizable user
base you know you can't be just like few
interested in programming languages
because that's you end up you know you
just disappear because there are 100 200
more programming languages most of them
are one man show okay so
I mean this is this doesn't mean your
language is is not good even if you are
a genius like for example there is this
there is this um for example there is
this language uh so let's talk random
for a bit so search for Um
uh search for what's the language name
programming language um
so minus
wra
so uh what is the uh
jargon and what and what determines a
programming language popularity That's
one of my rant written in 2007. So let's
go to here so I can find where is my um
the article I'm trying to find. Okay.
Comp lisp perving. No. Complving
syntax soup semantic noodle. No. Uh why
Python sucks. Why Python doc sucks. And
so the the article I'm trying to find is
let me think. Okay? Because otherwise
trial and error will waste time. So
uh wait
programming language vu so what
proliferation of programming languages
okay that's the word I want to search so
proliferation of programming languages.
So search proliferation there that is
the article I'm looking for. Okay. So
here's a here's a you know a kind of
list of programming languages and their
history.
So here is a lisp family timeline. So
Mathematica wam language and uh new
lisp. So new lisp is another oneman
show. It has some some kind of user base
but but anyway have you heard of it? No.
Right. So it began in 1991.
Uh archalisp is Paul Graham. That's
another white man show. Basically only
him using it. Paul Graham. Even though
you see Paul Graham is a top list
expert. Okay. But that's just it doesn't
matter. You need you need to somehow get
it popular have corporate sponsorship
otherwise you are just nobody's using
it. Okay. And one good another good
great example is this chiisp
and today known as shen. Okay. So I
designed the logo for the guy
chisp. Okay. So and now it kind of
evolved into they they he renamed it
Shen. Okay. So Shen is a dead language.
Nobody knows. Okay, that's another leisp
that's like
I suppose very good. Okay. So I mean
it's like uh it's kind of like Hascal
um you know but nobody nobody knows you
know nobody and this guy very
interesting story. Okay. So these are
examples genius programmer. Okay. He you
know this guy is one of the great you
know he know what he's doing. Shen chis
you know artist program
but nobody knows. Okay what can you do?
So closure is a counter example. Closure
also begin it also is a oneman show by a
guy Richiki. Nobody know what you know
who who the he is you know but it
became very super popular in fact it's a
you know like fairly popular you know
popular by that I mean in in the
industry you know if you are looking for
a job can you find a job with that
programming language yes you can okay
but not compared to like C++ or coland
but you can you can find it like okay
you can find a job so
closure is a counter example. So when
you program when you create a language
you may you need to somehow market it to
have industrial acceptance otherwise
it's you know it's like nobody care like
scheme scheme is a good good example
scheme by now it's like 40 40 years
scheme history but but it's like who who
is using scheme you know the Joe clowns
like the teenagers teenagers they post
this you know they post this this every
Hey, every day they
but but nobody cares.
Okay, that's a story. Okay, I think
that's it for today. Let's see. Uh
what's uh so
so that's 40 minutes? Yes. Okay, so
let's see. Um sad question. Is xx now a
global variable? Yes. So yes. So wait,
so what uh yeah. So let's see filter. So
actually we need to update the code a
little bit. Okay. So cop lisp we need to
need move to talk show not here not
there. So because we talked about cop
lisp. So let's post it there and
and go to this page and and copy that
paste it there. That's the that's one of
the great book. This is a great book
structure and interpretation of computer
programs. I read it in 1999. Okay. Uh I
read
three quarter of it. So three over four,
you know, except the last chapter and
and go back to this uh proliferation of
programming languages. Let's past it
there. Linkfy. Okay. Show today's talk
show. So proliferation of programming
languages. This is kind of long article.
So you got Dan also dead was sponsored
by Apple but kind of dead the change of
times meta language fantastic or camel f
the best and several variations Alice
and proof systems and modern
functional programming language has
concurrent clean nobody knows today it
was one of the best functional
programming in the 1990s.
Uh then you got Mercury and you know the
power derivatives uh PHP and uh and you
got this sleep and grow and something
groovy
you know you know objective C C sharp
those are C
C canc cancer cancerous objective C
sharp those are from the C didous
idiots.
they change a little bit over the years
because there there's always a problem.
So after 30 years eventually we got go
is fantastic. Okay. So the JavaScript,
the PowerShell, the TCL, Lua and the
Lynden scripting language very different
uh uh interesting Lindon scripting you
can never imagine
then uh and random thoughts and uh then
you know more languages. Va genie factor
uh go fantastic and rust a new new king
in town new kid in the block rust 2010.
Okay. Garbage collection. Garbage
collection. That's these type of people,
rust idiots.
They they got to have t they got to
chant about garbage collection and
pointers and and pointers and
references. That's these type of people
bitlers. Okay, that's the name for them.
Bit dler. Bit diddling. You know, Julia,
another functional programming language.
Fantastic. Coffee script dead dot
kind of dead you know Google's Google's
Java in JavaScript in Java okay kind of
dot um typescript you know uh omea and
elm and hacks and uh hack and uh
egisonen I forgot what is egisonen swift
from apple elixir and cotlin Land
Cotland is super popular. You see Colin
very interesting you see you need to
make again you the point is you need to
make your language accepted in the
industry okay you need to find some way
if you are just a nerd like me oh I
don't know anything about business oh I
don't know you know I don't want to talk
to people your language is one man show
after five years it's dead like nobody
cares nobody use it but cotling is
created by uh is it's created by one
guy, right? One guy from the uh from
that um Jet Brands um
company which is not a big company, a
small company, they create editors, you
know. So they they create and this is
overwhelmingly popular became became one
of the industrial standard replacing
Java. Okay. On on on the phone on the
you know
uh cell phone. So cotling so how they do
it how how did they do it I don't know
but they you know you got to make it
that's you know you know the the
question about success
and nim is another oneman show I'm not
sure there's many users a lot of people
are tell me vim vim you know it's like
vim oh don't don't use rust vim yeah but
it's well it's one man show and and
Christ crystal is another lisp thing I
think is also one man show. No, nobody
use it. Uh anyway,
so the one I'm learning is the uh ling.
Okay, that's what ling and f although I
haven't done much in the past four
months. It kind of sad because this ling
and f is what I really want to like
master. Okay.
So, I think that's it. Bye, guys. Pay
me, okay? Donate to me. Thank you guys.
Okay. So, now it's dead. Okay. I'm a bit
idealistic. Want to create this fast
like common list, but I despise OP and C
O S. That's correct. I agree totally.
You know the the the object
contaminated lisp.
Yeah. You know making money is probably
the most important. I mean yes. I mean
practically that's you know stop tech
geeking like me. Uh that's why I'm
almost died of hunger like literally in
USA. Hard to believe but that's that's
you know you if you want to be like me
like sometimes you I hear my people my
fans say how do you get to learn so many
things how do you how do you you know so
you know have the enthusiasm how how can
I be like you
chances are you probably don't want to
be like me yes you got you know you know
a lot of stuff but are you willing to
suffer hunger
like literally for 10 years you know
like when you when you know it's uh
anyway but mostly that's semi joke okay
but most people are not going to be have
a lot of problem because you you you
know unless you are extreme nerd you
know usually you know you go find a job
you know if you are you know have some
expert expertise in some programming
language you'll find a job, you know.
Um,
yeah, code somehow it took off. People
liked it. Okay, bye guys.
So, I clean up. We shut down in one
minute.
Okay, that's what we want to talk about.
Yeah. So, we did it. Fantastic.