to another episode ofan talk show today
we we are going to do swoard this
fantastic keyboard okay fantastic input
device Advanced if you are here say hi
hello Crystal ch ch thank
you uh and uh if you are watching
offline feel free to skip around because
I ramble a lot uh if you are expecting
this to be a perfect introduction
representation you know with quality
photos and videos this is not it
probably because I ramble a lot okay so
today I'm just going to explore this
fantastic device I'm going to uh set it
up try to plug it in for the first time
it's be being delayed for a long if you
want the introduction you can watch my
previous video
about five months ago it's on my YouTube
just search for SV l b o a r d okay CH
Ching Crystal thank
you um so so small board okay so we
going to try to set it up today uh this
so uh you know let me do a a little
introduction so this is a like Advanced
input device so you got two pieces and
uh let me just show you so each finger
you have this uh five Keys one 2 3 4
North South left right and also you can
press the key down now this um okay I
don't have great videos but uh maybe you
can see okay so and optionally you can
you you also get a track ball or track
point so this is mouse and for the thumb
it's special so you got one two
three four uh Keys plus you can press it
down five so one two three four five and
when you press it down you can hold it
like then it becomes a click so you got
six uh triggers basically for the thumb
so I think this is a fantastic device
that I will be using down the road for
years for years to come so but the uh
the issue is that you have to spend some
time to learn
uh about a month or two I I would
suppose two month or three months to
become really
fluent and there's a lot possibilities
so let me explain about the hardware a
bit more so each of these key is
magnetic device mag magnetic switch
meaning that once you dislodged the
magnet there's no resistance so it's
it's better than any uh mechanical
switch such as spring based mechanical
switch such as Cherry MX and each of
these piece you can actually take it out
take it out so you know you just pull it
off you know it you you just pull it
pull it off each and every one of
these so you see you you just pull it
off and when you pull it off you can
see this thing this uh wedge
they have you know so there's a magnet
or iron you know I don't know it's a
magnet or but anyway that's a like
magnetic part um you cannot see it too
clearly uh my lousy camera so so anyway
so so each of these are swappable you
know it's like swappable keyboard I mean
swappable socket so you can change this
so they become thicker and and allows
you to
you know so you don't have to move your
fingers so much so you know it's
customizable So when you buy it from the
guy you know on my website or just
search for SP board SV b o r d you'll
find the guy's website you can tell him
you know what do you you know what kind
of customization you like I think so but
anyway today I'm just going to try to
plug this in for the first time and play
with it okay so do you guys have enough
views or any
questions uh it's
a you know you can ask me so this is
Smartboard I'm going to plug in for the
first time so you see on the back you
got each component got two
USBC okay so one goes to the computer
the other goes to the other
device same thing for the left so you
you would have one extra empty
Port so they also included cables for me
uh so let's see USBC so I will need so
let let me just plug it in okay and this
keyboard so let me go back to the screen
this keyboard is using the most advanced
software to program it it's programmable
so you can you know you can change each
one of these key press to be any layout
you want roak quity of course they are
not the standard
keyboards but similar for example you
you know like if you press the northern
key they are like the upper row if you
press the Southern key they are like the
lower row and if you just press it down
they are like the middle row so similar
to a like standard keyboard yeah but
still you take some time to learn and
also Okay so let me switch back also so
north side is the the top row South
South Side is the bottom row but all
these left and right they do special
things and so each one of them is can be
programmed and the way you program it is
using the most advanced I know because
I've tried it I've tried you know
because several other keyboards I have
use that software so the most advanced
software called uh VI okay let me uh so
you program it via this V vile software
download it free it's open source um and
uh it's fantastic okay so let me just
try to plug it
in um and see how it goes I already
downloaded the latest file version
um you know but I never plugged it in
before so this is you know I'm going to
try it so this is how it looks like
um right yeah so you can see in the bio
software let's let's just plug it in
okay if you can time travel to year 2000
would you sell your younger self to
learn small board or data hand so as to
prevent long-term isi any other advice
you would say uh that's a hypothetical
question if I travel back to year 2K
I mean this device I mean this
particular one is not around yet but you
do have the data hand but that cost you
to $3,000 back then okay
so so if you mean I can get it for
free then maybe okay but yeah why maybe
because this thing takes some time to
learn and uh then you cannot I mean I
mean it's a wheel device right so if you
can use it home at home but at work you
know you may not um carry it around or
things like
that anyway my opinion that is that this
is uh this would be I think because I
haven't used it long time yet it would
would be a great device if but you know
for the average person if I travel back
you know 20 years ago I would I I know
what's you know to prevent RSI just get
linear
switches that's it okay linear light
switches that's the most important thing
and also several programming habits
anyway let's not talk about that because
today I want to focus on
the on getting this uh set up so so yeah
so let's go to my uh so I already
downloaded vile so let's turn it on uh I
mean let's open
it can you
see okay so V is up now there's no
device so no device uh detected so I
need to plug it in so usba a to USB C so
let me just do
that uh can you
see uh you cannot quite see but anyway
this is
just okay so so I need a so this is very
nice
this let me explain I'm just going to go
slowly okay for those of you so this one
side is a usba the other side is
magnetic and the twistable uh head you
see very nice cable uh cren gave it to
me so you got three magnetic heads so
the one you know one is for Apple
devices one is for USBC the other one is
USB you know the previous version the
USB uh don't know what's that micro plug
or something so I want the USB C
here magnetics
so just attached it on okay wait so
there it is so okay so let's do
that okay I need to find a hole
okay so I need the hole but so first of
all I need to turn off I need to unplug
my glove
0 but if I do that I don't have the main
keyboard so first of all I need to turn
on
Bluetooth then unplug the pl gl8 because
gra8 can use Bluetooth
okay so now this goes to the
hole and now the other side goes to
the you can plug it into either part but
if you have a mouse pointer on the right
hand side you want to plug to the mouse
po Point part
so
yeah
fantastic okay so the other
plug that needs to go between them so
they are also
[Music]
USBC that's right so that's this one
USBC
and uh the head needs to be USBC so
you're going
to pick
out this
one there it
is okay
so fantastic
fantastic so now I have it plugged
in okay so let's adjust this so you can
see kind of like
that so how do I
know oh there's a light I don't know if
you can see but there's a light there so
it is plugged it
in fantastic
okay so
now I just need to let's see if
the vile software detects
it keyboards let's go to
keyboards
uh Gabriel hey Gabriel So let let me
check the answers I mean the questions
later but let let's go to the vile
software so no device detected so
refresh okay
refresh okay so maybe restart
V can you guys see okay no so go back
here
so restart
V uh no device detected
okay so let's see
so system Doc in order to fully apply
the theme you should restart the
application okay I don't
care H keyboard layout okay
so okay so let's close this vile let's
try the old version of vile
okay so no device detected connect a v
compatible device and press refresh okay
maybe I should bug closen
uh Leon hi Leon hi Gabriel so a lot of
questions my hair is beautiful okay so
let's focus on this so why does it say
no device compatible device
detected
um shouldn't be so
let's so make sure I plugged in the
right place so this is to PC that's
right and uh the light is
on and this is to the other part
okay oh I wait okay I connected wrong so
this got to go there okay that's why
maybe
yeah you see this is a
magnetic plug so you know so that's why
it's kind of stuck
there okay I need to get the tracers
oh it's so
easy so this needs to go over
here yeah
then then I just snap it
on too many cables I have here okay so
put my glasses back so now now let's
what we do now let's try to run V so
lights on let's try try to run
vile okay no device so no device
detected connect a vile compatible
device and press refresh okay let's try
refresh or select file download via uh
download VR definitions in order to
enable support for VR keyboards okay
download VR definitions okay
download file download VR
definitions okay uh let's try
refresh uh didn't say anything let's see
download VR definitions
do
it okay refresh nothing happens close
via let's open it
again no device detected okay what's
going on this font is pretty small so it
cannot be enlarged that's too
bad refresh okay no device
detected now let's
try you know being a software engineer
so you kind of know you just have to try
lots of
things so this goes to the PC
yes oh I forgot oh you have to you know
you don't you don't even have to unplug
it because this is magnetic you just you
just snap it
off right so this is two PC are you sure
yes okay now it's connected now there's
a light I take it
off the light is still on but if I
unplug
here the light is off okay so you know
we are doing this
methodologically logically one step by
step we'll
find okay now it's good now I hear
Windows making a USB sound that looks
good okay now let's start V
again
uh do
it ah beautiful can you guys see
it
fantastic okay actually now we can
actually type with this keyboard let's
show we try it okay so you got you see
um can you guys see it clearly you know
this can you magnify
this I don't I don't really want to
press anything can you guys see this
fantastic so now we can actually type
with this
keyboard there it is SW board small
board okay and uh let's try to type it
so let's open let's not use emac let's
stick with the notepad 101 okay so
delete how do you do delete I I forgot
so let's say
q h q
w qw okay you have to be careful not
pressing other keys can you guys see
me yeah so can you see
qw uh let's see is is this delete no
that's enter now what is this space Oh
Enter
space delete oh delete is this fantastic
they are so light fantastic beautiful
so q q okay you need to enter enter q w
e r t oh T is T is the
T
is uh I forgot I don't know where is T
let's see oh t t is that okay so T is
let's see
enter q w e
r
t fantastic and the right hand side
there there it is UI
o p okay it takes some used to you see
so let's uh how how am I doing uh do you
guys see it so you
see fantastic oh then there's a pressing
down Okay so let's try pressing the key
down and uh so this is
enter so let's press the key down let's
put the hand in the position so a
SDF oh fantastic as SDF
space then this JK
L semicolon enter fantastic okay now
what is a delete oh this okay now I can
actually
fantastic yeah
so so far my impression is just
fantastic so far um let's see the down
Row the bottom row X so enter X ZX x c
v um and uh how do you type the other
one
zxcv B so where is b b okay B is the
ring finger push that way okay
Enter then then the right hand ring
finger oh this is closing the document
do you want to save so you see no I
don't want to save so no is n how do you
type
n now quy n is
um quy n is the
right pointing finger finger downwards
okay so no wait is that n so let's check
let's be careful here go
here where is quy n oh okay it's uh
right so
yeah so that's right so you have to
press that key so it's a ring finger the
ring finger left side do it do
it
okay but maybe you can just press in can
you actually just press in it's try oh
because I'm
on wait I'm am I on Uso borak okay so
wait let's try in here n okay n doesn't
work because you have to
press uh normal is control n right let's
try this control
n wait n actually should work anyway I
don't know what so let's try the mouse
pointer oh fantastic the mouse pointer
Works can you
see oh you guys cannot see okay so
fantastic you can see the mouse pointers
work the this is the what's What's this
called
The Pointer stick no the
IBM uh Red Dot that's
called
uh what is it called I forgot but anyway
this fantastic so actually for the first
time I got this setup to work I mean
trying this for the first time it works
so far the impression is pretty
good
um yeah so you you just have to learn it
so there's also the Windows key the
shift
key
fantastic okay let me answer the
questions and maybe that's it for today
so if you guys have questions for me ask
about this keyboard okay uh track
trackpoint that's word yeah thank you
Jeff trackpoint yeah abbm famous from
the IBM Thinkpad since
1990s okay let me answer the questions
CH Ching thank you Chris uh hello your
hair looks beautiful fantastic uh if you
can time TR okay so Gabriel says the bad
thing about uro keyboards Mar pads
function keys is that every program has
its own
shortcuts uh yeah that's true
yeah when you are on standard keyboard
like this then you know everything you
know where things are but when you have
like orgonomic keyboard like me you know
gra you know I have so many so each one
is different you have to look up the
manuals especially when they print it
you know the especially when you
customize your keyboard for example
usually you do for example on this gra
80 you know I have some micro keypad so
but after a while you know after if you
haven't used been using it for 3 months
because maybe you are using another one
then you come back you forgot where the
keys are so you and if you haven't
written it down somewhere then it's
pretty bad then you have to reprogram
you know like typically things like that
um so Leon says use V bindings they
exist for browser and IDs which is where
the majority your time will be spent
presumably uh well Vin binding is is one
of the choice or you can use S FL Keys
which
is superior than VM bindings to be
honest because I made it s flly Keys
okay if you don't know you can search
for it um but uh uh but then it's not
available for the browser stuff you you
know I don't use V bindings or anything
uh okay I think there was a project to
enable V bindings within Windows okay so
I'm going to buy smallb one day okay
seems worthy investment yes I think um
yeah so my impression so far is just
great uh oh I have to be careful
actually I don't want to press the keys
it's doing
something uh what is that okay now I
need to press
Escape Okay so left hand ring
finger push left okay there oh
okay
so s is not a big fan of V yeah so grav
slowly will be displaced uh
yeah uh oh by the way I got a new gravat
so I'm going to show you guys uh next
you know down the road in pretty soon
uh new
switches so about
shortcuts yeah so this keyboard this
small board you know I looked at it
right you know I I've been having so I I
think this fantastic because you use now
you have uh so many great possibilities
for mro keys and uh you know programming
the keys to do copy paste or whatever
like for example I use you know as you
know I use this ultimate hacking
keyboard here as my marro keypad so I
got 60 function keys you know when I
want to this you know you need them
because you know previous tab next tab
for example uh can I show it
here yeah so previous tab next tab close
uh you know full screen or close the
current
tab open the last close tab by mistake
if you you know uh and the you know next
window previous window uh volume I mean
switch keyboard
layout uh I gotta be careful because I
switch to Chinese over I don't know what
I'm doing
especially so back to English layout so
and and this key is for switching
windows
uh and this one so back backward Windows
forward
window so you I got six marro keys there
but with the
Smartboard you know you can like then
you don't
need you know I think you don't need
even a MCO pad because you really do
have a lot of
possibilities you uh especially with the
VR software the VR software is basically
a very powerful it's it's a fork from
qmk I
think okay and well I no no the VR
software is a user interface to the qmk
uh firmware so so it makes it much
easier to program the
keys and uh and you can program combo
keys and you know tab dance which means
you you press a key to
to activate the layer then you can type
something for example numbers then press
it again it revert back or something
like that or you can hold it down so you
have all these
possibilities so you see qmk set
settings key override you know so I I
use it before for the my
expose uh oh you are not seeing my
screen so you know so back to the screen
so I use it for my so you got the Marco
Keys here you know 2025 and
more 27 M35 m m41 m you know like 50 you
know something marro keys so so VR
software is just a fantastic user
interface to the
qmk firmware which is the most powerful
uh firmware for programmable keyboard
and both are open source so with this
swoard
I can you know I can imagine this's just
going to be a lot
of uh
potential okay I think that's it for
today any any other
questions uh if you have a questions tag
me okay uh tag me and that's it for
today inner Port should be connected
outer p go to the
PC uh no not Technic technically no not
that's not true so that's why I got
confused for a moment I don't know if
the current version you know has changed
but let's go back to the um Spar board
so you can see The Spar
board
they you know there's a
manual um
and uh you can see over here you see
normally on a on a keyboard normally the
inner two ports are connect to each
other but that's not the case for Spar
board in the case of Smartboard they are
left right left right so they are like
copied over
so so so you know on one part of the
keyboard the inner one is connected to
the other piece but on the other piece
it's the outer one that connects to the
other piece so it's like that so that's
a bit you know that's that's why I got
confus I pluged it wrong before so um
but I don't know if they change it you
know maybe they changed it uh but you
see there's a picture indic
indication you can see there's a a
little picture you they actually show
you but my video my camera is not so
good so maybe you cannot see you see
there's a picture this picture means
connect
to you know this this picture means
connect to the other part you see the
other picture means means connect to PC
yeah
there okay
uh you have to use software solution
like your software Keys okay that's it
uh guys thank you for
watching bye
guys yeah I think that's yeah so I'm
going to you know I'm going to play with
this uh maybe half an hour a day uh then
you know I'll let you guys know how it
goes and uh you know I I'm going to have
a lot to do with this because right now
by default C is using quy layout you see
this is getting a deep
territory you know so you know as you
guys may know I study a lot keyboard
layout
efficiency okay let me let me let me
just digress we we closing down in three
minutes okay so you go through my
website keyboards for example here's all
my
keyboards um
you know I I uh so you know I have all
these keyboards and uh so you know one
of the
things I studied is the keyboard layout
efficiency so you go to layout so you
can see ergonomic layouts so
magnify so you can see you got you know
Cy vorak comac and let's go switch to
quy and you can see the bigger Circle
means that letter is more used in this
case it's English you can switch to
Spanish or German you know let's go back
to English or you can switch to Chinese
ping in on quy layout or or pick vorak
so let's go back to quy and let's go
back to English so this is for normal
keyboard so for normal keyboard you want
the most frequent key is on the home row
right but that's not and and also the
top row is usually considered easier
than the bottom row on the normal you
know keyboard when you press it down but
but that's not the case for the SP board
for the SW
board I don't know for sure yet but it
seems like like pushing it down like the
claw motion you know like like grabbing
something is more convenient then then
go
outward
so so when you want to design an
efficient you know layout for for this
for this FBO it's going to take a while
so I don't know you know what I'm going
to do I might just try to learn the
quality layout
or I don't know you see this you know I
need need to think about it because on
one hand you know I'm a vac typer
so you know you might think that you
know I might change to vorax so they are
compatible but maybe maybe not because
they are entirely different muscle
memory so maybe on this I should use quy
but however we I know for sure that
quity is not very efficient I mean
doesn't matter which device quity is
just not efficient especially quy the
left hand you know the you know you the
top row is it you use often so that's
not the best for the SW board so I
probably will you know I don't know so I
have to try so okay that's it for this V
so for this uh SM
board yeah lot very interesting you know
I I would enjoy to study this uh and you
know I'll have to try and you know try
as I
go I wonder what put putting St or codes
yeah that's another very interesting
possibility I I've thought about because
this yeah I don't know how well that
works I I imagine it works very very
well because this um you know I I think
it also supports more than six
simultaneous
Keys yeah I you know and yeah anyway so
we'll have to see bye guys