good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of xl talk
show
today is 2017 2021 uh
april 24th and today we are going to do
uh lisp and mathematica lisp
and wufang language so this episode
would be interest to those of you
who are interested in programming
language syntax design
or if you are a lisp programmer
or if you are you know just interested
in wolfram language
mathematica then you'll find this
episode fun
and informal informative so good morning
bart good morning
jazke and friends
jason and jason from
friends oh hi jason khalif
and who who
introduced me to some technologies of
microphone and audio and good morning
uh this russian guy i don't know how to
pronounce
okay so we are going uh we are going to
do
2021 okay we are going to start to code
lisp and mathematic mathematica i'm
going to explain
the isomorphism of lisp syntax in
mathematica you know remember in uh let
me show let me tell you about
a few episodes before so if you look at
my uh
you know just search for talk show and
you arrive at my page
i did several episodes on mathematica
okay actually that's
it's easier if we just go to youtube
youtube then sally
okay i did a few episode on mathematica
and you would be interested to watch
okay where do i
uh videos okay let me show you okay
so starting with this one
uh star talk show 2021
february 6th then since then i did about
five videos on mathematica so you may
you know if you are interested in
mathematical start with that one
uh in fact i have a kind of a youtube uh
play list of my mathematical videos
okay so anyway let me begin okay let me
let's start
to talk about this serious topic lisp
versus wufang language versus emax oak
so
i'm going to show you the isomorphism
between this syntax and mathematica
syntax
and also the least symbolic form
and meta form if you are a lisp coder
you know what i'm talking about
and i'm going to uh explain the concepts
of prefix
infix postfix notations uh
and also then i'm going to do some demo
of typesetting
mathematica that i'm going to show
eventually
i'm going to show how the similarity
of uemax uses org mod users many
similarities
and functional equivalence you know you
know functional similarities about
using a mathematical notebook wufang
language in a book
and ogmod it can do essentially it's um
it's almost like oak mod everything ogma
can do mathematica can do
and much more actually so let's begin
okay
and and lastly let me okay let me show
you let me let me tell you about this
okay
so you go to uh xari yeah let me get
get this uh out first so you go to
programming
you go to wufam language uh so i have
two videos there you you know watch this
too uh
then then you go to
uh download wufam language for free you
know if you are a programmer
if you don't if you just want to try it
out
you know you there are several ways and
actually they are officially free wolfam
engine is free willful and script is
free
they are essentially the entire wolfram
language so you can
play and try it you can also try it
online okay
so okay copy that let's go back to emacs
and uh let's
um uh
uh language for free okay let's start to
do what we are going to do today so
so okay so uh
so first of all um
okay so if you have seen lisp
you know if you have not seen this
syntax for example this is a lisp syntax
uh this is my stuff like keys you can
see
this syntax is essentially lots of
parentheses
almost purely nested parenthesis that is
the list
syntax okay and the list syntax
essentially they you can generate the
entire syntax
uh let me let me just do the simple way
okay i mean let me explain in a simple
manner
instead of being formal okay so in
in in essence every this syntax
is this form okay they are either
an atom f or three or f
or two or three or three 3.5
or a string those are called atoms so
either they are atoms or they have the
form a parenthesis
then a sequence of atoms and it can be
nested so you can have that
or you can have uh that
that you know arbitrarily nested
this syntax so this is in lisp languages
this is called
symbolic expression okay symbolic
expression so forget about the atoms
basically just look like that
and you can see here check you know they
uh let me
show you some some uh
you know you see you see this uh you see
it's full of nesting you know
almost everything is nested brackets
parentheses
okay round brackets as the you united
kingdom
calls it okay now that's lisp syntax
okay
now let me tell you so there's
isomorphism between lisp syntax and
mathematics mathematical syntax okay uh
by the way lisp syntax
uh the use
space to separate atoms
for example okay for example you can
have
f34 you know there's a space in between
that means they are separate you know
so that's these syntax now what about
mathematica syntax
let me type it okay wufang language
syntax now they are almost
exactly the same in fact take take any
list
syntax you can transform it in a
systematic way
to obtain the equivalent mathematical
syntax
language syntax for example so
mathematica syntax let me show you so
it's
gonna be like that uh
let's simplify okay uh let's let's just
say that okay so
so what about how about this one how do
i how do you do that in mathematica
simple like that
you see that versus that
that versus that you see in the list
syntax you start with the parenthesis
then then you have several items inside
the first item
is considered the function and they
asked
uh usually okay and and and that the
first
item is usually called the head of the
expression head like
your head you know head of the
expression so in this syntax
this thing is called the head of
expression uh as an
actual example if we go here you see
this expression
so you can see this you know this real
life this
code this is the head of
that expression and similarly in this
expression the narrative region is the
head
and so on okay so in mathematica okay so
anyway let's go back to mathematica so
that's the least
syntax and that and this is the
mathematical syntax so in this
you start with a parenthesis then you
have a bunch of items
uh where the first one is the head of
the expression now in mathematica it's
similar
except you put the head
in the beginning then you put a square
brackets
they're nest or the same so for example
uh uh so for example okay and also in
mathematica you use comma
to separate items for example uh let me
let me write this okay so
f34 in mathematica would be written like
that three four okay
now now but let me show you what uh what
were we talking about
uh what was i going to say i i forgot
so anyway i i hope you see the the
equivalence
uh you know the kind of the isomorphism
in
in mathematics you kind of call that uh
isomorphism meaning that from one
thing there is a map one two one map
that transform this one thing to the
other thing and uh
preserve their structure so that applies
to
list this syntax and mathematical syntax
meaning you can transform one to the
other
and preserve their structure exactly
you just all you have to do is move the
head to the outside
then replace space by comma or comma by
space
vice versa so that is the um
okay so that concludes the isomorphism
thing
about lisp syntax in mathematica now go
back let's go back to
my talk show page let's write it down
okay
let's write it down
okay showing browser so we kind of
explained the first part
okay so first explain the isomorphism of
ideas leave syntax and
wu from language full form okay so
okay that's one thing now i have article
concepts
and confusions a prefix infix postfix
and lisp notations
now you need to go to
[Music]
concepts of prefix
infix post fix
this okay search for that there this
article
okay concepts and confusions of
prefix infix postfix and display
notations let me
okay let me quickly go of the go over
these notations so
in fixed notation looks like that this
is your typical arithmetic
you know uh traditional normal math
notation
five times two plus three then you have
post fixed notation this is actually
a polish post fix so you say
5 2 multiply that means 5 times 2
then you say 3 then you say plus that
means
add whatever previous two items that's a
postfix notation then you have the
prefix notation which is kind of just
the
reverse of the postfix notation so you
say
so you kind of work from right to the
left you know five
two and five then you multiply them then
you put three
then you add three and whatever
the sum of five and two that's a prefix
notation
then you have the lisp notation now
that needs no explanation we just did
before
so then you have the typical functional
notation in traditional math
mathematics for example sine cosine
uh you know so you put f then
parenthesis
then arguments okay
then you have kind of so-called match
fixed notation now
now this is also very common so you
essentially you
you bracket everything together
now you can you can see i have example
here but
most of you will probably familiar in
i mean any language pearl python ruby
c gold line c plus plus c sharp java
they all have that
for example array three four
five you know this is a typical array uh
syntax
in all these languages or you have a
block
of text uh three plus five you know
uh and and semicolon and return
let's say return okay return
so this is uh
these are this these these are called
match fix notation in
in a way okay there is actually no
standard name for this kind of notation
but
but in to be consistent with the infix
postfix prefix kind of thing
we call them match fix this is what
mathematica calls it
so when you have array example
array or list
in most languages
okay you have that
you know you just bracket them and and
what does that bracket mean that's kind
of a
that's kind of the operator matched
operator
so that means uh you know array and
for the code block
or sometimes scope block you know that
similar
match fix notation okay
okay let's copy that let's cut that and
let's put
uh that to here so we have kind of a
documentation
of what we did today there
match fixed notation okay so
anyway that's the digression digression
something about the syntax
but mostly i want to go back to
explaining lisp
and uh wolfram language okay so
so now we got comments
comments okay if you have a question to
me put my name to it
okay so so we have now
explained the isomorphism between these
syntax in mathematic
mathematical syntax now let me explain
the full glory of mathematical syntax
okay
[Laughter]
this is when we are going to go to
mathematica let me
demonstrate okay let me let me show you
okay so three plus five now you see that
three plus five uh
i mean three plus two right equals to
five now let's do three plus one equals
through four
you might be wondering hey exactly you
just said that mathematica has
you know it its syntax is fully
bracketed
you know fully nested brackets then
where do you get you know where do you
get that three plus one what's going on
i mean that should be embedded syntax
right that's not mathematical syntax
well let me explain
so mathematica syntax have
these um you know it's purely
nested brackets just like lisp okay
however it has a layer it has a
systematic
layer syntactical layer that
can transform any
uh nested expression to
to kind of a more a shorthand or
sometimes it's known as syntax sugar but
in mathematica it's very strict and
systematic now remember the word
systematic that means
for any expression you let me explain it
it's uh
it's easier if i just start to show you
okay
so in mathematica how do you write three
plus two you write it this way okay
plus three two
enter you see seven now is that
purely nested uh syntax yes you know
plus is the head of the expression and
three and four
is the kind of argument and you have
comma that separates
so how do you how do you do a three
times two
okay times
three two uh two okay enter
that's six correct how do you do
a okay so and similar for uh motor
for for divide and so on okay so let's
do a more complex
examples so let's say 3
3 plus 3 plus 2
[Music]
3 plus 2 times
2 okay so two and two is four four times
three is
uh sensor 12 right
oh wait oh first yeah so
three plus two times two is seven now
what is the
you know what what is the um the
mathematical nested syntax for that that
is easy let me show you
plus three actually you can imagine what
it is
right plus three then nested okay then
times two and two
okay enter seven so
let me make a point here so you see
these two
kind of different syntax but equivalent
now let me emphasize this they are
syntactically equivalent 100 percent
in fact whenever mathematica
you know whenever you evaluate some
expression the first thing mathematica
the kernel you know the engine does is
to
transform all these all these uh
you know infix or whatever shorthand
syntax sugar to the full form
so you can see the full form here so let
me show you another
a bit different example for example uh
list okay so let's say
example list okay so how do you do this
in mathematica
this is at list three four five oh array
okay emotion
in many languages you call it array in
mathematica you call it list okay
so uh let's say my list
equals two three four five okay now you
want to take the first element what do
you do
my list okay uh
okay uh my list first element
uh the index starts at one okay
in mathematical languages index start at
1 not 0.
this includes mathematica matlab
maple julia okay basically any any
math oriented language and api okay so
how do you take the first element of a
list you do it this way okay
you see my list bracket bracket one just
like python
or ruby you know similar to many others
except you use two
square bracket now so you might ask
again so wait wait a minute this is not
fully nested brackets what's going on
this is you know this is also not you
know they are syntax sugars so let me
show you the full form okay
let me do the same thing so
you said set okay set
x okay let's say uh okay my list okay my
list
uh list then you say list
three four five you see that
so this one is gonna be equivalent to
that one
okay let's evaluate
okay let's not say three four five let's
say three fours uh let's say
uh let's say nine four five okay
evaluate so that's at least so
so this this is the full form of the
of that okay so so and let me continue
and then okay let me show you this one
okay how do you
what's the full form of this you know
take the first element of a list
uh let me show you this way parts
[Music]
part okay part
then yeah my list okay my list
then then one the first element you see
here again we have a fully nested syntax
okay let's evaluate it
nine you see because our first element
is nine
so so let me emphasize again so in
mathematica
you the math the wolfram language uh
syntax
is a purely 100 fully nested brackets
isomorphic to lisp however
mathematica has a layer of a systematic
layer of
shortcuts of sugar syntax okay so
so instead of writing lists like that
every time
you can just use the you know curly
brackets
instead of set when you want to set x
equals to 3
instead of set instead of saying set
brackets
and x comma 3 you can
you can just use the equal sign you know
x equals through three
so this feature is fantastic because
this feature this
this systematic syntax layer
allows you to have very convenient uh
uh expressions for example if you are
doing a lot of math
for example if you are doing a lot of
math you know
which is what wolfram language is
designed for let's say
x third power uh
plus y times
x z squared
you know let's say let's say that
expression
how do you do that in this oh my god
that's gonna be
you know if you're gonna write this in
this it's gonna be a headache
for example let me show you so in this
it's gonna be something like
uh uh power
x three then uh okay
it's it's it's a pen okay so let me let
me show you how
how you might write that
uh power plus
okay actually we should we we shouldn't
do this in mathematica because
you know that's not mathematical syntax
it's going to show you lots of errors so
let's go
do it in this okay so if you want to do
this expression
in this
so common in fixed notation for
polynomial if you want to
in lisp form would be
okay so power x3 plus
uh okay so plus then plus
times okay uh now it's it's gonna be
painful
and unreadable times y
then okay then power
z two so you see that
that versus that uh you know the
that that so so you can
see so here is an important point
a side point okay you you can see here
the importance of syntax in the
programming language
because when and that's a common
complaint in these
languages over the past 40 years many
many
great uh lisp pioneers have tried to
introduce the infix form but it never
became popular for one reason or another
but you can see why it is necessary
especially if you do a lot of math you
do want
this kind of uh infix notation because
because this is just unreadable
especially when it gets complex okay we
are
we i'm going to talk about
especially when when the expression gets
complex you know you have
you have the you know uh
the formula for uh
polynomial of second degree or series
and sequence you know in this point is
it's
unreadable okay
okay so now
so so let's summarize
mathematic mathematical notation has two
layers
one is a purely nested uh
form that's syntactic that's one
that's isomorphic to the least syntax
two mathematical has a layer that is a
systematic
short should uh short syntax system
which is 100 percent equivalent to the
fully nested brackets okay so let's copy
it let's cut that and put this
into our explanation uh
okay showing browser so we have
explained several things about the
mathematical syntax
now okay now if you now hear something
interesting in mathematica now if you
are good morning
good morning lucas so i'm doing all
right
any any comments questions
video check audio check so now back to
mathematica so
there is a way for you to
get the notation okay so you all you
have to do in mathematica you just type
full form and any any expression and
mathematica will show
what is the full form syntax by the way
this purely nested thing
that syntax in mathematica is called
full form okay
so for example let's say uh hold okay
one plus two uh
so if you do that it will it will tell
you something like
um it will it'll return something like
that
but why do you put why do you put a hole
there because if you don't put hold
there
then one plus two will evaluate you'll
become three
so you just get three so but if we do it
this way
evaluate you can see okay let's not use
hold let's
say hold form okay it's a bit
yeah okay let's use hold
so you can see mathematica shows you
this plus
square bracket and and let me show you
another one okay let's say for example
so i'm explaining the syntax of
mathematica so for example let's do a
list
three four five okay then
mathematica tells you that the full form
is actually that
okay uh let's what about this one
this uh polynomial okay we can do the
same thing
okay so we paste the polynomial there
wait paste yeah so evaluate
you can see the full form of
that polynomial okay polynomial of three
variables
okay so that concludes our discussion
about the isomorphism
of mathematical syntax and lisp syntax
and
the layer the full form of
the wolfram language which
this do not have now in 1960
when john mccarthy who invented lisp
he has the idea okay he says that the
least
syntax should be two parts one
is called symbolic expression
which is the nested brackets okay
uh let me write it let me write it out
there so
so this syntax
called uh let's magnify a bit more
symbolic expression
aka s-e-x-p is often known
as sex okay that's a
symbol that you know that's so this
nested
parenthesis parenthesis it's called
symbolic expression
so when john mccarthy created invented
this
he says that okay it should have the
symbolic expression nested parenthesis
he also says that it should have what's
called a
meta expression now what is meta
expression it never developed
okay it never got created because people
got used to symbolic
you know the nested parenthesis
parentheses and it just stopped there
so it's like in indefinite delay so it
never
kind of never happened except many
people tried to do it but
so in mathematica it happened there you
know mathematic
so lisp is began in 1960
mathematica began in 1986 you know so
there's almost 30 years so
so you know stefan wufam i i guess and
you know i know he
he he he you know he he knows a lot at
least
you know he borrowed idea he said oh
that's a good idea we need
this meta expression uh but in
mathematica they don't call that that
you know they they just call it full
form okay so
so here's another interesting uh by way
okay segway
why so you know this is about the
jargons you know name
jargons jargons in computer science the
naming of things
so if you are a language creator and
there are many technical
concepts you know in programming
language design right
for example lambda for example lambda
currying
currying or arity of a function you know
and and and tail recursion and
lots of you know these jargons so but if
you are
designing a programming language you
you know you you have a choice like
which jargon among jargons which one
should you choose so it
so here's here's one example where
stephen wolfram
made his decision which is
characteristics of his
choices in mathematica instead of
calling it
metaphor or meta expression
he calls it full form why
why does he make that decision of course
i
i don't i don't know i mean exactly what
he thought but i read enough of wolfram
stuff i i can tell you
why because usually the the jargon the
choices of words or concept in
mathematica
is chosen so that in the english
language the general english language
human language
it makes the most sense okay so
for example compare meta expression
versus full form which one is more
intuitive you know like you you you
don't
you know we are not asking for you know
specialized
uh list experts i mean just in general
in the
english language if you have this thing
you want most people to understand it
which one is more intuitive full form
versus meta expression okay i would say
full form yes
i would yes so this is just one example
you know maybe this example is not the
best
best example but but if you use
mathematica enough you
you'll know you know actually i'm trying
to tell you something so
so you get a sense of how things in
mathematic
mathematica you know wolfham language is
named
usually they go for let me let me tell
you another example that's more
interesting
uh that's more illustrative okay for
example
in lisp and in in
in many languages in this in python for
example
uh and in ruby for example you have the
jargon
lambda okay lambda what the
what what is lambda what the does
that mean
[Laughter]
nobody knows unless you are a programmer
or computer scientist
in mathematica there's no such thing
called lambda
okay you call it function okay
uh let me show you an example okay so
let's do an actual
uh example of lisp coding okay so let's
start a emac list okay so let's start a
emac list
so i type lambda let's say i want to
create a function that
adds the two arguments okay lambda y
x and here return will be
okay that's how i define lambda now you
can evaluate this expression by
uh you know so so you want to put two
argument to it so
let's see if i can i'm not sure i can do
it this way but let's try okay
so lambda 2 and 3 okay
so this if we evaluate this thing
it should actually return 5 because it's
adding two and three okay
i'm not sure it will work in this
yeah it did okay so actually let me show
you the message but first so you can see
yeah i don't know if you can see it uh
okay let's let's do it this way okay so
you're so so okay so let's remove that
it's pretty five
let's add a comment this creates a
function
and apply it to two
arguments two and three
okay it should
return five okay that's what
this is okay now if we evaluate it
you'll see
in this message buffer you're say five
in fact you see it here okay
so let's do it again evaluate
you see five so okay so this is a list
okay let's copy it uh
paste it here pd5 show in browser
magnify so we can we have our code there
now let's let's show you the mathematica
equivalent to this lambda thing okay
now we are actually uh digressing
because we are now talking about
uh naming of functions and naming of
things naming of concepts
different philosophy different uh you
know predilection
okay so let me let me show you so so we
you want to create a function
so this is how you do in mathematica
function two variables
x y okay and what do you want to
return x plus y okay that's one way to
do it
and so and you want this to be evaluated
with two arguments two and three right
so let's do it here remember because
remember
the mathematica form is like the
function name then bracket
which contains the argument so the first
part is a function now
so now you just say two and three
okay now evaluate it
five okay so that's how you do it in um
in in mathematica so what is the point
here
now my point is that you see the
lamp.jargon
mathematica do not use it you know
stefan wufang language
no lambda what the what what the heck is
that
that's not a good naming name okay
that's not a good name for the concept
it should just be called function
you know so this this is a good example
that illustrates
the choice of jargons of concepts
in programming languages you know
depending on who you are
you are python you know guido one rosam
created python
or you know the the library world who
created pearl
or uh gosling who created java you know
they
you know you you it's uh interesting
naming of things okay
okay so that's about the naming of
things let me write down this quickly so
we have a
record of what we've talked about um
okay okay so
uh so naming of things uh
site note naming of
things naming of
concepts
and jargons okay
so this is interesting because you'll
see this this is a common issue
in computer language i mean in program
in uh computer science and programming
languages you'll see this everywhere
object you know object uh setter
getter you know you have tons of those
or you know properties
you know you or for example another
popular you know for example array
list uh uh that's you know
two different name vector array list
vector turple you know depending on
which language you are in
sometimes they mean the same thing
sometimes not really
you know then you also have
hash table hash or hash table or
dictionary
or map you know in python it's called
dictionary key value pairs
but sometimes they are called hash or
hash table in in perl and ruby for
example
in in in java and javascript it's called
map okay key value pairs so it's a
naming of things very interesting
uh let me write down okay list array
turbo vector you know vector is a is a
term
lisp uses which is kind of equivalent to
uh python's turpo which is kind of
equivalent to
c's array okay which is uh usually not
the same as
beast you know the different languages
they they have different
meanings okay
for example uh
and example another example is hash
hash table dictionary
and uh and uh map
okay so let's put that
put that there okay so
sync now we have our notes of what
today's lecture notes
okay naming of things that's a
digression about you know so let's go
back to mathematica
now let me go back to okay so how long
have i been talking i need to
i actually have a lot more to cover
uh i've been talking for 40 minutes oh
my god
let me show you one more example of of
the syntax equivalent thing okay for
example how do you write this
actually you actually you should know
okay so let me
write this by hand okay in the full form
okay so let me just type it by hand and
so we uh yeah let me do this quickly
actually we shouldn't
waste time on this but let me just
okay so
so you see this this
part is exactly identical it's
syntactically equivalent
100 to this part like i said before
whenever mathematica
start to evaluate the expression the
first thing
i believe so i'm not exactly sure
because i never
uh worked with the internal you know the
the
implementation of mathematica but i
i'm pretty sure that's correct okay so
the first thing mathematica do will
transform to a transformation of the
syntax
transform everything into the full form
like that
so these two are exactly identical this
is
very different from the sugar syntax of
many languages
in many other languages python or skim
disk
you know sometimes you have two things
that's oh that's a sugar syntax for this
but their sugar syntax notion is kind of
fuzzy
because they are not exactly the same
for example let me show you an example
uh for example let me show you an
example okay
the notion of sugar syntax
uh notion of sugar syntax
is not
well defined but
but for example okay i
plus plus versus i
equals to i plus one
okay uh i forgot which one is before or
which one is after
a plus plus i let's just say that okay
if i
i know i i you know you know what i mean
okay so
don't don't pick don't need pick okay so
in c
and c plus plus the worst language of
humanity
the worst screw-up in company in
programming industry c
and c plus first the grand daddy of
everything that is wrong
in computing industry they have this
syntax
i plus plus you know in fact that
that is the that is why c is named c
plus plus as a point to this syntax so
what what does i plus first mean it
means add
one to the variable i and return okay
so it's kind of equivalent to these okay
i equals i plus one so you say oh
normally you know most people will say
oh that's a
syntax sugar for this one but not really
because they these two forms they
actually compile two different things
uh well today the compiler becomes very
smart so today they may compile to the
same thing
if the context is right but but not
always
that's a problem you see that's a
problem
so anyway my point is these two are not
actually not
syntactically equivalent you know the
compiler doesn't
when the compiler sees this it doesn't
simply translate into that
then start to compile it doesn't do that
these two actually will compile
compile into different assembly code you
know
depending on context so that's it so so
for the c
c and c plus plus you know smart
smarties you know they do
up fused to cated you know c programming
you know
they know the difference in detail
intimately and they are proud of it
you know they they are called their c
code with very smart you know
impossible to understand
incomprehensible thing
sometimes they'll use that because they
know this is actually faster than the
that you know than this than the second
one
so that's a that's a problem anyway my
point is that syntax sugar is
often not well defined okay but in the
mathematica
situation in the mathematical language
they
are syntactically equivalent
100 and the the the two layers the mid
you know the full form versus the input
from they are
100 equivalent and systematic like
there's no exceptions
there there's no exceptions by the way
by the way mathematica i also have these
okay
i plus plus let me show you okay so
let's say i
equals to uh one okay enter so i equals
one let's say i equals to 1. then let's
say i plus first
okay evaluate okay
it returns one okay then let's type i
again
it becomes true you see mathematica
supports
these syntax because it it
you know it has short hands to emulate
uh two so you so it becomes easier for
you to learn
in short basically because you came from
c
or you know you came from industry you
you want to code mathematica so that
makes it easy for you
so but what is this form in mathematica
let me show you okay so let's
let's do let's use the power of the full
form
then you have to say hold because you
don't want to evaluate
let's say okay so let's say uh i plus
plus
okay let's see what uh returns okay
you'll read i don't remember exactly
what
uh set plus one or something
okay increment that's a good name great
name
so you see this form
i press first or x plus plus you know
is actually syntactically equivalent to
this kind of function increment then a
variable name okay
so this is kind of in my in my
point of in my in my view this is a
very beautiful part of mathematica
systematic
and you know systematic consistent
there's no exception
systematic in the and 100
equivalent layers
and uh okay so that's uh that's about
that
um
okay so let me let me talk let me let me
continue
to the next thing i want to talk about
actually i spent a lot of time on this
um i don't know if i'm too repetitive
um okay let me let me get a drink and
let's move on to the next topic i think
by the way uh why do i talk about this
these kind of full form thing syntactic
syntactic
equivalence for so long because in fact
this is one of the most important thing
you need to
understand about wufang language when
you become
advanced wufang language programmer this
is this becomes
critical uh you must understand
almost by heart how every
every x almost every you know when you
become when you have for example
after one years of of experience
programming mathematica
you must become almost by heart given
any expression you by heart
know what is these what what is its full
form
why do you need to know that so
why because late you know when you
provide mathematica you
you you will be uh using symbolic
pattern matching a lot
and when you do that those pattern
matching they are not matching these
you know these sugar syntaxes they are
matching the full form
that is the full form that all your code
using pattern matching is going to match
with okay
this is again this is there's a
counterpart in lisp
this is similar to lisps macro okay
so when you code these you know these
disperse they like macro you know
these markers you need to understand you
know
well since lisp doesn't have this you
know it doesn't have these
uh infix notation so you always see the
full form so
my point is that when you program this
you have the least marker
list marker one of the important thing
for it to happen is that you need to
have this
fully nested regular syntax for it to
work
because once you have this you know once
you have these
you know three plus two syntax your
macro
becomes very complex you know easy
so in the same way in the same way when
you become
advanced mathematica programmer you do a
lot
pattern matching symbolic pattern
matching you
need to understand uh be very
familiar with how every expression
is uh corresponds you know
is equivalent you know what their full
form looks like like
for example like that one okay that's
why it's uh important
okay so now let's shrink uh
so let's uh kind of uh
let's write down okay these are not
syntactically these are not
syntactically
equivalent no
semantically equivalent okay that's an
important thing
i plus plus versus i equals two
i plus one they are not syntactic
synthetically equivalent of course they
are not but they are no
no are they semantically equivalent so
when
when next time when you say oh that's
just a sugar syntax of something
for example that happens a lot in in
scheme list
or in javascript think again okay what
you mean exactly sugar syntax
okay like try to come up with a precise
definition
uh and there i mean not just these
examples there are tons of other
examples okay uh but anyway so let's go
on so
uh so
okay so let's go on with uh let's go on
let's see
where are we i need to move on to next
uh
interesting topic uh full form input
form okay
analogous to this symbolic expression
and meta expression okay
start easy uh explain this in that okay
show my articles i've shown this uh okay
where is my article
i've shown these articles here concepts
and confusions the prefix
infix and posifix notations in this
notations okay
this article there's quite a lot so you
might be interested to look into because
in this article
i pretty much explained what i i
explained now
uh actually there's more okay there's
more here
um let's skip that okay
because i got other things i need to
explain
i mean there's a postfix notation and
prefix notation
in mathematica too
um
should i um
okay so so now remember
okay so anyway so you know i already
explained these things
so let me move on to the next
interesting thing
actually how long have i been talking
today
56 minutes okay i think
let that be that so today this video is
just about the syntax
okay because i was going to i was going
to
uh explain how wufam language does
typesetting okay then i was going to
explain
some analogous features of mathematica
notebook versus the ogmod you know emac
emax
oak mod where you can have outline you
can have headers you can
outline you can collapse them you can
expand them
you can export to html or latex
or any other things uh you know you can
export to lots of formats
in fact that's exactly the same with
math with wolfram language
uh notebook okay so so i'm going
so let's not do that today so let this
video today just be
the syntax okay i think that's it
actually pretty much any
other thing exactly so jason
con
i believe jason you are also a wufang
language coder right
so yeah the next thing i want to talk
about the syntax is the prefix postfix
again they are systematic okay let me
expand okay
um so in mathematica so
normally right so normally you write
things like that
you know a function name square bracket
arguments
but mathematica has a also a systematic
way
to write this expression without
the square brackets
you know the fully nested notation
is kind of nice because they show you
the structure
of the whole expression similar to the
lisps
you know nested parenthesis but however
as
you know we as we explain they are
cumbersome some sometimes they are just
not good
when you want you know when you have a
polynomial or lots of
calculations so
uh so besides
sugar syntax for each hey thank you
thousand for five dollars
and the question is are you a citizen of
cape cakistan
uh yes i am
yes next time i should uh
i think i've showed you my id already
okay i wanna see the server
okay youtube is going to buy me now
okay so so wufang language has a
systematic
uh prefix notation okay let me show you
okay so so
what's the example sign okay let's say
sign okay
now you know sine is the sine function
you know sine pi
sine pi equals to zero right okay let's
do something fun
plot so we are doing some math
uh plot sine x and x from
x from let's say 0 to
9 okay let's say 10.
show it fantastic now so
sine as 0 is 0 right everyone knows that
i mean sine at pi is 0 okay sine of 0 is
0 as well so this here is pi okay let me
show you something fancier okay
so we want to do i believe
ticks
okay zero pi
uh zero pi okay zero half pi
actually i should use the range okay so
let's do range
range is like python's range okay 0
to 3 pi jump
by pi over 2 increment by pi over two
okay
ah wrong uh it should be
axis labels uh okay i hate this
because i forgot the syntax not ticks uh
i think it sticks wait a minute uh
wait let me try this again okay
there it is okay so you see this
is sign you know pi so we change
the axis the label for the x axis
pi over 2 pi anyway so that's a sign so
what's my point my point is let's go
back to the sine pi okay
oh yeah prefix notation so sine pi
so i was saying sometimes the nested
brackets
the fully nested brackets is kind of
annoying right
so so one one of the convenient
convenient way to avoid lots of nested
parentheses
is uh prefix notation so you can say
instead of sine pi you can say
sine at pi okay that's that is the
prefix notation
let's try another example sign at
one okay let's see what is what's the
value okay so
that's a symbolic result let's say sign
point
sign sign at 1.0 okay
so you got 0.84 something so you can
also write it uh
as sine bracket 1.0
so you you compare these two notations
sine add versus sine you know
bracket so the add is
is a prefix notation and this works for
any function not just sine okay so in in
general
whenever you have x that
can be written as x
you know f at x okay
so any function any okay any function
that takes one argument instead of
saying you know
instead of using the square bracket you
can just write it you know f
at x in the same way you can
post fixed notation okay so
uh okay so let me turn this into a um
cell format uh i want to what is it
format
style okay uh alt 807 text okay
so i forgot o7 it's not
key yeah okay so
and in the same way
so f at x this is called
prefix notation
and in some way there is post
fixed notation okay
f square
x can be written
as x slash slash f
okay that's the post notation by the way
this post notation
is similar similar to unix pipe okay
unix pipe you know in unix is common you
know something
type something that means return output
and
feed it to the next function's input and
so on
so in mathematica you know you can think
of it as a
postfix notation and in mathematica the
the syntax is slash slash so again
this works for any function not just you
know any
so any function with one argument so for
example
sign so for example 1.0
slash slash sign okay
enter equals to 0.84 just like before so
they you know
and you can mix any of these notation
prefix infix
or fully nested you know
you can mix them in any way
and so this is uh so again let me
emphasize this is this is systematic
there is no exceptions it's like the
rules are very simple you just like
one two three four you know just for
these four rules and you can create
the combinatorial variations
of expression is phenomenal i mean it's
exponential it's kind of
so you know it in the 1990s the pearl
people the programming language they
used to say
there are more than one way to do it
they are so proud
you know of the pearl uh syntax because
it's like
incomprehensible there are 100 ways to
write the same thing
but in mathematica they are
systematic way and there's actually more
variations
than purp then it is possible than pearl
yet it's systematic and simple
so in fact i have lots of articles on
that let's forget
about that okay so so let me show you
yeah okay let me show you some articles
about this uh
postfix notation and prefix notation
because they are very interesting
so you go to so so first of all you know
you might want to read this uh article
okay
uh concepts and confusions of prefix
infix postfix
and lisp notations by the way that title
is a clickbait
[Laughter]
this this is written in 2006 before the
word click
bait
that's why they call me a troll okay so
so anyway so
but i also give you concrete solid
information
about history of kind of you know
the history of notations the naming of
notations why
you know the what does it mean to be
algebraic notations you know i give you
a
uh clarity of understanding you know
these kind of things
so this is one article so that you know
you go to my website
then you go to uh let's shrink shrink
then you go to hacker code then you go
to um
uh syntax soup okay here is a collection
of articles or about syntax programming
languages
and there's a video i did before then
there
are the point i want to talk about is
i have one two three four five six seven
seven
articles related to the pipe notation
because there's so many things to dive
into
for example we talked about unix pipe
you know uh let me show you some
example you familiar with unix pipe
right
yeah i you know i explained some of
these uh things back in 2002
you know this is a post posted to the
mac making this
so anyway let me show you yeah here is
the unix
you know prototypical unix slot uh
pipe you know in bash for example
ps you know w auwx oak
something then sort then x ax echo you
know that's typical so
pipe notation so i mean in unix unix is
called pipe
so you can from a notational point of
view
this is called post-fix notation
why do i say notational point of view
because they are different point of view
you know the pipe is actually i mean
it's not just notation
it's also about how it does computation
it
you know it you know so i mean
for example in bash you don't usually
consider these commands as functions
because
actually they have lots of side effects
but anyway from a notational point of
view
the unix pipe is a post-fix notation
okay so that's one article explaining
that unix pipe as functional language
okay
and by the way that that occu that
article
has um where are we that article has
uh the creator the inventor of the oak
language
alfred a ho you know he made some
comments
about why he what he think what he
thinks about pipe
you know so there's a it's a it's from
an interview
is there a connection you know someone
asking is there a connection between the
idea
of composing programs together from a
command line
through through pipes and the idea of
writing little languages each for a
specific domain so
you know so he said uh uh i think
there's a connection certainly in the
early early days of unix
pipes facilitated functional composition
on the command
command line so you can see the idea of
functional programming is there
from the creator of the awk language
okay then he says you could take an
input perform some transformation on it
and then pipe the output into another
program exactly
that is what that is the paradigm
of functional programming input output
input output pi pi pi pipe
the entire program is one giant pipe
that is the that is kind of the
that is actually in reality in real
world that's kind of how
functional programming works oh you know
you know as much as you can you know it
is
um and you know uh
and uh okay so anyway that that's about
that article
okay so unix piper as functional
language let me copy that and put it
here so we have a record of what we
talked about
so later on you can see in my youtube
description
uh okay so i'm about actually i should
stop soon okay so let me return to the
article so i have like six articles
about
pipe and let me mention this start okay
dot notation okay so this has to do
so so let me first of all let me
tell you about method training post
operator and
object oriented programming okay so
if you program in ub or if you have
programmed in javascript
you will be or even if you have
programmed in java
you will be very familiar with this
syntax something
dot something dot something okay dot
notation
sometimes known as method training okay
especially in javascript
and ruby okay especially in javascript
and ruby very
uh very popular you know you see
programmers talk about it all the time
but they don't know
what they are talking about okay so
method chaining
again from a notational point of view
that is post fixed notation okay postfix
operator in other words the dot is a is
can be considered a postfix operator
again there's many details because
because for example in javascript
when you say x dot f dot g it's it's not
actually not postfix note
notation actually the x must return
a object that must contain a method
called f then you can x dot f
then if that returns the object and if
that
object contains a method g then you can
dot g
if it doesn't contain that you know if
it doesn't return object and
it doesn't doesn't contain the next
whatever dot you're gonna dot you cannot
dot
it's gonna be your error so it's not
exactly
a postfix notation okay it's it's not
but from a notational point of view
you can see it is like a posifix
notation
in fact i in fact i have a created i
have wrote a
um let me show you okay i have a wrote a
javascript code
that actually allows you to have postfix
postfix notation postfix
function composition or like unix pipe
so here's the javascript code it's just
uh
two lines of code okay actually i'm
proud of this code
because i thought about this for a long
time and come up with that
so anyway let's go back so so i want to
talk about this a lot to
um you know just just on this issue
there's a lot to talk about
so let me just grab the url and post in
my talk show so we have a record of it
okay so so okay
so now you know about let's close that
you know about
you know the method chaining very
popular in ruby and javascript
uh and now you i as i explained you see
there's kind of a connection between the
postfix
operator and also a connection with op
because method chaining
is not exactly a post postfix operator
although syntactically it looks like it
it's similar but it requires the
oop semantics but you know it requires
they return
object and have the next method
otherwise it doesn't work
okay so that so so that's what this uh
article is trying to explain okay
uh then then there are other issues okay
so
so there's a concept of namespace comes
in okay so namespace you know for
example
dot notation you know you know so you
have dot notation in javascript
but however that notation is not just
you know you
okay so on one hand you can consider it
as a
post fixed notation but on the other
hand
you can consider it as tied to name name
space
name space mechanism
yeah so that's what this article kind of
tries to explain okay so there so there
are quite a few
issues about these uh so i have several
articles on that
uh then there's another question um
yeah so this question dot before data or
after data so all these also have to do
with oop
they they they do not exist in
functional programming
so for example should you should you
have object dot method name
or should you have uh sometimes it's
different okay i mean
for example in python you have string
dot split
that splits the string but in python's
regular expression
you have re dot sub you know re is a
regular expression object so here you
know so
and in javascript you have the same
thing so javascript you have string dot
split
or string dot replace you know the
you know you begin with a string which
is the thing you want to work on
then you dot the method you know what
you want to do with it
but but there's inconsistency
when you want to use regular expression
you have the regular expression first
then start
a method of regular expression then you
put the string so
there's actually two kind of
inconsistent so this
so this is a
and so this is you know so this is a
design
issue this is a dilemma kind of a
among two different design choices
that's
very common in object oriented languages
so if you are a designer of a oop
language what you're going to do how do
you avoid this
inconsistency in fact it's a problem
there's no way to
avoid it it exists this problem exists
in python
exists in javascript exist in java
as well the most typical example is
number
should you have a number dot plus number
dot times
number dot uh
divide you know like that or should you
have a math
class math dot then two numbers math
dot times two numbers math dot divide
two numbers you know so
it's very income inconsistent and this
problem is very common
in oop
so this article i'm trying to explain
that aspect
so what's the really i mean so so what's
the whole thing so the whole thing is
about you know the dot notation the pipe
notation this
uh mini aspect of it so okay that's it
for today i think
so uh thank you fassin and uh
then you know people who can get over
the syntax never actually get this
that's
incorrect danielle i have
a i have i i did like two three videos
one hour each
explaining how incorrect is that
is that statement you know the statement
is people who don't get over syntax
never actually get this okay let me
explain one more one thing
uh as a retort to that statement okay
many these phonetics they will say
uh you know if you don't get over the
syntax oh you you are not qualified to
study this
you don't get it because you know you
think the parenthesis
necessary parenthesis is too much
problem
but let me tell you the nested
parenthesis
actually syntax is the most important
thing
because without the nested parentheses
the lisp will not come up with the idea
of this macros
okay that's how syntax how important
syntax
is so for example
um for example
if you have if you don't have the syntax
of apl
then it will be difficult to have to
come up
with the idea the concept of array
programming languages
which includes api mathematica julia
matlab okay which is very convenient
when you work on matrices or trees
like almost you know instead of working
on one number at a time
almost all your uh every time you call a
function or operator it's always on
a bunch of numbers matrices that's
called array programming languages okay
but the first thing you need to have is
kind of this syntactical you know the
syntax of apl
once you have that then that that idea
develops
and similarly in the so what's a good
point about the list
nested parentheses syntax the good point
is that it
shows a clarity between the structure
and the semantics okay the structure of
the syntax this is a kind of a
correspondence of the structure of the
syntax
and the the semantics okay or sometimes
they they are called you know the
the nerds okay the c c plus plus they'll
say
uh abstract syntax tree
idiotic okay so anyway
the least the the the good property
about this list
list syntax is that it gives you a
clarity of the
from the structure of the syntax you can
see
the semantics of the expression okay
what so what's good about that what's
going to do with that
well then you started to develop you
start to think
it these syntax give you uh
it suggests to you the notion of macros
then you started to have the concept of
macros
which all the lispers love you know a
very
uh great concept transformation of
syntax
at least marcus that's what it does
which which mathematica does
far more you know uh in a far more
advanced ways
which which then becomes symbolic
pattern matching
okay if you expand the least marker idea
what you get
is symbolic pattern matching in
mathematica
okay but there are there are
disadvantages
okay for example if you want to
polynomials
like i explained earlier in the video in
this it's a pain in the ass
it makes you basically your language is
not suitable anymore
if you're gonna do polynomials all day
and every day your least language is
gonna be problematic unless then you
have to create
like a rendering system like maxima you
know many
computer algebra systems are written in
this um
anyway i'm digressing too much that's it
for that
so so jason says the structure of lisp
is pure math the syntax
is optional i don't agree i disagree
because anyway so that's getting uh
philosophical okay that's it for today
uh if you guys like my stuff donate
paypal me
buy my stuff you know you uh or buy my
emacs list
tutorial or buy my javascript in depth
you know where to find it you know it's
everywhere on my website you
should see a patreon link and
my paypal on my home page okay thank you
guys bye
i'm gonna yeah i'm gonna shut down in
in a minute happening in half a minute
this is the opportunity for the last
words
did i did i miss anything i want to talk
about syntax
well we covered enough
uh yeah so tabs type setting
and type setting and the org mod
features
we're gonna talk about next time
notebook
and so-called uh reproducible research
okay we're gonna do that next time
uh and we have a lot to do you know in
my talk show i'm
i think i'm gonna start to do regularly
i like schedule every
every almost every day every other day
or something
three times a week or or four times a
week
uh yeah so anyway just watch for my
youtube
channel right now i haven't decided what
to do but anyway i have
you know i have for example topic notes
there's uh
quite a lot of things i want to do about
emacs and emac lists
where for example i'm thinking about to
create a
emacs xr emacs distro so it's going to
be
like a competitor to doom emacs
and space max okay so you just download
emacs and everything works out of the
box you have like
my style of you know
maybe you'll like it maybe not but i
think a lot of people you know a lot of
people want it
it's not you know it's not difficult for
me to create it
i can create it like almost the whole
thing in one hour
you know in one hour or two okay but the
the
the problem is once i created it you
know put on github
then the questions will start to come in
you know i becomes the tech support
you know every day will say oh cymax it
doesn't work how do you do this how do
you do that
oh yeah you know text vote and usually
for my past experience i don't get money
okay you know maybe ten dollars a
month fifty dollars a month i cannot
do that i have to leave so
anyway i'm thinking of doing you know
emacs distro maybe
you know i i don't know i don't know
about the money issue
uh that's the issue right so
i yeah i don't know if i if i create
that it's going to be tech support i'm
not
i'm too old for that anyway so
bye guys
yes jason uh you know i so jason asked
the question let me answer that a little
bit okay so if you go
uh if you go to my uh programming blog
if you go to programming lisp
you know there's a funny uh image i i
did i did
more than two i did several uh one-hour
videos
on lisp syntax okay so there's a lot of
detail and i have like
50 or 100 articles about lisp
syntax so one of them
is what you just addressed or you
you claimed for example that's um
uh that's the the the infix notation
right
so you are saying many people has
created infix
notation exactly and i have a collection
of them all uh let's see
where uh but at least it does okay this
what the symbolic language mean okay
this mark will change list
syntax list apostrophe quote
came from mac lisp that's a history of
that apostrophe
syntax syntax mathematica versus list
syntax xml versus list
syntax you know there's lots of issues
uh
systematic syntax okay um
[Music]
there okay so this article lisp infix
syntax survey
here i collect from you know the
beginning of list
1958 all the pioneers of these
programmers who have created infix
syntax for lisp okay well including
mathematica okay
so it's up to 2007
then closure uh oculus 2009
they have they have kind of variation
then racket list
which also supports not just parentheses
but also
square brackets and braces but
although it's not infix but however
there are several
scheme packages that supports infix
syntax then up to 2015 the closure
in fix you know this as a project then
then quite a lot so every three five
years there are
some these programmers trying to do that
then often they get ridiculed
ridiculed by whispers
uh you know they that's wrong okay
that's a code problem that's
a code problem so anyway lots of
articles and in earliest you know lots
of
examples in fact as i said the
very first lisp by created by john
mccarthy
he wanted a infix notation called meta
expression
which is the main topic we talked about
today
okay that's it bye