Hello guys, good morning, good evening.
Welcome to another episode of sound talk
show. We are going to uh code emacisp.
Uh we got many things to do. Two major
things. Uh make a
citation
eag command to make a citation like when
you if you blog you got a some website
you put the title and author and date
and you press a button and they format
it. So make citation that's one thing.
The other thing is when you have a
photo, you want to, you know, a
screenshot or a photo you took, you want
to remove the, you want to get the date,
the image date from the meta data of the
image and put that date into the file
name. So, rename the file. So, ex
extract the image date. So, that's the
two things we going to do. and just
randomish. Okay. So, let's begin. So,
let's
see. Yeah. Okay.
So, so I'm using Emacs and keyboard.
Every episode I introduce my keyboards
and Emac setup. So, I'm not going to do
it today. So, let's just do these um
things I need to do. Okay. Show today's
talk
show. Yeah. Let's begin. So, if you are
watching, if you have a comments, say
love to see your comments. Okay. If you
are watching offline, play at 1.5 speed
and skip around because I
ramble. Okay. Uh start coding.
Yes. Uh so citation makes citation. So
let me demo. So for example, let's say
some website. Uh let's say what um
so programming languages. So we got uh
we got a new someone told me thank you
jolly
uh thank
you Jolly Jack. He told me the origin of
this list this logo we talked about few
days ago. It's from this book little
lisper third edition 1989. Okay.
Apparently this logo is designed by uh
the the great guy Guy Steel Jr. you know
who who is one of the greatest uh list
coder and
creator. So that's about that. So I
wanted to
um I want to do a demo of uh of citing
some website. Okay. So let's see. I. So,
how do I do it?
Um, so we need to find an example of a
website. Okay, hold on a
second. Hold on a
second. Let me stop the video. Hold on.
Give me a a
second. Speedo. Speedo camera. Can you
Okay, click on that.
be right back in one minute.
back. Back. Okay, I'm back. So, let's
show an example. So, let's show example.
Let's just say lisp. Okay, let's go to a
Wikipedia. So, um talk show, today's
talk show. And let's just search for
lisp.
search for it and go to Wikipedia. Now
when you are blogging there's a lot
websites sometimes you want to site
uh
so so for example let's say I want to
site this website so typically the URL
is is everything you need I mean not
everything that's the most important and
but al also often I want to have a
author name let's say by by Joe or
something so you know when you find a
blog you copy their uh name, you find
their name, Joe Blow, and uh usually
there's a date and uh so then usually
there's a title something about this. So
you copy that then you see then you
press a button there's a command I I've
written you you know you that's called
uh make citation okay so let's see so
you can get the code I believe let's see
do I have the code for example let's say
yeah I have a code here showing browser
uh make
citation okay so I remove the code
because
uh code removed because it requires uh
yeah because it
gets you know it gets larger that's why
I remove the code because to include the
code on my website you need to include
lots of other
utilities yeah so for example kasa is
date time stamp fixed state time string
uh what others then kasa html
URL to dated links. Yeah. So
you Yeah. So you need those
um kind of three things. That's why I
removed it. But anyway, here's that's a
command. Okay. So you can see made it it
made those lines. Let me uh redo. Okay.
So copy paste it here. Do it again. Make
a paragraph. And this one make a list.
Okay. Actually make both list. Okay.
Show in browser. So you can see the
difference.
Uh why is my uh hold on a
second why is my font not increased? Uh
so let me hold on a second.
Okay. Ease of
access 130.
Apply. Okay. Now it's much better.
So you see was like that now it becomes
this nice format. Okay. Um
uh I got to make some changes. So
recently I made a change so that in you
know right now it's using this
bracket the name is left total shell
bracket. So if you search for unic code
brackets which is
um bracket there. So you can see all
sort of brackets very useful. Okay.
Unicode brackets. Uh you got all these
fantastic bracket is the most useful
characters of all characters because
they come imagine pairs. Okay. So let's
close that. Close that. Let's paste that
link
there. Uh got we got a lot to do. So
hold on a second. So we got a lot to do.
So show so we show the example of this
citation. So I want to make some change
because right now the command adds this
bracket. This you see this matching
brackets. Uh but I recently made a
change so that it no longer uses the
bracket. It instead use the um god I
need to show you. Okay so let me show
you. So search for x site. I now I have
a custom
tag. Okay. So for example, show you this
page Allen key on objectoriented
programming. So you go down, you go
down, you can see citations. For
example, this one object orientation
generic functions by Peter
Seagull. Peter
Sebell, he's uh oh yeah, he's a guy who
wrote common this book.
Um yeah god I I got so many things uh so
let me just work on my website. So I got
so many things going on. So let's show
another uh website. So Microsoft Apple
Mosilla dismisses dot. So there you got
several citations. So when you look at
the source code you can see there is
this
uh let's highlight it this site tag you
see so instead of the total is bracket
that's that's a change I made so let's
fix the
code go to the source code fix the code
make citation okay So hold on a second.
Copy it. New buffer. Paste it. Go here.
Copy XX date. Paste the
name. So this is a temp file. X UTF. So
make it lexical binding. Then go back to
the site tag. We need to change. So here
is the code.
So, let's search
for that character. Yeah. So, yep.
Change that there. Okay. Delete
that. And uh put that there. Delete
that. Okay. Now, search that character
again. Let's
see. Do we have it? Okay. So
actually yeah
so yeah so actually we instead of that
say that okay backslash now custom tag
is very useful
so okay so this is a documentation and
create a date
version paste it there today's date and
go back to our code I
think we forgot a slash there. Okay. So
now evaluate the
code. Okay. Go back here. Go back here
and uh
let's copy paste remove all that and
remove all that and call it make a
citation. So So you see you got the site
excite. Now make a paragraph of it.
Showing
browser. You got this one. Fantastic.
instead of instead of that one.
Okay. So that's one thing changed.
Now now there there is so this is
original. So
uh let's remove the what uh I don't want
to format the code.
So this is before and uh and this is
after.
showing browser. There it is. This
before, this is after. Then this is new
with a citation
tag. Custom tag. Okay. Uh now let me
show you guys custom tag. Custom tag is
very
useful in HTML because that way you
avoid all the dive you know nested dive
custom tag allows you to find the
beginning and end tag easily. Okay. So
just uh just go to saw web de block
custom search for it. You got custom
data attribute and also you got custom
tag custom element. Okay, like that. One
requirement about custom element is that
the name can be anything but it requires
a dash. So it needs to start with a
letter then some a dash somewhere. Okay.
So let's copy that. Close that. Um
showing browser. So with a custom tag
and let's make this
um
okay paste a link
linkify list remove I mean com join the
two and delete this whole list and uh
make a wait let's not go there so uh
then let's
[Music]
Um yeah so add add a breaker line break
paste it there show in browser so we got
different sections so this part is about
make a citation so let's um so actually
we got a example here
uh we should have used that but anyway
so now select select select select
select select select select
Press a
key, they add a section. Okay, so you
got a section. So delete, delete that
citation.
Okay, so this section is about make
citation. Then this section remove that.
Uh then then the next thing we need to
do
is is about
extract date in
image file and rename
it in the file.
Okay. So now make citation then extract
date in image file then then something
else we talked about. Okay. Now let's go
back to the main
citation. So we know what we want to do
and we have done demo. Uh the next thing
we want to do is
um
is so let's remove that one. Okay. Uh
after Yeah. Okay. So Oh yeah. So one one
Okay. One of the problem with the
citation is that sometimes
uh sometimes you don't have this
particular order URL title author date
sometimes you you know you got the date
there or the title there some some
something like that so it is very
tedious uh to order them. I would like
to make the command automatically
recognize which one is URL, which one is
state, which one is author. Okay, you
cannot do that 100% because there is no
precise way to determine because for
example this job below a person's name
that could be a title. So there's no way
to
tell you know but there are huristic
means because typically a title is not a
person's name and and and typically if
you say by something something then
that's that always almost always means
it's author. Uh similarly you know a
date usually your title is not just a
date but it could be so but usually not
so so usually this heristic means to
determine which line is the date. Okay
so that's what we going to do. So we're
going to modify the make
citation to to do this recognition.
Okay. So let's go there. So here's our
code. make a
backup. Uh so you know I had the code
before to recognize but it's like very
cumbersome and so and now I don't feel
like coding
it. Hello Gabriel. Does that work like
BB text? Uh no it it's not the BB text
format because those reference citations
from APL I mean from you know those
standard academic
organizations they are very much
corrupt. So like you know you have a
particular style guide depending on
which university you know they have a
particular style guide and there are
several of them uh and but they turned
out they are you know they are extremely
complex and not practical and they are
just like corrupted you know they they
are fake they you know they are no good
you know those uh bibliography
formats So my citation does not follow
those formats. My citation is just my
own. So you got the title, date, very
important, critical, then person's name,
then the then the
URL if there's one. Okay. So
um it would be nice if we could have a
file with the metadata and you could
simply site in HTML. Uh what do you
mean? Yeah. Well, okay. So what we going
to do now? So we got
um I've been coding so much. I have hand
pen.
Uh, so what I want to do, I want to be
able to
um, uh,
go auto order somewhat also allow allow
emit URL. So you want to you want the
code to be able to identify which one is
URL, which one is title, which one is
author, which one is state. Okay, you
want the code to be able to identify
that.
Um, so yeah, so I used to have code like
that, but then it's pretty
complex because so this problem is
involving you got a list of items. Let's
say 10 could be a 100. Okay, but in our
case it's just four things. So you got a
list of items you want to be able to
identify which one is
which. Now if you don't care much about
if you don't care about the being the
most efficient way to do that then
it's kind of easy. Not exactly because
it's it's all huristics because you you
cannot be 100% sure to be able to
identify each one of them with
certainty. You see, because like we
talked about, you know, this this by
Ewan Morrison, that could be the title
itself. There's no way to tell except if
that if you have a by word in front,
then usually it's just the author, you
know.
So there's no
100% certainty URL typically you can
know for certain because if it start
with
https okay
um and similarly for date you see if you
have if your date is always in this
format this is ISO something 89
something format this is the best format
for date then it's trivial to recognize
is however in real world most websites
most author most academic paper they
don't use this date so like they have
the American style the most idiotic
style like sometimes January 23rd 98 or
gen
23 sometimes they say 23rd sometimes
they say 2 three then sometimes January
is one instead of Jen or or sometimes
it's full January you know sometimes Jen
sometimes one sometimes 01 so the date
so so I got the
command kasana fix day time uh you know
so that command rec tries to recognize
and make them into this universal format
So, so for now it recognize these
varieties of format. You see some
sometimes people use a slash sometimes
with a dot you know and the order is all
screwed. So even with this command you
know I was using this command but in the
past I you know often
uh
like you know still often you cannot
recognize the date.
So, so but if you Yeah. So to to
recognize so you know so this is fixed
day time
uh this code is here if you guys want to
use it fixed day time so if you have any
of these type of date time format you
press a button it'll call this command
and those day time will be fixed so
let's copy the URL and let's go to talk
show and paste it there
Okay.
Uh okay. And also this code is not being
updated. So the you see I can I know
because this version format is old. So
2024 February. Okay. But let's
um describe function go to the source
code. So okay. So the code haven't
changed 2024
February.
Uh yeah so you can use that code and
what else we are doing
uh daytime passer.
Okay
so what are we doing now? So let's go
back to
this to
do. What is this? Programming block.
Close. Close. Close. Close. Back here.
Make citation. Yes, that's the code we
want to fix. And
uh
um Okay. So, right now they require this
old URL title author
date. Okay. So URL title of the
date you know to actually code
this it's not going to be trivial you
know it will require a lot of thinking.
So basically what you do is that you got
a list of four
things. So, and for each one, you know,
you got four variables, URL, title,
author, date. You want to set them to,
you know, one of these items in a
list. So, you you pick the one that's
the most easy to recognize. Let's say
URL because URL always typically always
begin with
HTTP, right? So, you start with URL, go
through the list. If you found the
match, set that to URL and DD that
element
ei. Okay, so now your list got three
items. One of them is Neo. So you got
three items.
Well, you see this problem is
complicated complicated because your
your list of four items some of them may
be new to begin with.
So anyway let's suppose all of them are
field uh
so so you start with URI you got it then
you set it then you start with say let's
say
date then when you find the date you set
to the date make that item Neo so now
your list got two more items that's not
Neo okay so that would be between title
and
author. Uh so how do you determine well
title is
usually so if the line contains by
something then that's often that
typically is
author. Okay. So, but you don't know for
sure um because very often the title
will be you know by something or
sometimes the title could
uh must contain the author name because
for
example so you know you got all
literature's for example Arabian Knights
you know uh sometimes you want Arabian
Knights by by Sir Richard Burton okay
they uh other examples
um for example this one the time machine
by HG Wells so the
title contains
by for authors that has been dead
classic work you want you typically want
the author name to be part of the
title
so so you cannot determine you know so
when the title you know When a line
contains by you cannot be sure it's
title or
author. Yeah. So this is a great novel
by the way. One of my favorite the time
machine. Uh so you so you
got Yeah. So you can you got this in um
you cannot be sure to find
it. Yeah. The code is going to be
tedious. a bunch of guests.
Uh
so I was thinking you know I use this
command
often it used to do this guess but one
time I find it too tedious I so I remove
them so I decided to always require it
to be URL title author date in that
order but
then by now it's been like a few years
uh I find that you very tedious because
every time it's very annoying you go to
a you know you found some programmer
blog blogging about something right like
today we were talking about uh BEM CSS
you know I was trying to find what what
the [ __ ] is that so for example this
page BM style CSS is a methodology that
helps you to create use reusable
components and code sharing in front-end
development By the way, I looked into
that [ __ ] Okay. So, we were, you
know, someone were we were discussing
about that web de
uh George. So, you know, George was
explaining to me and I asked the
Grogbot about this. Anyway, I think it's
this is
uh the Zuma generation idiocy, a snake
oil that doesn't help you anything. It's
just
like and then you you see this, you
know, we were talking about logos two
days ago. You know, these stamped cookie
stamp websites, they have like companies
companies using BM and then and then you
got like one bunch of
logos. [ __ ] idiocy. You see this is a
way to promote themsel you know because
you know if they say Google or Microsoft
then you oh yeah I recognize that you
know oh oh my god they are all using
this I need to use this too you know
it's a tactic to advertisement a
marketing or brainwashing
tactic you know with these companies
using you know our product you know them
a bunch of logos And this a bunch of
logos. This thing is cookie stamp by all
these frameworks, you know, since like
uh 15 years ago. There are so many
websites with this format, you know,
they like they look
nice. So anyway, so for example, so you
know, I'm a coder, so I run into these
articles. So I want to site it, you
know, because I want to make comments,
you know. So I you know so let's say for
example
uh comp my program my programming blog.
So actually I was I was um just starting
to write a blog about it. So here so you
can see web dev blog what's
bem smash css cube css. So I asked gu a
bot you see I asked
gu because I I was trying to read you
know what they say you know like easy
modular flexible you know but I don't I
don't quite understand what what do you
mean you know so I was reading it learn
why it is better you know I was reading
this I don't quite get it like what what
what is the point then I asked Gw then
gu did a good explanation you know then
I see oh okay it's kind of naming
convention then you know
then anyway
so so I you know so I want to blog about
this website so what I do I copy the URL
go here copy the URL go to Emacs so for
example then let's say start a new
blog to-do okay so let's say paste URL
and And typically, so for most people,
for most bloggers, programmers, that's
it, you know, then they just comment,
"Oh, I found this website something
about BMC CSS." Okay, that's
typically what people do. That's it. But
you got a problem with a simple link
that like that because by next year, you
know, by five years, it'll come. You
know, maybe you are young today, but
five years, 10 years will come. You
don't remember what the [ __ ] that is.
You know, you click it, it's gone. You
know, like mo most of these, you know,
they last five years, then it totally
disappeared. Like you don't know who who
the [ __ ] they are. All this all these
like, oh, CSS, you know, like and more
Mo
more, we we got a moto elite hacker.
He's like, "Oh, you need to use
this." You know, so most of these sites
like that, they don't last long, you
know, five years, 10 years, they'll be
gone. And
also, so anyway, so so most people when
you blog, you got a URI out, but by you
know, in few years, you don't remember
what it is and you don't know who wrote
it and you don't know what date. Usually
they don't even have a date. I always
have a date. Okay, I always have a date
on my blog but you you go you know to
other website like often times you
cannot find the date you and also you
don't know who wrote it you know so if
you want your writing to be more
permanent you need the URL but also the
date and the author okay and also title
okay that's why you need this
citation
so so the next thing I have to do is I
need to find the uh author and that is
is usually a headache because this
[ __ ] this starting in like around
starting around 2000 year 2000 you know
they they started to not including their
name at all. So you have no idea who the
[ __ ] wrote the wrote this. Okay. Like
like what what's your background like
what what what are you and half of the
time they are corporation because they
are making money you know they want to
promote something they want to sell
their snake oil so they don't give a
date or author
or you know company company names
usually okay like have it you
know so I cannot you know there's no
author name attached And the
title like a lot this website you know
this this particular website is an essay
you see it's a essay or documentation
they are trying to explain to you what
is
BEM you know BEM CSS right but they
don't know you know they don't know
stuff they don't have a proper title you
see instead you got a instru in
introduction so a lot a lot website like
that. So in this case what can I do? Uh
I just make
[Music]
um well usually in this case I don't I
don't site it. I you know I just you
know
like I just say uh I just say BM
website you know because they don't you
know they don't have title author stuff
like that but for many other more
serious academic papers then they will
have proper title and author and
eight. Okay. So anyway, that's why this
is uh you know make citation that's why
uh you want this
um so yeah I was blogging about that
then yeah so I was saying that then I
started to you know it's so I was trying
to show example it's quite tedious to
find title they don't have a title so
well let's so we make one for them BM
homepage page.
Okay. Then by you don't know who the
[ __ ] it is. Let's say who is it by? Then
you have to
dig. You have to dig like what
corporation who they belong to.
You know this is this this is like
little thousand problems of the coders
and that's
why society gets worse and
worse you know because they don't
understand how society works or
whatever. So you you you go to
FAQ about
uh this crap. I want to know who are
you maintained by core team with the
help of our
contributors. So what the [ __ ] is core
team? So go to
it. There it is. So finally you get some
names.
So like but what what what is their
company? What do they
do? You know this this kind of situation
not not
good. Uh Vadus Sakov seems like
Russian Va. So people organization
overview and see overview get BM. Oh
okay. next generation of
BIM. Now, is that an actual company or
is it just a GitHub for you two people?
You don't
know. Uh,
okay. Yeah. So, so this project, this
seems like [ __ ] It just seems like this
is not useful at all. This just some
some Joe created
this and oh lots of stars
5.7 kilo
uh project structure inside of your
Astro project. You will see the
following folders and
files. Astro looks for Astro. So what is
this? Get
B. Oh god. Back to this page. Naming.
Introduction.
Introduction. Naming.
Okay, I think I'm tired of
this this
website.
Um, so what we do now? So I Yeah, so I
was working on my uh
citation command. I wanted to be able
to automatically figure out the URL
title or the
date. Okay. And uh also I want to be
able to sometimes
omit
omit a URL also. Okay. But I decided now
actually coding I decided it's too
complex. Let's not do it.
Yeah. Okay. That's
uh yeah kind of
annoying. Okay, that's about that. Now,
there's another thing we I want to do is
I want to be able
to, you know, when you do a when you
take a photo from your phone or
screenshot, you got a file, but on
Apple, they don't include the they don't
have a date in the file name. Typic
usually cameras they do but I noticed on
Apple's iPhone they don't have a date in
the file
name they have the date in inside the
file as a meta data so that's very
annoying because metadata sometimes gets
removed so when I transfer file from my
Mac to my
PC usually I automatically strip the
meta data so by the time I get it the
you know I I don't have the
date so I don't know when is the date
this photo was created I forgot right so
that's very annoying so I want to write
a script such that before I remove the
meta data
I you know move the date into the file
name
then remove the meta data okay but right
now I don't you So, how many people are
watching? I don't feel like coding it. I
mean, so what do you guys think?
Okay. Uh so if you guys don't know,
well, so there you know, so there is
this command command to delete exif
data.
uh very useful and uh that's how you
know so I have a bunch of command that
show meta data or delete meta data so
for example I can show you screenshots
directory so this is a screenshot one of
I did so you press a key then it'll show
you the meta data for that file
uh you see you got file modification
date access date creation date, but this
may just be this may not be the date the
this photo was taken because you know I
have another command
that now we move remove meta data so
it's it's gone so now if you show it
some of the minimum is still there but
it it's going to be
um it's not it's um you
So what I'm saying this file creation
date is not necessarily the date the
photo is
taken. So you got all these command. So
all these commands I'm relying on this
external command
exif.
Okay. So now I want to Okay. So let's
focus
on how do you get the date out of
it. Okay. So I don't want to show all
meta data. So let me
show okay my emac command show meta data
and uh it
will what does it do?
It just Okay. So when you call it this
command on a file name, it will just
show all meta data.
Okay. Then
but oh god this is going to get complex.
What I want what we want is the specific
date for the for for when the photo was
taken.
Okay. So then in that case then you need
to look into the
standard
for
exif. Uh for example here's a sample
from from nikon camera.
Okay. So there it is. So there is the
daytime original. I believe that's
the so camera model
name file modification
time. So you need to look into JPEG or
PNG their
specifications
standard meta data
headers
to in order to use this
X E exif tool to extract that you know
so exif tool their man page is very
complex
uh this is their man page image very
complex.
The
complexity may be due
to either the complexity of the meta
data of different image formats
themselves which I believe is fairly
complex because you got EXIF standard,
you got GPS, you got quite a few, okay,
from different standard bodies
uh JPEG, PNG, you know, then then camera
makers, they may add their own some of
these image files they may have
extensible metadata format okay then you
got video formats that's extremely
complex so that's
complex but then this command
itself you know it may adds more
complexity it doesn't
uh well yeah
so so our job is to extract
ract the original date of a photo from
the meta data. So, how do you do
that? Uh, okay. That's going to take a
lot time to code and research.
So I don't think that's suitable for for
my live stream
now
because you know
so yeah another dead end we okay so
today we got two dead
end. So this is metadata
sample. Uh this is what this is MP3 file
sample. Okay. Oh yeah. This this Nikon
camera is a camera I had in 2023. I mean
2003 20 years ago.
Yeah. Wow. So I had this page like
two 20 years ago.
uh 2010.
Okay. Okay. Yeah.
2010. Okay. But this is 2013. Okay. So
that's a sample
exif meta data. Okay. So search for
date. If
you search for date, you got date date
date. Okay. Now this is now what is this
one? This is sample output on MP3 file.
Okay. Okay. Right now we don't care for
MP3 files. Okay. So then you got a
daytime original. Okay.
2001. Yeah. That's one of my file
bulp MP3. I bought a CD then uh ripped
it. Okay. So then you got GPS there.
Okay. So
what then you got let's look at the man
page. Okay. So then check the man page.
Uh search for date list or date names.
Okay. So, there is a easy way. Let's
search for date.
Okay. Let's highlight all words that
says date.
Okay. So, let's go
down. So, this set format for daytime
values that sets the
format. Okay. But not necessarily the
date. Then you got preserve file
modification date time. Okay. that you
don't care. Then you got shift all
formatted daytime values. Global time
shift. What the
[ __ ] Shift all formatted daytime
values. Okay. Then you
got optional details tag. Extract
information for the specific
tag. For example, create
date. Okay. Yeah. What is that? The date
the photo was taken or what is it? Okay,
there's so many. Okay, so you see we are
only there are so
many there are some 20 pages
more. Okay, so we
not Okay. Uh cheat. Let's cheat. Let's
ask AI bot, how do you extract the
date a photo is taken? Okay. Yeah,
because this this is going to be
incredible.
Uh it's
such
update date
format daytime original.
Oh, so you can daytime or you know
create
date not create
date. Okay, let's ask Quoke.
in a photo. Let's see. Let's
magnify which header is
the which
header is the date time the photo was
taken you know very broad question
because it may depends
on the image format JPEG or
PNG and let's just ask
it. In a photo file, the date and time
the photo was taken are typically stored
in the
EXIF metadata, not in a single header,
per se. Okay,
exf something something. The specific
EXIF tag that contains the daytime the
photo was taken is called daytime
original. That's what you want. Okay, so
thank you AI. Now go back here. Then
list all lines containing that word.
Okay. So
this so that's that's basically uh
that's what you
want. Okay. So now we
um so now let's color all that wood by
pink.
Okay. So,
oops. My I
think my screen went to the night mode.
So,
let's turn it
off. Night light. Now, does that
actually show up on video? Let's Let's
see.
nightlight. I don't Oh, so I think it
does not show when you
stream.
Interesting. So
anyway, we don't know how to do it. So,
so it's stored in that daytime original
tag name datetime original format. Okay.
To view this
information.
Okay. How to extract this using
PowerShell? Let's see if you can. Let's
see if it
suggest to extract the data original
from photos exif meta data using
powershell. You can leverage the system
drawing. Wow, it gives you a script.
Let's try it. Can
we?
Fantastic. Okay, so looks nice. Now,
it's a bit promising. I'm not sure, but
um so let's go
to today's talk show and uh
extract. Okay, then let's make a
PowerShell script. Paste it
there. Pop it
out. Okay, that's the code. And let's
copy this uh book so that we have a
record of so we can reference to
it. Okay. Here so here's the code. So
it's using the net system.drawing image.
I've used that before to extract the
width and height but that is very slow.
Uh, so you need that. Okay. Then
property ID for daytime arrangement. Oh,
so you got a property ID.
[ __ ] you got property ID, then get
property item. So, oh, so we can
actually get it just like that. Image
get property item.
Okay. Uh, wow.
So then you got ask key get string then
trim
uh then write output daytime is that
so okay looks like this is this could be
the answer but now we need to test it
with a actual photographics image
uh I don't have it you know I just got
screenshots here
So, yeah. So, I need to do it offline. I
don't want to try to do
it for my photos. Okay. So, I'm going to
do that
offline. And uh and close that. Close
that. Showing browser. And that's it for
today.
So this is PowerShell example. Can you
do it
in oh god can how do you do it in bash?
Okay let's try to ask it. So in on
windows you know this requires the
system.d drawing
image. So I don't know you you see
PowerShell is dependent on net and the
entire net is open source and powershell
is al also available on Linux you know
you can install it which I have I have
have installed on Mac and Linux but does
that mean all the
net functions are included
uh I'm not sure so the question is does
it include the system.drawing image for
powershell on
Linux that is critical question I don't
know so anyway so let's try to ask a
different question how how to extract it
on Linux okay let's see what it
says okay so you got use exif tool okay
this I can use this I have
I already installed it. There. There it
is. Fantastic. Just use that.
Fantastic. Great. Okay. I think that's
the answer I want. Okay. And that's that
would be it.
Um that would be it for today. So you
just all you have to do is just say
shell and that command show in
browser. Okay, bye
guys. Hey Pash. Hey we got some people
joining late. Hello Kasa. Uh hi there
Emulation Edu.
Hi, may you prosper and be well. I would
love to suggest you duck the duck go AI
just opening up options for you. Thank
you for your honest
ramblings. Duck go duck go is no good.
Okay. Duck duck go they started massive
they well they started censorship when
the Ukraine war began.
Now I don't know you know I don't know
what is your political
inclination. So when I talk about
politics it you know when you talk about
politics it may offend some
party you know depending on like which
thing. So so duck if you but I have a
blog about it. Duck duck go sensor
results. So before 2018, duck duck duck
go is supposed to be you know well loved
by all the nerds because they don't
track privacy and they don't censor. But
starting 2018 that's when Ukraine war
began. They say oh all the fake news we
need to you know we want to prevent
censorship. Uh where is it
here? Uh
wait, they got several problems. They
got technical problems, too. But anyway,
starting here, Duck Duck sends a result
for Ukraine war because the guy apparent
apparently Anyway, that's politics.
Okay, that's another topic. Ukraine war,
if I may summarize, Ukraine war is a
massive
plunder by the USA deep state, you know,
and killing lots of people, you know,
that's what we are doing. Uh, you know,
so far half a million, you know, uh,
yeah, half a million young people
died and Trump is stopping it right now.
Uh, okay. That's it about that. Bye,
guys.