good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is 2019 October 21st
Monday 10 o'clock a.m.
San Francisco time in the morning and I
have tons of stuff to talk about to show
you guys okay make sure I don't have
controversial stuff in my tabs okay I
should usually I check that before the
stream so I got a tons of things to talk
about and and good morning you guys good
morning George
good morning to Perth Australia
good morning green deck to Russia a good
morning part to Germany good morning
Freddie Freeman Freddie Freeman we we
are you from again good morning good
morning League of noobs we are the
League of noobs and I have a keyboard to
show you actually I have this fantastic
fans fantastic Gauri called keyboard you
see this is my normal set up how you
call it the cameras kit kit kit kit rig
okay this is this is my big I'm thinking
I'm gonna show you this keyboard now
look at the lights
can you see it now you cannot see it
[ __ ] you know the it's a lighting there
there you go
sar layout okay the ultimate hacking
keyboard that means I'm using whoever
uses this keyboard you are a hacker okay
stupid camera
stupid Logitech
[ __ ] logitech why is it okay so what is
the topic today we have a lot of topics
today and I have a lot of topics today
and there are several questions I think
so let's begin begin at the beginning
and remember to show remember to show
live chat otherwise you know so that
links shows up csgo damn how many frame
per second when you get on that see csgo
csgo is stand for you know one of those
games fighting army soldier fighting
games what did what is the name you know
I love to play that if I play I'm gonna
beat you guys ok trust me I'm old but I
can see with you guys in those games
csgo that did you know the soldiers with
a bunch of guns you can switch guns and
stuff CSKA csgo yeah what is the name of
that game anyone type it so good morning
Liam
where you from Liam Freddy is from
Germany oh my god I have so many Germany
German German friends German friendship
Counter Strike global Offensive oh ok
yeah I know the name Counter Strike
but I suppose global Offensive is
another version something different a
new map like every every year they have
a new map new things the the final goal
is that you buy you buy London good
morning to London
my European friends you know it's funny
I don't actually have that
proportionally I have a lot less
American followers American for reasons
I can kind of guess why
so anyway so I we have a lot of topics
to talk about and so what are some of
the questions okay part sales goal and
functional programming yes we can do
some examples of that code examples of
explanation anything specific but
because skoland is just a fun generic
general-purpose language and it does
support function of programming well you
know depending on who you ask you know
is because if you ask the Haskell people
like in modern days people think
functional programming must be like
Haskell where the language do not even
allow you to define a variable and
change the variables value the language
simply do not it's impossible in the
language so people think that's
functional programming but that's that's
not true functional programming these
things to 20 years ago or 30 years old
basically means you program without you
write functions and you try to you
program it without side effects and a
lot languages such as C C++ Java you
cannot do that okay you simply cannot do
that and the least Mathematica APR they
are supposed you know they are
functional programming languages you
can't you can't do that but they also
have they also allow you to define
variables and change the variables value
okay it's always nice to show some code
but we're gonna we have tons of things
to talk about for example let's say this
let's say this let's say define let's
say Co okay so X so we define two
variables x and y and
here let's magnify and that is close
that close that and the sauce start
command log mod so we're gonna do a
multitude of topics and here you're
gonna see all my Emacs commands
multitude of topics magnify yeah I I
turned off my key Marco keypad because
I'm plugging this new keyboard so things
are new a bit here so so okay so set cue
set set X value to 3 then we can print
messages we can set say print messages
okay let's print X okay and but let's
just say one variable and then we can
set X to 4 and we can print it again you
see so that's a code if we evaluate it
now let's show the message but ok
messages buffer now we need to go back
ok here so now we evaluate this code you
see we change the value of x2 from 3 to
4 it's doable let's run a code Linette
ok so the message is it's not the string
so it's X here okay so let's do it again
so now we run it debugger entered don't
type arguments Trina shut the [ __ ] up
okay so so the message is needs to be
like that ok because it's expecting a
string meanwhile our X is a number type
mismatch so you need to do this okay now
now we'd run it okay
then it you see it prints out here three
and four magnify you see so you can see
in eMac list you can change the value of
a variable now in Haskell and basically
only Haskell it this is impossible you
simply cannot do such thing the language
design makes that impossible so anyway
but this is a is considered a functional
language one of the first one the first
one and so but today the new generation
you know they don't know history they
don't know [ __ ] and they think oh this
is not functional because oh yeah you
have you change the value of variables
anyway so Haskell is like the extreme
okay yeah because you know as time goes
on one decade two decades three decades
we have more technological advancements
there so therefore you have languages
that's more you know we can do it
because remember before Y thirty years
ago you don't have a language that do
not allow change of variable values
because you know it takes a lot compiler
technology you can do it but it's gonna
be ten times twenty times slower so it's
like you will be have no use in the
industry this already back it back then
it's the very slow very slow and
consumes huge amount of memory has cow
is pretty old by the way has cow is like
twenty years old or 25 years old nine
1990-1995 you know you have has cow it
has now become popular because around
2010 2009 or so because because the cpu
we you know we no longer have faster cpu
so we have multiple CPU and partly also
because javascript javascript javascript
is the language that introduced function
of programming to the masses
primarily by the guy called Rockford the
guy who invented Jason he wrote us he
wrote a book the JavaScript the good
parts okay so anyway let's close that
that's about and also so functional
programming languages so Haskell is kind
of extreme and Haskell is kind of a long
second so let's do this show in browser
and I don't have the keys the proper I
don't have my keypad
Mako's so you see that's the base in
Haskell is the extreme so a functional
programming languages change of
perception list versus Haskell the
ability to mute mutate not mute okay
mutate variable the ability to mutate
variables value this versus Haskell and
by the way there's also ml Oh camel ml
standard ml camel o camel then F sharp
now that's a lineage of the Oh camel
meta language family they are all
basically the same language
now these languages allow mutation of
variables and these languages are also
extreme functional programming languages
they do almost everything has spoken to
almost you know it's that it's the same
Haskell is in fact derived hope learned
from much of Haskell is learned from you
know
of these you know mao metal language but
but however in this meta language family
you do allow mutation of variables why
because that's practical that's actually
first of all it's practical because in
industrial industrial coding in many
situations it's simpler is simpler if
you just allow it and also that's one
reason the other reason is that when you
allowing variables to change value
that's in many cases is just faster it's
just faster less memory usage to
implement it okay that's why so actually
we have a lot of topics to talk about so
but party is asking about : so we were
talking about basically what it means to
be a functional programming language
more or less right so unless but you
have more specific questions ask it okay
me make sure I'm reading my comments so
Freddie says damn how many frame per
second you get when you play in Counter
Strike I'm not sure what you mean like
like I'm a Mac on a Mac it sucks to play
games you know you you don't have the
nice you don't have graphics cards and
you cannot install graphics card yo you
can do is just buy the most expensive
Mac $3,000 you know Apple sucks blood I
know about graphics cards because
backing from 2008 to to the 2008 to from
2007 to 2012 I was playing second life
oh and what what the difference graphics
card makes let me just show you my
website again I've showed this many
times in my previous talk but a lot of
people new people don't know second life
is the worst hack in the universe okay
and I have a website dedicated dedicated
to Second Life I have like hundreds of
screenshots so
I was praying in second life in in data
on I was praying shooter games fighting
with the teenagers [ __ ] you know
headshot headshot or whatever [ __ ] you
go [ __ ] you and I beat them you know you
know I think that they are using they
are using automatic or semi-automatic
rifles you know the technical name you
basically just like machine guns do too
you can shoot you know they they are let
me show the screenshots okay of that
second life was hack in the universe
okay so then here is also when we get
into furries you know look at that
beautiful panda with her half kids
showing where she hear these lovely
creatures of the world what a wonder it
is so many oops
God Google is going to censor me
okay so panda soldiers there we are now
some of these are my friends we are on
the same team this this is me you know
in second life you can change your
avatars any time so this was me at this
at this time so I was this skeletal
Sonic the Hedgehog and by the way you
can watch a video of me why in this
guy's out YouTube okay so open a new
okay we digressed a lot I have a lot of
things to talk about anyway but anyway
that so let's just keep on with this so
YouTube am i doing good am i doing okay
guys in my my arm topic how many people
11 people not too bad
11 people is my usual number of live
viewers sorry
they call me cheating okay because they
they cannot feed me so they called me
cheating
so someone recorded me taking one of the
guys out in combat in combat and you
know and they they put on YouTube
actually it's a good video okay I don't
know where is the video I we have to
find it wife caught life cheating second
knife so you have to yeah that's not you
have to find I have the link here so
second life combat videos
Kotani canonic syndicate that's the the
military group i'm with so this is this
is another acquaintance
I wouldn't say friends well we we talk a
lot we are in the same team she is a
leader okay
she is what you might call a thought
actually she's not well she's the leader
okay she's a girl and she lead the team
and you know and so in his sex life you
have to obey her like yes yes yes madam
because you have this is like role
playing and he is also another leader
he's one of the you know young guys I
would say no yeah normally they are much
younger than me like 20 years younger
than me so this is one of the young guys
and he also be old you know he peeled
lots of things you know guns and the
scripting you know to make the gunfire
and things like that
okay so this is me you know this is me
in in this military in this notice now
notice this you see the avatars they
have the same they are this is the
uniform so we are you know this is the
the the army the
our groups uniform I just woke up one
hour ago but anyway so this is me and
you see the gun the you know the style
every other style match so you can see
and she is wearing a [ __ ] Tootsie how
you caught that you know it just for fun
she's wearing that you know the for the
ballerina the tutsi second life is a lot
fun actually and and in this guy in the
background he's from another army I kind
of also know him I don't remember them
now because I haven't been his ten years
from now and this is our base and okay
this is this is some other guy okay
those are some other guy but I'm going
to show you a video where
so oh it's good great
good morning la casa la la la cacica
la cacica you are in Spanish I write or
where you from Matt says Muni Matt Matt
says the tech lead advised to learn a
scripting language to get results fast I
just saw another of his video Oh the
tech big guy huh to learn a scripting
language to get results fast resourceful
what is he thinking of course you know
since 10 years ago you have to know a
scripting language in fact most coders
called scripting language like no vast
majority of programmers don't know the
compiled language anymore like C C++
Java you know web dev it's all scripting
language hola cus lo la casa Kazakh
Kazakh Kazakh is I think it should be
Kazakh right so it's from Guatemala it's
very interesting we have the we are
cosmopolitan of the people of the world
you know there's a girls magazine
cosmopolitan the [ __ ] idiot
girls magazine cosmopolitan okay the
girls magazine you know it's look at the
images you know girls magazine
cosmopolitan you know there's sex how to
hunt how to do a [ __ ] how to this sex
position will change your life fact
second [ __ ] cosmopolitan [ __ ] [ __ ] girls
you know they cosmopolitan I was always
wondered why do they name their magazine
cosmopolitan I actually never researched
on it but I assume because you know like
50 years ago you know the cause the word
cosmopolitan being a cosmopolitan is
fashionable because remember it's not
like today where you have internet you
can see people from different countries
but back then let's say 50 years ago you
you know you're actually very local you
know you don't know people from other
countries this is so yeah internet is
quite amazing like even 20 years 20
years ago in 1990s in USA you don't see
Chinese okay I mean every time in USA
when Americans you know they publish a
photo of girls from China it's always
even in movies even in the movies it's
always the extreme ugly you know like
ugly girl from China they they put it on
Hollywood they think that's Chinese you
know but today it's different right you
go to youtube you see tons of cute
chicks from China that that is actually
normal because I mean in China if you
look at movie stars of course you know
lots of girls and they are so extremely
sexy and beautiful but even in the 90s
and even even in 2000 in USA you don't
see that like like you know even the
Hollywood or newspaper magazine whenever
they have a asian girl it's like super
ugly that's like you know it's like it's
basically like fake news but today you
can go to youtube you see tons of you
know Korean girls hum you know sexy with
dead doing dances and stuff so here is
some so so cosmopolitan where does the
nink came from you know I'm so I'm
thinking 50 years 50 years ago the idea
of cosmopolitanism about like the Paris
you know
fashion you know like so you know and
also so so you want to be you know it's
a past positive thing you want to be a
cosmopolitan especially for girls you
know women they you know they need to do
fashion stuff so cause that so that is
why I think that's how the magazine
picked the name cosmopolitan for their
name so anyway back to Second Life come
back video so you can see here is this
tea oh yeah video unavailable [ __ ] I'm
not sure they still around the compact
combat communities in Second Life
but so for example so the games we are
talking about it's kind of like CS
counter-strike kind of like that he's
not exactly though because Second Life
the graphics and combat system is is is
five times worse then then those
dedicated first-person shooter games but
still you can you do combat so I'm
trying to find the video where they you
see so back then I also so here is a
list of Second Life combat so group
soldier groups you know do you have you
have tens of armies you know is stiffen
army different you know military group
you fight each other the biggest one is
auto auto where they you know the video
is gone it's professional for this video
is professionally made by the way just
just like the you know the seen the
movie scenes when you see in video games
you have the pre you know pre pre pre
prepared you know video how they static
or intro seeing whatever there's this a
third you know they they play the 3d
scene so this video is well made its
profession
done so there's a lot interesting
talented people in Second Life artists
typically they don't make money okay
they are they are dirt poor you know
artist again like I said before
everything you see in second life all
these the the soldier the Avatar the
guns the the the uniform the buildings
are all made by people like you and me
you go in there you start to build so
this mug mug shatters maybe so tears
this is another big Second Life military
group mugs Egeus and this video is kind
of is this video is kind of their
recruiting video you know something nice
and fun for people to watch and after
you watch it oh you maybe you say oh I
want to join I want to join you
marketeers so you go there and sign up
with them then you get the uniform and
guns in and then you can fight and so
they made a video
so this video is not not like this kind
of have fun it's you know it's they made
it kind of have funny so and they all
have their websites let's see this so
this is Auto Imperialis let's see if
their website is still up
oh there's website is still up so they
up still of pain I gotta go in there and
beat them up now I'm not sure because
sometimes they are not active you know
because I mean it's been 10 years so I'm
not sure so this is November 17th is
this just I guess that's just video of
some other games I don't know if they
are still there or not
so although imperialists but I wanted to
show
okay am I talking too much about second
life or should we change topic comments
guys so yeah I put that without context
he made a video about how to code faster
in more tips for newbies okay maybe I'll
change when web assembly is ubiquitous
yeah webassembly more language support
for it
ten people watching so let's go to
YouTube let's just look around
they are actually two videos I want I
want to show one is where am I am a this
steampunk Mecca spider
I hope I can find it these are videos
other people made basically my enemies
okay there they are there we are
so these three videos these four videos
or are all made by other people they
hate me because beat them up various
footage casado super Second Life Sato is
my second life name back then in second
life you have first name and last name
the last name is fixed you choose among
the hundred choices you have you cannot
change the first name you can change
Thank You gonna die okay so here is
thank you cannot die and second life
they are I'm fighting with a bunch of
trolls naturals how you call you know
they they [ __ ] around in any game what's
the word
okay this one's point
so this is 2010
um I'm hyperactive in 2nd night so my
opinion about Julian Assange and what
might happen to him in the future I
don't know I don't have much opinions -
about that you know he's right now he is
in jail he so his story so you know he
you know he released secret documents of
the government of USA and other other
countries basically the the information
that people should know citizens you
know the government is doing nasty
things for his for example Clinton
Clinton Hillary Clinton she she ordered
you know us spies to eavesdrop on German
German counselors phone private phone
you know so the German you guys know
about right about that right many of you
are from Germany so German in Germany
the leader is called cancel right each
country you have different names so you
have Emperor you have kings you have
presidents you have chairman chairman
mao you have you know za you know this
basically the leader of the country or
the tribe or group so in german you have
this this woman i don't think i don't
know but i think she is not good this is
just my guess okay so so you have these
cancer so have every Clinton when she
was the Secretary of War later on it's
called Secretary of Defense
you know you changed our name war to
defense so it sounds better
you know Defense Department he used to
be war war Department so anyways Harry
you know ordered people to listen to the
phone conversations of the German cancer
right guys you know you guys know snow
about that type it so you know so so so
WikiLeaks Julian Assange really you know
get those information and he released it
and also there's a helicopter killing
people the US soldiers just killing
innocent people to clean machine gun so
you know Julian Assange a song in my
opinion he's doing great now of course
then the you know whoever the
politicians you know people who don't
like him whoever who doesn't like him
then smear him so then they say that in
particular the US government's many many
of the US government leaders Polly
polish ins they say oh he indentures
American citizens he you know that's all
[ __ ] there's no proof whatsoever
he's the document eight the documents he
leaks released never indentured any
American okay in my opinion even you
know I am not well I'm not going to say
it you know because I'm an American
citizen so I want to be lawful anyway so
so the government you know he's doing
nasty things and it's been trying to
hide it and also the corporations for
money you know the things like that so
of course the politicians they don't
like him some you know some support him
but but many doesn't so if they trying
to kill him basically but you know
America is supposed to be this demo
democracy freedom you know America use
these words to kill other people yeah
that is true guys so American USA we so
you can't you cannot just grab Julian
Assange and kill him because you gotta
have some reasons you know you in war
you always have to have create reason so
the reason is the reason is he waived
girls okay in in Scandinavia
julian assange you know Julian Assange
so 20 years 20 years ago he's still like
30-something of course then a lot girls
flock over to him because he is somebody
you know he's the leader of the
WikiLeaks we're now
so apparently Julian Assange when he was
in Sweden I think through girls you know
want to you know want to you know slept
with him you know one after the other
they didn't know each other like they
didn't know the fact but anyway Julian
Assange slept with one girl then like
the next day or few days later he slept
with another girl then afterwards the
girl realized the fact that they Oh oh
my god no you are cheating you know so
they start to talk and they worry about
basically they worried about is Junior
Assange a playboy you know maybe he's
slept with every girl you know every day
maybe he's called venereal disease you
know he maybe he's got AIDS and also
there is a broken condom thing in the
broken condom issue like you you know
the oh the condom broke
so apparently today in Sweden broken
condom constitutes rape okay it's it's a
social justice final feminism gone
berserk so if you if the condom broke
then straight okay something like that
so anyway so the girls went to police
and actually I think they dropped they
don't want okay after a while they think
okay we want to withdraw you know
there's nothing anyway so the girls you
know they worried about Julian Assange
being a playboy and also there's
jealousy issue I suppose you know
because he's you know he's you know
cheating suppose the cheating yeah you
know so anyway so they went to the
police then that's a great opportunity
to lock up Julie
son Assange because he raped girls big
news
Julian Assange the leader WikiLeaks
raped girls so for that reason you know
the the US government the high powers
you know they are they have billions of
dollars you know trying to get him so
now you have a reason Julian Assange
raped girls and then you know then you
know the court Linden is discord so
anyway so baseless we basically so he's
when he left you know to the in England
and and you know so so the they get
international police you know actually
and by the way there is no formal
accusation to to there there was no
formal accusation they just want the the
protects the deagle you know the orderly
go jargons is that is that Sweden wants
him back in Sweden so that he can he can
answer some questions of the police
that's that's something like that
there's no formal accusation but that
the thing is you know the you know the
Sweden has contract
you know contract with USA things like
that so once he go to sweat and then USA
is gonna take him to USA then that that
would be the end of his life so anyway
so he's in UK and you know they try to
get him then he went to the edge of
cuarto conser conser you know that was
basically a hotel room where it's
supposed to be the educator sovereignity
you know the political political
political crap anyway so when you are
there you know you are supposed to be
like just as if you are in a jerkwater
another country so cops cannot get you
so anyway he then he became a a
jerkwater citizen so ever since he lived
in that little room for like five or six
years in the beginning things
okay kind of he just hides you know kind
of hides hides in there but but then
apparently the edge of a dog president
they changed you know every four years
they have their elections they change
then us spot out but out the new
president so then the new president is
Pro USA so they have like hey I give you
1 billion dollars you do something for
me so so now the New Age Ecuador
president you know they they started to
remove internet connection of Julian
Assange remove any everything you cannot
go out see the son because he goes our
CEO said you might be shot so he have
not seen seen the Sun sunlight for like
you know five years or so he'd removed
everything you know this is it's like
you know the solitary confinement you
know typically for normal average people
that's the thing you don't want when you
are in prison you don't want solitary
confinement because human animals just
like many other animals especially
dolphins and wolves for example you are
social peope social animals when you are
without other human animals around you
become you go crazy okay so for no more
people vast majority people that's
that's the thing you don't want you
rather be with someone even in jail
so anyway Julian Assange so he is in
this situation then then you know
without internet for four to two years
or so then it became worse the the the
UK polite police just simply went in and
take him out you know grab him you know
and so he is now in UK prison USA wants
to trying to get him to USA so that is a
situation and so what will happen to him
I don't know I don't I I don't know and
it's it's pretty tough you know
that's the politics we are talking about
so the questions part says do you
seriously believe that fake stories
about him doing the girls it was an
obvious cape scapegoat reason to capture
him in his powerful knowledge like what
you mean I mean he slept with the two
girls that's that's true you are not
questioning that right I mean the I mean
I'm saying it's a fake yeah so a Julian
Assange is a hero from the same module
as a Snowden is both should get each
other on wrong and she we should give
them companies to further pursue their
journalistic practice yeah I agree
between them I like Julian Assange I
think Julian Assange is great you know
how Americans you know I'm talking to
Americans a lot you know since I'm
America Americans you know they like
today most Americans would have the
sentiment like Oh China is Evo Oh China
kills people
Oh China put Muslims in concentration
camp that's all [ __ ] okay that's all
propaganda created by us you know to
benefit us now if you want to actually
if you really want to know the truth
free Julian Assange okay and he will
publish all the secret documents of
China that would be the true truth okay
I'm pretty sure Chinese government they
do nasty things okay but not not not
what you hear from American media that's
all crap that's all [ __ ] you get
Julian Assange you free him he will
publish you know the this this truly
real document so if you are American you
know who do you get Julian Assange out
then you are here truth about China you
know not for me for China okay not from
any poor China though 50 cents
this is this [ __ ] propaganda from
American you know the American they they
are panning Chinese on Twitter you know
because you know treaters is saying you
know they are panning they are basically
they are doing censorship but they put
but then they say we are doing this
correctly because because Chinese
government is actually creating all
these straws the [ __ ] propaganda so
Snowden is still part of the US
government
you know Snowden he's hiding in Russia
so so so yeah I support Snowden but you
see I like Julian Assange much more
because Snowden you know I haven't
really actually studied them in detail
but but basically Snowden is small he's
he's thoughts you know his view of the
world is is kind of more American
ideology ideology oriented so for
example he is he is very much concerned
about the privacy of citizens things
things like that
in my opinion that's that's good you
know I also care about privacy that's
good
but compared to Julian Assange you know
point of view I much like Julian Assange
better because Julian Assange is more
general you know you you are concerned
about corruption talks you know dark
things people you know government
powerful people to meanwhile the Snowden
is more like American kind of thought
you know concern about privacy and it's
still good but it's not as as
generalized in my opinion it's more
American kind of thinking but anyway
yeah so he is hiding in you know he's
hiding in Russia now yeah by the way I
heard he he got married
was it he's Orange
you know girlfriend I think he got
married yeah secretly in some in some
Russian Church but Bartholomew Bart says
by saying this you just invited NSA
right now
yeah being always watching no he has
been spied from the start and probably
of his snow snow during his part of the
part of US propaganda why what how is
that so actually I wanted to share some
various footages not this one so
actually I have a lot of things to talk
about but I guess we we already talked
for forty minutes
hold on a second
there is some internet slowness now this
is another video I you see how long
second
so you see this Walmart this fantastic
remember everything in Second Life is
made by people so people have recreated
this warm heart in Second Life
it is amazing yeah so actually so this
is actually this same is fighting you
know so people have recreated this
Walmart in Second Life
so we go there and to shoot you know so
so this is this is this palm pressed
plasma palm I made it you know I created
I scripted I coded I learned the Second
Life scripting language Linden's
scripting language you can go to my
website and search for Kali
Lindon scripting language ASL tutorial
you will see my discussion about that
language I have actually a full tutorial
of that language very interesting
because it's it's nothing like Perl
Python Java CC plus nothing has nothing
because you this language is created to
interact in the Second Life environment
so it's very it's very very different so
I created this plasma bomb this is my
favorite thing you throw it it's like a
tennis ball okay bounces around very
bouncy you know it bounce it's not then
after a few seconds like five seconds it
it it creates this plasma and if you are
within like two meters you die
so that this place is the spawn spot so
when you die you would reappear here so
anyway so that that is part of it but
there is another one I really want to
show but I think it's this one
the Internet is super cell not this one
okay I'm going too slow I'm kind of
anything else
okay I cannot find the apparently there
are quite a few videos of me I cannot
find the true I want to show one you
know I cannot find out maybe it's this
now I cannot find the one that one of
them shows the Steampunk spider which is
really cool you have a avatar that is a
spin
steampunk spider maybe if you search
Sato you'll find it but I have it
somewhere but it'll take some time to
find it so so let's see what is the next
topic ok so guys comment comment and
let's see what's the next topic
you see so these these are soldiers of
another group called 2042 so you have
this body this body is you know furry
and you have this Fox or whatever girl
and this is a guy fox fox or wolf you
have this girl so cute and you have this
soldier and then you have this another
this this is kind of a dragon some kind
of mixed wolf dragon with hones antelope
or something Oh and then we got this
video antelope is a giant rabbit
yes what kind of okay so it's a while
and this recreational programming yeah
so actually I talked about this quite a
few times if you want to know about you
know what I think about least so you go
to my channel search for you know just
type Saudi Lisp and so I did that one
hour you know 19 minutes videos actually
more than one of them you so you might
check that out
widen this actually I don't I would not
recommend this you know you can you can
do it if you have time it's it's not bad
I mean it's not I mean if you ask me you
know just pick one language to learn or
two language to learn Lisp would not be
on my list
you know without qualification like just
just ask me like which which you know
can you recommend two languages only and
only two and I'm not going to tell you
it you know if you ask me you know know
without any qualification like for a job
for four particular purpose
like it just generally
I would not this would not be one of
them anyway
comments guys comments okay so let me
just do some work and put this stuff
here so okay that's the things we talked
about crows second life military least
clothes okay that tastes here clothes
paste that here clothes so let's see
what's the comments League of noob says
do you prefer to work for someone or to
build a project company yeah I would
prefer to work on a project instead and
like what you mean would like work for
someone when you work for a project
that's also work for someone so you mean
so I guess you mean do you prefer to
work in our company or do you work as a
some sort of contract like you just take
a project then you can just call it
yourself then you know the project is a
product they pay you I probably would
prefer that but I haven't been working
in a company for for like 20 years and
you kind of I kind of missed that
because it's a different experience so
actually there were there was a lot
other topics I'm not sure we you know
it's close that second life so yeah I
prefer project walk along because I
usually I'm not so good with talking to
people and stuff like that
so apparently there are people talking
about you know the warm screamed so the
apparently there's supposedly study
where blue light effects sleep I think
that's all [ __ ] okay like today you
have immune systems you it they offer
you like when it's at night when it's at
night they will turn the screen warm
color with warm color okay like night
shift you know if you turn it on when
it's evening the screen color will be
warm I think that's all [ __ ] yeah
because they say you know scientifically
you know they say oh there's some
scientific research you know Bruce doing
they affect your you know bright screen
affects your sleep pattern you know
biometric there's a turn you know the
idiotic term the cicadas so the cicada
cycle things like that you know that may
be technically true but however it's
much more important if you say if you
don't smoke if you don't eat before you
sleep you know that that is far more
significant than reading iPad it's bad
using you know with bright light okay so
how long have I been talking like so I'm
kind of one hour so let's see so I was
going to talk about keyboard but but I
guess not today so we talked about
Second Life
well yeah efficient layout phone numbers
so let me tell you about efficient
layout phone numbers efficient layout
phone numbers so you see these are
numbers one two three four that's a
normal layout that's not efficient
because you're because if you type if
you touch type we are talking about
touch type if you do not touch type then
it doesn't matter because you
in pig but if you are talking about
touch type then the layout of numbers
becomes of matters because of the
numbers you see here's a statistics of
the what's the most used numbers and
punctuation so in programming languages
the parentheses are used the most often
then that then the asterisk then the
dollar sign then the number zero then
the pound sign then one then the end
sign then - okay but if you only
consider the numbers basically one two
three four five eight six nine seven
okay so it's almost in order so number
one is used three times more than number
three
so basically number one and number two
are the most often used in and number
zero so zero one two are the most often
used numbers actually there's an
interesting issue about that but like
why why is number zero one two appears
the most often the number zero appears
the most often is easy to understand
because when you have 1,000 or 1 million
it's all zeros after so that is easily
understood but however why is number one
or two the most frequent than the other
numbers that is a unsolved problem okay
you can go read Wikipedia
I don't remember what's the title but
anyway you try to search you know what
what is the most frequent you know the
the number of frequency statistic you
search something like that then you will
find Wikipedia article basically it's a
well-known unsolved problem but like we
don't know why number one number two
appears the most often in in the corpus
like they you know you you you anyway
that that's that's the thing you might
look into in you know for example you
if you take all the published magazines
or online articles old you know any
articles you know then you do the
statistics on the characters you find
that number one and two are used most
often than the others and and we don't
know why there are several theories you
know but it's not proven
so anyway number one and two is most
often used so you want so but however on
the normal layout number Wyant number
one is pressed by your pinky which is a
worst rather you want you want keys to
press by your index finger or pointing
finger so it would be better if you
place number one and two you know in the
middle like seven eight so anyway this
article studies what is the most
efficient number lay out phone numbers
so I created I basically created my own
and also why is this important this this
is I mean if you are an average
programmer okay then this doesn't really
matter to you much first of all if you
are if you are not a touch type then the
whole article doesn't matter to you okay
doesn't matter but if you are a touch
typist however you are a a virtue
grammar which means you don't touch that
much you don't type that much especially
the numbers so then it doesn't matter
dinner but however if you our data entry
clerk or you know if you really type a
lot then this matters especially if you
type Chinese because if you type Chinese
using the P input then about every five
or ten strokes you have to press a
number one two three four one of them if
you type Chinese for example I can show
you
okay for example now that's one
character I have had to pick a number
one two three four one two three four
five you know so I picked press two then
that character is entered can you guys
actually see it ah let's see you cannot
see it okay so actually let me move the
okay so let me try it try this again
magnify
so I'm going to type Chinese so you see
now you have to pick a number so I type
two that's the character okay
then another bunch of numbers I have to
choose I pick one then that's that press
Enter
so that means typing Chinese okay so
when you type Chinese using the P input
method you have to the number keys
becomes critical you have to type number
keys every about every five or ten
keystrokes so so this is when the
placement of number keys becomes
important when you type a lot Chinese so
that is why that that is why you want
them to be efficient so this this
article is about that so anything else
so I'm kind of out of out of focus you
know out of the spirit to talk about
something so what is this about
so apparently not no TPM was compromised
Oh note VPM was compromised at some
point they're expired private keys have
been leaked meaning anyone can set up a
server with those key keys okay
so okay so guys type something so
anything maybe that's it for today I
have a lot of things to talk about
but usually the thing is you if you have
if you don't have a call like I don't
have a call and when you are doing a
video how good you do often depends on
your mood at the moment like right now
it seems to be out of it Navy wants okay
so there's another topic so unless you
guys asks a question then I can have
answers otherwise so Freddie says on
Twitter I send a few tweets about open
source oh yeah I need to answer that now
I have something to talk about so on
Twitter and you generalizing the
community-based someone some [ __ ] I
think the original idea in the mindset
of sharing software for the sake of
progress is really good proprietary
software is good for making money of
course but which is why but which is why
it is actually progressing faster in
open source products off and lagging
behind but still don't you agree that
you would be difficult as a programmer
and even consumer without open source
yeah that's answer that question so you
see I flame about open source and free
software foundation a lot in fact there
are more than ten videos where I talk
about that at length more than more than
30 minutes each so you might check that
out so basically if you watch me you
know you see me calling open source and
free software [ __ ]
you know you maybe that's too extreme
what part of it is because you know I'm
doing a show and and also that's is that
is just my personality okay so you it
might be better to follow the you know
to
but better articulation and precision
you know not instead of just Conan and
[ __ ] it's like oh open-source [ __ ]
rather you say you know in my opinion
open-source is actually not a good thing
because you know you give detailed
reasons you know you know with good you
know rational reasons I've done that
yeah I have tenths of articles about
that anyways it's my style
it's my personal personality and also
because I'm doing YouTube talk shows
usually actually when you say [ __ ] face
like that you get more viewers so but so
what's what's what's my beef with the
open source I mean maybe maybe you know
don't you think I'm too extreme okay no
because well I okay first of all you
know it's a little bit dramatic okay but
I have real I have given lots of actual
solid reasons over my videos maybe it's
not so well organized but it's there and
also I've written I've written tens of
articles you know you don't read that
nobody reads them I've written tens of
articles document documenting the evil
you know the actual evil and hum of the
open source and free software phonetics
you know their deeds for example
yesterday we talked about Firefox we
talked about how Firefox threatened to
lawsuit the genome people and free
software foundation people the GNU
project to use their Firefox name and to
use their five Firefox logo that's a
solid example of how the open-source
ideology has become you know that it's
like turbo standards and self
conflicting you know they'd you know
fighting with each other you know
open-source like you said I agree in the
beginning it's it's it's a good you know
it's actually good thing you know it's a
good thought but it has become a
ideology I mean I'm not going to be peed
you know the hours of things I've said
you know
but anyway yesterday I gave the example
of Firefox
you know they trying to sue you know of
course then they have reasons they say
oh because legality oh because it's all
[ __ ] ok you want to help people you
want to you know share stuff things like
that you don't lost you people to use
your logo just let other people use your
[ __ ] logo ok
that's back then wind when when Firefox
is the most popular is you know it they
are the dominant browser you know have
the most share it is 80% of browser
market but now ten years ago when
Firefox becomes smoking when Google
Chrome took over favor Fox you know he's
struggling and then then they say oh
please please to use our logo please -
you know that's okay now you know that
that's a [ __ ] criminal behavior and
that's part of open-source you know you
don't you don't see it you know because
you you guys believe in open-source it
becomes ideology you don't think anymore
you just you you and any negative thing
about open source you push off you don't
see it because people vote it down so if
it becomes you know you only you live in
a bubble so regarding about your
question this okay
I mean regarding about you Chris that's
such that's just not Mozilla it happens
in chrome in new with Richard storm and
every happens pervasively you don't see
it because not necessary I'm not
criticizing you okay as usual I created
you know the general but you know my
opinions what I perceive so what I'm
saying is that okay so to you you a
particular issue you know you you you
might think that okay okay so you don't
like open source then what's the
alternative should we or then just be
proprietary no you see I'm not thinking
like that so my my my reason my my
answer to that is you know don't don't
think just like open source versus
proprietary okay just don't think of
that way don't look at things like open
source
view point like you look you start to
look everything with only one one way of
seeing open source or no open source
lets you know that's not good thing it's
like the social justice scan the social
justice card they see everything as Oh
is this is this racism or is it not
reason racism everything is like racism
or female
feminism you know they see everything
you know pavement pay gap you know is
there's no gap okay but they see
everything they church by all is this
whether this is patriarchy or is it not
Iraqi this is wrong way to see things
that way because when you see everything
in that way then everything becomes bad
you know indeed it's the same thing with
the open source thing you know the
reason it happens like that is it's
because he has become a etiology you
don't see anything else you just see
open source or versus proprietary that's
not that's that's one of the results
consequence of ideology that's that's
what it become so instead of for example
what what's the alternative
well let me tell you about alternative
let's say before open source movement
before the open source free software
foundation movement we have we we have
the concept of share you know I act it's
popular in scientific community in 1990s
I wrote mathematical code not just me
okay other I follow other steps you know
you write you write a program you
distribute it you know three you know
just don't you know you put it maybe you
put a head or say just don't use it for
evil okay everyone can just use it
without you know attach Oh what license
what the open-source is which license is
this which is whether it's a GPL flack
okay this happened before the open
source movement you like you share you
you are good person
you you create code just put it out
there even without any mention of
license [ __ ] without the copyright mana
mention of copyright [ __ ] okay people
use it they just use it now if if there
are some company who are concerned about
law I mean law is
sure thing you know you have to I mean
even if you know it's it's it's a
practical it exists so some company you
might check with you hey I saw your
software I didn't see any license can
can we use it they will ask you ok they
will ask you then they maybe you'd never
say yeah sure
if you are truly you know that could you
should show go ahead you email them then
they have a solid proof you know then
they can use it so that's before open
source it's called public domain
oh good hard you know you don't even
have to be public domain you just read
code put it out and people can use it
what what some [ __ ] with the open source
you see so so so technically you can say
oh there but that is also open source
you know you don't don't think of that
way so it for example so the company so
I wrote a great software without any
license whatsoever so people can use it
you know but this company let's say
Google they saw my code this this they
see my code they liked it very much
I mean the software and they want to use
it so they send me an email you know
maybe the law department send me e-mail
say hey we like your software can we use
it then if I'm good you know if I you
know if if if you know I could say yes
yeah sure go ahead so they so they got
proof you know they can use it then they
maybe they are thinking ok maybe they
are thinking oh but we like to make some
changes and we want to charge you know
we want to put into our Google servers
so people will pay us you know ten
subscription or something like that no
we won't we wanna you know do something
so they can email me again
they will they will email me again oh we
want to do this can we do that do we you
know then I can answer I can you know I
have choices I can say no okay it's
sorry but I don't want I don't want my
software to be for the commercial
purposes to make money okay no sorry
oh if you are truly good the phone
answers [ __ ] if you are truly good
you could you could say yeah sure go
ahead
come on
go ahead oh I can just reduce my
software you know in the in the you know
header say this is this software is
public domain public domain that means
anything can do anything with it okay
so anyway so if Google asked me they're
gonna sell my software can't do I allow
I can say no oh I can say yes either
choice that's fine okay so but suppose
if I say yes so they start to say out
the software now is that proprietary or
not how do you judge you know so so what
I'm saying is that don't look at things
you know because because the most people
the open-source fanatics they are
looking at because the open-source has
become fanatics become it becomes
ideology ideologies when people stopped
thinking it's just like we have to do
this open source you know open source
all now open source you know it's that
is that is what happens and I gave the
example on the from other things for
example the social justice they view
things is like the way they view things
is like power power or no power you know
the so they [ __ ] up the everything then
then also let me give you another
example controversial they like the
American American thought he's like just
justice justice and obsession with
justice and in the rape and and what
what's the other you know justice
everything is like you look at
everything is whether is this just oh is
this not just for the [ __ ] you just live
live and let live
you know the people can thrive to
whatever you know not not follow a
ideology American yeah Western thought
is justice and in America this democracy
is this democracy oh is this not not
democracy that of [ __ ] idiots yes I
have seen I've met witches so many real
life back in nineteen I about this
before
I met which you know like he saw me why
we I talked to him
so back in 1998 or was it 1999 there is
that this is when Linux and open source
and free software is thriving because of
Linux and power Linux Perl Apache you
know it began to gain public mainstream
awareness so so back then you have Linux
Expo around the country every year so in
1990 in 2001 in 1999 1999 there's a
Linux Expo in San Jose which is you know
20 minutes drive you know down here in
San Jose big city so Richard Stallman
was there Eric Raymond I think he's also
there Larry war was they okay Larry war
was there which was someone was there
and other people other Linux bigshots
bigwigs so I went to back then I was a
phonetic of Richard Stallman okay so I
was carrying this book mastering regular
expressions you know I usually I always
carry a book with me you know I'm a nerd
you know I was you know a back thing I
was you know reading all that Perl
so I was carrying the book mastering
regular expressions I read it of course
back in 1999 so I went to the Perl
talked binary war I came in late you
know he's like last five minutes of his
talk so I asked him to sign it so he
signed it back then I was at the startup
called brain power comm brain power
dot-com we are we are a job hub like
monster.com today you know you go there
if you are programmer you go there to
find jobs and companies go there to post
their jobs so we are company doing a job
hub I wrote a book database
in 4,000 lines one file in Perl okay
connecting to I think it was ms Qi or
was it MySQL 4009 spell database web web
interface using CGI CGI technology so so
anyway I went to so Larry was signed
signed this book 1999 I also went to
Richard Stallman you know when I didn't
attend his talk but anyway I want to him
to sign but he refused back then I was a
Richard Stallman phonetic you know
opposed to open source by the way yeah I
don't know a lot of people don't know
open source and free software foundation
they are enemies okay they hate each
other I mean Richard Stallman hates the
open source group because open source
group is kind of robbing Richard
Stallman's idea and you know like today
a lot of people don't know that anymore
lots of problems with open source but
anyways we just Roman refused to sign
and he's got several followers behind
him saying starting to tell you why he
does not want to sign it because because
the the the book already books back then
they the reaches home and disagree with
their with their license about the book
you know that's when you begin to have
the free software what's what's the code
you know the license for documentation
that the [ __ ] door it's all miss miss
Richard Stallman's
is problematic so anyway I was a fanatic
of him because I believe his idea is
because his idea is actually think oh
well the open source is like just
nothing it's just for you know helping
the commercial world you know in fact I
can I have an article to prove it I
showed it before let's not do it
so anyway I'd so he refused to sign and
you know he's got several followers
behind him turning me or the reasons you
know oh because you know you have to do
the
so that or go across the street by
Adebayor new menu or something you know
with a license which is llama grease
then he can sign it
but I was like I know this already
because I was a fanatic of Richard
Stallman I've read everything he's
written I know the food detail okay so
anyway so he refused to sign it so I met
him for like you know three minutes and
I do remember he was looking at my
nametag you know when you are in these
tech conferences you have to wear your
attack with your names okay
who is this guy looking at my nametag
anyway that was 1999 he probably don't
he probably don't remember me oh and
also I emailed him yeah he probably I
emailed him back in 2008 when I was you
know I I was telling him about the Emacs
manual which sucks donkey ass that's
another story anyway I think that's it
for today what's your opinion of Richard
Stallman stage stepping down with I I
did a video about that at actually two
video two videos about that like two
weeks ago so him you know you might
check that out
you know if you ask you know if you
don't never say you know Richard
Stallman I talked about this in my past
videos too so it's a lot I am just going
to repeat you know never if you invite
Richard Stallman know if you are talking
to him never say thank you so much for
your contribution to open-source he gets
very angry ok he gets this video you
know YouTube on it he gets go [ __ ]
yourself
if you he gets very very angry because
if you guys I don't know if you know he
you know he he clearly you know free
software foundation their position on
open source is that they are criminals
cuz something like that okay they they
have their position about open source by
the way open source is there's
organization these people today's people
you know you guys I don't know you guys
don't know much of things history
anymore open source is an organization
it's like this number is a nonprofit
organization started by Eric ESR Eric s
Raymond and and other people so it's a
you know it's a joke they sanctioned
what you know they they control the name
kind of open source they you know they
trademarked the name
so anyway Richard Stallman is very you
know the free software position is very
much against open-source you know you
watch Richard Stallman's interviews
there are a lot they almost every one of
them Vicki will mention it you know he
will say open-source stole our idea we
don't we as free software foundation we
do not support or approve open-source at
all you will see it but this this stays
you know it
like I said open source or free software
actually both they become idealogy
like people you don't people don't even
know what what they are talking about
you just ideologies like we do much you
must do open source otherwise you are a
[ __ ] [ __ ]
that's what mostly
think and they become what so what's the
end result the the end result is google
facebook treater Microsoft they become
the evil empire they have all the power
in a world
meanwhile the open source becomes
nothing I talked about this almost thing
every one of my video anyway that's it
for today thank you guys for watching I
think yeah that's that would be it
no V p.m. so 90 minutes on the spot so
we always 90 minutes so about my
schedule I don't know what's my schedule
for this week I'm thinking and maybe
I'll start to do random so tomorrow
maybe it's not ten o clock anymore so I
don't I you know that's that's just my
life story so I don't have a plan I
don't have a schedule I don't I don't
know what is good and you know
indecision and maybe I should just
follow 10 o clock every day but then but
people in Australia and in China they
don't they don't get to see my lab view
so I don't know what's a next one but
usually if I do have a schedule I'll
announce it in my youtube channel the
communities tab you might see it there
so anyway that's it for today so thank
you guys for coming bye guys father says
be consistent with your schedule you are
right I mean you see one of the one of
the fundamental thing about SEO or
blogging you know if you want really be
popular you have to stick to a schedule
yeah I know what you mean but so I need
to you know it's just indecision I don't
know what I need to fix on time for at
least for this week or something but
I don't know yeah so yeah I don't know
maybe maybe you just spitting o'clock
everyday then you know because I've been
thinking several things I've been
thinking also doing you know separate
videos with not livestream but anyway I
don't know I don't know okay
do something that's correct that's right
yeah that's right but you know yeah also
it's easier said than done you know I've
been living my life the way it is you
know that's just you know you cannot
change yourself to be someone else
anyway that's that's it for today bye
guys