welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
today i'm going to uh it's a work
session coding live work session i'm
going to work on my website and i'm
going to show you now
so let's skip the date you can what you
can see the date on the left right
on the lower right corner of my screen
is that true that's true indeed okay so
let's uh let's begin so let's uh
show you
the keyboard blog go to
keyboard blog and let's
there is a photo i want to do okay so
this is a working session lots of coding
and i'm going to explain the workflow
the emacs workflow the commands and any
technical stuff
so there is a keyboard showing saudi
discord if you haven't already so
keyboard is a fantastic keyboard by dion
this is pepe colored keyboard save it
okay save it name it tt something
tt keyboard pepe okay that's a
great
save it close it
and
you go to saudi keyboard then click on
do it yourself
and you can see this stack tile menu
form click on that
and you can see the glorious glorious
photos of the back to lacto menu from
keyboard
so we have many
such photos i've collected painstakingly
collected like since 10 years ago
back then there are not that many photos
on the website uh you know reddit
mechanical keyboard forum wasn't born
yet
so anyway so so i collected several so
this is here is a glorious paper colored
keyboard
and by the way let me show you this okay
do it yourself and you go down
and then
there's this funny uh
uh image okay go back up
back to man laptop manual form
and
you can see many glorious tactile manual
form
so that to a mana form let me explain
what is this keyboard okay go go back to
the do it yourself keyboards these are
do-it-yourself keyboards that means you
buy the kit
from
uh from one of these people there's
usually a link at the bottom
that that is a website that tells you
what uh
you know what um
what
things to buy to build the keyboard you
know pcb chips and and stuff
so that to manufacture
in the beginning the stack tool well in
the beginning there's uh
there is let me show you okay so in the
beginning there is
motron keyboard 1977.
you know motron keyboard there's a video
of it typing and there's a flat version
very expensive
uh i wouldn't recommend it because it's
500 small tron keyboard 1977.
then
there is
copied it from
there is kinesis advantage 2 which is
what i have this is fantastic 330
dollars
you go buy it if you buy it you can buy
it from go to the all the way to the
bottom there's my review
video review
photos lots of things
video typing uh and
all the way to the bottom you can buy it
from amazon or you go to the kinesis
advantage uh website and you give it
give them the discount coupon xah
let me show you okay
kinesis advantage two keyboard discount
coupon
x a h
okay you give them that then you get
some discount
now i'm not certain
uh if whether you buy it on amazon's
cheaper or on discord if you have common
questions type it okay immortality says
are you talking are you taking
suggestions from the show notes no
but however if you have a question you
want to ask me you personally want to
ask me the attitude is very important
because that so if you have a question
oh god i got this question i think son
knows the answer i want to ask sir or i
want to know son's opinion on this side
then post it
then the show is going to be spectacular
but if your attitude is oh um uh i want
to suggest
to talk about this topic you know
that doesn't that doesn't fly
there is
there's 10 000 topics uh
okay so back to keyboard okay uh so
uh great six people watching so back to
keyboard so we were talking about um
yeah the history of the
the history of the tactile manual from
keyboard so
in the beginning
there is motra 1977
then there is kinesis
1970 yeah 1992 okay somewhere 1992 some
some somewhere around there
which is my current favorite
then
then there is a do it yourself version
tactile tactile
uh 2015
okay tip 2014
by this guy
by this guy you see a different aspect
these different perspectives different
viewpoints of the doctor by this guy uh
his name is matt anders
i've met him in california keyboard
meetup
great guy he codes closure he's a
closure coder he's also a e-max user
uh you know so
and i tried it this is i love this okay
that tactile keyboard
um
you know it's very similar to kinesis
but i think it's it's uh even it's
smaller so it's better for my hand
so this kind this is the stack tile
then okay there's many different
versions people build fantastic and
beautiful tactile keyboard
okay then go back to do it yourself then
there is stack tower manual form okay
wait i skipped one there is a menu from
keyboard but i don't have a photo of it
uh yeah well i have it i have a photo
somewhere but it's it's not easy to find
but
it's there's a keyboard called manual
form okay
it the thumb keys the thumb keys of the
manual form looks like that however the
the rest of the keyboard is not like
that
but then someone combined the ideas of
tactile and manual form then they
created tactile manual form so this is
2016.
and now they sell so let me show you
several different versions so this
version one two three four five five
euros six
six rows
so dion our friend
on discord they he bought he bought one
uh from
you know so it looks like that one two
let's see one two three four five six
one two three four five six six
rows uh okay so anyway so he bought it
and this is his
his battle station you know he's his
power station at home
and there's a red light red light is
fantastic okay i haven't turned it on
but you know you want to go buy a red
bulb
at night you turn it on just the red
bulb that's uh that soothes your soul
that makes you
sleep better and everything red light
okay because i did
you know
i spent several days reading about red
light
uh you know it so it's actually good
buy a red bulb
so and dion bought this but however so
and he bought it from this guy
oh keycaps
however there's a flaw there's a warning
okay
when if you buy it from them you know in
the dion case he got delayed you know
delayed because korea then so on you
know several months delay and he's in
you uh you know
he's in united kingdom okay that's
public information so he he bought it
for them there's delays and delays then
eventually he got it then the soldiering
job is pretty bad you know several keys
start started to not work you know and
so on so he had to uh manually do it
yourself fix it
and very and fairly expensive you know
like you might be thinking whether you
should buy the do it yourself or just
simply buy uh
you know pre-pre-build let's go let's go
to um
you know you can you can buy
the
you know
i would recommend just by kinesis okay
preview that means the quality is
assured every one of them is about is
the same okay and also i recommend
linear red switches but for you
maybe
you know i i personally recommend if you
have already have hand pin then you want
linear light switches
okay so anyway
dion bought this and it works out great
except you know it's got some problems
but if he fixed it it he fixed it and
now it's working out great
and let me recommend stuff like keys
okay so dion is also a e-max user so you
go to
softlightkeys which is the keybinding
system for emacs
you are looking at stuff like keys and
the in the pink window is all the
keystrokes i press in emacs and the
corresponding command name so let me
turn on the highlight line mod so you
can see so you see
every every key stroke i type
it shows up
uh
such as move moving choose the left
right and also the corresponding command
because in e-max
doesn't matter what you do what keypad
you press eventually it's going to
correspond to a command
even when you move a cursor for example
if i press the right arrow key
right arrow
you see it's actually calling in the
command right char
you know that's emacs everything is just
oh it's just a command so even so it's
all uh it's about keys and command emacs
so you are looking at the source code of
software keys and you can go to the top
of that file open that link showing
browser this is the home page of emacs
stuff like keys okay
it's on github it's free downloaded free
as in libra in freedom and also
doesn't cost you money
fantastic okay so here's the key binding
anyway i talked about this many times so
stuff like keys so copy and let's let's
let's have a record of what we did today
so we talked about
we talked about
a history of
manual
form so there is
kinesis there is a lot jesus
uh
let's go back to keyboard show in
browser let's go up logo keyboards let's
open cleanses let's open
okay copy that back here
okay workflow okay so you are looking so
i'm gonna just show you this that's
kinesis
open or go keyboards
open
motron
linkify
showing browser
links fantastic
and
then history of dr manuform that's right
so put it here
showing browser that's today's topics
and the
manual from keyboard do it yourself
tactile and doctor manufacture okay
tactile
paste it here
back doctor menu form
pc here linkify
join the links
showing browser
fantastic okay now
so
dion gave me a photo so but there's a
new photo it's a better version so let's
we already saved it okay let's do it
again
save it
uh you know
tt
it's already exist do you want to
replace it no okay cancel okay now close
that now i want to
so this is my block i want to
replace this photo with a new one so how
do i do it so first of all go to the
blog so you
press enter to open that link
and you see here it says six rows
version that corresponds to this header
now i move the cursor here now normally
so we just save the image so normally
you want to go to the directory download
directory or whatever
then
they move you know unix command or
something you know move some
move download then tt i guess yeah move
that directory to move that image to
whatever the current directory i don't
know what is the current directory so
copy file path of the current buffer
paste it here so current directory is
exactly keyboard you know
too much problem so let me just show you
a single command that will just
put the keyboard photo on this block
okay so let's do it
okay which move image to which directory
so current directory plus you know i i
means images actually uh io go okay
yeah
i2 okay that's a that direct that that's
the directory i wanted the photo to go
to okay enter
yeah and what's a keyboard name okay so
key what's the name uh you want the file
to be so i want the file to be
done command from
pepe
dia okay
enter
there it is
wait i i i made a mistake let's do it
again
yeah i screwed up because i moved my
cruiser but
but um
uh what did i do
okay here
yeah okay so
so here
is the
you know this is a new file it just we
just added okay so
showing browser scroll down
you can see there it is
now the file name the image so open
click uh
return to open the image go to the diet
you can see there is a low line in front
of it we don't want it so we want to
rename so close this close this
by the way the command to move image is
here so
where is it
these commands fly by fast
yeah
i want to so
comments questions
immortality
people people get annoyed by
what i say so i mean
yeah okay so let me just keep doing this
okay so let's do it again okay
go to discord
open the file
save it
tt
okay save it
why is it already exist i thought i
deleted it okay so this already exists
do i want to replace it
no okay cancel
close that
so open this
press the key to delete the image
is no longer exist
delete
go to the browser refresh it's gone
move the cursor here then call this
command this command is
html move image file okay
then save choose a directory to save it
to
so kb pepe okay let's just say that okay
so
open it it's there go to the browser
refresh there fantastic now rename the
now i want to rename the image okay
so
call this command
which is
html rename source file path
okay
then rename it by
doctor manual form
uh
and then say paper dm okay
so when you call the image command it
automatically adds a
random string
so enter so we have renamed it
so
copy the file path paste it here make a
make a new one why do i make a new one
because you can see
the old
you know the the old attribute
over here is still the old attribute so
anyway delete that
okay the new image is now smaller okay
refresh
magnify refresh
okay now i have to choose which image to
use because
okay the new image is actually much
inferior you know there's lots of jpeg
after effect
the image itself is better i mean the
the image content the photograph is a
better photograph because you can see
more
different
you know keycaps
and you can also see
the
wrist pad
but however the image quality is
inferior so i i i think this one is
better you know i don't want repeated
images
because it takes a lot of time to
download and okay so maybe dion will
give us a new photo
so
okay so fine eventually i decided i
don't want this i don't want this new
image so delete it
refresh
so that's about the keyboard okay
is your command history searchable
uh no
so what do you mean command history
searchable so you know
like what do you want to do
answer okay answer the question what do
you want to do exactly what do you mean
searchable because this pink window
that's
that's the command called let me show
you
okay uh
that command is called exhaust start
command lock so you go to the source
code here is a source code
source.commandlog and it's
it's basically just calling the command
log mod turn turn it on and several
commands to turn on the
turn
turn on the logging
so what do you mean by it's searchable
it's not saved to disk
if i quit emacs
all those uh you know commands will be
good but however if you want to save it
you can just copy the entire buffer
right now and and open a new buffer
paste it there you have it that's you
know that's the past 30 minutes or the
command course
and if you really
that's why that's why i'm asking you
what's your goal if you really want the
command log
you know
like i talked about there is a
okay let me show you okay
sorry emacs
okay
sorry emacs blog
so here is my emacs website
excuse me
for a second
so back to the emacs blog
so uh emacs so you want click
okay so so yeah let me
finish this okay so you go to emacs keys
turn on javascript so i talked about you
know i've done
by now two years of
videos youtube
uh
and then you go to um
so this section emacs pinky how to avoid
emacs pink soft light keys why emax keys
are painful the default keys emacs
commands frequency statistics that's the
one you want
so you open that so i did a study
research on
all the frequencies of
you know
your order or emax commands by the
frequency they are called of different
people so here's a result this is
actually pretty old 2007 okay so this is
why i'm so you know i'm obsessive about
keyboard about efficiency i did i
studied this for like by now
30 years because i talked about this
before in 1990
uh
i
am i was on the mac mac os and i
used
rest edit to create the vora keyboard so
i started to use vera keyboard so so i
study i read the books on
keyboard you know before there's the
internet
so anyway so so this is 2007 study of
emax command frequency this is when i
created the ergo e-max mod you can still
download it okay logo emac smart so
let's see search for
you know actually i have a link so 2013
ergo emac smart's home page is moved to
github and now led by
matthew
fiddler basically
he is now the leader the maintainer of
the
of the package so i switched i
eventually started stuff like keys
instead
so you are looking at ergo emacs mod
still fairly popular okay so
so i you know so
so when i was doing ergo emacs i did the
study of the frequency the statistics of
the emacs command okay so that's about
that so but
okay hold on a second let me copy the
links
close that don't save
cancel
split
go to talk show uh today's talk show let
me copy what we talked about
uh start command log mod okay
so we talked about start command log mod
then uh i'll go emacs key binding then
the
other emacs website okay
and uh i'll go emacs keybinding go to
go
back yeah keyboard
uh frequency statistics okay so i want
to link it
link
combine
combine show in browser wait hold on a
second make that a code
so
that's what we have talked about a
record of it so now so on the emax
command frequency statistics how do you
get the
statistics this uh you know this can
last for a year so just like the command
log mod
it so the package you want
the package you want
is this one okay so go download it
actually there's updated version by
david coppello so go there so that uh a
new version on this okay
here okay
copy so
so this code
is what i used for these statistics
and it will lock your statistics similar
to this okay except it also count how
many times each command is called
but then
you go to this link
you know
last week i removed most links for my
website so these days you have to do it
manually because these corporations
including github including github
microsoft
new york times cnn
fox news basically all mainstream medias
you know they they are all like
half of it is fake news and uh
crap they are just doing devious things
so actually
so
if you want to log your command
commands in using emacs and their
frequency you
use this one okay
use this one i recommend this one i have
it on for years uh but
but since
since like a year ago i stopped i i
didn't
bother
because i've been logging it for over 15
years already so i didn't use it now
so this is the one you want okay so make
a copy of it paste it here
linkify
so that's a digression about emacs log
so actually today we have a lot to do so
i want to finish so i'm gonna
so is this just me talking hey dan
crispin so guys
post your questions and comments okay so
in immortality you know uh you know if
you have questions to ask me just ask
ask it you know not not suggestions you
know i'm telling you things as is
uh okay so
so
we talked about uh dactyl manual form we
talked about the history we uh
demonstrated some emacs workflow about
copying images which uh
went in van because eventually i didn't
want to
use the new photo so anyway so i have a
lot to talk about that i plan to do
today so let's open let's start to do
them so again this is my exactly working
session i'm working on my website you
know for the past
20 years basically i just wake up and
work on my website
good morning uh
the lima okay
so now what's the next thing to do
so i want to do
so this one i want to add okay
uh let's
so um i'll go emax mod so let's see uh
talk show having us
shipped it's okay copy so go back to
talk show today's talk show
show the pink window and uh
let me let me show you what this one is
about okay so
close that close that
show in browser so
so emacs there is a feature of shift
select that is you can hold down shift
key
then you press the arrow key it will
make a selection okay
it doesn't work right now because i
turned it off okay
and what i want to tell you as a tip is
that don't turn it off that is a very
bad
that's a very inefficient way to make
selection
you know seems easy it seems convenient
a lot of people wanted why because habit
you got used to it
but the more efficient way is to press a
key
to start selection then
then do uh you know single hand single
finger move cursor
to make a selection you know
press the key again if you want to e you
know if you want to start over so you
know so so turn off the shift select
feature
okay now what i want to do is i need i
want to add that turn that off in soft
light keys
because i don't believe it's uh in stuff
like keys so i need to
change modify the soft light keys
source code package you know so i'm
showing you my workflow so i hope you
get you know you get random tips when i
do my session and talk about it for
example i'm telling you
that the methodology of shifting of
selecting a text one of the way shift
select that's a very bad one inefficient
what you you want to turn it off so if
possible you want to turn it off in vs
coding anywhere like never use it
instead you want to create if if
possible create a way
to have a key to start the selection
okay
because shift select so why why is that
so this is a keyboarding tip why is that
so the shift select because that's a
holding down a key that's a modifier
that's uh that adds adds stress to your
hand okay
adds stress to your hand
so
so you so so you might say oh but i
don't believe i don't i don't think so i
you know i disagree
so what's your reason what let me you
know you can test these efficiency
statements by scientifically for example
you know a lot a lot of people they
don't know things you know i i talked to
many people back you know by now
the millennial generation and even a
hacker you know they don't know
things so
how do you test
something you know if you have two
methodology two key strokes to do
exactly the same command how do you
how do you test
uh which one is more efficient very easy
you can count keystrokes or
you know
like statistics of emacs like you know
like that's one example you know that's
one of the scientific scientific way to
test which command is more frequently
used not by asking the emacs phonetics
like if you ask emacs phonetics oh
please vote which command you use most
often so that we can you know arrange
the keys
they they will give you
uh
fake news they give you they they will
each one will have opinions so i used t
emacs for 10 years i said you need to
you know
put the caps lock on the shift on the
on the control on the capstock position
idiots these you know this
so back to the top to the focus so how
do you compare to
keystrokes or methodology of doing
something how do you
test which one is more efficient so one
way in this case you can
you can first first of all by logic you
know that's
shift select involves holding down a key
holding down a key and then use your
other hand
to move the cursor now typically in vs
code for example let's uh for example
let's open the current buffer in vs code
so i call the command vs code so you can
see there's a command x open vs code
do it
that will open the current emacs buffer
in vs code so there it is visual uh
source code so let's say if i want to
select this line okay so let me let's do
the shift
method so
shift
arrow down there it is okay now if you
want to move around let's see i want to
move all the way to the top so
um
let's say if i want to move by word so
you do shift
control
and right arrow okay
so you can see can you see that shift
ctrl right arrow can you see my
okay it's hard to see there but
uh it's hard to see my screen in my
camera so shift
control right arrow then left arrow
let's let's let's strain on your fingers
that's a painful
so
so on the other hand if you can
press a key i don't know if this works
this is the emax way control y to start
selection yeah it doesn't work in vs
code but there are people who have
created key bindings so it works so for
example so so what you want to do
instead you know
press the keys
to start selection then you can move by
block of text you can use these by
paragraphs text block
or
if i hold it down it moves side by block
okay yo you can page down okay this this
page is not long enough long enough
let's open a long
giant
you know long long page okay back to
emacs so go to the top let's say start
from here
start the selection now you can put
press arrow up down or left right or in
the case of exact keys i don't have to
press the arrow i can press just
uh one single key you know
move move right by word
move left by row by word
move down by line move up by line or
move down by paragraph all these sci-fi
keys which show the ping window let's do
it again
so start here start the mark okay so you
can see the command is
uh set mark command okay so now i can
move i can move by paragraph and select
or i can press the arrow down
i mean not arrow down page down you see
now i scroll up you can you can see it's
all selected
so that's sufficient instead of the
instead of the
shift idiots of the linux idiots
you know like when you talk to these
linux people like
uh tiny windows managers right many of
you uh
started to watch my video because of the
article telling windows managers it's
linux 4chan idiots
you know you you watch them okay they
rising or whatever they think they are
they have they have the efficient way
but then
they are the people they do this yeah
you know they do this they they they
shift select they
[Laughter]
in r clinics in whatever
i3 i you know telling window manager or
haskell ex monad or whatever
they do this yeah they they they're
gonna shift control idiots this
is why
no depth okay so so okay so so i'm
telling you
so i i hope i demonstrated or persuaded
you that the shift select is actually
just a bad method inefficient way to
make selection okay so this mo generally
speaking this is about user interface
design or in modern fad that by the
online
css design guru idiots they would say ux
user experience ux ui and ux something
blah blah blah blah the idiots
this jargon tarting this
guru web guru design idiots
after 20 years of the software industry
you know windows smack or unix linux
the user interface became worse
you know have you got you know hamburger
menu hamburger menu
you know
after 30 years
all these gurus use the interface
interface design gurus with phd from
what harvard or google whatever it
became worse
the interface you know the twitter for
example start a post now i have i have a
30 inch screen you know 25 or 30 inch
screen something
then i start the post then then i'm
shrinked you you cannot enlarge this
window it force you into a two inch peep
show
you know and this is very common um
on twitter on stack overflow
um you know uh maybe not cycle you know
very common
you know this you cannot read and if you
go to private messages
there's a lot of posts you can only see
a tiny portion of it then you have to
scroll what the is this
idiots but the the irony is that
the irony
that pains me is that this tech geekers
these emacs users emacs phonetics veeam
phonetics this unix philosophy you know
unix people linux people titling window
managers they
they never mention this kind of thing
they they don't know they don't you know
they don't know
uh
you know so that's another
article digression you know like
about that okay so let's go back so what
i was i doing so yeah i was talking i
was talking about shift select is a bad
thing okay
so showing browser
shift select okay now
search for now what i want to do i want
to modify soft light keys so that i can
put these
shifts like neo to part of sci-fi keys
you know violate user choice
you know before because normally it's a
good practice that
customizations such as these you should
not put it into your package
i mean that's normal
normally because
you should allow you know for emacs you
should especially emacs
let people you know people each
different person have different
customizations so
so your package should do just one thing
what is supposed to do while
if user has these customizations it
should respect them you know your
package should not just
go over it and wipe them out
but in this case actually it makes sense
because stuff like keys the purpose is
to change your uh
key binding so
it's reasonable okay so let's go to
software keys page
press describe key then press the key
one of the key took soft like key
command then you can see the link jump
to it so here's the source code
now
uh list matching lines so i want to this
matching nice select uh see if there's a
line matching it no let's just say
uh
okay
search for shift select so it's not
there so let's add it okay so some flag
keys miner mod let's add it here
somewhere so
so first of all let's go to
open another window
now i'm going to go to xr
my personal init file directory so how
do i do that use a bookmark type abb
that will jump to my emacs
personal upgrade file
okay here open it then press the key
uh that will
dial jump that will go to the directory
of my personal emacs you need files okay
so we are here now
press the key
that will call the command satin text in
all the files in this directory so let's
let's open the brief so do it again
so search for
shift
select okay
and in this directory our files do it
no
oh okay i know where so go to site
emacs okay so emacs packages so this is
ximax
distro now if you want this distro you
pay me okay
so this is all my packages delete those
backup files and go up one directory
then there's a settings file open it
this matching lines shift enter there it
is so
inks are emax package
emax distro so just like space max and
doom emacs so i have my distro but now
it's not
open you pay me to get it to get all my
packages together as one
so now
and
so now so in the settings file so close
that so in the settings file
this matching lines
shift enter there it occurs so open it
so there it is disable shift select
that's what i want okay copy it
okay back to stuff like keys now
let's just put it here okay disable it
so
you know remove comments so when you
load software you you know when you uh
activate soft like keys there will be
this side effect it will turn off shift
select
so ideally that's not a ideal solution
because
you should have it restore user settings
for instance okay let's see
okay so again i guess the proper way is
just put it inside so if sci-fi keys is
on
then turn this bunch of things on okay
yeah actually that doesn't work neither
you know so i was thinking when soft
like keys on
then turn it on otherwise
okay this code is not so
okay i need to fix this code this code
is contributed um
by wheel we or something he wrote
he uh he did a major upgrade of sapphire
keys engine but
uh
so this is my not my coding style so
actually what i want to do is you see
whenever you have a if statement
it should have
ideally you should have only two
arguments so here's the first argument
and the rest
should be wrapped in a prong block such
as
that okay
so ideally so that's that's more close
to my working
my uh style okay pretty fire code yeah
like that is better so now
so you see
so
this is what should be happening so you
see
so if some fly keys is on
wait why is that what is that variable
tv selection mod okay
shift select mod
all right
search for it
remove that shift select mod if soft
like is what is that variable
uh
sci-fi keys is available its value is t
so oh that's a
right that's a minor mod when you define
a minor mod it automatically creates a
corresponding variable
and the value of variable is t if the
minor mod is on otherwise it's new
so
the code here is checking if that
variable is true so if it's true
then
then do this
otherwise
okay that's just a
minor mod okay so when you turn it on
yeah okay let's just do this here shift
select yeah
turn off shift select and uh
and also turn on tv selection mod that
means when when when you have a
selection and you start to type
something it will override it okay this
is more traditional
to
any other editor vs code or whatnot
uh so there's a question why don't you
like hamburger menus lots of problems
okay but for that question you can
easily search for hamburger menu just
search for hamburger menu you'll see a
lot of criticisms
i know because i read them all because i
actively i read a lot you know so i just
read every day you know read this
research user interface uh issues so for
example let's see
let's see if you go to saudi info my
home
site
then you go down
you can see these
big buttons css sucks
so here's a collection of articles about
all kinds of design problems windows ui
design issues
muscle memory ui ui design criteria and
pip show window so this is what we
talked about pip show window you know
there's twitter there's microsoft
windows the idiocy no microsoft
window let me show you this one
live demo okay
okay another what the
microsoft windows very confusing idiocy
okay there it is
you know this
this tiny unreadable this you know i'm
getting old the font is too small for me
to see you know i cannot read it
uh and
and you see
and let me show you okay and i you know
you go to ease of access i have the font
magnified to
110 doesn't work you know let's say
make the font
200 okay apply
no i hope that doesn't crash my system
that's windows
ah
i don't think i ever tried to make the
font size 200
i think it's crashing the system
ah jesus oh okay so you see now i
changed my font to 200
but this window
this tiny i still cannot read and
and look at this each one of these you
have to scroll
this claustrophobic
you know picture window and that's still
the you cannot you know you cannot
there's no
maximize the window you cannot enlarge
this window and there are like tens of
these
these windows on in windows in microsoft
windows this
and the the people don't know and people
you know they they are you know pushing
for windows 11. oh you know the
next generation of user interface in
windows 11 blah blah blah this or that
but did they fix this fundamental issue
no
it's everywhere
the windows and linux idiots
because every time you know why why is
this windows idiot because
for example you guys linux people okay
so let me cancel this okay cancel let me
revert the font to
i hope the system doesn't crash
uh let's see
so it's okay to apply okay
so can you so you might still
good
uh so
what
okay system i'm just gonna apply
so why so
if all you people including linux people
you know
now is my audio still going when it's
doing the weight
you know if people
see these user interface problems in
windows they will complain because a lot
of people complain that window nobody
you know likes windows the windows will
fall apart
and window when when windows people the
windows designer when they see people
complain they will
uh
unless you're going oh dear that was
brave why don't you like hamburger menus
so am i still let's see
uh let's check
okay i think i'm still going
you know the the thing is all these
problems most people don't you know they
don't know they don't care including
especially the
ninox the elite hacker types they say
about this or that but they never
themselves care or
think or find anything wrong about this
that's why these things persist
you know linux they they went their own
way about hiding windows whatever and
it's also usually crap too
you know so
all these problems you know and
yeah so so that's about windows okay
okay let's see
still good audio still good
good
okay so good
so that so
we have demonstrated the windows
the windows make text bigger make make
your ass bigger the windows
and these windows you know now the
windows 10 the
metro you know they have they have all
these shiny joggers metro their ass
you cannot tell which window is part of
which because it's all squares no no
shadow and no border you know you cannot
tell which window began or which window
is the sub sub you know ui part of what
windows
and
okay
you know
every time i talk about windows ui
problem i need to talk the linux
because
when the linux when they hear
i talk about windows
you know how it sucks they they will
feel very happy
yeah that's right because i saw right
microsoft sucks but linux is
worse
far worse what was in a
in the most significant way because
windows
windows they are a commercial entity you
know you go there every month you work
for microsoft you go there you just take
money you know paycheck you do whatever
you don't really care that's that's the
nature of commercial entity microsoft
you know it's a giant corporation okay
they they github you know github
linkedin that's all microsoft okay
but linux this open source
phoneticism the open source you know
vision the utopia
so
you you know you are not working for
money right
and but then you look at the what the ui
design of linux it's full of crap the
worst idiot possible so that's
that that so that's
so that um
gets me angry you see microsoft ui
sucks
there's a good reason for it because
they are a commercial entity okay nobody
cares except when the beginning in the
beginning five or ten years it's
microsoft products are very good that's
why they became successful the price
quality ratio is excellent microsoft
word they revolutionized the industry
microsoft word one of them and this also
worked perfect but microsoft windows is
pretty good
price remember
quality of the product features
divided by the price that ratio that
that is a good measurement of
the the product okay so microsoft
they suck today there's a good reason
for it because they are commercial
entity nobody cares you come and go you
know you go work for microsoft you know
as a programmer you take a lot of money
every month next year you let you leave
you know you you did you don't care
nobody cares okay that's microsoft the
linux
are created by people this
typically elite you know holier than
thou type of people they tell you what
to do they tell you what is good what is
bad the code formatting the you know the
the what how you should code your python
or whatever
this type of people they they
then look at what they created the unix
the the linux you know the titling
windows manager the whatever you know
the the the
the file manager you know it sucks
donkey ass these these idiots so that
that
infuriates me okay
so you you know you guys lean linux
users you are gloating oh yeah cause
it's all right he's you know flaming
yeah microsoft no you suck you
idiots
and and look at this okay peep show
window it's on stack overflow okay
stack overflow you know let's let's go
to it okay
can can you actually let's let's instead
of search wasting time
yeah and let's not do it
but you can see you you probably have
seen it if you are a programmer you go
to stack flow then you that you have
this horizontal scroll bar the
idiot
the better design you know you want to
know what's a better design
let me tell you what's a better design
okay javascript
you can see this is my javascript in
depth okay now you go to dom there's a
complete tutorial on dom and you don't
need you don't need no libraries
or framework no framework no library and
your code is more efficient
simpler more succinct
than whatever
you know uh react view or whatever okay
such javascript in depth you know you
paint you you know support me and buy
the tutorial okay so you go there's a
dome section let me show you some code
let's let's not get too far away so
let's um
let's go to one of the you know the
you know so here's the code so what does
this call this code does pipe functions
like the unix you know like the batch
shell pipe functions
without requiring them to be your object
okay so you can see
this line of code so let's magnify okay
so with if your window is small
if you are on a cell phone or whatever
you know they you know they shrink you
don't there is you don't have to do the
horizontal scroll okay that's a
better design that's css
okay css
these design gurus responsive design
these idiots this is css okay
if you don't know what is css you click
on that click on that click on that
complete tutorial on css okay
simple
you know
no framework no css you know what what's
this what says you know 1000 frameworks
of css you know they say all the
idiots
and i can i can also tell you why it is
that way okay it's mostly just because
money
and you know in in the linux case it's
um
anyway that we are getting all over the
place
so apple so yeah good point about apple
apple have always been the best design
okay
they are also commercial that's true
they are blood hungry they are blood
thirsty very much so
just like microsoft if not worse but
however apple because of the steve jobs
steve jobs the great innovator the great
entrepreneur you know he
he may be an he may be batting
several other things but he's a great
he's one he's a great one of the
greatest salesman and entrepreneur
he has a vision a truly good vision on
design what is truly best design he
knows steve jobs okay so steve jobs
so apple has always been the best design
okay everything just works consistent
it takes pain painstaking work to do you
know just like my website every every
element every detail every character
is by design okay there's none of it you
know but then the millennial generation
comes in you know the millennial
generation they see my website oops your
website is
it's not modern
they don't know
so
so you know they want me to add you know
1500 megabytes of frameworks
anyway
idiocy so so the point here is that
truly good things are not being
appreciated because people don't know
what is a good design people like
the the quality of general populations
education right generally when we talk
about
the the quality of a country you know
the
the literacy level of the population is
very important in you know
in the knowledge level
knowledge of the population of a country
in the same way for programming in the
programming industry the knowledge of
the people in the industry for example
programmers design designers whatever
whatever
is very important
so you need to have a basic
understanding of what is good design can
you actually define you know ask
yourself
can you you know maybe you have 10 years
experience in programming
you know you have used lots of uh you
software maybe or maybe you are a
student but as you you know ask yourself
can you define what is a good design
give you know give me five examples or
three give me two examples of good
really good truly quality design of a
software that you have used
give me two other examples
that's really bad design of user
interface or ux you know user experience
yeah you know try it
so and
and
and enumerate exactly why
one is better why is worse can you do
that can you do that you know my
audience you guys can you do that have
you ever thought about that so i'm
asking you to give me two examples of
software
user interface that you think that's
great and give me two examples you think
that's bad
and
write an essay you know like you you
have to have the skill of writing your
essay think you know you all these are
part of it
right i say you know tell tell tell
people exactly why you think you know
what's the reason
that
you know these two
software is great in ui
what's the reason the other two is bad
can you do that
so
so so this so i'm telling you to you
know this is maybe as an exercise maybe
you like it
and this so this this is the quality you
know the quality of people in software
industry determines the overall quality
so when you see microsoft sucks
don't just play microsoft you are part
of it you and me we are part of it
microsoft is this way because key people
don't care they don't know they they
keep buying you know they keep paying
you know and if you are linux phonetics
you you there's more to say because that
you then you're gonna say oh yeah you
know
you don't think you know you you are
part of a problem you are a major part
of the why microsoft sucks
let me tell you why okay because if
linux is truly better and it's also free
all the people wants free because
if open source
or free software foundation software is
not free they're gonna die with it
cannot disappear within a year okay
they're gonna completely disappear if
it's not free just like
because these packages when you have to
pay nobody nobody use it
living in a lie linux
so if you
you know i'm rambling over let's get
back so i i need to actually a lot of
things i want to do here so
close that
so
go to talk show let's paste the link
so today we already talked for
over an hour already i think
so close that because that
user interface design
because that
there are other things i wanted to do
but because but we've been rambling all
over so this is um
it's a keyboard blog that's manual form
that's a doctor manufacture doctor
keyboard kinesis vantage uh this
software keys copy the link
it's already there
showing browser so today's talk show
topics
uh user interface design doom yeah so
but i want to do other things so anyway
here back to software keys
i did add so shift select is added okay
so
go to the top change the date here
okay
save it and
go to
ishow
git add stuff like keys change
and git commit
and say
uh
supply keys okay
software keys
mod shift select
neo
now okay
enter it okay so commit it okay close
that close that
close that one thing done show in
browser
so casa like keys so that
item is done
so now if we go to
notes let's see some toxic topic notes
this
actually i i wanted to
do quite a few things today but
we went all over
so
uh so emac this association list we can
do that
so what um
are not free users have to pay for
internet services
yeah that's you are talking about micro
payments you know the whole
infrastructure
um anyway
they never you know like micro payment
you know they've been
people been talking about that
which is
supposedly great but they failed for 20
years you know every
there's not many people even talking
about that
much anymore but
it used to be in the 2010s every few
years this people tried to push that
this never worked
it never worked partly because
because these empires google they are
controlling it they don't want it they
don't want it basically google
google facebook or whatever you know
they are controlling the thing they
don't want it to happen
that's
one of the things because if if
if they really want it to happen it will
happen micro payment system
uh the other reason is that most people
they want free they don't want to pay
the vast majority of people that that's
just building intuition in intuition
usually you know when
when something is you
if you have to pay for something
even
if it will benefit you overall
people will not choose to do it they
rather prefer whatever is free
you know just like
linux versus
proprietary systems you know for example
you know
anyway
so if you use linux or whatever free
usually you spend a lot of time every
day
to
you know try to get something to work
um
okay so let's see what i what's the next
thing i want to do let's just keep doing
okay any more comments
so i'm going over how many people are
watching
five
uh
there's a lot i want to do but i think
that's it that's it for today
yeah i kind of
feels like i wasted
my working session today because
i wanted to work on my website
so let's see exhaust talk show what have
we been talking
history of tactile okay so
okay let's let me just work on
um
okay let's open back up open notes
okay what is this emacs settings
so did we
get status okay there's no change here
so what's the next thing okay and it's
and it's i want to do
things on my website let's do next thing
so that's wufam language uh
partial
emacs workflow we do site map okay
okay this command i need to modify
site html keyboard shortcut markup
and this one
how to delete
association list by key
so i need to write a tutorial on my emac
lisp tutorial on association list i need
to add an item about how to
delete
a key
element by key okay so i need to write
that then
okay so that's emac list coding here
then
write a e mark this command to update
side panel of current html okay that's
another emac this task
that's gonna take half an hour or more
so this is also gonna take half an hour
or more
on the association list
then
emac this writer command highlight
unicode okay that's gonna take 10
minutes
okay i think that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
if you like my stuff buy my stuff okay
pay me paypal patreon
amazon gift card okay that's it bye
visual studio code close
you know funny you can see
processes
visual studio code
memory
you know with a bunch of processes we
only have one single file open and it's
closed now
so
megabytes of
ram used
meanwhile emacs
it's only 60 okay so emax is here so you
can see 52 megabytes i've been using
emacs all this while
visual studio code
okay close that
should shut shut shut okay so this key
will show that that's
that's old f4 another windows idiocy
uh okay twitter
twitter
i'll go so this is a command frequency
statistics
close it
ergo emax mod because it
key frequency this is great if you want
to lock your emax command it will count
them you know by you know tell you how
many which command you call the most
often because it
okay bye