welcome to another
episode of sun talk show today is 2021
today is june 20th
and it's 3 o'clock in the afternoon san
francisco time
so what i'm going to do today what are
we going to do we are going to i'm going
to
do a workflow of emax so
let me explain what i'm going to do okay
so you go to so
let's show in browser xr tv
the fantastic start tv show and go to
the
sections section okay and go to
talk show today today's page and so we
are going to do let me show you okay so
live stream indeed open the notes
to do notes topic notes
okay so i have this command html select
current
element so this is what are we going we
are
i'm going to do so i'm going i have so
the first
15 minutes is going to be emax
workflow then we are going to talk about
random and possibly politics politics
[Laughter]
politics okay very sensitive topics
be prepared that this video will be
zapped by google okay
so if you have any questions comments
just post it here okay you say
i talk i i see what you say and i talk
okay so but the first first 15 minutes
or so we are going to do a emacs
workflow
you know this is a mixture of technology
and
and random so the emacs thing so i have
a new function
and i'm going to show you what this
command do
i'm going to explain then i'm going to
uh
do a workflow on on adding this function
to my emacs blog
okay and i'm going to i'm not going to
explain much after i explain what this
function does
then i'm going to just do the workflow
quickly because
because every time you know because the
workflow you can watch my
uh the video before today
which i explained you know so when i try
to explain what i'm doing
it takes 20 minutes without trying to
explain it'll take
uh five minutes so for a change i'm not
going to do explanation today but first
of all let me show you let me do
explain what this function does okay
so let's uh cut it close it uh back to
emacs talk show paste it here so showing
browser so you can see there is a
command
so this is a new command because i html
select current element okay
so you can see here's the command name
so what does it does
what does it do so inside html mod i can
press a key
it will select the current element the
cursor is in so
suppose my cursor is here uh anyway here
so i
press the button it select the current
element okay
now suppose that cursor is here press a
key
select element okay now suppose like my
cursor is here
press the key okay it's select that
element it select the element before
uh so if i'm at the top over here
so if i press a key it select that but
if my cursor is here
press that it select the whole entire
body um
element okay so that's that's a command
now
that this command can
can uh have some extension i need to do
more work on that
so that so that it will
increasingly select the outer elements
for example
if i select i select you see it select
the frame
but i want to press the key
one more time and it should select the
next
outer element which should be the
forward figure tag
and i press the key again it should
select the whole body
so anyway i need to code that still but
anyway
but let me show you the command the
source code okay
so that's the command let's uh describe
function
and jump to the source code so open it
so here you are seeing the source code
uh it's about let's narrow to region
okay
so it's 40 lines of emax lisp
i coded this yesterday
okay so now what is the so that
completes my explanation of this command
okay
you can find it inside html mod which is
in on github
comments no comments dion
good morning dia your background looks
so much more human than in the early
streams my background okay
yeah well life has been better
you know life has been better for me
uh you know okay so let's
let's finish the emacs thing okay so so
i just wrote this yesterday so what's
the next thing i'm going to do
so let's go to e-max my
emacs blog so what i'm going to do first
of all i'm going to explain what i'm
going to do then i'm just going to do
quickly okay so in my imax blog i need
to create a new page
for example you go to
this is lottery
tutorial so you have lots of uh emacs
tutorials
then under here there's a section on
html
everything you need to know about
working inside html so
so in html then there's like 20 or so
commands
that specialize in working with html so
what i need to do now
is to add since i created a new command
yesterday so i need to add a new page
somewhere insert it somewhere over here
or create a new html page
then for example one of the page let's
say uh for example
insert html tag let's let's pick another
example okay so let's see
let's say uh example we just did
two days ago i think this one so you
know typically a page you'll have
explanation what this command does then
the source code
so people can search it and find it and
use it you know
put their in their init file and they
can use it
or they can just download you know
install the site
html mod so i need to create a new page
you know some explanation source code
then
then add a navigation link into this
collection
about all about html
and also add a new entry to my emacs
blog
you know saying that oh here's something
new so people subs
can subscribe it to you know so people
can see
okay let's start to do that so now i'm
going to shut up
and just typing okay typing for three
minutes
let's see how fast we can do this okay
so what is the command anyway so what is
the command
okay let's let me start to do it so go
to talk show
okay so if you have comment and comments
and questions
post it okay but are you still alive
it's late for what so uh uh
her body is still alive so
so so we have people from germany and
united kingdom fantastic this
is the globalization of satok show
okay so okay so so this is a command
so go to emacs so i'm gonna so i'm gonna
start coding now so in a pink window
is all my emacs command codes and
function names okay
create that okay so here's the function
name um
so first of all what's the name uh will
be the new file name okay uh
html select element uh okay
okay that's a bit long uh
emacs so okay that's
that okay that
then that that that that
that that that
that
select html element okay
that that that that
that and so this is uh okay so i'm in a
competition
i mean a competition to see how fast i'm
i can do this
copy that actually uh copy that
okay describe function go to the source
code and modify the source code to add
the url
so url so people when
they do describe function they can see
the url
okay so the first version then we
modified it at a today state
then copy the source code then go to the
website
then here add a emac list
template paste it here show in browser
we are almost done
now make it pretty fantastic
now let's add some explanation what this
does
here's a comma here is a
command that uh select
current ht typo
current html element
under cursor okay
okay showing browser almost done now we
need the navigation panel
okay close that close that uh where do
we get the navigation panel we get it
from
here okay split go back to the blog
blog emacs exhaust
emacs blog search for panel so here is
navigation panel you don't know what i'm
doing because
this is my website i've been working it
on it for 20
plus years so i'm like
can work on this blind almost
so i'm just chatting so there it is we
added the navigation panel bar
on the left and we also added the
topic the html specific
navigation box under each page now we
need to add a
link to this particular page so so we
are going to do
a find and replace on all files under
this directory i'm talking too much
okay so yeah find okay so so copy the
file path
paste it here make it a h
a list then delete that part then modify
this should say
uh select current html element that's
what we want
okay now copy this block
cork some find replace and this is the
find text and replace text will be
call it again we want to insert it
somewhere uh this is select contact
where do we want to insert it
select current tag okay so text delete
okay here write write
right before or after dd tag
uh let's say before okay so
you see here is a delete tag added there
there is a new one so enter in this
directory yes
or html files yes yes yes yes
shut the [ __ ] up
okay so now it's done so you can see all
these files changed
now we go to the browser refresh
and fantastic you can see it's there
on every page so you can you you see
it's on every page
okay that's complete okay uh now go back
to now
now go back to my web browser i mean the
site
blog emacs blog copy the link paste it
relinquify it delete that make that okay
here's a correct entry selected html
element that's correct
now make it into a atom feed add a new
element
new entry atom atom feed web feed
so that people need to read you know
modern society we
modern people need have a need to get
all this information
otherwise otherwise we cannot leave you
know we have we get
giddy we need coffee so now there it is
so for all of you so and then the rss
you can see a new entry
here select current html element
now this is fantastic that now i'm
actually i'm done now all i need to do
is press one key
to the power shell a magnitude better
than the
idiocy of the unix fashion two backs
sorry sorry dion and friends
okay now we get we need to r sync okay
r sync now you can see the r sync the
unix tool bag
operating under powershell now there's
some glitches
there are some glitches because now
every time i you know it asks you
uh it asks you to okay so you see
it's done so now you go to xr emacs blog
on your computer you can see this new
entry
uh all these files has been synced
updated but you know there's a problem
because every time i run this command
it's asking it's saying
the you know could not create directory
home
dot ssh uh the authenticity of host
blah blah blah and cannot be assigned
because for some reason you cannot
you know it's a nasty problem this is
this is one of the examples of the
complexities of the software industry
because you see rsync is a unix tool
now theoretically if you use it on
mac or windows you know it's ported to
windows it should work
but it cannot because it cannot create
directory
home dot ssh okay okay
why is that well this is this is when
you need
technical knowledge you know you need
10 5 10 or 20 years of experience well
that's because
environment variables of the home
variable on windows you have the home
path environment variable but on unix
you have the home
environment variable and environment
variables on unix and
and windows operating system they are
not exactly the same the similar
kind of similar but not exactly and also
on the mac you have the p
list p list from edge
from xml to to to binary format
then before that it gets getting complex
then we come back to the issue of the
registry binary versus text
let you know the unix text binary format
which is
an issue that's been discussed to death
in the past 20 years and in my opinion
it
looks like by binary format one for
uh reasons for um anyway so that's
uh starting to digress so anyway so this
little issue so
and i've been spending 10 minutes i
haven't found
the proper answer but you know like
okay we are digressing so any questions
on comments because
now basically we are done with emacs now
it's just uh
we're gonna talk random am i still live
okay there's a disruption in my uh
there's a disruption in my uh in my
stream
so anyway so
so let's see let me read the comments
okay then then
then uh let's see where we go so anyway
so we are having this problem
sync you know on windows could not
create directory the ssh
keys now in fact i don't know if i you
know i just
exposed or this fingerprint whatever
yeah you know i don't know to what
danger degree
i'm ex exposing my web servers anyway
you hackers don't hack it okay it's a
it's run by my web hosting you know
service provider
okay anyway so
let me read the comments and let's see
how we um
where we go okay dion has a question
about
typesetting mathematics uh
hola the first agi so let me read the
comments and see okay the first agi will
learn to reprogram itself from
sas website what what is agi
santiago chio hey hi from chile
i uh
okay agi so what is agi
so now we are in the realm of random
chat
adjusted gross income what
okay dion says i've long contemplated
creating a form of notebook software
that would allow the content compiled to
html yeah
that's the um that's the idea from
wolfram research in fact that
you know in my opinion that's also the
answer to the
question of what type setting software
to use
let me let me explain that okay uh
in fact i did a video like uh uh this
month
you know a month ago uh around there
uh mathematica type setting have you
seen it
dion because i think that would answer
most of your questions about typesetting
because
in my that video it's a demonstration of
mathematica type setting
but but let me answer the question okay
so anyway so if you have questions you
know
type now in detail and so i can answer
uh to your to whatever your question
uh need uh is about okay so
you know instead of me just
just start to rant on whatever i i i
wanted to rant about
so the video is about youtube okay let's
go to my youtube let's see
youtube.com okay you need to turn on
javascript
you know i'm i'm i'm this uh hacker
tradition of painstakingly
trying to guard my privacy the american
way
the american obsession you know in china
they don't they don't care
whether in america it's a thing it's a
thing you need to be concerned about
your privacy
oh my god microsoft sucks because
everywhere you go it sucks your privacy
and
then google the great do no evil
open source took over google
yeah google is more you know google [ __ ]
up your privacy more than ever
a magnitude probably you know
today but few magnitude more so than
microsoft
ever does but however you linux
phonetics
every day you you just still focus on
microsoft oh microsoft
sucks especially you jonas you know
we have in our forum uh linux phonetics
you know this type of people i am again
is the linux
unix fanatics and hacker types you know
they are
they typically are very elite you know
they know what they're doing you know
they
they know the technical details of the
kernel of the c programming language
particular c and c plus plus low-level
languages these type of people in
general and e-max you know
e-max or vim you know they know very and
before that it's pearl
you don't hear that anymore but people
they went away
but so they are very technical and they
tell you what to do they tell you what
should be the idioms you know you should
follow this idiom
variable should name this way and that
you know this
this this i believe it is true okay this
is actually there's a class of people
that
i'm talking about that fits you know
this description
they they share a lot of this kind of
the their
world view their tendencies they're the
way they
they think about things or speak you
know especially about computing
and the way they think about government
about privacy
and also you know i'm actually you know
in the same
kind of the category of with these
people
so so for example it's them they are the
microsoft haters
from since like 20 years ago like every
day you know
like things changed in 20 years but i
think you know in 1990s you would you'll
have people that say
you know bill gates died you know with
the website dedicated to it you know be
okay
you know things like that and richard
stowman of course
we cannot talk about microsoft hatred
without mentioning which which is
snowman you know he
and today's people you know a lot
younger people
you don't know you don't know about that
but anyway so
and usually someone has been you know in
microsoft
corporation in their conference in their
room talking about microsoft stuff
this happened in 2019 well because i
guess because
microsoft now is now now officially
the open source and free software
foundation sanctioned by future snowman
i don't know if you know that uh i don't
know
you know you i don't know if you have
seen that dion but i know
jonas i want i want to talk about the
jonas jonas guy
you know because because you know he's a
young guy
a great guy okay jonas do whatever you
want
and make yourself successful okay but
your
opinions i mean you're uh let me
criticize well maybe
because i'm older so maybe i can give
you a few advice you know you can take
it or leave it you know
i i don't care i don't mind you know but
but i can see some of the my followers
okay
they are you know i can tell but you
know just by a few posts i can tell
their mentality they are the unique
psycho types
okay those things they say you know i
of course i don't you know i if you
watch my videos of course i
disagree and i talked about it i
criticized it
so much you know in every detail fact
you know
but to these people it will fly over
they will not see it
so okay okay i digress all over so today
you can see how sad it became you know
meanwhile these open source phonetics
they are still chanting open source
every day
but now look at google you know youtube
you know who is invading your privacy
all the open source sponsors the biggest
open source sponsors in the world
without them open source will be
dead google and now microsoft in the
past five years you know google facebook
twitter
uh you know not so much twitter but
facebook you know
they are the companies that put tons of
money into open
open source anyway so i'm digressing
it's not uh i don't want to do another
talk show on the
on the you know again it's open source
anyway so
yeah go to the saudi okay youtube
youtube so xr tv so let's see uh
do i have uh javascript on you know it's
really
actually silly to turn off javascript
because nobody does
now even though even among
many of you of you guys you know the
privacy sensitive open source
guys you know jonas
but now you say you just turn on leave
open you know javascript on but then you
have the other things
javascript is the key okay turning it
off if you
really really concerned you should you
don't need to be anywhere
but you really can turn off javascript
but then java if you have javascript
off today nothing you know all the
website doesn't work anymore
you know it's a gradual struggle you
know you guys don't know
i mean the young people okay you have no
idea
well i mean i guess i guess i guess i'm
getting old you know i'm getting old so
you know so i'm like you you know 20
years ago we fight for the freedom
you know no ads you know no spammy ads
and google is the one
who who rose and rid of the spam ads
but now it is google itself doing all
these scamming spams
google itself and back then you know
among all the nuts like young people
don't know anymore but
among all the hacker types like we you
know
counting myself we are fighting about
javascript
you know you should if you don't support
you know you should have a website that
functions without javascript
too but but that war has been lost
like since even 10 years ago but today's
people they don't know
this this you know they they still chant
open source
you know you know what when you channel
open source and you know i think
it's actually it's created by google
these
empires they want you to do that
and then also the the obsession you know
a lot of my uh people
it's a frequently asked question they
keep asking me why is your
son why is your website not https oh my
god we need https your site is not
secure
[Laughter]
you know they they've been sold they've
been educated by google
and facebook and twitter you need https
but they don't know the details what why
who
who give you this they don't know the
details i'm not going to get into
so google you know they sell you you
know they they
they they want you to chant open source
because why
because when you do that they become
more and more powerful they control all
the programmers
if you don't work for google one of
these you know corporations
you cannot make money you are you know
you are nothing
and so and then they can you know they
then you programmers become replace
replaceable [ __ ] wheels and anytime they
don't want you they just kick you out
there's plenty open source they don't
need you
uh and uh if you want to you know the
only way
to survive as a programmer with without
you know agreeing to google and facebook
is to be like richard stowman try it you
know
try to be the guru where people just
donate your money and worship you as a
god
anyway so uh so i was talking about yeah
so let's go
let's go back to maybe mathematics okay
about youtube so
so where is this
so yeah click on saw click on videos
so here's the videos woof so there this
this one okay
uh if you know uh i think this one
you know might interest you dion uh
where
the i spent like one hour
talking about uh demonstrating wufam
language type setting
and tech problems in problems of
traditional math notation
and syntax and proof systems so i think
you would be interested in that because
i know you are doing some
um you know proofs but you
uh hey emily emily from logistics
fantastic powerful technical people here
emily is uh one of our greatest tech
technical person
so anyway so i remember over so i want
to and i want to
okay i want to actually uh try to answer
the question
uh
i know how you don't like la tech okay
so you know of a good alternative okay
so
uh so let me yeah okay so let me okay
yeah i do
let me read the question okay because i
do want to let me read all the questions
and answer
some things
uh have you looked into a synchronous
emax libs
okay that's another question uh
i don't like it okay because all the
asynchronous e-max things they are just
hacks okay if you really want
a sync asynchronous things in e-max
the best solution is called a external
program
you know anyway one of the major
problems
okay so i i don't know what i'm doing
i'm rambling all over because
because i still need to answer the math
question okay anyway asynchronous
what you know one of the major
complaints about emac
is that it's synchron it's not a
synchronous okay it's
like a single thread meaning that if you
every time you call a command you
just have to wait until it finishes
meanwhile the emax freezes up you know
you cannot do anything
until it finishes so one thread single
thread
so that's a major complaint uh so
there are talks about trying to add a
single or thread support or things like
that in emacs for like
for for at least 10 years okay it just
just never happens
uh and then there's a lot of libraries
that try to
uh add asynchronous features uh
i haven't looked into aio i'm getting
old okay
anyway a lot of packages tries to do
that
uh but in general i don't like them
because they they are hacks
okay meaning practically what does that
mean in practice that means you
go through a lot of trouble to try to
get the
asynchronous feature uh so every time
you have
you know like hacks okay i despise hacks
i
refuse to read uh to use any hacks any
any kind of hacks i despise that's
that's one of
the things i despise hacks and the unix
operating system the unix philosophy the
unix people
the people who like unix they tend to be
they love
hacks hacks it's their life you know
they love it you know
trick tricks and smart coding you know
idioms like they're trying to do this
you do this way and it gets oversee
because memory and
[ __ ] okay i despise hacks i like
i'm getting into the unix trend again so
so i like you know i don't like hacks so
anyway so
so i think lots of these libraries they
are hacks in emacs so i don't
i don't like i generally don't use them
and you know and
as as so what how do i solve the problem
whenever
i wait you if you need to wait for emacs
just wait for it okay
two seconds thirty uh two sec ten
seconds
for example i just did a star find
replace on the whole directory
that takes five seconds
the the time it takes most is because
the disk you know
loading up the disk reading files but
now i have a
now i'm using a flash you know the the
solid state drive so it's much faster
but
i used to you know last year for example
i was on a spinning disc
and that takes but anyway you wait for
30 seconds for the first operation then
so anyway so i don't like hacks so i'd
rather just wait
or alternatively for example let me let
me show you okay i showed this a million
times
go uh let's say find okay so what if i
want to find a word
let's say i want to find the word
haskell in my 6000 files
you know you know so i just open this
file so this file is online
you can just you know here's a website
you go to it
okay show in browser find string so this
is a
this is a program uh 200 lines 150 lines
written in golan
go language that uh find a string like
like a grip
like like unix script okay but unix
script has lots of problems
again i can talk about this for one hour
and i've done before
unix scrap is one of the unique script
and set
lots of problems unicode problems
multi-line problems
and lots of problems so i have you know
i talked about this
too many times in my videos i have a
version i have find
find and grab or find and replace said
in over the past 20 years i've written
them in perl
in in in perl in python
in in golan in you know this you are
looking at it right now
you know anyway so one of the solution
if you
to to to solve the e emacs sync problem
waiting for emacs
is that you just call external command
so that way
so so here is the example so let me show
you okay so
so here's a script i want to find in
my xl web directory all words
uh oh what's containing haskell okay so
what is this
let's just say haska okay
okay i you know that's pretty fine you
know i use this for myself
so you so this um right what
let's purify the code oh delete c
okay so now you can see the predefined
code so i
actually i can delete those
makes it confusing but anyway so here's
the code
okay so here's i want to find haskell
let's just run it run it
so you see now it's running meanwhile i
can do stuff i can open a new uh
new buffer you know it's now it's a you
see another result pops up
now i can uk um so you can see
among my 30 000
or 40 000 files among them there are 10
000 html files
so you can find all the result uh
you know that of a files can contain
containing the world has got and i don't
have to wait for it
okay so that that's kind of the demo for
that
uh what's going on
yeah okay it's still running
actually it's still running
i don't care for it let's close it i
made a mistake
actually right now it's
stuck because i made the mistake of
turning on
turning on the buffer formatting
while the program is still running so
that is why
let's cancel it okay let's can we cancel
it cure it
program learning process do i want to
cure it yes
kill it okay
okay so so here's you know ghost script
so so that's about
the emacs sync or sync issue
what we really want is for the emacs new
people to fix this
okay to to fix this in emac bits to
create a thread or whatever
but further let me let me make another
complaint about this
uh you know my one of my things again is
this
you know again it's these hacker types
because
you know this thread is one of the
complaint
you know very frequently asked feature
in emaclis and all the other imac this
hackers they want they want this feature
but to me this is not important okay so
to them to most emacs hackers they want
emac these
to have a feature of thread you know
what's called thread
so if you don't know if you are not an
advanced programmer what that means is
that
in many programming languages you have
this feature of creating a thread
which essentially means you can run a
different program at the same time okay
use using two different uh cpu processes
okay called thread technically
and so say they want that i don't want
that okay i don't want thread [ __ ]
i don't want thread to tent emac this
language
because once you have the third feature
it becomes very complex
i don't want that crap i want what i
want is
yes i also want the auto the thread
feature but i don't want
i don't want the the thread construct
and whatever [ __ ] the c
thing just do it automatically i just i
i don't
as a emac base programmer i don't have
to
think about oh this takes too long i
need to create a thread to
no i don't want to think about that i
just code whatever
as is if it takes too long
you the compilers just figure it out
yourself the c
c plus plus [ __ ] heads go figure out
that's your problem
don't throw your problem onto the
programmer okay don't do
throw your problem you can you don't
know how to solve oh threat how do you
don't throw the problem up to into your
product
your product is the language the syntax
the emac list okay
don't don't throw your problem onto the
language like int
float pointers idiot okay and memory
management okay
then i know people square root rust they
love that they
did these hacker types that's why i
despise the archetypes
okay that's my opinion i'm getting i'm
getting angry over this
so that's about threat okay so
let me summarize yeah it's a long time
problem
a complaint about emacs it throws up you
know every time you do a command the
first of it
you know you have to wait until it
finishes
that's a problem and emac these people
have been trying the hacker types they
they want a thread feature
in emac bisp okay to solve this problem
i also want this problem soft but i
don't want the thread i don't want the
thread i don't want the thread feature
in my
this rather i want to kind of
alternative just solve it yourself
you know i don't want you know there are
ways
okay so how do you solve the third
problem without introducing
some explicit threat construct in a
language okay
question how do you do that okay that's
another topic that's another
deep topic about programming language
design about computer science about
their you know theory you know
theoretical computer science or
what or whatever that's a big topic
and uh i'm not too qualified to to talk
about that but
anyway so anyway what i can say is that
don't listen to the cc
plus plus programmers they don't know
what they're talking about
the the the the most easy way to solve
the
the weighting problem is just to create
a thread in the language that's what c
and c plus first type of coders do
that's what they love to do just you
know
like the unix philosophy keep it simple
stupid
the [ __ ] idiots no design that's what
unix the entire unix is about
no design and hack and speed you know
remember the word speed speed is
like everywhere you go that's a c c and
unix
idiots they created the concept speed we
are fast
look we are fast [ __ ] [ __ ] okay i'm
getting any
okay stop stop talking about that let's
go back to the
uh discussion about wufang language okay
so that video i discussed um
wufang language type setting but however
i haven't talked i have
not talked about what is alternative
actually the alternative
okay so if you need to do type setting
okay
so what are the solutions of course most
obviously tech
and attack you know that's that's kind
of almost that's a standard
free free you don't have to pay free and
standard
accepted everywhere and loved by hackers
loved by unix
linux idiots they love it hack uh tech
okay it's also supported on the web you
need to you
yeah okay so let's search for sally
math type setting
okay actually i have compiled a list of
results
uh uh you know i've written about this
um you're here okay nine tools to
display math
on the web okay so you can so math
math jacks okay which is a which is a
javascript hack
extreme hack that gets the website to
displays
to display math formulas using using
tech
okay using tech and javascript very
complex it's
extremely hack to the most degree okay
anyway it works it works so that
so that's that's one thing you can do
you can use
uh then uh where is my article okay so
uh
so let's go back go back okay so uh
back back to previous page okay so let
me turn on javascript so you can
actually see
the result of type setting okay there it
is so there you see
math so that's one uh one solution okay
but
uh i don't you know i don't i think tech
is very bad it depends on you okay
so depends on your need you know do you
want it
to be free do you want to be you know
kind of standardized
then go with tech go with tech la tech
and the math math jacks
okay you know just go with it
uh then there's uh so i have a few
like related to a smash url so what is
this simple site for creating math
notations
yeah so this is basically online tech
you know you type
whatever then then
then you have to um
then then it creates yeah then it
creates an image
you know kind of you know another hack
uh and uh unicode symbols okay so this
is also related
a bunch of unicode symbol symbols this
is this is not
a hack this is just direct unicode
symbols you can
have all these symbols then you have um
detectify i forgot you know this is
written 10 years ago
yeah so this one is also pretty cool
by the way so you can i can use the pen
to write a math symbol so you know for
example let me
write javascript tone
refresh uh
draw here so what why is not what is my
pen okay
for example summation it show you the
unicode symbols
then let's say let's say fee
so you have a empty empty set or
uh do we have fee we don't we didn't get
fee so let's try again
so maybe it's slanted yeah there is
there it is uh you know greek character
fee and uh then you can let's say let's
try this double stroke r
there it is okay so that's that here's
another tool that helps you
essentially help you find the unicode
uh character but if you want to do that
try my website okay so
you type fee then it shows update in
real time you know
so you get you get latin small letter
fee
you get greek capital letter fee you get
greek small letter fee
you get greek fee symbol okay you know
called make a distinction
so these are all different then you have
t thigh you have hangul then you have
you know all these characters contains
the word fee in their unicode names
so you know you can try my unicode
website saudi unico
so anyway let's go back so there are
some of these tools
so anyway so if you want to do
publishing so you can use you know
so like tech or tech or math jacks or
you can uh i would just recommend
mathematica okay because
because now you can get it for free
you know or pay 300 okay um
of course there are flaws such as it's
not open source okay
it's free but it's not open source and
also uh
also if you buy the student version or
hobbies version they might
you know your publication might have you
know you have a
it says you know this is a
non-professional version you know this
is a hobbyist version you'll say that
things like that and
you know uh but or you can just use the
free version
okay so i don't
actually you know wolfam engine okay i
mean you can download for free i don't
know if it
actually does the type setting i think i
don't i don't know i haven't
you know i have i have a version they
send it to me okay
so anyway so so so that's one solution
then
there's other solutions okay there's
other solutions
uh such as let's go back there's other
solutions
um plain plain muffin
language notation okay this is very easy
to read
basically ascii ascii
way of writing mathematics now there is
also a format called
ascii math which is kind of similar but
anyway the wolfram language syntax is
perfect it's fantastic okay
here's how you represent sun in plain
text okay plain text this is how you
represent sun
this is how you represent you know
another if this is an infinite sum
and this is how you represent integral
so integrate 1 over x
x from 1 to k plus 1 this is how you
the syntax for it and this is how you
represent
that's a natural log okay so this is how
you represent you know
a definite integral
uh do i have a example of indefinite
integral
well just replace the second part by
just the variable name x
okay then here's how you represent limit
you know it's very systematic syntax
okay anyway i talked about this in
another the
other video um and here is how you
represent over bar
this is absolute square root and this is
how you ever
send a matrix or a matrix multiplication
okay so plain text is another way kind
of
and if you paste this into mathematica
it becomes let me show you okay let me
just do a demo copy it
uh copy it let's shrink it go to
mathematica
let's say a new one uh three
plus three plus two evaluate
let's magnify
okay now paste this bunch of thing
over and evaluate
uh so we got a bunch of um
oh yeah so
yeah we need to modify because it
doesn't allow this dot dot
okay so i want to do this quickly okay
so anyway so let me just do this okay
ctrl shift
n okay so there you have it so it's a
okay this over bar is not correct
ctrl shift t
[Music]
ctrl shift n anyway so that's you know
i'm not going to get into details
so okay so here's a plain text way to
to represent mathematical expressions
okay
by plain text using the wolfram language
syntax okay
then you have gnu tech mac now this
is not based on this this
this is um this is not dependent on tech
nor is it based on emacs it's funny okay
so gnutec
techmac is like a
emacs like editor that allows you to
to do type settings for example you can
look at their examples okay
so this is typeset in gnu techmax but
it's not emacs no is it tech
funny okay so you can use this this is
alternative
okay so here's the example screenshot
uh glue tech mac okay funny
and then then you have then you have
then you have other search math which
sucks pretty badly
because i tried it one time 10 years old
it still sucks so there are
these are some of the alternatives you
know what's most infuriating the insult
you know
20 years ago uh 10 10 20 years ago
the worldwide the the the w3c
the standard organization for html you
know the other hacker
unix types loves citing html
validation all the time you know things
change like today's young people you
guys don't know like you [ __ ] you
you don't know you never heard of it
it's like you don't
it's not like you don't even remember
because he wasn't there you don't know
but w3c the standard organization
loved and chanted by the unix linux
[ __ ] all over
10 years ago they created mathml okay
mathml which is the because there's a
need for formulas on the web so they
created this math email which is a xml
based prototype okay
then firefox and google
you know google used to be good you know
the do no evil company in the
throughout 2000s and also firefox you
know
firefox the enemy of microsoft
internet explorer they
you know they oh yeah oh yeah we we need
to implement this math email also
so firefox and google both implemented
then about by not eight years ago google
google removed it google google chrome
the web browser eight years ago they
become or they are already the winner
you know
they are the most popular browsers used
in the world now
they removed math math ml
what's their reason they are saying they
say um
nobody no not many people want it that's
their reason
basically they they basically have all a
complete
implementation of math ml then google
chrome removed it
okay now i don't know what's the status
with firefox i think i think they still
support it
anyway that's the story of math ml and
mathml and
okay that's a that's a political aspect
um a kind of a story political aspect of
mathematic the creation
and the the four of matthew meow you
know
once google chrome don't implement it
that's kind of dead okay
that's a social political aspect now
there's a also a technical aspect i want
to talk about
mathematic really sucks okay mathemate
not not the typical unix
people do as they say i disagree with
them
they also think it sucks but the the
reason i think it sucks has to do
because it's
it doesn't it it just it's it's similar
to tech
latex the donald glute [ __ ] you know
it destroys any structure in the in the
mathematical
expression it destroys it
instead it becomes kind of like a type
setting
you know it's just a typesetting thing
controlling the position
of this symbol of grading drawings
things like that it doesn't
anyway i talked about this before too um
in my critters criticism of latex and
tech
so you know it destroys the it does
not it does not focus on the
the the inherent structure
of mathematical expressions rather
it focuses on on the
rendering part like which position
should this symbol be like a fraction
so to do a fraction what you do is you
you create two symbols one is on top of
the other
and adjust their position things like
that that's what tech and latex do
that's what that's the the central
purpose of tech
latex to creating micro symbols in their
positioning
and destroy all mathematical structure
in it
so so it is impossible to convert tech
latte back to actual
uh let me give you the most simple
simple example x squared okay x squared
in almost in most languages you write it
like that
or write it like that okay that that
means
x squared okay now
in traditional math notation you render
it as a um
you know you you know you know what i'm
talking about you render it you know x
squared okay let's let's show you that
okay so you render it like that
uh you can also make this to show uh uh
ctrl shift you know
but you can see there's a math structure
so this is an
operator on two operands okay but if you
render this in la tech i don't you know
i
it's been 10 you know i haven't been
working with latex you you do something
like uh
you know you use this syntax it destroys
the structure so it's it's
it's impossible to for it to
anyway i i think you know what i mean
probably i don't want um
it what i'm trying to say well
actually i should i should show you how
do you do this in la tech but i have
examples but that takes you know two
minutes to pull it up
because i don't i don't remember what's
a la tech tech
syntax for it
so anyway i think i've been talking for
over an hour probably i should uh
finish that's that's it for today
so so mathml okay it has the same
problem with uh
with tech and latex then another group i
think there's another group of people
who created a
uh i don't know i don't remember the
name now but you if you go to wikipedia
you read the details about mathml you'll
see
a here okay here um
they created kind of an alternative
called semantic
mathml something like that
to actually just like mathematica they
actually focus on the structure of
mathematical expressions
not focusing on the positioning
rendering the typesetting thing okay
they created that but it went nowhere
because
you know google chrome killed it you
know there's no map any other
you know it goes nowhere so so that is
you know this is why i despise you know
i despise the height i hate
the unix and see the unix philosophy
these [ __ ]
this is the thing this this is not just
talk you know this is actually this
happened today
you don't have a system in browser to
display mathematics in a universal
standardized way because the unix
[ __ ] okay i
blamed it directly on the unexpected
because they embrace
they invest like tech you know the crap
then google says the do no evil open
source google says oh we don't need it
because nobody wanted
meanwhile they support you know the
youtube the poem
videos that's what google spent
tremendous time because what people want
to watch video youtube
okay so that's that's that's it
that's about that um that's about the
type setting thing okay the
uh rent uh so so here
are the uh kind of the alternatives you
could use i guess
i don't know if i answered that your
question or is it just
my rent
okay so i think that's it let's see how
long i've been i've been talking and
final any final questions then i'm gonna
shut down so it's four o'clock
now so it's been one hour exactly
good event okay uh so
so let's see who else is saying what
virtual blue sky you could place the
you could pass the website with a snow
browser like chrome or firefox to avoid
this
okay show look at the google censorship
at work
the [ __ ] google censorship emacs is
unstable to be used as a operating
system
use a lot of other tools as well
externally
emacs has such a packing amazing
framework and when you get
used to the keybinding you cannot get
away okay show
i don't want a censorship okay any
opinion is welcome
uh if you disagree with me your opinion
are welcome
well there's one requirement i require
you to be sincere
okay and don't do [ __ ] you know you
believe whatever
you know you don't you i know most
actually
have at least half of my people who
follow me are the unix type you know the
the the very type
i despise but that's good that's good
because i'm
you know i know you know i'm not saying
like i'm i'm the best
but you know i'm in the same group so
let's just uh talk about
things
uh so let's see uh it was hack hacker
started using the programming
joe nash okay um john nash
shouted that as a pejorative a lesser
mathematician so really
you know hacker you know another thing
about the word hacker is that
you know the hacker you know like
like there's two meanings okay one
meaning
is the meaning by the richard stoneman
or the classic hackers like esr richard
stoneman you know the previous
generation
the hackers you know hacker meaning the
origin from the mit
hackers from the mit the you know
massachusetts
institute's institute of technology you
know they are the hacker types
which is the is the exact type i
criticize that
i don't like even though i'm kind of the
in the same
group you know because they like to hack
things
you know they like they like to
discovery discover things you know
hardware
so where you know they dive into uh you
know they they ditto and you know
do it yourself the kind of like is a
next generation of hacker types you know
they
and they like puns um you know things
like that
and they use they they also like
linguistics a lot which i do
but not today's generation you know
today malayan jain is kind of new thing
like
jonas if you are watching this a little
bit different
today's you know hacker is dead okay so
anyway that's a classic
sense of hacker but beginning around
1990s there's a
kind of a new meaning of hackers
and these hackers despise that is
the journalist you know in the media the
pop media you know the newspapers
they use the word hacker to me to mean
what the hacker
calls cracker meaning basically
criminals you know computer criminals
they
hack into other systems the government
system you know
that's the so so the according to these
hacker types
the proper word for these type of people
computer
criminals is called crackers you know
they crack
passwords crackers okay but that but
that word was never popular
so so this is the thing you know
throughout 1990s it's a big
you'll see it discussed everywhere but
my personal opinion actually i despise
the hackers
[Laughter]
i think they're wrong let let the world
hacker be
too many criminals because then
it's a bit complex complicated okay i
don't want to
um i haven't talked about this for a
long time i haven't thought about this
for a long time but anyway that that's
that was the thing so and today so
again the things different today the
millennial generation they don't know
they don't know about this hacker word
history
like they don't they don't even know
what troll means anymore the word troll
went through like several three also
stages
in the 1980s or early or
1990s troll originally means someone is
like
smart you know they create they post
something get lots of traffic lots of
talk
but the guy who posted is kind of like
like a hacker like
they are doing a practical joke you know
the hacker types love that
they are doing you know they they know
what they're doing so they created they
crafted their writing so that
it gets you know kicks up a lot of
people's emotion they think they don't
know they try to explain it
you know things like that true that's
the original meaning of troll
you know it came from the fishing
practice kind of
and also etymology of truth you know one
is the
the the greek i mean not greek but the
the
scandal navy or northern european uh
mythology of a creature you know
kind of bad and good you know creature
you know who make practical jokes on
people
things like that cultural you know then
the other
etymology is the kind of a fishing
technique you throw a
net into the ocean something like that
you poo a lot of fishes
but today you know so so all this
information
it's gone you know the truth the world
itself went through several
every every decade the meaning change
changed okay
so originally in the 1980s
it was it meant someone you know kind of
doing a pr
who knows things and do a practical joke
online forums you know new
news net news news groups it doesn't
exist
much anymore today anyway
the the you know they post online photos
to
kind of like a practical joke and gets
lots of
you know make a mess a chaos of the
group of the community
because all the people you know put in
different ideas opinions
that's the original meaning of true now
i let me put a year okay so around year
year 2k then it becomes basically it
becomes someone you
someone who's opinion you don't like so
for example in unix
community if you say anything against
unix or python your favorite language or
emacs or vim
even if you you don't mean to be a troll
like usually i am like that okay
i mean let's not talk about me let's
talk about so so if you have some
opinion
that's different that's contrary to the
main stream
in the current community let's say emacs
so if you are a
vi user you you know and you
come into the emacs group you don't you
know you know you don't throw you
i mean you you sometimes you honestly
have a question or
on some certain issues you certainly you
believe that emacs is
vi is better than emacs in particular
cases
and you are you know very earnest and
honest and you
post well you know you crap you know you
write your opinion you don't mean to
you know you have no intention to attack
people
you really just you and you do spend a
lot of
time to write you know why you think
this way you know
but then because you are in emacs
community most people they just want to
support emacs
they call you a draw so that is the
meaning of trolls
starting around late 1990s okay year
that happens a lot anyone you know you
someone who you know in emacs versus vio
programming language debate you'll see
that happen all over they
people just call you a troll when you
are kind of like a
outsider okay kind of and sometimes it
mixing with you know someone intentional
trying to [ __ ] up things
too so that's around year 2000
okay now in year 2010
the social justice scan the social
justice
justice [ __ ] they arose true
by year 2010 doesn't mean you know
it doesn't mean anything about
programming nuts
fighting each other doesn't mean that
anymore trump
means by 2010 it's like usually in a
political context
in what they call you know
things like um
online harassment bully okay that's the
same word around that time
booty online harassment nothing to do
with unix or
or emacs versus vi troll okay
troll is online bully or online you know
some
you know nothing about programming
anymore
that's why most people think uh
you know that's the usage of troll
around 2010
and they and these people they have no
idea they never looked up
what you know meaning and you know they
don't know
so that's a word troll anyway
uh that's it for today
um i think i remembered too much on the
troll issue
okay i think that's it so that's it for
today so if you like my stuff
put money in my pocket okay donate
daniel hey daniel langlois
s canxa
from the south disco server that i have
my name set to
yeah emily emily the logic
this is the logic something
uh logistics
demo type setting in mathematica i did a
little bit right i think i did a little
bit
uh but to watch my other video because
that that whole video is about that
hey thank you guys hey emily thank you
coming for coming by bye guys
you