good morning guys welcome to another
episode of cassatt talk show today we
are going to do emacs emacs 28 new
features and i'm going to explain
you know some particular features of
emacs 28 fantastic emacs 28 is truly
fantastic you know i just installed it
like three days ago and
tons of fantastic features and i'm going
to focus today on the i complete
so i complete
fido
i do
and smacks you know i'm going to talk
about this you know this uh category of
emacs 28 features so it's gonna be
nothing but emacs
so if you have a emacs questions ask me
okay
and don't forget to donate like chiptune
you know put money in my pocket
and so let's begin okay so so let's see
yeah let's begin right away so uh audio
check video check
i'm still alive not dead yet
so uh let's
uh what am i gonna do yeah
so yeah stop this
thing
and
okay emacs okay
so the emacs 28 is just fantastic you
know you download it you know you can um
you know you know you know let's just
talk about the features okay let's not
um
get distracted okay so you know
you know maybe later on i'll talk about
where to download and stuff it's all on
my website you know sorry emacs just
search for my name emacs you'll see
where to download and for mac for we uh
for windows and for linux okay so emacs
28 one of the great feature you know
emacs 28 has i was i'm truly impressed
okay so let me show you so you are
looking at the emacs
gnu emacs news file you know you know
you know in every other application when
you have a new release you have release
notes you know but it's an emax
tradition because emacs beginning at all
you know 40 years ago they they don't
have release notes instead of
you know instead they say it's news you
know
emacs news so you are looking at the gnu
emacs news you know
so
which is the release notes you know for
this uh imax 28 and i was going to you
know i just installed it three months
ago i mean three days ago and it it's
released actually just this month uh
it's just released you know uh let's see
do they have a date here that no they
don't put a date so hold on a second let
me
add
wait yeah let me add the highlight the
current line so we can see where my
cursor is and actually i can increase
the cruiser size now never mind
so
so emacs 28 you are looking at the
release notes and i was going through it
you know and this is the best release
this is emacs 28 is the best
uh
feature reach uh release in the past 10
years i would say just by impression you
know
and and one of the fantastic thing is
that
the release notes you know what they say
here you can you know go read it
yourself so you how do you get to this
page you know you start emacs then press
ctrl h
n
you know then you get this uh emacs news
so you can read this page and you know
there's just pages of them and one of
the great improvement is that now they
are readable you know like you know i've
been coding emac this for 10 plus years
i've been using emacs for 20 years but
every time emacs released you know new
new feature you know new emacs release
you know i read the e-max news release
notes
half of the items i don't understand
like incomprehensible
but now that's but now there's a big
change now actually almost every item is
like you can understand what they are
talking about you know so you can read
it yourself so anyway so let me let's
start to talk about the i complete
things so
in imax 28 they have
overhauled the i complete my okay so
hold on a second let me go too so go to
powershell
uh powershell you are looking at my
and let's
saw wait what's going on
let's magnify you so you can see
uh
sartargo
dark theme
so now it's you know it's um
not dark themed so it's easier to read
okay so so i was saying that um
the imax28 so they they did a complete
um
change upgrade you know adding a lot of
features to the icomplete mod okay let
me let me begin for from the let me
explain from the beginning so those of
you are kind of
uh new to emacs you can read it
okay so in emacs you have completions
okay so for example i want to call a
command let's say
uh what command should i uh call let's
say
i search okay i search is one one of the
most useful feature which lets you for
example i want to find the next
occurrence of the word
emax in this file in this buffer so i
press a key i'm using supply keys so i
can
type
so you can see in the mini buffer e max
so you can see that and you can move to
the next occurrence or move to the
previous occurrence you know so that
that command is called i search okay
so for example i can describe key okay
hold on a second let me show the pink
window the pink window shows all my
command names you can you know look you
can look up so you know
and keystrokes
so i want to call i search you know
there's a shortcut but
you can also call it by meta x you know
mental x
then i search okay let me show you uh
let's see describe key okay
let me just go quickly so describe key
then i press the key in soft like keys
to invoke i search which is this key one
single key press b
on for our keyboard so you can see it
calls the command i search forward
and you have seen how that works you
know press b
then type e max you know and you can so
that that's i search now so let me
let me try again now let's call the
command okay
so
let's this time i'm going to call meta x
you know i'm going to press meta x so
so in starfly keys it's just one single
key a okay so you can see let's see uh
cancel okay so you can see
i'm calling you see there execute
extended command that's a full name for
the shortcut key
meta x which is
typically alt x okay on windows on mac
on on linux
so anyway so meta x so i'm gonna call
meta x you know execute extended command
now you see the mini buffer now that's
that's new okay you see
i'm not using any fancy mod you know i'm
now actually not using any third-party
packages i'm
purely using my own
you know anything that's not developed
here i'm not using i'm using
only xr packages
and the gnu emacs mothership so meta x
you can see now in a mini buffer you see
it suggests you know first of all you
have this vertical display and it
suggests you know it gives you all the
command choices and also the key binding
the shortcut associated with those
commands that has a key
so now i can type you know i search so i
type i
then it immediately narrows down
it narrows down to all commands that
contains the letter i
you see
before it doesn't work like that before
when you have you know it you have to
type
whatever the command name begin with
so for example
this stiff command
you know diff you have to type d first
so you cannot type a letter that's in
the middle of the command name for
example some command switch
switch to buffer you know some long
command name you forgot
what comes in before comps comes after
you just remember there's a word buffer
in it
so in that case you can just type buff
so let's cancel let's do that okay meta
x b u f f
you see
so so all these commands contain the
word buffer
and you don't and also you know so this
is new this is fantastic
you know before emacs 28
you also have that feature but you have
to download from third part party
packages you know such as
helm such as icicles such as
a bunch of others you know and i do is
one of them but i do is included in imax
so anyway so that is the fantastic
feature okay let's do it again meta x
then i
s
e
okay then you can see a bunch of i
search you know then i type a
uh you know so so that's the example so
let's cancel let's um yeah so this is
fantastic okay
right so if you are not using emacs 28
then what you do is you call you install
the external package they are several
you know helm you know i don't use but
there's one i use i highly recommend
which is smacks okay let me show you
where it is so some key
uh
that's a file let's go to the directory
search for smx okay there
so let's okay let's hide you know that
that one smacks okay so you can download
it on mailpad so if you are not using
emax28
this is the one i recommend so what does
smacks do
it enhances your meta x
so now you see in imax 28 meta x is
fantastic but if you don't have emax 28
you install smacks
then you have similar but in fact emacs
28 is better because it also includes
keyboard shortcuts you don't have that
in smacks
but now with emacs 28 i highly recommend
go install it now okay with emacs 28 you
don't need smacks anymore so my last
you know the the the last external
package i don't need anymore you know i
was planning to you know write my own
smacks at some time but now i don't need
to
so no more smacks
okay that's
so so
so the so so this feature
you know meta x where you have vertical
display and
flex matching okay the technical name is
flex matching
it's just fantastic it
okay that's one thing okay that's one
thing i covered we covered today
questions comments
on what i'm talking about uh posted okay
so smacks is fantastic i mean the the
icon feed okay i complete the emacs 28
feature
i complete
now
has flex matching and also has vertical
um
thing let's uh let's type buffer okay
let's see all the commands
involving the name buffer so you can
move cursor to you know eval buffer very
useful save buffer kill buffer of course
usually you have you do a key to call
those commands next buffer diff buffers
okay
you know great suggestion you know i i
rarely use that uh erase buffer clone
buffer oh there's even a clone buffer
i didn't i didn't know i never used that
command so
great feature okay so now let's let me
go to the next thing let me tell you
okay so this is a demo of the feature
so this feature is called
i complete okay technique technically
technicality so in emacs there's a
command called
i complete mod
okay so technically it's a minor mod so
that
when you turn this mod on that's what
that's what allows you to have this uh
kind of
nice um
you know uh pop-up selection
and it's it's fast okay
it's
very fast okay so i complete mod but not
just that emacs 28 also have a bunch of
others okay so let me show you where
okay so fido yeah so let me show you so
it might be confusing
to you you know if you don't know so
i'm going to explain so you have i
complete mod
and in imax 28 you also have something
called fido mod okay
so what's the difference between these
two
actually all these are part of the i
complete mod in the in the file so let
me show you okay so meta x wait
so now i do um
ctrl h f
describe function
you see so con you know uh hold on a
second so let me show the pink window so
you can see my command there you see so
let's do it again
describe function so now you can type
you know you know let's see i complete
okay so let's just say i come
here you see there okay then
c o m and m o d there it is you see
very nice you see you don't have to
match the whole substring so whatever
you typed have doesn't have to be a
substring of the command you can type
part of the word here part of that word
here as long as they are in order and
you get you know you get the command you
want
so i complete mod okay so describe
function let's show let's show the
documentation of the icomplete mod okay
expand the window magnify so
there it is and you can
okay that's too big okay now it's good
now you press tab you press tab to jump
to the source code you can and you know
then you can see the key binding and so
on so
so what's my point so i can yeah so
anyway i complete mod and oh yeah so
let's jump to the file okay so
so let's jump to the you know
source code of i complete mod so you can
go to direct direct jump and you can see
here's the you know e-max this source
code directory so here's i complete mod
and now let's
these matching lines and let's type
defend
enter
then you can see
all the functions defined in this file
and now you can see
where is fido what
i complete i complete wait feeder is
here but
where is the feeder function oh it's not
using different okay so
let's do it again let's search for fido
okay
this matching line is fido
so you can see there define minor mod
it's in the same file you see let's jump
to it you see define minor mod feeder
vertical mod you see and there is also
feeder mod um
you know you see the feeder define miner
mod feeder mod let's jump to it right
here
then there's also feed of vertical mod
but anyway
so
you have i complete mod and fido mod and
i complete vertical mod
then you also have feeder vertical mods
so all these are actually the kind of
the same thing they are in the i
complete package they are considered the
same so how do they work they actually
they actually just change they actually
just change some mini buffer
configuration
you know
that's how they work they are actually
not the engine or co they are just right
they are just changing some
configurations of the mini buffer so
they are all kind of the same
so we when you call any each or any one
of them
you know icomplete or feeder mod or i
complete vertical mod or feed or
vertical mod they all turn on i complete
mod so you can consider them all just as
variations of icomplete okay
i mean this information is helpful when
you started to
you know put configurations in your emac
list because you might thought oh what
happens if i turn both i do mod and i
complete mod on you know maybe you'll
give me some richer feature you know
combined no no it's not like that so you
can pick any one of them they just
change some configuration okay so i
complete my so what's the the difference
between i complete mod and fido mod is
that with i complete mod is which is the
classic you have to
whatever you type has to be a substring
of the command and has to begin with the
first character of the string so you
cannot you know if you remember command
called something something buffer
and you just type buffer it won't show
because you you have to type you have to
begin with whatever the letter the
command begin so i complete my
the classic
way is not useful
you want feeder mod so that feeder mod
is using flex match okay
like we demonstrated like buffer if i
type buffer
then you got i buffer e buffer pp buffer
i don't know what that is you know then
view buffer then eval buffer save of you
know you got a bunch you know reverb
buffer
reverb buffer is when you want to
refresh the file from the disk you know
maybe someone else change it you know
very useful too
and rename buffer oh
i'll remember okay that's not too useful
uh html you know so
what is this smiley buffer look
look we found slap smiley buffer i have
no idea what that is okay so let's do
uh mid you know uh
h control h
f let's see
smiley buffer so what
what is that smiley puff smiley buffer
is an autoloader from blah blah blah run
smiley region at the buffer okay
specifying argument okay what that is
what what is that let's let's go check
smiley region
okay smiley region is auto loaded
replaced in regions smiley regular
expression a list matches when
corresponding images
a list of images is returned
i have no idea what that is but it's
interesting it's you know this we can
jump to
uh jump to the
source code of smiley thing
written by dave love
from year 2000
okay i don't know what this package oh
okay basically it does smileys okay
the precursor of unicode of emoji you
know the malaysians emoji so this is
hackers emoji in the 1990s precursor of
the emoji
smiley
so i suppose this package help you type
smitey something like that
okay so anyway so
so back to you know well
so so all these you know video mod like
so the main difference between i
complete and fido is that fido uses flex
matching okay
that's good
then you have then you have you know you
can go to my website and read all about
it you know just like you know
so then you have um
i complete vertical mod
and the feeder vertical mod they are
just the vertical version you know for
example let's turn off the vertical
let's say so right now i'm using fido
okay let me show you the difference okay
so i'm going to call
i complete mod okay
do it
now it says i complete my disabled okay
let's call it again
because they it toggles okay
okay now you see now i complete is
disabled now i have you know now there's
no
suggestions let's magnify let's see
you know this
you know so i complete there's no
suggestion so i have to i have to press
tab
oh oh and god and i okay i complete so i
have to type o
tab
okay tab okay i complete
then tab
then mod tab okay finally so this is
what happens when you do not have i
complete on or any of these songs so
okay but now let's turn it on
so now it's on
oh god we got
it wrong
we got a quote okay let's do it again
i can
complete and
i complete tab
mod
okay i complete mod enabled now let's
try again
meta x
i complete okay it's vertical now it's
doing the vertical version
we want to turn off the vertical version
so
cancel so i complete
vertical one cancel
i complete you see
right now we want to call this
i complete vertical mod command
to turn it off okay but right now i
cannot type v so if i type v
nothing shows up
why because you are not using fido it's
not using flex match so that's that's
why fido is better than i complete okay
so i have to first of all do a
completion
then v
enter okay that enter doesn't work even
though it's the first choice so now i
have to type m
when so now there's only one choice now
i can enter
okay so now it says i complete vertical
disabled
so right now we are just in i complete
mod let's do it again meta x
i complete you see
so this is uh
this is what happens when you don't have
the vertical mod version
okay
okay so i think that's um we covered
that okay so
let's just go back to fido vertical okay
i want the fido
mod what
yeah
fido
vertical uh so
without you know without fido
you have to always complete
you know press tab to complete i don't
want that
and
wait cancel
it's enabled okay now let's try again
fantastic now we are back to fido
vertical so
if you installed emax28 or you know just
turn on fido okay just this is the line
you want that's all you want okay now
but if you are using emacs 27 or before
then then you you know i so i have a
code here you can just copy paste your
emacs each so if you are using emacs 27
then you want to turn on
icomplete and you also want to set the i
complete separator to be a
to be a end of line character
so that's how you make it display
vertical so before before e max 28 you
have to do all these you know manually
like configure it so it display
vertically but now it's just you just
call i complete vertical you know
so anyway in before emacs 28 you have to
turn on i complete mod then you also
have to turn off i do
so let me explain what is i do i do is
basically
you know
flex matching okay but the thing is that
i do only works for
file names and buffer names like when
you switch buffer or when you open a new
file so fido com you know fido is very
useful and you can also configure fig
fiddle so that
so let's magnify so that for example
you know said you know
i do i mean free i do not veto okay so
emacs 28 you have to turn feet
you have to turn i do mod
and what does i do mod
do
it makes
it allows flex matching
and
for buffers
buffer switching commands and open file
commands so you don't so for you know
matching file names
so and you can also set it up so that it
displays things vertically
you know so for example here
i do enable flex matching true you know
so the problem is i do
mod it's which is part of emacs
it only works for buffer names and file
names so when you want to do meta x it
doesn't work it doesn't apply there so
that's that is why you also have to turn
on i complete
but however i complete in emacs 27
doesn't support flex matching so you
have to press tab all the time like tab
completed part of it then tab again type
something tab again complete again
so that's
so but now it's all soft okay
okay so that's about
that's about that okay so let's see what
else i
need to explain
and
maybe that's it for today okay
uh any questions comments so how long
have i been talking for 30 minutes
uh
sits on top of the native com completion
emax28 yes
so it's awesome thank you money money is
what i need okay
yeah well
yeah so donate me or um buy my emacs
tutorial okay buy my you know patreon
amazon gift card or paypal
or bitcoin
or
you can buy
my
uh
you know complete emacs tutorial which i
provided for you online okay let me show
you some another thing a recent addition
to my website okay
so you know
look at my emacs tutorial it's here if
you like it you know support me pay me
okay
uh so there's a recent addition which is
a search feature you know in in the la
in my last video i did about two weeks
ago
i was live coding
uh
a search engine essentially uh you know
the
premier a primitive search engine
so now it's complete you know so you can
just you know go to my excite website or
sally.info each part has a search engine
so let me show you okay
so it supports lots of features for
example uh
let's suppose you want to you know i
have like a few hundred articles on my
for my emacs so you want know you want
to know what is i do
you know
because you know i have emacs tutorial
emacs init emacs keys
you know and emacs keys you know 100
articles uh practical emac list
then several videos emac these examples
you forgot where they are where is the
page i talked about i do so you click on
search
then
i do there it is fantastic instantaneous
result as you type now you you remember
reading something about buffer how do
you set a buffer in emacs so but you
forgot where it is so you type b-u-f-f-e
so immediate result so you got a bunch
of them
so ivy mod yeah
ivy mod is another you know
um
completion i think i forgot
third party mod
so let's see okay so wait so
yeah anyway so that's a search feature
okay you can you can also do minus
let's see
uh uncolor next previous buffer
let's see so some of them are um
let's see so let's search for lisp okay
you know you are into this programming
so let's search for lisp and you have
you know 200 articles
so
but suppose
you know you have a minus feature let me
let me try to find a good example
okay list
so let's say you want to find a list of
all emacs hooks
okay so you just type list
but however you got 20 results because
in emac this
a list is one of the you know data
struct data type so you got a bunch of
results on emac list which is not what
you want you you want a list of hooks so
you can type list minus wait minus minus
where is the minus key here this minus
lisp
you see you narrow down the result so
that's a you know that's a feature
so you can see a list of emacs hooks
uh and list buffers how did you list
buffers and so on okay
so that's a new feature on my website
and it also works on xsa keyboard for
example let's go to keyboard you are
looking at my keyboard condenses
advantage
ultimate hacking keyboard okay
let me let me show you some keyboards i
want i want to talk about so search for
sadie keyboard google
and you arrived at my website
there is a search button just for this
page let's turn on javascript so the
video shows
the
you know
you know the advertisement well i mean
the
the image you know thumbnail screen
uh clickbait
type of
thumbnail screen so anyway here's my
keyboard site there's a search button
then you can type
you know there are 800 articles there so
type mouse
so there are 1 100 articles about mouse
and let's say you want
mouse and something logitech okay so
type logitech
so you narrow down to titles that
contain both mouse and logitech okay now
let's try if there's any there's any
article related to emax on keyboard so
emacs
there it is okay
vi emacs keybinding design history of
emacs and vi keys emacs plus keyboard
kicking the nth episode okay whatever
emacs meta key history
you know so
that's the search feature using
javascript typescript
fantastic okay that's a feature i want
to show you show you okay let's go back
to emacs so we explained i complete we
explained fido
uh we explained smacks which is a
replacement you know the flex matching
for meta x
which now you don't need anymore
and we explained the whole i complete
set of commands we did
and we explained let's magnify we
explained i complete is for all commands
i do is just for files and buffers
that's right so i complete you know for
any command that
that requires a bunch of choices in the
mini buffer
i complete a price you know i i
completely will make them you know put
you know fetal vertical mod you know
turn it on
so show configuration you know i did
that overview of history of i complete
and i switch and i do and fido okay
uh
okay so i complete is pretty old you
know let me show you guys you know so
let's do
uh
meta i mean control h f
describe function
and type i complete
i-c-o-m-m-o
okay there it is
then switch
the cursor to the pen
tab
and enter to jump to the source code
expand the pen
so we are on the in the source code of i
complete go to the top now you can see
the history you know it's good to look
at the source coding you know now and
then gradually your learn more emac this
you know it's fun you know when you
look around the emacs you know community
the emacs culture or the emacs code
you know the emacs philosophy so you
know it's good to sometimes to look at
the source code so gradually you'll pick
up more uh how to how to or you know
useful tips about emacs so you are
looking at the i complete
source code so in the beginning you can
see it begin in 1992
and it's written by this guy
you know in my in my past
20 years of using emacs especially in
the last
15 years i sometimes look up people you
know so you have to
thank them you know
most emacs users you don't know who
wrote what
all you know is richard stroman okay he
hasn't been coding he hasn't he hasn't
coded for 10 plus for 15 years more
likely 20 years
but you have so it's a good thing to
know
who are writing these you know great
features you know
so i compete begin in 1992 and written
by this guy then you can look up you
know look up
uh mod you know you can pay me and get
that package so you you can look up
oh so he this guy is on wikipedia is he
oh well
i didn't know this you know sometimes i
look up people so you know you learn
you know your community you know what
they did
so ken
manheimer has been a prominent software
developer for soap and glue mailman okay
that's asian you know software that's
1990s
zop and gnu mailman who works for nist
and baba
and spider oak okay
he's been listed by guido van rossum the
creator of guido
together with barry warsaw
as the probable inventor of the term
benevolent dictator for life ah that's a
that's a jargon from the
you know hacker community banana
dictator for life so anyway that's
interesting so you know and also you can
sometimes go to their home page you know
okay so he works for government some
yeah so anyway that's interesting you
know so
i complete begin in 1992
of course over the years you know he
essentially donated and signed over you
have to sign give the rights to free
software foundation you know then
over the years free software foundation
you know developed more of it you know
like today now it's massively expanded
starting in ex-28 fantastic
so and also let me tell you how does it
work okay
so this i complete you know and i
complete vertical and fido mod and fido
vertical mod
actually they don't do actually they
don't do much
i mean the the change in emacs 28 all
the great features is actually not
not much in this file you know all these
all these minor mods they are actually
just changing
the
you know when you call you know video
mod or when you call i complete mod or
when you call fido vertical they are
actually just setting up
you know changing some variables of them
for the mini buffer
configuration so let me show you okay so
let's describe
function let's say feeder vertical okay
so okay let's go there
and
tap jump to the code so you can see the
definition of the feeder vertical mod
you see now you look at that it's only
four lines you know only four lines
you know
what what you know you might think what
kind of magic oh it must be a lot of
code you know to great feature right
but it's only four lines you know so it
basically
so when you turn it on it basically all
it does is just turn on video mod
okay right that's all it does it just
turns video mod
then
it turns on i complete vertical mod
so that's why i say it's kind of
confusing you know you think you might
think they are all different but
actually they are
just i complete
so it just only does it turn on video
mod and turn on i complete vertical mod
then you might go look into what does
feeder mod do exactly okay so let's
uh let's um
so let's go to fidomar describe function
fidomar let's jump to it let's jump to
the source code
there it is fido mod okay it's only five
lines you know
seven lines so what does it do
well it
it first of all turn off i complete mod
then turn it back on
then
set two hooks that's it that's it it
just set two hooks ad hook
ad hook mini buffer setup hook
then
then call this function you know i
complete mini buffer setup then another
hook you know i complete fiddle mask
setup you see so now
in order to trace how it works now we
have to look at these two functions you
know what exactly they do
to make this rich feature so for example
let's let's look up this function i
completely feed all my setup okay
uh do it do it there it is let's jump to
the code the source code let's jump to
the definition there it is
there it is not many lines you know 20
lines so i complete fetal mod setup so
what does does it do so it uh
you know
there it is change you know set local
set set queue local change one bunch of
variables exchange set the variable i
complete tidy shadow file names true i
complete shadow matches
um no input true i complete height
command prefix nio
i complete scroll something something
i complete completion style this is
important line okay completion style set
it to flex you see so when you turn
feeder mod this is this is the critical
thing
it
it it sets the variable completion style
to flex
that's that what makes fido different
from i complete okay
then other setup you see
so this whole file you know i went
through this whole file you know there's
actually no
like
core machinery to to do this completion
so
so the code machine machinery happens
somewhere else happens in those
variables you know they um
basically they happen in some other
functions you know
who which
takes you know new variable values okay
so that's essentially you know i haven't
looked into in details yet but that's
the
how things are
okay that's it i think that's it for
today anything else
okay so far so good you guys like it any
comments and questions and that's it for
today
okay video check audio check and uh yeah
so
yeah okay so let's shut down in five
more minutes okay we talked yeah
shut down in five more minutes uh now
i'm gonna
you know wrap up let's see what else is
interesting so in you know emax28
fantastic
and
let's go to um
xr emacs mod i mean xr emax
this distribution you know exa emax a
complete emax distribution
with all my packages you know look uh so
these are all the all the packages i use
nothing else
so for example
i can show you my emacs init
you see
you now with emacs 28
is you know you can show you know type
version you can see in the mini buffer
emacs 28 or go to the message buffer
emax28 right so
uh what i want to say so like yeah let's
go to bookmark you know i have a command
called open bookmark mark fast so you
see even in bookmark prompt it also you
know uh uses the feed of
uh
completion feature
fantastic so now let's just type
init so let's go to my emacs init just
two lines so let's so the first
line of my init is load emacs
okay
but if we jump to diet jump to my emacs
init directory
you can see let's open elpa that's
nothing you know so i'm i i have reached
the a point where i'm using no
no external packages
well except actually uh there's one i
still use
which is well one of them is
the log you know the command log you are
looking at the pink window and the other
one is html
okay but anyway let's go to
emacs
config okay
uh what
so emacs can fit and go to direct so
this is
emacs distro
okay so
and go to the packages this is all my
packages so that's what i use
okay so the other external package i use
is this html lice which allows me to
syntax color programming source code
computer language source code in html
okay
but
um you know i'm i'm i'm going to switch
to javascript based solution because
because otherwise the source code in
html is impossible to read
so anyway so
emacs distro okay so if you like my
stuff you go to my website you can you
know get it you know you have to pay
uh it's open source of course
and so with emacs 28 you know i did a
lot
uh changes so right now they don't you
know they used to use i do mod i do mod
it's fantastic but now you don't need it
anymore so this
so you just rely on fido vertical
fantastic
and also now the
the universal
the universal leader key for all my
packages you know
css smart
direct
uh
emac this mod
start find
flat keys sapphire keys and golan mod
html mod all the javascript mod od smart
now they
they universally support the same leader
key and that key has been changed to tab
which is fantastic
because recently you know i've been
using this 60
keyboard let me put a plug to this
keyboard okay so you go to normal
i did i did a review of this keyboard
uh two three weeks ago
uh they sent it to me for review
i
gave you my honest review so i've been
using this keyboard when i'm lying in
bed which is right there you know the
keyboard is right there so
so i've been using this 60 keyboard
you know one of the problem with 60
keyboard is that you don't have much
keys you know
so i started to use tab as a little
leader key which is fantastic you know
because a lot of people especially when
you are on a laptop you know it's very
common like vast majority of people are
using a laptop
and then on a laptop you usually don't
have function keys i mean the function
keys is set to
volume up volume down and so on
so
so the so the use of tab key as a leader
key is a great idea so now all my
packages does that
and this
keyboard let me you know plug
for them is great okay key move
not expensive okay you know you know
it's it's cheaper than logitech but it's
fantastic i had i had you know i enjoyed
it very much it's
very
high quality build okay i like it
okay that's it
bye guys so
so there's a question what's the
difference between set q and set local
okay that's a bit technical so set q is
you know just normal setting a variable
okay
in summary in short okay now set local
is to
make
a variable to be buffer local
okay so let me explain what does this
mean so in emacs
you know and
you know you have variables you know
variables you know you can have a value
and
normally
[Music]
just like programming languages a
variable is global
okay but in emacs you have the concept
of buffer local meaning that the same
variable name
can have different value
for each buffer so every buffer
the same variable name they will have
their own values so it may be the same
with or maybe different you know so
that's
the buffer local variable okay now in
e-max some variables
are buffer local but not all of them
summer variables are global
so
sometimes you want to
set a variable
in a buffer just for that buffer only
but but that variable is not a buffer
local variable
that is when
you want to use the set q local
so when you use set q local it it forces
that variable to become buffer local to
this buffer only you know
okay that's that's what that is
uh y e max over vim okay that's that's a
common question i'm not gonna explain
okay exactly so luis explain that set
local good
okay that's it
thank you guys for watching bye guys
uh
what are your thoughts on tmox my whole
dev workflow is vim and tmux okay that's
that's good for you
tmux yeah if you are using if you are a
vim user
then god you need tmux without tmux
you become a you know if you're
a veeam user t-mux
they have to go hand-in-hand if you are
a vim user you need t-mux and you also
need the entire
unix tool shell bag you know bash and
find and xox and
you know you need that grab
sort
uh you know
that's a veeam workflow you
kind of componentize you know you need
all these tools
but if you are using emacs typically you
don't need tmux you can if you want to
but you could
you know log into remote computers
without you needing tmux you know
and so on many many different ways and
ssh within emacs i can do it now okay so
ssh
or not ssh so for example okay cancel
term okay so you start a terminal
emulator okay
oh god um program
okay it's because i'm on windows so it's
telling me to run what kind of terminal
application
wait
cancel i think term is should be built
in emacs
turn mod there
okay term mod
uh arrow menu bar update hook uh i don't
know what's going on i haven't
you know called that command
close
wait not turn mod just term okay
it asks me which terminal
program oh yeah that right so actually
it's built in on windows you see
you see let me show you the file path
okay so let's see i don't know if you
can see so you can see
it's actually part of emacs 28 on
windows this is critical because
normally on windows you are screwed but
now it's built building so let's do
let's just run it let's see what happens
arrow
uh arrow in menu bar update hook okay
okay that doesn't work so anyway term so
in emacs if you are e-mail user this you
have lots of ways you don't need t-mucks
okay that's it for today i just gonna
read uh one more minutes comments and
that's it scarface
scarface great to see you pro justin a
mathematician from canada
um
nelson okay
moving emacs covered okay yeah maybe
that's too late
uh okay
um
fantastic so if you have bought my stuff
fantastic
i