good morning my friends welcome to
another episode of Santos show and we
are going to show you today one of the
most idiotic thing in programming
industry program industry standards so
I'm going to wait a little bit for
people to come on so meanwhile I'm going
to I'm going to do a little screen shot
so what I'm going to show you is this
SVG path elliptical path and let's see
let's try let's do a screen shot okay
one second
now I'm gonna I'm going to show you why
this is the most idiotic thing you know
in the programming industry I'm going to
talk about why you know in programming
industry if you are a programmer and if
you have let's say ten years experience
you know you've been there well I guess
most of you are not there because
experienced programmers usually they
don't go you know online and watch stuff
anyway so the if you are a programmer
you know you've been in the industry for
a while you know that every day you have
programming languages protocols
standards they are often the most
idiotic you know a lot lots of problems
and issues and the reason you know I
I've been programming for over twenty
years and the reason so I realized in
recent years the reason is that it's
just because corporations and I realized
that it it's likely that programming
languages or protocols they will never
be clean
usually okay this is not all because for
example go line is pretty good you know
JavaScript is extremely bad the web
technologies are extremely bad HTML CSS
fairly lousy extremely bad especially
html5 you know and also if you program
in c unix linux they are extremely bad
you know like so like you see
programmers complaining all the time and
you see you know like you go to stack
overflow and you have millions of
questions or these weird problems that
people can now solve so you know we have
that experience and i'm going to show
you today one example of white one
example of that okay but but first of
all let me get the screenshot okay and
it's c welcome so let's do a screenshot
and screenshot javascript mod okay close
that i'm going to do a screenshot here
let's see if that's it yeah so I'm gonna
try that and go here yeah forget about
the screenshot I'm just going to show
you okay a DVD screenshot I'm just going
to show you about the Elise okay so what
what is the issues let me show you a let
me let me drag it here so what is the
problem the problem is in SVG you know
SVG allows you to draw graphics in HTML
basically you use JavaScript to draw
graphics for example let's let me show
you here
you see you have this clock and that is
turning JavaScript and the code is right
here
it's about hundred lines so it's not too
bad you know
but suppose so you have a circle here
you can you can draw a circle easy but
suppose I want to draw a pie pie chart
you know an arc of a circle now that
turns out to be extremely difficult to
do what you have to do is you know there
is no let me show you some of the basic
SVG okay let me it's for the screen here
so you can see
SVG basic examples okay so I need to
drag it over here more okay so here are
some examples of how you do SVG SVG is
just HTML
I mean XML syntax file so you put this
you create a HTML page then you put this
this there and you'll see a line so
basically you have the SVG tag you know
saying you know create the SVG tag then
you put this you create this line tag
that says you know starting point and
end point and you have a line so this is
the basics of SVG you can learn in five
minutes
so you have this line tag then you have
rectangle attack you know to create the
rectangle you have then you have a
circle tag you specify for example you
specify the center X&Y then you specify
the radius okay and in the same way you
can specify Lisp just by adding you know
with the radius attribute and in the
same way you can create a polygon text
and path and so on so that that is the
basics of SVG you know you just it's
just the XML you know it's just static
XML like like this you know you just
copy and paste this into a file and show
in browser and you'll create a image
graphics now however you see so these
are the primitives you know what what
you might call graphics primitives you
have rectangle lie circle a lisp polygon
text and path that that's basically it
okay and but however what if you want
to draw an arc of a circle you know like
a pie chart you know like an arc you
know a quarter of a circle or half of a
circle and what you have to do for that
is you have to use this path primitive
the path element path
tag so this path tag this path tag is
very powerful in general and it's fairly
complicated to understand so and easy so
I would say it's actually not good not
well-designed
you know because it's rather extremely
complex so what you do is you specify
this path and give a attribute D now D
means Steve essentially is a list of
points okay D mean means data yeah so so
you can see this you know to create this
zigzag the syntax for the path is that
okay it means starting at zero zero then
draw a line 250 0 which is the
coordinate you know then draw a line to
0 50 which is here then draw a line to
1990 which is here so we have a zag
zigzag then in path the stroke style and
there you know so there are some
variations such as how do you not draw
from some point to some point you know
creating a gap or how do you close the
gap from the last point to the first
point you know things like that but also
path is also powerful in that it can
draw curves like that so so one one of
the use of path is to draw elliptical
arc like this you know showing this page
and and the way you do that is you use
the a syntax you know when you have a
capital A that means you know that
section of the parameters for a data
attribute are parameters for drawing a
lisp but this is extremely complicated
so you can read you know the parameter
the meaning of the parameters here they
are very complicated
I'm not to go over them but what I'm
saying is that the morning George
good morning from to Australia what I'm
saying is that so to create a part of a
circle an arc of a circle there is no
option except to use this path element
and the path elements parameters are
defined in such a way
it's totally incomprehensible
it's like incredibly bizarre so it was
so so let me actually explain what what
this path means okay yeah okay so so
this parameter so you start with an A
Ami's you know the the rest one two
three four five six the rest you know
six numbers following a are the
parameters for the Elise and the first
two is x RX r RX r y the first two
numbers means the major radius in minor
radius of an ellipse so first of all so
what does I mean well to understand that
you have to understand about it Lisp a
little bit so you know here we have so
here is an example of a lisp so from
here to here
you know from here to here this length
is a major axis and the shorter axis is
the minor axis so basically to specify
an Elise you have two parameters one is
the length of the major axis or semi
major axis and the one the other one is
the shorter semi minor axis that's what
it's called so basically you have two
radiuses good morning
Isaac yeah early today so I'm going to
talk about this extremely convoluted
bizarre thing about how to draw a arc a
circular circular arc in SVG and as we
the reason I'm talking about that is
because this is an example of the
extreme idiotic I mean there's no excuse
it for it this is an example of the
extreme idiocy in in tech standards in
you know in software standards protocol
standards that we have for some reason
you know you know so this is an example
let me finish explaining that so so so
to specify a elyse mathematically
basically you just have like two
radiuses you specify the center you know
the location of the center and two
radius for the Lisp major axis in minor
axis okay that's one way that's one of
the simple way to specify an Elise you
know that's a intuitive in a simple way
there are many other ways to specify an
Lisp you know but we are now going to
that going to go into that so back to
the SVG so the way you specify the way
the SVG specify any list is by using the
path element and the way that works
that you you you write capital a with us
one two three four one with seven
numbers following that one two three
four five six seven yeah seven numbers
following that so the first two numbers
are the major and minor axis you know
the radius the distance okay the third
element is rotate it's a degree you know
how much you want to eby's that the
whole thing to be rotated okay then you
have two flags you know kind of code
flags they are large OCH flag and sweep
hog flags we are sweep flag they are
extremely complicated to understand they
are not by the way they are not used
anywhere in math okay there they are
just created by this program
programmers okay so what what are they
what what are these large arc flag and
sweep flag both of them should be values
of 1 or 0 okay so they just end up
indicate kind of like you know two
options 1 or 0 and what they are is
actually let me show you it's like this
you see they specified for of the
possibilities of which part of the Elise
to draw from a starting point to the end
point ok now but how exactly what does
what does it mean exactly it's very
complicated ok but I'm going to explain
let me go back here
so SVG so you have these parameters okay
Flags two flags then you have XY the
last two numbers means the point you
want the end point you want to finish
the drawing - okay so let me repeat so
Elise you have like seven
to service as parameters the first to
number is the major in minor axis then
you have a rotation which is a you know
how much you want to rotate then you
have two numbers for flag you know then
you have two numbers for the last point
to draw now what about the starting
point the starting point is basically
where the current point is you know it's
when you have a path you know for
example in this path we began at at this
point zero 50 so Oh
at this point 10 50 so 10.10 50 is this
point right here so that's not the
starting point is not part of the Lisp
parameter so anyway you you start at the
current point whatever that is you know
before the release parameter then you
have these seven seven numbers to
specify the release the Lisp now the you
see so here is an example and here is
the other examples this these are
examples showing rotation and more
variations but now the problem is if you
want to draw let's say a quarter of a
circle you know like like this clock
from twelve o'clock to 3 o'clock a
quarter of a circle okay how do you do
that basically is you cannot do that
because first of all there is no
primitive that just specify a circle a
part of a circle there is a primitive to
specify a circle for example like that
you know you you say circle then you say
the center CX and CY and you say radius
but however there is no attribute for
you know how much how much you want to
draw you can just own
draw the whole circle so and so but you
want to draw a part of a circle like you
know a quarter of a circle so how do you
do that the only way to do that is to
use usually elite elliptical arc so
suppose you want to draw a circle from
12 o'clock to 3 o'clock okay and the
only way to do that is you to use the
pass with the elite elliptical arc
parameters okay but how do you specify
the parameters like what what numbers do
you put them you know that is the
problem that is the question you know
drawing part of the circle is extremely
common for example young up you know pie
chart you know what one of the most
useful thing in graphics is pie chart
you know one of the most common but
however so you want to draw that but how
do you do that you know that is the
question and the the solution is
basically it's impossible to figure out
I mean it's you have to almost be you're
a mathematician you know so that is a
problem okay that that is a father I'm
talking about you know you might try try
it you know you have to do like like I
showed before you have to do is you copy
you know you copy this into copy paste
into a file and showing browser then you
try to put the path element you know try
to experiment you know I guarantee you
that you are going to spend several
hours to to draw a arc of a circle and
that's the problem and yeah and you know
unless you go to stack overflow in fact
you cannot you know spend an hour just
to read stack overflow of solutions so
that is a problem so the situation is
that we have a common needed thing you
know drawing part of the circle but
however in this technology
you know SVG technology it is almost
like impossible you know it is almost
impossible so so do you guys get what
I'm saying
so this situation is someone is almost
impossible now I'm going to show you
almost impossible okay so this is this
is a extreme idiocy you know like and
this is one example this is one concrete
example so I'm going to show you next
how the specification how they talked
about this issue
so here is the speck on a second I mean
turn on let's go to their website SVG
spec
so we're going to go to SVG spec and
basic types and interface you know these
specifications are extremely convoluted
the way the style they write it it's
impossible to read and it is not because
it is actually difficult no is it
because it's written for in fluent
implementers you know those browsers you
know who needs to implement this it's
not because of that it's really big just
because they are is they're extremely
convoluted because because corporations
in the standard body made it that way
almost like intentionally they this
extremely impossible to read you know
try to read it you know you try it for
example you try you know you can try to
read my SVG tutorial you know you spend
on our and you can pretty much
understand what it you know how to work
with this then you try to read the SVG
spec you know it's going to take you a
month you know even a month yeah it's
going to take you full time a month and
you cannot understand it that's the way
they are and what I'm saying about this
is that it's not necesarily it's it's
not that way because it's necessary it's
that way because because social many of
the social reasons there are
corporations and standard bodies
standard body they are there because of
money you know for no reason other than
then money they are usually a nonprofit
organization but it's not why it seems
so anyway so the other so the point I'm
trying to make here is about all these
documentation from you know the
specifications from the standard body
the
extremely bad battered Wheaton so that's
a digression into another point but
let's get back to the Elise to draw an
arc so let me show you the document
structure dome interface styling
SVG Tom over views as Dom interface
okay Dom interface based basic data
types rendering model
document structure
geometric properties coordinate systems
my god where is it okay finally okay so
finally they are here so here are the
basic shapes and here is the path
element ok path element is what we want
and here we have elliptical arc curve
commands ok so here is the respect for
the Lisp parameters we were talking
about
you see you see this SVG too you know so
you know SVG 2 came out about last year
last year two years ago the SVG one or
one point one came out about twenty
years ago it didn't catch on because the
flash you know you know the marker media
Adobe Flash they took over the industry
you know the those are commercial
technology but the flash got killed by
Apple beginning around 2006 also because
of the iPhone you know Steve Jobs
basically banned it
all right iPhone so that that subsequent
we killed it so fresh you know the flash
technology is gonna fetch
technology is basically 2d drawings
pretty much like like SVG so since flash
was killed beginning around 2008 so SVG
revived so today you know we use SVG so
SVG version 2 came out about lasya
finalized and we are looking at SVG two
right now and you can see they have a
comment here annotation SVG 2
requirement make it simpler to draw arcs
in SVG path syntax so you see they
actually realized this is a problem but
however they did not they did not
provide a solution you know I didn't
read this page through early yet but
anyway I you know the way you know they
don't have a solution so far it's
actually only you're just a note no
draft ok draft November 2011
and this this page is basically chat
among the SVG standard writers you know
they just chat about it so they have a
notice about make it simpler to draw an
arc in SVG path syntax but it's not done
you know we don't have that yet but
anyway let's go back to the you know the
the thing I want to show you on this
page is that they actually have a
section that talks about how to how do
you convert parameters let me show you
where
you know these extremely idiotic
writings implementation notes
okay sit somewhere here
so I'm going to show you where is it so
view example okay so I'm going to show
you a section in this SPECT where they
talked about how do you convert an
ellipse from the parameters of a center
and major minor axis to the parameters
used by the path syntax
okay here you see there's this note here
the implementation notes appendix has
relevant formulae for software that
needs to convert SVG arc notation to a
format that uses center points and arc
sweeps extreme idiocy so so here it is
it's an append appendix p2
so what's going on here
okay so here it is so on this page so so
here they show you they talk about the
mathematical formula where where for
example normally when we you know in
math you know in anywhere when we talk
about a lisp we specify it by the center
and the major and minor axis you know
then then possibly a rotation you know
you rotate the holy Lisp and also the
parameters to specify the starting point
and end point like how much of a sweep
you want oh it can be specified in as a
degree you know that's that's how people
you know think of it Lisp that's how you
specify it but however the SVG the SVG
way of specifying a lisp is you have
this you know sweep large arc flag sweep
flag and XY is the end point so you
basically you specify it by a starting
point and end point and with this you
know two boolean values for which part
it is so high Andrew so anyway so so so
on this specification page they are
trying to explain how do you convert
from one set of parameters to the other
okay so if you are a programmer if you
are going to draw a pie chart you know
if you are going to create SVG graphics
you need arc of a circle then you need
to do you need to know this formula you
know what you do is you look at this
formula and you
the function that tries to convert it
there's not no way around it because it
is impossible to you know like it's
impossible to understand to directly
specify an arc you know by these path
parameters so anyway that that is a
situation and and let me show you
something else the point I'm showing you
so anyway in this appendix P they talk
about how to how to convert one to the
other but what is the point I mean I
mean you see this is such a common need
when you design the SVG you do not
design you know you it's like nobody
ever you know no mathematicians you know
this the way this days define a list by
this parameter of using the starting
starting point and end point and these
flags that does not happen in anywhere
you know I don't think it happens in
history I mean if you like if you take a
survey okay
suppose if you are God and you look at
all exists you know literature's text
books on Elysee you know all the math
books you will not find one is I don't
think you will find one instance where
they specify a lisp by this way by this
SVG way you know we you have a starting
point you have end point and you have
these two pooling flags
then you have this then you have a
rotation you know you will not find it
so this so this is a extreme idiocy and
you know I'd like like I work in forum
industry I have looked at a lot of
technologies you know lots of protocols
computer languages and it's very ease is
fairly common to find this kind of very
strange impossible things you know
you know simply idiotic things and I
began to understand the way they are
that way is just because corporations
you know they they are not they are not
based on design I mean it's not like
someone you know some programmers sit
there and they think about design and
they can't come up with this way or
maybe they come up with a way that's bad
you know by mistake no it's not like
that
that's what we normally think how these
these standards or specification came
about but I realize in in the past few
years that's not a case the way standard
date you know this standard standardized
spec came up out is mostly due to social
reasons like cooperate cooperate
struggles and incompetence and and
basically irrelevance and you know of
these designers so hi Andrew Georgie and
Isaac so yeah so hi guys so if you want
me to you know just post your comments
if you want me to talk about anything
you know just say it you know any
opinions or questions or anything I'm
talking about or anything else you know
about keyboards or anything so anyway
back to e list so so you know I'm
showing you an example and look at this
the paragraph they try to explain you
know they say look at the way they the
reason the pretext the excuse they give
they they say here about why they design
they design the release the way they are
okay let's see what they say so they say
to be consistent with other path
segments notation arcs in SVG paths are
defined in terms of start and end points
on the curve okay this parameterization
of elliptical arcs we
be referred to as endpoint
parameterization one of the advantage of
endpoint parameterization is that it
permits a consistent path syntax in
which all path commands ends and in the
coordinates of the new current point
however this is not the only way of
describing arc geometry used in software
or mathematics this section describes
the alternative Center parameterization
and how to convert it from and to SVG
endpoint parameterization so what they
are saying is that what they are saying
is that the way the reason they are they
that you know the SVG Lisp is defined
that way is because it's because it's
more consistent with me path you know
the path parameters the way they you
know the path element is defined that's
that's I think I think that's not true I
think that's a lie
you know I think this paragraph is not
the true history is you know I I don't
know for sure because I have not dig
into the history of you know who like
which or engineer you know
exactly what is a history how how did
the SVG path element came about you know
who is the first person who created this
I have not looked into that you know and
also in my past experience it's almost
impossible it's extremely difficult to
find how things are in the beginning you
know it's it's like a research task for
a month something like that for a week
week or weeks so I don't know what's a
true history but I do have a sense of
why you know because of my experiences
in researching this kind of thing and
for my experience I think this paragraph
is just lie it's not true it's just you
know someone you know working on the
standard they just write you know they
just think
no they just came up with a you know
excuse you know that seems logically
reasonable but I don't think that is
true so that's one thing and also they
say that you know look at the way they
say it you know however this is not the
only way of describing arc geometry used
in software your mathematics that's
completely idiotic that's completely
that that indicates you know the above
paragraph is just a lie lie you know
because you know they say however this
is not the only way of describing arc
arc geometry using software or math what
what the does that mean
because in math I can tell you of you
know directly the way you you describe
Italy aliefs
you know at least by starting point in
point and arc that does not exist okay
now you know basically if you look at
you know like eyes you know you look at
all the math textbooks that almost
doesn't exist I mean you may as possible
to find you know one such instance like
one one one in ten thousand textbooks
you might find it but it's practically
never exist no mathematician describes
Elise ellipse in that way but but
however look at the way they say it you
know however this is not the only way of
something something it seems to imply
that you know both way are common you
know they are they are saying this is
not the only way they are the other way
it's a you know it's false it's
not that's not the only way it's you
know the way you are doing it it's like
Impa it's doesn't exist
you yourself the SVG spec cooked it up
nobody ever did it you know does it
so anyway that that is about this
Elise thing I hope you know I hope I
conveyed my you know my opinion about
this
so in summary let me just summarize it
let me just summarize is this what I'm
talking about today so why is that I
showed you how to create a circular arc
or elliptical arc in SVG okay I also I
talked about you know I give you a basic
introduction to SVG so that's one thing
the other thing is how convoluted is the
way to draw an electrical arc in SVG
okay the third thing is that this SVG
spec is in fact extremely idiotic and it
reflects it is actually a common
industrial phenomenon in programming
where the standard SPECT or protocols
they are they are out of touch with
reality they have nothing to do with you
know they are not actually like designed
by a programmer they they are a result
of some kind of cooperate struggle and
evolution you know that's why we have
this bunch of garbage okay yeah that's
what I'm saying about that topic today
so and Rudy says in university right now
how do I get the most out of it to be a
good programmer instead of just another
code monkey that's very broad question
like you know it's very broad question
like depending
who you are like what where are you in
University in USA oh you know elsewhere
and so I suppose you are majoring in
programming like computer science and
also what year what you are you in
university like a freshman first year
second year third year fourth year so
okay so let me just make a general
comment okay Oh computer science in
Australia okay
here's I what I recommend okay it
actually depends on people on you you
know on people because you know it I
can't you know it's it's hard to give a
generic recommendation or guide to
people when you don't know the people
because people differ a lot I mean like
I have no idea what you look like you
know what's your background you know
your family your age even you know
because it's different for for example
if you are 30 years old and you are in
college to maybe pick up computer
science pick up a degree and it's also
you know different from if you are say
18 or 20 you know in university and also
depends on your background so it is hard
to make a generalized recommendation but
here's what I generally okay I think if
you want to be a programmer you know if
being a professional programmer you know
make money by programming is your goal
you know if that's what you want to be
which is a very good goal I recommend
that you know go to be a programmer you
know job and that gives you that earn
see you money you know a programmer is a
good job you know it's also has a future
you know in in the next 10 years or 20
years it's a good a very good job okay
so that's a good thing to do you know to
be a programmer and so first of all you
know you might do that so but but then
that I do I actually do not recommend
going into a university to do that I you
know it depends on people of course but
if you have any increment you know if
you have what it takes I mean if you are
the type who can study on your own for
example because you are very interested
in programming in computers or maybe
video games you know you you stick on
with computers all day you know if you
are that type and you have no problem
learning about the new programming
language then if you are that type then
I do not recommend you go to university
at all
don't go there instead you know try to
maybe possibly find an internship at
some company you know or something you
know get some little even a small pay
for for half a year
okay then just switch jobs and you know
talk you know negotiate you negotiate
you Sookie you know talk and switch shop
and get a lot more money like twice you
know like you know after year you you
you know Google Google will hire hire
you if you are really interested in
programming you can do it you know just
learning it by yourself after year -
Google will hire you even as an intern
you know even as an intern you earn a
lot money at Google for example I mean
not just Google but Facebook Microsoft
they are endless you know jobs you know
for you
the key point is is is about new
negotiating your salary and you know be
competent I mean I mean I'm talking
about it depends on you of course I mean
depending on a person for example I'm a
nerd and most nerd people are not so
good at when you know doing interviews
you talk you
you know you are not confident and maybe
you think you are not great so you don't
ask for much money so that's a issue but
you can you can walk on that so but
basically don't be afraid you know it's
just for yourself that's really a good
you know and ask big money for it you
know I'll ask more than what you would
expect
that's and and stick with it you know
it's not like oh maybe I'm not good you
know really for my experience you know
you just you know you know like pretend
pretend for you for a moment when you
are doing interviews pretend for a
moment that you are salesmen you know
thank you are these smooth-talking sales
salesmen forget about everything else
you know just you just talk them talk
fancy talks but meanwhile I'll be
yourself that's an important key be
yourself meaning you know you stick with
you know you know you just go there hi
I'm a nerd you know if you feel like
that I just say that you know I'm a nerd
I know these things but no I think I
should have you know $10,000 $20,000
something you know just you know yeah
yeah be competent be competent you know
that's that's what you have to do of
course the exactly what to say and how
it applies what do you mean by competent
that's up to each person so I know I
don't know what you are like so you know
I don't know if that applies but anyway
so I recommend you know to be a
programmer as a profession I do
recommend that you know and also
eventually you know after 10 years you
know you might open your own company you
know you're you happen if you you know
so a programmer I recommend you know
doing that a professional programmer and
and I do not actually recommend going to
college for it you know for a programmer
you can you can do it and you can do it
more efficiently than going to a college
if you are the type that you know you
are interested in programming you are
interested in computers and you don't
really have a problem learning stuff on
your own you know but if you are the
type who you know like most people who
prefer to have social interaction you
know with other people other students or
go to a class where you learn things
together you know then maybe you go to
university you know that's no problem
with that yeah the other thing is that
actually if you go to university I
actually I recommend that you study math
instead instead instead of computer
programming because math is the thing
that gets you seriously into many
important thoughts you know that's
permanent you know you know math don't
go away and everything you learn in math
stays they don't go away because math
theories are theories they don't change
a supposed to computer science stuff
like when you go to a college university
to study computer science most of the
time or more than half of the courses
you are taking they are not actually
computer science proper they are not
pure computer science they are not
theoretical computer science as far as I
know actually actually tell me what you
are learning you know yeah type it out
show me what what are the classes they
are teaching at University but as far as
I know what they are teaching is like
half of the courses you are learning are
actually just ephemeral like current
technologies you know they change they
come and go you know this year is good
after five years it's it's useless it's
kind of outdated
you know
so that's a that's my opinion about that
so are you guys still here George George
and Isaac and Andrew so what's up George
so I guys give me some feedback George
so what do you up to like and how old
are you like in like in general like in
your 20s 30 so like do you guys like my
talk show do you do you want it to be
more programming stuff or non technical
stuff or non technical stuff so I'm
drinking my energy drink this is like
red red paw but some nameless brand and
here is grape juice
Andrew are you still there
so anyway okay yeah so so what do you
think what I just said about the going
going to university does that make sense
to you or does that strange oh I mean
like you know yeah there is a delay
that's yeah this I think five seconds to
sent ten seconds it's I don't know yeah
so I mean tell me about the university
like that's why I say apply to you or
does it you know I give me some comments
because I have no idea because because
you know is this this this is a problem
that happens often because when you are
watching me or when you read my website
everything is clear to you because you
know especially if you are watching me
you know you see me you know that
conveys lots of things my clothing my
face you know Mike it conveys my age the
way I talk it tells you a lot of things
and you can you know so you a lot you
you you know you guys know me but like
but I have no idea like what you are
like you know like like imagine imagine
you know Andrew George and Isaac you
know imagine each one of you imagine
what's the other people like like it's a
plank I can you don't know and I have
people you know who are you know reading
my stuff some some some of them are
teenagers and some of them are like 50
or 60 years old you know who's been
programming in the industry and you know
different different people that is like
all walks of life
we're very interesting and strange
so Andrew say says I think I will fare
better in university because I walk
better among others okay and many faces
in Australia won't accept best in a high
degree oh I see
yeah that's yeah yeah I suppose so I
guess that's in Australia that's it's
interesting I have like people following
me in Australia like George you are also
in Australia right but by the way George
and Andrew you guys know each other
he's like did did you guys tell each
other to follow me or just by
happenstance so I think George is also
in Australia what city are you in
George is in Perth let's go look at
Australian because I always love to
Google G are you in Perth there's a
country named Perth Google Maps wait I
don't want Google Maps Australia
oh okay so Perth Perth seems like a big
city because I know actually all the
people I know you Australia from Perth I
think I knew a girl from Perth she is
amazing let's see Perth oh yeah so the
other big city is Brisbane I guess
Brisbane in Sydney
yeah so let's see Google Maps yeah
Google map is always just fascinating
okay so yeah I think George George is
also in Perth anyway let's see hold on
second so
you know in over here in San Francisco
Bay Area in a Silicon Valley where
Google Facebook you know the big
companies basically in USA degree has
not big for programming okay for the
programming field degree has not become
important it has become not important
over here so you don't need a degree you
know just study computer science and
come to California actually a good one
is Scott so actually these days you know
program means a lot of it are done
remotely so you don't even need to be
you know you don't you know you can you
can stay in Perth and work for Google
well I actually I don't know if Google
anyway a lot of companies do that you
know remote working remotely and
actually I knows I know companies I
think quite a lot of them all their
employees are remote like they don't
have a office you know they just
good morning Scott
yeah so Scott gave a good recommendation
Scott says I would say for every
programming language construct made to
improve abstraction learn how it is
implemented
underneath Scott Scott is a low-level
system program programming in Z who has
to make everything as fast as possible
[Laughter]
Scott says otherwise some programmers
choose poorly when coding up an approach
then be sure you know how to profile for
memory and speed some knowledge is
assembly I think is the must god Scott
front-end programming which is the most
popular feel today they don't know they
don't require to know Co assembly or
anything remotely like that you know fun
in programming like they don't have to
know you know in fact to know how things
are implemented is a waste of time like
they they don't they do not have to know
that but however they need to spend
their time knowing all the frameworks
and libraries and stuff you know NPM and
stuff but you know assembly I think if
you study actually you you want a broad
understanding of programming and
practical computer science I think
assembly is essential like for myself
you know I know little about you know
yeah you know for myself I know very
detail about assembly or CPU or you know
the C programming language and I learned
a little bit you know in the past few
years and I really appreciated it
because I learned you know the CPU the
design of the CPU itself you know the
the instruction architecture said that's
what they call it is extremely complex
and it is in fact it's a science by
itself it's a it's a science and
mathematics and art by itself it's the
design of the CPU so you know I so I
don't know much about that in fact Scott
in fact I would actually I do have a lot
questions in that I you know you could
tell me you could you know answer my
questions yeah so the other thing I
think is important if you are study
programming is to me to me is just like
just do a lot programming try to write
you know try to create projects instead
of reading stuff like me you know I tend
to just read stuff you know I think you
just create projects create a lot
projects hello Otto so Scott says you
are writing for funny and you I yeah
oh so you did a lot and CPU design okay
well let me ask you daily star just to
ask you question then since it's since I
don't have you know any subject right
now so CPU so so in the past few years
you know we started to have GPU so you
know a lot you know people programs
these days they try to use GPU but
basically my question is you know let me
just say directly do my question is why
why isn't CPU designed like GPU in the
first phase is it because mostly because
historical reasons
I mean CPU you know the central
processing unit why can't they just be
designed like GPU you know in the first
phase is it because historical reasons
because so far you know as
I know the GPU design is mostly parallel
you know the architecture is like
parallel computing so GPUs are force
GPUs are focused on SIMD and data number
crunching s I'm SIMD stand for what
okay Skaar says but CPUs are optimized
for the random stuff that programmers
throw at it
oh I see
okay I think okay III think that gives
me some crew but of course you know I do
not fully understand let me go to a page
where I have some questions about that
oh okay yeah
si MD stand for a single instruction
multiple data single instruction
multiple data okay and GPUs are focused
on as I am the single instruction
multiple data number crunching okay okay
Scott actually I have a lot of more
questions to ask you it would be very
helpful to me actually so I have I have
some notes I wrote out when I try to
study CPU stuff and let me try to find
where are they
so how are you doing is Scott you are
backing right you are in the East Coast
right and it's almost 12 o'clock for you
syntax
so scott says imagine 512 threads of
execution or operating in parallel but
in lockstep right that's the GPU right
so another question I are just throw a
random question so why is that you know
today I think that many you know we I
think there is a push for parallel
actually architecture in CPUs for
example as far as I know the Intel X Co
n is designed for that I mean you know
they start to design it for parallel
computing but it didn't really catch up
so do you have any comments on that
because the way we are doing it today
the compilers is trying to you know the
compilers is actually trying to parallel
code and it's doing it very efficiently
because you know compilers are trying to
parallel sequential code you know from
like the C language so that's why we
have you know the the heart bug or
whatever I mean fine let me find the
article because then I can refer to it
here
not this one
Oh only limited problems like matrices
graphics are good fits for SIMD type
execution Oh one would never design word
processor to run on a GPU Oh what what
about something like mm what about
something like wait yeah but there is
this you know the you know I don't know
about these things so if I have a
student my question is stupid you know
just say so okay so so what about this
RISC architecture and this interaction
and you know the say Microsoft spark and
M IPS
those are like those are CPUs their
instruction set is designed to be
parallel right as opposed to the Intel
x86 you know it's because you know the
we have we you know Intel x86 is mostly
we have that because of historical
reasons you know you know because we
need compatibility as far as I know
therefore we today we have a situation
that the compilers is trying to convert
sequential code like C source code into
some kind they they try to turn it into
parallel program at the CPU level you
know doing things like speculative you
know speculative execution you know
doing things like that
and in turn it creates lots of
complexity and problems one example is
the
bleeding hearts that you know that CPU
bug so you know what I'm saying is that
as far as I know you know because of the
sequential you know because the sorry me
read Wisconsin's okay risk is easier to
implement and make it fast higher clock
rates and when you want to break down
risk and pipeline it then risk is easier
but when your instructions are complex
it can be more difficult to pipeline
okay I don't really quite get it by the
way Scott do you have any
recommendations for like books or some
websites for people who do not know CPU
or any of these GPUs stuff at all I
don't know I I do not quite understand
what pipelining means it's you know I
think it's breaking up instructions so
that so that the CPU can execute
something like that
break breaking you know computer
programming instructions into units that
that are the CPU units
okay think of car assembly line
so here is a book scott recommends hansi
Hennessey and Patterson Oh
computer architecture this book it looks
like they wrote more than one book
computer organization and design
computer architecture
I see pipeline so pipeline means why a
one-stage is doing one operation
the next is doing the next operation but
multiple cars are in the pipeline
like in a car assembly going okay right
yeah so anyway Scott let me ask you a
more general question that's what I
intended to ask I mean what I'm thinking
the the impression I get is that today's
CPU design or GPU or you know today's
situation of the hardware or CPU or GPU
what I think is that they are not they
are not optimal design I mean in the
sense that if we can start from scratch
it wouldn't be anything like what we
have today the way the way we have it
today is mostly due to historical you
know reasons like compatibility mostly
is that does that is is a statement
somewhat I mean can we say that's
correct or more or less or something
like that or totally wrong so x86 is
messy to be sure okay
MIP s arms SPARC are pretty clean
start what what about the newest book do
you recommend that the art of computer
programming because I think that book
teaches people about the CPU
architecture and assembly I mean it
teaches people about algorithms but in
terms of implementing them in you know
you know machines structure so do you
recommend the newest order for our other
programming book Oh for computer science
people they are good okay so but it's
not like it's less practical than the
Hennessy and parison I think
by the way Scott do you read any online
news websites hacker news or anything
like that
so for those of you don't know Scott
works for Scott is a experienced
programmer you know with 30 years or 40
years the experience and yeah tell us
Scott you had you know what do you work
for
what do you work on stuff
I'm a GPU designer for Qualcomm
Snapdragon chips that go in most mobile
mobile phones
okay and anything else I think maybe we
are done here because we've been talking
for 70 80 minutes oh I used to follow
hand canoes okay
anything else
Scott anything you want to say or you
want to tell us so does anyone has any
other questions if not we're gonna close
down I'm gonna shut down
okay Scott says I'll treat you later
later the video where a hardware blew
away auger with algorithmic algorithm
assumptions okay that would be great
thanks ago ago King says hexa shall I
get my uhk not so much for typing but
I'm not so yeah uhk the ultimate hacking
keyboard that's a great keyboard but
whether you should get it you know and
not for typing what do you mean I mean
it's one of the great I would say top
three okay something like top three
great keyboard in my opinion great
ergonomic keyboard so you know whether
you should get it you know whether
that's the right choice for you
that depends you know but it's I do
recommend that yes it's supposed support
marker so it's great yeah
oh it's ultimate hacking keyboard yes I
recommend it
Oh for making music okay in that case
now you might need another you know
extra programmable keyboard because the
ultimate hacking keyboard they do not
have many keys you know that's one of
the issue so yeah let me let me talk
about this keyboard for maybe five
minutes and I'll be it for today so if
we go to you know the automatic hacking
kibo it's fantastic I have a video
review you know you can watch it here
but however
it does not have full set of keys for
example it does not have function keys
you know there's no function keys if you
want to press function keys such as f2
you have to hold down one of the
modifier you know the FN you know but
it's Heidi program program programmable
so anyway one issue is that it does not
have many function keys so if you need
to do a lot keyboard macros for making
music you know you can you can program
lots of markers but for each mark well
you will need to have key combinations
and I don't like that I don't think
that's a good thing especially if you
need to do that often so so but but the
ultimate hacking key bow is still a
great keyboard to get what do you want
to do is you want to buy separately a
program programmable keypad such as such
as this one you know or this one
Oh or even or this one you know you you
want to buy or separate you know all
these are good you want to buy a
separate programmable keypad so that
gives you you know a whole bunch of
function keys okay Scott showed us the
video that talks about let's go to it
oops oops
yeah
so Scott showed us a video that
check
mio fly no okay I'm still alive okay
it's stupid Google one second let me get
that I have to wait for this
so this video is si
great I'll check this out I think that's
it for today so Sean says Sean says I've
got I got the yoga dogs and it's like
learning to ride a bike again
yeah those key words takes a while to
learn so Scott says I think this is the
video that shows how caches have made
arrays vectors often to be higher
performing then link twist
o in these conditions where you would
think this would be better that's
amazing that's that's a great you know
yeah that that is a great topic for me
because I always had this issue with
array you know with this especially
among these programmers they you know
they like least you know leagues least
as a as in linked lists but to me lists
linked list is just stupid okay
the cons especially the list cons
business you know the the cons car
cutter I think those those design in the
language are idiotic to the extreme so I
have this issue about Arava surfaces
you know linked lists its I'm glad to
see you know these tricky issues coming
up you know about that
kula Tron yeah so anyway that's it for
today you know I talked about for 19
minutes so thank you guys for coming so
I'm gonna shut down in 10 seconds yep
hi Scott bye guys