good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show
today is August 18th 2019 Sunday
California time greetings greetings
battle of MU and so today's topics so
battle amuses I choose four random okay
let's talk about random so who else is
here
battle new battle um you you are here
but youtube google tells me zero
watching so there is a conflict of
information so bathroom you are you here
still like type something oh there it is
so pariah warrior I'm okay with random
okay so a lot you know looks like people
like the random thing and random random
is actually easier to talk you know is
easy you know because I can just talk
random supposed to a tutorial which
tends to be it's hard to do you know you
you have to be fluent with the language
you know like you coded in the past
month or two every day and then then you
have to know the language very well then
you have to organize it you know in real
time you know since I'm not prepared
thing you have to then I have to like
stop you know you know you know you know
you know you know you know I have to
stop that and also when you talk about
some technical stuff like you know
JavaScript or go then people don't watch
it because when you talk about technical
detail especially like when I'm
if I'm going to talk about JavaScript
what you know order tech details of
JavaScript Watts you narrow your
audience like immediately to 20.1%
because few people actually you know
code that particular language I mean
first of all most people are not
programmers then you know you severely
limit your audience but also in that
audience you know for example JavaScript
Oh : or whatever that audience is
usually picky you know there's lots of
tutorials out there they they don't want
to you know if you talk about that they
think wanted to be really good so so all
things considered you know if you just
talk random it it is actually better
because then you have more audience you
know you look at all the YouTube stars
with millions of followers you look at
what they talk about every day they talk
about [ __ ] you know like drama oh this
this or that or you know online cameras
and stuff and there are typically
brainless but it's a show you know
that's what they do is they you know
they they talk about memes and funny
pictures and stuff okay so it's not talk
show and today is whatever it is and we
are so today's topic okay random and
today okay so when random we we gotta
start somewhere this is my index page
for talk show and okay so let's put this
here so random just anything random and
see random keyboard key key layout and
Unicode stuff hey Justin good morning
great to see you Justin Justin is from
Vancouver Canada and Justin is a Haskell
code and Scala code
hey guys so Justin any topics you are
interested just type it okay because
right now seems like people want to run
them today so we're just going to you
know I I guess I'll just visit you know
my oh my brats and start to talk about
some random things so this begin so any
any topic anything you find interesting
just type it then okay you know this
this Bitcoin you know Bitcoin is
something I think is tremendously
critical important you know it's in
society I mean not necessarily Bitcoin
specifically but you know in general the
cryptocurrency it's it's it's very
important not just important but it's
it's it's it it is going to change
society doesn't matter what's your
opinion you know even if you are
government or not doesn't matter it's
going to the society is going to change
you know sooner or later in five years
ten years it's gonna drastically change
you know like but some people might say
I mean the question is maybe actually it
will never happen but act actually so
that's a that's a main question we our
society you know the world adopt you
know cryptocurrencies sometimes in your
future so I think the question is not
whether it will happen it is how soon
will happen you know happen I'm talking
about adoption not like almost like
Universal you know it's kind of like
like that kind of thing not just
regional oh you know I'm on hackers or
you know among us you know of course
today most government they don't want
that and you know but this is something
you know Bitcoin you see this this thing
you know clicked cryptocurrency it's not
something you want or not it's there and
it's gonna it's out you know it's like
genie out of the bottle
it's like Internet is its unstart
unstoppable so it will happen
it's just a matter of like how soon five
years ten years you know and of course
right now it's already you know it's
already very extremely significant
already in terms of economy you know
people are doing things with it let's
see so so so yeah so since I'm doing
random chat I'm gonna read the comments
more often now if i if i am my voice
went away or something or something went
wrong say it right away okay so
sometimes i went on five minutes without
voice or something so let's yeah let's
look at the chat and so let's get back
to Bitcoin in a moment so let's see so
Justin says did you see there is a big
announcement tomorrow by a Bitcoin
creator no what is it
what announcement the real Satoshi
Nakamoto promised to unravel the mystery
of his truly Oh seeing it wow that that
that would be something thank you for
for that news I didn't know so keep an
eye keep an eye out on it yeah but it's
you know but but seeing and you know I
don't trust the end anything CIA's maybe
it's just another clickbait you know so
am i familiar with cryptocurrency that's
the thing you know I not really I know
it's basically like well I know the
basic concept how it works it's based on
this they basically blockchain okay let
me talk about maybe yeah I I think I
could be able to give a you know how it
works the basic concept you know because
a lot of people don't know you know I I
guess there are a lot of people still
don't know seeing a market what do you
mean seeing SEC and markets what do you
mean what's easy
sien oh-oh-oh not seeing NCCN what's CCN
market so cryptocurrency so basically
the idea is this so it's based on
blockchain okay so what is blockchain
you know I'm trying to explain this to
programmers so youyou can get a really
solid understanding what's the gist I
mean what what actually makes the whole
concept work but you know I but I don't
know the technique I'm not you know I I
am not even close to I I don't know the
tech details so in case you know you can
we really keep it here and so on
so anyway blockchain first of all
understand there is a hash function so
hash function you probably are familiar
basically hash function is a function so
you have a bunch of number you have a
number okay let's say your number and
you apply the function you know put a
number into the function and that the
function comes out another number now
the property the special property about
this hash function this function why
it's so critical is that the number that
it's impossible to find out what is the
input from the output so given the
output you know a number of this
function it is basically impossible to
find out what you know what input gave
that output okay so this function is
called hash function you know quick
cryptographic key level hash function
anyway it's a hash function so called
hash function now I was talking about
input numbers and output numbers but you
remember any text you know like like
this text here it's a number basically
because these you know it's bytes you
know bytes convert to number basically
so mathematic mathematically it's a
number a function that you know takes a
number and output another number
but in computers side you know
practically speaking usually it's text
you know just a bunch of text
could then output another text and it is
impossible you know given the output
text it's impossible to find out what is
the original text now that is a hash
function this property you know
impossible to find out what's the input
that's a key thing
so okay first of all so you have hash
functions then so so so so you have hash
function this is this is like the the
the the the most elementary key without
this nothing works without is without
this the crypto tog Rafi you know the
current doesn't work here nothing works
so hash function that's the most
fundamental then you have what's called
blockchain
okay blockchain so so how does what is
that so basically so so you begin with a
text you know input you know for example
this block of text you okay so you begin
with a bunch of text you you apply the
hash function you come up with another
text a string okay then with that string
you attach whatever information you want
like let's say my blog or Twitter post
or whatever you know let's say let's say
I went out to see the you know full moon
you know let's say that's you know the
text I went out to see the full moon you
know that's a that's an information okay
let me begin again so I begin with a
piece of information whatever text it is
you know I I went out to see the full
moon or today's a nice day or I borrowed
you know I borrow five dollars from you
or I'm saving my Mac to someone okay and
he owe me $1,000 anything a piece of
text okay now you take the text could
put into the hash function
it comes out and you know quick you know
cryptic you know comes out another text
okay so so so so so what so what so so
you do this again okay let me continue
let me continue okay let's say so today
okay so we I did this today I have a son
I wrote a diary I put into a hash
function come out a piece of stream now
I publish this to the web so you know I
publish anyway so so today I did this
okay now tomorrow I'm gonna write
another tire diary you know I bought a
car from you or whatever that's another
piece of text then I combined this text
with the the hash output from yesterday
combined it you know joining stream you
know stream joint so that's a new piece
of text now I feed that piece of text
into the hash function so it comes up
another piece of you know cryptic stream
okay this is tomorrow and publish this
you know I publish this kind of like a
tree thing I publish it so anyone can
see then next day I do the same thing so
after several days I have a chin you
know like a chain you know you begin
with the text into the hash function
come out a piece of text then you have a
new text much with that output then put
into a hash function and come up another
you know hash you know key then you add
another new text and so on each time
it's published okay this this is
basically this is called hash chain now
remember the hashed hash function
property is that you cannot find out
from the output what it is what is the
input so you cannot you know given
yeah you cannot like regenerate this
chain from from the end you cannot do
that you can only start from the
beginning so anyway so this is a hash
block this is so-called block chain okay
that's a basic idea you know they take
the technical details it's very
complicated the bit you know if you want
to implement but that's a basic idea so
today's topic is just random okay so I'm
talking about I'm trying to explain what
is the block chain so anyway so you have
this block chain so what you know so
what why is it you know is okay so so
next next is that so so far we have a
block chain that's just myself you know
like my diary you know each time you I
chain okay I you know I don't think I'm
not I'm not sure I can could do a good
job on this anyway let me try okay so
that's so far it's just myself now
suppose you guys join me you know five
people then say oh it could be you know
all the words population you know anyway
let's say you guys join me so so
together we are writing is let's say
collective block you know let's say all
of us you know the thing of us together
our society you know so tomorrow so okay
so so so far I have a blockchain of just
myself you know sequential it's just
linear but now you guys can join me so
so let's say today you know you you one
of you let's say green deck okay you
write the block block block you know you
write whatever that's interesting to you
you you take the the block chains you
know the hash key combined with your
message you know whatever you wrote then
you apply the function hash function
then it comes out another text you see
and someone else let's say you know
Bernie okay Bernie Sanders you can do
that too
so so these you know you can do that too
so this hash chin I mean the idea is
just you know you have some text you
combine with whatever is the last output
in the chain in a key then you merge
them and apply the hash function then
you got a new key so so this has changes
becomes a hash tree you know with many
participants you know we are owning it
and and remember because of the hash
function property it is impossible to
you know start from the bottom of the
tree and and find out what's what what
is comes before and so so we have this
tree of hash chance and at the point
here okay so now now we have this tree
of hash in blockchain the the importer
critical point is that nobody can change
any information in a tree because in
order to do so if you change any
information the hash function doesn't
work any I mean it doesn't you know for
we already have a tree right we already
have a tree you can only like add new
things at the bottom you know add to the
chain you it is impossible to change you
know some some messages you know some
tire we I wrote you know two days ago
it's impossible because if you change it
then all the hash functions value will
be different because you know you you
know if you know how this works you know
everyone can you know it it works by
text combines with a key then hash
function then come out another key and
text combined with that key come back
come out another key you know this is
the tree so if you change any
information there you you basically have
to generate new neutral you know all the
hash keys you know they will not match
that is the important thing so we have
this hash hash tree it's distributed to
all the people you know on the internet
and nobody can actually change something
because once you change you know then
you got two different trees they don't
match but you need to change everybody
Street and also once you change you have
to change all the you know things below
it you know because the hash function
you know it has to work out so that the
point here is once you have this hash
blockchain okay the point is that nobody
nobody can tamper with it you know now
the critical point about this hash chain
is that when you apply these to record
financial records you know money like
today I owe you $20 you know and
tomorrow you you know green deck also my
money you know things like that
distributed and immune immutable exactly
so yeah exactly so you know so the
critical phone is and nobody can't you
you have a record in the form of this
blockchain block tree you have a record
of things and nobody can actually change
anything because they changed it anyone
else we all know because it is
impossible for that person to you know
fix everything and make sure it is
impossible because of the hash function
the chant you know the the chant way of
using the hash function so so but what's
the critical point to society is that so
now you have the record that nobody can
actually tamper with that is the key
thing then we you apply you use this in
financial you know services then that is
how why that that is the impact that
that is how it's useful now okay back to
the Bitcoin now I so I don't actually
don't know how the Bitcoin currency
actually come into play I mean how does
it work I don't know I you know I only
know so far that you know that's a basic
idea of the blockchain idea you know
and the reason why it is immutable why
nobody can you know tamper with it so so
then I mean but I guess the the Bitcoin
you know any cryptocurrency is basically
using this idea and to make transactions
mean money transactions and also to
generate coin you know currency I don't
know how that works
so anyway I'm mentioning this because
you know I think that's you know big
coin idea to me is critically important
it's great but I never actually spent
much time to do to learn to learn it I
think you know I really should this is
something I really want to buy but I
didn't spend much time to study it you
know I I should and this you know in the
past few years since the Bitcoin was
born like how long was it six years ago
or something oh yeah or even ten years
ago but you know so um they are a lot
things have happened
you know there's co-co-co corrode you
know I read the story of that guy still
grows its type it you know that guy is
kind of a sad story
you know and we are talking about
billions of dollars worth you know going
going around in this in this Bitcoin
band
oh so Justine says the arrangement of
paper is a good read only nine pages
okay okay hey that that is the impetus
for me to read it today okay let me copy
that copy so I want to read that so you
know the you know there's so many things
to do every day that you know treat a
partner political stuff Emacs you know
in mathematics oh my god math you know
is this I have so many things I need to
read about math but usually you get
tired or you know Bordeaux so usually
people you know we are human beings you
know human animals okay so and we have a
habit you know we we need like Twitter
you know we need someone to like post
something you know brainless and then we
started to oh we you know we start to
reply out to that you know that's that's
kind of how humans are so I'm going to I
think I'm going to yeah I'm going to
read this paper becoming a peer to peer
electronic system I want the original
because these days you know you cannot
trust anything they have like copies and
click baits so the sauce I think I
probably should try the Wikipedia to
find a sauce first right
yeah so anyways the Bitcoin there are so
many stories I mean they are already
like billions going around I mean in
terms in terms of us money and fep FBI
is of course you know CIA government is
very very involved you know like disband
banks and institutions you know we are
not we program us you know we we talk
about random things on unrated on
Twitter and so on Hacker News but you
know we just talk you know obit going is
great you know we should all use it or
open-source you know this is stuff like
that but there are people they don't
talk you know there's financial people
the the CIA those bankers they don't
talk about it they see they do you know
they are doing things so Bitcoin is
already like 10 years old and you know
they are doing these things with it you
know and and also I've I know that you
know China is actually the the like 50%
of the majority of places that's you
know doing Bitcoin generating you know
this like the world is so big you know
China legally it is illegal you know
chant chant Chinese government you know
they they have you know it's
illegal to trade Bitcoin you know it's
not legal but a lot of it is from China
you know it's amazing like more than 50%
or something so what is this anyway so
this is well I don't know anyway so I
need to read that paper about Bitcoin so
let's talk about maybe something else
let's see
thank you hey Bernie Bernie Bernie
Sanders 2028
[Laughter]
Justine says explains what you talked
about just now and how transactions work
between individuals okay so I yeah I'll
read that okay what what else let's see
what else
Bitcoin so I actually have a Bitcoin
account like someone gave me like one
Bitcoin I guess seven years six six
years ago donation from donations when I
was in trouble
I think I have like one Bitcoin so it
you know it at one time two years ago
it's like ten twenty thousand dollars
USD oh my god I but I I don't know what
to wear I don't know what to do with it
yeah but anyway when you talk about
money there are lots of you know hidden
dragons crouching Tigers you know they
you don't see them they don't talk about
things but they do so Bitcoin you know
there is see yeah did this another story
about Silk Road did I you know Silk Road
you know just Silk Road is I read the
story there's a story on reported by
Wired this guy incredible you know and
he but he's in jail now you know you you
read the story where the FBI catches him
caught him in San Francisco San
Francisco library ready right here
you know you you read you know how the
FBI tried to catch him and also he's you
know he's you know he's a B D and I
don't know how much medium he had you
know 100 million here because a bitcoin
he's doing stuff on this silk silk road
he created and he's not a professional
programmer he's just you know like
amateur programmer you created a website
and then a young guy a young white guy
this is a picture actually I I saved the
picture of him with his family you know
so he become this he become this magnet
you know which is like one of the you
know top 100 powers in the world you
know he's doing the silk silk road and
and one day he's sitting in the you know
San Francisco Public Library you know
doing you know talking to you know doing
his Silk Road thing becoming then you
know the FBI is already already know you
know he's gonna cat cat he's going to
catch him sohave f eb FBI is you know
playing co-op role and agent you know
all around you know surrounded you know
the fe you know what you know the fe the
FBI they are afraid the moment he shot
his laptop you know because he's he's
sitting there you know doing typing or
whatever they are afraid the you know if
he close the laptop then that's that's
no good that they are all wasted because
because these nerds you know we you know
the bitcoin stuff cryptocurrency you
know you know how you know you know you
know that you know if you know you are
aware you know so you you can set up a
system so that once you close your
laptop okay
press a key everything i have top will
be deleted you know so that FBI wants to
catch him but also they want to prevent
prevent him you know just you know
prevent him from crossing the laptop
well he's because if i'm him for example
i see the you know the something
you know immediately I you know pay some
Kyoko's laptop you know it's things got
erased so so anyway wired has the story
you know you can read it I think I
showed it's linked on the Wikipedia I
think let's see I think that's wired
published by wired but by the way why
wired you know used to be a ok article
ok magazine ten years ago in 1990s ok
but then today it's like it's fake news
so quiet it's a you know but anyway
there's a what you know you just search
the guy's name you find it that's an
interest very interesting read but okay
so so Silk Road is one of the major
chapter in Bitcoin history but then
there is another guy this is a guy rose
William outrage
okay he's in jail he's in jail now but
anyway I heard I think I heard this year
last year that people are trying to make
a pardon for him you know trying to ask
Trump or was it someone else yeah I
think Trump to ask to give him a pardon
you know so so anyways so that's one
thing then then there is another big
chapter in becoming history is there is
this Bitcoin exchange in Japan you know
they operate in Japan called Mount
Mountain something anyone know the name
yeah if you read Bitcoin you'll know but
so that's what I heard you know so like
this you know a lot he story big story
like and also there are people who lost
Bitcoin that's that's worth you know
millions of dollars you know if you lost
the key or something then it's gone and
you know you know they are quite a few
story and people steal Bitcoin you know
they are hackers you know they hackers
are very interesting I mean we're
talking about
is you know real hacking you know they
did cracker you know some people call
them crackers you know they and and they
are very different from programming you
know to numb programmers you think oh we
are all programmers you know we must
know we I don't know I you know I don't
know I don't know how to hack well I I
could I could know but it's like it's
like a specialized you know you have to
it's like specialized field but also
they are a lot hackers you know this
seems to know a lot but actually not
because actually they don't know how to
program you know they're you know the
some sometimes we call them script
kiddies you know you got you are a
teenager you know you don't know about
programming you don't know about you
know computer science or theoretical
computer science you don't know you're
nothing of that and you don't have you
know you don't even have programming
experience but however you can hack you
know you you go into this you know you
get you immerse yourself in this hacker
vo hacker communities and you learn okay
download this program this program we
will let you do this this and this
program will hide your IP you know that
like but but they don't know how act
what IP is I mean they don't they don't
know tcp/ip you know they don't really
know you know the details but however
they can hack you know because you you
know immerse yourself in this hacker
communities and just use you know just
download programs install things and
things like that well that's one part of
the hacker community on the other hand
of course they are they are professors
you know in academia who who study you
know cryptography and you know whose me
and also they they know how to hack
anyway I think I'm getting boring so so
what's what's so green deck says have
you heard about sigh hub yes
what do you think about scientific
papers being behind paywalls that's no
good you know this that's all
it's all power struggle you know yeah
mount mount [ __ ] no that's a man [ __ ]
is the big chapter in Bitcoin yeah this
so many thing I you know I I would like
to read them in detail like know exactly
the story it's almost like it's almost
even better than reading a science
fiction because this is the real you
know a story but the intrigue and other
stuff it's like almost better than
science fiction and this is not just in
Bitcoin this happened in hacker
community in computing history UNIX
history a lot you know I so I you know
back in 90s you know 2000s I I do read
them but it keeps happening but anyway
mom Cox and okay so scientific
publishing you know sigh hub sigh hub is
this website that started by a king girl
I think you know today's social media
everyone likes to talk about you know
young girls or teen girls oh they they
invented this thing changed the world
some of it is true though but in this
case he says it's a true is true by a
girl you know a young girl from where
she from she's from Eastern Europe I
think Alexandra Russia
Alexandra L Bakken okay this girl it's
fascinating
so she's 30 years old okay so she's not
that young okay so so she created SCI
hub which is basically like you could
say one way to put it is that you it's
stolen you know use you you you you
steal or the scientific publication and
put on your database then so keep okay
I'll read it for free I think it's great
you know I think it's great
well I don't necessarily there you know
that's not something I would do even if
I could have
you know that's I wouldn't do that you
know but you know it's a company complex
moral issue you know it's not like just
black and white you know so anyway she
did this sigh hope so and the scientific
publishers there's one you know he's
hated by everyone what's the name that
you know that squeeze money okay
Casa kung oh she is from Casa Kong oh
great
a quick green deck what you in Russia
are you the are you guys are you the guy
in Russia I'm sorry I forgot
so anyway so Sahab yeah so and I can't
that reminds me of the errand guy who
killed himself also because of hacking
oh yeah you are in Russia great type
some Russian show us you know I like to
see it you know say hello like see
whatever I said you know types and you
can type in Russia all right Russian you
know let's show some serial ik alphabet
okay so okay so I hope you know so
there's many moral issues and then there
is this guy who is askin this guy who is
dot-com king.com you know that guy
this guy king.com he also you know he
also does the same thing he steal all
the movies you know from Hollywood and
put on his website so everyone can
download Li but this guy is askin this
king.com he is on Twitter megaupload
things yeah that's right then he got you
know the FBI you know us the media
corporations you know get the FBI the
FBI to - how do you how you code you
know like stink you know not stink but
like breaking like king.com he's like
100 media mayor you know like obediently
uh you know he he lives in New Zealand
you know that's how I learned about New
Zealand you know then you started to
look at the map and look at how it's
like New Zealand
I think it's New Zealand right oh did I
confuse it wait wait that's that's a row
with the word raided you know so he the
kingdom is in New Zealand he has a you
know castle-like mansion you know
hundred rooms with tents you know
hundred servants whatever you know ten
BMWs Tim you know Porsche or whatever
you know helicopters you know he that's
king.com is this fat guy I don't he's a
scum Oh guys come back he's the type you
know he just he just abused abuse things
so that he becomes richer that's that's
his nature you know you look at things
you don't church I mean on one hand you
know the megaupload which is actually in
a similar nature to this girl's github
yeah I mean not kid hops I hope you know
but there's a difference you know this
quite a lot of differences you know
anyway so the King dot-com guy you know
he'd he's you know in his house
the Fe the FB I have to like flag
helicopters and you know drop in you
know 100 you know if if bi agents with
machine guns and fake into his house and
caught him yeah that's then you know
then after
now he's the king dobkin guy is on
Twitter now you know things happen you
know
then Trump got elected now he's like for
Trump anti the social justice can so you
know things gets complicated you know
then he so now he becomes kind of a hero
to some some people you know i yeah i'm
anti social justice so you know i'd like
to support him but then that's politics
you know it's very complicated you know
you know he so it so he's like that
king.com i don't know what so what's the
current situation of him i mean did he
so he is out of jail or what I mean so
did did the court say something what is
a kinked outcome did you if did we find
the how this already let's go Wikipedia
megaupload
yeah so you know all these stories so
why are all these stories you know
Bitcoin Mount [ __ ] you know megaupload
sigh hub and you know Silk Road because
human animals we each of us or struggle
for power
you know today I happens to be you know
a nerd and pool so I talk about these
things you know almost like you know
night you know you you know as a good
person you know but you never know what
we you can I'm going to become you know
because it it is very likely you know if
you are in their shoe you probably you
probably do exactly the same in other
words you know today I see this
politician I say you know he's a scumbag
you know but it's like lottery you know
like if if if I was there you know if
you know if I was in his shoe possibly
I'll do exactly the same of course in
his point of view I mean from his point
of view he don't think he's to me
anything wrong you know that's how it
anyway that's getting complicated
you know did so anyway Silk Road so I
was going to say the and another guy
Aaron Schwartz okay he okay I think we
are starting to get into some areas that
YouTube might want to censor so maybe we
should not talk much too much about that
so he he is also a big story he's a
hacker he's one of the guy who started
reddit basically and he he killed he end
up killed himself few years ago six
seven years ago born died 2013 yeah and
he you know in it turns out it has
it's hack is not because of hacking you
know he it's because it has to do with
WikiLeaks anyway let's not talk about
that make upload so okay so so King calm
he's free so what is the judgment I mean
did I mean they don't just let him go
right I mean it must be something anyway
so maybe I'll probably read about it
later to get myself updated mega NZ is
its sequel it is the best cloud provider
available on the Internet oh really
so you use it you like it oh so you so
mega MZ is popular I haven't used any of
these oh and also we since we are
talking about these topics there is also
pirate bay of course who's new you know
Pirate Bay has been struggling for like
over ten years oh did that beam then
that reminds me the open source I don't
really like open source because you know
when you talk about Pirate Bay you talk
about you are talking about we are
getting into the issues about patent so
copyright and you know stuff and also
you know encrypted content you know
digital you know management you know
system things like that of course the
free software foundation and most
open-source vast majority they oppose it
but you know the the thing you know
annoys me is that you see as you know
and probably some of you believe you
know when when it comes to open source
people and you know is it free software
open source you know they say info must
be free you know software must be free
four must be free like that's that's
that's pseudoscience you know that's
meaningless like you cannot define you
exactly what do you mean info must be
free or all things are free you know all
good things are free that's what this
you know open-source it you know
ideology [ __ ] say oh you info must
be free oh you know all good things in
the world is free like water and air but
if you actually try to define it doesn't
make sense what do you mean air is free
you know I can give a counter example
right away water and air is free you
know they say okay the best thing in
life is free not so not so you know so
so it's amazing i food you need food to
survive
is that correct is it free go [ __ ]
yourself you know those people you know
all the good things you know you know
the best things in the world is free
people say that of course the the the
the open source free software ideology
ideologues they say that these only
needs them said they possess a who says
that anyway some when it comes to the
you know Pirate Bay I'm on the open
source and free software some some we
are supported you know open D like yes
you know we don't like Hollywood you
know you we should we know we just gonna
pirate it and so many so there's a
sizable group people a mono open source
of free software they support openly you
know the actions of Pirate Bay meaning
you know taking Hollywood you know
movies you know put it online free okay
only or any software you know
proprietary software so some group they
openly support it on the other hand some
some of the open source and free
software publicly they do not support it
okay
their stance would be something like oh
yeah we are for free software or we are
for open-source however we do not you
know condone the the Pirate Bay action
usually they don't say anything like
they they just shut up this is the this
is the this is the hypocrisy part you
know one of the hypocrisy
part of the open source and free
software [ __ ]
you know ideologist so when when they
say something in just but however it
relates to their their you know their
ideology they don't they don't say
anything they don't they don't public
politically go say no Parab a is no good
you know we should they don't they don't
do that on the other hand there's
another subgroup they they just quietly
you know like this is most people it
just quietly go to pyro Bay and download
movies they want to watch don't talk
about anything vast majority people are
like that you know they including them
programmers you know so what can you do
you know this you know this is things
like that anyway I want to mention back
about the size up so I think you know it
I think it's good and also let me
mention this logo I'd love this logo
this logo is spectacular it's the most
beautiful and well designed you know
it's so beautiful you know this you got
the crow crow is the smartest you know
animal what do you one of the most smart
and more get quote so you got this crow
and do it beautiful we look look at the
you know the how they the illustration
of the you know feather you know like
it's like stars you know like you know
in a dark night you see other stars so
it's like cosmological you know you like
the immense stars in the sky and then
you know the crow the smart crow is
holding a key that's just you know
that's just that's fantastic I love it
so anyway sigh hub and there is there is
the second sigh her okay so sigh hope
yeah so the the evo publisher there's
one called
s that name just came to me but I forgot
right away
what you know anyway so scientific
publications it's all you know the
reason it's in under pay else else they
else via thank you green deck else via
yes you know the reason the scientific
community is like that because actually
the entire thing you know all the topics
we talk about it's basically your result
of the you know the human you know
animal struggle for power for money but
it that is it there is actually
you cannot say oh this this group is
right that groove is wrong or this
ideology is good it's not like that it's
intermeshed complex it's like almost
like a cellular automaton you know
things just happen you know chaos you
know things just happen so Elsevier why
they they are there you know why they
pay war and stuff of course they want to
make money and they become greedy just
like Google [ __ ] Google you know that
originally do no evil now becomes though
oh in camp encompassing the most evil
entity in the universe that's Google we
trusted it you know we helped Google
anyway so Elsevier you know of course
they did their publishers they become
you know rich and greedy and then sigh
hub happened you know and also the
scientists the [ __ ] the scientists you
know the professors and Akademi
typically typically they are all for
open source you know on the mouth about
open source free software every day the
professors in academics and they you
know they play along with Elsevier of
course otherwise Elsevier would not be
possible to exist like it was you know
it wouldn't be possible for Elsevier to
become powerful or reach and you know
with this paywall stuff why well because
the professors helped alone why would
professor help along because the
professors academics they are concerned
about their own way
fail you know they want to get tenure or
whatever they follow they follow the
career ladder the faculty those open
source chanting professor academics that
day they made Elsevier possible thence I
hope happened happened then they are all
like you know a lot of them these yo
like oh yeah this is supposed sighs I
hope it's all a phony or show okay so
that's that
so let's this we took some of the
comments so Bethel Muir says it's the
only one I can trust at least to some
degree
oh okay so I'll make note of that the
which is the what's what's the name mega
and Z okay okay I'll check it out okay
this I need to like copy the stuff here
so I can actually see make NZ you see
Emacs is so powerful I can like navigate
stuff so mega and Z so okay so mega NZ
is good e to e encryption by default and
they don't push it oh okay so that's
great
then okay so this is great unless you
need to make a living so how long have I
been talking 50 minutes okay that I
think maybe we can you know that's one
hour this is great unless you are making
a living compare mega
NZ to opal are services like Dropbox or
Google Drive is like comparing a
Lamborghini to a bicycle oh really Wow
okay so definitely I need to check out
mega NZ now easier make this a wiki wiki
pedia article so you see usually my
first stop is Wikipedia but remember
Wikipedia is not to be trusted most of
the you know not depending on type of
the article there megha service know if
it's anything about politics politics or
anything on the news the Wikipedia
article will kidding you cannot trust it
it's all you know it's all like you know
colored you know you but typically for
math programming stuff you can trust it
Wikipedia anyway most most of the time
make Wikipedia is my first stop
you know once once you know you you look
you read a lot of stuff you can then
when you when you see a Wikipedia
account article you know you know you
keep in mind you know how some articles
are bad but anyway you can experience
you know you know which part you can
trust but anyway first stop my first
stop is usually Wikipedia because
because I can you know I can start to
look up you know references you know I
think I've been using Wikipedia with
since 2004 you know so I know you know I
can tell you some articles all the
references even they have you know
hundred references all of them from
front end groups of some pallet pallette
politics you know for example Falun Gong
you know I can tell you right away some
of these powerful organized
organizations they have like 200
websites with different domains and you
don't know like you cannot tell you
visit some news website you know it says
you know some news website and since its
popular but actually behind it it's run
by this you know this this this or that
groups so
sometimes I can tell and then also when
it comes through social justice thing
you read Wikipedia article you see all
the references are like pointing to fake
news but you have to have the experience
to know that because average person you
will not be able to see no anyway magus
mega okay mega is a crowd storage and
file hosting service offered by mega
limited an Oakland based company wait
this is this is this also started by the
kinder calm I don't like the Kingdome
guy okay so okay so anyway let's see
what what else articles here I mean
comments lots of people so just in say
starts up people that advocate for free
software makes money in academia or
institutions okay fatum you say it's my
autocorrect misspelled there I mean to
say other popular
okay other popular yeah patthamas says I
don't agree with your view on parenting
though you mean the I'm talking about
torrenting the movies movies and music
you know those are yeah well in my
opinion okay so yeah so in my opinion I
don't you know even I hate Hollywood you
know but I wouldn't you know I would I
wouldn't sanction or you know I wouldn't
say you know go ahead and upload it to
online you know either you watch it you
don't if it's proprietary or for some
reason you don't like it don't watch it
that's that's that's the thing you know
that's what I do you know I I don't
exactly do that I have watched you know
I have watched movies you know from
piratebay not not in the past five years
though
but part part of the reason is because
I'm getting old you know so there's so
many superhero movies I don't watch them
anymore
not much that much but also because the
Pirate Bay
you know these days like you so many
going you know the FBI CIA you know
although all these organizations are
watching it and technology also changes
they have you know see they have
whatever you know you have to be careful
like you have they have all kind of
things you you know so okay I think
that's maybe that's about it today yeah
so let's see methanol mayor says there
is a German document documentary that is
in total several hours long five hours
that exposes the political influence
behind the scenes of German Wikipedia oh
okay so this confirms precisely your
opinion regarding with media yeah but on
the bottom you say I'm not sure if it is
precisely by kim.com but as far as I
know
mega NZ is the sequel okay I don't like
king.com what's so funny about that
so a Mac Maxim Maxim Bandhan what do you
think about shortening copyright
duration oh yeah absolutely that should
be done you know copyright you know I
have actually I forgot to show my
articles my god I need to show because
he sadly okay because I Lee maker upload
because I wrote some blogs you know when
when things happen I did wrote some
blogs make a upload crime boss okay
there it is
let me show you some you know this is
his this is his abort
you know makeup you know look at the
house oh so great this is
what hundred rooms Auckland New Zealand
New Zealand hundred rooms you know let's
see
super super resolution photo let's see
okay Ariel Ariel shot maker uploading
Hongkong headquarter mega beautiful okay
this this is a guy and and he's that's
his co-conspirators or something like
that and so yeah I don't like you know I
I don't know him that much but I do I
did with red you know I think he's askin
and he's this fat guy and he and once
you are rich you see once you had you
know which girls follow you so you know
sometimes you see he posts on Twitter
he's got wife you know with beautiful
beautiful white beautiful daughter you
know like you know tottered little girls
and it's cute so when you see that photo
you cannot say what the fact you know
this is a bad cab you know it so looks
cute it's a family you know beautiful
girls and yeah but you know we are when
you are reach girls follow you that's
the key you know that's that's actually
the truth you can have any girls you
know they are eager to you know to
whatever you can go up or whatever
they'd be happy to they are afraid you
don't go up them that's that's that's
the reality when you are rich like that
or like Trump
so yeah copyright oh yeah let's talk
about copyright so let me show you the
[Music]
Mickey Mouse copyright such Mickey Mouse
copyright nation so this is you know I
wrote this in 2006 this is a great
artwork and this was okay okay there's a
CGP guy explaining on the copyright
that's worth watching or actually so
let's see hold on a second let me get
the that so we are about done okay so
any more questions type it and we are
about done so I want to I want to post
this so let's look at the oh yeah CP G
gray so we want to there's he c PG gray
he did a video about copyright you know
so he explained you know so basically
copyright is a manifestation of u.s.
United States of America the greed of
United State of America which I am a
member so you know basically they want
to extend Mickey Mouse you know Disney
stuff so in the beginning it's like you
know 50 years then it's 70 years then
it's you know after the author debt you
know 50 years a 100 years a median years
the [ __ ] these people it so Quizon you
know it's all all of this is about power
struggle you know each one of us
basically essentially you know yeah that
that's it for today so think yes I guess
that's it for today
we talked about an hour so thank you
guys for coming any anything else
okay bye guys