Everyone welcome to another episode of
talk show. We are going to code
JavaScript exploration of JavaScript
uh markdown to HTML code. So I'm going
to download um JavaScript markdown to
HTML and look at the code and see how
they do it. So there are quite a few
things um to do. So this video is going
to be about 1 hour or less uh because I
gota go. So if you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed. If you are
here say hi. Okay. [snorts] So let's do
talk show. So talk I talk and show.
Okay. So today's talk show um page here
and uh let me tell you what why am I
doing this like what's the purpose?
Okay. Now to explain the purpose is
going to take like 20 20 minutes but
we're just going to blow with it. Okay.
So uh Emacs so um so about a month ago
we did a HTML markdown to HTML I mean
markdown to HTML written in emacisp. We
wrote it live. So, let me demo um
uh let let me demo a code. Should I demo
it? Uh
yeah, we can. So, okay. So, let let's
let me let me demo the code. Okay.
Markdown Markdown tutorial. If you don't
know what markdown is, this here is a
tutorial. And uh let's say copy this
code. Okay. So, uh open it. So, close
that. Wait. Open it. Copy it. Close it.
And uh this is today's talk show. Uh go
to the section page. Delete that
section. Paste the link linkify.
Make it a list. Delete the todo. So we
got the link to the markdown tutorial.
So click on that. Copy the code. Copy
the code. Okay. So let's just open a new
buffer. Okay. So here is a markdown. So
markdown is a easy way to mark up text.
So
one uh number sign means heading. Two
number sign is second level heading or
section. Three number sign is third
level section. And uh then you got
inline code. So markdown. Everyone um is
familiar with it if you are a coder. So
this video is for coders, programmers.
Okay. So here's markdown and I want to
turn it into HTML. So I can select all
and call
uh markdown
to HTML tab S. Okay. So cancel tab S. So
you can see this become H1 heading H2
heading H then then uh okay this is
wrong. This is incorrect. [laughter]
Uh heading heading heading then you got
code. So let's save this. Okay. Save
this uh xx today's date and html. Okay.
So save it. We can view it in browser.
So you can see level and and all that.
So you got you also got code block for
example. So
so you can see this code this pre-tag
means code. So this is turning markdown
to HTML. And this code is written in
Emacisp. In fact, we did this live about
a month ago. Search my YouTube, you'll
find it. Search for markdown. Okay. So,
let's look at the source code. Tap s.
So, here's the documentation. Uh, you
know this command. Replace markdown text
to HTML in current block or selection.
And uh so but anyway this code and by
the way if you want uh to get a code
just go go to the this URL open it
showing browser so you can actually grab
the code if you are a Emacs user. Emacs
is the best editor. Okay like VS code or
Vim or Neo Vim. So you can you can grab
the code. So let's copy that.
So uh yeah, copy that URL and close that
and uh let's let's go let's go to
today's talkshell there's a link okay
linkify then go uh then show in browser
you can see emac this code and go back
to our markdown so show in browser so
let's markdown to HTML written in
emacisp and we haven't showed the code
yet so let's look at source code. So
here is the source code. Okay. So
uh
not too long about 50 lines. Okay. So
here here here stop here. Okay. So but
this is not complete and uh to make it
robust for industrial use this won't
work. There are several issues. The
issues are let me explain. So you can
see the code by the way if you want to
see the code you know just go to the URL
I showed before. Okay the URL is also
listed here. Open that show in browser.
So the code is only like 100 lines
mostly just find replace. Okay. Am I
doing good? Say hi. Okay. So is is
nobody here? [ __ ] YouTube. Three people.
Okay. say hi because I talked about this
yesterday. In order to be popular, you
need to conform to certain ways and do
tactics like clickbait and memes and
very nasty. If you are real authentic
talking about things like no, nobody
knows about your video. Okay, so
markdown to HTML. Now this code is
incomplete. So let me close that. So
wait, reopen show the pink window. So
the pink window shows all my command
course and the keystrokes on the left.
As you can see, let's um for example, I
move the cursor or I delete that undo.
So you can see all the command names are
there. I'm using safely keys. Okay, the
most efficient key binding for Emacs. So
markdown to HTML. Yeah, open that. Uh
yeah, that's the code. Close that. Close
the source code. And here's a sample
code. Copy close. and uh make a link
there.
Okay, we got all the links. Now this
code is incomplete because there are
several uh complexities
which is not trivial to do. So the code
we wrote is just like simple but what
are the problems? Okay, the problems
uh problems or complexities
complexity
Okay, the problems are
uh let me uh tell tell you. Okay, so the
problems are if you have nested list now
that is hard to do. You have to pass
nested list. Okay, or if you have um
nested list if you have table
markdown table
T A B L E. Okay, that's also difficult.
Well, not not exactly too difficult but
n not not not trivial. Okay. So, and and
another thing if you have
uh but that uh if you have code
and
in that
code it shows
it uses
the back tick. Okay. So this character
is called grave accent. The uni code.
The full unic code name for this
character is called
grave accent.
Okay. But colloially we call this
character backick. The idiotic
programmers you know we just call this
backick. So if you have a like triple
quote in markdown that means that means
a uh code you know code here for example
JavaScript console log print uh let's
say print something so code here so let
me show you okay so uh JavaScript so
this is JavaScript this is this is code
this is JavaScript
and uh let's say uh constant uh cn st oh
god I don't remember without completion
I don't know how to code anymore so
let's let's just um create a javascript
okay
so console log uh console log and also
constant x equals through three and
let's say I want to say I have um
three cats. Okay, so you can run this
code. You can see I have three cats.
This is valid JavaScript code. Now, now
copy it, put it back. Okay, so now if
you have the markdown
like that.
Okay,
um showing browser. Okay. Will it show
correctly? No. Because you know anyway.
So if you have this text block, this
text block in markdown that means code
and the first line means what language
it is. Okay. Then if but if the code
also contain a back quote, you got a
problem because you can you cannot just
turn these triple back ticks into
pre-tag. You also because in markdown
this back tick one single back tick tick
means verbatim.
So if you then if you convert so for
example if I do this with my command
it's going to get it wrong. Okay. So if
I now uh tap s you see I turn this into
markdown. So you see it got the triple
quote wrong. And also here it became it
it got [ __ ] up basically. So it took
you know so that's complexity. So and uh
the way to say it if you have co code
and in that code it use grave accent.
Okay. So these these are the major
problems. So here is a example. Um
let's put it to pre uh
okay. So now
delete that syntax color everything show
in browser. So the the problem or
complexity of
um
of a command that
convert
markdown to HTML are
this. Okay. These are the so far the
major issues I found. So you know you
can code them but it's not like it's not
10 minutes job. It's going to be for me
to write a robust markdown it will take
me 20 hours few days. Okay. So and we
have a demonstration of the problem
here. Okay. So that's a problem. So you
know my eaglist code you know is not a
robust markdown to HTML. So I need to so
I can just spend the next 20 hours to
code it or I can look at other people
have has written
uh markdown to HTML in different
languages
because this is very frequently used. So
it's heavily used in industry. So it's
available in JavaScript in every
language JavaScript, Goland,
uh TypeScript, Ruby, Python, uh and and
of course C++ and C and F in you know in
every language
and uh I I assume there's one in EAC
list as well. So I can actually go get a
package. But I last time I tried one
that's that sucks very badly. So it may
not exist a robust markdown to HTML code
in EMAC list. So my problem is so either
I spend the next you know 30 hours to
write write one or
I can use my emac command to call a
external command
call a external command to um to do the
job then it it will show the result in
the buffer you know
so that's the thing
I need to do I'm going to do and I'm
going to show you so this This is my
workflow. So, I'm just going to show you
how I get it. Wait, hold on a second. My
alarm clock.
So, this is my iPad.
Every every 30 minutes
it beeps. It beeps tells me to get up
and walk. Okay, I now I have 30 minutes
more. I can finish this today. But then
again this is my just talk show okay I
show you guys what I'm doing what are
the issues this is like a real life
coding okay like if you are at a job you
know you run into this problem as well
but not exactly markdown because
markdown is so it's already written in
every language.
Uh so the question about swabboard I'm
very sorry and I feel sorry for the guy
this is fantastic okay can you guys see
it this is the swabboard the question is
asking about it's the most advanced
Hold on a second
the most advanced keyboard okay it's you
know so I did a review like preliminary
review but I actually just I never spend
time with it. So,
so that I failed, you know, I failed and
I promise it's my been two years, but
but it's not abandoned. So, it is still
my intention to actually use this every
day. Okay? It is still my intention, but
I'm just like the way I am. So, there's
no schedule. So, but I I I I would
recommend it. I you know
to you guys to have a look. Okay.
SWboard. So I just haven't got to
uh to it yet. Okay. So that's that.
So the guy you know the guy is great
guy. So check out Sabboard website.
Okay. SV A L B O A R D. SV A L B O A R
D. Check their website. They have news
and they also have a discord forum.
You know, I should talk to the guy
because, you know, he so this is fairly
expensive, you know, because you know,
you if you have ergonomic, you know, you
have hand pen, which I do. Um, so this
is especially for those people and it's
very good. It's supremely, you know, by
the way, so I showed this before. This
is magnetic key switches. magnetic
meaning that once you dislodge the
magnet it has no resistance so it's the
best switch possible and you know so
it is I will still be you know uh using
it
so that's about board and uh uh let's
code for 30 hours then
okay so lighting
light lock blog says I should code emac
this for 30 hours. Yeah.
Okay. So that is possible you know I I
still might plan to do it because
because it it is fun you know I just
love coding coding and also coding emac
this among others you know also other
languages such as wuam language and so
on.
So let uh wait describe P. So you see
the I'm operating in Emacs the fantastic
Emacs. So you can jump to the source
code because I'm markd down to HTML you
know. So so one option is to just finish
this code you know write my own like
everything I have is my like all my
packages.
You see this I basically use zero other
people's packages because I've been
coding eag this by now for 20 years
starting from 2016. Yeah. 2016
uh 2020 for for 10 years.
Okay. So that's one option which I
likely I might do. Okay. But meanwhile
there are something you know so I also
want to write a wrapper that just call
either JavaScript or Python.
So
so like right now my job is just do do
uh some exploration look at the
JavaScript code from Deno possibly. So
there are quite options I already asked
AI about it. So one option is the common
mark.js.
Common mark is a variation of markdown
is supposedly standard. There's a big
drama. I talked about it a month ago.
But anyway, so one so one of the robust
code from JavaScript is common mark.js.
Okay.
The other option is you use the one in
Python or look at Python, Ruby, Golan,
they all have a version. Okay. And also
another thing I'm learning is F. So I
want to look at so so basically you I
just want to look at all the all the
code. I want to look at them how they do
it. Okay. So this is not typical from
typical programmers. Typical programmers
you just you know you just get the
things done whatever you know go go
through the easiest way you know just
download this install it and and be done
and write a EMAC wrapper. So instead of
coding
you know the tedious issue yourself you
simply call the shell command you know
call this command and get the output
then you are done you have you know the
command to do that in EMAC so that's
another option so that's easy
so I want to look at all these
programming languages their
implementation of markdown and right the
wrapper and or complete my own code in
of Emac this. Okay,
but now
and of course there's a reverse problem
turning HTML back to markdown which is
also necessary. I need to do it. I also
have a command already but again it's
not it's not like fully complete. Okay.
So for example uh for example I want to
turn this um let let's just say this
link okay you see showing browser you
see you got several links so so let's
turn this this link to markdown so I can
what I can do is um the key is
tab dt
yep that's it so so it's using uh right
now it's using my special kind of using
a bullet unic code bullet instead of the
markdown hyphen or asterisk but anyway
that this is the format of the link of
markdown okay so undo so
so markdown to HTML and HTML to markdown
and look at all the programming
languages uh implementation the one I'm
I would be interested is JavaScript,
Python, Golan and F. Okay. And maybe
Wuam language too.
Then okay. So then then there's another
thing. Let me just explain. So we not
going to we're not going to download it.
We so but let me just explain but
because I got to go. So the other thing
is you see when you code in eacisp let's
look at the markdown uh to html command
again
sourc scope you see when you code eac
this which I have like over like 200
videos about coding text processing in
emacisp
okay so actually so let me show you
where they are so
the emacs okay just Search for my name
Kasi Emacs and go to Emacs tutorial
you know uh today AI brave search brave
I recommend Brave browser and the brave
search AI they they got a AI brave use
Brave browser and use Brave search
engine and the engine also features
automatic AI answer you know is a
longtime EMAC user and developer who has
been using Emacs daily since 1998.
That's true. Okay. So anyway, so go to
Emacs, my Emacs tutorial.
You go to then uh video tutorial. So
this is like a short collection of my
best videos about Emacs, how to use
Emacs, Kasarly Keys demo, uh Vim Evo Mod
versus Kasly Keys.
Did Richard Storman create Emacs? That's
controversy and so on. And then Emacs
workflow efficiency. Uh Emac Lisp from
the ground up introduction tutorial.
Emac this writing a major mod. You know,
we did several from the ground up
writing a major mode and Emac this
coding. So I have like over 200 videos.
So when you code emacisp
doing text processing
eagisp is very different from all the
other languages python ruby javascript
goland c++
rust whatever because in eagisp you have
this buffer data data type which is what
you are looking at this is a buffer you
can create a new buffer you can and in a
buffer
it's a special data type so what what is
a buffer buffer data type. It is
basically you can think of it as a
glorified string data type. So it's like
a string in Python or JavaScript
but however within the string you can
have the current position like the
index. You can delete you can delete um
uh you can you can uh wait you can
delete some text or you can insert some
text and actually you can also do undo
programmatically.
You can move the cursor the current
index to any position. You can save the
position. You can go back to the
position. You can do regular expression
search on the on the buffer which is a
string. So, Emac this coding
when you are doing text processing
involves the fundamental core data
structure called buffer which is just a
representation of text. Okay, it can be
very long can be actually even one
gigabyte but that's not practical.
So in other languages like let's say
Python, JavaScript,
what do you want to do text processing?
Well, your text becomes a long string.
Then then then what can you do? Not much
you know you can't just replace part of
the string and because usually in Python
and in JavaScript both of them string
data type are immutable.
That means every time you make a change
like you know you insert a character or
delete a line or whatever it has to
recreate the entire string. So it's very
extremely inefficient.
So typically you don't you know if you
want to do text processing in Python or
JavaScript you don't you don't do it
like the Emacs. You don't just like go
to this line number delete this part and
whatever insert that new text in some
you don't do that. Okay, you need to
uh one one way is you turn a string into
a array. So each character may be a uh
array element. So so then you modify the
array in in Python and JavaScript those
are called their array. In Python it's
called list. in Java in JavaScript it's
called um array but what they actually
are
they are dynamic array so as far as data
type goes
Python has one called list
JavaScript has one called array
but as far as computer science data
structure
point of view both of them are actually
called dynamic array. That means a array
that cannot grow, cannot shrink but
actually hidden array that has you know
that allows you to grow or shrink or
insert anything. So that's called
dynamic array. So anyway so back to so
the issue is that so in eaglist you can
create a buffer. Okay. Now buffer is
implemented as a there are several ways
to implement it. One is called rope. Uh
another one is a gap buffer. Now I don't
I don't know too much about them. Okay.
But anyway, so
so the the the the issue is that I want
to look at if you are going to do heavy
text processing, you know, maybe make a
report, generate a report of thousands
of text files or do like transformation
of text like find replace on millions of
files.
What do you do? How do you do that in
the most in efficient practical way in
Python and JavaScript? Okay, so that is
my question actually.
Now I I I kind of know you know you you
for example in Golan you turn it into a
uh in Golan you turn it into a um slice
of run
which which run basically means
character you know. So anyway, but I
want to so what I want to do that's why
I'm interested in looking at the
different programming language
implementation of the markdown to HTML
because this is a great best example of
text processing this task. No turning
turning markdown to HTML is a text is in
a category called text processing. This
is the best example. So I want to look
at them how they do it. Do they turn you
know [snorts] if you have a long test
text do they turn them into like an
array of characters or what do they do?
You know like once you finished
doing the transformation you turn it
back into one huge string something like
that maybe or maybe you don't you save
you bas directly save the array to a
file maybe so that so there are many
issues that's why I want to look into
the implementation of JavaScript python
and golan that's the three primary one
and also because these languages are
different So,
so actually they may choose different
implementation to do the thing. Okay. So
that's the explanation kind of the what
I'm doing. So today I just explained
what I want to do but we didn't actually
begin.
So but I going to go in 20 minutes. So
for example let's look at the common
markjs. Okay let's begin to do it. So
it's on GitHub. So you go to that
GitHub.
So copy the URL.
Close that. Close that. Okay. Let's say
let's paste the URL here. Okay. Linkify.
Make a list. Wait. Oh god. You know
this. So this link is wrong. So you So
whenever text ends in JS.js, if I link
it, it became a script. But that's not
what I want. So what I want is um
some html link
uh ur URL to link. Okay, now that's
better. You see? Wait, I want a dated
link. So
some HTML
link
uh
UR
URL
to dated link there tab we so do it
that's better so you got no referral
complexity of HTML target blank open a
new window that means and that date
success. That's what I want. Whenever
you want to link to somewhere, you need
a date because otherwise after 10 years,
you forgot like when did you link it?
When did it go dead? You know, you have
no idea what it is. So, it's always
better if you link to some other site.
You got the date
when you write a blog. Okay. So, anyway,
so here for example. So, here is a link
and now I can um I can open uh let's go
to directory. Let's say current
directory. Okay. So start shell
get
clone
this thing. Let's look let's get the
whole thing and we start to look at the
code. Okay. So go to the directory. So
uh search for
search for common
there. Okay. So open it. They got a
bunch of complicated MPM the Zuma idiot
thing.
MPM
which is the Zoomer's thing the Zuma
generation which are idiots.
Okay. So I'm not very familiar with the
MPM structure and stuff. So it's ve you
like like from my experience it's very
annoying to look at them. You see what I
want is simply a one single JavaScript
file. But usually that's not the case
because you can see the bin actually
calls some other you know call a bunch
of things. It's not doing the actual
work. Then you so you have to trace the
code. Exactly. or whether do you need to
build it like like with you know instead
of just a working file you have to like
build
like make you know create to create a
working file. So do you guys know
[snorts] so t so so normally I would
have just to spend time to look at you
know library blocks. So this you see
this turning markdown to HTML
looks like a simple task you know really
ideally just find essentially it's find
replace but then you look at the actual
real world code it's it's not just find
and replace there are many approaches
they may be using a real parser then
that also means you have to you have to
define the grammar
of the markdown. So you don't but
but not necessarily depending on you
know how they do it. So that's why it's
very interesting to look at the code. So
what is this blocks.js.
Okay. So they are using uh import you
know the eggmas script 2015 features of
static import.
So that's you know so that's what I'm
doing. I need to start to look at the
code. So what is this re HTML block
open? So okay wait.
So this is basically this is kind of
passing HTML.
Why do they need to pass HTML?
Because this is marked down to HTML. So
I don't know. So there's a lot to look
into and and look at this complicated
regular expression
you know the JavaScript
30 years of JavaScript baggage gives you
this oh you know so this is industrial
real life code not toy
you see so re okay re is regular
expression bullet list marker. Okay. So
you So another annoying thing about
markdown is that you have like many
variations
like if you have a list
each line can start with a asterisk or
plus sign or minus sign you know it's up
to you. So you got that then all the
list. Okay. So you got these uh regular
expressions. Then let's say let's color
that. Okay. So,
so let's let's look at, you know, maybe
how they do list. Okay. Oh my god, this
is how many lines? 1,000 lines.
Okay.
So, bullet. Let's search that.
Okay. If match rest dot match bullet. So
it so the current line suppose match the
beginning of the bullet mark then data
type equals to bullet sets the type then
then data.bullet bullet character. So
get the character.
Okay. So
Okay. So there is a function pass list
marker. Okay. So we can see.
So apparently so now we can tell they
are not using a full parcel. They are
not defining a grammar.
This is like so their approach is just
text processing
effectively find and replace
same thing I was doing in emac
so let's see other occurrence of this
okay just actually one occurrence okay
so this is pass a list marker and return
data on the marker
So what does it return? So function
another another thing annoying is that
they are using this is JavaScript before
you know I have no idea why why didn't
they use you know the modern JavaScript
this this var is basically obsolate
this is before JavaScript 2015 code
so why do they use that you I don't know
use you know but wait so they use so
wait the import is from ECMAS script
yet they are using VA so this is kind of
idiotic okay
because in 2015 you don't use VA va is
considered obsolate because it's got
lots of problems that's another story
okay so you can you guys can look at my
JavaScript script
JavaScript in depth search for it you'll
find it about you know 400 pages in
depth it's the best JavaScript tutorial
to tutorial you will find
in the world in English okay better than
Mozel whatever or printed books you can
buy
if you you know trust me kali is my name
then that's my word this JavaScript in
depth I wrote I spent like three four
years writing it reading all the specs
you know tedious
it's be better than whatever JavaScript
is the best JavaScript in-depth tutorial
in the English language in the world
okay that is my claim so you guys can
check it check it out so so about the VA
we are talking about you can see here VA
you know basically obserate
so you know but they are still using it
and these people are the leaders you
know this oh MPM you know the [laughter]
this
you don't know you don't know why are
they what the [ __ ] they doing v import
from 2015 but then v
uh you know
so so okay so you got this block.js
so do they have a comment on what this
file do no okay now go to the now you
got common.js JS. So what so what does
the common.js do?
Okay. So you also need to import MD URL.
Let's look at what
Oh, then you need to import entities. Oh
god, this is fairly involved because how
do I know because the entities you know
there are thousands of entities. You go
to HTML
and uh you go to uh char set encoding
self closing tags class attribute. Then
you go entities. Okay, entities is
basically this escape mechanisms in HTML
to allow you to have nonasky characters
such as bullet
or math symbols. Okay. Or escaping this
you know greater than sign or amp% and
then but
from about 10 years ago they added so
before there's just a few hundred but
then today is like thousands of them you
know each one has this special name
entities and also idiotic jargon they
call it entities.
It's just basically it's a it's a way to
allow you to have unic code you know
non- English characters
but without actually using those
characters you know so so if you want to
do this fully you need to have basically
a table of these 1,00 few thousand
characters okay uh math symbols you know
esoteric like these esoteric math
symbols chances are you never seeing it
used once in your life. Okay? [laughter]
But if you are a mathemat mathematician,
you might see it one time in your life
like one time. But if you are not
mathematician, you'll never see this in
your life in your entire life. The coder
idiots, you know, the coding idiots,
they you know who who added this or
these symbols. the what the [ __ ] group
from Apple and Google, you know, like WT
uh WT something, you know, the new HTML
5 standard organization, the what the
[ __ ] group, that's what I call them.
They created this before before 10 years
ago. It's it's it's only like a hundred
of them frequently used ones like uh
like some of these. Okay.
But then they added like like why why
the [ __ ] idiots you add them because
by now you just use unic code you know
but they have to or you you use the unic
code point so you don't need you don't
need these named you know named entities
but they do it anyway they for some
reason they that so
I don't think it should be done so
here's another um segue you know
digression. This is another
proof in my opinion, an indication of
the utter
kind of corruption
inefficiency,
the idiocy of the standard
organizations.
Okay? Like this is 2025, you know, we
got AI, you got Unicode, Universal, but
they for some, you know, they they they
decided, oh, we need these special names
for for for reasons I do not know. I do
not think you need it. Okay? You know,
so
so the point is people might say, "Oh
yeah, well because you are you don't
know because if you are actually you
know participating in the standard body
then you realize actually in the in so
many protocols you actually need it. You
actually do need these special name
characters." Okay, some people may say
that. Okay, maybe you guys will say
that. No, my claim is that they are just
idiotic. It is unnecessary. I will
challenge them. Okay, like like the
reason they have this is just idiocy.
It's a corruption of the standard
organizations.
Okay, this is this is just one of the
example. There are so many that's why
when you code this is like so many
complexities.
Anyway,
so here's the HTML entities. So you see
thousands of them and
and now you go back to the code. So you
can see here
apparently this line indicates they are
they are actually implement
imple implement um
implementing
implementing these entities.
So can we find so they are importing
from entities. So, can we actually find
the library called entities?
No. Jesus. Jesus. Let's see. Package
JSON. Is are you are they going to tell
me this this to make this work? It's
going to load 1,000 libraries from MPM.
This Zoomer [ __ ] idiots. [ __ ] the
Zoomers.
Are they telling me now that in order to
have this markdown to HTML to work, you
need 1,00 libraries? True.
[laughter]
The [ __ ] [ __ ] basis.
You see entities here? Here, here
entities. Uh, where enti? Wait, I just
saw there dependencies entities
version seven MD URL I don't know what
the [ __ ] is MD URL and mi mini mist like
what the [ __ ] are they
so in order to actually so you have to
so apparently you know you have to build
this now I'm not familiar you know if
you guys code JavaScript you can tell me
like how to build it I I have to like
look up documentation but
apparently you have to build this
library and there's dependencies and
then there is let's see script this mpm
package [ __ ]
mpm is the most one of the most nasty
thing okay let me tell you guys the
story that's why the creator of notjs
uh Ryan Dah his name is Ryan Dah the
creator of NJS about 15 years ago that
made JavaScript hugely popular. The
creator of Ryan Dah created NJS
then after two years he kind of let
other people run it. Then the other
people uh what's his name? The leader
his name I forgot what's his name you
know he created MPM
which is a nasty crap. So Ryan D saw it.
He regretted it because that's really
nasty. He doesn't, you know, but there's
nothing he can do. He already left the
project. So after 10 years, he created
Deno. Okay, which is what I use. And I
highly recommend Deno. Den O. Okay, so
you use Deno. So Deno don't have this
mpm like like you you you download one
package and it downloads 10 others and
each one download 10 others. There's no
way to stop there. So every time you
download some mpm it download 1,000
packages coming come to your to sit in
your computer.
[ __ ] this Zuma idiots. And the the the
Zuma generation they don't know a thing.
This is normal. What are you talking
about? This is normal. This is how you
code. You don't know how to code mpm.
You know this zuma idiots.
Okay. Uh dependencies and engine
directories and then dev dependencies.
Okay. So if you're going to dev this
then you need this this this [ __ ]
Oh god. Load dash, you know, like low
dash the [ __ ] You don't know how to
code, you [ __ ] You need low dash.
Oh god.
Yeah. So that's a situation. So
very sad. That's a story of JavaScript.
Now if we look at other programming
language like Golens
uh markdown to HTML it would be much
better. Okay, you would get one single
file. Okay, and also Python probably but
JavaScript is a different story. Okay, I
I got to go. So that's it for today.
Thank you for uh guys for watching. We
shut down in two minutes. I'm just going
to read some uh comments and see
Uh, thanks for the update. We don't see
your screen, by the way. Oh [ __ ]
[laughter]
Oh [ __ ] That's so bad. Did I talk for
half an hour? [ __ ]
Kind of [ __ ] wasted because I was
talking about code. This is important to
see the code. Kind of wasted 30 minutes,
but I got to go.
Oamio says, "Hi, I just built a podman
container to help me transcribe
faster.
What is part man container?
Okay, back. I feel frustrated because of
the I forgot to turn the screen back on.
[ __ ] [ __ ] So anyway, let me let me
go back a little bit. Okay, so you can
see the code. Let me show you the screen
just a bit. So you can see the code you
are using import from 2015, but they are
using VA. That's before 2015.
And then I was I was showing you guys
entities. Okay, on this page I'll link
to my talk show.
So you can see entities, okay? Entities
like there's thousands of math symbols.
Um,
okay. You see they they created that
[ __ ]
Okay. Shut down. So copy that. Go back
here. Go back here. close that comment
mark. So we, you know, we did a get
clone.
Here's the code. We did get clone of
that comment mark. And uh let's go back.
So close that. Go back and paste the
link here about entities. [ __ ] [ __ ]
Forgot to turn my v uh screen back. Bye
guys. I gotta go.