hello guys welcome to another episode of
star talk show
we are going to do emac like uh emac
beast coding today emac this coding so
i'm going to do a live coding of emac
this of a html command and i'm going to
demonstrate it i'm going to show you i'm
going to talk about html mod
then
the main thing is that we are going to
modify this command so there is
something uh i need to do so
so while i'm coding it i'm gonna teach
you some emac this tutorial
so if you are here
if you are new say hi say hi and ask me
questions okay so let's begin let me
double check my video check audio check
one last time video check audio check
that's good okay so emac this code so
let me let me let me demonstrate this uh
so you are looking at my uh html uh
source code for this page because i talk
show today's talk show so the command
we are going to work on is this one
html pre-code to new file so let me
demonstrate what that means okay
so for example i'm going to for just
like oakmod if you have used oakmod
before
okay so
let me show you okay
uh
org mod tutorial so you can find my
ogmag
oakmod tutorial
um
closure mod uh
ogma tutorial
okay search for it
yeah okay so
it's not showing up on the first result
okay sardi
pokemon tutorial let's hope that shows
okay it didn't find it but let's just go
to emacs tutorial then you'll find it so
emacs tutorial let's turn javascript
so i have a tutorial on org mod so you
just go to emacs
emacs
click on that and the org mod tutorial
is somewhere here
so shell
view special file editing brackets org
mod there it is ogma tutorial so there
are actually several pages about it so
ogmod is fantastic you know i don't use
it because i'm
i've been coding html since 25 years ago
so for me
coding html with my customized html mod
is much more efficient
uh and flexible
than oakmod so
in fact what i'm going to show you is
one of the feature in oak mod that is
also in html so for example in oak mod
uh passing org mod customization augment
for to do source code markup yeah so in
oakmod as you know you can markup
programming language source code you
know you can include emac bs code python
code
ruby code golem code or any number of
programming language code and this is
how you do it so you have a shortcut key
to do it and to insert this smart curve
and then you can type or insert you know
code and then you can run the code
you know so oakmod has this kind of um
uh
feature that allows you to embed code in
it and also run code in in in your notes
kind of like wolfram research notebook
like
like pool means
poo poo man's um
you know
uh notebook anyway so
so let me show you ogmat so ogmod so you
have these features right
now if you don't know you know look it
up so
check out my website so okay let's copy
it here
and uh
okay so that's called ogmod ba
okay this this feature was called babel
because originally it was a separate you
know old
mod extension written by this guy
uh written by eric schut okay so
then but now after a few years it become
part of oakmont so it's you know it
supports many languages c c plus plus d
r
orc
closure css
uh emac this is our fortran haskell and
and so on javascript and so on
so let me show you that feature in html
mod okay so let's say i want to start a
javascript source code so i press a key
which calls the command kasa insert
pre-tag okay so let me show you again
uh
cancel you see
insert pre-tag okay so anyway let me do
it press the key
then select a language js for javascript
okay so you can see i got a javascript
uh
uh you know markup there so i can now
i can say console
log
and uh
three that will just print three you
know let's say just three plus four
you know so that's javascript code now
if i uh let's let's use console okay now
i can pop up this source code into a
dedicated buffer so i just press a key
you know so
you see it creates a buffer
with javascript mod you know i'm using
uh let's see
you see i'm using some javascript mod
you know usually you know i have my own
mod for
most languages i code so
you know but for you it can become the
standard javascript mod in emacs you
know so anyway so i press a key
then
then this marker pops out you can see
then becomes a new buffer so i can
actually run this code not line you know
i press a key to run this code you can
see the result is three
okay so
you can see the command i called is for
example xsa run current file
and
and uh
html pre code to new file that's that's
a command that pops out the code into
this new buffer
so let's let's run some command so
console.log let's say uh
magnify three plus four okay run it okay
you can see it's seven okay now i'm done
let's say i'm i'm done with the code i
want to move them back to the html so i
press a key then you can see i'm back in
my html file and showing browser
there it is that's a javascript code
so that's a feature
inside html mod similar to the oak
barbell babel oak bible feature okay
so that is the demonstration of that and
let me show you so okay so let me show
you some
html mod you have to pay me okay so it's
open source but you pay me to get it
okay so
i call describe key
then i press the key
to activate
html mod so that which is this key okay
so you can see the documentation focus
on html pops up
it's this one so you can see
you know you have many commands to deal
with html tags and so on you know 30
commands or so
then you can then i i go to um
you know there's a url so that's my
website so open that
press enter to open that so
so this is uh
html mod and i did several video talks
about it you can watch it and learn what
is a feature
uh if you like it you know i've been for
the past two years two or more
every my youtube is using
html mod
pay me and get it okay
uh and okay so you know on this home
page i show several features
okay so so so
we demonstrated one of the feature which
is the you know embedding source code of
programming languages and let's show in
browser again you can see we can also
press a key to syntax color this one so
for example i press a key
okay so you can see
it adds span tag function name so now if
you refresh in browser refresh you can
see
certain
uh words are colored
you know including strings and so on
okay so now
now
now here is uh any any comments
blz brz hello from brazil
hello to brazil so now
we have demonstrated this uh command xy
html pre-code to new file
and now
comes to the part where i want to modify
the
modify the code let me tell you what
needs to be done
so for example i
you see so here is a javascript code
let's show the ping window javascript
code
i press the key it pops out
you know so i can uh
let let's have some
let's code something so constant x
equals to a array
three four five okay
then let's just say print x
so you can see different colors okay run
that
so you can see array now let's say the
array the first element
index zero print it you can see
the result is three okay so
and now
i press a key to move them back to the
html file showing browser you can see
it's here and i press the key
to color it
go back to browser refresh you can see
it's colored
okay but now here's here's what i want
to do now let's pop out this source code
okay
there's a key problem pop sim now how
does it work you see
where does this buffer uh where is this
new buffer
you see so if you go to diode you know
jump to diode this is a very convenient
command command that will jump to
the directory emacs directory feature
directory
where this current buffer file is at so
i press the key to jump to it you can
see this is the file
okay and
it's in the directory of startup show
which is the directory you know of this
page
so you can see here's a file
now let's magnify okay now let's hide
those details so here's a file and the
problem is the file is kind of too long
so you look at the file name so you see
the file name
embeds information
it embeds the information where
this source code
is originally you know which html file
is this
this temporary source code from
so you see that's not talk show
so that is a file so if we go back to
you know this file
you know you and then you you jump on
direct and you see
that's a file you see
you see
so this temporary javascript file embeds
invest information about where it came
from
the original html file and then
kind of a date
date time stamp you know
so
so so that make sure the file name will
be unique now the problem is the file is
kind of too long
you know sometimes it's a long file it's
not good
the uh that's one of the issue file name
too long okay the
the other issue is okay so let me
let's write down the problem
problem
file name too long
and the other issue is that
not
desirable it's not desirable to have a
temp file
um
you know basically basically you are
little intent file all over the place
over your directory like wherever
wherever your current html file is it'll
create a temp file there
you see now let's let's go to the file
now let's move them back to html okay do
it okay it's back to html now if you go
to the directory
and refresh
okay it's deleted
right so you know so
that's good
but still you know it might
be it may not be desire desirable
okay let me write down the reason may
not be desirable
to
liter
10 files
or over directory so in other words
it's possibly better to create this temp
file in a designated
directory for temp files
okay so we are going to do that
so first of all name too long we need to
fix then
you know and then create a temp file in
some some directory instead of the
current directory
so we updated you know problem found
them to too long okay so
add a break
so that's uh so that's that is what we
are going to fix now okay
now we already talked for 20 minutes so
let me do it quickly
hey real tito hey hello brazil friends
so
so now we are going to modify the code
okay so
so let's jump to the code okay so this
is this is the code i mean this is the
command name
describe function
uh okay copy describe function paste so
here's the documentation for this
function html pre-code to new file
it's an interactive disclosure this
function in
htmlmod dot yeah okay it's bound to the
key so that's the key i press
and this is documentation this is this
syntax and here is what it does create a
new file in current directory with
content from currentpre element okay
you know then for example and so on
so now i can just press tab to jump to
the link
so we can jump to we jump to directly to
the source code of this command we are
about to modify it okay
so
we gonna modify this code okay so first
of all
first of all
copy the code create a new buffer paste
it and save it okay because we we are
going to work on this with a new file
so for the date so
kind of
so i create so okay so we create a temp
file to work on this code
so
so now remember the thing we need to fix
is
make it use a temp file
in of a designated directory okay
now now if you have questions just ask
me okay
uh make this
into a temp file you have a designated
directory okay uh okay now we start to
code now this is gonna
be uh a lot thinking you know i try not
to
be stuck too much
but that's the nature of coding you have
to actually you know fairly complex
okay so this code is 50 lines about 40
lines minus the comma 40 lines
so instead of creating a file in the
current directory you want to create a
file in your temp directory so first of
all
which temp directory
we do we want it to be so that's the
first question
which temp
should it be okay
now normally now
now let's go to my emacs init okay
so you can see this is my emacs init
file let's jump dire jump again let's
dial jump to the file location here it
is and here is a directory you know my
home directory.emax.e
so one of the possible
fixed
temp directory is in the emacs directory
so
so for example i can just create a
directory named temp okay
for example here
so
so i can say my command should use this
as a temp directory so let's copy it
okay
close that so
possibilities okay one of them is just
whatever e-max
your e-max indeed file is at you know
that's a
the other possibility is uh in each
operating system you have designated
temp directory for example in unix it's
um
[Music]
slash tmp i believe you know
in the root directory slash ph tnp in
mac it's some somewhere else okay imac
it's in the user directory slash
i believe slash applications
uh
no slash libraries or something
and on windows there's also temp
directory so
we can look at that so let's go to temp
directory so let's see
so we are looking at the c directory
and where is the temp directory
okay it's not in the yeah it's in your
in your personal directory okay so it's
not here so it's
so in
in on windows
it's at let me show you okay
so go to my emacs
app data you know you go to app data
app data
yeah god windows is fairly confusing
let's see local
temp there it is this is one of them you
know so
so on windows the upgrade operating
system wide
designated temporary directory is
at least one of them is
you know app data local in temp in your
home directory so you can see we have
lots of temp files here you know a bunch
of garbage
so let's close that close that so the
question is
where do we um
i forgot where is it um
okay so the other option is uh let's
just say
so one of the option is
you know dot emacs temp the other option
is
yeah let's go back to it again
appdata
local temp okay copy the directory close
close
then we can paste it here
there
and delete that
so here are the two possible locations
for temporary file which one should it
be
uh so let me tell you my experience so
this is a software
you know if you are a software engineer
if you are a coder
you know you're writing software this is
one of the decision you have to make
so
in my personal experience of coding in
the past 30 years
i think the answer is that there is no
absolute answer
so i mean so the question is whether you
should use the
application specific temp directory for
example emacs e-max is kind of a
well-known application and for emacs you
have a
designated
config file you know directory for your
config files and stuff
or you can use operating system-wide
designated temp directory on mac on
windows on unix each one is different
but they have a fixed temp directory so
which one should you use so in my
personal experience there's no
one correct answer
so i mean either one either way you can
do it you can do so in our case
i think
i'm i'm going to go with the emacs
you know
the application designated directory so
so first of all so we have to define a
var okay define var
temper let's say
xa
temp
the
path okay
so we have to define this variable
the optional initial initial value okay
so
let's say neo okay and docstring
temp
used by xa commands
star packages okay
so here's a documentation for this you
know path and we need to set it so let's
set it
so where do we want it so
well we can
you know we decided it's gonna be this
okay
and instead of using the brief let's use
the full well let's use a three but you
know the tioda
tear dot
the tilda symbol
in emacs
expands to the home directory so
on my machine my username is
so the tier i expand to the c drive use
excel okay
uh
you know normally you should use full
path but in e-max
this is uh
the tilde is widely accepted
no problem
but if you are coding for example in
python in ruby
in golan
then you better not use that but in
emacs it's uh
accepted
okay so i'm giving you some kind of tips
from experience
so
so we want the temp directory so
actually you know the temp directory is
not created so you have to write code to
make sure it's created you know if and
also that
also
you know the emacs in its init file is
not always that
so you want there's a variable in e-max
that specifies where is your
emacs init
file directory so we want to use that
variable because not everyone is using
the emacs.d especially on windows
so and also even on linux there's many
different conventions you know over the
past 30 years it changes every
every seven or ten years
so in fact right now in linux the latest
convention is not
dot emacs.d instead it's something else
i i have a blog about that so anyway
so right now we want to find the
variable
the emax variable that specifies where
your config directory path is okay so
let's try to do that
so in order to do that let's go to um
let's go to um
emacs tutorial so because i have a info
there that's the easiest way for me to
find it so emacs tutorial
then you go to where to download emacs
on windows
okay so
wait okay so you go back to emacs
tutorial then you go to emacs init
so this is all about emacs you need
setup then you click on emacs init file
then
you can see the different conventions
for the init file location and the
current one
is
home directory dot config slash dot
config that's the current
latest convention since emacs 27 about
two years ago so
so you know i'm still using the previous
convention
starting starting in 2010 you know dot
emacs dot d
okay so but
we want to know the variable here so
user emacs directory so this is a
variable
that
whose value is a file path to your emacs
directory so let's try it okay paste the
variable name and now let's call
describe variable
and you can see the documentation so
yeah so user emacs directory is a
variable defined in this file and its
value is uh you know
tier.emacs.d okay so this is the
variable we want
so uh wait let's see
yeah so
so the file path would be
you need to join string okay so
join stream uh how do you join string
concocting okay
so in emacs the join stream
function
is concat
okay so you want this variable first
then you want to
say temp okay temp is the directory
okay then
then you need to check if that exists
okay so so delete that actually so we
can just put it here
okay so that is uh wait hold on before
we do that
let's put it here okay so this this code
sets the temp directory but now we need
to check if that directory exists
because if it does not we need to create
it okay
so
file exists p okay expand so that's a
command
check if that exists okay now we need to
do a if statement
if
the file exists
then do nothing okay
new
otherwise we need to create it so
let's
make the
um i forgot what's the command to create
directory okay
so the easiest way again is for me to
look up my emacs tutorial
so
you go to practical emag lisp
then there is a page about directories
and file path
okay there are file and directory path
click on that
okay file exist
rename file copy file
delete file set file mods
directory files make directory that is
the command we want
yeah
there it is make directory okay
so md
expand to make directory okay that's the
syntax so we want to make a directory
and we want to
yeah so we want to make this directory
so
and parents optional parents
we don't care i don't think so let's
look up the documentation for mac
directory describe function
[Music]
okay
in fact we can see it right here in my
uh
in my website so make 3 directory create
a directory da and optionally any
non-existent parent directories
oh okay that's very convenient
if there already exists as a directory
signal an error unless parent is the neo
yeah okay so i don't okay i don't care
okay
so we make directory then we give a full
path that should be good
actually a better way is actually look
the better way is like that okay
let's
here is a better way
yeah so you want to make a directory
named temp
and the parent directory should be
whatever user emacs user directory
if
okay so whether should we use that or
that
yeah actually
actually let's use the first one because
the first one is more explicit what are
we what we are making directory for you
know we are making a directory for the
extra temp
to a path okay
so predefine the code
so there it is uh making making a
directory now
now let me give you another tip about
emac this coding typically when you have
an if statement and if one of the
clause is nil by emax convention you
usually say when instead so when
so we can do it this way okay
when
not
directory when
when the directory does not exist then
there okay then you make the directory
so
so these two blocks of code are
doing exactly the same thing so uh but
by the emacs kind of style guide usually
the sec this one is preferred okay so
let's let's uh so let's use this one
so here we make sure we create the
directory
let's write the documentation creator if
not exist okay
now
okay now we make sure the directory
exists now what's the next step
uh
so this command will be creating a file
okay so let's go to it let's go to it
let's see somewhere it creates a file
so
pre begin p1 is position you know
buffer position
one the beginning of the
source code p2 is the end of source code
position
language code is what language it is you
know javascript or powershell or bash or
whatnot
text content is the actual source code
okay actual source code we are grabbing
file uh any comments questions fantastic
cortez thank you so much contest contest
is
my lawyer loyal sponsor
okay thank you
uh so there's a question
are you getting the kinesis advantage
360.
did you miss my video because oh yeah
okay so i got a view i got a better i
was the better tester of kinesis
advantage 360. you know the new keyboard
from kinesis i talked about many times
i'm not going to do it today
you know just search for saudi keyboard
so you know kinesis advantage 360 is a
new model that came up
and so i used it for two weeks
and it's fantastic okay but they are
still
better so they don't want me to do a
review they don't want me to show it so
so that's why i didn't show it so it's
fantastic so i would recommend
so which one is better okay is it the
360 better or my the current kinesis
advantage too you know which is what i'm
using
this is actually my second one it's it's
great okay so
i would say
um
it depends on you okay it does it i mean
for my experience it's not one is uh
absolutely better than the other it
depends on you okay
so and i don't want to talk too much
about it because they are you know
you know still making it so
until they give me a go
and if they send me a new one
when it's out then i'm gonna do a review
okay so that's what i'm going to say for
now
okay back to emac this code
uh how many people we have four people
grand total of one two three four
fantastic okay so back to emac this code
so
so here then um so we talked about so
then we have file path extension
so for example for javascript that is
dot js
for python it's dot py for golang is dot
go for wufam language it's um
dot
mb or dot wls wolfram language script
so that's a you know then you have
java.java and so on so that's file name
extension
uh temp file name this part is what we
want you see
very tidy code you see this you know
this this is why when you write a uh
when you code you know when you program
it is
important to
organize your code very well so that
when you need to modify it
you know to maintain like right now we
are doing all we have to do is just
change this part okay temp file name
oh we have that's all we have to do so
here is how it creates temp file name
you see
xx is just a temporary name i mean then
then three variables so you have the
current directory so so this part is the
current directory this part is the file
format basically your timestamp
i mean not format yeah timestamp so so
it's so the file name temp file name is
made of xx starting with xx then comma
then current directory
path then a timestamp then the file name
extension you see so all we have to do
is change this part okay let's let's do
it let's do it here
let's make it outstanding so we can so
we're gonna modify here okay so now file
name now let's go up let's see what is
our
file path okay so basically
the file path should be that okay
that's the temp path okay so now all you
have to do is change the directory part
so the directory part
okay temp file name okay anyway so
[Music]
so temp file name i suppose it will
create a file at that path
so now
let's paste it here first okay
wait let's paste it here
so
so again we are modifying this code and
this is our new
uh
section so
so temp file name let's let's check
tim file name yeah
so
so you so you want to go to
okay let's let's modify it okay so let's
start to modify it
act and the
the creating directory
should be
should be the code should be here okay
okay so if the directory does not exist
create a directory then
okay now we need to give it a program
which is collection of code
okay so the the progn is kind of the
curly braces in c it just group a bunch
of this code
it's very useful and important because
you know the code
because
over here you know over the let
block basically you have a variable name
then this part needs to be a value
so this part needs to be a value so
basically the the last thing we return
will be the value will be this one yeah
so first of all
make sure it exists
then if it exists we need to create a
file name okay so yeah so this is just
the path you're also missing the file
name so the file name so we actually
need this um
so let me show you okay so we need to
join stream
the first part is the directory
okay
join string the first part is the
directory the second part is the file
name okay and how do you get the file
name the file name is gonna be here okay
so let's do it here
so you can see emac these the nesting
parenthesis there now it's now it's
easier to see
so join stream
first of all
the directory then we are going to
create a file name so the file name will
be named um
xx
so you don't need a directory part
anymore you just need
yeah so you just need the
time stamp
and
you need the timestamp and you also need
um
the file name extension okay so let's
double check
yeah so x
followed by timestamp followed by file
name extension so this part is your
short file name
okay directory file name
that should be correct
okay
okay that
basically this solves the problem so
this part we don't need anymore so this
solves the problem
of
you know creating a temp file
path
but there is another issue because now
you see before
uh where is original file name let's see
so
[Music]
hold on a second let's go back to the
html code
let's let's try this again
okay let's see you see this is our
javascript code you see
the pre-tag
you see i can remove the pre-tag you see
undo
remove the pre-tab and do so this is the
code now let's
create it let's make it pop it out
so you can
see right now it's creating a temp file
in the current directory you can see
that the current directory you know
and it's using a file name
and the file name
the file name contains the original
html html file path
now that information is important
you see the where the file came from
this information is important because
because now i can press the key it will
pop pop it back to the original html
file you see
pop it out you see
it's popped up now
this is how it looks like when it's
popped out
it shows you the file path now if you
pop it back
you see
it deletes but the point is that once
you pop it out
once you pop it out
this source code needs to know where is
the original file
and that information is embedded in the
file name
okay but now
since we don't you know since we are
creating the temp file in the temp
directory there is no such embedded
information
you know so we need a way
we need to we need a way to find where
is the original
file okay
so let's pop it back okay show in
browser
okay so let's
yeah so we need to find a way to
encode
where is the original
um
file okay so let's think about
okay so i know what to do
so
so we need to create a new variable
okay so let me show you
we're gonna create a new variable
original
file path okay
and the value of would we or that will
be that okay
file name none directory
buffer file name so buffer file name
returns the file path of the current
buffer okay the full path
yeah so we need the full path uh yeah so
we just need the full path forget about
the other thing
so
so now we have the file original file
path okay
and now
so the problem is we need to store this
information somewhere so original file
path where do you store it you know
yeah so we need another temp file
yeah we can do that you need another
temp file
okay so let's create another
another temp directory i mean another
variable
the this variable will be called
temp file id okay
and that id will be the timestamp okay
let's make sure this is correct
so year month date hour minute
s capital s i believe is second so
describe function on format time string
let's see the documentation
and
so
capital s is the second
okay that that's uh we need microseconds
too actually
n is a nanosecond
and let's see what end does
okay it's capital n let's see what the
end does okay
create a new buffer
magnify
let's say format string
capital n
i want to know how many digit is that oh
okay
yeah so that's the microseconds
you see i want to know the microsecond
because you know
right now what we have is just second
but second
cannot necessarily guarantee that the
file name is unique
but if you use micro second
that's good enough
actually second is
[Music]
pretty good enough because it's rare
it's
almost never happens
where you pop out a file
like within one second you do it twice
it's not likely so let's just use second
okay let's then let's add some random
string
okay so let's add some random string
random
random pseudo random integer
so random from limit let's say 100 okay
yeah let's say 100 pseudo random integer
okay then we need to
concat this okay so let's let's let's
work on this okay
so we need
concat
one is this
concact
timestamp
followed by
a
underscore let's say
followed by
that okay let's predefine the code so
okay so we
have time string timestamp
then underscore then just random number
that will make sure
this file name is unique okay that's
good enough
so yeah we don't need this part anymore
okay so we got original file path
what time is it
we
already did almost an hour now okay so
we got original file path that's the
html file
we got the temp file id
okay that should be unique okay
then
then we want to add it here
um
yeah so here is the temp file id
right okay
and which is part of the temp file name
cookies or flamio so what's what's up
everyone am i doing good
is the
emac list
live coding and explanation are they
good
let me know okay good say good
if it's no good it's unclear say unclear
if it's boring say boring okay it's if
it isn't you know it's on topic
interesting
and you know you are learning something
about coding or emac this you know say
say good
um okay so
we have temp file name okay so let me
see it
so we got original file path temp file
id
10 file name okay 10 file name
we need so this is uh
yeah ok so 10 file name okay that's all
good
now this code is ready to go except
except now we need to
um
in create another temp file for the
original that contains the original file
path okay
so let's say temp file name two okay
yeah so okay so
let's do it here
10 file name
or reach okay that means this temp file
will contain
the original file path okay
so let's do it
10 file original so
and where it will it be located it will
be located something like this okay so
it's just so let's just copy the code
so the directory is already corrected we
don't need to worry about that
then
[Music]
then contact temp the file path
then the file name
so the file name now will be
you don't need the file extension you
just need text okay
and
in format
yeah temp file id dot text
and now let's say dot
let's say dot or reach
okay let's say dot origin.txt
okay so this stem file engine
will be a
file path and this file path
will be in the temp directory and it
will be named
with temp file id.oh.txt
and the content of this file
will be
[Music]
that
okay so in fact we can actually create a
file
so
you know we're gonna we're gonna create
this right away uh
so how do you create a file
of a given file path that's what we need
to do create a file with a given file
path hello guys great fantastic keep it
going fantastic thank you guys
so now the problem is how do you create
a file of a given file path
okay there are many ways
um
yeah there are many ways but what is the
most direct and efficient way you know
for example one way is just to create a
buffer then save it
but that may not be so efficient so
let's look at my own tutorial so
so here this one is file
file and directory functions okay
now we need a
let's see write file okay
right region
right file
okay write file write the buffer content
to a file okay create a new file yeah
this is probably the best if you want to
create a new file with uh use with temp
file okay
so with temp file file path and body
exactly
that's what we are going to do
with temp file okay
so we are going to actually
create a file so with temp file
okay
then the file path will be
[Music]
the file path will be that
then the
the body of the file will be
it will simply contain the original
files file path that
uh wait does does it create a temp new
buffer make it current evaluate body and
write the buffer to file yeah
exist existing file at that is
overwritten yeah the value return is the
value of the last four mean body okay
that's what we want to use
you know simply
create a temp file
okay now let's shrink let's pretty find
the code shrink so you can see the hole
but
this part
you know we cannot do it here because
here right now it's the let
you know the let block
so
uh
wait yeah so we need to move this line
somewhere else let's see
create a temp file uh so
here is temp file name of
original
yeah okay let's let's for the simply for
simplicity
shake let's
just move it
the code somewhere so
okay so now
you see
uh wait what is this
okay let's clean the code okay let's
shrink them shrink them shrink them
shrink and shrink them
so that you can see
this whole block
you know from here to here
that's the let there's a bunch of
variables
and now
what follows is the actual code
so somewhere here is
uh
creating the file okay so
speed window below delete region go to
char insert temp file name
yeah then
switch to buffer
buffer disable undo
if major mod set it to the right major
mod javascript or gold line or whatever
insert text content that's a source code
um
[Music]
then remove the html
markup you know like coloring the
functions and so on
and write file so here is the part so
you write file
now if if the file is java you have to
do something special because for java
basically you are compiling you you need
to compile the file and for java
the class name and the file name
needs to be identical
so you cannot simply use a random file
name
so for java it's a special case but if
it's not java
then simply use temp file name right
okay
so write to file so this part actually
yeah so we are we are in a buffer
then we
insert the content the source code then
we write to the temp file okay
okay so now we need another block to
write file okay yeah
right here
so with temp file
temp file name original in original file
path okay i think that's it
okay i think that's it so
okay am i doing good
okay so now let's evaluate let's
evaluate the buffer okay so you know we
created the temp file
let's evaluate that show the ping window
evaluate
then also evaluate that
so now describe variable x the path
you
see
it's right there that's correct okay
tempter used by xr packages that's right
let's modify the capitalized t
there okay
then
eval this function okay
now let's now let's test
what is this don't want this anymore
uh do you want to save no
okay now let's go back to html file
there
so now if we pop out how about this
javascript code you can see this
javascript if we pop it out
we
will see the file will be created in a
in a in a new temp directory not the
current directory so the current
directory is the talk show
not here okay so
let's see if it works okay
pray to god
cross my heart
okay so it's let's call it okay
wrong type argument wrong type argument
sequence p87 what the
you can see you see here's the error
message run type argument sequence
so
it requires a sequence which means
a vector or a list
or a string
but however
emac this got 87
you know so apparently we are calling a
function that requires a
list
or vector but it got 87 instead so let's
see where where did we go wrong
okay wait
uh
let's go back to the code where did we
go wrong sequence p
it needs a
sequence but got 87 instead
i don't know where but let's go back
let's do it again and let's now turn on
watch the pink window okay i press three
keys watch the pink window
so you see i just turned down
toggle debugging arrow
now i'm going to call the command again
and when if there's an error it will pop
up detailed error messages instead of
just you know wrong type of argument
okay so let's call this again
there it is okay expand the window okay
wait expand
magnify
so wrong type argument sequence now it
got 41 okay concact okay
the error happened somewhere in concat
so we are concocting what
charset window no that's not good char
set window what
so it's you know calling this command
pre-code to new file then a bunch of
variables i mean the local variables so
the error happens somewhere in this
local variables block
and it happens with the concat let's
jump to it
no you cannot jump to it
okay so i know i know what's going on so
let's go back to
concact right here so
so let's you know we have to think about
this
so concact happened well oh concat
happened several places
ah where did it happen let's go let's do
it again
concat
timestamp
oh then random number okay concat
timestamp so i know where that is
so
go back
yeah so the problem is here
oh okay i got it so here you see random
function returns a number
but however
concact is
joining strings
so this random
you need a string instead you need to
convert to string so okay let me show
you how do you modify this
so we're gonna so so what we can do is
number two string
okay
that'll work
another way now this is getting you know
another way is simpler okay let me show
you
okay so
copy that so
another way is
just say format okay format
okay format
prefi format give it two things
okay
percent as you know two strings so the
first one is format string
oh actually then
underscore okay so
this code and this code and this code
are
effectively identical
okay and uh you know
and usually this one is preferred
it's simpler shorter and easier to read
okay so let's remove that
so it's so we don't have to call number
two string like
that's actually less efficient another
function call so remove that
remove that pretty fine
eval the buffer okay back to html let's
do it
fantastic
okay we got something wrong
so anyway it kind of worked
so you can see
the html file it creates a temp file
over here and the temp file is over here
it worked so
but however the temp file name is not
what we wanted you see
you see it didn't
it it didn't create an attempt directory
instead of you know so we got the
directory uh
path kind of wrong
okay so
so open that deleted open that
also this is wrong
deleted
okay
temp is still empty okay so
undo and what
ha no further than doing regions
something is up
i up something
okay so save it close it just in case we
reopen it you know usually in when you
call emac these sometimes you want to
close a file to get rid of you know
a bunch of local variables you know
likes
like restarting emacs you know like if
you code a lot emac this
it's very helpful to restart emacs when
you after a session because it clears up
all the bunch of local variables you
know buffer local and
complexities and
and other times you want to just close
the buffer
and reopen it
these commands are part of software keys
you know so i can just close close
close back trace close scratch close you
know reopen
reopen
it kind of
uh clear all the
local variables you might have set so
anyway so
so now we go back to the code we kind of
know the problem
the magnify again
so the problem is that it when it
creates the file
uh the directory is incorrect so let's
go
yeah so we created
the temp file
team file name
okay creator if not exists concact
and wait
why is it not
let's describe variable
oh you don't have the empty
you know so here is another tip
in emacs convention
in emacs convention a directory should
always ends in a slash
okay
and
let's see user emacs directory describe
variable
okay
yeah so
in e-max convention
whenever you have a variable for
directory that should always end in a
slash
now this convention is very different in
unix and linux this is important you
know because i have
for my years of experience so in
basically in linux and unix whenever you
have a variable for directory usually
you don't want to you don't want it to
end in a slash
but in
emacs this you do okay so it's that's a
kind of a
thing you pick up because otherwise
you're gonna learn it in a hard way
so okay so now we
so the temp file name let's double check
so
so the temp file the path
exam
the path
so it's a directory path that's a slash
then temp okay
and evaluate this okay then
and it's search
so we make sure
we
if it doesn't exist we created
yes
then
then the temp file name will be the
directory path
slash you forgot about the slash
okay
slash wait
oh wait wait yeah the path already has a
slash yeah no that's good
okay
eval the buffer
go back to html code
magnify
okay now let's do it
let's make it like that it's here easier
okay
fantastic
did it work well yes it did
you know so we created
our code
10 file directory you know this random
type this timestamp plus a random number
and the file is right here go to the
directory there it is our temp file
uh
you know
temp file and there's something wrong
here you see here is the original file
path
this temp file should contain the
original file path but now it's empty so
we need to
we need to insert it
so for now
uh let's let's go back to html undo yeah
okay that's good and do undo and do
and something is
okay there's something wrong i need to
fix okay
to do that
okay let's go back to the code
so
so the problem we need to fix now is
so you created the temp tim file that's
successful yeah we need to insert
original file path in the other temp
file
so that would be here
with temp file let's see
documentation
create a new buffer evaluate body there
yeah so we need to say insert
okay
insert
that
we forgot to say that
okay
run the code
run
run the code go to html close it reopen
magnify
now let's do it
okay now jump to the die directory now
you can see
there it is this is original file open
it it contains the original
uh html files file path fantastic
oops
okay so fantastic
okay so
that is almost done you know that is
almost done for today's function we
already did uh 90 minutes or 80 minutes
okay
this is not complete yet
because now you cannot pop up
you see
normally i can press a key to
pop up
pop out you know
pop back this code into the html but now
it doesn't work because
before
it relies on the file name that has the
embedded original file path but now it's
you know in a different name so
so the command to pop this back into the
html is called is this okay
it's this one
tml pre-code back so we need to modify
that command so we can actually jump to
it
jump to it jump to the source code
open it
so you can see
here's a code
so
okay so i have two choices either stop
it for today
or continue with this
one so which one should i do uh i'm
thinking of stopping now because
it's
uh 80 minutes already
hey i came late what are we working on
you came late we are about done
uh so
two choices if i start to cover this
or that's it for today uh because
you know pretty we did a lot already
today and uh
as far as this function is concerned
it's done it's job done so in fact let's
move it back to
html mod
okay so let's move back to html mod
okay first of all
um
first of all copy that
okay wait
cut
delete
back to html back to exhaust talk show
so we did the code
let's let's put it here somewhere so
start a new code let's show the ping
window
so you can see all my commands and
keystrokes where our keyboard and
software keys okay now create a new code
emac this yes
paste the code
showing browser
so you can see
this is the code we did today where what
yeah so this
you know what this
this is the code you know this is the
code we did today but however it's not
rendered correctly in html because
because we have html tags here so what
we need to do is we need to call
syntax called ah god
and
this is issued
yeah whenever you have that it's a
problem
okay
you know i can explain them but
because the you know what's happening
here it's not rendered correctly is
because the source code actually
contains html tags so html got confused
so what you do what you need to do is
actually you need to encode this
um
this html
tags
so one easy way is
that okay but
you know then you refresh now you can
see
it's better but then it happens
somewhere else
so
yeah so this is becoming kind of tedious
because this code
this is okay let me let me let me
say something that's more constructive
and useful okay
now whenever you have recursion
typically it's a problem like
right now this problem occur is because
you have html file
html source code
that contains the source code of another
language emac bisp
and this emac this source code contains
source code of html
so
this is typically a very nasty problem
happens everywhere for example when you
are in emacs we are writing a some
command that calls xiao and you need to
pass the string let's say you need to
pass a regular expression
you know in string you have lots of
escape escape so when you pass when you
pass to xiao you have to deal with those
escapes you know so basically
you have to encode a code
that's a problem you you have to encode
the code sometimes several levels so
right now for example
in order to solve this problem
we have to encode
the html which is for example escape
this
you know this uh
angle brackets by
ampersand you know less than you know
and so on entities html so you have to
encode them
and normally i can press the key
it will encode the whole
um
it doesn't even work now it will encode
the whole source code
uh like
let me shrink so you can see you see
normally i can press a key
it will encode all html you know angle
brackets
you know do it one shot but i cannot do
it now
because when i call the command
first of all it'll try to find
you know they'll try to find the
beginning of the tree
you know class some language he'll try
to find that
then he will try to find
the end of the pre
you see
but however the problem is the pre
that you know those
beginning and that happens inside the
code it happens here you know right here
for example
it happens here
and it also kind of happens there you
see that pre
and you it also happens um
[Music]
uh do we have an end pre maybe not okay
so
so the point is you are encoding some
code inside another you know nested
recursive encode that's a problem
if the languages are all different for
example if i'm in html
and you this is e-mag this which is
entirely different
but however it's i'm not dealing with
html code then no problem
but however when you have a nested
encoding
it creates a very nasty problem
that is almost impossible to solve
programming programmed materially
programmatically
okay so that's kind of a useful tip
but anyway so
what are we doing now so anyway we
finished coding this
so for the
for the for the rest of the problem i'm
gonna do it offline
okay
um
and what else um
[Music]
yeah so it's now uh
it's now a 90 minutes talk show okay
that's it thank you guys for watching
uh bye
so now i'm gonna shut down i'm gonna
copy my code to part of um
html mod okay
okay so here is my
html mod
so here is the code
pre-code back okay not big real bad
yeah so we're gonna replace this
function this is old version
cut it out
new buffer
save it xx
date
function name
underscore old dot el okay
save it for backup
close that
now the new one
the new one is here so let's copy it
cut it
paste it okay so let's shrink it
so we have just so this is the code we
did today
and let's clean up we don't need this
commented out
thing
clean up
cleaning up
okay
and add version date at today's date
this kind of modification date so remove
the previous one
okay
so you can see
this is what we did today
okay and we also created two temp
uh
temp path
you know
and this
delete we don't need that
okay
and make a backup so this is go to all
the way to the top this is
html mod if you like it pay me okay buy
it
now add today's date timestamp version
number change
18.8 to 18.9 okay
and
make backup again
and let's jump to yeah so let's
go to
isha
then git status
okay well i made changes so let's say
git add
exci html
okay
then git commit
then
now use uses a template
okay so this is a message
the changes to
that command
you know that's a change git commit
fantastic
now you are looking at uh this directory
this sar emacs
so this is kind of like so emacs
and this contains all my packages
you know html images and so on
so close that close that close that
so we wrote this new function fantastic
we
so it uses a designated template
okay now
close that
okay so
yeah let's remove that
and
clean up open this javascript
okay yeah the
pop back doesn't work
so in that case
cut it
delete the file
paste it here okay
and color it
in showing browser okay that is because
that is
today's xl talk show
bye