test
test hello good morning good evening
good evening good evening everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
we are going to code wolam language
Mathematica on Geometry plan curves so
let me show you my keyboards glove at
Fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard
fantastic newa track B
fantastic and this ultimate device this
this is
called
yeah this is called SW
board uh SW board okay s v a l b o a r d
now this active so it's connected so you
know it's all
magnetic I did something mag mag
magnetic sensors okay s v a l b o a r d
so for each one of these devices I have
reviews on my website and on YouTube so
search for
it now back to the screen okay so we uh
let's
begin okay I press some key that started
a new emac
instance so what happens so close that
okay so we're going to code wolam
language today
so geometry okay mathematics geometry
fantastic if you if you are here say hi
if you are not here uh play at 1.5 speed
and jump around because I ramble all
over hello
tjack okay mathematics let's begin so
usually nobody is here and that means I
just going to do my stuff okay hyperbola
I we introduce this subject many times
this is plane curves a visual dictionary
of special plane curves uh project I did
since
1994 okay so it was the most popular
website on the web in the throughout the
1990s and uh uh
2000s one of the most popular math
website so linked by like over a
thousand universities okay so anyway so
I'm going to update this because many of
these are eight like 30 years old
graphics for example this is hyperbola
and we just updated so this is new Fresh
Image but uh but you can see as you
scroll down you'll see 30 years old
images you see these are 30 30 years old
images so we're going to uh redo them
today okay that and uh these two for
example okay so showing
browser jump to hypera open it showing
browser okay okay at the top there is MB
that's wolam language notebook open it
open
it so you are seeing the wolam language
notebook source
code and here is 100 ml red wine to
soothe my soul am I doing good video
check audio
check say hi okay comment
okay open the notebook source code make
a copy go to the directory so you can
see we got a copy close that close that
close that go to the wve language
notebook now is the font large enough
yeah kind of uh we can magnify it one
more okay so now let's so this is 30
years old but what we want to do today
let's try to do this one
okay this is called pedo so if you uh
let me explain the mathematics okay this
is called pedo
curve okay
so so there's quite a few let's see yeah
so one one image is that the other one
is that uh pedo curve of the hyperbola
with respect to
the center and here is the pedal curve
of hyperbola with respect to the
focus uh it's very fascinating because
the pedal curve of a hyperbola turns out
with respect to the focus then you get a
circle how beautiful you know you got a
circle right
there am I doing
good okay you got a circle right there
uh but when you have a ped curve with
respect to the
uh with to the center then you get this
curve which is called lemiscate okay
which is another famous curve like
figure eight shaped lcap of Boni I
believe so you can go to my visual
dictionary of special plan curves go to
hypera click click and go down then
you'll see the pedal curve section
properties okay so Point Wise
Construction Optical
property pedo now I'm not sure that's
pronounced pedo or
pedal uh actually I don't
know you know you never read you never
hear you know uh someone speak it you
have to be in a mass Circle too but this
is this topic uh planker properties is
not a super popular Topic in mathematics
it's not something they will teach you
in school in calculus courses you know
in calculus
courses uh all these are suitable you
know but usually they will cover
hyperbola ellipse Parabola conic
sections as Elementary but some of the
other cisoid of Dios conco of necom
medes quadrix of heas they will not talk
about it they we you know you might see
it in exercise you know like the
exercise 51 uh there is this curve
called quadrix of heas created by hipas
in 2,000 years ago by the Greeks so so
how do you prove this property you know
using the thing you just learned
calculus so sometimes you'll see that
but usually you will not learn about
this so similarly for some of these
spirals archimedian spirals equal
angular Spirals and konu litus and hypot
troid this is the most famous known as
spiral graph they are used in dollar
bills you see if when you see a dollar
bill you you'll see this thing going
crazy you know I learned at only this
year last year that the reason they put
that there this spiral graph so calleded
technically in math it's called hypot
troid okay hypot troid or OT troid so
there's several
um variations OT troid looks like that
and the hypot tro looks like that so the
the reason they put this on dollar B is
that it is very difficult to figure out
you know given the curve it's very
difficult to figure out the paramet
to generate that curve therefore if you
are a counterfeiter you know if you're
going to print money from scratch you
know your your Curve will be different
so that's why they put this in dollar
bills you see all the different
currencies in US dollars in other
countries do uh money so hypot trco it
so this curves
so these are all appropriate subject at
the level of calculus okay so if you are
college students majoring math these are
all good for you uh some of them cover
algebraic geometry basic I mean they are
uh objects of algebraic geometry which
is very Advanced usually that's graduate
level okay but you know you can you know
but but it's easy easy to understand for
beginners you can understand what they
are about so anyway so so that's what
this PL cve
are okay so there you got s and cosine
this look at this
spectacular spectacularly beautiful
Graphics which this one I created I call
Theory
okay uh and the wolam language code is
right here copy it let's let's try to
plot it okay let me just show you
cheers you see how beautiful is
that this is typically called implicit
plot super hello hello The
Violator so I bet you will never use SW
board it will end up in your being no
that's not true
okay so let me talk about that because a
lot of people has been waiting for me to
review this small
board let me digress a little bit okay
so a lot of people has been waiting for
me to review where's my
OBS review
this this fantastic Advanced keyboard
device with Magnetic switches you know
it's not a normal keyboard
board I haven't started to try it
because you know
I'm it takes some time okay so I put it
there it's right on my desk and it's
connected that means uh that reminds me
I actually need to do it but it's been
over a year now but however it's that
situation is common with me sometimes I
have a subject that just sit here there
for sometimes a few
years but I will get to it okay
so thank you for that comment I bet you
will'll never use it you know so that
makes me you know I'm going to try to
use it uh you know take some time to
learn and explore because that's a big
that's that's kind of a big project for
me okay I mean on the other hand you
could say well I mean it's been over a
year and you haven't done anything with
it that's true okay but it's that's kind
of common thing for
me common situation okay so can you
explain flux in calculus please no I
cannot I don't know about
flux what is flux in
calculus c a l c maybe I can explain
after I read it okay so wait where is
the okay turn on the gro turn on the I'm
using the
uh Brave search which has a buildin
artificial intelligence chatbot so I
highly recommend Brave search brave.com
okay and I highly recommend the brave
browser I'm using the brave browser for
my Twitter here okay so I recommend it
download the brave browser or set set
your Google search web search to the
brave.com search engine just in install
a plugin search it you'll find it okay
so let's see what is the flux in
calculus particularly in Vector calculus
flux is a measure of how much a vector
field flows through a
surface okay a vector field flows uh uh
flows through a surface it conies the
amount of a vector field passing through
a given C surface okay taking into
account the strength of the field the
size of the surface and their
orientation relative to each other okay
the concept of flux is often used to
describe the flow of fluids or electric
field through a surface okay I know
what's a
vector you know I know what's a vector
field but but what but they are doing it
onto a surface so that's a that's the
part I'm not sure
um uh I understand okay so you can see
there's you know a lot tutorials these
days on YouTube on K Academy on lots of
places so but let me look up Wikipedia
okay because I prefer there it is
Wikipedia the real
thing so can I explain flux pay me how
much you pay me for my
explanation because my
explanation oh I forgot to switch
back okay because my explanation is um
gives you the gist of things so you
avoid
misunderstanding okay so there it is
flux flux describes any effect that
appears to pass or
travel whether it actually moves or not
through a surface or substance flux is a
concept in Applied Mathematics and
Vector calculus which has many
applications in physics for transport
transport phenomenon flux is a vector
quantity describing the magnitude and
direction of the flow okay of a
substance or property you see so the
thing I don't know is that it's on a
Surface you know so normally a vector
field a vector field can be 2D or 3D or
higher Dimension but let's think of 2D
so Vector field is easy to understand so
you just have a plan for each point you
have a vector okay Vector is basically
just an arrow so for each point you have
a vector so you can see that point will
move to what direction or how much by
the magnitude so when you have a vector
field you can plot it and you can kind
of see the direction of flow like wind
for example if you check
weather you know you check weather map
then usually you will see a vector field
so let me just ramble okay so uh let's
see Vector field uh national and local
weather radar something okay let's go
there uh turn on
JavaScript okay so you got this this is
a countour plot okay that's not a vector
field but can you see are you going to
show Vector field somewhere you know you
see it uh let's see let's look at this
one this is uh this is kind of not
Vector field but
anyway I want to get back to Parabola so
anyway let's read uh in Vector calculus
flux is a scalar quantity defined as the
surface
integral uh of the perpendicular surface
integral of the perpendicular component
of vector field over a surface okay
um yeah okay I cannot explain it okay so
General mathematics definition transport
okay so
flux so you see the key about flux how
they def from a vector field is that
it's applied to a surface so you got the
vector field but applied to a surface
but
um okay so what does it mean so you can
see the graph gets
complicated
uh oh okay so now it should
visually so now you can kind of
understand okay so it's
actually right so the blue the blue
arrows you see here are the normals
meaning that the blue arrows is
perpendicular to the surface okay now
the red arrow is the is the the thing
you want it it's I suppose it's called
flux the red arrow actually show shows
where on that surface at that point
where the force or whatever is going so
these red arrows are the flux the blue
arrow is just perpendicular lines to to
the surface at that point
okay so um but what what I mean so I
don't know the application so you know
this is supposedly related to uh a lot
of
physics I'm not too you see I'm not too
interested in physics in you know in the
math for physics so so that's why this
this subject does not attract
me okay so General mathematical
definition transport okay the field
lines of a vector field the field lines
of a vector field F through surfaces
with the unit normal
n okay that's the normal that's
perpendicular to the surface the field
lines of the vector field
f f okay so this yellow line is the flux
I
suppose a vector field F through the
surface with unit normal n the angle
from n to F is
Theta okay so this is a perpendicular
line to the surface at a point on the
surface then you have another line
that's a flux so this line makes a angle
with the normal so that's
Theta flux is a measure of how much of
the
field passes through a given surface
okay how much of uh fux is measure of
how much of the field passes through a
given
surface f is decomposed into components
perpendicular and parallel to n
okay right
so okay f is the flux okay so right it's
so this flux line so this is
perpendicular normal this flux line it
may may Point anywhere so but this flux
line can be decomposed into three
vectors okay one one is the normal the
other two is is parallel the the tangent
surface to the to that point okay so f
is decomposed into
components perpendicular and parallel to
n to the normal that's
right only the parallel
components can contributes to flux
because it is a maximum extent of the
field passing through the surface at
that point okay the perpendicular
the perpendicular components does not
contribute okay but they contribute the
direction don't
they uh so so top three field lines
through a plain surface one normal to
the surface one parallel and one
intermediate so one normal one
parallel okay that okay this F you see
this this one parallel and intermediate
that's the
flux okay
so bottom field line through a curved
surface showing the setup of the unit
normal and surface element to calculate
flux okay so to calculate the flux of a
vector field red arrows
so this is a vector field on a Surface
okay okay so I think you know so you get
the idea so does does does that help
does that help your
question uh where is the uh what what
did you just delete it why do you guys
do that who asked that
okay that's that's kind of flux okay
that's related to it's not you know so
this topic flux is
not it's more
about
uh it's about it's more about
mathematical physics it's not
mathematics Okay so so I'm not too
interested the word flux came from Latin
fluxus means flow and flow Ray is to
flow a fluxion this term was introduced
to differential calculus by Isaac Newton
okay flux describes any effect that
appears to pass or
travel through a surface or substance
okay now you see the thing I don't
understand why why through a
surface because when you are talking
about fluids or you know
air it's it's a 3D manifold so it's not
just the surface so when is it useful
when you actually do you know talk about
these things on a Surface you know
surface is just like a a
patch yeah I don't know what is it used
so we can look look at the application
okay so properties quantum mechanics
okay so
flux flux as a surface integral okay
surface integral is
complicated
electromagnetism okay uh I don't know SI
radiometry radiometry units
okay yeah I don't I don't know it's kind
of it's more physics
related why do you delete the
question uh colostomy back says I just
got a Mac and is incredible Snappy even
better than a lightweight drro on gaming
PC yeah Mac is very
good yeah especially when they came out
with the
M1 soall Apple silicon you
know anyway let's go back to uh what we
need to do okay so let's go back to this
pedal did I did I explain what it is um
I didn't I guess so hyperbola so you go
to Pedal oh God we kind of rambled a lot
so you go to
Pedal so you can see pedal exper there
then there's a lemiscate of banoi uh
let's let's go to them
pedal lemiscate a Boni so when you have
the pedal curve of a
hyperbola of a of a rectangular hyper
hyperbola with respect to the center
then you get you get the lemus lemon
skate of boli which is this curve like
like a eight infinity the symbol for
infinity
okay so let's see let me show you okay
so that's a unic
code
uh you
see beautiful Infinity okay so go there
describe
character then you can
see the name of that character is
infinity there
okay so the function you want to call is
describe character okay so this is the
power of
emx so this infinity symbol is kind of
like this the lemon skate curve
so and uh you can see the properties
with relations to rectangular hyperbola
and Lon skate is also a curve when you
slice a
taus okay particular tus
okay and uh there is linkage properties
fascinating so these curves are so many
fascinating properties okay uh close
that close that so let me go back to so
what is Li what is the p uh pedal okay
so pedal curve is um how do
you so pedal curve is given a curve okay
given a curve you know it be can be a
sign can be a circle can be a line or
can be a parabola or any any given a
curve on a
plan you can you see me yeah so given a
curve on the plan
you and with respect to a specific point
on the plane okay so you got a curve and
you got a point somewhere in the plane
okay given these two things then then
you can define a thing called the pedal
of that curve with respect to that point
so what you do is that for any point on
the curve let's say p okay so you got a
point on a curve
you uh how is it defined so given a
curve and the fixed Point O draw a line
from o to any point p on the curve so
you have a line from O2 passing the
curve okay then draw a line perpendic
draw a line perpendicular to line
[Music]
op and passing P okay all
right okay so repeat sp sp step two and
three for every Point p on the curve the
envelope of the lines is the negative
pedo okay so that's the negative pedo so
I want the positive pedo so so draw a
line tangent okay so let's see given a
curve and the point O draw a tangent at
any point p on a curve that's right yeah
that's right okay so let
me uh can I show
you can I show you interactively yeah I
can so let me do this this way
okay so let's um
pin uh I want pH same
sketch okay given a curve let's say that
and uh given a
point this is called ped curve
okay okay so given a curve and given a
point now you can now you can have a ped
of this curve with respect to this point
okay so what you do is find any point p
on on the curve any point p on the curve
okay so then for any point you got the
tangent in this case it looks like that
then you want to find the point on the
tangent such
that that that point to the O is
perpendicular so in this
case it'll be a point like that there
okay let's call it
Q so you got that point so for every
Point p on a curve you draw a tangent
then you will find another Point
Q okay that is such that q o and Q is
perpendicular to that tangent okay so
for every Point P you got a point
Q now the set of all Point Q is the PED
curve of this curve with respect to this
ped point oh
okay uh I hope
that's interesting and clear okay save
it close that
okay so that's what pedal curve is okay
now so you can see some examples so if
you have a parabola and then if you have
the focus of the parabola as a pedal
point then the pedo curve of the
parabola is a
line
fascinating you know so this so that's
what ped curve you know so there's so
many relations you got Parabola l lias s
of
Pascal um then you got uh Parabola with
a different P points you got several
different curves then a
circle if the P point is on the
circumference then you got a cardoid
cardioid okay which is very famous as
well so you
got uh so you got lots of these cardoid
deltoid Del is particularly
beautiful if you put a pit point on the
curs of the Delta which is like one of
these uh
pointed uh position then you get uh you
get a double volum okay that's
fascinating let's see if I got a example
here
ped uh deltoid so many interesting
properties okay so let's see pedo there
it is so you see if you have the curve
this is this curve is called trifolium
okay it it looks like that okay it can
be generated by Rolling circles like
that okay you see just draw a circle
then you got this curve called
deltoid now now that deltoid has many so
many properties okay so many properties
but one of them is
pedo so if
you if you create a ped curve with
respect to One of These
Cuffs cusp you know one one of the
corner then the result is this this
three leaves that's called trifolium
okay so it's incredible trifolium is
this curve okay that's one of the Rose
curve okay
so incredible beauty okay in this
mathematics do you guys see
it uh do you guys understand what I'm
saying is it
interesting okay so back to hyperbola so
let's let's quickly do these graphics
and let's let it be uh that for today
okay so remember go to
visual dictionary of plank CES you'll
find all these interesting uh properties
if you are college students focusing on
mathematics okay this is the heart of
engineering and Ai and technology and
rocket
science if you're going to build a
rocket you need to know all this okay
so every time I see Elam musk you know
our our dramatic Boss El musk let's see
where is his uh following okay so you
can see El
musk he's shooting Rockets almost like
every day every week every month okay so
you'll see these incredible
achievements of rocket it's flying and
Landing like I mean one of the key issue
today is that you want to get you want
it to come back and land it so that you
can reuse it again okay uh where is my
uh let's go
here El musk okay so there it is El musk
okay so go to his
Twitter so you know so this is mass
let's see let's let's show some you
[Music]
see now this is incredible feat of
mankind okay that's that's that's
incredible feat of mankind
okay so you know the issue today is that
you wanted to come back like in the past
you just just throw away you know once
it FW it just throw away the the the
booster the engine whatever but because
because we don't know how to make it
come back and land but now we can so
this is literally rocket science and
Elam musk is doing that like every every
month you know you see incredible things
happening you know animus does a lot of
things
so I don't know if it's possible you
know maybe is actually someone else to
it and he's
taking at least he's taking some of the
credit you know but actually he knows
things you know anyway but you know this
this rocket is happening okay that's for
real and in order to know all this you
you have to actually know all this you
know this this what we are talking about
today geometry
okay okay okay so let me quickly just
finish that uh let let me quickly finish
this pedal thing okay so I just want to
quickly finish
this let's see if I can do
that search for p okay so there is the
PED section we're going to update the
graphics so um so
let's let's do
it wam code
okay paste it
here okay so here's a code and this part
we don't need this part we don't need
um yeah let's let just
um copy paste that make it
comment
copy paste that code
and uh what is the next
one okay
[Music]
copy paste
that make a comment I'm using wolf and
uh wolf and mod so that allows me to
code wolam language in in Mathematica I
I mean code WFAN language in emac
actually
so copy that new notebook paste it okay
so we're going to work on
here
um copy that okay so we wasted so we are
doing this uh
okay so let's delete the semicolon
because the semicolon suppresses output
okay now this par plot we need to load
it okay
so uh so
um there so we load it and uh this
hyperbola equation we also need to load
it
so uh
okay so actually so we need to Let's
Define a variable and let's define
hyperbola it's for my package so let me
get the package get uh formulas okay so
formulas WB search for hyperbola okay so
this is the format
this thing copy it
because defined here okay so we Define
this formula and this second this
actually this formula is can be improved
because secant secant function
is even function uh yeah because doesn't
matter
um any anyway let's not worry about that
so anyway so you got the hypera fun
hyperbola formula defined let's make it
um more readable syntax
okay so this line and this line are
equivalent I just made it more
readable okay so you got the hyperbola
and this e is e
centricity now highlighted
um yeah so this gets complicated so par
plot so this name
change uh this is actually not called
par plot this is called because I
changed the
name uh it's called PL curve plot okay
so so for every occurrence of par plot
you need to change it to PL Cod plot
um okay uh
wait yeah uh
What uh there
okay so we load the package we de clear
some
parameters uh local variables we Define
the hyperbola
formula and
uh okay so yeah then we Define some of
these uh this actually we don't want the
first okay so let's highlight all
occurrences and you see this is 30 years
old code 30 years old code so I'm doing
some cleanup
because uh after 30 years there's a lot
of changes in wolam
language so I don't want this first
there and but you put the first there
and
uh okay
so let's let's let's do
some and this part parametric
PL Pi / 2 2 pi
half pi 1.5 Pi 2 pi so this is 2 pi
here okay so let's remove
that and display function we don't want
because that's
changed so let's just part this part
okay let's
[Music]
see uh there's a lot to do
here there a lot to do here so save this
save this as
Untitled okay save
it so paste
this uh wait
what okay so we need to copy
that copy see that and
uh open a new
paste shift enter let's
see successful okay so what uh so what
about this part so let's see
3.1416 that's basically
pi and uh so let's let's let's put that
paste it here shift
enter beautiful successful okay so we
got that now can we just change this to
Pi paste run beauti
okay
so so let's let's get let's remove those
um
tabs okay 100 red wine to S my
soul uh so we are almost 1 hour okay
so that Z works that's good and uh what
about this part what does this part
do PI okay
Pi okay there there is you got some
problem now is it because this uh thing
uh why because oh pedo we haven't
defined
pedo yeah so
okay so anyway let's let's let's wrap
this up okay so we got these two images
we want to
replace and uh we can do
that so yeah so the second image we
haven't yet that's supposed to be this
one but now we got a error error because
this function is not
found uh yeah that function is not found
that's why but this
uh but let's just do this one okay now
why are there two of them what's the
difference
uh oh because every time I'm using
random color
okay so these two are exactly the same
you know so this one is using pi and
this one is not so DD that but anyway so
this is a picture we want copy
it okay and we can replace that image
okay let's do it put this back
and uh add the image move the image here
okay well that's actually that needs go
go to Cel talk show
soel talk show there and uh put the
image
here okay and Reen rename relocate it
to talk show and rename
M uh p.
cve okay and update this line do it
showing browser talk show there is what
we talked about now go back here close
that go back here this we delete now
move the image again uh here is the pedo
okay rename it
fantastic showing
browser search for ped okay
fantastic now we just need to delete
this one okay
um and here we copy
it so delete this image because now we
got a much better
one let's put it side by side so we can
see showing browser refresh there it is
okay yeah beautiful
so yep much better so now we want to
delete this image before we do let's go
to
find uh we want to make make sure
this image is not linked from other
places so paste it there and do search
this is a goand code which is basically
doing
grab uh okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
okay so there it is the result not yet
done
fantastic uh but that's it for today if
you like my stuff go to CAD doino and go
to the
bottom
cinfo okay
so so our code f.info go to the bottom
there is Amazon patreon and PayPal okay
pay me
$100 so this search is still running
let's look at some of the
um El musk okay
that's it for
today so let's go back
here what did I talk about close that
close that wind as low as minus close
that flux uh I have no idea what is flux
okay
um showing
browser
there just save
FL okay bye guys