hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we're going to talk
about speed typing so I've been studying
speed typing doing research on it in the
past two days two or three uh it's a
topic I have always been interested so
let's talk about that let me tell you
guys what I found out
okay uh uh video check audio check I am
alive okay let's go so introduce my
keyboard This is glove 80 the most
fantastic my main glove 80 this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard I have too
many keyboards so I use this one um for
keyboard maros most fantastic if you are
here say hi hello I don't know and this
is s board I love it very much I'm still
learning it so I don't I don't have
anything new so I'll uh show you guys
down the road glove uh this is uh s
board SV a l b o a r d mechanic switches
you know this is one of the fancy
keyboard so of course there's two of
them okay so that's about my keyboard I
have video reviews you can search
YouTube you'll find it so now let's talk
about let's let's go to the main topic
the keyboard speed typing how fast can
you type 100 W per per minute 200 W or
300 W per minute there actually YouTube
you can see 300 W per minute but with
conditions okay so so that's the topic I
want to talk about so question do you
think glove 80 usable by people who are
used to ISO layout as opposed to
American yes of course it's all about
habit whenever you adapt a new keyboard
there's always a habit issue same thing
with keyboard layout vak uh quy V you
know and also you know so it's all about
habit so same thing with emac you know
whenever emac you know you you you
change your key binding you can get used
to it and for many people who has been
using emac for 10 years you know they
they just not going to change because
the muscle is already building just just
like when you ride a bicycle
you know there's a video a bicycle they
they change the direction of the turn so
that when you turn this way it actually
turn right so your brain is all [ __ ]
up so it's a habit so when you first
adopt something new there's a strong
resistance you just I don't I don't want
to you know because it's painful because
it's like you have to start over it's
worse because you already you know you
try to type something this way and now
this you always make a mistake because
now this keyboard is new so there's a
habit for example one of the Habit about
keyboard is the um one one of the Habit
about keyboard is the arrangement of
the of the page up and page down home
and key you know that's that was a thing
so let me show you uh
where uh no more keyboard uh so I forgot
where I have it so which section uh so
let me talk about that a bit so answer
to your question you know ISO you are
you are talking about ISO layout so ISO
layout first of all that is the um so
let's go let's have a look key caps no
not key caps
keypads uh fun history OS key switch
design key cabs special keys so this is
all about special keys the fat Enter key
you know this is ISO the fat
enter American users is the got the th
strip enter and the
Japanese the Japanese got
this okay medium fat then there's
there's extremely thin uh fat key like
almost vertical I mean vertical return
like like this one you know the iso
enter two you back space so anyway so
ISO layout is like like that also ISO
layout ISO is a standard you know
International standard organization
something so in Europe they have this
so-called I ISO layout which they have a
extra
key besides the Z so so let me yeah so
you know today is random so let me talk
about these things but the main thing I
want to talk about is a fast the the
supposed fastest type type Shan Rona
okay
there's quite a story let me tell
you uh crackpot theory of speed typer
you know he
he's that's that's that's my opinion but
I'll tell you guys so ISO layout so let
me show you what is ISO layout for those
of you don't know out there Americans um
so you want to look at ISO layout so you
have to look at um International uh okay
so we got some okay so so first of all
copy that so I'm using emx so sof FL
Keys most sufficient let's show close
that show this is today's talk show and
paste the link there fat Enter key so we
have a record of what we talked about so
now let's look up ISO layout so go to
search go to search search for Apple
keyboard I know where it is to look
so you know many interesting topics
Apple keyboard touch bar the most
idiotic
thing when Steve is scun Steve Job will
never create this but instead then the
other people they don't know what they
doing they they they become Tech geekers
you see Steve Job he has created massive
amount of in Innovation not just in
Computing in Computing in Computing
peripheral
in you know especially the graphical
user interface that's a re Revolution
okay he is the entrepreneur
he take inventions that would otherwise
be buried he take it he put it into
Market successfully he has The Knack to
make it successful you know like iPhone
iPhone Microsoft created phone you know
pocket phone but it did failed but Steve
Jobs when it comes to Steve Jobs it
become Revolution then everyone is
starting you know everyone has a phone
now Steve Jobs lots of things CD ROM DVD
ROM Wireless Apple is leading by like
three five years you know after Apple
did it for five years then the PC the
windows started to have it a standard
then after another few years the Linux
idiots start to you have that such as
USB 3 or
whatever or or Wireless connect you know
wi uh yeah Wi-Fi USB Bluetooth you know
Linux is you know so Apple did it then
after after usually three years then it
became standard on the Microsoft Word
then another two years then it become
standard on Linux you know uh so so I
digress into Apple so let's go to go
back to ISO keyboard layout yeah so we I
I want to show you guys ISO keyboard
layout okay
so uh where is it uh so you need to go
to Apple keyboard I know where it is
okay so
actually actually go to
layout okay so everything you want to
know about layout design then you go to
inter International layout okay then you
go to so this uh here's a bunch of in
International layout United Kingdom
puges Dutch Belgium Czech Danish
Estonian Iceland yeah Iceland and look
at this this funny thing you see this is
no way layout no way so you you got a
key here it's got this bunch of symbols
you know section sign one and half one
over
half sign and section sign again in
vertical V section you know section you
know many of these symbols and layout is
kind of idiotic because they are almost
never used but however they became
standard you know it's so when you look
at the different layout in the world
most of them are like extremely
incompetent you know yesterday the last
episode live stream we talked about
Russian keyword like extreme
incompetent okay so let's not uh let's
let go back to uh ISO layout I wanted to
mention ISO layout okay so
um in fact actually you can see it here
you see this Stanish keyboard you see a
key here and z or Zed as Canadian would
say it Zed then to the left of Zed you
have this extra key so this is ISO
layout look at the fat enter this is ISO
faring to Americans you see fat enter
and extra key to the left of Z so all
these are ISO layout so typically it's
used uh in
Europe so um but I want to show you
actual actual keyboards of iso layout
there it is okay so let me show you few
actual keyboard of iso layout not just
diagrams okay so here we have nadiia
multilingual layout you know some of the
layout some of these layouts are
designed for to type multiple languages
for example the Canadian multilingual is
is for both English and French you know
French is a issue in Canada they need to
go bilingual so Canadian so there it is
okay so let me show you a few actual
keyboard so this is on a Mac La laptop
laptop Apple's Mac laptop in for Europe
so you have so they are using by default
so you have the you see this is very
interesting physical keyboard This is
Apple MacBook Pro in Canada and you can
see the layout is ISO you got you got
this vertical Enter key then you got you
see this extra key to the left left of Z
and moreover you see these strange
symbols you see Escape they use the by
the way there's also a standard for the
for the GL graphical symbols for each of
these keys so you can so and this
keyboard is using it so you can see the
Escape key is a circle with a with a
Northwest Arrow like escape the circle
you
see and the shift key you can I mean the
caps lock and shift key okay caps lock
that's new the shift you know up Arrow
that's common but then you can see see
the the helm the how do you call this um
the steing wheel for
ships Helm Helm yeah for the control key
and uh this this um option key anyway so
that's uh interesting okay
so this is ISO layout and here is
another ISO layout Apple keyboard you
know this this is for what language oh
also Canadian Canadian multilingual so
it's used in eastern part of Canada
Quebec
kec that's where I lived when I was 1
when I was 16
or for three years so that's about ISO
keyboards and uh we so your question is
can you get used to the like glove 0
yeah it's just a matter of habit you
know in fact
yeah anyway anyway so that's about that
so next next question good
evening
Maris
fan do you think an introduction to
programming in EAC LP that's the worst
book okay before I even finish reading
your question by free by free software
Foundation is a good way to learn emac
list I want to get good at eist but
don't know where to start okay uh uh if
if you want to learn emac list you know
I would say the best resource online or
anywhere any book is just my emac this
tutorial
okay uh if you ask my true opinion
there's nothing remotely comparable like
well because emac is is not a popular
language okay but I have you know
tutorial for JavaScript for goland and
and they are comparable you know very
good
tutorials so you know but for emac this
my tutorial I would say is like the
only
one that's that's that's that's a best
by by a magnitude okay because because
basically there's nothing else nothing
else okay there are some books like
written 20 years ago and there's a
couple books I believe published in the
past last 10 years uh I haven't uh
looked into them but the book you you
mention okay so you can search my uh you
know website emx book uh let's see Elis
book so lisp
book okay actually I have an article on
that you know he he passed away that guy
introduction to programming emac this he
passed away his name is Bob
H uh where okay so where do I find it
okay let's go to emac
tutorial uh and go to emac list
miscellaneous emac list miscellaneous
technical
essays emac miscellaneous index okay
let's look at those
here his name is Bob he passed away
about five years
ago uh
okay here is the old Asian list
manual here is how to learn emac lisp
here is should beginner programmer learn
emac LP here is author of intro to emac
L Robert J chasha you know he so he
passed away I and I wrote a uh you know
so here is his book emac this an
introduction okay so this book so here
is how this guy looks like he's a he's a
open source fanatic you know part of the
early very early
Fanatics so my opinion on this book so
this book is good if you never ever
programmed before you don't know what
what a variable means you don't know
what the function means you don't know
you yeah you don't know what what the
[ __ ] they are this is a good book okay
this is the best book for that you learn
emac this from you know and and
programming from the ground up
okay so this is a good book for that
it's free online in fact it's bundled
with every emac so you just press
controll
h i okay then you go down tab tab tab
tab tab tab there it is emac this intro
okay so you can see an
introduction uh you know you can read it
online it's bundled in with every emac
so you can buy a copy to support Richard
storman to give money to Richard storman
basically your money just goes to him
most of it or half of
it okay so it's a good book if you don't
know any programming at all you don't
know what's a variable you don't know
what's a function now if you are a
programmer already for example maybe you
know some Java or JavaScript or C maybe
you know some python PHP you know even
just a bit PHP bash
okay this is not a good book because it
will spend 10 pages 10 to explain what's
a
variable you know to how to set a
variable it you know you have to scan
scan scan 10 pages
then you find oh this is how you set a
variable in emac LP okay then next page
about something about what's the
difference between Global variable and
local you know another 10 pages so not a
good book I Tred to read it when I begin
reading uh learning EMA this in 2006 you
know I thought I'll just scan it you
know the technique of scanning because
you can just you know it's a book so you
can oh I already know this but it
becomes so tiresome like you don't learn
anything like like in emac this how do
you create a variable oh God scan scan
you know so I would not recommend it
okay so that's the situation that's my
review of this book the nature of this
book but if you don't know any
programming at all this is a good you
know good it's a good introduction very
verbos okay
I have some experience in programming
bash power sh C++ okay yeah then this
especially C++ That's a hardcore thing
so this book will be two verbals for you
but you can try to read it you know
verify to see if you you know if you
agree with my
opinion okay so that's about that and uh
so so let me pedal my emac this tutorial
you'll find you know this is the best
one out there including all printed ones
okay it's the most condensed and the
most
concise and yet it's most easy to
understand and and not not assuming you
are three years old let like a lot of uh
web tutorials today written by pajit you
know
pajit like they have to hold your hand
oh let me explain what's the directory
you have to you know or or like the
JavaScript word where oh you just run
this and your mpm and W 1,000 things
come to your directory and next all you
just do this don't ask why just just
just type this and it'll work oh it
works okay situation of the Zuma
situation so most concise most precise
and also correct and and uh um and
comprehensive you know it covers you
know L you know all the fundamentals of
lisp then it covers all the fundamentals
of emac lisp such as a CER you
know what's a cruiser what's a region
what's a buffer you know in other
languages you know in Java JavaScript we
don't have that because this is editor
this is programming editor you have
buffer you have Cruiser you have region
you have uh you know region active
region and so on so you know things like
that
so then you have then you can you know
move on how to write a major mod okay so
in fact I have done this one or two you
know I you know tutorials
um learning iMac this from the ground up
several you know so you can check them
out you know I find myself always have
to repeat and repeat and repeat you know
everything almost every question is
frequently Asked question but I have
realized that's life you know it's it's
it doesn't just happen to me you know
there a here's an interesting story you
know when when about 15 years
ago I started to see you know emac
questions you know why are these people
asking frequently asked questions Jesus
like all of a sudden I felt all these
questions in reded you know emac
Community it's it's like basic questions
Jesus didn't you guys just read you know
this been asked and answered 1,000
times you know then next year same and
then eventually I realize that's life
that's the cycle of life it just means
I'm getting old younger people they come
up they W they won't B you know young
people and and then I thought about
that's what teachers do professors at
University they have to teach calculus
the same thing every year for the whole
day
life you know it just means you you are
old so okay
so okay so let's talk about keyboard
okay so let me let me show you guys this
um H where where is it so talk show
uh I wanted to talk about keyboard so
first of all the quackpot theories of
speed typer Shan
Rona so Shan Rona is one of the fastest
typist okay on record because he won he
became famous in
2010 U from a competition so-called Tima
typing
Championship which is created by the
company Das keyboard you know the
keyboard maker
that which is one of the early uh
mechanical keyboard maker okay actually
oh they have a Wikipedia entry for
them you know so this used to be popular
among programmers but not Gamers because
they are different Community back then
you know starting in
2005 so anyway that's keyboard so it's
created the dash keyboard in 2010
created created a competition called
ultimate typing
Championship it's like one of it's a
marketing thing so because you know they
create this so that people will you know
know about Das Keyboard and we'll make
them more money so Sean was you know
he's fitting down you know he he he was
um anyway so he's he joined and he won
okay so
um so anyway he that he became very
famous he he won this so-called ultimate
typing Championship 2010 there's no such
Championship until 10 years later
2020 actually I just discovered
yesterday you know when I was doing
research on speed typing so anyway so
Sean become very
popular and he he wrote a book like
three years ago you you go to his
YouTube Sean Rona he also got a website
you can search and you'll find it and he
started to write a book and he started
to create a video this came out in uh
this video came out in let me show you
2022 two years ago how to type okay this
you know how to type keyboard geometry
by Shan Rona okay so in this video he
started you know basically crackpot
theories okay shaa he's a quy typist you
know he doesn't he doesn't go for this
ergonomic Batman [ __ ] you know he think
he he like dismiss them and he doesn't
go for the V you know the V act the uh
let let me show you for those people you
don't
know okay so keyboard layout so design
key caps special keys layout so I talked
about this yesterday uh previous two or
three videos okay so you have keyboard
layouts you know
quy vorak KAC you know different
arrangement of the letters okay
so many of them you know vorak comak and
Workman Norman they are more efficient
okay so he so the Shan Raa guy doesn't
care about it he think you know he like
dismiss
it but however he has a
stance okay there there is him starting
to talk okay so that's him when he's
younger and he's you know he's talking
about his theory okay but basically he
dismiss all this vorak or this all this
KAC
and uh he
also this the conventional
typing methodology of putting your hands
on the home row you know the
ASDF J K L you know he diss it okay he
like contempt he holds contempt of that
methodology so basically he's saying
that you should put your hand in this
upper row and then the right hand should
be also upper row but but then the thumb
can be used for the end key or like you
know he's trying to sell he pedals his
own idiosyncratic Theory meanwhile he
dismiss the standard you know home row
approach and also dismiss vorak dismiss
KAC you know crackpot okay that's a
crackpot
Theory uh it's
it's basically untruth okay I don't Rec
so in my opinion it's
crackpot so but but he's the fast he's
the worst world fastest typer you are
not how can you how can you question him
obviously you know you would trust him
right
no he's right now he's not okay he's not
the world champion anymore because well
anyway that goes into another story you
know when you have when there's money
you know for example
gaming in the 1990s nobody nobody cares
about gaming you know but beginning
around 2010 there's Millions dollars
price for gaming gaming become a thing
it becomes actually become an industry
bigger than movie and so on but but the
the thing is there's a gaming
competition you know the the you know
the World of Warcraft and lots of others
you know if you become a champion you
win Millions you know you become a you
know
millionaire so once you have money you
got real competitors okay you start to
have real competitors but for typing you
know fast typing nobody care about that
okay and it's actually not that useful
touch type is a very useful skill for
anyone who uses a computer touch typing
okay but speed typing you know touch
typing Beyond you know let's say 100 W
per minute it's useless basically okay
is more or less useless touch typing is
a practical skill but beyond 100 what
per minute like in a competitive way
it's basically useless there's also no
price no money except you know this
marketing effort by Dash keyboard in
2010 you win like $2,000 okay then you
know just $2,000 so it there's no it's
it's not a you know it's not a thing
if speed typing become a championship
you know with Millions dollars like
gaming then you will actually see real
competitors okay right now it's like
just among a few nerds you know I can
type faster than you you know they have
a leaderboard you know they you know
they they are usually young you know
teenag
or in college they got nothing to do but
if you if it became a thing with
millions dollar price you will see it's
in my opinion the top players will all
be using vac okay none of the quy [ __ ]
and and his crackpot theory about how
you should you you know you should stick
with C you know he kind of tried to
imply that you know he he's like telling
him his story you know any
anyway so that's my opinion that's my
criticism on
his theory about
typing okay Sean
Rona you know he he's he's a great guy
you know but but it's just that his
theory I think it's like very
questionable but I think he's a great
person okay I want to make sure I don't
get Mis misunderstood okay I think he's
a great person he's a he's like a bit
younger than me is kind of like yeah a
bit younger than me he's a classic nerd
classic nerd like the Nerds I know in '
90s you don't see that much anymore so
you know and also one of
his uh his reply on YouTube is very
informative okay I've I've kind of
copied on onto my um my website you can
you can also read the original on
YouTube you know if he wants me to
remove it I'll remove it so but anyway
so this article by him is very
informative because
he this is long winded you know like you
don't see that anymore like one one of
the things he say funny is that you know
like today's generation or they say you
know let me read it
you know all they say is parus based you
know like you guys zumas all you all you
can able all you are capable of saying
is spaced
pagers you can't write a one sentence
one full sentence this is Zuma
idiots so anyway this article is this
kind of reply is very informative he
talks about his life and he also talks
about the speed typing scene who are the
other you know great speed typers okay
uh very uh very
informative okay that's about this Sean
okay now let me talk about meanwhile
there's
another uh
guy okay this there is this guy car
jobst a zoom
grifter okay let me show you this this
is a Zuma generation grif car jobs I
discovered yesterday okay so you know
look at his YouTube so his thing seems
to be debunking you know uh other things
you know okay 26 years record okay more
legal action whatever that is what is
cheatah exposed
okay 250 IQ fake you know he he seems
his thing his snack seems to be like
Expos other fakes okay this one this is
so bad look at this Zuma generation Fox
you know with this this face you know
this drama you know this is this is a
pictorial version of clickbait you know
like oh my God oh my God I discover this
this this greatest thing you know
[ __ ] Zuma
Fox Okay so he he created a
video that
badmouth the the world's fastest typist
Barbara Blackburn Barbara Blackburn
passed away in 2008 you know she's the
you know many previous
generation so let me show you his
YouTube you know this video okay so was
she lying you know look at look at this
dramatic [ __ ] this car jobs the biggest
scandal in typing in speed typing
history what a what a [ __ ] scum this
car jobs is okay one million views okay
2023 I watched it you know it's 20
minutes okay so in this video he
discuss he discussed how the you know
the the frequently
quoted that Barbara Blackburn types 220
words per minute is fake you know he you
know that's the way he he kind of say
that okay he's fake and how it is his
you know Guinness World Record is fake
and you know blah blah
blah basically he just badmouth bar
blackb you
know so in his his research he actually
spent time to dig into all the Guinness
record to see where it says what you
know uh it's reasonable research okay
and what he say is not necessarily false
okay it's not necessarily forse but
however the overall
ination the overall you know the gist of
his you know what he's trying to say is
basically Barbara Blackburn is a shi
okay is like a fraud or sheer or lying
you know like the like the you know the
you know he's saying barara you know is
is lying what a scum this car jobs is
okay which is false overall his his
video is just
false why why does he do that because
because he's a Zuma he's going for the
money you know 1 million subscribers you
know is [ __ ]
rumors so barara is he really fake
no what about you know 22 words per
minute that's real you know you you have
to understand you know back 20 years ago
even just 20 years ago it's not like
today where you have internet you have
Wikipedia you have pocket you know you
know a computer phone in your pocket you
can stream anytime anywhere in the world
you can verify information so easily
Wikipedia you know that's not like that
during Barbara's time in the 1950s or
1980s okay you don't have internet like
that so when this speak so you know
speak you know the 220 words she she you
know it's genuine she's not a liar she's
not like a scammer or she like like like
many of these zumas
are of course she promote herself
you know she she she you know and she
types really
fast
so is is the but but what does it mean
the world's fastest typing back then
there's no such thing I mean you you
can't you know there's no internet
there's no you know Global you know so
most people don't even know this typing
competition or you have to travel you
know like like to you know this but so
in general is Barbara lying or a fraud
no she's not and does she really tape
that fast yes she's one of the world's
topest at the time as far as media knows
you know there are probably a lot more
fastest but you don't know who they are
they you know it's not like today
internet you know you always see like
Unknown People they they suddenly become
very famous because they did this they
are skill at this or that or singing you
know lots of singing
to this so this this Zuma idiots car
jobs okay I find that them disgusting
disgusting and brainless you know to him
he probably thought h i this is my
greatest research [ __ ]
idiots okay that's about him okay now me
let me make a disclaimer I don't know
who I don't know who he is okay that's
just my criticism on his video on
Barbara blackb okay I don't know who he
is uh I don't know you know I'm not
saying he's lying he's just sh you know
he because you know he wants to be
popular just like most most of these
YouTube
YouTubers okay I think maybe that's it
for today and uh
should not get too
angry uh and let me read the comments
and let me answer the comments and maybe
that'll be it okay keyboard big fat
enter key okay then character frequency
plot now there's a new
feature select all okay select all
delete uh actually shrink it
now now type
something and you can see the frequency
plotted
immediately in real time okay now it
supports Json output so if you are doing
any research about character
frequency even Russian or Japanese or
Chinese or Arabic you can just paste it
copy and paste it here and you'll show
in real time and you can also get the
Json output in case you want to put it
into JavaScript or whatever so you can
turn it off they also update in real
time it
up updates in real time okay that's a
new and uh that's about
it okay so about speed typing there are
so here's some introduction today you'll
see a lot videos on it
the there are few things important to
know that 15 seconds speed test is very
different from 30 seconds or 1 minute or
5 minutes or 10 minutes you know it's
like running you know the the duration
is very significant how fast you can run
the longer it's become is significantly
slower so if you search YouTube You'll
see a lot of oh two 200 world per minute
world record 300 250 you know that's
mostly all [ __ ] because there are
some of them even 5
Second 5
Second 1,000 W per
minute okay that's a [ __ ] so if you
really want to look into you know the
actual speed of the top typist you have
to check for their one minute or five
minutes you know that but vast majority
on YouTube or the YouTube shorts is just
like 15 seconds so the other thing
important is that the text used is also
important depending on you know like one
there's a website monkey type so let's
go to Monkey type let me
Demo
uh so I'm updating my website so here's
a bunch of tutorials and here is um who
wants to race
me so speed uh typ in speed test site
monkey type okay so monkey type you know
by default monkey type is nasty you know
by default
they they they just show a list of
random the most frequently used top 200
or 300 English words no punctuation
no capital letters you know it's just
the random words the simplest easy to
type words so that it's pleasure when
you type it you know because you don't
have to type any capital letter it's not
even a sentence just random easy words
so if you do that you get the highest
word per minute typically by the way
word per minute means you know each each
word means basically five key strokes
okay so if you have 10 word per minute
that means 50 characters per minute
okay so anyway so you know they use the
simplest thing so you get pleasure you
know kind of like a game addictive so
you feel good so so so almost all the
YouTube videos is using monkey type you
know monkey type 15 seconds then you you
you get a high uh word per
minute I'm drinking uh
coffeee and honey and
milk okay let let's let's type
the okay let's type let's
see uh
H [ __ ] 77
okay so that's my types typing
speed so let me answer
so so that's about typing and uh
so so anyway yeah and this girl is
really funny you should check it out
this this baby
Shar okay I think that's it so let's
check the questions
modern
solutions
hello yeah I don't know about hard
swappable keyboards I don't really know
much about
it hi
Echo hi
heata he Maris I never learn to write
properly because I use computers
jobs is a speed Runner which got hung up
on some cheats
oh
interesting 10 years G 10 years ago we
had
Wikipedia okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching pay me go to
PayPal okay you go to s info my website
you can easily find my PayPal you know
PayPal or you can patreon
me I think that's
it bye
jobs has genuine W class skills in
golden eye on Nintendo 64 oh interesting