good morning everyone today is 2019
December 6 Friday 10 o'clock in the
morning San Francisco time we have a
crowd here and you are watching saw talk
show so what is today's topic good
morning guys
the morning then Emily and a CMAC mom
pone AC mom hung and good morning Bart
and and what is the topic guys so today
so Dan says suggested topics
contributing to Emax hacking with Emacs
eMac this for general-purpose
programming Emacs distributions for
example space max s sx Emacs
oh my god you are a owed b10 were you
from the end of Brazil and then says
Emacs window managers e xw m and desktop
apps you know that's a lot of topics you
have to pick one you know in general why
I'm asking like what topics you have to
the best thing for me is for you to pick
a one topic you want me to talk about
like you what you want to hear I mean
the attitude is instead of Oaks ah needs
a topic let's let's suggest him some
topics instead of that you know the man
the the the the better my mind set for
me would be what you have questions for
me that would be better because but
anyway that that's a not that's a lot
topics and bodies company not Emacs
again so actually so we can talk about
one topic one of them you know you know
see if we're gonna start that on Emacs
that's gonna be usually it's going
be in this but Emily is here Emily is
probably interested in you max so then
pick one topic do you do I use fire ward
no well other than the whatever
operating system provides so I mean
dedicated firewall no I don't use
firewall but I do have a tutorial on how
to set up firewall which is the most
complicated thing in Emacs
okay so then demo is you know pick a
topic you have to respond so let's go to
okay so let's let's just start with such
Linux firewall okay sorry
Linux firewall so I don't have a topic
topic today so it might I might just go
random so Linux firewall I spent one
month full time to write this tutorial
the Linux firewall there is these IP
tables it is one of the most complicated
thing okay IP tables the documentation
is worst [ __ ] possible so I spent one
month few months to write this tutorial
and if you look online so how do
contribute it to Emacs okay so if you
look online all the online tutorials on
IP tables that's like 20 years old so in
2013 I spent one month to write this
tutorial because I was thinking you you
know so anyway so here is my tutor
tutorial on IP tables which is firewall
on Linux so you get the Linux Linux
machine and you can use the Moschino of
whoa machine so you guys might be
interested in that and I was thinking
today we might talk about something else
like none technical none programming and
random so Dan says how to contribute to
Emacs well to contribute to Emacs you
write a package then you okay how to
contribute to Emacs well okay so you the
easiest way is for you to write a
package Emacs package you put it on my
Appa
you put it on my Appa so okay so let's
go to my Emacs tutorial let me show you
okay you so little so let me top top
talk about how to contribute to Emacs of
course first of all you learn eMac this
you have to write a package you know you
you should you know spend half a year to
know what you are doing you learn eMac
B's then you write a package that
doesn't exist anywhere else yet oh you
already know some other package but you
think it's not as good so you write one
of your own you write a package okay
then you put it to mapa now in order to
you put it to male power how do you do
that first of all you write a package
you put it on github so other people
your friends for example know how to can
download it and use it so and if it's
good then then the next step is you put
it on mail pop so let's go
where is mapa so let's go to practical
Emacs practical Emacs in its setup then
you have install packages okay basically
when you install packages you are most
most likely install form alpha so
you go to Malta okay well not Emacs Viki
Emacs anguish is not Emacs is I want to
go to Emacs Melva okay there so on Emacs
male part you that's where you download
Emacs packages milpa is a Emacs packages
repository then you click on their
github let's turn on JavaScript okay you
don't you go to their github then there
are instructions like contributing that
that tells you how to make your package
available on map are basically basically
it means you have to follow certain
formats for example your headers for
example let me show you okay
so I'm going to show you one the my most
popular packages kosaka let's start
command log mod topics guys okay topics
so for example you are looking at stuff
like he's you know one of my most
popular packages and in order to put
mail per basically you have to follow
this this header basically those those
are the head headers you need to have in
in that particular specific format good
morning Kathy good morning Campbell so
I'm gonna read the comments in a moment
so you add anyway you go to my up our
github page they have instructions you
just follow it then the mail per people
which is Steve something okay let's see
where is it
let's see commits so mapa is maintained
by basically two or three percent you
know actually they do a lot of work and
they are not getting
money that is a situation with
open-source but they do have jobs you
know mapa is started by this guy who is
known as milky men milky postman that's
his nickname online you search for milky
postman Emacs you'll find him okay so
let's see commence now so these are new
packages so you see one of the guy one
of the maintainer of mapa is this guy
Steve Purcell and the other guy is TAS
yes this guy okay and they both have
written packages I mean they are good
they are good
Emacs coda so steeper so now on github
how do you get into his you know I want
to go to Steve burrows there is a guy he
is the main guy that that does work on
me apart when you submit a package he
basically looks at that a little bit
then he approves it he you know he
merges your package to map out
repository so he's one of the main guy
and he's a nice guy
okay so I've sent my you know I have my
packages there and he is very helpful
and the other guy the Tessier's now
Tessier's is another guy that helps out
on me open now how do you get his name
okay here so his name is Jonas Bernoulli
he is also the maintainer for Matchett a
very popular email smart for forget for
example I can show you magic right now
okay a mess mad magic status okay so let
me show you magic status
okay so here is my so you see let me
magnify okay so I have a bunch of temp
files all those are all those are temp
files but anyway here is my code stuff
like this and I have some yeah I made
this change I haven't committed yet so
that's you are looking at magic which is
a great mod for github folk forget okay
and also github it connects so I can
actually commit it but I don't want to
okay
so magic you know so Jonas Bernoulli is
also helping out how mapa and the other
guy is Melky postman Melky postman works
for Google let's see if I can find you
know I don't think he's very active but
he's a guy who began melba about 5 or 7
years ago
so if we can look at his name Emacs
Malky postmen that's the name he goes by
ok it's knit by the way it's named alpha
because you know it's named milky
postman's Emacs
this package archives that's the
original name that's ancient so milky
postman is this guy and I believe he
works for google
ok he's American so basically this as
far as I know these three are the main
guys who maintains mapa so you just you
follow the map instructions you sub
submit your packages then your package
will be on remember now however mapa is
not a free software foundations project
so it's not really part of Emacs map is
like outside of Emacs the the gue new
Emacs from Richard Stallman the free
software foundation they also have a
repository it's called alpha ok
ARPA
which sucks donkey ass for every package
on ALPA there are like a thousand
packages or melba that's that's that's
how how that's how big the difference is
you see I go to the air power website it
doesn't even load unless I turn on
JavaScript it's sucks in every way in
every way just just like oh wait no way
this is a different website you see the
search doesn't even show up because
nobody is using it help us so let's type
Emacs
ALPA so there it is not wiki wait okay
so this one said the second one hold on
so this website ALPA this is Google new
Emacs list package archive repository
this is the official package repository
from you know free software foundation
approved packages now when if a package
shows up here that means it's owned by
Free Software Foundation so if you want
your package to be part of ALPA you have
to sign paper you know you have to sign
paper and give give away all your rights
like this from today on this software
belongs to free Free Software Foundation
not yours anymore that's what you have
to do you have to sign it that's the
process you know that's the process for
your package to get onto our path
that's not all okay the willingness to
sign the paper is one thing but if you
are willing nobody is you know they are
not going to just let you allow you to
put a package there you have to you have
to talk to the new developers for
example they don't really have a formal
process but basically the way it works
as far as I know III don't think I'm not
I don't think I'm outdated yet but
basically the process is that you go to
the gnu emacs dev okay you go to Emacs
dev mailing list
it's meaningless you join then you pass
participate there for a while for you
know several month or things like that
for example here is the official
meninist
Emacs death so we can look at thread you
know right now so that what they are
talking Stephan we see you know I'm
familiar with you know more than half of
these names so Angie I don't know who
that is
Keith David Ellie Ellie is basically the
primary maintainer right now Keith David
I don't remember Steff amount Manya is a
professor who does research in
functional programming he is based in
Montreal Canada and
he was the Emax maintainer for five
years around year 2010 also for five
years so anyway so you can see this is
the GU GNU Emacs meaning list Eddie
Eddie
zorroski is a he is a very annoying
annoying guy and very stinky you know
every like when you talk with him or
every message is the way he writes is
Sting's you you know he just stains you
and not polite and always always you
like you know he anyway he is a old
email is code and he's being with Emacs
probably won one of the oldest okay at
least for 20 years at least more than
twenty years I I think so Eddie is in
fact he is currently kind of the the
leader of the Emacs staff you know in
practice the fish officially is by the
leader of Emacs maintainer right now
officially it's the okay let's go to
let's see
officially it's this guy John Wiggly but
he's kind of beast busy so anyway so
anyway so this is a new mailing list you
join them you kind of mesh with them for
a while so people get to know you then
you propose your package you know you
suggest oh I have this package you know
you ask them you ask them how do I get
my package to alpha you have to ask kind
of kindly okay this this list is a it's
pretty [ __ ] up in my opinion okay it's
a new Emacs communities
lots of fuck-ups so surely and
technically you know the in my opinion
now those you know for most of you who
know me you probably know you know I'm
not liked by many many of them they call
me a troll and but all
so you know I just want to tell you my
opinions about them so you can so you
have so you know you know you get you
get a non mainstream opinion about how
what how things are so this new mailing
lists they got lots of problems in it
anyway
so my advice if you want your package to
be um to be part of new to be on ALPA
okay first of all first of all you want
your package to be on mapper which is
easiest and the most the most easiest
okay it's easy to put there and actually
it's the most practical as well so you
put your package on male part first then
if you want your package on alpha that's
another thing finally if if you become a
great Emacs programmer you might want
your package to be part of Emacs Lisp
bundled I mean part of Emacs like
building that is super hard okay don't
don't think about it okay I can't like
tell you right right away don't think
about it okay but but the thing I want
to talk about is that doesn't matter you
know it doesn't matter what what genius
you are
suppose you are the one of the most
famous programmers suppose suppose you
you you you you coded the google search
engine so you are a big shot you are
world renowned you you you you wrote
Firefox engine let's say you wrote
Firefox you created JavaScript like the
the guy okay
print printer oh you created Ruby or
whatever whatever you go to the Emacs
minion list you have to pretend like you
are nothing you are nobody okay
in the eMac this you know many nice you
are nobody did
they don't give a [ __ ] what you've done
like Richard Stallman is the king okay
you are nobody you know many of these
people for example I've seen I've seen
discussions great for and well
well-known programmers can
you know scientists programmers whatever
well no you know the I have several
examples the purl many examples but in
anyway but in the eMac this many nice
community you are nobody okay so so if
you want to if you want pack your
package to be you know part of alpha or
possibly max you have to talk in the
most most polite way possible and and
the end and they they don't give a [ __ ]
even that they don't give a [ __ ] about
you
you have to kind of beg okay like say
please can I possibly you know you and
you cannot just go in and say hey my
name is my name someone my name is Sally
I wrote Firefox okay and can you guys
would you guys consider this package
know if you used to do that forget it
okay you have to like go me and stay
there talk to people for a while up for
several months and then eventually you
introduce your package then your package
you know your suggestion of including
your package in Emacs or something we
all go through the gauntlet of all the
people they will attack you they will do
they will say all kind of things like oh
oh but this your package can you can you
fix up that I don't like this part can
you go fix it and someone else will say
no I like that part can you change this
instead of that you know they will tell
you what to do and something and and
meanwhile there are other people you
know many of these people in the Emacs
save they they will tell you no I don't
like you a package okay I don't think it
should be part of your part of Emacs so
you you encounter all these opinions and
in pat and by the way did I mention
there is no process okay there's nothing
like a formal process or or written down
nothing so you go that it's it's like a
commune it's like a communist commune
okay you you got a bunch of people and
including newbies like who have encoded
one single
emag bees they there are some of people
some of those are there in there too all
it takes to be there is that you believe
firmly the free software foundations
ideology then you are respected member
that's the main thing okay doesn't
matter whether you can code or how good
you are how famous you are it doesn't
matter the main thing you to be there is
that you firmly believe the free
software foundation ideology that's
that's the primary thing okay so anyway
you go there you you talk to these
people and then you sub eventually you
you you know suggest you know your
package to be included somewhere things
like that then after all the discussions
you know random people they will say oh
I don't like it
and sometimes the conversation will just
die out then you get nothing like no
nothing okay so you have to like the
conversation die out and that's it
that's that's it for your package
whatever how many doesn't matter how
many years you spend on it let's see
that's it so you have to have some kind
of tact to you know and you know know
these people and okay so also so you
know when the conversation that you
might suggest it again
because there's no formality no process
you know so if if if maybe there's an
argument or digression about you know
it's your package to be included and
they died out then you possibly might
you know suggest again a few months
later or something
the point my point is that there is no
process you know don't hope for it don't
hope for it so anyway if people like
your stuff and you know they agree that
it should be part of Emacs or alpha then
then you then then you get you know then
your package gets there so that is my
opinion about the nature of the
emacs death okay and that's that is how
you contribute to Emax I mean by
contribute like there are many many
meanings of contribute what do you mean
so if you wanted your package to be on
my Appa is easy and the people are mail
pass Steve you know the the people they
are they are great people now I don't
know much about this guy milky postman
do not cut us we never talked but Jonas
Bernoulli we know each other's okay a
bit and also the Steve puzzle and I they
are nice people okay in my opinion so
you top them to you know it's not
difficult to get your package on my Appa
and in fact that's the most practical
thing you know once your packaging on my
Appa is on email / everyone will see but
the new helper actually nobody uses use
it okay and many packages on both impose
ALPA and the mail PAP but nobody
actually uses alpha version because in
you know it's a it's one factor you know
goo you know the Emacs led by Richard
Stallman that is my opinion
so that is about that Emacs community so
I don't know if that's helpful or not
anyway so let's see hey chat hey Jason
so actually how long have I been talking
so I kind of let's see how long have I
been talking okay so check thirty
minutes okay so let me read the comments
okay it's so hard to talk about Emacs
iptables okay so about how do you know
so but part apparent ease is framing
iptables of Linux but
how do you know about body is saying
iptables is cancer but ufw handles well
my ass you fw if I think I know what it
is
okay so B knocks you you fw okay so I
started wrong you fw yeah Linux you fw
an introduction to uncomplicated fire
what you have W my ass
it's no good okay so you have W so when
I was studying in Linux firewall I have
run into you fw i could be wrong okay
but i don't think it's good it's it's
you know it's trying to be you know the
problem with linux is that you have so
many complexities then you know that
it's like the the unix linux the system
is entirely [ __ ] up from the ground up
okay then you have people trying to
write a wrapper
trying to write you know a gentle you
know wrappers easier to use this all if
this is like a thing of unix part of
unix it happens in every program you
know you have something entirely [ __ ]
up then someone else tries to improve it
or write a wrapper like gentle
easy-to-use thing so ufw is one of the
thing i you know as far as i know let's
see and its space song you know it's a
wrapper to iptables okay so I don't know
for sure because you know I don't really
know fire what - well I you know I spent
one month studying it because back then
I was trying to get into a company and
they want me to do something about
firewalls so yeah their company you know
a startup they are thinking of the idea
where every home you know when you have
there let me yeah okay let me tell you
the idea so you know like home ink
seumas everyone you know have a internet
connection basically you for example in
America I don't know you know the you
know what happens in other countries
when you know America you you create
account
you know AT&T or whatever you know
company then you pay like $80 $50 a
month but your neighbor you know you
know apartment complex you have 10 or 20
people basically each person do that so
each one is paying $50 of $80 a month so
that's no good right I mean the company
makes our money but you guys don't
necessarily need to have a account you
know you could share you'll be much
better anyway this this startup company
is trying to create I don't remember you
know the details but anyway they are
trying to create some kind of share
network so that if I see my neighbor I
can say hi and this share Network and I
can just you know press some buttons and
we we have a shared internet something
like that okay
this is five years ago so so any that
that is the reason I looked into the
Linux IP tables which is one factor [ __ ]
you know the the documentation for IP
tables is entire [ __ ] you know the no
joke about it is the worst possible of
documentation I've seen in my 30 years
of programming well nobody I would say
the worst is Apache Apache talk and the
Linux man page okay but the IP table is
up there easy and you know I mean I beat
a poor man pages you know it's man page
you don't have it on the Mac man man IP
table you don't have it on on the Mac
okay so anyway it's on Linux only it's
you know the documentation is the entire
worst possible technical writing in
comprehensible [ __ ] and when you search
online they are like five ten tutorials
and they are all like twenty years old
so I wrote mine and you might check it
out so you if you prefer if you like
Mike
kind of writing my logical exposition
the way I look at things logical kriya
you know no no jargon no nonsense crap
you might check out my tutorial
okay so Linux firewall iptables tutorial
so let's see so we are we are site
tracking or you know something something
something yeah I need to read I need to
go back to read the comments ufw so well
bad says ufw is good I don't I don't
know for sure but from what I remember
it's it's not good you're part of the
thing you know part of the reason part
of the thing with this easy to use
gentle wrapper is that they don't they
cannot do I mean they are not powerful
okay they they they you know you have a
situation like that you know and this
happens in Linux a lot like someone
created something then people write a
wrapper to make it easier but but then
once you start to use it have heavily
seriously then it cannot do something
then you need to go back to the you know
deep down code thing you know that's
what happens so he says yeah I do
remember I've kind of looked into but I
don't I don't want to use the UFW and
also if you are looking for a job I mean
if if networking is the area you want to
go to do not use any of these nice
gentle wrappers you get no job okay
that's the thing you know if you are
looking for a job I mean I don't know
networking or if you are thinking about
a career or networking that interests
you or if you are you know interest to
be you know if networking is your thing
you don't want you don't want these
gentle rappers this advice to other
things as well language programming
languages linux issa mean and although
those for example if you want to be a
linux seasoning you don't want to use a
water the town nice for consumers easy
to install version that's that you go
nowhere okay
you won't type down type it down you
know that that's that's what
professional means you know that you
know of course there are good reasons
you know there are many good reasons
cases when you want to use this kind of
thing but you know depending on what you
want to do so so if you just want a
basic home firework maybe they work look
you know let me read this let me read
this you know that this [ __ ] Linux UNIX
[ __ ] one of the many eroded aspects of
Linux is its security security my ass
the worst insecure system Linux
you may remember guys remember that that
bleeding heart and all that from the
desktop to server you will find every
tool you need to keep those machines
locked down as tightly as possible for
the longest time the security of Linux
was in the hands of iptables
which works with the underlying
netfilter system no it is not the what
that's incorrect
although incredibly powerful IP table is
a complicated especially for newer users
to truly make the most out of this of
that system it may take weeks or months
to get up to speed thankfully a much
simpler front-end for IP table is ready
to help get your system is he secure as
possible as secure as you need he
secured my ass Linux UNIX the worst in
the most insecure operating system in a
history of computing
another interest havoc is NYX GUI xpm
okay so I actually I talked a lot
already today
and maybe I can just like call it a day
so 36 minutes so who are common what are
all these comments so let me get to them
okay
so dedicated if I were hardware or
software so I mean dedicated do you use
firewall no I don't use fire so how to
contribute to Emacs we talked about that
so is my answer
satisfactory you know is it because I
don't see you guys face and it's hard to
get information from textual you know
from writing so sometimes I'm talking up
you know so let me know what do you
think okay so bar says I'm setting up a
firewall for our corporate network okay
that's that's good but says how do not
talk about you max okay so IP tables is
cancer ufw handles it very well now you
might you might be right I don't know
for sure
demo essay so another interesting topic
is next GUI XP and package manager Oh
Linux package manager what a [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] up all [ __ ] up [ __ ] Linux
package manager you have pack your every
distro has their own okay you know so
you you have this you know the
incompatible fact and you know Red Hat
has NPM the Debian Ubuntu has the well
time to show my Linux tutorial okay so
let's go to
so computer network tutorial okay I
don't actually you know I don't know
computer networking that much you know I
did I did studied them since like even
since you know since 1999 but networking
you know networking is a deep subject
you can dive into it you can spend you
know you can spend your whole life you
can you know be a professional
networking expert networking networking
is actually critical it's you know just
just like Linux kernel so you have
kernel developers or operating system
experts you have networking you have
networking researchers you have
networking and networking protocols you
know the the protocols that's a deep
dive okay networking and and not
networking it's not just like tcp/ip
then you have phone phone networking
system you know your your your your
iPhone you know your mobile phone then
you have the wireless networking
protocols it's it's it's it's a it can
go as steep as you want okay you can
spend your whole life into it but in
general to average programmers you are
thinking of you know basic understanding
of tcp/ip so if that's the case you
might check out my tutorial okay it's
it's it's not bad for beginners okay my
tutorial tcp/ip introduction to tcp/ip
so that gets you an idea how the
internet works okay and also includes
some practical tips so what is IP
address what is the MAC address and
things like that how do you how to find
it out you know what's the command to
find out okay so that's that and let's
go to Linux tutorial okay Linux tutorial
and we were talking about
oh yeah the the package managers so I
haven't been using Linux for for like
three years or four years now three
years now
well but I'm on a Mac so you know did
you know this Maggie is supposedly to be
BSD system Linux [ __ ] it's the Linux
phonetics you know the the the the the
fanatism is such that for example what
if you are Linux phonetics or UNIX
philosophy oh you know UNIX UNIX with an
ethics open source or that Obst okay
so for example if you are a BSD phonetic
you know I have you know we have people
on this code who are PhD experts and and
in fans okay so so if you are a bsts
phonetic then wait wait let me go back
here okay if you are a BSD phonetic then
when it comes to Mac you say look look
even Mac adopted BSD you know bsts
fantastic look the Mac OS is the most
popular application who adopt the BSD
but when it comes to for example when it
comes to let's see let's say let's say
BSD kernel wait not gonna obviously yard
wait you know when it comes to any
specific that when you don't want you
know you don't like it max then you'll
say Oh Mac Mac is not BSD at all so you
see that these phonetics they are
flexible they need so cherry-picking
that that's what they doing you know
they actually all of us us to you know
we just only see the things we like and
we say it that way so and this happens
to Linux - especially in Linux you know
the Linux is more popular so when they
say you know Linux fans they are also
UNIX fast because UNIX is the granddaddy
of Linux so when they say you know when
they talk in general they will say oh
these notes is the most used you know
fantastic look even Mac adopted UNIX
system these people [ __ ] named Bob
but when it comes to let's say buying
Apple suppose they are also typically
they are also open source fans then you
know
when let's say someone wants to buy a
computer what they wonder if they should
buy a PC with Linux and or Mac and they
will say oh no don't buy Mac Mac it's no
good because you know they forgot all
about Maggie's part of unity linux
that's these people so anyway the you
know so open source you know as you know
I've done this many I talked about my
opinions on many of my videos the open
source and free software on foundation I
think they are a they have become I mean
the idea is not too bad it's it's it's
good okay but they have become a
ideology a very harmful ideology and and
the result of that is what we get is the
all-powerful all-encompassing Big
Brother Google Facebook Twitter they
control everything you do you have and
you cannot make money you cannot be a
independent programmer you unless you
work for Google do what they say or you
have no job you have no food to eat
that's that's what open source and you
know and free software fanatism cutters
okay that is my opinion so anyway back
to the linux distro I mean the Linux
package managers so so I haven't used
them fold before were also install
packages so on on Tavian and Ubuntu you
have the apt-get apt-get and app cache
and and dpkg this these commands are
pretty old they are they are like 20
years old
yeah about about 20 years old and they I
mean over the 20 years they have changed
quite a lot you know and it is basically
it's a pile of [ __ ] [ __ ] upon [ __ ] the
in Red Hat you have npm system then then
you know they don't they don't want to
adopt you know they don't want to unify
because you know the open source that's
the way things are you know yeah I want
my things to be popular you want your
things to be popular that's why there's
1000 distros none agree with each other
they are not
vibrating any you know they just fall
apart it's that's what what they are so
you have then you have pac-man pac-man
is what using up our clinics or
somewhere then you have Jen - Jen - is
doing and you know you have quite a few
then of course there's a NYX NYX is the
latest you know that you have a NYX NYX
a package manager which is space NYX OS
okay they call it NYX OS now basically
it's Linux with the NYX package manager
the NYX package manager is based on the
idea of functional programming so they
try to have it such that no side-effect
things like that based on you know
functional programming ideas so I heard
this is very good I would use it okay
Knicks I you know if I have to choose I
would use this so that that is my that's
that's my story about Linux package
managers you have a bunch of this thing
n F tables okay so a cm AC mom hung a
see how do you pronounce your name in C
AK mom hung something so let's see what
all the topics it's not bad with the
snaps now I'm very satisfied thanks okay
thank you
let's see how long I've been talking 13
people watching and 46 minutes live
scream rubber sauce
okay let's see what a green deck green
deck morning to Russia
haven't seen you for a while
Wow but he's leaving wait but why would
you you max again okay on a second see
me so let me see the comments
so the question is how to cope with
always having to learn new stuff when
programming I think that is the most
mentally taxing part of human to always
be in that state of confusion you know I
think that is actually the state of
things you know it's you know you might
think I mean if you are I mean I'm
talking about new people okay so for new
people who just came into programming
field they maybe they just graduate from
college they think you know they learn
things in college so they they now
working a company and they're gonna
apply their knowledge okay but most
likely that's not the cases at all you
join your company you're gonna be its
new things every year even more so every
or every few months it's new things new
protocols new its new things new library
new things every you know basically most
of your life you are working on things
you don't know you don't know how it
works you are learning that's that's my
experience
more or less okay I think that that is
the state of things that that is a
normal state of things you know because
today you might think oh maybe only
JavaScript is like that no you know if
you know it's not just about the
language okay so suppose if you know see
you working a company you know depending
on what company it does you know it
might be you know creating networking
products might be creating batteries you
know it might be research in something
wind turbines might be ecommerce you
know I was I was doing e-commerce you
know so maybe a gaming company so anyway
the the company they the company they
swim in all kind of new things and
including the management management
including I mean not just technical but
also none taken
change changes change is a key that's
the key of companies if you know if you
don't change if you don't know top you
die so this can't you know change all
the time
spec changes things change you know the
protocol changes you change it you know
so what I'm trying I think it is the
change that is actually the call of the
thing so you you just have to deal with
it so as to you know they don't stay put
you know if you want things to stay put
you become a lawyer or something hinder
and possibly you make more money
actually so so yeah so if you work in
technology sector change changes the
this is a normal state of things that's
the thing and you just deal with it you
yeah so I mean so so so if I can so I
would say you know that that's what you
that's a mentality you you have to you
know that that is a mentality to begin
with then you are fine you know is but
so if used instead you are thinking oh
how why is it they change it again you
know I just wrote this code for this
spec but now it changed again well what
I'm gonna do this is no good if you have
that mentality maybe you should get out
so that's that's that's what I think so
Campell Campbell says you can review and
give feedback to other people
packages if it's not yet yet accepted
Eddy it's an area you are experienced
with yeah
so yeah that's hey good morning Campbell
that's helpful
Nick so s okay yes sir Frankie's is our
mapper yes
so search for terra terra cotta el mapa
commits why
Tanika Yau is full-featured telegram
crying for new Emacs okay I never used
telegram okay so we need to put Emacs
here so github new Emacs telegram client
okay so Taylor Katya is full-featured
unofficial client for telegram platform
for new he max it is actively developed
for this reason some features are not
implemented or they are present just as
skeleton for future implementation
however the core parts are mature enough
okay what do you want me to look at this
I mean what's a what's the issue
okay special screenshots so as far as I
as far as I know telegram is a instant
messaging service similar to slack and
discord you know slack as far as I know
slack is focused on intercommunication
between co-workers in a tech company but
telegram we began in Russia
someone told me okay on discord someone
oh yeah there's a Reaper guy who told me
that
so telegram is from Russia originally
and I think Facebook only at now
Facebook product and they are so anyway
I never used it
okay so Campbell says to be fair
managing package so canvas Cameo says to
be fair managing packages repository is
a lot of work I think it's fine to have
mail pal community management yeah Mel
Parra yeah it's great yeah so like I
mentioned these three people you know oh
Maude you know I know these three people
they did you know it so I work for them
you know Steve cam
Steve Purcell he also has his own I
think he's he's doing his own company he
has his own company so he's based on New
Zealand that's interesting he's on
Twitter so you can follow him and see
his you know his opinions on things and
Jonas Bernoulli is also on Twitter the
milky postman I don't think he talks
much I mean he's last I know he said he
has at Google so next time when you run
on your next stop using Emacs then you
can talk about know about you know Emacs
is part of the thing you know a lot my
people use Emacs you know so den
Morris's international knowledge skills
Sian chat so Dane says I'm trying to get
in touch with more Emacs developers in
package maintenance to gain skills okay
so then I would recommend you join eMac
B's okay
I mean don't worry about what I said you
know I said a lot of bad things that
that is my opinion and then and that is
my true opinion but but still I mean for
anyone interested so you might join the
goon Emacs mini list okay do that you
know so you learn how they talk how they
do things you know the community is more
evil than evil mod in Emacs okay so hexa
hey Jason Jason is from North Ireland so
Campbell says well Emacs having small
codebase seems ok similar to Python will
be small core health package manager -
ok all our package features are ignored
- being added in Emacs
in terms for good reason so Jason says
what would you suggest to an enthusiast
amateur programmer like myself to do in
order to start learning emag B's oh well
I you know I I have written a Emacs to
tobio and I spent 15 years on it so I
would recommend you just read my
tutorial I mean they also a few others
but I would say you know it's normally
that's what not people you know if these
people don't do that but you know I just
say just read my tutorial because
there's not much they are not many
alternatives out there I mean they are
like they are just one page summary one
page summary but I have like 30 pages on
eMac B's I have like hundred pages in
detail for eMac this and for beginners
so I would recommend you read my image
tutorial you read it half an hour day
and try to code you know spin one hour a
day in a month or two you will be pretty
good and if you like my stuff if it
works out for you you know support me by
my tutorial okay
you have I have the links over there so
demo demo essays start by reading Emacs
through yo there is a beauty in command
yeah but that is for learning Emacs
that's not for learning eMac B's essays
hegemony Matt oh you are so late Matt
good morning to Germany
oh yeah shows
so I think that's it for today it's not
so bad with snaps now snaps now what
snaps so Benjamin mone I thought
telegram is for Russian who wants
encryption to hide from government yeah
something like that
I mean they I think one of the thing
about telegram is that they support
encryption but apparently now it's owned
by Facebook so it's so American now and
anyway I haven't used it so you can go
to Wikipedia and you can find a lot of
details so I think that's it for today I
don't know if I did good
you know it's half French and have a
simple one hour okay so that's it for
today thank you guys for coming so any
more any more comment questions posted
okay we shut down in maybe five minutes
or two minutes and I'm just going to
thank you Cathy house house house going
Cathy so Cathy Cathy you are doing
research on data science right so how's
your projects how is your oak Mart and
how is your tech all our tech going and
what what package did you end up
choosing for doing the tech go tech so
let me copy the things I talked about
today and put it on my talk show page so
that later on oh not here so later I can
put them into my youtube description so
other people can go to you know they
will see the descriptions of the topics
V sub topics so Emacs mailing list you
know Emacs meaningless is colorful
because every month or two
you know when whenever you meet let me
tell you this story okay so Kathy which
package did you end up using for tech or
latech so so our eMac main list every
two month or so there is a GUI
discussion for example should Emacs have
this GUI or something like that
okay graphical user interface and and
every time that comes up it's going to
be a big flame fest okay hundreds of
messages and every Cho will have an
opinion like you know one of the very
annoying thing on inactive list is that
they you know this this it's like a
commune okay like I was like I said the
richest omen it's like you know the
communism idea commune basically all the
people go there you don't have to be a
good coder you don't have to be nothing
any joke you know in fact they are kind
of you like you know we're just you know
oh like you just showing you deeply
believe in the glue you know the the
free software of ideology you know like
richest omen you deeply believe me with
whatever Richard Stallman says so you
join it then you'll have a voice and and
and and like you know some of these
people many of them they are there for
20 years they are really good eMac miss
developers I can say it is true for
Eddie
he sees the you know he's you could say
he's a yeast card Steph ammonia to
they've read you know they've written
many packages I can name them I'm not
going what is he I'm not going to beat
you know you can find out many of them
and many of them from and some of them
are you know Jonah I don't know this guy
well but he's been there for ten years
also and you know I you know I know most
of these people and many of them they be
in writing eMac based for 10 years 20
years
and Martin root root Alec I think he
also and bastian bastian is the
maintainer of oak mod for 10 plus years
ok so you know you have many great eMac
mr. kotis but but you also have like
random Joe and also this guy this
Japanese guy Yamamoto
misoo shahru ok he has contributed he
doesn't talk much
only you know I can I can I can start to
give you a who is who on a on AG new dev
you know list like you have different
characters some are colorful some I
always make troubles some like to always
talk about their opinions ok and you
know and son are always quiet they never
talk they never when whenever there is a
controversial they never give any
opinion they didn't you know
for example this yamato mitsubishi miss
sue her guru is one such guy he I never
seen him showing any controversial
thread such as when they'd start to talk
about GUI ok graphical user interface
whenever there's a GUI topic comes up
everyone it becomes a flame war although
you are idiot ok each one calling each
other idiot I mean they don't use the
word idiot but there you can see it's
it's very heated ok like yeah like I
think this it should be this way why you
didn't say so why waste you proof then
someone says well I already posted the
proof two times you know yesterday you
didn't see it you should go check it you
know read it again it's a big fight
every time every every few months doing
whenever there's a GUI issue comes up
but anyway this guy for example
he never I never seen you never join
such controversy but however he's a big
deep eMac this expert ok the kind of
things I've seen I you know I I don't
remember exactly but I've seen
contributions he always his contribution
is the call of Emacs okay not not just a
package that does something you can see
you don't see it you cannot you know
he's so he's a contribute to the co of
Emacs you know like like the deep down
engines things like that you know so I
know many of these people and for
example Eddie and and also there's this
guy
Dimitri good 12 is also there you know
for a long time
Alan this this [ __ ] Adam against Alan
McKenzie he's a old Eva Skoda and he is
the one every time there is some you
know people try to improve Emacs he will
shut it down this Adam McKenzie guy she
wants
Emacs to be like the like the way it is
in 1980s Alan McKenzie this guy every
time there's a people trying to improve
Emacs for the new generation he is the
one who shut it down I talked about this
before and I have articles on my website
you can you can just search my name you
might find some some info yeah I have
articles I I am now going to spend time
to bring them up you know I'm just
giving you the dirty laundry okay now
this poor Oh Gert is also a old old time
okay he's there I think he's there for
at least 20 years or more and he is one
of the he's a maintainer of the the
granddaddy that you know the very old
packaged compiler generator what's a new
compiler generator
anyway have I only ever met one of these
people I've met Zhang Jiang Wiggly who
is the current maintainer and also
but most of them most of them I have not
met face to face I mean they know me I
know them you know some up in for
example Eddie we've been we've been
[ __ ] each other since since 2005 okay
my dramatic way of expressing it you
know we've been arguing since 2005 and
this alum against Mackenzie Mackenzie
this German guy we've been we can
[ __ ] we've been you know fighting
crying each other's out since 2005 on
the new scoop and the true Adam is also
a very old whisper you know he's he's
been calling this for I will say 30
years or more you know I think he's he
might be 60 something now or even though
the drew Adam also you know me all these
people has made has written many
packages you can find emails wiki you
know Joe and Emacs people you have lots
of weirdos in Emacs among Emacs users
okay counting me you know you know in
many because I am pretty weird drew Adam
is also weird you know he he refused to
use github funny he refused to use
github he insists that he he only put
his coat on the Emacs wiki and there's a
big flame war you can see you know lots
of stories the Emacs law poor at okay
Paul oh god is the he what's the name of
the package but anyway you might search
you search his name you'll find out my
website okay let me show you some go to
Emacs search for poor oh god okay
actually it's search for in a whole
directory of my Emacs website you can
see the flame wars and dramatic stories
yeah there it is one of the story
JavaScript mod war
this happened in 2010 when javascript is
not in emacs yet and and then you have
this emag be stock string Cody called
controversy big flame war 1000 messages
fighting fighting about this issue and
the end the at the end the island
[ __ ] you know but actually the Alan
McKenzie bring bring brought it up and
at the end that which her soul man
killed it
he is not a maintainer but he just he
just farted and he killed it he killed a
major improvements in emacs which has
stolen which as omen is the is a guy who
did the most damage to Emax in the past
10 years so anyway so you know you join
the group okay then you talk to them you
learn things and then you will be a good
part of Emax death okay that's it for
today so let's see so and so la tech oh
c'mon
okay I don't actually I don't know much
about that though Tech was not only
early syntax personally I cannot think
of any better syntax for editing math
functions in Unicode system so I thank
whoever for making that text
tolerable okay so have you ever made any
of those okay so another interesting
topic fracture factors Metapod yeah
let's talk about that next time
so does anyone do what richard stallman
say so i guess he has much influence
yeah okay that's it for today thank you
guys for coming and bye