hello welcome to another episode of San
talk show yay today we going going to do
three things or maybe more so first of
all I'm going to
introduce the review of the kesis
360 keyboard This is USB wired keyboard
okay I have been delaying review and and
uh we're going to talk about that kesis
keyboard so that's first thing then I'm
going to demo cly Keys cly Keys okay uh
I'm going to demo emac cly keys this is
for Kim posm kosm okay demo soft keys
then I'm going to do wolf and research
Mathematica okay so wam research
Mathematica fantastic powerful
programming language okay uh
wam
research Mathematica we're going to show
you some fun things okay programming
language function design design of the
functions so kesis Advantage keyboard
let's go back here okay uh sof Keys emac
then wam language and uh some maybe
something else you ask questions I talk
okay and pay me okay Che uh PayPal or
whatever patreon PayPal or Super Chat
German hello German hello Q intent Q
intent okay so first stop is kesis yeah
kesis Advantage keyboard so this
one now this is $400 you know I got it
about four months ago but because lots
of delays I got uh by by the way this is
magnetic Snap-on magnetic uh you know
but you have to buy this separately very
expensive fancy keyboard okay made of
solid
metal actually I'm not sure exactly
what's the material it's it's heavy okay
it's like 1.5 kilog or 3 lounds three
something pounds okay so anyway I did a
live unboxing so let me talk about the
keyboard kesis 360 okay hello
immortality kesis
okay and this is also Fant this is also
fantastic automat hacking keyboard okay
now let me switch to my keyboard so to
my browser so you can see let me show
you okay s.
info okay you are at my homepage uh
search KES
KS kesis okay kesis Advantage 36 okay I
have lots of vles on kesis Advantage
keyboard let me show you a few okay
unboxing
Gallery uh okay this is 360 and this is
kesis advantage to so let me show
you so there you know you got some
layout you know the fantastic you can
show quy vorak comac this is my personal
layout for soft FL keys let me show you
the okay so let me show you the key so
this is kesis advantage to customized
version people customize it so you got
this fancy buttons and uh uh track
boards okay so let me let me get to the
point okay so this is unboxing Gallery
which I did review so um let let me just
get to that so this is kesis advantage
to I have been using this keyboard for
like
um six years okay if you watch my videos
you know yes magnetic pads that's
fantastic so I've been using kesis
advantage to for six years they gave me
one and I bought one myself okay love it
uh then about 4 months ago well about uh
about 10 months ago the kesis 360 came
out which is an upgrade after after
about 10 years or 15 so that's what I
have so by the way can you see my screen
or what are you seeing okay so you are
seeing okay so the 360 came out this is
the successor of the kesis advantage
2 uh and lots of features you know lots
of it's upgrade so lots of
improvements now they they sent it to me
about about four month five four four
months ago but I was spe busy with glove
at0 keyboard and I also was busy doing
uh programming and stuff so I didn't I
never got time to really review it and
also one of the most critical thing is
that the one they sent me is brown
switch Brown switch Cherry MX Brown I
think uh but because I have RSI uh all
over mostly my left arm so these days I
need super light switch in at you know
it must be linear cherry red at least or
lighter
so but now I got the brown I so I cannot
type
this um for long long durations because
I type a lot I type you know four hours
nonstop every day so um so the problem
so if I am writing a long
essay can you see it yeah so let's
magnify I
uh what what's going
on oh yeah so if I'm writing a long
essay then I really need the super light
switch okay so I'm going to return it to
them you know although they gave it to
me I said I can use it so I'm going to
return to them because but I haven't
done review so I'm going to maybe this
is last review I'm doing today then I'm
gonna send it back around what price
expensive my friend so this kesis 360 is
about 400 but that's about the price for
this kind of keyboard it's over 400 so I
did a live stream video
review uh you should go you guys should
check out because that's a full one hour
a 35 minutes unboxing and I talk about
you know this kind of keyboard okay so
that's cant talk show
2023 May 9th kesis advant Advantage 360
Unboxing okay so you you guys watch uh
go check that out then I have a website
just search for Kinesis s Kinesis 360 uh
so you can see my detailed review about
this
keyboard lots of photos uh and detail
okay so um yeah pretty expensive $400
but your hand if you go see a doctor
it's going to cost your life
so uh keyboard is very important okay so
they send me a brown switch but I cannot
use it so I I'm going to return it to
them uh you
know okay so you know I'm going to talk
to them and see what
happens so I was going to re so what uh
so I guess you guys uh haven't seen you
know what am I going to say about the
I'm GNA just use it today okay so
because I haven't been using
it I'm just going to use it okay so
that's about that so let's talk about
let's go to the next topic or is there
any other questions uh now let's talk
about Stu like ke okay check check check
check okay let's talk about Sly
keys so s like Keys okay so let's go to
okay
so copy that go back here showing
browser so this is today's talk show
paste the link linky showing browser so
we got a link so German says German
Molina says is when did people start
making these custom keyboards okay
that's um that's a good question so
there's a history to this so kesis
advantage to so if uh let me show you
okay so if you go to S keyboard review
so you you have a full bunch of them the
earliest in in America uh in English
speaking country this this one is kind
of kind of the earliest depending on how
you judge you know so anyway the the
first curved ball keyboard is this one
1977 okay so this is multron keyboard
1977 they still sell it now okay you can
actually buy it there's a video uh so
molon is the first one then kesis
Advantage came out not this one the
earlier version but they look the same
so let me show you the earlier version
so actually I have a history so let's go
ergonomic keyboard and ergonomic
keyboard
history you know so you see the full
history of this ergonomic keyboard
including a typewriter ergonomic
typewriter symmetric key Arrangement
since
1935 now I'm not actually sure this is
the earliest anyway so it's it goes way
back so anyway as far as keyboard goes
then you have
the motron is the kind of the first
then uh kesis Advantage uh hold on a
second let me do
that so motron then kesis Advantage let
me go to the previous
version so you you know I have a lot
photos uh the previous version
is
now I don't have it on my I think maybe
I I have a photo somewhere but anyway it
looks
exactly it looks exactly like that so
anyway this came out this came out in
1993 around there okay kesis Advantage
so they are basically a copy of the
motron except they remove the middle
Keys now I'm not sure what's the deal I
think originally they tried to get the
right for the patent or something then
it didn't work out or something I don't
know so
anyway Advantage kesis Advantage came
out
1993 I have a history page somewhere
here I forgot where
okay so you can you can see so and
then
then then
basically the glove 80 came out this is
what my current keyboard if you watch if
you have watched my past YouTube live
stream you can see it starting this year
February also uh so this is kind of the
third one so that's the most prominent
ones okay now there are also some do it
yourself ones so let me show
you
um you know so do itself the most famous
the earliest one is the dtile
you see you buy the components and you
build it and you do itself also very
expensive you know be then you spend
like $300 to buy all these things then
you assemble you try to Soldier and put
it together so if you are into that if
you are a into soldiering and
electronics you can do that so this
ttile is do it yourself and came out
around
2014 okay then there's uh quite a lot
Japanese ones for example this uh this
one you have to I mean Japanese do it
yourself I'm not sure they sell uh ready
made so there's a video you can see uh
Japanese usually they have smaller hands
let me get my
drink okay so that's kind of the history
so
then if we go back so I mean let me show
you a few there's some weird ones really
weird ones so for example there you have
that one you have this
one not even sure how do you type on
this one uh some of them are
experimental you know the all these came
out in the last uh 10 years starting
2013 also and then you have this
one
and you have this one thumb eater you
see this one you put your thumb in that
hole you know and you can you can you
can you have fourway switch you can move
your thumb in four different ways uh so
this is thumb eater well the official
name is atlas 56 so this you know so you
see so this all kind of weird you know
do it yourself once and uh you have this
one
and then you have this one this this one
is also from the same Japanese sky so
anyway and you and one of the
interesting thing in this one is got uh
joystick on it which is very useful okay
so anyway these are to it yourself ones
uh and then you have this uh Russian
made Russian ones this is from Russia
so okay so that's some of the and also
you have some Comm man scams for example
this one they announced it on
Kickstarter and they got the money but
it never came out uh about 10 years
ago okay so you know King's
assembly uh then you have this one uh
this one is a do yourself from Hong Kong
it also never went anywhere I
think oh from
yeah uh yeah they kind of went
away then we don't have C okay you know
either they went away the product never
never
came uh and this one this one is came
out this one is available key Mouse so
it's also interesting so the idea with
this one key Mouse is that you move the
entire keyboard it function as a mouse
so you can you can type type type and
move the entire keyboard as a
mouse they also have a track boo version
in fact several of you guys who watch me
bought it I know Kathy bought it uh
Kathy and and another guy bought it and
some of the some of the photos on my
website is actually from them I have uh
you know given the name you know some of
the photo there this one from coo
2018 so he he also did a video review so
you might search for
coo uh you know on YouTube so anyway
that's some of the curved curved sub
concave surface keyboard okay the we
ones then you can look at the history uh
the history
of of ergonomic keyboard his
so like we mentioned you know the
earliest one I know is this
typewriter ranto portable ergonomic
typewriter
okay then you have this Luigi colani
office chair now L you see now Luigi
this guy is some kind of artist you know
Visionary so I don't think those are
mass produced but they he makes a lot of
these artistic geometric kind of design
things this Luigi colani I think it's
Italian you can search your web you can
you'll find lots of his like design of
entire city like futuristic thing like
this picture you
know usually it's not practical and mass
produced then if we look at theonomic
keyboard history then one of the most
Pro prominent one is from Japan so Japan
has a bunch of them you know for example
this one thumb shift keyboard starting
in uh
1978 you know you look at their keyboard
is entirely symmetrical you know not
entirely but you know the you see
1978 okay so you search for my website I
have a lot history so then so this page
is arranged by date so
19 1970
1978 then
1977 oh is actually one year
earlier then you have
1983 from Japan NEC NEC is a big company
so you have this fantastic plastic
design you know all kind of designs of
symmetric ergonomic keyboard you see
their key Arrangement is a grid kind of
so you don't have this
weird you know weird semi diagonal shape
on a typical PC keyboard the reason they
are like that is because back then the
mechanical typewriters underneath each
key each key is basically a hammer and
underneath each key they need to make
the lines of the
hammer equal distant to each other so
you end up with the keys uh in a weird
Arrangement actually I have a history on
that so you look at the design
page so you can see this is kind of the
typical arrangement of the keys you know
they are not it's like weird
semi-regular not exactly you know and
why is it that way you can
see you can understand why they have
this Jagged uh kind of arrangement
alignment by looking at this picture you
see this picture is a mechanical type
writer and you can see the metal bars
underneath it those are levelers you
know you you you press here the key hits
up and uh you can see they are equal
equal distance
uh why are they equal distant because
otherwise you don't have space you know
you you you you need to make them equal
distant so but then at the end of the
level leveler is the key attached to
it so if you so you cannot make them you
know the key to form a grid shape
because otherwise it won't work so due
to geometric constraints
that is why today's keyboard have this
weird you know
diagonal Jagged
alignment okay so and uh and we stuck
with it because when we started to have
computer keyboards we don't have these
mechanical things underneath but however
people's habit
overruled you know if you design a great
keyboard people say what the is
that
because they are already we are already
used to this weird alignment same thing
with the shift key you know why is it
called shift because when you press that
key it actually shift all the gears
shift all the gears like kind of like
the piano pedal you know it shift all
the gear all the levels underneath then
therefore then you press a key they hit
a different spot so that's why you have
shift key and that's why you have to
press it down hold it
first then press the other key then
release the shift completely idiotic
well that's that's the way it is when
you have mechanical keyboards but when
you have computer keyboards people are
stuck with a habit so they insist you
must have a key such that you hold it
you must hold it so that is a disaster
and we lived with it even today
including the shift key control old meta
you know Windows key you have to
press it down hold it and press the key
then you in in in that order you cannot
just press them together you have to
press the modifier first hold it then
press the other then release the then
release the modifier okay completely
idiotic but
haveit stuck okay that's why we that's
why you know so we will we will uh
explaining originally why they are you
know in this weird sh alignment okay but
let's go back to the keyboard
history uh ergonomic keyboard history so
you can
see then we have manyu and uh Japanese
Japanese has a lot fantastic designs for
example this
one okay are we uh what else are we so
are we ready to talk about soft FL
Keys let's
[Music]
see uh around what price when did people
start making this keyboard okay how do
you like the keyboard iio model
100 I never had
it uh so you are talking about let me
show you the keyboard model 100 okay
so so we so but uh okay so let me talk
about keyboard model 100 okay it's not
here
actually oh yeah I put it where did I
put
it ergonomic keyboard
reviews yeah here so here is
the this here is the keyboard iio model
one it came out about uh what
2017 uh 6 years ago
I never actually had have it
so uh so I don't I don't have um from
from just the design point of view I
think it's
excellent okay just from the design
point of view uh I think it's excellent
and uh there is a innovation in this
one nowhere else
before a few okay one of the Innovation
is look at the thumb keys look at the
key caps of these thumb keys they are
not Square they are not concave they are
convex okay you know like little bumps
little bubbles thumb Keys okay so so the
shape of the thumb Keys is a
Innovation from this keyboard IO uh guy
okay I kind of know this guy he's a
pearl programmer uh you know classic
nerd from
1990s so the shape of the thumb Keys is
a Innovation on this keyboard and they
got a palm key so you can you can see
they got a palm key this this thing so
that's another in Innovation so you type
type type with your fingers then you can
use your thumb then you can use your pal
like pal press uh yeah I I hope they
send me one for review but you know that
and I I don't have
it us uh and they yeah they they went
into elaborate design so they choose
wood material I I'm not really into this
kind of luxury design I prefer practical
so this you know as compared to
grandfather Clark that's my classic
example you know when you see a
grandfather clock I don't know if you
guys young people have used ever seen
it let me show
you
grandfather clock I don't know you guys
know what that
is okay so let me show you some pictures
of
that okay that's what it is Grandfather
Clock you know this this ancient and
elaborate and it's a luxury item you
know it's very uh you know of course was
very expensive and you know carved you
know this fine carving so heavy and it's
heavy and
uh you know you know
Baro okay
so
so instead of that you know and and so
sometimes also guilded you know they
have goldplated Guild you know like
extremely fancy like Trump's Trump's
house
you know golden look uh I don't like
this kind of design style kind of luxury
style I don't like this kind of
elaborate luxury style rather I prefer
scientific and Space Age you know when
you watch science fiction movies you see
the space station the things there
that's the things I like functional
everything is functional
and I like them light you know I don't
like heavy so in keyboard and lots of
gadgets many people judge the quality of
the gadget by how much they weight so
today you have lots of keyboard they
actually just put a brick inside like
heavy metal inside the keyboard so it's
heavy idiotic okay well it's kind of
like a taste of style you know different
people have different
you know some people like this so what
I'm saying is that
this this keyboard
IO guy they went with this kind of
luxury kind of design so you know they
choose to make this keyboard out of wood
and uh you know and also and and look at
the giant huge octo
feet they have to have this giant octo
feet
so yeah okay so that's a design
aspect
okay so in comparison for example let me
tell you this this is one of the issue
many
reviewers mention about this keyboard
let me uh show you okay so when you know
today online you can see many review of
the of the k
360 as compared to you know these are
competitors okay kesis
360 is a
competitor to
the uh to the
um to the glove
80 okay glove 80 keyboard so you know I
have both of them right now so this is
glove 80 so glove 80 is the as far as
the design of the style goes just the
style aspect GL 80 is what I like light
made of plastic okay made of cheap
plastic you know what's what's cheap
plastic that's Space Age material if
you're going to go out of space you want
plastic you want the most durable you
know and cheap to make and doable and
you can you know most practical made of
plastic and functional design okay so
when you watch other people's review of
the glove 80 versus the kesis 360 kesic
360 3 360 right now I'm using weights a
turn Okay
heavy so I I don't know if I can I'm
like like this is cramped it's like
heavy okay it's uh
this it's a
brick okay meanwhile let me show you
my 360
okay uh where do where do you see it
okay 360 so you can see side by side
it's kind of much more
smaller and if you remove this you know
it's kind of much more smaller and Light
so many people will say when they first
see it is this is kind of like oh it's
not look you know it's cheap you know
it's like
cheap feather light you know Fe feather
weight you know they'll say you know so
a lot of people will judge the weight
judge things by their weight meanwhile
when they see this oh my God this is
luxury you know so but that's a matter
of
taste okay what else uh what what
else so yeah so let's go back is there
any some more questions let's go back
about
um so lots of Articles
okay From Russia with Love quis quis
From Russia with a nuke the one with
palm resting pad may be very comfortable
one okay actually I I talk I I talked
about this many times I myself don't
don't like the I mean I don't use the
Palm rest much I prefer bath Tower okay
you see these thick bath Towers that's
the best Palm
rest do you still like using your U uhk
ultimate hacking keyboard yes ultimate
hacking keyboard let me show you okay
version
two H what is
this ultimate hacking keyboard version
two can you see
it oh you cannot let me show you okay uh
well you can see it here okay fantastic
okay uh I use it right now as a keyboard
marker pad so I can for example I can
you know I can uh you cannot see it but
let me show you so I can switch browser
tabs just by pressing this Keys backward
forward or close it reopen it and not
that one reopen is this one
okay keyboard mro okay so because I
already have a a fancy keyboard so I use
it as a keyboard marro
and
um
and where is it
and if you're going to use it just for
typing it's also fantastic okay this is
high quality one of the best keyboard I
I highly recommend they also they send
it to me they are very nice to me they
send it to me I have a video they send
it to me they also send me all the
different modules you know the track boo
module the extra key module and the
trackpad module excellent design okay
and by the way I also have the first
version ultimate hacking keyboard first
version I use it for a year
and I use it for half a year typing for
typing and I used it for uh keyboard
marro for like five six years so I've
been using you know the automa hacking
as a keyboard marker for like over for
about maybe 10 years the best it's the
best um software to program the keys the
best feature okay so that's automa
hacking keyboard so if you are
interested you know watch my review so
you know
um okay and uh yeah I'm not going
to talk about Tima hacking is good okay
and uh what else King King uh King
hering King hering are you the king
poome guy well I well how long have I
been talking uh maybe we should do a Sly
Keys another
day NASA Punk the aesthetic you are
describing is NASA Punk okay I never
heard of that term let's look it up NASA
Punk can can you guys see my screen no
let's go back okay let's see NASA
Punk oh that's
a uh that's not a established term
Starfield a Sci-Fi game developed by
bista has a NASA Punk aesthetic that
aims to capture the feeling feelings
evoked by the American space
organization okay let's see some images
let's see what's NASA
Punk okay uh
well anyway so let's see thank you for
your thought thank
you if you have to pick a keyboard as
your daily Drive which one would it be
you know that's one of the frequent
frequently Asked question and I have a
frequently answered answer the answer is
I cannot tell you okay
okay well for me currently my daily
Drive is the glove 80 okay this one can
you see it yeah
okay now but if you ask me so if you
want to know which one is the best best
ergonomic keyboard SAR pick I can I can
explain you know they the various
keyboards they differ by price they
differ by for example glove 80 is light
right and kesis advantage to is cheaper
but bulky then if you go with the um you
know the the B the bottom line is
somewhat some of them are portable some
of them are not some of them are
Bluetooth wireless some of them are not
some of them are $400 some of them are
150 okay some of them are adjustable
tting some of them are one piece okay
one for example another one let me
recommend I highly recommend is this one
one single
piece uh about 150 expose light you know
this is one of you know my top three
favorite so depending on you if you are
just going to buy one keyboard right you
do you want it portable how much you're
going to spend first of all $200 too
much 100 200 or 300 or 400
this kis 360 is over 400 okay if you go
with the glove 80 that's also I think
close to 400 okay so how much you want
to spend do you want them to be portable
do you want them to be Wireless or not
or some people rather prefer wired for
me when I sit down I want it wired I
don't want Wireless I don't want
Bluetooth okay uh and you know do you is
it split is it is that necessary for you
for many it's not okay so many different
and do you want the light you know fancy
light usually I don't care about fancy
light and how much programmability do
you want so kind of depend depends on
you okay like people most most people
want to know which one is the best which
one which one of them like is you know
there's no absolute answer I can
but I can tell
you my you know absolute which one is
the best quality so gra8 I highly
recommend kesis advantage to I highly
recommend okay uh kesis 360 I can Al I
can also recommend it's kind of
expensive over $400
okay uh Expos night I highly recommend
okay
and uh ul Ultimate haing keyboard I
recommend
okay and there are others so you know I
cannot say exactly tell you which one to
buy you know for example This One isra S
SRE new Keo it's from
Japan I don't have it I never tried it
but as far as I know from the design
point of view and from seeing
other uh people who have used it reviews
it's
excellent however this one is
$500 five 500 US dollar so you know
price comes into play you know it's like
if it's a best keyboard but it cost a
million are you going to buy
it so that's why you know all things
considered I give you some of my
recommendations so you can go cheap you
know for example this this one you can
just buy two of them you know this made
in China kind of
programmable uh together they are 150
you
know so it's all up to
you or if you want to go with a quality
build quality Brand This one is also
pretty good you know kesis freestyle
Edge keyboard or kesis gaming keyboard
This one is also pretty good you know uh
150 or something programmable and uh but
you know but they got the grid you know
the it's not a matrix layout you know so
this pros and
cons uh oh the grandfather keyboard
style okay so the aesthetic so so thank
you for thoughts okay so if you have to
pick keyboard is your daily driver okay
so the light is out of
stock they only have the night right
yeah I believe so so the expose night
right oh excellent so yeah so yeah I I
want to give a shout out to this um
where is
it uh I want to give a shout out to
the expose okay so s keyboard guide
ergonomic keyboard I want to give a
shout out to Expos because when they
came out they came out in um they came
out like in early two uh they came out
in let's see
2017 they sent me one okay that's even
before the Expos light you know before
that that model came out two years later
also so they sent me the very first
prototype and I used it reviewed it it's
this one okay a photo you see it's
fantastic this Expos every time I use it
it's just a joy because I so by now I
have so many uh each time you switch it
takes some energy you know to set up
your desk but every time I use Expos
it's just a joy okay and I can get used
to right away okay despite it kind of
new design fantastic can you guys see it
yeah
okay so then
then because you know this the the the
the version they sent me uh is a
prototype then I cannot program it
because they Chang the
firmware then after a few years they
send me
the uh the night the night of nature you
know they send me the the the you know
this one two years ago fantastic okay I
also did a video review of it you can
see you know all the details quality
photo details uh where is my review here
okay okay so that's it I
guess so we talked about keyboards uh I
think let let it just be keyboard today
because uh because that's better for the
video focusing on one topic anything
else you guys have any questions
anything
else let's
see okay keyboards now I was going
to you know let me do some typing I
guess something
typing I was is going to
um well what what
uh yeah it's too bad you know they they
send me with this brown switch so I
cannot you know use as my
main
uh I might as well return it to
them uh is there anything else I want to
say yeah it's it's you know I can
recommend it it's kind of expensive but
it's got you know
uh highly programmable and and one of
the feature one of the great feature in
this one not in others is on the Fly
programmability that is let's say if I
want to make this key to copy contrl c i
can program it just press you know I
just hold this key and press this key
then press contrl C then press that
key then that's it then whenever I press
that key that's that'll send contrl C I
do not have to launch any firmware or
any application or GUI none of that you
know just press a few Keys you can
program your keys on the Fly
programmability okay this feature is
rare uh as far as you know among the
keyboard I have you know it's rare this
feature is rare so but it's part of the
kesis Advantage okay let's let's go
to it's part of the kesis advantage
but let me let me show you
okay so the kesis 360 they have two
versions one is
USB the other one is Wireless called
kesis 360 pro that's a wireless
Bluetooth one okay now they both of them
look exactly the same they look exactly
the same however the programmability is
entirely different okay so the One USB
with USB which is the one I
have they come with the Smart Set
firmware and that's the best okay the
Bluetooth one come with the zmk firware
and to program that is a is hell you
know like if if you want to set a key to
be copy you have to
like uh you have to like go to the
website read the instructions download
the firmware then then then something
you know I don't I don't really have
that keyboard so I my description is not
exact but I I know the experience I
heard of it you know so the kesis 360
pro the wireless one
with zmk firware if you want to program
it it's kind of a lot to do okay so but
with the the USB version 360 USB it come
with a Smart Set software Smart Set
firmware which is identical to the
advantage to firware and you have on the
Fly programming and other features and I
really like that
okay
Tre sits in emac and Mathematica okay so
you want so let's do
some uh do you use e-readers no I don't
use
e-readers I don't use you know because I
had to
read um I mean not these days I yeah
usually when I read I just read
Wikipedia and website I don't like PDF I
don't like
it's not like I don't like I just these
days I haven't really read any
electronic books the so-called
electronic like
ebooks Mathematica okay Mathematica is
great let's not let's say not today and
Tre C in emac that's also a great topic
but uh not today and also I haven't
study it much anything else about
keyboards okay about keyboard guys let's
shut down let's shut down in three
minutes okay so let's let me shut down
in 3 minutes I'm going to put uh what we
talked about
into into uh into my talk show page so
yeah okay so how
so 360 and uh
okay CL that NASA Punk GR grandfather
clock idiotic
thing you know grandfather clock is part
of the
Baro style uh b o not ba
a uh I spelled it
wrong Yu
let's
see yeah you see this kind of style I
really don't like at all this kind of
thing you know people some people love
them some people think oh this this
is this is luxury this is fine art and I
don't like them this you see because
this kind of design it's the opposite of
being functional it's heavy you know you
can't move it hard to clean impossible
to clean well unless you are super rich
you have nannies to clean it for you
then and elaborate you know this ugly
artwork ugly ugly I don't want to see it
okay and gold plated you know whatever
this you know gold
thing okay and
uh you see no good it's not
good elaborate
useless okay some of them are pretty
some some but useless okay now on the
other hand you know so you can
architecture is a rich field
architecture AR architecture is the
exhibition of geometry okay architecture
you know some of them is extremely
beautiful especially Cathedrals and
church right so you know this one I like
you know although it's Ro
Roa uh style but on the other
hand so we
can you know there are many
architectural Styles uh on Wikipedia
Wikipedia is very good on this oh
uh let's just look at architecture
okay so uh not here AR
Pi okay so you know you have some of
these elaborate famous Church there yeah
they are beautiful but it's not my
favorite style as far as style goes okay
now you know far as style goes I
like you know so you have some of these
ancient Asian Roman or Greek
style uh and yeah you have the Chinese
style uh not my taste also you
know and you have oh these are beautiful
this Islamic
style yeah but they are they are also
kind of elaborate and not functional and
they are beautiful though they are
extremely beautiful some of these are
just amazingly beautiful you
see but one of the style I like uh let
me just show you
oh yeah
U
art I don't know how I pronounce it
correctly
but uh oh
God okay kind of funky so here's some
examples uh what what is this
style oh god there are so many
hereu yeah so you can
see beautiful okay I kind of like this
style but uh but still this is not the
functional style I'm talking about
because they have a lot of elaborate
curves and so on but I I I love
this uh but then there's a lot okay let
me let me show you some functional
style okay for example some some of
these okay
this beautiful okay let me show you
okay this is our no I don't know how do
you pronounce it in in French so anyway
this is uh well this is also
not so anyway so this is kind of modern
kind of geometric style I kind of like
okay
functional and also this one beautiful
okay in in a different way
okay and this one beautiful okay
beautiful kind of modern okay that's it
for today so have you tried other input
methods like voice gesture like Stephan
Hawking uh yeah I tried it a bit before
but never in
length it's looking for that arasaka NE
militarist
style arasaka mil Neo militarist what is
that style so let's
look okay I'm going to go that's it for
today thank you for watching pay me
okay PayPal
me uh AR Saka rifle
[Music]
no I'm not sure what he
said okay bye
guys
for