good morning everyone
yeah when I get
right
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sod talk show check if I'm
alive okay today I'm going to talk
random things well every day is random
things but today I'm going to talk about
I'm going to talk about YouTube things
and okay let's go through the website
sorry Donald
okay then go to were the English okay
and the were the English website is
about literature about vocabulary about
writing about linguistics about things
related to that and also you see there's
a language a artificial language called
loach bong it's an artificial language
that is based on logic now what does
that you see what we have English French
Spanish Chinese Japanese Korean and
Arabic and so on those are called
natural languages that's our human
language now but there is also one thing
called artificial language or today is
called constructed language now this
language these are not natural languages
they are like created invented by people
so why do you create artificial
languages they are actually quite a lot
of them more than ten for example the
the you probably have heard of King Kong
you know it's from the Star Trek show
Klingon that's an artificial language
and you know and you know in token token
stavos you know the two towers the
hobbit ring of yeah the ring you know
one ring to rule them all
you also have constructed constructed
language you know constructing languages
for the elves in some but so those are
two that's two examples of constructed
language or you know used to be code
just artificial languages now those
languages are created obviously for the
purpose for the novels you know you so
you know you have a language of a
particular race you know the troughs or
the elves or the you know monsters or
aliens
you know Klingon but but it's more than
that okay so those are artificial those
are created in the novels in fiction you
know in science science fiction in
particular but however they are other
there are many other artificial
languages and for several purposes one
of the reason people create artificial
language is that they for example in
most like natural languages for example
English English French Chinese Japanese
you know Korean German they are
extremely complex you have so many
exceptions and idioms I mean it's not
regular like if you have ever tried to
learn a foreign language you know a
language that's not your first language
you will notice your York you'll keep
asking why do they do it this way you
know there's so many exceptions like
thousands ten thousands like you know
the for example Chinese the whole
language is exceptions like there's no
you know regularity so so that there's
so that is one reason people create
artificial languages or construct
constructed languages so one of the
reason is that they create a language so
that is extremely regular so that it's
extremely easy to learn you know and
that's one reason the best example of
this type is
does anyone know
hi guys hi Danielle like oh hi break the
loop and hi Danielle hi Daniel by the
way I think you wrote to me several
emails I responded to one but you said
you didn't receive it but anyways then
so let me go back to the languages yeah
so exactly so this so so one of the
reason to create an artificial language
is to so that it is simpler in regular
it's easy to learn and most and many of
them they hope they hope it to become a
lingua franca meaning you know the
universal language so it so for example
in America you know Americans German
Europe Chinese African or Middle East
they all can use this simple language as
a international language you know you
have a vision of world unity so the most
the most famous one for that purpose is
Esperanto yeah that's the one let me
type it ok and you know the other
official languages they have many
interesting characteristics if you study
linguistics let me magnify magnify
magnify actually among or why is it so
so so among or artificial languages
Esperanto is probably the most popular
okay Amin or they are like tens tens of
other visual languages so so you can
read about it here it's it's Esperanto
is the most widely spoken constructed
international auxiliary language they
changed the terms these days so you know
it wasn't it just a constructed language
so anyway Esperanto is is one of them so
it's it's very regular and it it's
originally it's intended to be you know
one language
every for every one for you know for the
international you know communication but
typically they never catch on you know
just for many reasons they people just
don't want to learn other visual
language although it's extremely simple
I mean when you study when you learn
artificial language it's like ten or
five times simpler you know it takes ten
or five times less time to learn it so
that's about artificial language so so
what are the so okay so let's go back so
go to the my back my page solo Shuang is
another artificial language I have a
tutorial here I wrote I wrote this
tutorial like back in 2004 I was
learning English mom now what does snow
shebang okay Lauren is an artificial
language so what is what is it about
it's based on logic you know predicate
logic it's you know largest logic so
that the idea of this language the
primary idea is that it's of course
first of all it's very regular and
simple just like Esperanto but the the
highlight of lachemann is that it's
based on logic so that the idea is that
it allows you to express ideas in the
most logical way possible and also also
if you study linguistics you know among
in linguistics there's the idea that you
know maybe your language controls what
is possible in your thoughts you know
your language at least influence your
thoughts
that's very famous you know proposition
called supper wolf theorem something
like that let's find it let's search for
it
hypotheses
there it is okay now these days it's
called I guess it's called linguistic
relativity yes sapir-whorf hypothesis
okay basically it says it's it says that
there's a strong form and weak form the
strong form form says you know the
language what you can possibly think is
controlled by your language in the weak
form is that you know your language
whatever your language what language you
speak influences your thought so so you
know you can look into that
you know this interesting ties to
programming languages you see okay let
me finish talking about constructed
language first so so there are many
types right this you know and and the
purpose of brush money it's it's it's
based on logic and it it it also ties to
the saberwolf hypothesis because people
thought if you construct if you create a
language you know lodge bond that's
based on logic then you can you can
think the most possible you know all the
possible thoughts with this language you
know so that you know you can express it
and there's no ambiguity there is
everything is regular you know and it's
logical so there is that you know those
one tutorial you know you might you
might check out my tutorial it's just
well interesting I mean if you are
interested in linguistics you might
study it but as for practicality
it's basically 0 any of these even I
mean including Esperanto you know
however if you study law found for
example you will learn many aspects of
languages natural languages you can see
many aspect flaws or problems so what
does grammar means things
that you learned quite a few things okay
so constructed language language there
are many you know there are many of them
you can like you can if you could we
keep here you can click on constructed
language they all show there's a list of
them and Esperanto is the most popular
roschmann is based on logic
Najma is actually the branch of the
another language called Locke LAN ello
goe and G hello gl a and G Lachlan now
Lachlan is the first logical language
however because there's a copyright
fight among the community there for
large bang is branched off and basically
Lachlan kind of just died off be knock
you know because people the guy who
tried to make it proprietary you know so
it's kind of died off so so large bong
is more popular
so anyway construct a clan languages now
actually this is this interesting ties
to programming languages because in
programming languages
it's very is kind of funny you know in
programming languages you can see that
most people do not like regular syntax
it's quite funny so it's opposite from
you know natural languages human
languages so in computer languages what
language what language has simple syntax
for example Lisp Oh Mathematica or APL
or maybe you assembly if you count
assembly ok so anyway these these these
has very regular and you know almost
100% regular syntax so you don't have to
learn you know what is the syntax for
for loop what is the syntax for wire
loop what is the syntax for statement Oh
function definition is another syntax or
you have directives you know kind of
something called directives and you have
expressions okay expressions need same
semicolon at the end but not the
statements you know so you have all
these syntax OOP
you know
most of them are based on C so that's
why I say another video of C is the
granddaddy of everything that is wrong
Inc in in programming industry so anyway
so in computer languages you know they
are almost all of them at least the
popular industrial languages they all
have syntax OOP I mean there are syntax
there is no one principle basically yeah
there is no one principle or grammar or
you know systematic grammar that that
creates them B so so where does the
syntax grammar come from it just came
from happenstance you know just by habit
just you know you okay so you have seed
and C created you know you have CC
credits Perl seashell Java C first-first
c-sharp you know JavaScript and so on
you know that's why I say C is the
granddaddy of everything one that is in
a computing industry why do they do that
why do you go oh you see C syntax
because it's popular and why is C
popular because I'm the fastest you know
they don't care about where design you
know extensibility quality of you know
design quality of the scene you don't
they don't care any of that so just make
it extremely fast in and simplistic like
stupid it is simple so that's what
that's my opinion okay yeah I mean it's
a it is a opinion so see so anyway so
most languages we use industry is all
based on they don't have a simple syntax
it's it's case by case there's no
general rule to describe them however
there are some exceptions Lisp is one of
the exception this family okay so the
the interesting thing is that I mean
it's Q years I mean wouldn't it be great
if you have a you know so simple
language that you know you don't have to
learn each statement you know each
expression what's the
syntax is just the same thing you know
it wouldn't would that be great now
there's one thing I want to mention in
this many people don't like Lisp syntax
obviously because there's too many
nested parentheses you know if you ask
these people they say oh I don't see it
you know you just get used to actually
it is a good criticism actually too many
nested parentheses is a problem it is
actually a problem because when you have
too many nested parentheses you cannot
count you know you can on the other hand
if you look at C code or you know Java
JavaScript because they are so different
you know in each place you can you can
immediately determine you know which is
what you know which part is what now
however this is important however it is
not necessary that a hundred percent
systematic regular syntax will require
you know you know we are we will become
a certain uniform look like Lisp you
know that's a problem so for example
Mathematica is an example it's extremely
simple regular syntax yet
the code is look you know the code looks
so different
okay let me show you a quick example
sorry info let's go to kassadin info
let's go to yeah sorry in for
Mathematica okay it's just go to sorry
info so magnify a bit I'm going to
program in blog on the Left panel you
can see on this and well it's just such
folks sorry anyone showed this quickly
because I got a lot of things to talk
about by the way keep the comments
coming our answer them
oh the stream turns off for a second
from time to time is that
the stream turns off for a second from
time to time
hmm that is a problem
maybe because okay maybe this way it
won't let's try it that way for a while
okay I think I know why
maybe it's because this oh yeah it's
because this adblock that's creating
that thing I think you know Google the
extreme evil empire you know it does it
does it do everything it can to well
anyway so mathematical vs. this syntax
anyway so there is Mathematica well I
want to show you let's just go here okay
so okay so here this page I have a whole
bunch of Mathematica example you can see
woof M language Mathematica and that's
the logo for Mathematica version two in
1990s so you see this is the Mathematica
notebook a notebook is basically the IDE
of Mathematica but you don't I mean you
can actually do it in Emacs there used
to be well anyway let's go there so
anyway so what I'm saying is that
Mathematica well I talked about this
subject in another video Mathematica
syntax so just take my word for it it's
that it's extremely regular I mean it
does the syntax the grammar is
systematic regular yet yet it has a
variable forms that you don't you know
you don't you don't see you know just a
bunch of nested parentheses you don't I
mean that so when you look at
Mathematica code it's not just like
uniform you know incomprehensible you
know formality like everything is just
nested
it's not like that but however if you
want to you can actually write your code
in purely nested brackets if you want
actually I have an example here
somewhere here for example it's kind of
of an image so in this screen you see
three forms of mathematical let me
magnify three forms but they are
syntactically equivalent meaning that
you can press a key and one becomes the
other so the pure 100% nested form is
the last one
full form you can see it's you know
everything is just function name square
bracket that's it you know and inside
that you can function any square bracket
and so on but however in general most
people write Mathematica in the first
form here you can see it has lots of
syntactic equivalence so let me get back
to the my topic so what I'm saying is
that so most programming languages their
syntax is just a syntax loop however few
people I mean including aidid hackers I
mean usually they are idiots they don't
and you know nobody ever you know think
about or tell you you know say you know
hey why don't we you know shouldn't we
have a regular syntax so that you know
so that that idea it simply is just not
popular for some reason actually why why
is that idea never you know come up I
don't know I haven't thought about that
but anyway so so I have an article yeah
I want to show you my articles so syntax
OOP there it is
syntax OOP so you go to the syntax root
page and so I have actually several
articles describing the situation formal
definition of systematic grandma that's
what I'm talking about so I'm here I'm
trying to give a formal definition and
okay this article is what I'm trying
talking about
unconstructive unconstructed languages
computer languages and their grammar
complexity you know so it's interesting
that for natural human to human
languages you know people create
artificial languages because you know
obviously it's so difficult to learn
your language because all the you know
exceptions however in computer languages
you know it seems like people do not you
know raise the idea of a simple you know
regular language so that's interesting
so I was going I was talking about
constructing languages and let's get
back to the previous parenthesis
parenthesis of speaking I was actually
talking about what I was talking about
today which is I mean the topic of today
is supposed to be so if you go to woody
blog saw talk show I kind of wrote some
some topic like index of things I might
talk about today most of them is about
YouTube actually the incredible the in
credibility of YouTube the stuff going
on YouTube including like internet
stupid internet things including society
this one is obedient median 100 medium
PDM air ok
so many interesting things this guy you
know remember this kind of pace I have
in my garage or Lamborghini you know you
wanna be like me that key is knowledge
you know and you know this is quite a
story I'm gonna you know I might get
into today I don't know and and the
story of fat francis you may or may not
know because the thing happening on the
Internet is that on YouTube in
particular is that you know they are
like billions of meat videos ok it's
like this you know I used to go to the
library physical library in the 1990s
every day in the almost every day so I
go to library
several libraries local like libraries
you know I'm almost all familiar with
him like I go there because I go there
every day I go there you know sit there
for a few hours I looked you know every
aisle every bookshelf I kind of have
looked you know I know what you know
what kind of books are here so once you
visit library for you know a few years
you kind of get bored because you felt
like you know I know every every
everywhere I know I know what the books
they are you know you kind of get bored
until one day you know maybe you have
some subject you know let's say magic
you know magic tricks there are a lot of
books about magic you know they tell you
okay for example magic history what kind
of magics are there magic the tricks
exposed you know for example there are
many books so until you actually have
something in mind so then you you know
study you go find the books and it's
like oh my god I'd never know these
books existed so you got you know you
know so many books you want to read so
it's like that Internet is like that you
know on internet they are you know all
humanity is basically more than all
humanity's information on the internet
but every day you kind of get bored you
know because you just maybe visit this
side or that side of 4chan or you know
you get bored like you don't know where
to look like you don't even maybe not
interested because maybe you go to
hacker news maybe you go to slash start
maybe you could read it but you still
get bored you know even though they are
like thousands of different topics and
subjects but until like one day you know
you you needed to like know something or
you found a game of community or program
a community or keyboard you know
economic Kibo community it opens the
door you know so it's like that so
internet is like that so you tube is
like that YouTube there's just you know
billions of videos like you know until
then you rent into this guy now this guy
his name is fat Francis what in what a
incredible story I mean he said you
tube star okay now he's a millionaire
you know but however he started more
than 10 years ago he's about to die you
know he like someone fat like him you
know he's just he got nothing to any you
know he's about to die so so so you
might you know check check up his story
fat francis incredible he's very abused
by his parents by his mom I mean
physically like violence you know he
could could have he probably have been
harmed physically or could he you know
he could have been killed so you know he
has you know and but now he's a YouTube
star then he got a wife you know some
some girl just married him and stuff
there's him Anita
so anyway so if you have time you know
you can you can read my page or go to
his YouTube channel he's his nickname is
also known as Francis or boogie2988
boogie2988 so incredible story and so
that's one of the story I was going to
ok so it's back up one step so I was
going to do some Emacs stuff I'm going
to create a unicode page let me show you
unicode page that's that's another topic
okay I'm 20 minutes I've been talking
for 30 minutes now so if you go look
sorry that info keyboard programming
okay scroll down unicode now that's
that's another rich topic you know this
you can you know the Unicode stuff in
Unicode that the it contains all the
words languages you know the written
language that's that's a you know great
topic you can study Unicode stuff for 10
years so recently I did
I did a Japanese page which is old news
you know Japanese anyway so what I want
to say is that let me show you just some
interesting things
hi rope guys the Egyptian I have a great
wife that's very interesting and you
know what's more what's interesting
about how they have released and it
turns out Microsoft since censored these
these three characters because if you
are using Microsoft Windows then these
three characters does not show okay so
this Egyptian hieroglyph in this linear
be linear be is a ancient script that so
there is linear a and this linear be
linear a is never deciphered to this day
never understood but linear b has been
deciphered so his ministry so anyway i
was going to talk about that so let's
get back to you know so I mean so these
things are linguistic or things and and
Cunha foam is also very interesting why
is it wait something wrong here it's
it's supposed to
oops hang on a second
okay so it's go to
yeah Unicode cuneiform
wait for some strange reason it's what
the I don't know what's going on
there I don't think it was anyway so
Cunha foam is another interesting Asian
script so anyway let's go back to let's
go back to let's see what what we're
gonna talk about for the rest of these
saw talk show so I was gonna do some
Unicode pages and talk about it I guess
and then we gonna talk about okay story
of fat francis we already talked about
that and I was going to talk about some
videos on the YouTube having amazing
videos this guy this guy and they are
connected because he interviewed the fat
francis guys but anyway let's let me
look at the comments and see what
direction we gonna go so which
unofficial language have I learned I
learned lachemann and that's it I
learned you know basically I know you
know lachemann is pretty simple I mean
all artificial languages are very simple
so I I learned some logic ah and I have
a tutorial there's so many pages oh it's
not the one page any anymore talk show
okay so yeah anyway I've showed that
before I learned some lotion on hand and
that's it
you can see your preview screen goes
black for a second and come back I'm not
sure what preview screen
oh how expensive in Internet Wow income
so I'm in California I mean San
Francisco area it's about like $60 a
month where are you where are you at
going deck so next question these
functions have stupid names Calcutta
said queue and so on if you don't like
Kai and cut the right first and rest
what changes is the syntax what do you
mean what changes is the syntax yeah at
least this has Cayenne cutter because
well because it has to do with the cons
business yeah
so Kai is like the so how'd it became
car it's I forgot I don't I don't
remember hi good morning Diane Diane
Bridger bridge bridge bridge bridge oh
good morning Mike good morning splendid
your internet cost $5
really
pay attention to logic ignore syntax
different languages have the same logic
that's not true that's not true at all
so five dollars is that in Morocco if I
remember correctly okay I'm gonna I'm
going to show you guys my dinner my
lunch show my dinner whatever it is this
is today's dinner I live a good life now
this is some kind of Jack manga real
what would have whatever they call it
cheese cheese and this is garlic
this is chopstick and so one piece of
garlic that's delicious and this is ham
and this is how I eat bread so I need to
put it together and wait yeah so that's
him so I just went with my roommate and
about that so that's going to be my
let's see is my lunch or breakfast or
dinner so right now it's 11:42 p.m. so
it's close to midnight but this is going
to be my well I guess you can call it
lunch and I'm gonna drink this this is
almond milk or something like that and
then dairy beverage what is made of
almond milk I'm not sure what the
it is but my roommate bought it and it
seems he doesn't like it so I'm gonna
like it I eat everything anything is it
edible if it is is good for me
so let's see okay so my video is like
blocking out every few seconds you
alright I don't know why it's very
annoying
here's to good health and live a
thousand years I need to get the video
fixed why is it uh okay let me refresh
maybe that's what
Oh Rocha okay so Rocha
so okay so elsewhere it's much cheaper
than yeah I heard that US Internet is
kind of screwed up because of
regulations you know
no it's not true I mean it's okay it's
not true to say our languages are based
on logic it's actually far from the
truth if you I mean you need to study
well I don't well maybe you'd know some
I mean maybe you have studied logic but
basically you have to study proof
systems proofs theory foundation of math
to know about those subject it's not
true at all that languages are all you
know alike semantics see semantically
actually they are far from alike they
are you know there's a functional you
know most functional programming
languages their basis is lambda calculus
okay and and most other languages they
they have I mean in many of them they
don't have a basis I mean they just then
but later on people create a name kind
of you know and say this is you know the
basis of imperative languages so
imperative languages I mean for example
what that means see see first first Perl
and Java JavaScript you know that that
means so what does imperative or
imperative programming means it means
the so yeah in terms of bases you know
so what is a computer science basis for
impair imperative programming you could
say it is based on what's the word state
yeah state machine yeah but that's you
know but the thing is just remember that
people I mean there is state machine
okay it's not like okay you know people
want to create a primary language okay
but there's a state machine which is
kind of mathematical idea then they base
their language on state machine it's not
like that it but but rather you know
they just created languages see out me
almost it's more almost like out of the
blue there is no mathematic
foundational basis about it you know
they just you just you know you have you
begin with program you know electronics
you know resistors and stuff and they
you start like that there's no shape you
just created people just created then
you have CPU you have chips then you
have assembly the machine languages you
know first then you have assembly then
you have things like Fortran and so on
you know you know and well from punch
cards you know actually in the beginning
it's punch cards then it just evolved so
it's you know it's the programming
languages almost none of them is
actually from a math foundation math
bases so logic not none of them they
just like come into being
then afterwards people of people ascribe
them some kind of math foundation so
they say you know people say most most
functional programming languages are
based on lambda calculus you know that's
kind of a true in some way but it's not
it's not true in certain practical way I
mean you know the you know anyway so so
so yeah so then you're landlords
so you wrote me several are several
wrong messages you know I have I'd be
pried one a couple short reprise but
basically I'm saying that you know I
cannot reply to messages you know emails
you know I try to avoid email like I
cannot because I've been talking you
know I've been writing blogs for over 20
years so a lot of people know me you
know like thousands people know me and I
have interacted with many of them
hundreds of them over over the years but
I don't remember them I don't like I
cannot possibly remember people and also
people tends to use handlers pseudonyms
on different paths
you know platforms come and go you know
you have Twitter you have YouTube you
have China has china has several you
know different country have you know
several you know there's Facebook there
was Google+ there was Google oh could
there was you know myspace you know they
come and go and this there's also a
one-hour chat remember those you know
AOH at Yahoo child so oh people you and
and also in games like Second Life they
you know they all use Hendra so you know
that's very you know they all use they
don't use real names so it's impasse and
also one person maybe this name on this
and on this network but another name on
different network so that that make it
more severe I mean I cannot possibly
remember even someone I may have talked
to several times so okay so what I'm
saying is that I kind of got distracted
so what am I saying so that's one thing
about names you know the other thing is
that people send me emails you know I
got emails from all the time from you
know over the world and I cannot remain
pain you know I cannot spend time to
respond to each you know but but you
know for the past you know almost 20
years every at least for the past ten
years every day I spent one hour or two
hours just to respond to people you know
on Twitter or here and there and some of
them are private and so so I would say
you know don't you know if possible you
know just just to public never private
because I don't want to spend time to
private because I have you know people
when you become I'm not a star right I'm
not a star but many stars but even for
me you have you know a lot of people
know you and they they kept it tends to
be the same quest
you know everyone she wants to ask you
the same question like what what is the
best keyboard you know what's your
opinion on this keyboard you know
suppose some hero just came out so if
it's private you add you have to I have
to answer the 100 times you know it may
seem rude you know people write to you
privately but you tell them no please
you know don't let me probably it seems
but that's that's fact of life you know
you so I used to on my website there
used to be a discussed like you can just
post comment and that is really great
because whatever you say especially on
programming stuff like I have you know
opinion some controversial programming
stuff right for example let's see in
this closest on this let's go to this
syntax roof constructed for example this
page you know it's an opinion so I said
I used two ever discuss comments so
people can reply the good thing about
that that's really good because if you
disagree or if you have some opinions
about my article you can post it there
and you can be long or short if you want
or long and if I do not have time to
reply you know I have like six thousand
HTML pages so when I have common people
are posting comments all the six
thousand HTML pages so I cannot you know
so when I don't have time to read to
answer your particular point of view or
criticism of my article or anything like
that if I don't have time but other
people who visit the page they see it
and they can reply they can say this is
a good you know opinion sorry is wrong
you know so they can do that and let all
the people see yeah you know so that's
that's a great thing but unfortunately
the discuss they start to
force ads commercial hats and their ads
is very badly read you know like how to
lose fat you know you don't know this
secret way to lose fat Oh and usually
with you know girls in skinny in biggie
in bikini or some something look like a
dick
you know like eat this fruit that you
know California are stolen you know
people you know major corporations don't
want you to know you know eat this fruit
and that looks like a dick or something
so they have you know like the gossip
trash magazine ads so disgust they force
that ads into your page unless you pay
something like ten dollars a month so I
ideally I removed it so that's the
situation so now I don't actually have a
way for if you want to reply you know
you can post it to reddit but also some
of the topic for example on Lisp all my
frames about many popular things for
example tech lock tech you know I have
been arguing with programmers you know
the least first or whatever the in the
community for over ten years you know
for over 20 years so I kind of have seen
I have seen all sort of replies I have
seen all sort of counter arguments so
and I'm getting old you know I'm getting
I'm fifty old and I live in poverty so
so at this point I don't have an urge
you know I don't feel like I you know I
don't have urged to even respond because
I've seen you know it's the same thing
repeated for ten years you know I've
seen it you know at the same same oh he
almost always same thing you know so so
that that is about you know how the
situation you know I so many of the
topic yeah I mean I've been there you
know but that does not necessarily mean
your idea it's no good or you know
occasionally it happens there's some
people
yeah there are a few people you know and
also I know some people who come and on
my blog
often there are few people they they are
really expert at what they are talking
about and where I have you know why when
I have an article on something or where
sometimes I have a question and they
answer it right exactly to what I want
you know my question exactly you know
it's so so there are some comments it's
not really good so I missed those so I'm
thinking you know I'm going to put the
discuss back or I'm thinking you know
pay them with $10 a month or something
like that yeah so back to
[Music]
so yeah so thank you for your emails
like I'm gonna go through them and you
know you are long very long emails so I
think that's it for today unless you
guys you guys have any other questions I
was going to talk about YouTube but okay
but then I began with constructed like
constructed languages and that kind of
took half an hour so let's go back to
YouTube yeah that's a very interesting
story this Lopez guy and yeah maybe
maybe we talked about that another day
let's see what else okay so I think
that's it for today thanks thank you
guys for watching if you like my videos
you know you can go to my patron and
it's obvious it's go to go to my blog
hacker coat so you know you have I have
patron Amazon PayPal Bitcoin you know to
do that and you know support my videos
so that's it for today so thank you for
coming I'll see you guys next time and
I'm going to eat my lunch
bye