good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of excel talk
show
today is 2021 april 16th
and today we are going to do javascript
live coding plus tutorials and
explanations good morning
neighbor neighbor from neighbor neighbor
from
australia i think and good morning
ripper from united states
okay so we are going to do javascript
live coding and
creating a bar chart in
svg scalable vector graphics that's
going to be fantastic okay
and uh i'm an emacs user i'm using stuff
like keys
so for those of you emacs users on the
pink window you can see all my command
calls
their command name and the keystroke
such as moving cursor forward by word
backward by word
right word uh moving closer to the right
by a chart
to the left or jump by paragraph and so
on
or switch window okay so
let's start coding okay so this is going
to be pure javascript
no libraries no npm no nothing
javascript svg
tutorial live coding i'm going to try to
do it fast
if you have questions comment about
javascript comments in the box
uh i try to get to answer uh answer it
okay
and donate don't forget paypal me or
patreon
okay thank you and uh you know by my
javascript tutorial it's a fantastic
javascript in depth truly in depth
okay okay so let's let's start to coding
let me tell you what i'm going to do
so i so you go to
uh okay so let's go to browser let's go
to let's go to bray browser so
xari keyboard let me show you
uh what are we going to do today so
saudi keyboard blog
so you see my keyboard block then you go
to
layout click on layout then scroll down
a little bit
then you can see this chart okay
and then turn on javascript turn it on
so you can see a bar chart okay
magnify okay then i can
select all delete start to
type here and you will see
a interactive chart
of the character frequency
as you type okay so you can
see the character frequency in english e
is the is the uh most frequent letter
so what we are going to do is uh
something similar to this instead of but
instead of the character frequency what
we are doing
is diagrams okay background frequency
let me show you a
static image to uh to illustrate
so we are going to do this okay we are
going to call javascript
uh but instead of a character frequency
we are going to do diagrams so
where is let me show you an illustration
okay so
here is a bi-gram chart so what is
diagram
it's basically a sequence of two letters
so you want to compute a sequence of two
letters
and you want to find their frequency of
occurrence
in english text okay so we are going to
generate
a chart like this dynamically we are
going to write a code for that
okay so this is actually the so that
that's what we are going to do this is
actually the second part of
of of the project last time we begin
uh hold on a second here so about a week
ago i did a live stream
greetings from from macedonia
greetings program
[Laughter]
okay so last time about a week ago we
did a live stream
of live coding of the diagram
calculator so it's done so let's see so
select
all you see here's the input and here's
the output so in this text
you have t y or current occurring one
times and t
y p or green one times okay let's let's
say a b
a b a b a b okay so you see a b
occurs four times b a occurs three times
now
now let's type something random
and the and he and she
and they and them so
you can see a n occurs six times
nd six times he occurs five times you
know h
e is one of the most frequent um
diagram in english so last time we did
this
here's a code let's see okay so here is
the code so you see
this page corresponds to this page and
you can see this line is a javascript
code
so let's open it so last time we did
this
and what is missing is the actual bar
chart we don't have the bar
chart that's what we need that's the
most the visual you know we are visual
animals human animals are visual animals
we need to see the chart
not the text text is the civilization
thing
okay so here's the javascript code and
shall we go through quickly an outline
so it's not
many so it's a 80 lines okay 80 lines of
code
uh okay so we i need to think about what
um
okay i'm i okay we need to code this um
so where do we begin okay so last time
we have
so we already have these so the result
of this is basically a frequency
map okay a table map or hash table
or map or a dictionary whatever you call
it so basically the key each key is a
diagram
and the value of that key is the number
of occurrence for that
diagram that is a result okay so today
today we are all we have to do is take a
a table of the diagram data
then just generate a bar chart out of it
okay
uh okay so that's what we took need to
do so but um
okay so let me think uh
we i i haven't you know i'm doing this
uh without preparation which is a good
thing
because you can see where i struggle
okay so
so now so the input is a um
okay the input is this data so let me
show you where okay so you can see
uh let's see do we have a console.log
update okay so update let's
let's remove last time we did some
coding
and let's remove the comments i mean the
okay so we have the diagram map
that is actually the output then we
sort it then we filter
why do we have to filter because we want
to remove anything
that involves a comma period
space or punctuation
so back to the code so we filter it out
then we convert it to json
then we insert it to the text content
okay
the text content is basically
yeah the show box basically we insert it
to the html page
so so what we are concerned the input
is just the diagram okay let's
okay should i go over the code from last
time
uh yeah i think i should because i need
to do it i need to go through it myself
just to be familiar okay so let's let's
look quickly so
javascript app uh
javascript app to draw a diagram of
given text first part of the problem
grab a given text and
compute the diagrams and print the you
print the count of them example
input text a b c d e diagram is a b
b c c d d e okay now that's the first
part of problem which we've done
uh and sample output okay let's see
sample output okay so let's copy that
so we are doing kind of documentation
pasted this so let's say sample
output okay
then the second part of the problem
given
a map object which is that of the
diagram
draw a bar chart by generating a svg
object yeah that's what we need to do
okay so but
uh let's look up i mean that let's get
familiar with the code here what's going
on with the code so hold on a second so
so uh okay so the html page
you see here is the html page for that
for for this uh background so you can
see
okay so actually let's see make a backup
okay so the
relevant part is okay okay
too much garbage here actually
okay hold on a second shrink
um yeah we we need to do this quickly
okay
let's just modify let's start to modify
let's remove the other irrelevant things
ads and the google trackers
delete delete
okay background calculator ah
shrink a little bit okay
so so here is the uh bike sorry
dd dad okay so here here is the
essential that's that's essentially
that's
uh remove the keyboard guy guide
okay here's the essential uh thing so
here's the html the whole thing
showing browser so we you get a clean
version
okay the the important thing here is the
text area that is the
this box and
for example many texts
here thth okay
refresh okay so now we got some kind of
uh
data okay the important thing is the
text area
then the spam uh id
show box okay show box is basically a
empty element here so that
our javascript will you can see
show box this line get element by id
show box
it will grab this element show box
then insert the final output there okay
so that is the html good
we are familiar now okay now to the code
okay it's not so
get the text area element uh then get
the showbox element
then okay let's see what we have string
two diagram
a string to write diagram given a input
string
return a map object where keys are the
diagrams and value is the
count okay that's uh that's that
function string two bigram now remember
that
we coded that last time next
sort map sort map
sort map sorts a map object and return a
array of entries
sorted by the values okay
uh return a array of entries sorted by
the
okay it returns the array of entries not
map okay sort map
now it is used yeah it okay then
okay sort map then
then we have some map filter
returns a new map where
the function so map filter takes a map
object
and a function so returns a filter where
the function returns true
return a new map where the function
returns true so
okay we need to filter the map because
we
need to remove any diagrams that
contains a punctuation
okay cassandra map filter then uh then
filter map
then filter map there's a documentation
error filter map takes a map
map object returns a map object with
keys that contains
char that's not english letter oh okay
so this filter map function is general
then we write a wrapper using the
submap filter so that it filters out
you see it basically
we only want keys that contains letters
remove any keys that contains
punctuation and so on so that is that
function
um filter map okay
okay okay i mean okay so
then we need to start to draw the svg
okay
yeah okay so we start to draw svg here
now
near the bottom it says add event
listener
on the object text area so that means
so this is a text area so that means at
we add
event listener to it on the event input
so that means whenever this whenever
you know there's a change in this box it
will call the function f of
f update okay uh
then let's see f update
oh oh okay f update is a different
function okay then
i close it okay yeah
so yeah f update grab text area
grab text in text area and insert it
into show box okay that
that is what it is okay okay so now we
have that
now let's think let's think about a
little bit we need to grab
let's say this is the data okay
so this is the data um
okay before we um okay so this is the
data we
we need to
am i doing am i good audio check video
check
good okay so
we need to so so so let's see
then we need to start to draw svg assume
you have 100
distinct charts how many possible
backgrounds are there
okay uh write the filter function to
okay what is this write the filter
function to a given map so that
background contains space or punctuation
should be removed
that's already done write a function
given a diagram map
return a map object where the value is
percentage instead of count okay we
still need to do that
uh
we we don't need that okay so we okay
let's begin let's
let's really start to code okay so
we have
oh my god what are we doing
so so so
let me think okay so we need to start to
draw svg
and the input is something like that
and where does the input came from the
input
came from string two diagrams okay
string two diagrams but however
it is not being filtered so we actually
so the
final input needs to be these
okay so f filter map
salt map background map
okay so so this is the actual
this is the actual final input of a
diagram data
okay so once you have a diagram data so
okay i need to begin i need to begin to
code uh
okay so let's so this is the
so first of all
create a svg tag okay
let's begin to code it
let's begin to code it uh wait
uh wait where is the
okay so here's the code that's so let's
go to
i need to refer to my uh svg
uh tutorial okay i need to go to my svg
tutorial so you just go to xrd
keyboard uh web dev uh
and shank shrink what's going young
shinxing what
so here's the svg tutorial let me let me
give you a
a walkthrough of svg okay svg basics
so here is how you draw this is how svg
looks like
so if you have this code in your html
page
where svg width and h
then you say a line x
x one equals to a number y one equals
equals to a number
they are coordinates and x2 and y2
equals to a number they it will draw a
line so this is how
basically how svg is done
and you have same thing you see here is
a full code
you if you copy and paste this in into a
file
you will see you know that
and to draw a rectangle you do similarly
so you use a rectangular
rect tag okay so this is
so svg is basically just just
xml okay it's just like html
but now the problem is that we need to
generate these tags
using javascript so uh so what you do is
you can
click on this scripting svg and it will
tell you how
and i'm going to uh walk you through it
okay so let's copy that javascript code
and let's go down
let's go down let's let's paste it here
okay so you can see the code here
uh so first of all
okay let's let let's let okay yeah okay
first of all create a s svg element that
okay
uh
okay create a svg element and let's
remove that remove that create a svg
element svg1 document
create element ns then this is what you
have to put then svg so that
is a svg tag okay now once you create a
svg tag
okay oh god this is
then we need to uh create bars
ah okay let's do it them one at a time
so this is a bar
uh rectangle
uh iect i need to
shrink
okay this uh there's so
many so much to do actually
yeah there's so much to do actually i
need to
uh
yeah i need to go back to the uh
to i need to go back to
let's see let's see talk show i need to
go back
to the frequency
plot so to have a look at the chart
so as a reference
and now we go to the background
character go to the code
so we need so okay we need to think
actually
um so we have a scvg tag then we have
rectangles inside it
uh so first of all
yeah first so so
so um
so the the height
of the bar should correspond to
a number okay we need to scale the
number to
to feel you know that will be the height
of the bar
and first of all also we need to know
how many bars we have we have to have
okay
we need to know how many bars we
gonna drill because you know once you
have a svg element you need to
you you need to have the divide them so
we
you find out how fat are the bars
to find out how the
how fat to draw each bar
okay so we need to know so that
corresponds to how many elements in the
biogram okay
then okay then let's write it out
the height of
the bar should
correspond to the frequency
of the diagram as
percentage okay
yeah then
okay uh then
okay let's do this uh let's let's
simplify let's do a dummy uh example
let's see
let's just say
this is dummy input okay let's simplify
this
let's say uh 30
okay let's um
oops
let's just say constant
dummy diagram input
okay so this is a sample input we start
with a simple
uh input
okay so constant
number of diagrams okay
wait the dummy input should be actually
is a
the dummy input should be a map object
yeah it is a map object so we need to
turn this into a map object okay we can
do that
new map okay this is how you
turn a array of arrays
into a map object okay
let me input the number of diagrams
that's just
number of elements in the map so how do
you how do you find the number of
elements in your map
you you go to
javascript object javascript in depth
object reference
map uh
okay there is a size okay yeah
map object dot size okay
is that uh yeah it's not a function it's
just a property okay
map object dot size
then
the height for each one okay so so first
of all before you do anything you need
to find the percentage
like for example what put you know at th
occurs 30 times
you need to find out what is that
as a percentage of the whole so okay so
we need to write a function
okay constant okay wait constant arrow
function
compute percentage okay
uh given a map
we need to return
given a background map objects return
a map object where the
values are percentage
instead of number of
occurrence okay
so okay so so first of all we need to
sum
sum all the values in the diagram okay
so okay so so
so so so so let's look at the how do we
do things with the map
okay for each reduce
uh let's see for each
okay there are so many you know there
are so many ways
i want to do functional programming but
let's
you know let's just push through by
whatever method we need to finish this
you know
live coding uh so let's just yeah let's
just use for each then
uh for each okay function
uh this function will be error function
so for each uh for
each
what does the function what does the
value key okay so
value key
uh f is passed three arguments value key
map object okay so
we don't need actually we don't need
array we don't need
the destructive assignment
destructive
no it's not called destructive
assignment it's called
argument destructure okay we don't need
that but anyway
so function value and key
okay so so actually
there are better ways okay values okay
so dot values returns the okay i need to
go faster
returns all the values
of a map okay
then then what you get is a
iterator okay uh once you get the
iterator i think you can do uh for each
uh four of loop okay
four of loop yeah yeah so for a loop
let's do this
okay vows okay
for each v in
values
you can use i i want to use a reduce
okay
go to object reference go to array go to
[Music]
uh reduce okay
yeah that's what we want uh
let's just say reduce
okay
we don't need initial value
so that's basically some total
okay
okay so here is the total then
then okay then then for each
result map equals to
new map okay then
then for each of
for each of the
for each of the diagram map
value and key
background map set
so set is how you let's go to
um map how do you set a map
set yeah
so here is how you set a map say the map
key value okay
key value key
then value will be
okay value will be object
value will be background map
get key
divided by total okay
okay actually you don't want to
you know you don't want to overwrite the
background map so let's
uh let's this should be result map
result map dot set
okay result map dot set for each
key in the background map the
the value should be background map get
the keys value divided by total okay
then return result map
pretty fine
okay let's check check our code
constant compute percentage is a
function let's add uh
let's add that so compute percentage is
a function
take a bigram map
first of all compute the total
backgroundmap.values.reduce
yes let's compute that's a sum then
result map equals to a new map then
then for each of the input map
result map key
set the key gets a new value yeah that's
that's
that that should be it okay now
we can cancel out print it and see
uh oh god
it's let's uh let's just use dummy okay
okay now we comment this out
we don't need that yet okay this should
work
okay prettify the code and actually
this is a typescript so i need to
compile the typescript typescript by the
way is just a javascript
uh but with type checking
added but otherwise it's
identical to javascript so it says error
duplicate identifier line 46
what duplicate identifier line 46
uh what
yeah we don't care about yeah
okay two let's do it again compile file
correct okay now let's try the code
let's see if it works
it should print in the console log okay
refresh okay
arrow type error diagram dot value start
reduce
is not a function oh okay
okay yeah so diagram.values it returns
a iterable but it's not an actual array
so in order to make it
array let me show you how to do that so
in order to
make it array we need to use the
spread of operator okay so like that
compile the file okay
refresh okay
type arrow mymap.entries.sort
is not a function what uh
start sort is not a function
my map
sort map so the map object and returns
the array of entries sorted by vars
mymath.entries.sort
so my map dot entries
okay so yeah you need um
again the same problem
let me show let me do it okay so
mymap.entries
that returns a iterable you need to turn
that
into a actual array otherwise you don't
have sort function
row 89 i think you need to multiply by
100 to calculate oh yeah you are right
yeah thank you so let's correct that
later
um my mapped out entries
so my map dot entries let's go let's go
check the map
entries what does it return map dot
entries return
a iterator also iterable for the map
each yield is a array of the form key
value okay so it returns a iterable
but not actual array
so yeah so that's why you need
uh you need the spread operator dot dot
dot okay
so comment this sound again
compile it
okay now back to back to this
refresh there it is
there it is fantastic now why is it not
console
uh log it's it's not printing a
percentage okay hold on a second what's
going on
uh so go down
so we did console.log right
oh okay so you need to let's see
console.log undefined you need to put
this
whenever a keystroke happens
so you need to put this in the okay
first of all
this function needs to move up
uh let's see where is the dummy input
so this function cut needs to
go up
paste it here okay
and let me remove the the
the curly braces that encloses the
whole file i do that
so that the variables are
confined within this script but it makes
the code
indented one level which is less easy to
read
so now let's pre-divide the code okay
now it's better
easier to read so we just smoothed
the compute percentage yeah
and also you divided by total
yeah but let's not multiply by 100 for
now because
that makes it more you know
we we want the actual you know the
decimal
like us uh
scaled version from zero to one instead
of
zero to one hundred okay so here is the
function compute percentage
right and
and we are calling it here
but delete that it should actually be
called
within the update okay
so let's put it here
let's paste it here okay
uh check one file what's going on why is
it not
okay good so there is probably some
issues with
deno formatting so function update
the console.log okay let's refresh let's
see what happened
see if no it's not updating
it is printing no it's not printing
anything
in console what's going on
if oh compile okay compile
refresh is it compiled
it's not working close the close the
file okay
close it refresh i mean
okay so f12
now let's ah
okay actually so it actually updated but
it says undefined
you see as i type you see that undefined
error just repeat
so it's undefined that's our problem
open the file so let's see what's going
on so
this compute
percentage is incorrect
why is it incorrect for each
oh yeah return result map should be
yeah cd it should be here
yep compile
back to browser magnify refresh
now it works yeah fantastic so you can
see
yeah th occurs 0.57
0.5 is 0.85
times over 1 that is that means 85
percent
then ht happens 5 yeah so this is
correct so this
compute percentage now is correct now
you see writing code is
so tedious you know imagine this is a
day job
how long i've been talking probably 40
minutes
52 minutes and
no bar chart yet oh my god
so compute percentage that is the um
so we got this okay so
so we got we got the compute percentage
hello is it crazy so we're doing
javascript
today um okay so what's next what
and hello bot uh what
so what so we got the percentage yeah
now we can start to draw svg
right yeah so create a svg element there
uh and
okay then
okay now we need to think so here is the
input
for each one of them
okay so let's write it down
for each element in a bi-gram map
such as
we need to loop through them
and for each
create a bar as a create
a svg rect element
okay yeah let's do that so
yep so
yeah so so so wait so so compute
percentage here is the
uh here is
actually we need to say update here so
cons console.log compute percentage yeah
uh
compute percentage of
filter map filter map returns a map
object okay so
too many parentheses
so background map then sort it
then filter it out then compute
percentage yeah
let's try again just make sure
it is correct okay yeah we
actually we forgot to compile
yeah diagram calculator cannot find
name car1 cir1 okay so here's the arrow
again
uh coming down compile
okay refresh
is it working yes
refresh something
in the water okay
okay so so now we need to yeah
so we need to for each element in a
diagram such as that we need to loop
through them
and for each create a svg rectangular
element that's right
so okay so
copy that
actually yeah
so remove the console log so here is our
diagram
data x okay
so here's the data data x
let's just say good diagram
data good diagram data so good diagram
data
dot for each it's a map
right so we do for each map has a for
each method
then we need a arrow function
and the value
key is the argument
for each let's see
value key yeah so
given a good diagram data we go through
them for each
and then we do a you know then we give a
function
then what's the function going to do the
function is going to
uh the function is going to
to to create
a rectangle object which is here
okay copy it put it here
so the function is uh
a bar a rectangle object of svg
there then
set the attribute basically we want to
set the coordinates
the coordinate of the
rectangle so basically it looks like
that let's copy it okay
let's put it here so for reference
so we need to create something like that
so x and y so attribute x
okay the coordinate for x
coordinate not for y we don't know i
you know i don't know what's the value
yet
uh then you need the width and height
okay
so okay
okay so width
height okay uh then style okay let's
just add style
oops style
ah okay so let's just copy the style
there okay
okay so this this part is creating
a single bar in the bar chart
now there are more things we need to
figure out
because what is the coordinate
coordinate for x and what is the
coordinate
for y we don't know uh
okay so this is getting more tedious
uh first of all what is the width uh we
need to find out
what's the width of a bar and what's the
height of the of the bar so so first of
all what is the width
the width is going to be
you know we we want pixels
uh okay so we want to pick we we want
pixels
so so first of all you have to know what
is the width of
your entire svg graphics
uh i don't know but let's just set it
myself okay let's just
set it svg1
set attribute
width i believe so let's go to
viewport viewport this is how you
set the width and height of a
svg here is an example
uh so width equals to
900 okay
900 pixels wide that's our svg
box and height let's say 600
okay okay
yeah okay
yeah so so now we know the
okay we need to define
actually better it's better to define it
so that as we define them as parameters
so we can change it later
okay so wait
okay so here we have the width and
height for our svg box
now now we need to find out what's the
width and height for each bar
okay and
okay
so bar width equals to
svg width
divided by
divided by the number of bars
so the number of bars will be
this okay
size that right is that right
map object size
yeah it's a property not function
so bar width will be equals to
the width of svg box divided by
number of bars
number of bars times a
you know 0.9 so that
so that each bar doesn't you know touch
the other bar okay so that's the bar
width assume that's right
you know we we probably need to fix it
then bar
height bar height
will be dynamic
bar height will be dynamic because it
will depend on each bar
so we go back to the for each
uh so bar height will be
uh yeah
bar height will be basically the
percentage
basically the value okay
yeah by height will be just v okay so
right so bar height will be svg
height times
the value of the um
predefined uh the the value of the
of the diagram okay so let's copy that
each
this they will be here
inside okay so
uh so our code is now in a mess
so we need to uh maybe we should tidy up
right now so
clarify you know what's going on here
so we have a dummy input
number of diagrams number of diagrams
okay so here is just number of diagrams
number of diagrams number of diagrams we
don't
we need um
number of diagrams cut we should put it
down here somewhere
put it here okay so
so first of all let me input then
svg width and svg height
create a svg element then
then
so then okay let me let me just
just put it here okay
so create a sg element then for each
element
in a diagram map we need to loop through
them
and for each create a svg rectangle
element
and attach it to the svg box
okay so
so let's change that to svg
box so it's easier to read to understand
okay so if
svg box so for each diagram we need to
attach it
to we need to create a rectangle element
and attach to this so that
so that you know like xml elements they
are inside
so you know so okay so
um okay so the good diagram data
is the our data and the width of the bar
okay so we need to uh how many bars we
gonna draw to find out how
fat to draw each bar the height of the
bar should correspond to the frequency
of the biograms percentage that's right
so number of diagrams is that
and the width of the each
bar is that
okay then then then for each
diagram data we compute the bar
height which is svg high times v
then create a bar now okay
here we create a rectangle element of
svg to represent the bar
but what is the coordinate okay that's
another
ah it's what a pen what a pain in the
ass
so you see what we are doing we are
let me show you okay so so you see we
have a bar chart
we that's what we want to draw each bar
you know each bar is a svg rect element
and one of the attribute is the
coordinate
x and y where it appears in you know in
the in the canvas
so x will be you know
incremental like increase increase for
each bar and the y will be
always the same be the bottom basically
the bottom of the
svg okay so the y element
is going to be constant
now svg coordinator you know the upper
left
is zero so y goes from top to down
which is uh different from
mathematics uh in general computer
graphics the coordinate
coordinate y goes from top to down so
anyway so the value of y for each bar
the coordinate is a constant and that
value should be
svg height basically okay so let's
let's go here let's there there we have
it
now the value for each x
will be different we we have to do some
kind of
uh for loop increment so much
pain so much pain in creating this
and we spent already what
an hour already so x will increase
um so what
so so okay so
so now we need to find out we need a
increment
to know which element you know the index
of the element like one two three four
five
so that we can time that by a value
to find the coordinate where we want to
draw it
okay so how do you do that well
we are using uh four each let's see
the for each method has do they have a
index
a value key map objects
no no
[Laughter]
jesus you know so you cannot do it with
four each
because we need
we we need the value and the key but we
need
also need an index so we can like
increase it
yeah so we cannot use for each
so the easier way to do it is
probably to convert the map into
a array yeah we convert the map
into a ray so so let's go back to
array javascript object reference
array then use the for
each here
you know in if you use array
then the for each the function will get
a argument that's the index of the
current index
okay so okay so let's convert this
entries okay so convert this map to
array
then i mean convert
it to a iterable then use the
dot dot dot spread operator
to convert it into an actual array
so that we actually have the for each
method for that array
uh what a pin what a pain javascript
is you know and what pain you know what
a pain it is
with these iterables crap
okay am i doing good how many people are
watching
uh this becomes a grueling
exercise night people watching
okay so okay so anyway so
we well we have to do it so we convert
it to
an array so that we have for each
element
then the function for the array is
actually different from
the map object yeah idiocy
so the function you know will actually
take
current element current index and array
okay so
the function will take three arguments
current element
so let's use argument destructure
okay now what does for each return is it
key value or value key yeah
so let's go back to map
entry key value you see if you do for
each
it's value key but if you use entries
key value so the javascript is one of
the circuits
language so any anyway so map.entries
it returns a key value pair not value
key okay so key value
key value okay then
then then for the array
then for the javascript array for each
you have the current element okay that's
the first element
key value then current index okay so
uh this will be index let's say i i
k vb i like to double them up so that
so so we have referential transparency
we have unique identifier through our
code
hopefully you know something like that
anyway so
current index uh yeah okay so so i
i is index so
yeah that's that's what we have okay so
this v
will be v and it's not to be
it's not be too weird okay because
people don't understand what we're doing
what i'm doing so okay value v is value
uh so now we have now we are able to
compute the coordinate for each bar
okay so the i increases so basically
this will be
i times
the width of the rectangle okay
so let's fix this bar width
so width will be bar width okay here
okay so so the coordinate
of x will be i
it will be um
i times spa with
times point
yeah well okay so actually
it will be i times spot width okay
then hey we got a new comment greetings
from turkey i just bought my first
ergonomic keyboard
fantastic okay so
the corner nut for each bar will be
the x will be i times bar width is that
right
so let's say the seventh diagram seven
times
yeah kind of yeah okay that's right the
height will be svg
height yeah okay
let's see what what is the orientation
of the
svg rectangle
oh it actually draws from top to bottom
damn it it draws from top to bottom
so let's say the y is zero then
we have to do we have to do kind of
inversion
geometry to get it right but anyway
let's say zero
so now the bar chart will be from top to
bottom instead of bottom to top
okay so the width will be about width
what what what about the height
okay the height will be uh bar height
okay we computed here
actually so and we compute it here
okay here's of our height then feel
green okay we don't care about that
stroke with
uh stroke with two okay
then you need to now once you create a
created
a a bar element you need to attach
it to the svg element otherwise it
doesn't work so
ba dot uh actually svg
box
dot append child okay
i believe that's what it is a
child let's go back let's go to let's
see
a scripting svg
yeah a pen child so
okay let's try to compile the program
wait not yet
so
so we need to actually dummy input so we
need to
copy all these
this we don't need the dummy input
svg we need to put the whole thing
into a function actually
yeah let's let's let's uh let's just say
draw svg okay
function okay constant arrow function
draw svg
then cut cut cut cut cut cut cut
cut cut cut okay
then put it inside here
pretty fine okay let's go back
so the draw svg
draws inserts the
svg element into
into a area in the html
into yeah where did it go
into somewhere here okay so a pen child
okay
into display okay into um
okay let's let's create a new element
okay so this is gonna be called svg
display
area okay copy that id
open that go to the top then we
create a new constant
this will be called svg display area
then get document by element by id
svg display area so we have that element
then go to the bottom so once we draw
the svg
we need to
svg display area dot append child
append child append the svg box
okay uh in fact
yeah is that right
yeah okay anyway we are probably we are
not doing something efficient right now
but uh but whatever so
so draw svg
okay so draw svg will take a
argument let's call it good diagram data
okay let's review the code uh because
otherwise it's gonna
arrow out so dummy input we probably
don't need it
yeah we we yeah we probably don't need
this
okay it's coming up
so where is dummy input so actually
good diagram data
okay cut this out
comment it out so it takes a bigram data
so it takes a
map map object
and draw and create svg
bar chart and
insert the svg element into
into into this display area element
okay
so it begin by width create a
uh you know width and height then create
a svg box
then insert it into the
display um
into the display area
a pen child right that's that's right
then
then compute the number of diagrams
that's right
then bar width that's right
then for each
then then create the bars
okay so for each
we do that constant by height
then bar x equals to that then
then blah blah blah x y with
height style a paint child that's right
so this is the example okay so this is
the example
okay so i think that's it let's we can
try it okay
compile javascript it's probably errors
i know it
okay uh error 106 32
error argument of type number is not
assignable to parameter of string okay
this is a common type script error so
all you have to do is two string
okay two string okay
yeah let's
compile it again
again you need two string
so line 127
this is a very annoying type script
tediousness to string
to string because you have a number here
but when you set attribute it requires
you know the argument should be string
but if you do it in javascript there's
no error because
the browser will automatically convert
so anyway
so let's compile again
so it says error an identifier for
keyword cannot immediately follow a
numeric
literal line 128
oh okay so wait uh zero two string
idiotic javascript
so you know so what you have to do is
you add the parenthesis
i think that'll work
compile again
okay error 126
132 oh yeah
we got element we
this should be bar okay so append child
append the bar to svg box okay
compile again yay compiled
now let's shall we try it refresh
and see what happens refresh
nothing happened nothing nothing
what's going on f12 to turn on
what is going on why is why is there no
um let's go to inspector
let's see where we didn't did we create
the svg element
no because if we did it should have been
inserted there oh yeah obviously because
because we did not call this function
draw svg
in the in our code for update you see
we are actually updating you know we
need to put the draw svg
into the update so pretty good
so what's the comment a pen pen yeah
that thank you yeah
so i found that error so almost you know
we are doing this without much
tryout and error you know actually you
know that that's a style of coding i
prefer
you know you just um okay so we need to
call draw svg into the
update function so we have it here
we copy that part so basically we want
to
yeah draw svg you know draw svg first of
all the
background map which is the crude
diagram data which includes punctuation
then we want to sort them then we want
to filter them actually we should filter
then sort that would be better because
once you filter you'll be less
uh item to work with okay let's let's
let's fix
okay uh filter okay
you filter it
then you
okay then you sort it
okay so so
so background map it's a map object
you filter it it returns a map map
object
then you sort it okay
actually we have a problem with sort
because our sort returns a
array not map
okay but but when you feed it to
[Music]
i think javascript automatically
converts array to
uh to object
yeah let's just be safe let's use the
old code forget about efficiency
okay so then we compute a percentage
right
then we feed it to draw svg right
yeah so i think that's that's
uh that's it and yeah so yeah
okay let's hope everything is good
compile
yes sir refresh yes sir
[Laughter]
actually we can call it a day
we can oh oh oh okay so every time
you type
you know it's just going to draw a new
svg that's what happens
yeah so you see you see the th is like
increasing
increasing increasing fantastic we
you know okay let's do some fixing
maybe 10 or 15 minutes and that that's
it uh
you know you know we it takes a while
one hour and you know we've been coding
for 90
90 minutes so so what
in order to fix this is that before
before you generate svg
you want to remove whatever remove the
child okay so you can you know you draw
a new svg
so so we need to fix the draw svg
function
now draw svg function should be above
the update code
so let's uh i don't know why it even
works
because usually when you define a
function using arrow function
you know these you know the syntax of
arrow function
it does not you have to define it before
uh before you use it you so i don't know
why
is it actually working here because we
defined it at the bottom so anyway let's
move it up so
let's move this update down okay
so let's move this update down yeah so
wait what what happened
cut the update code
move to the bottom here paste it here
okay
compile okay
now in the draw code we need to
remove the svg okay so before we do
anything
um
yeah so here display area
we can say uh inner html okay
inner html equals to empty that will
work
now there are many ways to delete all
children of a
element uh and
i researched over that to see which one
is the most
proper and fastest uh
and so i have article here somewhere uh
wait it's
it's part of dome so let's try
search for children okay
get element okay basic dom methods
element attribute get nod
navigate nodes create new nodes
insert remove replace nodes there it is
uh wait uh
replace child okay you can actually do
replace
child apparent child change
elements text content okay change
elements text content
ah let's let's just say you know html
okay that's the easiest
so before we do anything we remove the
in
html then we append the svg box
into it okay compile
go back go to the top
refresh now
type and see fantastic
and now now it is
working select or delete
so that we start
fresh again now there
is a problem that the
bars do not have gaps
in between them okay
so anyway now what we need to do is we
need to add
labels uh you see these spots you know
you need
to have labels like you know like
here uh and also you
need to invert the box not from top down
but
you know from bottom up but okay that's
more work you know that's you know 20
minutes 30 minutes so you know there's a
lot of cleanup we need to do
so let's call it a day for for this
video thank you guys for watching
uh if you guys like my you know you like
my
tutorial if you like my style go
buy okay go back saw javascript in depth
okay thank you very much oh donate me
or patreon me uh okay
so now so yeah so we basically done
we're gonna close down
uh maybe we're gonna do some cleanup of
the code
just let's go over what we've done today
clean up the code so
so our goal was to create a program
our goal is to write a program
that generate that
computes diagrams in
in english and
draw a svg bar chart for
it okay so we
basically have the prototype you know
prototype to prove
that our idea works
okay that's the end let me show you my
face instead of my let's have some human
touch
you know some human touch so we finished
fantastic and so we have a prototype and
we know
we have a outline of how to
how to do it so
so you can so here is the code
so last in my last video we we
actually wrote the code to compute the
statistics
to find all the diagrams that took one
hour
and today to draw the actual ssvg
takes you know one and a half hours
uh you know last time we wrote this
function string two diagram
which computes the diagram of a given
giant string of you know then we wrote
sort map then we wrote
map filter to filter out diagrams that
contain spatial punctuation
then we wrote then today
we wrote compute percentage you know
given a
diagram map object we want to
instead of number of occurrences we want
to change that into
uh percentage
you know so which is you know the value
divided by total
okay we wrote that today then the big
thing today we wrote is the draw svg
so this you know it's actually 10 lines
of code
if you remove the comments yeah let's
remove the comments okay
it's just 10 lines of code but you know
that's
coding that coding is usually tedious
you know anyway anyway so so this is uh
this
thing is what we did today 10 lines of
code to
for each diagram element we want to
create
a rectangle svg element
and you know it's tedious to find the
coordinate for the rectangle
where to place it and also how wide or
how
high the rectangles are so that's our
code
then finally we um
you know we have this function update
and this update is the is responsible
for
actually adding you know this
information
in the bar chart as you type you know
so you know it just caused the function
we wrote
before to do the job so we don't need
the console log
uh you know we don't we don't need that
you need a
let's remove it okay so it's just like
three line
five five you know three lines of code
this update
then we have the event listener that
means whenever user types
it cause the update function to refresh
the graphics
okay thank you guys for watching
fantastic thank you bye
you