good morning good morning welcome to
another episode of exotic show and today
we are going to talk about this wondrous
subject of geometric inversion so let's
go to curves my plane curves website a
visual dictionary of special plane
curves now this is a project of
geometric inversion let's go let's see
it's a topic here geometric inversion
and I'm going to show you how this image
this beautiful image is made this is
this is a geometric inversion of a grid
of a rectangular grid you know just like
vertical lines and horizontal rows on
two lines after the transformation of
the geometric inversion then you get
this picture and this topic is related
to it's related to quite lots of quite a
lot of things in mathematics in complex
inversion in Raymond sphere in the
complex function one over Z which is
inversion
it's called inversion and Mobius
transformation and ya and n
stereographic projection it's all tied
together and geometric inversion is kind
of you can it's actually the the heart
that ties them together yeah yes it's
one of the fundamental part of it let's
see if I'm actually alive because
sometimes I make mistakes
I'm live good so if you are new here say
hi this is my you know saw Tokyo and
what I'm going to talk about and the
quality of my talk depends on your
feedback your comments your opinions
okay
just put it here
so this topic you know avocado rose has
been asking me to do so I'm gonna we
haven't done a math talk for a while
so we're gonna do it and by the way of a
month ago or so we did a talk on complex
numbers the origin of complex numbers
and you know so you might be interested
in you know watching that video the
arrangement of complex numbers numbers
it's not what you think you know what
you learned in school is wrong you know
in school they teach you how complex
numbers is invented so that you have the
solution to x squared equals to negative
one
you know no that's not true but anyway
so let's talk about geometric inversion
but I want people to come on
so how many people are watching three
people great so we can begin and today
let's try to use I got this pain tablet
so let's try to make use of that use of
it you know this is a huge pain tablet
you know with this I can write all right
let's start and let's see if we can
start to lecture on mathematics and
geometry
oh that it's the eternal fudge it
eternal subject so let's see so let's go
to so geometric inversion let me
actually let me write out the cut the
topics and also I need to update this so
you know so let's see thought out show
create a new page here okay
one second let me create a new page talk
section and there it is
shut up show and copy that switch paste
and the topic is going to be about we're
gonna talk about geometric inversion and
let me write I mean writing out the
topic so we I don't forget you know
we're gonna cover these topics I'm gonna
teach you in yes and stitch you about
this these topics geometric inversion
it's beautiful you see even from the art
perspective you know just for decoration
for example if you have a house you know
you eventually you are going to have a
house maybe
and you're gonna decorate your windows
you can decorate your windows like that
like a stained glass window or your
garden you know or your tiles you know a
bath bathroom floors you know and that's
going to be spectacular so I'm gonna you
know show you what those means so and
Steve and sto ste ste are your graphics
tier stereographic projection and
Raymond sphere
complex plane and the complex function 1
over Z ok so these are the topics I'm
gonna talk about ok so it's and again
the more comments you have the better my
talk will be so you know to comment on
the here you know in in a chat box
so okay let's listen it's starting on a
second
let's get that correct list of Phi
that's right these are the topics and
okay so let's let me show you this okay
so this heidi uncommon indian do you
know anything about fading markers have
options about them what do you mean 30
mark was is like a keyboard Marco's
Emacs keyboard macros or do you mean
Lisp macros but today we're gonna focus
on math though so I'm gonna focus on
geometry and math if we're gonna you
know we this is gonna be maybe in an
hour so let's talk about geometric
inversion so how so geometric inversion
is a transformation okay that means it's
like okay they are transformations for
example reflection you know what's a
reflection let's go to Wikipedia because
that's so so the the so in mathematics
this think especially in geometry okay a
branch of math especially in the context
of geometry you have the concept the
concept of so-called transformation okay
now that word is used in math in lots of
places and the meaning may differ
slightly but in general a transformation
means basically a map okay also
programmer is it means a function I
means given an input you have output but
in math it typically means in especially
in geometry it typically means you have
a space or a plane okay then you go
through a transformation meaning
you know in a plane you have points in
the plane and after the transformation
the the points you move the points to
somewhere else so each point has a
position you know in the plane
originally after the transformation it
becomes somewhere else you know another
position so this this thing is called
transformation so what what are some
examples of transformation
transformation for example
transformation for example we have
reflection we have translation we have
scurrying we have rotation now these are
some of the examples of transformation
now and these are very simple you can
understand so let's see I want I need to
yeah so let's get to
so reflect a for example you have a
plane oops that's not what you want so
on a second let me just I want a pen and
I want the dot size is going to be four
points four point is good and I don't
want dynamic I want pressure size
actually I want dynamics off okay so
that's good so start a new one so
reflection if for example you have a
plane okay so let's see okay so this
gotta be here so you have a plan you
know x-axis y-axis so this is X this is
y and the reflection is means for
example if you have a lie and you have a
point here a P and reflection it just
means it becomes over here you know
let's say a dot B Prime
okay this is actually slow due to anyway
so this is what reflection means it's
like a mirror reflection you know the
line needs not to be vertical it can be
like horizontal so this point becomes
this point this point becomes this point
and that is point by point and you could
have a circle if you have a circle here
then it gets mapped to over here you
know if you have a triangle let's say
this and it becomes like that something
like that okay
so this is called reflection now again
remember reflection is is a
transformation you can think of it as a
function you know so in geometry given a
plane you apply this transformation then
you know
Serco becomes over here you know a
transformation over this slide this is a
function this this is mapping this is
called this particular transformation is
called reflection now that's simple
enough
now translation okay okay these are some
examples of transformations translation
just means move a point to some other
place actually let's go to Wikipedia
because that is actually easier the
arrow marker from croushore yeah we can
talk about that Nick next next episode
about Lisp about this Marcus and arrow
functions but anyway so let's go back to
so let's see so well let me get quickly
get over these so we can start to talk
about inversion so so transformation is
just a function a map okay so well the
four of the simple examples of a
transformation is reflection translation
trans translation just move something
from here to another place by a vector
that is you move horizontally by you
know by x by a number and you move
vertically by a number so you know it's
like you can move something to anywhere
like a point you start with a point and
you can move it to for example X to the
right two units
white up one unit so you move by the
vector 2 1 so basically that becomes
it's like it's moved
you know diagonally and so that's me
that means trans translation that means
you move the point two you know
somewhere else and there's a scaling now
of course you know what is scaling right
scaling is like for example let's go to
the Wikipedia article on reflection
Crick
okay and the reflection let's hold on
magnify now let's magnify now magnif
magnification is actually the geometric
process of scaling so we actually
covered you know the transformation you
see you see how how each point has a
position or internally but after
magnification it becomes somewhere else
now this process in math is called it's
called scaling or it's called dilate
dilation okay and it's one example of
the transformation geometric
transformation so let's see the article
it there so here is a article on
reflection you can see Wikipedia
examples now so scaling scaling is Kotak
dilation dilation okay oh no as dilation
and another thing is about rotation now
everyone understand rotation now these
four these four transformations together
is called isometry now that's important
that's a very important concept in
geometry when you study geometry in
maths okay now I'm talking about
geometry this is not geometry I mean
when you think of geometry you think of
oh element you most of you are probably
thinking of elementary geometry you know
Oh circles triangles trigonometry you
know the volume of a circle you know the
area of a circle you know that that's
well that's geometry but that's that's
kind of high school geometry but here
when we am talking about transformation
and these simple examples although they
are very simple but these are the
beginning of rather advanced geometry in
math okay you you see this concept
applied so anyway so I have given you
four examples of
simple transformation these four
specific transformation is called
isometry now we're starting to get into
job ins this this word isometry let's go
to so let's go to Wikipedia and we can
see isometry now let's meet okay in math
an isometry is a distance preserving
transformation between matrix spaces
usually assumed to be by active that's a
large organs but and we have the the
jogger matrix space but basically you
know if we are in a plane you know it
just isometry is just one of the
reflection or translation or scaling or
rotation you know or combination of
those because they are called isometry
because they there has they have the
property of distance preserving meaning
that if you have two points in a plane
you know there's a distance between them
now after you do the transformation the
points you know the points will become
some somewhere else okay however the
distance you you again measure the
distance between the points they will be
the same as when you before the
transformation so that's what distance
preserving means now this is important
because this is one of the property of
isometry you know these lists for
transformations are called isometry and
you have this property
you know distance preserving is one of
the properties of these four particular
transformation but later on you will
start to see other other properties for
example there is a angle preserving
property which is called conformal map
okay which is related to complex complex
analysis we will get into that geometric
inversion now the topic we are going to
talk about geometric inversion okay this
one
you see this do you beautiful but weird
shape now that is a transformation of a
rectangular grid for example you start
with this image okay this is just a
simple rectangular grid after the
transformation meaning you know points
are moved to some other place according
to a specific according to a function
then you get this picture you get this
weird-looking picture that's a
transformation and this particular
transformation is called geometric
inversion and I'm going to explain what
how it is done what what what is the
rules okay but but but like I mentioned
before this is an example of a
transformation just just like you know
the reflection translation scaling and
rotation are transformations okay and
those transformations are called
isometry like we talked about they are
isometry because they are distance
preserving transformation they are
called isometry and let's this let's
make sure if I didn't get it wrong if I
okay you see they you see you see how
the article I mean if you never studied
math as I assume you haven't you know
you are programmer so you start to see
these words you know isometry manifolds
you know so so that gives you a flavor
why how math gets become advanced but
the idea is pretty simple then you have
you know anyway so let me just make sure
I got this right
actually so formal definitions yeah so
distance preserving map is called
isometry by the way map the word map and
transformation has half the same meaning
okay a function or map or transformation
in
math they pretty much have the same
meaning which word to use usually
depends on context for example if you're
talking about geometry usually we use
the word transform transformation okay
if you are in algebra usually you use
the word function okay so but basically
they mean the same same thing so let's
see isometry okay but anyway so I'm
pretty sure you know the these four
transformations the complete list of
transformations that are distance
preserving in the Euclidean plane are
these for reflection translation scaling
or rotation yes
I'm pretty sure but I do not see it
listed in Wikipedia because this Arco is
general because you have to go to the
article that talks about isometry in
Euclidean plane because you know
Wikipedia gets becomes larger and larger
so so anyway is somewhere somewhere it
should mention rigid motion okay rigid
motion is another word for isometry in
Euclidean plane anyway that's not going
to that it's case complex anyway so so
we have transformations we have isometry
now let's talk about geometric inversion
now a geometric mean version okay now
it's a it's a transformation let's see
how long I've been talking so I I want
okay so let me get okay so how is it
define here here
here is how geometric inversion given a
fixed circle now suppose you have a
point P in the plane somewhere okay now
we want to know where does P lies after
the transformation after the geometric
inversion so again remember geometric
inversion is always with respect to a
given circle just like you know when you
have a reflection it's always with
respect to a given line you know and
translation is always with with respect
to a vector like you know a direction in
horizontal axis in vertical axis that's
translation and scaling is always with
respect to a number and you know that
like how much you want to zoom in or how
much you want to zoom out you know with
respect to a number rotation is also
always reached with respect to a number
like what degree you want to rotate also
with respect to a center like you know
with you know which Center but usually
we assume it's our engine like you know
given XY axis you have let's see here
because that you know given the XY axis
you assume the engine is the center of
rotation so anyway you know these are
transformations so back to inversion so
inversion is always with you have to
given a circle fixed circle so given a
point P where is how is it transformed
now from the center let's say center of
the circle is oh okay suppose that's our
engine point zero zero so you and the
suppose the circle has radius R okay you
know from here to here it's a radius R
and okay so
so the so the inversion is defined
define it's defined by a point Q in a
plane such that the line from o to P the
distance from o to P times the distance
from o to Q is equal to R squared R is
the radius of the circle does that make
sense
ok guys comments ok I only have ok I got
five people watching comment you know
company you comment I talk better ok so
so do you guys see the definition of
inversion now so inversion given so
first of all given a circle of a you
know given a circle you have a radius R
and given any point P in a plane
anywhere you want to find out where is
the new P you know after the
transformation so the way you find it
out is that you draw a line from point O
the center of circle to P then you have
a distance AutoKey the new point the new
point which is the inversion of P is a
point Q such that the distance from o P
multiplied by distance or Q is equal to
R squared this formula this formula ok
so I need to actually maybe I need to do
some interactive examples let's do that
let's see if we can do that so here is a
interactive example written you know
using the geogebra so this point you see
first of all we are given a circle you
know we are given a circle and we are
given any point P in the plane and you
can see the Q the point Q is the in
of P now in this interactive application
you can see how they relate how they
relate P and Q and the point Q you know
as I mentioned it's determined by you
know you draw a line from o to P in the
distance
o P times o Q is equals to R squared but
anyway from from this you can see the
further away P is the closer is Q to oh
now what and let's honor them and what
if okay so we can also actually change
the circle but let's not do that
anyway let's let's change the P okay
something so on a second we want to okay
so okay so we can see that as P moves
far away Q becomes closer to the center
of a circle now if if P is on the circle
then its inversion point is is itself
basically on the circle too now if P is
inside the circle Q moves far away so
the point P and Q are kind of like a
mirror of each other you know they are
kind of mirror images you know so you
have this line outside the circle and
you have this line inside the circle and
any point on a circle you know they kind
of mirror each other
so this line outside the circle is
infinite you know they they go to
infinity but all these infinite points
are mapped to inside the circle segment
you can see that you can see that you
see how they are they are mapped so and
what what if the point P is on the
center of the circle Q basically you can
see that as P
moves closer to the center cue moves
further away so when P is actually at oh
it's in verses you can think of its
infinitely far away it's like the
infinity at you know everywhere it's
like the infinity okay so here is where
you get the concept the concept of
infinity happens you know it just
happened naturally you know in math like
when you see infinity all of a fourth
dimension sometimes you wonder where
does this concept came from you know
like what the hell you know so but here
from an example we can see the concept
of infinity just happened naturally you
see because as let me move that let's
change the size of the circle so we can
see we can see more clear examples so if
we move the P inside you know the circle
Q cube becomes outside P gets closer to
O the center Q moves far away and you
can see a speak gets closer and closer
to all the Q moves further further away
so so now you you naturally get the
concept of infinity in fact it's you get
the concept of a point in a plane that
is that is infinitely far away from from
the center of the circle in fact doesn't
matter what direction like it doesn't
matter what direction so it it's almost
seems like you know the infinite borders
you know of the plane is one point
infinity that means that it's like there
is a magical point called infinity that
that is mapped to the infinite border of
the plane so anyway so this is the
definition of geometric transformation
now we are looking at this geometrically
and you can see how they correspond but
algebraically
you know it's defined by this equation
you know distance opie times distance Oh
Q equals 2r squared okay now that
concludes the definition of geometric
inversion now let's recap geometric
inversion is a transformation what does
that mean that means given a point in a
plane you have you know after the
transformation you have a new position
for the point now every point has a you
know corresponding point point except
the center of the circle now when when
the input point is at the center of the
circle we kind of say you know either
you know there's two ways to approach
that issue one way is that we just say
oh that's not in that's not defined
it's like undefined it's like 1 divided
by 0 we just say we don't allow it so
geometric inversion is a function such
that every point in the plane gets a new
position except one of the point okay we
say that the function is not defined on
that point you know that's one way to do
it or another approach is to say that we
kind of imagined there is a point at
infinity so if the input point P is is
the same as the center of the circle we
say that the result is is a magic point
at infinity okay we don't know what it
means but that's kind of how we can
approach it and in fact that's a lot of
math approach things when we approach
you know infinity is a very curious
concept in math but here we have an
example we have given definition of
geometric geometric inversion and we
have also touched upon we we have also
encountered this infinity concept and so
far we have we we give we have two of
one is that we just say it's undefined
okay we define the transformation to you
know have one special point that's just
undefined for the function another
approach is that we kind of elaborate or
think of a point at infinity now this is
important and this is very curious you
know you might think this is getting
kind of messy and you know kind of you
know strange but math is full of these
strangeness and they and it's also how
it becomes interesting because this this
point of infinity has significance okay
it's critically important in math it's
like when you you know in as a
programmer or if you are interested
interested in AI you might think you you
might have heard of the concept of
singularity okay
the singularity concept came from math
and what it means is also kind of what
we are dealing with right now
it's like 1/0 it's like some kind of
infinity some kind of things that's
either undefined or it's infinity is
some sort of magic okay that's that all
came from math and we have just
encountered one such example now okay
now we have defined geometric immersion
I hope I'm not actually repetitive you
know okay I'm losing I'm losing Watchers
fast okay let's read the comments
good morning omen so if P is the circle
arrangin the inverse is effective of the
visible canvas that's correct yeah we
you know yes so it's kind of you know it
just went infinity went to infinity yes
yes now I'm gonna talk this now so today
we we are talking about geometric
inversion now this is related to
stereographic inversion which actually
connects
to this strange concept of infinity like
the point went out of canvas it connects
them in a coherent way in such such a
beautiful and coherent way I hope to
explain next okay
we'll come to that so first of all let's
go to let me let me just show you the
stereographic projection okay so you can
see a picture of it now remember the
connection between stereographic
projection and the inversion we just
talked about geometric inversion is that
it makes this concept of a point going
to infinity concrete like we can
actually see it now at at this moment we
cannot see like what what do you mean a
point went to infinity like we don't we
cannot see it because the point just
went faint went far away but now when we
do geometric inversion when we do
stereographic projection here we we can
actually see the point and everything
makes sense now here's what we're gonna
talk about this is this is this is a
stereographic projection now this is 3d
okay this is three-dimensional but but
the geometric inversion we just talked
about is 2d okay this this is 2d
but we are going to connect them
together so you can see how they connect
together so well so anyway before we
talk about Stevie or graphic projection
let's come back to geometric conversion
let's let's cover a little bit something
tie them together so geometric inversion
you know like the geometric
transformation we talked before the
isometry
there are many extremely interesting
properties of geometric inversion now
this thing when we are doing this we are
mapping one point to another point right
I mean it's a transformation so given a
point we have a result which you know P
becomes Q so in the same way we can
actually start to draw a circle here a
circle or a square or a photo of
yourself like you can put a photo of
yourself here and you do the geometric
inversion on the points on the circle on
the photo and you will be transformed
into inside of this circle in a weird
shape you know basically given any image
any image on the plane will become some
other image because remember this is
geometric inversion is a transformation
meaning that it maps all points to some
new points so so now you know that rule
of transforming one point but you can
apply the rule so you can transform any
picture like any photograph any you know
like a picture of myself you know epic
you know so you get interesting pictures
this is an example this example is
transforming a grid you know just a
rectangular grid it becomes this so
there are many interesting properties
not remember before the isometries they
have a interesting property and that
property is they are distance preserving
that means given two points they have a
distance after the transformation such
as reflection the distance between the
two points that there are new positions
remains the same they are called
distance preserving now now now
geometric inversion is not distressed
distance preserving obviously because if
you look at the grid you know you know
in a grid each point you know between
the squares after the transformation
they are not the same
you know any anymore you know some
becomes further apart some becomes you
know closer together but however there's
the extremely curious and the important
property they are angle preserving you
know that is okay for example this is a
grid you know suppose we speaking with
this this picture this image in math we
call it image okay we call a pre image
after the transformation we call the
image okay so this is pre image we're
going to apply our transformation and
what we get is called the image okay but
anyway so we start with this picture
this image okay so you can see so what
we mean by angle angle means for example
in this picture we have you know the
lines and they from night 90 degrees
okay they from 90 degrees after the Geo
make after the transformation after we
apply this geometric inversion you know
for every point on a grid you know every
point you know not just the course
intersections but every point we get a
new picture and that picture what does
that picture looks like it looks like
this this one okay so this is a pre pre
image this is an image so so you can see
lines become circles after geometric
inversion yes that's a theorem okay
lines become circles and actually
circles become circles or lines is it it
gets extremely interesting and and
there's a very important and interesting
property that is angle preserving
meaning that you see here we have lines
they form 90 degrees angles after the
transformation
you see they become the lines become
circles okay and all the circles when
they intersect
their intersection is always also 90
degrees you see here we have 90 degrees
intersection here is a 90 degree
intersection here is 90 degrees every
intersection remains 90 degrees so that
means you know this is very curious you
know because we have this transformation
geometric mean version it looks like on
the surface things becomes you know
warped out of shape but actually all the
angles
doesn't matter it's 90 degrees or any
other degree any intersection between
two lines are preserved the angle
doesn't change you know remains whatever
anger it was before so that there is a
fundamental did this is very critical
importance when you study complex
analysis you know this this is one of
the most important thing because right
now we are talking about right now you
know so far we've talked about just you
know plane you know real numbers in a
plane X Y axis Y axis points in the
plane we are not talking about complex
numbers but but as you know math is all
related when you study complex numbers
and complex analysis it is it's the
whole thing is is fundamentally based
relates to this is based on our idea of
geometric transformation and angle
preserving by the way the jargon in math
for angle preserving transformation is
called conformal map
it's called conformal map okay let me
write it down because because if you go
to Wikipedia and you look at the word
conformal map okay that's the word that
let's go to Wikipedia and you can see
you can start to see you know it relates
to the complex analysis the whole branch
of math is based on this idea you know
mobius transform a
conformal map and derivatives of complex
functions and so on conformal map okay
let's go to Wikipedia you can read it
you know offline you know it's you know
I I hope I'm giving you I hope you know
I'm giving you a good introduction so
that now when you look at these you know
jargons you start to understand you know
because before when you read this you
may not see what's going on but now you
do
anyways so conformal map so anyway let's
go back to geometric inversion so we
were talking about so geometric
conversion is a transformation and it
has a bunch of very interesting and
important properties for example circles
become circles itself and lines become
circles or lines circles also become so
close allies so basically circles and
lines are preserved they becomes either
circles or lines for example in this
picture in this picture let's open it
you see you see this yellow circle this
yellow circle is the inversion circle
remember geometric inversion is based on
a fixed circle we have a two ever given
circle now this purple eyes is the
preimage okay this purple eyes becomes
this red circles and vice versa so if we
start with this purple lines after
geometric inversion they become these
red circles okay on the other hand if we
begin with these red circles you know
and after inversion they become these
parallel lines so in geometric inversion
circle n lines are preserved they become
Sakura lines now let me let me show you
another very interesting property about
geometric inversion now when we think of
action like reflection let's go back to
reflection you see how you know like
reflection are like mirrors right you
know you know things becomes to the
other side comes through your side now
geometric inversion is actually you can
also it's it's actually you can think of
it as a generalization of reflection
okay
why is that because look at this this
picture you see all points on the
outside of the circle becomes it comes
to the inside of the circle and any
point inside the circle comes to the
outside so so this circle this circle
this fixed fixed circle is like the
mirror it's kind of mirror
it mirrors everything inside to the
outside and everything outside to the
inside so geometric inversion is
actually is actually a generalization of
reflection or mirror you know why
because you can see as the circle
becomes large let me let me see if I can
make okay
I'm trying to make this circle a lodge I
cannot okay I can do it here I can okay
I this this Geo this geogebra
application is not constructed so that I
can just drag to change the circle size
I don't think I can do that yeah but
anyway what I'm trying to show is that
you can see that as the circle becomes
larger and larger you know the the
inversion circle imagine it gets larger
and larger it becomes infinite large
infinitely large so that the radius
becomes infinity and the circle actually
becomes a lie that that is when this
inversion becomes just reflection you
know so again we have the concept of
infinity involved you know just imagine
the circle becomes large and large you
know you know the radius becomes
infinite and you know the circle is
curved but now it becomes you know less
than less curved it becomes a lie then
you can start to see you know the left
side is mirror to the right side so
that's kind of like that's that's a
generous generalization of you know this
reflection concept so that's another
interesting thing to think about it is
the geometric inversion kind of just
warp everything inside the circle to the
outside and vice versa kind of just
mirror it so interesting properties
include you know lines and circles
become circles or lines and yeah let me
show you an example there's a
interactive application again
hello beta base okay
so here here we have a geometric
inversion of us so this black circle is
fixed okay
this blue circle is the circle we want
to invert so this blue circle becomes
this red circle inside the circle so we
can move the blue circle around you know
so these two are inversions geometric
inversions of each each other so you can
see circles actually become circles at
some point they become itself and you
can also see how they becomes you see
another you see how circles start to
become a lie when the radius becomes
infinite you see there and it warps back
you know so this is how this is the you
know the fascinating thing about
geometry and math you know so anyways so
that's you know so how do you know how
do you know circles become circles I
mean how do you can you prove it yes so
I have a proof here you can read it
offline it's it's very simple it's very
easy to understand proof circle house
circle and lines becomes themselves so
that's one property and another property
is that angle preserving called
conformal map so geometric inversion is
a conformal map okay that's all I want
to say about geometric inversion so I
hope next I'm gonna talk about okay I
hope I hope in 10 minutes I can cover
how it relates to stevia graphic
inversion in three dimension and I hope
that would be it for today and there are
other things like complex plane
Riemann sphere we almost touch it like
we are like almost here almost there
they are like because the Audis you know
topics are related together studio
graphic projection Riemann sphere
a complex plane and complex function 1
over Z now stereographic projection is
actually just a geometric inversion in
3d okay we're gonna we're gonna talk
about we're gonna get over that let me
show this yeah this is steel graphic
projection it's actually it is just
actually a geometric inversion in
three-dimensional space and the Riemann
sphere hemisphere is actually just this
sphere of a stereographic projection
this fear when it's formalized into math
we call it wet Riemann sphere
it's actually just a extension of the
complex plane which is you know which is
basically a plane with a point at
infinity that's how we tie it to the you
know the point at infinity we can you
know so a point at infinity is actually
just the North Pole on this sphere yeah
yeah so and so we have complex plane and
we have complex function one over Z
complex function one over Z is actually
just the geometric mean version plus
plus a reflection of the along the x
axis so you have a geometric inversion
you do that first then you reflect you
know the whole plane over the x axis
that is the complex inversion the
complex function one over Z ok so that
that so that's how they are all related
but let's talk about the stereographic
projection how they relate to geometric
inversion ok now the series as you know
this how so stereographic projection is
it's again it's a transformation
geometric transformation is oh it's a
function that map's a point on a plane
to a point on a sphere ok on a bow
or vice-versa so you can map a point on
the ball anywhere on the ball imagine a
football you know and and you draw a
point on the ball you want to have a
corresponding point on a plane the way
you do it is you just put the ball it's
like put the ball you know on a on a
plane and see if we can do that you know
like that let's see so you put a ball on
a plane you know then at the top of the
ball you let's call it North Pole you
you put you draw a line to to a point on
a plane a ball point on the sphere let's
let's start by you know a point on plane
you draw a line and the line we
intersect the sphere and that that
intersection would be the corresponding
point to the point on the plane so in by
this way by this method by this rule by
this function this is how we have you
know a map between any point on the
sphere and any point on the plane and
this method this rule this approach is
called CBO graphic projection okay
that's the name of it now except there
is one exception what what if the point
you know on the sphere is at the North
Pole where does that point become where
did put us that where is that point on a
plane again we have a situation just
like before just like the geometric
inversion we can either say you know the
North Pole is undefined by this
transformation okay it's not mapped to
any point on the plane or or we can say
the North Pole on the sphere is mapped
to a point is mapped to a some sort of a
point at infinity because you can see if
you have a point on the sphere you can
see if you move the point on a sphere
closer and closer to the North Pole
or the corresponding point on a plane
will be further and farther away such
that if your point on the sphere is very
close to the North Pole then then the
point on the plane is like very very far
away and in this process you can kind of
see you know you can kind of picture the
ideal so what happens if the point is
you know the North Pole you can kind of
see it actually become a point some kind
of magical point infinitely far away
doesn't matter what directions is it's
just a point infinitely far away so so
mathematicians what you do is that so
they just say mathematician says okay
you have imagine you have a plane okay
and a sort of ideal plane and this plane
is called Riemann sphere okay so what
does that mean is that you have a plane
you know infinite in all directions but
however there is a point in the plane
that's called infinity the point at
infinity this point we call the point at
infinity okay that is just a point
infinitely far away that connects to the
whole plane in other words in other
words when you look at the studio
graphic projection you can think of the
whole thing is just a sphere okay so so
now the hope the whole plan mapped to
the sphere except except the the spheres
got one extra point then the plane that
is the point at the top the North Pole
but now we imagine the plane actually
has that point so the plane becomes some
kind of ideal plane with one extra point
added that point is called the point at
infinity and now with the stereographic
projection that point is easy to
understand because you know from this
process you can see you know you can
just
think of the pen as a sphere you know so
by this magical means of projections
stereographic projection now any picture
on the plane you kind of see the plane
as a sphere and and vice versa so
anything you do on a sphere is kind of
like correspond to the pen and anything
you do on a plane is corresponding to
the sphere okay now that that is
stereographic projection now this ideal
plan we've been talking about with the
extra point of point at infinity is
called Riemann sphere that's just the
math jargon okay now you can go and read
that article on Wikipedia is it this
this this is this is the concept what
mathematicians called Riemann sphere so
for example let's read it so in math
Riemann sphere is a model of extended
complex plane the complex plane plus a
point at infinity okay that that is what
it is so when you study complex analysis
basically you are studying women's feel
you know that that and it's related to
the which division by zero you know so
so the extended complex numbers so what
what is the extended complex numbers
basically that's that's just the plane
we are talking about with one added
point called the point and infinity and
that point give give give us the meaning
of one divide that by zero in the
complex plane so it ties to complex
you know analysis even though we haven't
talked about complex numbers yet okay
but we are just talking about the
geometry so but you can see how they are
all related you know that's what makes
math so interesting so anyway complex so
so we covered stereographic projection
we covered inversion
now what's left to do is what is the
connection between inversion ends and
the stereographic projection how are
they created okay they are related in
many ways in fact when you have
stereographic projection okay you can
you know by this process we explained
how you know points on the sphere
corresponding to points on the plane now
you can start to draw lines on the plane
you know and see how you know what's
there image on the sphere and vice versa
you can have a circle on the sphere and
see what is the image on the plane and
you will find that in fact lines or
circles mapped to lines in circles just
like just like steel
just like geometric converging lines
become circle lines circles becomes
circle lines you know on the sphere on a
plane you know if you start to do this
so actually so this example for example
this example you have lines here right
and those lines are may actually map to
circles how can you know because you can
see you see this look at the green
square okay so you follow a line on a
green square so this this line becomes
you know becomes this line they are
circles they are circles on the sphere
and also look at the border the border
of this plane you see they become these
four kind of arc of circles but
basically you can prove and you can it's
not difficult to prove prove you can see
the proof if you go to Wikipedia Stevie
or graphic projection you can see the
proof that circles becomes lines or
circles and lines becomes you know they
map it you know two lines or circles
Stevie or graphic projection now let me
talk about how are they connected first
of all just like inversion - become
circle or lies okay now let's talk about
inversion in three-dimensional space
five more minutes that should be it
let's talk about talk about
three-dimensional inversion okay so now
we know now we have talked about
two-dimensional inversion you know which
we begin you know we we do inversion
geometric inversion our plane in us in a
similar way we can do an inversion on on
three dimensional space by imagine so
first of all what are we doing so
imagine so we have points in space you
know 3d space now we have a bunch of
points now we want to do a
transformation so given a point after
the transformation we have we will have
a new position for that point
that's what transformation means in this
case we are doing transformation in 3d
space okay
and now the transformation we want to do
is a geometric inversion now just like
2d two-dimensional case we start with a
circle you know I am in another saga a
sphere in 3d space in 3-dimensional
space and and just like the 2d case so
given a point we draw a line from the
center of the sphere to the point and
the distance from this the distance from
the sin the centre of the sphere to that
point x distance from the center to
another point on the same line
will be equals to R squared where R is
the radius of the
fear just just like the 2d case we can
see the 2d case here you know but
imagine this is three-dimensional where
this circle is a three dimensional so
three dimensional sphere so in this way
any point in space you know we all have
a new position so again just like the
two dimensional case any point outside
of the sphere will be mapped to a point
inside the inside of the sphere now this
is a three dimensional case of geometric
inversion but okay so how does it relate
to a stereographic projection now the 3d
case of inversion I am Not sure I did a
good explanation you have to kind of
imagine you have to convince it yourself
how how it works you know am i like
clear let me let me take a break and
read the comments so normal says
speaking of geometry ray tracing might
be an interesting topic of future talk
yeah ray tracing is it's it's more of a
computer graphics related math in math
you don't do that let me see where am I
like am I still talking good okay so so
Daniel says people say that now
non-euclidean geometry is invented
ukrainian geometry is force there is no
certainty and you know that's let's push
it okay that's another topic about your
idea in geometry and non Euclidean
geometry they are all geometries okay
they are just there are different
geometries there are different
geometries with different axioms okay
they are all models of geometry
now when when Euclidean geometry is
first thought about its it's a one huge
chapter in history of math okay it's
like it's like a shock among
mathematicians because it was impossible
to believe okay but anyway you crazy and
geometry non Euclidean you know they are
all just models of geometry we have
different models now the questions to a
lot of people is which universe is our
universe you cried Ian or non-euclidean
we don't know actually the answer is
actually we don't know we you know so
far you know the science in the
physicists you know we we actually do
not know and we actually don't even we
don't know I mean there are a lot of
questions we don't know what dimension
you know are we actually in fourth
dimension
so are we in five dimensions oh you know
then there's a question by the way
there's also relativity which is by the
way our instance you know it's related
to time in space that that combines time
and space into one concept inseparable
like there's no different thing time in
space is one thing and by the way that
is not that is actually different from
the dimensionality we are talking about
in geometry fourth dimension of
information that's that's totally
different in you know in in geometry
doesn't matter you cried you know then
you cried yet you have dimensions and
those dimensions are not related to time
then you know it's not the time we are
talking about so in your Nativity you
know that time in space things is again
it's a different thing so we have you
know so we are getting complicated you
know into these advanced topics and and
we you know to go into that we need to
explain what is you cried in geometry
what is non Euclidean geometry and
that's you know that's big topic you
know that's how you you actually that's
how you study you get a PhD
math to begin well you don't you know
you just need you need a degree in math
to to understand those things so you
know so then let me get back to the how
stereographic projection is related to
geometric inversion in fact
stereographic projection we talked about
the way they correspond points on the
sphere and points on a line on a plane
is actually a instance of geometric
inversion in 3d so how is that related
let me just explain I'm not sure I can
do a good explanation now but let me
just do it let's go to a new tablet okay
a new panel so let me try to explain it
in into two minutes you know just to
give you a flavor and you can read up on
Wikipedia you go to the article stevia
graphic projection you'll see how house
TV or graphic projection is actually
just a instance of geometric inversion
in 3d space that is why that is why you
see a lot of similar properties such as
lines becomes circles or lines and
circles become circles Alliance you know
so imagine this is a circle okay I'm not
doing a good job so this is a circle and
we are doing Stevie or graphic
projection has te ha yeouch g AP okay
there's a lot lag here so I cannot write
well but imagine this is Stevie Oh
graphic projection so we draw a line
so let's say this point is P and this
point is Q so that's Stevie Oh graphic
projection right imagine this is three
dimensional space so we project the line
from Northport to you know any given
point in a plane and see okay so we
project you know that's how we got our
point Q when the line intersect with the
circle I mean the sphere we got a point
Q intersection and that is the that is
the image of P you know P and Q are
related in that way now imagine there so
imagine there is another circle twice as
large so I'm going to draw a circle here
I mean not a circle but a sphere imagine
there is a okay this is a bad joint
imagine this okay that's this is so bad
okay I'm just gonna go wrong and I am
NOT going to fix joints imagine there is
a circle twice as large okay
something like that twice as much so
from here here this is our this is our
this is our this is our so you know from
this sphere has radius R and this sphere
has radius 2 R so and the the larger
sphere is centered on the North Pole now
now look at this line imagine we are
doing okay right so so so so we got this
large circle centered on a North Pole
with radius of 2 ah
now we are going to do a geometric
inversion of this point P and Q I mean
this point P now can you see that you
see we are doing a geometric inversion
with this point P with respect to this
large circle you will see that the
resulting point is this Q exactly the
same as the process of stevia graphic
projection with this small circle small
sphere now now that that I just covered
that that's how they relate okay they
are the same thing
you you might want to think about that
oh you know go read Wikipedia that is
how they relate so so on this picture of
stevia graphic projection imagine there
is a largest sphere twice as large and
we want to do geometric inversion with
respect to the large square large sphere
so any this point on the plane will
become a new point and this new point is
you know on this sphere is actually just
the point of the geometric inversion
with respect to that large sphere okay
that's it that's that's about it that's
it what that's what I'm gonna explain
okay I hope that's a good talk I hope I
did the job 70 weeks oh we did 80
minutes I hope I covered so we have
covered actually we have covered we have
covered G Omega the meaning of geometric
geometric geometric transformation we
have covered the four fundamental
geometric geometric transformation that
is that is reflection translation
scaling and rotation and this four is
called isometry we are covered
and isometry is a distance preserving
transformation a important property of
geometric transformations okay then we
have covered in geometric inversion
which is a transformation a geometric
transformation we have covered some
important properties of geometric
inversion which is one angle preserving
and also circles mapped to circles or
lives in lines becomes lines or circles
that's important interesting property of
geometric inversion and we are also
covered how geometric inversion is
actually kind of a generalization of the
process of reflection you know you know
because as you know you can see and
anything outside comes it becomes inside
anything inside becomes outside it's
kind of very interesting mirror you know
around the circle or sphere and we have
also covered how the the geometric
inversion in three-dimensional space you
know just like two-dimensional space
example so instead of a circle we have a
sphere anything outside of sphere comes
inside inside comes outside then we have
also covered the interesting concept of
point at infinity how it naturally
arises and you know we have this concept
of point at infinity then we have also
covered stereographic projection you
know which is very simple idea you look
at the picture you actually understand
that immediately how points on the plane
and points on the circle on the sphere
are related by a line you know and this
is another example of geometric
transformation in this case is
transformation between actually two
different spaces one is the Euclidean
plane another is a sphere
and we also have seen how a point at
infinity concept occur here because what
happens if your point is it as at the
north point so we have a concept a point
of infinity and we are we have also
talked about this how this point of
infinity in a mathematicians
idealization they become what's so
called women's field and you know
mathematicians called Riemann sphere so
Riemann sphere that's the that's a
jargon okay so that's that's that's what
I've we have covered today and Oh
finally we have covered how
stereographic projection is actually
it's actually just a it's just a
geometric inversion in 3d space with a
circle twice as large and st. centered
on the North Pole they are the same
thing you know yeah so let's see let's
read a comment so any more comments just
type it this is this is a good time and
we all say goodbye
so the gnosis is a universe you cry do
or not the answer is that space is
3-dimensional you cried Ian because the
concept is space space is just the
mathematical concept you can start with
any meaningful math what do you mean now
first of all Ateneo are you I mean do
you have a degree in math like do you
have equivalent I mean that you know
some of us summers some of us may not
have a degree but we have realistically
equivalent lot knowledge because I mean
a lot mathematicians some of the
greatest mathematicians did not go to
college for example Fermat you know who
is famous
for Fermat's Last Theorem he does not
have a degree and and actually quite a
lot
examples of mathematicians who do not
have a degree so so then you know I mean
do you actually know this math or are
you just suggesting opinions because you
really you know if you want to discuss
you know you cry the end geometry on you
cry the end and talk about whether we
are in our spaces Ukrainian space you
have to actually know the stuff because
you know if you are just few years you
know I first of all I don't have a
degree okay so you know it's so my math
background you might say you know I
don't have a degree in anything I don't
have a degree in computer science
neither so I don't actually have any
degree you know but I studied stuff so
you know whether you trust my opinions
is up to you you know just judged by
what you already know in programming
maybe you know so it's up to you but but
to talk about these things you kind of
have to know math you know so Daniel
says okay you have a grad graduate
degree but it's but let's make my point
simple that is interesting stuff you
cried Ian versus you cried you yeah you
cried Ian versus non you cried ian is
interesting but what are you saying
though but what what what what are you
saying your last comment so the news is
is the universe you hiding or not the
answer is that space is 3-dimensional
Euclidean because the concept concept of
space
okay I don't know I don't know exactly
you know I
yeah I don't know I don't know I don't
know exactly what do you mean your
comment in your last comment about the
Euclidean versus non Euclidean and the
space we live in it seems you are saying
that the space we live in is is you
cried in 3d space because the definition
of space I'm not sure I agree or
understand that you know what do you
mean because as far as I know we don't
actually know our space you know by our
understanding you know the cosmetology
cosmology I mean the proper term for
this study of whether our space is
youkai do or not is cosmology you know
it also relates to what to mention how
many dimensions do we have is our space
and also is it parallel universe because
it's all kind of you know kind of
related and as far as I know you know
I've read you know I'm you know I'm not
a professional mathematician or thesis
or you know as far as I know we don't
know the answer you know the the top
scientist you're the the the
cosmologists we don't know and we don't
actually know definitely or agree upon
or the cosmologists we don't we don't
have one solid answer whether our
universe is you cried young or not and
we don't know our universe is we don't
even know that what's the topology the
shape of our space and we don't know how
many too many dimensions is our space
it's all it's kind of all open questions
so that's what I think okay so anyway I
think so tenuous a space is invisible
heck or straight lines are invisible
they are one-dimensional
the idea here is not to know if space is
your idea math is not discovered it's
invented yeah okay that's that's that's
an again that's veering into philosophy
of math
math is not discovered its invented yeah
okay I guess we are touching on the
philosophy of math then because you know
then you know becomes you know there's
the philosophy of math where whether is
math already exist or it's just
something we you know invented we you
know it you know yeah there's you know a
bit quite contentious contentious
different philosophies of math you know
that's getting congregated anyway so so
thank you guys for coming by and thank
you for your comments Danielle that's it
for today
so I hope you guys have a good Monday I
guess Monday is a workday
yeah if nobody knew the Pythagorean
theorem yet would it not still be true
yeah that's like saying you know if tree
forcing a forest but nobody is here
they're you know do you still hear it
you know yeah so it's like in a rearm of
philosophy kind of and there's a
platonic school of you know thought is
large logis ism there's formalism
there's a Intuit intuitive nist school
authority yeah you kind of get into
philosophy of math is it's very
interesting topic by the way okay
oh good day guys I hope to see you next
time