hello everyone so today I'm going to
show you some Emacs commands I'm going
to show you these Emacs commands these
are custom commands they help you they
makes Emacs commands more efficient so
so these are commands I wrote and they
are also links fi keys so they are great
so I'm just going to show you so this
video will be about I'm planning for 20
minutes so so so here's my Emacs and and
this screen you can see what command I'm
calling right now so in my Emacs
commands new file okay so so that
command is that see normally when you
max when you want to create a new buffer
what you do is you call the buffer
switch command then you type a random
name like something T DT and ok confirm
that that's annoying so so now you have
a new buffer and you type something then
you let's say queue it kill
it will ask you to confirm so you you
confirm it notice that it doesn't ask
you to save so that's a problem
so with this commands these commands
sonic new empty buffer you can just
create lots of buffers and they are they
will be titled untitled 1 2 3 4 and so
on and and you can close it so so anyway
sorry max comments you can find them on
my Emacs block this page right here so
so these 5 commands are they are kind of
they are all related so new file and
next previous user buffers so okay so
these commands lets you let's go to my
Emacs blog so I have my Emacs block
let's open let's open some other file
Emacs demo ok so ok next demo
ok so so there is lots of files Emacs
pinky Emacs keyboard so now I can show
my buffer so you see I have several
buffers open oh did I just close them ok
so don't close them open don't close
them open switch back open switch back
so when I switch back I'm using this
command this command so our previous
user buffer so you see right now I have
all these buffers open country and I can
press a key to switch buffers around and
that's convenient
usually Emacs creates lots of buffers
you don't want to go through like health
occur
messages and so on so that's so now it's
closed that Emacs blog okay so that's
the next previous user buffer so that
the code that the coder here you can
just copy and put it in your Emacs init
file all these commands are also in soft
like keys okay so that lets cycles
through previous and next buffer but
there's also one cycles through Emacs
buffers you know sometimes you want to
go to a bunch of Emacs outputs for
example least matching lines untitled
and title you see so why useless
matching lines here it creates a new
buffer and this buffer is named occur so
now if I update the my puffer list
you'll see
Who am I okay you'll see is your new
buffer okay so usually when you walk in
Emacs you know day so after the many
days you have lots of these and you can
go through them by okay I forgot what's
a key I have it for that and so I think
it's so switching around
I want to curse this curse message
Kousaka cuz I prefer but anyway you can
assign it to a key any key you want so
let's go back open last close crossfire
this is very convenient it's like the
browser like right now in this browser I
close the file and I can press a key to
reopen it like sometimes you
accidentally closed but for a tab you
don't want to close like you know close
it then you can press
control shift tab or command shift tab
to reopen it so so that's the same idea
like in Emacs like if I could let's do
that so I can close close close close
and oops
you know I crossed by mistake so I press
the key to reopen the last open again
you can reopen again we open again so
that's that's what this command full
open ask close command now you see they
are closed current buffer you see you
cannot just have a command that open
last closed because Emacs would not know
does not be called which file you just
closed so you have to have another
command to use when you close a file and
in that command is for example I want to
close this one that command is so close
current buffer so when you call that
command it will be called add to the
list of that the file you just closed
this another advantage of you know this
closing command because like when you
use here it's okay
reopen when you use kill buffer queue
buffer you ask you for confirming
confirmation that's kind of annoying so
you know you have to press Yes to
confirm okay
okay Open File underpass that that's
also very convenient like normally in
Emacs you can like when you have a file
like this one you can open it by corneal
command F F ap which is short alias to
find file at point so like when I call
that command and your pump point pumped
me for confirmation you know then I
press ENTER and it opens the file it
opens the file now close it so it's
let's try that again
dad yes they open this file but the
content confirmation is kind of annoying
so so I so what I do is I use the
command that just open it without asking
you know if it's a if it's a file let's
see
it's find another file for example this
file I can just open in anywhere it
doesn't have to be in HTML it's like it
can be English L it can be shout output
for example let's say yes so so this is
shout output it's just two nos so I can
just open anywhere and open the file
yeah so so this is open fire on the path
open fire at kusa okay open fire in
external external app that's also very
convenient its closest closest okay wait
it's open that so you see we have an
image here now I want to see this in
finder you know in on the Mac it's
called finder which is like that you can
make the image is bigger now so what so
I want to open this one so I just press
a key and here open whatever my operand
is operating system said to the
application used to open a file it's
like double click the it's like double
click the icon so I don't so so now I go
to find sometimes this is also
convenient for PDF okay so so wait so
let's see okay so I can open it because
because because now what if I want to
open the directory there's this in this
command you can do then it opens the
direct directory this this is communion
but in Emacs you can also do that
I think it's called Tommy it's it's a
weird name but yeah Tommy he was called
to me then you you you ask you a
directory then you're ill
it will call imagemagick to generate a
bunch of let's just try that I don't
want to try that because then you take
time to create all the thumbnails then
the the thumbnails is saved in your
Emacs in in file directory which is dot
Emacs study
so the that's the Emacs version let's
see if I can hook up mod eight reference
menu
okay so close that because that close
that because because because
okay so what let's go back here so there
are two commands opening external app
and showing desktop oh and there's also
open terminal let's try that so I forgot
what key I gave that too so let's just
go ahead open Excel open in terminal
there it is okay I don't need that
closing close it
okay so such yeah such current would
like usually like you know you know fire
let's say you want to such the next word
meta so you press the key for such then
you type meta then you can search next
next and so on
but a a convenient way is that you don't
have to type meta like you can you just
start such you can press a key you know
you're automatically search the current
current the word under cruiser like like
so like okay let's say keyboard I want
to search the word keyboard so I just
call the command and then I can I can do
such
in in standard Emacs what you can do is
that normally what you do is you you
call the search command then you press
ctrl W to highlight the word and and
that will automatic automatic research
that but it's still inconvenient for
examples suppose you have let's say some
hyphenated word water okay let's say
Blue Water Valley okay someone random
what
so you want to search that so what you
have to do know normally you have to
move the cursor to all the way to the
front then start such then you press
ctrl W ctrl W ctrl W then you know then
that's that's that you know you can
start to find the next one but with with
the such under the word command you can
just press one key and and that they'll
be so ok yeah I do some explanation
about the problems of the default Emacs
so select line block quote ok here's a
bunch of commands that's useful all
these commands are related to selecting
selecting parts of your buffer so so
normally when you if you want to select
you you start a mark first then you
highlight to where wherever you want
for example select word I start a mark
and move cursor then I have that were
selected again now correct or whatever
if I want to select the line and let's
format so if I want to select the line I
go to the beginning mark then goes to
the end okay but so with this with this
bunch of commands you it it's a single
command to do what you want it's easier
so let's try this one select text
between quotes okay so so there's a
quote I can press a key then select it
let's try that again
so select that whole select that
oh here's select that oh here's like
that you know select between brackets as
well so it's very useful as especially
when you are in programming languages
say he Emacs Lisp for example
especially when you want to select
everything inside streams anyway so
again you don't want that known that
select lines so ok so let's select
between quotes select current line
that's also one command that lets you
select current line ok select current
block that's also that's like that the
current block based basically means
paragraph now Emacs also has has a
command that select paragraph but Emacs
paragraph is syntax table based that
means it it what exactly means the
paragraph is different depending on the
current major mod and that usually as
gets confusing confusing for example
let's skip example but anyway so this
command
there's select Park it lets you select
the current block and if you call the
command again you're just keep striking
simply same thing with a select line
select line if you keep pressing a key
it just keeps tracking a line now let's
let's break this into smaller parts so
you can actually see the difference so
select block so xx select now if I do
select line here just be like that ok
extent selection now this command is
most useful when you just want to select
the word like select the current word so
that's why use there's another very
useful situation for this command is
when you want to when your cursor is on
on a bracket or parentheses or in any
type of bracket then you call the
command you'll select the whole bracket
so let's try it try that you see China
Sea
you see if you press again you'll select
the outer brackets so that's extend
selection now what what if you are in a
programming language like C or C++ or
Python the this command extend selection
is designed is supposed to design to
working or languages but right now it
doesn't really do that so it's so right
now let's for example let's see X I
extend collection so selection word
bracket expression or we expand
selection subsequent course expand the
selection when there is no selection so
yeah it gives you some usage but anyway
anyway what I was saying that is I it
doesn't really work well in Python or
CEO or the Ruby for example if you want
to use the extend selection feature so
what what is actually reliable right now
is to select an word or select bracket
looks like the bracket like that so so
these two are the main use of this site
extend selection command for not for now
yeah there's a package that's called
expand selection by
um by the Emax box guy that's very good
but I stopped using that because the
extend section is simpler and faster and
it does what I need you know most most
most of the time
okay selection so so now this moving
move okay
yes right so this is move by block or
paragraph four block backward block okay
that's it move to back end in quotes
this is also extremely useful it will
just move the cursor to any type of
bracket like like all these brackets you
can move forward or move backwards and
it's especially useful in in in
programming languages doesn't matter
it's eMac Lisp or Python or Ruby it's
because they all use lots of brackets
okay so you can jump back to the
matching black bucket bracket like like
this like like so
jump jump you got you go to any bracket
then you can jump go go go jump jump
back jump
okay that we covered selection delete
bracket tech text okay um did you
bracket by pear TV repair good okay this
this is also useful command but yeah
it's useful so for example like right
now I want to delete the whole thing I
want to delete this whole thing one way
to do it is put the cursor in the
beginning of the bracket then selected
selected then you know just press the TV
key the other way is to is to place the
cursor in front of the last bracket and
just press a key
we are deleted if if the the character
to the left is a bracket but if it's not
a way or not for example let's I call
this command you see this command I go
it toward code called Cole Cole Cole
Cole Cole you see so so what's useful
about this command is you can give it a
key the same key for the backward delete
key on your keyboard so you know when so
so you just use one key and here do
multiple functions it also work when
it's like this like like this way so for
example let's see GD GD GD GD G GD you
see okay that's making a backup in case
I screwed up my code
so they're small but I think we are over
time so let's stop here