welcome to another episode of excel talk
show today is September 9th Monday 2
o'clock p.m. San Francisco time and good
mornings e-tron crazy good mornings
e-tron crazy and good morning bathroom
you so different crazy is doing homework
math homework about FX equals 2x squared
plus e ok that's a polynomial so is that
calculus or okay so what is the topic
today topics guys topics so okay so
let's prepare this this this window is
is JavaScript by the way and I might
want to convert it to typescript and it
could be your topic today you know
convert this script to typescript
sophist walks our start command log mod
okay if you like to see that conversion
to typescript say it so this window on
the left is my Emacs commands oh my max
commands you can see it there like down
arrow up up arrow right for word word
right back word word and so on so
comments guys what is today's topic wait
the the letter C so today's topics
includes the bathroom you say is 11 life
and death of Flash well I don't have
that much to talk about that well unless
we get into started to talk about some
history
okay so flash as you know fresh was
Macromedia flash Macromedia let's type
it macr ome dia that's a company
Macromedia fresh that's their technology
which is like today's let's go to
Wikipedia which is like today's which is
like today's JavaScript process VG okay
Oh cameras so there it is Adobe Flash
okay it was Macromedia in Adobe bought
it
now Adobe Macromedia in Adobe both
companies they are they are the pioneer
of software on Apple's platform in 1990s
you know in 1990s there's a huge amount
of pioneering software on the Apple
platform for example joining software
like Adobe Photoshop is one of them
freehand is one of them
Adobe Illustrator is one of one of them
and you have Macromedia you have
Macromedia you have fractal which is
painting software factor paint and quite
a lot you know many many of these
pioneering software's start on the Mac
then you know as you know Mac users are
typically 10% of all computer users so
eventually by the late 1990s or early
2000s they all switched to Windows that
is originally they most of them or many
of them they produce only Mac only
software in the beginning then they
switch to then they become both Mac and
Windows
typically Mac first you know they are
primarily mag then you know around year
2000 they are switched to Windows like
Windows Windows is their primary
platform windows first
they Mac because Mac you know you know
in the history of Mac Apple there's a
large struggles you know around 1997
Apple is about to die you know
reading breathing and you know people
say Apple is gonna be so too much sun
microsystems and so on but eventually
Steve Jobs came back to Apple and he
revived Apple he is really truly one of
the greatest mock marketer and innovator
so Steve Jobs came back to Apple in 1998
around 1998 and he is known as the I CEO
why I CEO because you know at that time
you have iMac you have i something i I
something something you know everything
is I something something ipod yeah I I
pod then so Steve Jobs became known as
AI CEO the AI is supposed to stand for
interim CEO but eventually he's just the
CEO yes no no other guy have to you know
actually take take place then around
2008 also Steve job died okay so let's
look at you know I have some articles on
Steve Jobs death so hold on a second let
me close the door
so Steve Jobs died around 2008 okay so
and then going to show you the bathroom
you talk and g-tron talk and who else is
here talk type your opinions and stuff
comments
okay let's such folks sorry Steve Jobs
you know is that is this a topic we're
gonna talk about so because once we
begin it's gonna be endless it's gonna
be 30 minutes 40 minutes and we won't
have time to do technical programming
stuff so Donald Knuth Steve Jobs and the
idiocy of typography and this one
Richard Stallman on Steve Jobs death and
this one death of Steve Jobs versus
Dennis Ritchie John McAfee now those
those are the UNIX philosophy idiots and
so you want to change the world that's
Steve Jobs on keyboard okay I'm gonna
show you each of these articles and
let's also search for Steve Jobs photos
I have photos of Steve Jobs I personally
took for example this one this one this
one this one all these these are my
photos so this okay except except this
the last row here my personal photos of
Steve Jobs Steve Jobs 1995 to 2011 okay
he died in 2011 okay so are we gonna
talk about these topics good morning
good morning so good morning web table
potami says I read that Richard Stallman
had a talk at Microsoft oh yeah I'm not
sure what's going on but apparently he's
giving a talk at Microsoft
he would never do that
before I don't know so you know a lot of
people are thinking something's going
young you know maybe he got paid oh well
he always get paid I mean I think
whenever Richard Stallman gives a talk I
think he get paid but you know possibly
there is some kind of a issue because he
would you know normally Richard Stallman
would never give a talk at Microsoft you
know and he did yeah that's what they
say you know Microsoft is forced now you
know open source and free software
foundation yeah that's what they say you
know it's like Mac Microsoft is now is
the biggest open source of which self
you know force rather mostly open source
supporters because for example github I
mean Microsoft bought github right but
even before that Microsoft is one I mean
if you count lines of code or project
number of projects Microsoft actually at
some point like two years ago or
something Microsoft was the number one
contributor to open source
you know so I don't know what you guys
open source phonetics you know some some
of you not necessarily you guys but all
the people watching my video some of you
many of you are open source phonetics
or free software phonetics I don't know
what do you guys think of it you know
but to me that that just shows that how
much this open source is just is just
ideology went wrong you know ideology
induced you know all these problems are
ideology induced you know they are not
good they are doing nobody good except
they are doing Microsoft good they are
doing Google good they are doing
Facebook good they are doing you know
all these evil companies good
okay show that what I'm gonna lick Z
transferred sieve and my groceries going
for us okay didn't you hear okay so yeah
that's about Microsoft you know that
that's so my general that's my you know
that to me is a proof you know that how
open source is X the or the open source
is just no good okay it's okay
let's switch topic let's not talk about
open source well it's an inevitability
so web dog says I agree with you sir
open source is welfare for F Aang what
does that stand for and SaaS startups
what does that stand for
so type it so that's you know III heard
like I would like to do some technical
stuff you know I mean instead of instead
of talking about this you know
philosophy I mean kind of thing random
chat oh my god angie is here again Angie
says can I do a logarithmic frequency
spectrum ng P Vai Jess what's the deal
Andrey like you have to say okay I mean
what do you want like like are you are
you are you doing are you did you write
that what's the reason you want me to
talk about that and did you hear last
time you mentioned that I talked about
it for a few minutes because I and I
said I don't know nothing about it I
went to the website I don't know nothing
about about that
you know frequency spectrum JavaScript
project it looks nice but I don't know
nothing about it what what do you want
me to talk about it what's the deal with
that
okay so let's go back to the flash okay
this let's talk let's go back to flash
okay Adobe Flash so I was saying you
know Apple in the 1990s many great
software began on the Apple platform you
know so then Adobe bought it you know
things changed like all these companies
you if you lived long enough you can
observe their history you know that like
this company was good but now it's bad
or that company was bad it did something
evil extremely bad everyone knows and
now it becomes good but the thing is you
see the younger generation they don't
know like you you know you saw it like
yesterday this company is so bad but the
young people they are saying oh you know
you should support company X because
they are so great this or that but if
you lived long enough you know that's
and there's nothing almost nothing you
can do because you know that's that's
what happens in society that's that's in
general the situation of humanity okay
so this article is about typography now
I hate typography I'm I'm not sure I
want to talk about this topic because
this topic is gonna be 30 minutes at
least so you have typography and you
have you have how the tech gurus tech
sucks donkey ass I'm now going to talk
about this let's talk about Richard
Stallman ok so let me finish these
subjects quickly so Richard Stallman or
Steve Jobs dead death so he says I'm not
glad he's dead but I'm glad he's gone so
this is around 2011
when this happened you know Steve Jobs
he's a you know very famous popular guy
and he has a lot of supporters even even
in the free software
I mean well yes it is some in the free
software community and also allowing
open source because Steve Jobs he I mean
as far as I mean he did he said truly
truly a one of the greatest innovator ok
whatever you want to say about other
aspect but at one thing for sure is that
he is truly one of the greatest
innovator he introduced especially ample
in of early days he introduced lots of
things into the population you know for
example Mouse he popular popularized it
for example music you know digital music
he made it legal I mean he made it so
that it's big he made digital music
popular right beep yes because around
early 2000s people are pirating music
you know they live you know there's a
term ripped from CDs you buy CD you rip
it use you know you you share it with
your friends and so he see it he's he
Steve Jobs see this is a problem that a
social problem that it can be solved you
know like nobody all these music
companies they are not selling digital
copies yes they are selling CDs and when
people are pirating over and this
company's behavior typically they are
trying to see you you know doing all
kind of that kind of thing and Steve
Jobs sees that you know this is this is
not right you know society as technology
progresses you know there is actually we
need to do something so he did he made
digital music the selling of digital
music popular you know it's you know you
have like he's interruption or like you
have to go out and do it you know you
know you have to talk to the
the people of the music companies you
know you have to make them you know open
a company and do it and start to you
know and talk about in this law you know
legality legal issues you have to solve
those issues so see jobs did that and
his iPod of course the iPod the first
mainstream music player becomes very
popular so that's all Steve Jobs and
before you know you have USB you have
firewire you have CD on a PC USB CD you
have DVD also you have Wireless also
they are all they all began on Apple you
know on the Apple platform
yep opposed computers on the PC on the
other on the other hand on the PC
Windows typically they wait they wait
and see you know is usually typically
half after Apple you know made it you
know out of the box on the Mac you know
a CD player on the Mac or USB you know
on the Mac or all these other things you
know or a wireless on the Mac or
wireless Wi-Fi on the Mac you know it's
all first on the Mac then you typically
after two years at least a minimum of
two years then it becomes you know they
appears on the PC you know Windows then
it becomes like popular and same thing
for mouse for GUI it's all Apple yeah so
Apple has tremendous innovation and that
is also why I use Apple is my main
machine from 1990s up to 2008 also 2011
2009 something like that
and why do I use a Mac because you know
in my first Mac is 1992 Mac Mac - si Mac
- si okay I have article on my website
but for example you can see here so I
guess today is just random chatting
random chatting
so yeah and J I don't know what's your
issue you know you you you are wasting
your time let's see if I have any way
let's let me finish about so this is Mac
- si this is this came out in 1990 now I
bought my first computer with my own
money
in 1992 I think it's 1992 so that's what
I have Mac - si you have it's running
Mac OS classic you know system 6.0 and
let me tell you what's memory memory is
1 megabyte okay that's you know that's
that's a lot you know back then one
megabyte of memory and the CPU is
motorola 68000 20 megahertz imagine that
today you have two jjigae hertz fiji
guards so is the cpu is 20 megahertz 1
megabyte ran and the hard disk I think
it's 20 mega byte 20 megabyte hunter
disk 40 megabyte okay 40 megabyte hard
disk hard drive
so that's Mac - si that's my first
computer ok so let's go back to Richard
Stallman on Steve Jobs death so Steve
Jobs many people respect then Richard
Stallman says you know he he posted this
on his own blog you know which Stallman
dog he says Steve Jobs the pioneer of
computer as a jail mate cool design - so
designed to serve a force from their
freedom has died as Chicago Mayor Harold
Washington said of a of the corrupt
former Mayor Daley I'm not glad he's
dead but I'm glad he's gone nobody
deserved to have to die not jobs not mr.
Beale not even
people guilty of bigger Evo's than
theirs but we all deserve the end of
jobs malign influence on people's
computing
unfortunately that influence continues
despite his absence we can only hope his
successes as they attempt to carry on
his legacy will be less effective now
this is from Richard Stallman what a
[ __ ] you know so anyway so Richard
Stallman made this statement so a that a
lot of time at that time a lot of free
software foundation members you know
meaning that people who donated you know
you donate you become a member they quit
you know they got angry because Richard
Stallman says it's a sleaze now there
are many aspect to it ok people become
angry partly because Steve Jobs just
died and they here they see this Richard
Stallman and they they went crazy you
know they they cannot tolerate this
behavior you know they so they quit you
know there are some angry posts on
Twitter or elsewhere they say you know
you know you know I'm tearing up my free
software foundation in the membership
you know so but to me you know a people
instead you know you you should not
change your opinion just because someone
is dead
ok I don't I'm you know as as you know
I'm a schizoid so I don't I don't have
much emotion you know emotional kind of
thing I don't have that thing I'm rather
like mr. data ok more logical code so
when Steve job ties and I see these
switches home and saying these things I
don't think it's wrong ok yeah because
you should not change your opinion just
because someone died is you know you
these people emotional people they are
like Oh at the moment someone tired you
shouldn't say it you know if you know
something like maybe until later then
you can say that that's that's that's
not
that's that's incorrect that's that's
not a good thing
that's the map invalid thinking you see
you know your opinion on someone should
not change just because someone just
died you know
so Richard Stallman said these things I
don't I don't mind but however in
general
Richard Stallman is just wrong you know
he is just he's he's this is his
ideology doing evil showing yeah I mean
if we if we want to ask my judgment of
Richard Stallman he is just first of all
he is very honest and to what he
believes you know that in that sense I'd
respect as opposed to a lot of this free
software open-source [ __ ] you know
on one hand they seen the song of open
source and free software but however
they work for Apple Google Facebook and
they own they own all the new Apple
computers toys these [ __ ] these are
these are the true hypocrites these
people are more evil than Richard
Stallman at least you know Richard
Stallman is someone I believe that he
you know he's just someone he went into
the wrong way like totally ignorant of
economics ignorant of reality you know
like ignorant of any practical issues he
only focus on this ideology you know
share basically that's a that's a bottom
line of communism that's what you know
but however he's rather so far as I know
honest guy you know because he you know
you he doesn't own any computers not
these days not even not even he doesn't
even use Linux because even Linux you
have lots of problems you know that lots
of political issues so you know in the
beginning he's for Debian Linux you know
it's strange when you look at you know
the history of things you know
in a beginning you have Debian Linux
which is very Pro you know free software
is sanctioned by Free Software
Foundation by Richard Stallman
but then they have Kouros you know they
have clothes they have arguments every
day about Oh documentation license you
know minor details they disagree they
fight you know this this this to me is
actually the reality the the human
nature you know you you fight for your
own your own political values well on
the whole you are just [ __ ] up
everyone else you know just look at the
Linux community you know Richard
Stallman with versus or the you know
Debian so in a beginning in a beginning
vicious storm and you know sanction
approved Debian you know he pushes fort
a being which you know it's this is good
we like you know I like it you know we
should
but then there's lots of chorus they
kicked you know order basically ordered
which all the Linux communities they
kicked out which has doorman because
they disagree on so many things you know
the minute
Soto did details on licensing and stuff
and to me okay to me that is that is the
reality of human nature of communism of
the sharing attitude because in reality
you don't share a [ __ ] you don't share
nothing oh you care is you you just want
to push your idea you your you know
whatever you like you know we should so
men or you know you guys you just want
to push whatever that that that is you
know benefit to you that's your your
opinion your color you know whatever
color you like that's what happens and
look at today so to me look at today
Microsoft you know Microsoft Google you
know Facebook they are all they are they
are they are the people who made
open-source popular in fact they are the
they are the main contributors of
open-source okay they it is they that
put money that made open-source survive
it is they and they and who are they
they have 1000 patent lawyers suing each
other [ __ ] this Google
book and and and you know Google
Facebook Apple Apple the [ __ ] Apple
100,000 patent suing each other every
day
and then you have you know these typical
many of my followers the open-source
chanting facts it's all it's all just
[ __ ] okay
so the so this is Richard Stallman this
is a story about Richard Stallman or
Steve Jobs death okay so that's one
story hold on a second let me copy that
to today's talk show so we're gonna
we're gonna log what we talked today so
copy that
so curse that then we have these UNIX
philosophy [ __ ] this happened in
- okay so so this so in 2011 Steve Jobs
died and this UNIX sky this unit sky was
his name Denise Ricci also died okay
then you have this mean you know that
went viral
like you know medium billions millions
of shares this this photo this picture
went viral it says you know becomes a
hipster sell stolen ideas Steve Jobs
traced by media as Jesus of computing
then on the other side you have inventor
invented C and UNIX Denis which II
ignored so this went viral you know all
this idiot in this UNIX philosophy you
know the Linux loving [ __ ] you know
they they love this they even on my
friends I've seen you know my friends
yeah post this share this you know what
what you know what are these people
thinking you know so they are saying
okay Steve Jobs you know he he is you
know not for free software he's just an
innovator okay and he died and he is
praised by you know he's on every media
like every publication you know
mainstream media praises him Oh Steve
job tag
but meanwhile the denis vici you know
the one of the founder of unix creator
of unix you know he died but there's not
much media attention
why do you know why what what about
Michael Michael Jackson when he died he
you know all the media is in these ten
times hundred times
you know publishing about Michael
Jackson's death more than Steve Jobs and
what about let me ask you this do you
know do you know what's the greatest
mathematician that died around 2011 do
you know like can you name one the UNIX
philosophy [ __ ]
they cannot name a single one okay let
me show you
Denise Ricci John McCarthy John McCarthy
also died in in what in what year around
2011 let's see what year 2011 indeed
John McCarthy the creator of lists
he also died in 2000 2011 but nobody
knows nobody knows okay what about
mathematicians they are quite a few
great mathematicians who died around
2011 if you consider their work that's
far more important than this [ __ ]
Denise Ricci okay so who are they for
example the fractal guy but the noid
Mandelbrot he died he died in in 2010
okay but not Mandelbrot the creator the
inventor of the fractal far more [ __ ]
important with respect to human history
then the [ __ ] Denis Richie the UNIX
guy okay who else Joe McCarthy Bernard
Mandelbrot disco disco DRA this guy is a
computer scientist okay he is a very
theoretical moral theory theoretical
computer scientist he died in 2002
buddy knows the [ __ ] UNIX philosophy
[ __ ] heads they don't know they don't
know about this guy who else let me show
you examples Harris Scott this
mathematician HSM coxster okay he's no
he is known by the abbreviation HSM
coxster he is the one of the great
geometers he died in 2003 he lived up
like 96 years old he you know many
mathematicians lives long so he died in
2003 no nobody nobody say the thing so
so I mean my point is my point is why
are these UNIX [ __ ] what made them
think you know what made them post this
and they think they are justified what
the [ __ ] is their mentality you know
thinking you guys can you guys defend
you know this UNIX philosophers what's
their problem you know
what's your problem incredible you know
to them you know you can see that they
post this you know meme viral you know
it went viral and you have a lot of
comments you can kind of tell okay so if
I were to guess their mindset it's like
they feel oh they feel so wronged you
know they feel like it's so wrong oh my
god Steve Jobs you know he didn't really
do something important to humanity
but everyone is talking about it like me
you know me more real about Steve Jobs
but but well then I love this guy you
nice guy but he died nobody knows oh my
god this is injustice the [ __ ] UNIX
philosophy [ __ ] so okay that's
about that okay that's my rant
you know that's my rant so technically
this would be classified as the subject
matter would be the programmers culture
okay this is a critters criticism of
programmer culture in particular UNIX
people culture
okay that's about that topic okay so so
Mendel brought he's an inventor of
fractal tremendous you know tremendous
this is a matter this is a creation in
science one of the great discovery in
science okay defacto you know to most
people when you think of factor you
think of pictures like this but that's
much deeper in I mean this is part of
mathematics okay this is chaos theory
and part of chaos theory complex
analysis and dynamical systems okay that
that's the topic okay fractals
so they meet time DUI dynamical systems
complex analysis and you know the end
and it has far-reaching consequences in
the study of fractal okay so he you know
and besides it's just visually
spectacular anyway that's one of the
great I probably won we won probably top
ten one of the top ten greatest
scientific discovery in this century
okay fractals far more important
critical than the UNIX [ __ ] the the UNIX
operating system [ __ ] and C programming
CD C language and this is the disco
disco chart
many of you especially lispers know he
is a computer scientist he usually
theoretical and he often likes to he
talks a lot and you know like control
many people like in today's today's
jargon today's you know you just you
just say he's a true ok these guys
this guy an HSM coxster he's a great
geometry and he studies usually things
like visual like polyhedron for the
polyhedron polytopes you know very pure
pure math pure and pure math and pure
geometry you know so usually a lot of
people like you know that you might like
his stuff HMS HSM coxster okay so he's a
one of the greatest mathematician okay
so that's about that okay then then some
other topics now I'm going to read ok
Steve Jobs now here's some of the photos
of Steve Jobs I took so this is 2000
2001 in Palo Alto you know about
Colorado is about 20 minutes drive where
from where I live you know this this
photo is actually taken back my friend
trying a nakamoto so you have Steve Jobs
here you know I'm right there you know
I'm right there and Steve Jobs talking
to another guy this is Apple parado when
Apple just opened the store so around
2010 that is when Apple started to open
stores Apple Store you know around
around USA and later around the world
Apple store and also this is when you
know people are thinking all the
frequent and war stores are closing down
you see so Steve Jobs is a innovator
because he sees differently like think
different you see around 2001 the
thinking is that you know the brick and
wall all the stores is gonna shut down
you know we have digital stores instead
like Amazon
but Steve Jobs think you know instead he
is gonna he's open in stores and that
turns out to be successful too you know
so he's you know he's a genius in in in
what he does so Steve Jobs the Palo Alto
apples Apple Store grand opening you
know more photo and this this is my
photo you know I I I took photo of him
he's talking he's talking Steve Jobs the
last time I saw him is around 2008 you
know I saw me on the street outside
outside of a conference some some Apple
you know a neo Apple conference and you
know I I was outside of it and I saw him
standing outside you know I I didn't say
hi this is so that's that's the last
time I saw him 2008 so you see these are
Emacs this are extremely popular back
then and also it was a innovation you
know Apple made this iMac computers okay
so that's photos of Steve Steve Jobs and
they're small and let me show you some
more okay so
so this is Steve Jobs just about few
months before he died this is Steve Jobs
oh this is Steve Jobs in 2007 you know
he looks he don't look he doesn't look
good
you know he's look he looks like that
let me pay it
so you know by by this time 2007 he is
pretty thing
he's already you know you know gaunt how
you say that quad can't
yes discard this Dijkstra is a guy who
said you know who made popular the Alico
go-to considered humph oh yeah Steve
Jobs anyway so okay let's close that
back to as I close that so you want to
change the world
okay let me read the comments and let's
see what people say comments comments
comments guys comments and how long
we've been talking about today so we've
been talking what
doesn't say what [ __ ] this is wrong I
need to go to okay so look at here 42
minutes
software-as-a-service okay and codeine
train whatever congratulations on your
first streamed troll fash bad s pas good
what is s pas Oh
SaaS nest and for software-as-a-service
and FA a and G stand for Facebook Apple
Amazon Netflix Google ok the fan ok the
fan of the evil flash bad s pas good so
what is s pas all these acronyms SP is
still not good web assembly is better
they are both bad I hope web assembly
never takes off may explain why there is
already enough blowed delivered through
my browser so what's your solution to
that Andrey says can you make a youtube
video about shut up no I cannot make a
video about p5.js I don't know what's
your issue p5.js so web dog says native
applications no electron either just
real programs I execute vo assembly
so sabatham you says you should make me
moderator okay well I could this hold
hold on second
Sophie oh just just ignore it okay guys
ignore it ignore is the best thing like
usually I don't like to ban stuff I mean
and Ray you know you have to say your
reason stop just repeating whatever you
know just sweep stop repeating yes
that's some library you know what's the
point
like what do you want me to do about
that I don't know that thing I don't
know I think so fire a fire ends up fire
hands up says IMS is an extremist yeah
feel they feel they read is the best
French operating system extremists what
is that
ok I don't know I'm just starting to get
into BSD ok
we've dog says I want to see you browse
canoes and give your thoughts on what
you see there that would be interesting
and the consequence would be I would be
swearing every minute yes I was born in
1968 correct SP a equals two single page
application okay okay bathroom is a
famous quote for 20 ignore is the best
thing okay what else guys so I think we
wasted today's talk I you know we talked
about Steve Jobs that's a you know
random chat and Richard Stallman that's
another day of framing the UNIX people
and the open source
it's you know it's old news I don't look
old well but you get old you know I am
you know your your your lots of things
went bad once you realize that beginning
in early 40s okay for example my for
example I'm 51 and I cannot see I cannot
focus you know it just happens like you
remember when you were a child your
grandma you know asked you to put a
threading a needle I do remember my
grandma asked me to do that when I was
like I don't know eight years old you
know but now I can I cannot see I cannot
see anything close and you know yeah it
happens yeah well you know it had it's
called aging it happens to everyone
you know besides beside your head going
bored you start to look ugly yeah that's
and that's eternal problem of humanity
everyone wishes to be young so anyway so
that's that anything else
so framing in ever wasted framing is
never never wasted okay so actually I
always I wanted to talk about some
coding stuff okay so I guess not today
hacker news let's go to hacker news okay
let's go to let me tell you some story
about hacker news okay that's gonna be
more swearing you know that's just be
more me swearing hacker news
sorry org and what is politics okay
and the idiocy of hacker keyboards you
know my site Mike you know my name now
and then went on to hacker news every
every two years or so some of my
articles went you know goes to hacker
knows about II about least my dis
aughtta goes oh my
MX Allah goes oh my MA
these are logos or my keyboard articles
or sometimes programming related
articles such as you know idioms in
stuff
you are happy you are still young yeah
that's good okay so how can you ask
Sally okay and what is politics you know
I don't use Haqqani hacker news because
I don't use hacker news I don't use
reddit well actually I do use reddit
like you know now and then now but when
it began in the first five years so 10
years of reddit I don't use it and you
know because I know you know latest
began around 2004 or something like that
the similar for hacker news because I
know from these forums online forums
that's near platform you know they they
are so purpose is to make money is to
squeeze money maybe now maybe maybe not
when this began but eventually you know
they just like Reddit and hacker news
today is all like it's all social
justice okay well anyway reddit you know
and all these platforms basically that's
their that's other people's stuff rather
what I want to do or you want to do is
to create your own websites so you have
opinion put you on your own website and
create a comment you know so people can
comment it that's discussion things like
hacker news reddit Stack Overflow you
know they oh they are in a way they are
all a lie okay what they what are they
about you know first of all they are
they are all from the open source they
are all like oh we are the open source
we are the people we you know we are the
programmers we are these so that we help
humanity [ __ ] you know but but in
reality they are just another
corporation okay and and as a
corporation in America ultimately what
they want is to make money and hold on a
second and ultimately this company do is
to you know in order to make money
eventually basically they
it conflicts with the idea of open
source and it conflicts with many ideas
of morality or ethics okay not not
always but in a sense okay
in particular they conflict with the
idea of open source or free software
okay so the you so you have you got this
Stack Overflow you got this you got
these hacker news you know let's go to
hacker news
you know let's see what day today I
never you know I actually never went to
howl canoes maybe not even once in a
year I the the times I went to hack a
news like front page is about maybe
maybe once every three years typically
whenever my name is mentioned or my
article is posted on a canoes I go there
okay but I almost never you know look
look at what what's hacker news except
sometimes I saw it on Twitter you know
when some some someone else shared it so
I never use hacker news and so yeah so
back to these companies how can you
stack overflow stack overflow including
github and also you know reddit they are
all just companies seen seeing you know
fake news yeah we are open source and so
on you know they get you to use them you
know and if you follow this news for
example they are there are so many
controversies about each of these
companies like you wouldn't know unless
you follow them I'm pretty sure some of
you know some of these like I'm pretty
sure some of you follow reddit all the
time you know even since they begin this
instance in the beginning some of you
follow hacker news you know since the
beginning or some of you follow you know
Stack Overflow or github or you know and
over the years over the past ten
by now 15 years you see many many
controversies like oh they did you know
some evil things they did you know but
pretty much all these news is that what
happened is that after you know after a
week nobody nobody remembers a thing you
know like but you you know only those
like you might remember all the things
happened but nobody nobody knows like
you cannot even start to write them out
because because it takes a lot of time
to you know you know to to dig out all
the information in the past and and or
unless you block all the time but even
if I if you blog such as I do you know
you know like for example I you know
it's it takes tremendous amount of time
to blog you know like usually I recalled
things like record of history of
whatever things I see for example
suppose I saw some controversy of hacker
news some extreme Evo let's say I saw
let's say there's a news that hacker
news sales or your data to all the
companies and there's proof
you know leaked memo leaked
documentation from program and things
like that suppose I see that I may not
blog it you know because even if I block
it I'll just say okay oh I saw this news
you know maybe there's a link you know
by by by panacea the link will be
conceived we've gone dead it's like no
use the you know if you really want to
plug it you have to spend one hour two
hours to get you know to to actually
archive in some sort of a way you know
to to explain what's going on okay he
you know usually these controversies
it's not easy it's not like one sentence
summary usually there's like this CEO
did this then it that happens then then
then you know who said what you know you
have to spend like days to dig out all
this information then you have to write
it out so it's not easy
it takes states to actually document one
incident so you know occasionally when I
see something you know I might just
write one sentence but that's not good
enough and even for each one sentence I
wrote about these companies you know
this controversy incidents there are ten
that I didn't blog because you don't you
don't have time you know you don't
follow each one you know you don't you
don't have time so so typically you know
it's like they say history the
population has no memory they say you
know there's a phrase the population has
no memory you know whatever Google did
bad people don't remember young people
don't know you know but you it's hard to
communicate you know to tell young
people like today if you tell young
people you know all the things you know
about reddit for example all the bad
things controversy you know they don't
believe you
like you use you need to say you know
you need to put post proofs and
explanations because otherwise you don't
know it's like it's like WikiLeaks you
know WikiLeaks they have produced
tremendous tons of documentation but but
do you know actually what's really going
on you don't know and you don't have
time to read WikiLeaks do you actually
go read what you know what
WikiLeaks actually found out no because
they they are in a form that's not even
readable to understand them you know you
need to know all the politicians what
you know you need to know other
politicians what's their role what's the
International thing you know you need to
know that otherwise it's like
meaningless to you oh you hear is that
oh someone did bad that that's you know
that's all you know and so that's that's
a problem so people don't know and you
know we got all fake news like fake news
spread on hacker news for example on
Hacker News you know all the idioms and
bad information misinformation about for
example I talked about yesterday about
currying about Mona
about lambda calculus is Lisa lambda
calculus you know they spread on hacker
news every day every day for the past 15
years this crap information idiotic you
know and why you know okay so for
example 784 points 300 points whatever
300 points 300 points okay why because
most people are not learned men okay
most people they are used and also most
of them are young people you know young
people you don't have nothing to do I
mean that's it is actually true for
young people you know you go to college
you don't as opposed to older people you
have a life you have family you need to
take care of you go to work you have
children you had you know you got things
to do you don't have time to go read
hacker news you know typically it's
younger people in college you know they
don't have nothing to do and in general
young people are less you know they
don't have the experience they don't
have knowledge comparatively speaking
that is true and and you know 10 years
older 10 years after today you will have
more experience you will know more than
what you know now you know everyone
grows older so 10 years will come to you
20 years will come to you and when you
think back Oh 10 years ago I don't know
I don't know nothing
but so most young people you know visit
hacker news and read it so young people
like when I was young you know you don't
know you just like oh oh you know for
example when I saw lambda you know
calculus oh yeah that's great article
about lambda calculus why because I
don't know nothing about lambda calculus
I don't know nothing about computer you
know theoretical computer science oh I
know it's like oh this is I heard on the
hacker news this is actually your you
know important thing lambda calculus Wow
is so cool you know I like it you know
the end but what I do not know is that
maybe that Arco is like bad quality you
know it's like you don't know what
you're talking about
you know so you use so in this
is the general situation of humanity it
is not it's not something you actually
can fix and it's not something it's not
necessarily a problem it's you see now
remember this is not necessarily like a
problem or a bug it's not it's just this
is the way life is you know young people
order and misinformation in in a world
like even before before internet you
know today we have internet the
communication technology you know if you
actually want to know the truth you can
find out if you spend time you can
actually find out about every article
you know every article you spend one
hour to actually you know I want you for
example let pick randomly pick one
article and spend one hour you know try
to find out what is true what is weather
you know like like spend one hour to
church like if you are going to if you
have a church and you are going to score
this article like 1 to 100 what score
you would give and you have to spend one
hour on it then you look you you know a
lot you learn a lot you know so so what
was I talking about you know so so
anyway so there is a lot oh yeah so I
was saying this is not necessarily a
problem or a bug you know because this
is just how things are and also consider
if you compare so today you know we have
internet and phones you know
communication technology is very
advanced so you can actually find out
truth about any of these articles or
about political articles for example
this one says this one says ok United
States Court of Appeals for the Ninth
Circuit
you know appeal from the United States
say something something something argued
something something what is they talking
about okay I don't know you have to
spend time to read it so he says it's
nice nice circuit holds that scraping a
public website does not violate the CFAA
okay anyway that's a that's that's a
political topic so today what I was
saying is that today with other
technology you can actually know the
truth if you spend enough time on any
issue maybe you know Trump something
Trump something social just is something
incident or Hong Kong people or China
this incident or Russia something
something oh me though is something
something you can actually know the
truth you just spent one day to do
research you can know you can actually
find out what you whatever is your
methodology you can find the truth
that's today but most people you know
you don't you don't you know because
most of you are you got other things to
do you gotta go play games you gotta go
you know to programming and stuff that's
why misinformation
misinformation spread but even before
internet technology before the Internet
let's say 20 years ago misinformation
also spread you know but they kind of
they spread slower it's much slower than
today and in fact in a sense that's
actually better than today because in
some sense you know I'm not sure which
is actually was because before when you
do not have you know this internet
communication technology when there is
an information well this TV ok TV is the
main source of misinformation
you know propaganda but you know things
do not spread quickly so if you don't
watch TV you know you cannot easily
spread misinformation back then so
information doesn't spread quickly
doesn't matter is good information or
bad doesn't
read quickly so it tends to be local
localized you know it's just regional
localized but now with communication
technology you can know so much you can
know like you are bombarded with
information but the thing is most people
do not really care about truth they just
you know they sit they sit you know at
home they read Twitter they just they
hear what they like to hear you know
like oh UNIX or UNIX is great oh you
know Denise which she died and the Steve
Jobs is bad you know oh yeah that's
great you know then you don't do not
research that that's it use you you'll
be treated you know Steve job died oh
but but Denise vici you know the UNIX
founder died nobody knows that so that's
injustice you just retreated it you
shared so that's how many information
spread you don't spend the time even
today you can know the truth you can
think but you don't so I think Engle I
think you know today the situation maybe
was you know I don't know actually is
worse or better actually maybe worse
okay so anyway that's that's about my
take on these corporations you know and
also you know what is hacker news about
hacker news you know as you know it
started by Paul Graham the Y Combinator
by the way this page is written this
hack annuity is returning och list
och Lisp it's a new lease language
invented by Paul Graham okay which
nobody uses except you know a few
handful of people so this is written in
a crisp so that's that's something
interesting with respect to tech and
also hacker news the hacker news page is
if you look at let me show you the okay
so today actually let me show you the
source code
more tools okay
developer tools I want to show you the
source code okay
it used to be control you or command you
to show the source code but now you know
things changed that command is no longer
one second okay view source okay so if
you look at the source code of hacking
news
oh they improved okay so they improved
okay let's copy the whole page copy it
wait this is this is what year this is
2016 so open open a new buffer paste it
save it xx dot HTML and and let's look
at the code okay yeah so if you look at
the hacker news source code you can see
this is like 1990 this is HTML 1999 okay
hacker news is still using HTML like
1999 well they actually improved a lot
you see font you see this font tag
that's 1999 HTML they actually improved
a lot so this page we are looking at is
from nineteen from 2006
so they actually started to use spam you
see spam in class class you know class
so spam head so those are you know CSS
but so this is so sometimes before 2016
they did some improvement but still
still you can see the font tag before
that you know before 2016 sometimes
before it's all found hot tag you know
every everything is font font family
font size on every element and also the
whole page is a table let's see
you see you see this TR let me show you
you see this TR t is a row TD is a
column sale and table you see the whole
page is a table and that is 1999 style
of HTML so hacker news you know they
program I suppose originally this is
this is written by program so they are
still like from 1999 for example image
sorry hacker news HTML okay I documented
so here this page this page and this
page let me open that so HTML style 1999
hacker news so this I wrote in 2003 so
you can see in 2003 they our page is
still very you know very 1999 they don't
use they don't use class they don't use
CSS class you see they are they are cell
using style or inline styles no class so
this is back in 2003
so between 2003 and 2006 teen they they
they improved and you know poor granham
program is website they are still using
image maps this is quite funny image
maps that's you know this is again mm
you know 1999 HTML tag anyway
let's see what is this hacker news
traffic effect okay anyway so what else
guys any any any other comments
so yeah web dog says I remember image
maps medium - yeah medium you know
medium is quite funny because medium
began medium began around 2006 was it
2006 2005 medium you see
by 2005 blogging is or dead you know
there's no more blogging but over sudden
you know medium becomes very popular I
was quite surprised you know so I look
into you know my blogging has been dead
for many years well for a decade you
know nobody is blogging anymore
but all of a sudden around 2016 or 2015
or was it 2017 I've I forgot medium
becomes very popular and it's you know
it's it's a blog basically a blogging
platform you know I was so I was quite
surprised so I looked into it turns out
you know medium became popular because
the people who created medium are from
the same people who created Twitter they
are these type of people so called CBO's
see with CBO and entrepreneurs okay that
that's kind of their jargon you know
meaning that they just do startups one
afternoon another you know they they are
you know they are so rich you know this
is there becomes their thing you know
they just do stop but startups every few
years they just do you know lots of
startups so so they are from they are by
the people you know one or two guys from
the Twitter who originally did the
treatise so they have connection you
know they have connection they have you
know connection to Twitter and all the
money and they don't you know what to do
so that's how medium became popular and
media is one of the evo you know crap
they they have they track they track
your you know when when you pause and
they do everything they do is nasty
things and also medium is very strongly
social justice affiliated very strongly
like I remember I you know
usually when this side come up often I
go and login you know I create account
just to look at them you know see what
they are like so I I noticed medium when
you're logging is all social justice
articles like Oh women this that oh you
know this that heavily social justice
inclined anything else guys so we've
been talking for one hour and seventy
five minutes so I don't know if it's
good or bad it's like random chat and
rant about companies I you know I'm not
sure about that because I've had I
rather do coding and you know something
more something more solid you know
things like that
close that copy that close it back to
Emacs pace it link of I showing browser
back to chrome close it hecka news close
this source code go back here so this is
one of my article
hacker news the idiocy of hacker
keyboards indeed so that's about
keyboard I'm not sure we want to talk
about that if you want if you guys want
me to you know just say it you you
comment you have to come and then we
talk about that I think that we're gonna
shut down in five minutes
yeah we should because it's already like
80 minutes so bathroom you says I
created an account our medium in the
beginning when it came out
then I logged in lockdown never logging
again yeah I still as you have a medium
I never post let's see sorry medium
okay media McSally and see if I can find
that there it is okay
did i ever post something media McSally
you know there's another thing let's
talk about that okay there is another
thing you see you see this sign sign
into medium with google this [ __ ] this
open source comes open source and free
software foundation scumbags hypocrites
let me tell you the story about logging
okay now in the 1990s to to to early
2000s you have log in each website has a
log in starting beginning with slash
start now stashed at is the oldest
website for online discussion forums
slash dot it's kind of a news news
aggregate you know they post news like
king or twenty news every day and you
can comment on it kind of like Reddit
and hacker news okay Cerreta slash Todd
is the oldest backing it begin 1999 I
think and four four four one year I was
reading slash dot every day / start is
the maker of the UNIX the UNIX fan okay
every every day the UNIX people they
loved it slash that and anti Microsoft
but you know now it's twenty years you
know the owner changed hand though or
even though original coders they they
did they move down and then they move
down like five to ten years ago long ago
the you know commander taco and you know
three guys two or three guys they moved
on and the company has changed owners
several times so it's you know it's just
the business it's a commercial you know
behind you have the big boss with PDS or
millions of money dollars they cooking
these things you know you don't know you
know you don't know who is running it
you you you as a nerd as a geek as a
geek you are just a small guy you know
thinking oh this is great side you know
things like that the same thing with
hacker news hacker news and read it you
know you don't know who is running
behind it's things like that that's why
I don't support and never like any of
these you know you want you want power
to the people you know like like the
free software idea or open source idea
power to the people not the corporations
all these corporations they are just
they are just a facade they are just a
front end of face they are just selling
they are just there to make money that
is all day two and the Richard Stallman
today what'd he do well he's not here to
make money but rather he's here to sell
his ideology he don't really actually
care about the real goodness of society
you don't care
he only care about he he sell his
ideology that he see the ideology
becomes successful that's what he cares
Richard Stallman and same thing with the
open source phonetics you know you don't
really care about whether something is
good for the people you know all the
people in the world you just care that
open source succeeds because that's your
you know religion so anyways slash start
so what was I going to talk about yeah I
was talking about the login system like
I'm going to give you a glimpse a survey
of the login system in the past 20 years
okay so in 1999 you have yes you begin
to have a login system you know you have
a website people can log in and and by
the way login system is kind of like
it's rather is kind of the thing that
has to do with commercialization
because once you have a la login that's
one of the way to make more money and
it's also one of way to keep keep your
audience you know keep your website
popular one of the way to make your
website very popular and and also
eventually it's one of a way to gather
user data to sell sell sell the data
like Google Facebook Twitter they are
doing so login system first first of all
it's you know this the very idea of
login you go to a website you have to
log in it's actually tied to making
money okay Patri okay not not all but
but it has a lot to do with making money
growing your site you know marketing
things like that it has less to do with
with it has less to do with benefiting
your users well for for webstore like
Amazon then it's necessary you know when
you have a web store it's a nice it's
kind of it's necessary okay so so we are
talking about login system okay so in
general in 1999 you have login system
now as time goes by after five years in
mean let's say 2005 2005 to 2010 there
is a problem you have so many websites
you know the web you know the internet
grows and grow you know it's like almost
exponentially so basically now each
person you go to the Internet you have
10 20 websites you have to remember the
login key you know each one you need a
login and password so that becomes a
problem and there are many solutions to
other years one solution is basically
the browser or the operating system like
a Mac they provide a master key password
database so basically like on a Mac for
example you log in one time using your
Mac password then
you have a database that stores all the
password and login for all the website
you visit so that's one way to solve it
okay that's you know with since Apple
Apple I think Apple is the first one to
do that then Microsoft also do that
Linux also do that okay that's one way
another way in the is browser
you know browsers also start to do that
I forgot which one came first but anyway
browser same idea for example if I use
Google Chrome Google Chrome has a master
password database you know so it
remembers all the website you visit the
login and password they can remember so
you only remember one login for Google
browser you know so you know that's
Google is Google does that ok so that's
one solution OS or browser but but then
the web developers they begin to realize
the idea called open ID okay you guys
remember that open ID
basically it's dead
okay it's a dead technology you see that
logo so open ID came along the idea is
that okay you know we want to we need to
solve the problem where each person has
to remember tens of passwords so they
they created this open ID the idea is
you know everyone can use one single
password and log in password just one
single login password pair for all sites
and basically for the so if you the
website you can implement open ID so I
think this is a distributed system
decentralized yes so basically all the
website they will use of an ID so
so anyway so open ID is kind of the
solution you know it's a solution cooked
up by a open source fence or free
software fence though they may cooked up
with this system so you only each user
only remember one pair of login password
but each website can implement you know
use the opens ID system so they are
distributed so that so it works you know
so one one password for all websites so
that's a beginning but it failed
basically it failed after you know for
for for a year or two for three years it
became very popular but it failed so
open IDs is like one chapter of the log
in thing on the web now there's another
thing another thing they meet you know
at the at one point when open ID was you
know was everywhere popular you know or
the program was like fashionable like
like on Hacker News and reddit they talk
about all day like you see oh oh you
know oh new system of an ID distributed
Oh everyone is like 1,000 points you
know 3 3 million points the [ __ ]
programmers it's so is so just anyway
that's the idea of opens ID the idea is
not bad ok you know but what people
don't realize is usually there are a lot
things behind it you know for example
the old open ID organization these
standard suppose the standard
organizations typically they are not
they are not you know the ideal good
people they don't you know they don't
want no money they just want to for the
good of society that's not true ok
usually when you look into things then
you realize you know the people who
created this standard you know the open
ID or whatever yeah usually ok often
this is a case you you start to find
that they they are just greedy you know
they have this stand
they want to do all things possible so
that they can squeeze money out of it
that that is basically what's going on
with all these open-source [ __ ]
but anyway so open or open idea tired
but back back then you can see you know
oh you know Google says you know Google
is a board member
yeah yeah there you go board members you
have to pay you have to pay to be a
board member
probably okay I'm not I'm not sure about
details I'm talking about general you
can always look into the details
yourself anyway you so you have board
name members corporate board members
Google Microsoft Oracle yeah the big
companies Symantec is evil they're doing
Symantec they they do fake certificates
fake it you know h ssl certificates you
know the google they are fighting with
Google because Google was plain plain
plain mean semantics they they check out
fake certificates because you know bad
guys or government pay them you know
Symantec they are doing fake fake
certificates VMware Verizon you know
these giants anyway so open ID failed
but anyway another P so open ID is one
chapter of the online login then there's
another thing which is which is you see
here our medium you see it says sign
into medium.com using Google with Google
okay so what so this idea is that most
people most vast majority people you
have you already have a Google account
or Facebook account you know with this
big online companies so the idea is that
you can so Google and Facebook they
create a system similar similar to open
ID
except it's not distributed you know
it's just their own so Google create a
system so that Google made their login
you know their password login system
so that you know they made the API so
that other website can use it so for
example if I burn medium you know I need
the password logging I can I can make it
so that I can use Google's API so users
can just log in with Google Google's you
know login so that's the thing you know
so that's you know Google does side of
course it gives more power to Google you
know whoever has more you know logging
users basically you got you have more
power so everyone wants that so Google
wants is doing that Google encourages
all the website other website to use you
know their login system and Facebook you
know wants to grow their you know
popularity so Facebook has their own you
know logging with Facebook and you also
I think you also have logging with
Twitter I'm not sure but anyway that's a
story okay but there is a tryst after
you know this is bad enough
well it's I want it so bad or not it's
you can judge that okay but then later
on there's a trade tryst okay after a
few years of these then today's website
you know like today you if you go to
some website you you will see I'm not
sure that's the case with medium but you
will see this you know signing with
Google okay so suppose you type in your
Google account login password okay you
signed in but but after that they they
still ask you they still ask you to
create a new account name and password
for their website you see so this is
like this is like scum you know so so
why are you asking me for my Google
account has over anymore you see so the
point here so the situation is that they
ask you to type your Google account name
and password not for the purpose of
you know making you using one account
you know convenience convenience to the
users no that's in our case because
after that after they asked that they
they asked you to create a username and
password to sign into the account you
see so so why are they asking who your
Google name and password because that
way they are gathering extra information
so they are they may not only require
you to create an account for their
website they only they also have extra
information they now know your Google's
you know password and you know login so
they can connect you know data and sell
more information this [ __ ] this
extremely [ __ ] oh this the older
open-source [ __ ] you know all this
website math as much but majority of
them like they have a code of conduct we
are good for the you know we are we
respect our users privacy [ __ ] and and
one particular website I remember doing
this is is the picture website for women
you know the printer Pinterest okay I
remember that Pinterest all the way up
said are doing that you know like if you
are a programmer like me then you know
but most people don't know like more
average fewer people they don't know
nothing about programming you know they
just they see this website oh I like I
like Pinterest you know I like to see
all these pictures so they log in they
see they Co type yo Google so they type
it you know password an account and they
say they see oh oh oh you need to create
an account then just they just type it
you know they don't know nothing but if
you are programmer you guys know just as
I do you know this why are they doing
that because they are becoming so evil
this sucks
hey good money Justine okay so actually
we are about to end yeah that's the end
of it actually so today's whole talk is
basically event okay so let me write
down write down just what we just talked
about the last item open ID and and
Google login open ID and using Google
login and a short account of the history
of web login okay so today we talked
about this other topic we talked about
is basically or rent
it's like random chat so Richard
Stallman and on Steve Jobs death death
death of Steve Jobs and Dennis Ritchie
and and John McAfee and and
mathematicians okay my personal photos
of Steve Jobs and we talked about hacker
news reddit how evil they are we talked
about hacker news traffic effect oh that
when we didn't talk about so that
actually that one is not too important
then we talked about open ID Google
login and a short account of the history
of web login basically it's all today's
talk like how long we've been talking 90
minutes is or rent organist again is
these corporations and again is open
source and free software foundation
ideology okay so that's it for today
thank you guys for watching so anything
else comment we shouldn't we shut down
in one minute google has a hash for
every person in the world yeah you bet I
mean not just that you Google has your
entire your entire life story including
your photos your you know like when did
you
your wife in their database and you know
even if you did even if you didn't take
take selfies of that they know they can
guess they can guess fairly accurately
if you use Google services so sqrl so
what is sqi secure and quick reliable
Auggie I don't trust those you know a
lot of you geeks
you know you probably say you know like
come up with technical solutions like oh
something new distributed and and
cryptographic you know encrypted so this
sqrl is secure quick reliable login is a
draft open source standard for secure
web login I don't think you go it will
walk you know all this if the problem is
not technology okay you know most most
you know people in Silicon Valley they
they are programmer idiots you know
basically programmers don't know nothing
about actual how the world works but
they think they do they think they are
the engineer they think they see the
world you know as mathematics they think
they know so much they think we are
going to have a utopia you know today's
all these bad situations we talk about
where they came from they came from
programmers basically they came from
these tech heads you know programmers
think they know I think programmers are
the worst so you know programmer
solution you always have you know oh you
know we're gonna have new distributed
system distributed system or in quick
cryptocurrency or whatever is gonna
solve the problem no it's not so we are
doing this for the past 20 years all the
notes all the notes even before me okay
well you know you know are chanting
these kind of things we've been doing
this for 20 years it's going nowhere and
in fact it's going Wars so what is the
solution the solution is
not about new you know spy versus spy
okay so let me show you this article
actually there is a lock Oh Haqqani oh
sorry okay and what is politics and you
know it's like spy versus spy there it
is
you know that's that's the technique oh
that's not solution to to the spammers -
you know it's like I'm gonna create some
new technology that's gonna thought you
and the bad guy is gonna create new some
new other technology that's gonna
reverse trap you you know that's spy
versus spy you know like the spammers
then then the geek the Nerds have you
know theaters cue fire you know this
although the the [ __ ] the from
program the program hand [ __ ] idiot
there's a statistical turn and stated
statistical term for fioating email spam
what's the name that like there's a
state jargon up from Statistics it's a
search for email okay
you know Paul Graham for a period of
time for one for one year so he's like
he is champion champion II this email
spam filter he just wrote like you know
there's a jargon some statistical chaga
anyone remember
so anyway program a typical program
nerds so you you know underground you're
all 4chan type of people their reaction
is that Oh we're gonna use
cryptocurrency we're gonna use we're
gonna create distributed system that's
you know that's been going on for twenty
years and where are you you are still
you are becoming niche and more niche
and Google and Facebook and Microsoft
they are become me more and more
powerful look at like today we talked
about Microsoft example they are now the
great more actually I you know two years
ago I checked they are actually bigger
than Google in terms of I think in terms
of net income or revenue Microsoft okay
although you don't hear it much you know
you cannot just search things from what
you hear on Hacker News I mean if you
really want to know you mean I looked
you know you gotta be heavy at PD I look
at their net income or or that the the
the gross income you know all the money
transaction I think two years ago I
checked Microsoft is still bigger than
Google even though we tend to think
Google is bigger you know anyway so you
see look look at what happened today
after 20 years
Microsoft is even bigger than bigger far
more bigger and then you have a Google
doing censorship all that censorship and
they are all social justice [ __ ] they
are on our social justice and now you
have code of conduct which is a kind of
a political documentation so that they
can they can you know they can hit you
anytime they want whenever you know they
don't like you they can pick you up and
erase you that's what the code Conduct
is about so that's what happens to to
the society and then gende and you guys
open so schmuck open source every day
well you know I have my I have lots of
friends not you know not not just you
guys but generally you know because I
mean open source Oh
basically most or vast majority of my
followers you know they asked your
chanting open source it it'll free
software you know they chanting about it
every day
it's like democracy you know to the
point today you really don't know what
it means anymore it's just a chant
democracy democracy yeah oh we must have
democracy we must have open source you
don't know what it means anymore so what
is the solution so the solution is you
want to you want to get people to think
you know like Bertrand Russell and many
great philosophers philosophers has said
about this you want the people to
actually think about things
Oh in other words awareness or education
okay
education awareness or thinking you know
you want two people to be free thinkers
to think about things and that you know
that seems to be going away you know is
you know in the past ten years or so
it's going away yeah exactly
code so just in say it's code of conduct
means you can exclude people you don't
like oh you don't like the politics or
religion code conduct code of conduct is
extremely evil okay I have so many I
have a last story to tell because I've
looked into many you know they they are
people you know like I mentioned before
you know if I talked about this this is
gonna be a topic about social justice
scan they are so much evil because there
are people you know the whole thing the
entirety of social justice movement they
are philosophy I mentioned these people
the entirety I've studied this for for
the past in the past four years I spent
about one hour studying in detail
academia in academia in philosophy in
post-modernism you know I looked their
engine and also people the social just
just is people on Twitter you know
elsewhere I look at you know what they
do you know I've been studying these
small-ass for the past four years they
are they are just extremely evil ok
without going detailed into detail
that's what I say but but that topic is
itself is gonna be ours and code of
conduct is just any anyway it's just
extreme evil ok it it's extreme evil is
not descriptive enough because that's so
general what do you mean extremely evil
the code of conduct is a kind of a kind
of a weapon okay you know like today you
say weaponized something you know you
weapon you know today people say
weaponized
weaponized sex for example weaponized
gun control issues weaponized you know
abortion issues you know that's what
they say yeah that's a term but code of
conduct so yeah indeed it's kind of a
it's just a weapon you know I don't like
to use that phrase because that's kind
of like it's it's just it's just a
method it's a method specifically
created by certain very intentionally
evil person not not innocently you know
people like you know people who simply
believed in something and turns out they
are wrong not those I you know it's it's
by certain people who are intentionally
trying to do bad trying to make themself
more powerful they created code of
conduct okay it's very exact code count
of conduct you know you look into you
know the lay of formation
you know why they create such you know
document document and not just the
writing style I'm not talking about just
writing style I mean even more more
fundamental that so what I'm saying is
that code of conduct is the document
that is intentionally intentionally
created by by bad people okay by
intentionally bad people so that they
became become more powerful it was a
weapon some kind of a system so that
they can they can they can you know they
can damage you know put you in jail or
fire you things like that any people
they don't like that's that's my opinion
about code of conduct you know that's a
big topic I can go I can go on for one
hour about that with you know with
stories and websites and details and the
person there's one specific person a
girl a woman who created that code of
conduct there's one specific person okay
and I can talk I can get I can tell you
her history you know you can look at
what she has done
it's a [ __ ]
yes okay those people I mean you you
look at their history you know they are
not you know they have a history of bad
things okay that that's it for today
thank you guys for watching that's
that's like 100 minutes of rent almost
two two hours of rent okay 30 minutes
I'm gonna shut in down 30 minutes in 30
minutes just live in the woods live in
the woods yeah
yes that's what I mean
Skeeter Skeeter Skeeter cell but I don't
want to post that whatever you wrote
because Google is going to censor me you
know anyway bye guys