good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi o 2019 December 13th
today is the last day not the last day
the day before last state to year 2020
and right now it's Monday December 30 3
o clock 37 minutes
San Francisco time hey but hey jet wha
and we have a lot people here so but and
greetings Bart and Holden mcgroin
Shinyoung quello Xin nian kuai la la
casa o Shang oh my god that's Chinese we
got a Chinese guy from wave form are you
in China oh you and all these idols oh
I'm either I am a giant I'm a I'm a God
for Grandma je dois good morning
greetings from Peru je dois from Peru
okay and hey Matt to Germany people over
the globe so so today today I don't good
morning ten good morning George
good morning Hold'em a growing okay
Bonjour Bonjour is in France fantastic
bon soir in France so I don't have a
topic today and I'm just going to go
random okay so you know go random and if
you guys have a question post it okay
ask me questions
I wasn't sure I'm going to do a live
video because you know in a pin yeah I
don't have a topic but you know as as
they say the the spice must flow you
know you when you do something you have
to just to keep
doing it like when they practice kungfu
they say if you stop in a day if you
stop in a few days you become you don't
do good you don't do good okay I told
you a topic what topic parts topic what
spots topic you your New Year's
resolution
I don't have a new year resolution okay
my resolution is to [ __ ] a blonde since
10 years ago and I don't think I ever
did what I did but not in a way I like
okay so I don't have a New Year's
resolution I never had that I don't have
a plan I don't have a I'm a man without
a plan
I don't follow those New Year's
resolution what resolution resolution my
ass you know you look at Tigers you know
you look at the lions tigers skunks dogs
cats do they have a New Year's
resolution so you don't want to do you
want to get better you get better just
by getting better you don't have to you
don't need a new year resolution you
need you don't need oh this holiday oh
this is today's International Women's
Day Oh today is internationals
gay day or today's was something Martin
Luther King Day or today's president day
your president is not my present no you
know today's Chairman Mao's day
what a [ __ ] as a human animal as an
animal you just leave well there's some
cultural you know this president day and
or this day or day this day that you
know okay that's good Christmas and you
know that's good but I don't have a
resolution okay I don't have a New
Year's resolution
I could do you know it's it's you could
do one if you want to
but you see the thing my problem is you
know today the modern society the the
Horde of people the you are you you have
become automatons you just follow you
you you you know you don't have a brain
you just follow the trend you you you
were born you get on the train you get
married you have a kid you die something
like that okay
New Year's resolution I don't have a
resolution Queen Chad Queen ahead
good morning to array big something like
that a wrap so bar says you always say
you are so poor why not want to get more
money that's not you see each of us are
in certain condition if we may say that
and that condition is not something you
can change if you just want a resolution
you know so but why don't you become a
mathematician like me you know why don't
you I have talked about videos about
math how come you are not learning it
you know you need a new New Year's
resolution be like me so each of us or
some of us actually most of us have
certain conditions or things or whatever
is you know some things you may want to
change and sometimes and usually it's
not just oh just just buy this book okay
twelve rules to change your life then
you're gonna change your life you are
not going to change your life okay and
and and also what do you want to change
it you know lots of these kind of
questions but anyway so for those of you
who wish to change certain aspect of
your life yes you can you can try and
they are of course there are a lot of
self-help books you know how to you know
like ten rules of successful people ten
six habit of successful people [ __ ]
[ __ ] my ass you know they do you have
turns of those books they make money
half of them majority of them are
crackpots okay anyway so there there are
some good books for example let me show
you an example Bertrand Russell Bertrand
Russell okay let's go to Amazon so you
can buy my stuff the the stuff I post
and you can buy so we go to Amazon and
it's type Bertrand Russell my favorite
philosopher logician okay my my most
respected person in my life
Bertrand Russell happy what is happiness
okay I can tell you what is happiness
okay so Bertrand Russell has wrote a few
books about hacked happiness okay there
it is
the conquest of happiness you know this
this topic by the way is a mundane topic
because you will find a thousand books
that tells you how to be happy oh
self-help these are self-help books okay
so how to be how happy the conquest of
happiness I can tell you how ok you go
to see your doctor ok now in America in
typical modern life you know America you
know they say oh you go to visit your
doctor what doctor I don't have a doctor
where do I go to see a doctor but you
may have a doctor your your home
physicians or whatever the typical
American life you know they say ok so
you go visit your doctor you tell him
hey Doc I want to be happy please cut
off my drain then they will do a surgery
you will be lobotomised or something
then you will be happy you see that is
the sure certain absolute physical
biological way to be happy you cut off
your brain the parts that make you
unhappy
and you'll be happy happy for good for
life forever you can become a veggie if
you want to that is happiness
ok so so what is happiness that
that is one that's that's a sure way for
happiness okay so you can do that
oh so anyway so this Bertrand Russell
book you know how the conquest of
happiness I think I read it like in
1990s 1990s I read a lot Bertrand
Russell's writings and I've read I've
read all these self-help books like my
deficiencies how to overcome my sorry
personal deficiencies so you can go find
books about how to be happy you can go
find books about how to make friends you
can go find books about how to you know
the successful people you know six
habits of successful people how to be
influential how to make many you know a
bunch of them and by the way majority of
them are crack crackpots okay so so what
is my point okay so here's one thing I
want to say one of the things you know
so if you have a problem in life you
know many of us always have some
problems you you can improve it yes you
can for sure almost always you can but
but but it's not going to be like like
if you really buy a book or something
then you can do it okay and the question
also gets complex for example a lot of
you guys I know now you see I'm a very
healthy person you see I'm um my weight
is perfect my everything my health is
reasonably what good but I know many of
you guys you know suffering from fat
being fat fat fat okay fat person and
you trying to lose weight you know in
America every day so I would tire this
tire like that you know diet this stores
you know paleontology [ __ ] you know this
ultra-slim [ __ ] and whatever weight loss
[ __ ] you know the
thousands start that diet everyday diet
descend so you want to wait lose weight
you know and then oh my god I lost my
point like I'm wondering about
overweight so you know so what I'm
saying is that what is my point
well I since I started to talk about
losing weight I forgot what's my point I
mean the so anyway I'm what I'm saying
is that you can you can do things to
improve yourself but meanwhile you might
wonder why do you want to improve in the
first place I mean what what is the
issue
why can't you be just the way you are
you'll be happy you see modern society
have increased you know a lot of
depression and those kind of things and
also media modern media you know the for
example girls they want to be beautiful
they the [ __ ] car dashians every day
with their ass and tits showing on TV
meanwhile you have this feminist [ __ ]
they are saying oh girls you know you
need to go to into a stem stem [ __ ]
my ass stem science technology
engineering and math [ __ ] idiotic
jargon you know these are chuggins these
are chuggins of our code they create
this jargon so it removes thinking they
created this word stem so meanwhile you
have the diss feminists and these social
justice [ __ ] they are saying oh you
need to oh girl so you need to study you
know you need to study math no you don't
need to the first thing you want to do
if you want more girls in technology in
programming you get rid of kink - iam ok
that Kim Kardashian [ __ ] and get rid of
the cosmopolitan [ __ ] Cosmo girls ok
cosmopolitan let's have look ok
digression and into all sort of
different political topics probably
offending a lot of people now so
cosmopolitan ok so let's say I want to
show pictures ok copy add a new browser
paste it and show cosmopolitan it's show
pictures you see so
you want girls to be in programming and
stuff you get rid of this [ __ ] okay it
is these that creates a lot of problems
okay this is this thing and Kim
Kardashian oh and all the Hollywood
[ __ ] you know with their you know tits
and ass showing every day and meanwhile
they are saying oh oh rape rape rape
rape rape everyday Jesus okay so that
that is a digression into the realm of
social justice things so what is our
topic you know I was going to talk about
something you know improve yourself what
else
okay so let's see general so join this
chord changes chords
oh by the way so happy new years happy
new years you know year to year 2020 on
the corner and I'm here [ __ ] this in
that okay so let me read the comments
okay
George says your website has scores for
2020 no I don't have a go over 2020 i
they are something i want to do in my
life like I'm getting old 50 I cannot
you know let me tell you about chess
okay
sorry dot info you go to Sally dot info
and there it is a interactive chest app
I didn't write it but I grabbed it
because this is open source so you can
play chess so I'm pretty good not too
bad but not in any you know chess
phonetic level and when you know this
race you play with computer you lose
most of the time anyway so you see
you've a chess and when I was younger
when I was like 13 or so I can't
remember every move from the beginning
to end game it's just like I don't have
to put effort is just memorized okay and
now today I cannot memorize the current
position you see so I'm getting old I
cannot even remember memorize the
current position so my years are not
many
down the road and also consider my
situation so there is something I want
to learn you know the mathematics the
proof systems proof theory and God so
I'm kind of rambling all over the place
so let me read the comments so you
always say you are so poor why not want
to make more money yeah okay so so that
is a comment we began the digression so
each of us have some issues or problems
or something we want to change and it's
not something you can just change like
that
okay and new year's resolution they
she don't walk okay the new year
resolution beak is mostly it's it's a
modern society just a fad okay just
something you repeat every year new
year's resolution
Houghton says do you like Haskell no I
don't like Haskell okay I talked about
that a few times Haskell is not bad it's
there is my video there's a video I
talked about what language is to learn
so you go to my YouTube you can find it
I talked about which language to learn
quite a few times okay so in Haskell is
not the language I recommend I recommend
okay moe
okay you guys go learn or camel o camel
camel Julia Golan okay googling colon
colon is the most practical okay master
it not just not just you know stop
taking stops stop you know obsessive
being obsessive about which is the best
language colon colon something practical
and make an app like like the Mark
Zuckerberg [ __ ] you know make a
Facebook do something useful okay not
the Emacs [ __ ] Emacs forever like me
so any self-help books you recommend
well I know a few but any self-help book
I recommend not really I don't recommend
these self-help books okay if you need
to read those book you are not going to
it's likely chances are you are not
going to be self helping at all okay for
those of you who really want to
self-help you already done it without
needing a book that's my that's kind of
my general opinion on that okay yeah
it's funny I mean it's you're useful
sometimes
you know but you know the the the your
mindset must be correct okay you don't
go by self books because oh I need to
fix this thing oh yeah there's this self
book people say it's so great they have
it you know you change their life then
you go buy it no that's wrong
that's a wrong wrong mindset you already
you already fail you are a failure
already okay that book will not change
you will not help you but rather you you
know self book a self self-help book
what the [ __ ] is that what what what
kind of who created that category
self-help book it's it's a concept of
modern society you know you you you you
go ask a cat you have a cat right you
have a pet modern society we loners lots
of us has cats and dogs
oh but you love them you know cats and
dogs but you don't love your human
neighbors but you do love your cats so
you have cats oh you you know you ask
who ask your cat what what what what is
her self help what does she so Holden
says what's your plan to learn in math
or computer science yeah I have a few
goals I can tell you okay I have article
on that I want to learn complex analysis
okay in math these are not tons of
things I want to learn in math but let's
be practical okay complex analysis
that's one thing I want to learn okay
okay let me show you my website then
sorry math and I talked about this a few
times I've done a few tutorials on
complex numbers and and the branches of
mathematics okay and I've done you know
these complex analysis so what I want to
learn
I wished to know before I'm dead is or
before I'm capable of doing any of these
at all
five more years you know is complex
analysis I like to know okay a math
textbooks
okay complex analysis this book ok this
book you go and buy it like go and buy
it by now visual complex analysis ok I
like to know this subject I got this
book in the 1990s I never finished
reading a never finished reading it well
however I learned programming all by
myself
nobody with nobody else I don't provide
me all by myself anyway so this book so
I like to know more complex analysis ok
and I like to know more differential
geometry ok complex analysis
differential geometry and I like to know
learn about proof theory now proof
theory is related to type theory logic
mathematical logic and homotopy type
theory you know that's a hard word that
that's a buzz word homotopy type theory
and uni valent
mathematics you know the foundation of
math so that that's the few areas I like
to learn math ok so that that is about
that doesn't it
ok so differential geometry complex
analysis and uni valence mathematics
foundation of mathematics new uni
valence I have I have arc on that
so today it's just me ranting about
things or whatever but I guess that's
kind of half my saw talk show is like
that
so homotopy type theory okay so you guys
go check it out by the way why am I
talking about this because I know for my
experience with talking to you guys you
guys you know you guys have no idea what
this is about and yeah it will take you
four years or more actually I do have
some mathematician followers then they
know the stuff okay but you know I I
realized much of the programming I'm
talking about like syntax and semantics
but most of you guys are not really
there yet you know like okay anyway that
means
stop that stop that crap okay so so I
want to know I don't know what I'm doing
right now okay so let's just read the
comments oh yeah so math so what what
what I want to learn about math so this
I like to know commodity type theory
differential geometry and complex
analysis okay these three I like to know
okay more I like to know more about them
and as for programming I have a lot of
things to do I need to write a compiler
okay but that's already old news like
two years old
so cringe ahead toss Nia tongs Tanisha
Tanisha Tanisha is in Egypt isn't that
right so good morning Daniel Anglo is so
the new language says well the official
Python extension for Visual Studio code
has almost 65 million downloads mainly
used by phone and developers though yeah
Visual Studio code very popular so Bart
says I have an idea about pon you have
an idea about hot but what idea I don't
think you know about hot and you know I
don't think you know about this thing
you know because different people you
know so I have you know you guys in you
know I have my followers I so I kind of
know have idea what they do what they
know you know first of all don't you
know you don't know nothing like I mean
I you know like there's so many
different people okay and different age
groups so if you if there is something
you don't know that's perfectly fine
okay and and in fact if you claim you
don't know then that's good
but if you claim you know something
usually it's no good because usually you
don't know it yeah shut up but shut up
you know the process I know it since
years well thanks for assuming I'm
dumping I'm not assuming you are dumping
okay that's that's what am I gonna say
to about that
talk about compiler constructions
you know so I got a problem with that
but you see you see you see no
money-wise I'm poor okay I'm doing bad I
failed but intellectualize if you want
to talk about how smart you know this is
something like that or how intelligent
I'm pretty good okay I'm pretty good I
would cream I'm better than most
professors okay but I got a problem so
every time I talk about things you know
I I'm not a good social person I don't
socialize well so when I talk about
things it's very nerdy and also very
rude in a way so but I got this problem
because every time I start to talk you
know I talk to you know people in real
life or sometimes online I got a problem
because the problem is pretty soon the
situation is going to be a competition
because the other people will fear I
mean they will feel that they you know
I'm being rude and I'm going I'm showing
off so they have this tension you know
it doesn't matter it's nuts or nuts okay
so there's attention so they're gonna
try to you know so they're gonna try to
show of or things like that and that
when that happens things not does not
end well because no usually okay they
don't know stuff okay usually you know I
don't care if you are a professor you
know I'm not the best in lots of things
in fact most things okay yeah so again
anyway what I'm saying is that because
of the way I talk because my personality
okay so often I got into into a
situation where whoever I'm talking to
or chatting with they become this
becomes a one-upmanship you know it's
like who is better are you smarter than
me
I'm snob smarter than you you know do
you I am I know I do you know better
than me oh I know better than you
this happens often when this happens
things do not end well usually because
you know it's just okay I'm kind of
confused and lost track you know eat
that so so yeah so so you know don't you
know don't if you know something fine if
you don't know something fine okay and
don't start to say oh you are done oh
thank you you know like who knows better
old P I assumed you are done oh that's
you see this is my problem
okay this is this is this is okay part
so you see what I'm saying is that this
is a personality problem that I have I
possess okay that's just the way I am
because why because there is a hatred in
me okay anyway I don't know where where
I'm going
home are to be type theory okay yeah
that's that I okay and I don't know okay
so I don't know actually what I'm doing
now
so Daniel Daniel knows a lot of things
okay
Daniel knows there are things a
potential foundation of math that's
right so it seems somehow I didn't
expect you know today's talk show I was
just going to talk about random stuff
but somehow it became overly negative
you know I you know I don't know how
that happened but it becomes overly
negative so how long have I been talking
so oh my god I got 20 people so what you
guys are doing today is a kind of a
holiday for everyone so I guess
everyone's got nothing to do oh you got
stuck with your relatives so are you
stuck with your relatives but are you
with your family or what to a reaction
to Arab countries I don't know anything
about Arab countries you know reaction
on Arab countries Google map okay let's
go to Google map so I actually so let's
see what are the things you know I'm
working on I was going to work on my
website so I was working on you know I
have like six thousand six thousand
pages I'm working on these photos you
know you you can't you know if you are
creating a website or writing a blog
about keyboards for example you can't
just dump all photos into it into it you
know you you know it's not like Oh
photos are good so you just take tons of
photos and dump it all in one page that
doesn't work that will actually decrease
your
the appeal of your page rather you want
to select the most best photo and also
each for each photo they must have a
purpose why this photo is there okay
that's that's some of the random tip
about writing a blog so about my
reaction to Arabic countries you know
Arabic countries they are typically a
blank to most Americans all we know I
think that in general is true you know
all we know is that it's trouble you
know it's war its Middle East especially
today with the social justice Fox they
are about Islam this or that every day
but anyway so trouble
oh you're oh you're in trouble so my
reaction let me let me give you my
reaction okay so Iraq we have Iraq war
where we killed six hundred thousand
civilians around 2004 to 2006 six
hundred thousand civilians dead that's
that's what comes to mind Iraq why we
kill them because we think they have
weapons of mass destruction this is war
on terror and it turns out no we didn't
find any so that is my impression of
Iraq and in general this whole bunch of
countries over here it's just a blank to
me okay so they are is like mostly I
guess something like that some of you
okay you guys have to correct me so this
is my impression and I can tell you my
fellow Americans they they they they
don't know better than me okay
my fellow America Marika's on your
average
they don't know better than me so so
Iraq okay
Iran Iran so Iran as we know it's a
country where they have they are going
to be on nuclear bombs
therefore we should kill them we should
kill them first because we have the most
number of nuclear bombs that's current
situation with Iran and what else Iran
well Iran is Persian okay
Iran was known as Persian the Persian
princess you know the the the the story
of 1001 nights
that's Persian so they have flying
horses
they have flying carpets they have you
know they have the genie okay which is
called anyway we know it as genie
so that's Iran they have the magic lamps
that's basically story from around year
of 500 Arabian Nights
Saudi Arabia nights so I talked about
this a few times this is the greatest
book the number one book I enjoyed the
most
okay the Arabian Nights so you go
through my website Arabian Nights this
this website okay you go there and you
read it and it must be this guy's
version translate by Sir Richard Burton
it must be him not not any other version
and not Disney okay Disney Disney is an
entirely different story it's not it's
not Disney is [ __ ]
so in fact you want to read this one
this one is very short that give you
that gives he gives you a flavor what is
what this Arabian Nights is about okay
which one it is this one let me show you
very short the Arabian Nights 70 Abu are
a SWAT and his slave girl okay they are
like three stories
each one is just like one paragraph long
this one you want to read so read that
first now for for those of you who are
in Middle East I'm sorry if I offend I
did you know I don't know anything about
it but anyway so this is you know this
is what we have this is a classic and
this in English and I know that I read
that Arabian people you know the middle
is people they don't care for it too
much about Arabian Nights so anyway so
that's what I know about Iran okay so
then I know about this country okay
United Arab Emirates very rich something
like that super rich Fatah Dubai
they are very rich countries ok then I
know what about the Saudi Arabia okay
that's the country I learned recently in
the past few months from a video I
watched and I trust her the so the Saudi
Arabia they become they are fanatics
okay the the Eastland fanatics inning in
the most severe form and it began about
hundred years ago something like that
okay so that is what I know if you ask
my you know my reactions Pakistan I
don't know nothing about Pakistan but
okay so then of course there is this
Syria is on a news every day something
something Syria Syria and Afghanistan
the USA is fighting there Afghanistan or
Pakistan or Syria okay exactly what I
don't know but I know US Marines
it is over there you know doing stuff so
what's what's the story about this so
that's my reaction about about the this
Middle East part of the country and of
course there is Israel the
most dramatic of them all in the heat
Middle East okay when we start to talk
about this we start to talk about Jews
okay the Jews now technically speaking I
know what is juice kind of but to me in
general juice okay
the sun is shining in my eyes in my face
of Jesus let me close the blind okay so
reaction my reaction to Middle East to
Arab countries so you know then when we
talk about Middle East we cannot ignore
Israel which is you know then then if
you start to talk about Israel then you
have 100 jargons that comes along with
it okay Jews and the zone Zoe Zoe sighs
okay so Zionism or something okay then
you have one whole bunch of jargons okay
I don't I don't I don't really know them
too much and you know but my impression
is you know so this this is the Israel
here right here this strip this it's a
mess okay it's a big mess you know in
the past two years I've learned much
more about Israel from because I have a
friend who is a my who watched my show
sometimes I have a friend who lives
there okay and he tells me his
perspectives well anyways might you know
Express impression is Israel so this
this is the land of USA okay this this
is the power station this is the station
of USA from there within you you you you
control the
was vicinities something like that okay
Israel the bastion of USA then Jordan I
don't know what what what what is Jordan
Jordan is the Jordan shoes
the Nike Jordan shoe or something basket
basketball player children Syria I don't
know Syria so so Israel then you have so
there is a conflict since ancient times
where the people kill each other the the
the Jews versus the AVA Arabs okay Oh
Lebanon you know and actually I also
have a friend a girl she's beautiful
okay she and you know I know her I
haven't talked to heard much now but I
know her like 15 years ago so she is a
mix of lebanon lebanese and mexican and
you know from the Lito i heard of her
she she's very much for Lebanon okay she
is very much for Lebanon okay I you know
I don't want to say you know so this is
our politics
you're gonna offend everyone so you're
gonna offend everyone so that that is
that's what I know so I don't know much
about anything here so Egypt so we have
friends you guys from Kerry Oh Egypt and
I have another friend from from Morocco
okay so these places I have no idea what
what is like okay so I don't know
yeah that's about that so I know
basically everything I know I've already
mentioned my impression of them yeah so
so there are some Corrections but I
don't know anything so you know that
that is just my reaction okay that's
just that's not this is my reaction
video YouTube man this is modern society
you know the cameras [ __ ] reaction you
need to do a reaction video oh let's do
a reaction video on something-something
reaction video so that is my video now
you guys need to respond you guys need
to respond to my reaction videos okay so
let me check the comments what what is
going on and where am I going
how to be your hero so I don't know
anything about groupoids but wait are
they Archer break and Gaara UNIX you
UNIX so unique so V sport also do a dos
game Prince of Persia yes yes I played
that game actually Prince of Persia yeah
that's a word I want I was going to
mention Prince of Persia there's a
extremely popular game Persia that is
even guys so Iran Persian and Arabic
they use the same writing system
you know this ok the demo demo time
sorry Unicode so you go to my unicode
web page and you will see a rabbit
arabic however you say it arabic script
ok this twisted thing
twist it you know this you know
understand but they understand you guys
understand I don't understand so it's
this is so Percy and in Arabic that's
what they use this this that's ligatures
okay so you know so it's a FG at this
system is called AB chat or something
where it's all consonants I think you
know something like that
linguistics the gnosis globular set is a
higher dimensional generalization of a
directed graph okay and groupoid is an
abstract homo topology home are
homotopic Oh model for topological
spaces infinite groupoid okay so okay
you are asking the wrong person
so Israel is not a country this is
Palestine okay
his view is not a country but okay you
know Google is going to pammi you need
to look at the world map as most of the
world accept it okay I'll go on to
Google Maps in search for okay and no
they attack pattern okay okay guys okay
let's not talk about that then okay so
maybe that's it for today
I don't know what I'm doing I don't know
what I'm talking but there it is we
talked for one hour and that will be 49
minutes
okay so right now it's 49 minutes what
what else so who the Queen Queen you are
from where who is Queen Queen Queens
form okay it's a you see this is a
political topic and it gets very messy
and angry different sites and on this
particular issue I don't know much about
it and I don't have a site really
because I'm Chinese
I'm Chinese by blood so I'm not
connected in any way to Islamic people
or Jews
so cold you know you know I don't know
what's juice to me juice white people
white people they are Jews okay but
apparently that's not that's not a case
because there's a you know it's like
this is big difference anyway so I don't
know about
these things okay and it's this is not
my stuff not my politics I don't have I
don't really have a side but there is
one thing I know that is we Americans
[ __ ] [ __ ] around these places okay over
we take grab what we want that's what I
know that's that is my that is my
impression okay because why because we
are the most powerful we have the
greatest number of nuclear bombs the
greatest number of chemical weapons the
greatest number of biological weapons we
have the greatest number of everything
greatest number of space weapons and we
must you know take responsibility on
controlling who is becoming bigger
that's what we do that is my opinion
okay of course I'm offending I'm
probably offending a bunch of white
Americans so you know the hawk the the
hawkish parts of conservatives I guess
you know many many of them complex you
know so politics is very complex because
you know politics is so complex it's
like you have so many you have 1,000
things and they form alliances you know
for example I like this this this but I
don't like that that that so I form
alliances or I support this disease but
but but that person for example ABC for
example put a for example he likes you
know fgh okay and which is what I don't
like but he likes so he forms alliances
with us it's a it's a complex graph
okay stop singing sensitive things guys
okay
that's it for today maybe so actually
yeah okay so I don't I don't know what I
don't have I don't know what I'm doing
today so maybe that's it
Oh 553 we've been talking for 53 minutes
maybe we can do five more minutes
just to complete to make it one hour or
something since this video is already so
long and so what else what else guys
sends a Chinese okay Center Nieman
momentos de Nadya new and inari Kosuke
young began Kosuke ambien okay so all
type of people and all colorful people
and
anyway I use somehow feel sad okay so my
guys