Evening everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show. We are going to do
randomish. We going to code some immacul
language. Fantastic and beautiful. And
uh some red wine. So this is casual
today. Today is what? Not not Friday but
casual. Okay. So here's some red wine.
Today is September 9th 2021.
2025. Tuesday.
Okay. So, Wuam language I've been
looking at, you know, because I need to
uh, you know, create Wufam mode.
Do you guys know what's the Wuam
language? You know, you know, just
search for it on.info. Wuam language
tutorial. You'll find it. So,
I've been exploring. But anyway, it's
got 7,000 building functions. And one of
them is this entity thing. These are new
about 10 years ago.
these entity things. Am I alive? Are you
guys here? Say hi. Okay. If you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed. If you are here, say hi. Don't
forget in the in the year of our Lord.
That is true.
In the year of our Lord 2025.
Okay. So, I mean, so Wufam language.
Okay. I I I actually I need to show you
guys this because otherwise you guys
don't know what I'm talking about. new
people. Uh because every time you do a
video video, you have to consider your
audience who has been following you and
watched many years of videos. Uh and but
they are new people. They they have no
idea. So you go to.info.info.
This is my website. It's got uh 8,000
pages okay on technology on programming
languages on mathematics and uh you can
play Chinese chess is written this is
written in JavaScript
I mean well I copied the code you know
it's a open source code so uh keyboards
so wam language you go there wam
language uh then you go download you can
download it for free okay so that's
woofam language language. It's a
programming language for a magnitude
beyond any other language. C++, Rust,
Haskell, Lisp, beyond a magnitude
beyond. So this is actually a good
example showing how why it is a
magnitude like people might say, you
know, oh, I I love Python. Python is
got, you know, the it's elite language
for machine learning. What possibly you
know you know there's a python l uh
python uh dro you know like packed like
two gigabytes of all the machine
learning mathematics you know so people
like that which is normal average people
you know so what possibly why is why do
you say wuam language is magnitude
beyond let me show you today this one
okay
so this so so this it's got this entity
thing
uh the you uh I'm not too you know I
don't understand too well because it
because it's huge you cannot understand
the entire thing so uh wait so let me um
yeah so let me go to the help
you know here's a documentation for the
entity thing okay so can can we magnify
this okay so anyway it's complicated you
wouldn't understand it if you read it
okay but anyway it's it's it's kind of a
Um it's a wuam language framework for
SQL database relational database.
So there I think there are two things
about it. One is it's a framework for
relational database. So you don't use
the SQL language to you know select
something table or something. Instead
you use a wam language like that. Okay.
So that's one thing. It's a framework or
interface to SQL databases. The other
part is that Wuam you know Rufam
research the company they have created a
massive uh database of all kind of data
in science, chemistry, physics for
example molecules you know if you study
um uh organic chemistry you need to know
or or biology you need to know a lot uh
molecule data like a protein what type
of protein are there uh how many atoms
are in this protein or what whatever But
you know so and also stars for astrology
or cosmology stars like data about stars
how many known planets uh how you know
the stars what's their size how far they
are you know things like that uh
astronom astronomy chemistry physics
lots of data about phys physics
uh for example quantum computing the the
the quirks in you know subatomic make
particles,
lots of data about that and basically in
any field and in computing in algorithms
you know so so all kind of data and one
of the and also geography you can plot
maps you know how many how many like you
can ask how many city like I can
actually ask it so let me try okay uh
control equal sign no control I want
equal sign where okay so how many cities
in USA that has more than let's say
uh
10 million people. Okay, you can shift
enter to ask the question.
So in order so oh so there it is you see
this entity class thing. So it's
actually a relational database kind of
thing. Okay. So you know query entity
class city count country United States
country city population greater than 10
million entity uh wait did it does it
give you an answer
entity city
country United States city population
greater so okay so the that's not the
answer it just repeats the question but
I think
I think you can get the answer by
um
I don't know so
I think you need to
enter
value okay so I think that's what you
need to say entity value so shift enter
let's see entity value entity properties
okay uh gives gives the value of the
specified property for the given entity.
Okay. So, but what does entity class do?
So, I'm not sure exactly how to get the
answer. Okay.
So, I'm that's why I'm looking into you
know I found this thing
fairly complex because it is interface
like uh the whole SQL language. Anyway,
the other thing I'm trying to say is
that it has a database of all these
things. And here's an example. You can
plot Pokemon
that that weighs from
50 kilograms to 100 kilogram. Okay. So,
that's at least Okay. Pokemon. And
here's Pokemon. Pokemon under 10
kilograms. Okay. So, you got that. So I
got curious you know I I I found this uh
from the documentation of the entity
thing.
Okay. So here is the entity list. Get
the list of all the countries. Okay. So
Oh yeah. So so can we do that actually?
So let me try to get the value. Okay. So
entity value
E N Tit Ty entity
value
then
I'll put 34. Let's see what do you get.
No, I want the I want the list.
So if you say entity list, do you get
the result?
Empty.
Oh, maybe 10 million. Oh, maybe it's
empty. Okay, so let's edit edit that
more than 1 million people. Let's say
no, that's not okay. I don't know how I
don't know how to use this.
Uh
so anyway, so so here is Pokemon from
under 10 kilograms
and here's Pokemon
from 10 kilograms to 20 kilograms.
Okay,
so that's what I mean. So Wuam language
I mean Wuam research they have internal
database of lots of things you know like
like um you know like it's like they use
that in Wuam alpha.
So anyway that's an interesting thing to
show you. Okay so here is another
example. Oh entity value. Okay so that's
what you need to say.
Here's an example. You want to know all
the sheep
breed all the sheep breed whose weight
of the their fleas
you know rank all the sheeps by the
weight of their fleas. So there they
are. So the the you know the first one
is
castword
sheep fleece weight 17 pounds. So let's
see if you click on that what you get.
Oh okay so you know so let's evaluate it
again
evaluate it. So you got that so you can
ask you know all sort of questions. So
that is what I mean how wuam language
is just a magnitude beyond.
By the way, here's poke Pokemon whose
weight is
200 kilograms or more or infinity. So
you got this castle thing.
Cheers. Red one to red wine to soothe my
soul.
A jet says you save the entity class
into a var. Oh, you know like a poke.
Then use entity value and reference the
var as a parameter
as the first parameter. That's what I
did, right? I mean that's so okay. So we
so we got someone who knows the uh
who who knows Wuang language. Uh
so let's say
cities equals to that then then what you
say use entity value. Okay.
Yeah. But it doesn't, you see, that
doesn't
get you. So, let's look at the Pokemon
example.
Entity class.
So, here is the entity class
with this properties. Okay. So, what do
we have here? So, we got an entity class
and uh these are properties I suppose.
Okay. Then you say,
"Oh Jesus, what they doing?"
Okay. So, oh, enter and value
Pokemon and uh Okay. So, let's try that.
Yeah, but uh
you know, but then you need to find out
what are the properties to use you know
I I don't I don't know. I don't
understand.
You see? So maybe it, you know, more
than 1 million that should be
reasonable. Let's let's say more than uh
uh 100,000 people. Okay. Let's see what
that get.
Okay. So,
okay. Then value entity value CT. Yeah,
it doesn't it doesn't give you the
answer.
So anyway, that's that's that's about
wam language. Okay, that's just
something interesting. Now let's switch
topic. Let's go to uh let me show you
something. Emac this. Now they are both
this family. Okay, same thing. A uh
let's say cat. Let's magnify. Okay, cat,
dog, and fox. Okay, I want to make a
list. So, just press a key. Press,
press, and it become list. Show in
browser. Wait.
Uh, press. Okay. Show in browser. So,
you see that's fantastic. Undo.
Make them a list. Do it. Show in
browser. So, that command is go back to
Emacs. site TML lines to list. Okay? And
you can get that command by
it's on my website. So, search for it.
So, here's a code and go to the URL.
There it is. Fantastic. Grab the code.
You'll have it. Uh, but I made a change
today. I just coded on our, you know,
uh, I made a change so that before,
let me explain what's going on. Okay, I
can copy this. So, copy the code.
Open new buffer. Paste it here.
Make uh it is mode. So, it's syntax
color. Go to the top now. Now, evaluate
it. Okay. Now, I'm using this code. Now,
back to here. htm. Close that. Back to
uh back to talk show. Undo. Undo. Okay.
Now, make a list. That works. But
however, if you have something let's say
um
uh let's say
let's say you are close
close this I mean I mean there's no uh
blank line so you do it
it create a list it turns each line to a
list you see but that's not good because
here then it's a HTML arrow can you see
that Uh let let's let me show you
something more um sensible. Okay. Uh
make a new section. So cut that put it
here and delete the date. Delete the
to-do show in browser. So you you kind
of we got a section. So normally you
make a list like that. Showing browser.
So you got a section of the list items.
Okay. But sometimes you don't have a new
line at the end. So when you do this
make a list but this is invalid HTML
showing browser. You see
you know because the section tag
you know a a list element cannot contain
the closing tag of the section. Okay. So
how do I so you can check if it's valid.
So press press
that calls the command HTML validate XML
buffer. We coded that command live about
two years ago. Search on YouTube, you'll
find it. So it's telling me error of
this file. Closing tag section at
position 643
does not match last open tag LI at
position 639.
So, where's position 643?
Let's call go to position uh wait go to
um
what
where is my command go?
What?
God. Um, now I I definitely need one to
find that command. Uh, I have a go to
position other buffer.
Oh, move cursor.
Wait, what? Okay, now I definitely want
to look at to find out my command. Okay,
so um
cursor
position
what? Okay. Uh space that
search for go to go to line go to char.
Okay, that's building there. There it
is. Yeah, cha. Okay, I forgot. Uh,
okay. This function needs to be renamed.
By the way, we coded this function live
uh maybe a year ago.
Open it. So, here's a function and uh
here's a URL. So, search for that talk
show. Oh, Karan talk show 2025 April
10th. So, that's just three month ago.
Emac this coding. go to line number next
buffer. Okay. And go to position. So
anyway, that's a command. So this
command it shouldn't be go to char. It
should be go to position. So I need to
rename it, I think. Okay. So anyway,
let's so close. So now let's
press a key to validate. Okay. So wait,
close that. Start fresh. So showing
browser back in EMAC
add a date XML. So here's the arrow
position
now go to char other buffer. Do it.
There it is. So that is the closing tag
of section. So that's telling you this
is invalid invalid HTML. So undo. Okay.
So that's what you need is so you need a
space or you need to select it first
then do it
uh wait okay so if you select it yeah so
anyway that is the old version of the
line to list okay
now if I go to the new version
okay so let's go to the new version now
uh okay so HTML
uh so what is the command my name. Let's
just search for it.
I need to find which one of these HTML
file is it in. So just open one of them
then then find to search it.
There it is. Okay. So this is in Yeah.
So there it is. Okay. So search search
there is okay. So now evaluate the
buffer. So now I'm we are using the new
version. So you see the new version is
dated 2025
September 9th while the old version is
March. Okay. So now we are using a new
version evaluated. Now let's go back to
the talk show. Close that. Close that.
Back to the talk show. Close that.
Uh close that.
Close that. Back to the talk show. Now
if you let's do it again. Okay. Do it.
Arrow. A line cannot start with a
closing tag at the bottom. Can you see
that? Okay. Let's do it again. Do it.
Arrow. A line cannot start with a
closing tag. So now if you have a space,
I mean a blank line. Now it works. Okay.
Now let's update. So let's update the
code to my website. So when you copy it,
it's going to be the new version. Okay.
So now go back to here. Uh
close that. Go back to here. There it is
the code. So press press. It will
automatically
wait. Wrong type argument. Integer
marker. What the [ __ ]
What?
Update code to website. So, so why can't
we do it? Press press press press.
Ah, god another error. So, got it. So,
turn on turn on able enable debug on
arrow. Then press press. Let's see what
uh
why why is this not
wait open the file? So show in browser
did it update? No.
Okay.
So, what qu uh what questions? So, I'm
going to have dinner soon. Fantastic.
Do says, "Hi, Ka. Hope your evening is
going well." It is. Thank you. God's son
says, "Ka, what are your thoughts on
the growing fandom of our Linux and
Mac?" What? Let's magnify. Okay, let's
magnify the chat.
You know one of the windows problem is
that if you want to enlarge the window
of course you can do it by this way uh
old space and then
then size okay space s then then you can
kind of do it then to the left okay
but otherwise if you want to use the
mouse you know you have to move the
mouse mouse to this very tiny position.
Okay, now I have hoover to activate
window on. So if I miss it by a bit,
then you know I I went to the other
window. So that's very annoying. They
should have this you know um
you know the the the border should have
a larger margin for when you for for
changing the window size.
What's your thoughts on growing fandom
of Ar Linux and Omachi? I don't even
know what that is. Okay, Machi. Copy
that. Uh, okay. But we are in the middle
of something. So, let's search for
Machi.
Omachi.
Okay. So, it seems like a an opinionated
[ __ ] You know today it became a fashion
in the in the past two years or so.
Whenever you have a software package
they will say an opinionated something.
[ __ ]
As if now it become fashionable when you
know you need to say your package is an
opinionated something. [ __ ] idiot.
The zoomers. Okay. These are the
zoomers. The zoomers.
Okay. So it's so let's open that. So
it's arc Linux plus hyperland you know
one of the you know one of the drama in
the Linux hyperland
by DH by DHH is that the guy I'm
thinking the DHH [ __ ] that the guy
the scum
David Hammond
something Hansen okay he's a scumbag of
humanity
this guy is a cocky and a scum he's
known for creating the Ruby rails and
ever since he's like, "Oh, I'm the king.
I'm going to tell you what to do. Oh, by
the way, you need to support women. You
need to support the trans or you need to
support whatever safe space." And then
then Ella Musk took over. And he said,
"Oh, no. You need you should not support
Black Live Matters and things like
that." You know, the scum,
one of the major scum. Unfortunately,
you people, a lot of people follow him,
you know, like because he's, you know,
popular pop a pop star. What a [ __ ]
scum.
All these are my opinions only. Okay?
So, you cannot sue me. This is my
opinion.
This [ __ ] Now, exactly what is Look
at Look at him. Look at his picture. You
know, he's a [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] because
he want to show how successful he is. He
very rich, you know. Of course he's
um anyway
so this guy so Omari opinionated arc you
know he
now observe now he's following the trend
or did did I don't think he started the
word but any anyway he used it why
obvious because that's how you know you
when you know when you are like when you
want to be popular you want to how to
how to become popular. You want to
follow certain ways. So when there is
some phrase that's currently in fad, you
want to use that because you want to be
popular, you know, you want to squeeze
all the money, whatever donations or,
you know, all the or the fame which in
turn gets you money, you want to squeeze
that. Okay. and hyperland
an opinionated arc and hyperland set up
by DHH. Okay. Manual ISO. Okay. GitHub.
Discord. Discord. Okay. He's got a and
merch. That's that's American way. Make
money or nothing or die.
You got to buy buy merch. Buy some
underwear. Buy some panties for your
girlfriend with an American flag on it.
the DHH [ __ ] hoodie and t-shirt.
Okay,
so let's see. Let's go back to the uh
archive. So what? So where is he? So uh
um
Okay. So this is the homepage. Yeah. So
you got to go to the GitHub. I don't
care about what the [ __ ] videos you
have.
Uh okay. So he's uh you know he's
starting a new dro or something. Turn a
fresh turn a fresh arc installation into
a fully configured beautiful and modern
web de development system based on
hyperland by running a single command.
That's one that's the one line pitch for
omaki like it was for omakub. Okay, so
there's another thing or markup. No need
to write bespoke configs for every
essential tools uh just to get started
or go something something uh something
something something complex Linux [ __ ]
is an opinionated take on what Linux can
be at its best. Okay, what a [ __ ]
blur. By the way, technically this kind
of thing is called blur in the printing
press community. Okay, a blurb.
Typically,
this guy is super rich, you know. So,
he's creating that. Okay.
Uh, is it good? I suppose, you know, I
suppose it's at least I can you I can I
know it's quality coding because this
guy he know what he's doing, but he's
just uh you know like the ESR guy. He's
like
inject his political opinions into your
brain.
So your question um your question
what are your thoughts on that? In my
opinion Emac sounds more featurerich but
are they not considered the comparative
system tools.
Cheers. So anyway I don't know I haven't
been using Linux for 10 years. So I
don't know anything about omaki. I never
used arc linux neither. I just know that
my the arc Linux is one of is the best
um technical documentation for Linux.
They have a was it a Linux? Okay. I
forgot you know it's it's been 10 years.
So I have like a collection of articles
a tutorial on Linux by command line.
your favorite thing. Command line. You
must use command line only. You know
GUI is for the stupid. You must command
line only. The [ __ ] the Unix and C
[ __ ]
the brainless completely brainless.
Okay. So they uh they so I have a you
know my Linux tutorial and by the way
all my tutorial today is worth [ __ ]
because
because you can ask AI to write a
tutorial on the fly.
Of course, AI grabbed all my tutorials
and just fried it. Reffried, you know,
he when you have whenever you want to
ask AI to code something, the AI bots gu
or whatever Jini
or whatever you or the Facebook [ __ ]
you know, they they look they go look
graas information website and they refry
the words and they come out tell you
why.
How do I know? search
age of AI artificial intelligence. Okay,
that's the age of AI and that's the
article
professors on demand. This is I wrote
this like a month ago, a few weeks ago.
Okay. Resistance to tech progress is
futile. Okay. Many of the Americans for
some reason the white Americans or
technically the European Americans or
technically the uh Brits, the British
Americans and the German like they are
the real white men. German and Brit, not
Irish, not Russian. Russian is the
whitest white guy. But they but no white
men in USA America means usually the
Brits and the Germanic
ancestry. Okay. I learned the hard way
in uh does not include Irish does not
include Greeks. You know the Greek the
foundation of Western civilization does
not include the the most whitest
beautiful girl the white Russians that
does not include that. Usually it's the
Brit and the German people in America
they are making all the noises
and Jesus
and where was I? So okay so where was I?
So I was talking about um oh yeah the
artificial intelligence professor on
demand resistant to take progress. Yeah.
So I was saying in America the white
like a subset
they have their culture this this Brit
and German subset of Americans
or
you know they they they they have a
culture of resisting
technology
you know when they see Elamusk they say
no Elamus rocket no I don't I don't want
that I don't know I don't want AI no
that's AI I don't I want AI. I want I
want I want a I want I want a farmland.
American white. They have that kind of
mentality. Resistant to tech for some
reason for for and and and and also very
tightly associated with Christianity.
Okay. So Jesus and no technology, but
they love guns though. And they love
[ __ ] other people like like, "Oh,
let's take Mexico. Let's rename Mexico
to Mexico. American golfer Mexico, you
know. Let's take Canada. Another another
white man. But let's take them anyway.
Let's take Greenland. Oh yeah, we doing
so good. Let's take China. CCP. CCP [ __ ]
evil. Let's communism. Oh, communism.
They are against God. we let's take them
[ __ ] them you know these white people
the white people
they and they got [ __ ] very badly by
themselves in the past 10 years in USA
okay
we we we are uh gradually moving towards
politics but anyway let's go back to uh
nonpolitics so I'm saying I was I was
saying these white people they have a
tendency to like resisting tech. They
don't like tech, you know, they are luds
kind of strange. Okay. On one hand, they
like they are aggressive. This this, you
know, in my study of races of past 10
years, which race is the most aggressive
like they want to do wars. They they
want to [ __ ] other other races. Which
race of all races, you know, white,
black or whatever, red skin, yellow or
whatever
is the most aggressive in human history.
And my answer is the white people. Okay,
most no more not more technically
correctly, the Germanic race, which is
from Germany and they move to England or
Anglo-Saxons
whatever the Brits and German. Okay.
They are the most aggressive
kind of people in their bones.
Okay.
But in USA in past 10 years they got
[ __ ] and they fight among each other.
You know they fight among themselves
too. So USA became so bad in past 10
years they
they got [ __ ] by themselves by their
own race like Ben Hillary Clinton and so
on and on and on.
And now Trump. Anyway, let's go. Let's
not talk about politics, okay? And
there's another white people, but not
German and not British, but they're kind
of also white
and are [ __ ] them. Okay. So, let's
not talk about that. So, let's go back
to resist. So, they have a resist
resistance to tech. You know, I'm not
exactly,
you know, sure how that arose. How why
why is that the let's just say European
culture they have kind of this
resistance to take progress? I don't
know.
But you can you can see it. Am I am I
correct? Are you guys listening?
So investing 10 billion into you know
dosi is like trying to defend it you
know. Oh but you are wrong but look they
you know Trump invested 1000 100 billion
into uh chat bots
[Laughter]
but you know you don't you don't get it.
Okay so anyway so go to back go back to
AI oh wait not this article. Okay. So,
let's go back to my search. So,
artificial in intelligence index. So, I
was saying
uh what was I saying? So,
we were talking about AI. Um
God, what what is the topic that I
talked I started to? So you were asking
about Arc Linux and Umaki
and uh okay I forgot
I was going to show something about AI
about um
okay I don't remember
okay So, how long have we been talking?
We have been talking for 40 minutes.
Okay, let's see some of the questions
and that will be it for today. Uh, did
we finish the Emacs line to list? Yeah.
No, but because we run into a problem.
God.
Anyway, let me answer the questions.
Okay. And that's it. I I'll update my
code so you guys can grab it with the
latest version. you know the HTML line
to list. Okay.
So let's see.
So in my opinion Emacs sounds more
featurerich but are they are they not
considered the comparative systems tool?
What do you mean? Emacs is a text
editor. Okay. Arc Linux or Omari is a
Linux distro. So they are different.
They are very different. Linux is a
operating system. Okay. And the arc
Linux and Omaki is a special
you know entire distribution packages
for the operating system of Linux is so
it's like a magnitude more than Emacs
and Emacs is just mostly your text
editor okay so what do you mean uh you
know I don't understand what you what
your comparison next question dosey says
godson one is a distribution config and
one is a list of interpreter that's
correct
Ferrison says today I read on Reddit
that Emacs cannot handle large file
and vim can. So I downloaded 500
kilobytes XML file and press CS some
text co to show occur and emac die aming
works normally. Do you know what it
happens?
Yes, that was true. That was true. Is
was it is no longer true. 500
kilobyte. What are you talking about?
500 kilobytes like half a megabyte.
I thought you were talking about half a
gigabyte. No, Emacs today can open one
gigabyte file I believe. So five years
or 10 years ago, it's got a problem.
It's correct that Vim can open larger
files than Emacs. But that was fixed
like five or 10 years ago. Must be 10
years ago. And you are only talking
about 500 kilobyte. That's like half a
megabyte. What are you talking about?
That 500 megabyte you can open like 20
30 years ago.
So I don't know what you're talking
about. Ferrison.
Next goen on Kas website. He has an
article about tingling window manager.
Yes. Uh next uh that was one of the most
popular uh
um article on Reddit on hacker news. So
Ashton says I'm just assuming he's a
tiding window manager based on pictures.
Okay. So does he says yeah he's a
farming zoomers.
I forgot where that that what that
refers to. I think Muk with your most
famous sayings would be profitable.
Hank, thank you.
First nation of stream Hank, my loyal
donor.
500 Oh. Oh. 500 500,000
lines. 15 megabyte. 15 megabytes
peanuts. You can open it. I I can show
you. Okay, so let's open let's go to
keyboard blog. So let's you know there's
my keyboard blog. There's actually one
over 1,000 articles on keyboard on uh on
key switch guide uh on uh you know lots
of videos I've done in the past three
year four five years uh er ergonomics
keyboard let's magnify okay so you know
lots of things uh doityourself keyboards
normal keyboards uh you know so
typewriters the history of typewriters
history of mouse and so on track and so
on that over 1,000 and articles. Okay.
So, you go there and you want to find a
large file. Okay. So,
uh so let's go to So, wait, where are
we? So, let's go to talk show.
Uh so, today's talk show. Yeah. So, what
we want to do? So, let's see. Um
okay, go there. Open this in terminal.
Open this directory in terminal. Press
press press. And that command is open in
terminal. You can go and search for it
and grab the code. Okay. So there we
have terminal and you want to um list
large files. Do it.
Uh wait list large files. So we list all
the large files in this directory. So
you can see the largest is like let's go
to the top. Okay. So, let's just copy
that.
Okay. Close that. And uh let's just
paste that. Okay. So, linkify that
typewriter. So, you got this large file.
So, this one is 48
uh 48 let's see
megabytes. Okay. So, what are you
talking about? What's the size you are
talking about? You are talking about
someone give noise on kitchen. Oh, you
can hear it. Nice. Good ears. Yes. My
wife is cooking dinner for me.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Oh yeah. This one is
important. I need I wanted to show you
the AI of how Google is grabbing my
website. So here
uh AI is unstoppable. Unstoppable. Tech
is unstoppable. Unstoppable. Okay, that
get that. Okay, you cannot stop tech
because if you don't do tech, someone
else will do it and then they will
destroy you. Okay, so this is for the
white idiots, you know. Oh, I don't
want, you know, we shouldn't do AI. I
don't want my life to be that way. I
want my life to be like homestead you
know a farmland you know you know I'm
gonna American
idiots okay if you don't do tech someone
will take over you nonstop startable any
tech biology cloning human whatever
whatever you know your Christianity
forbid
if you don't do it some somewhere else
including nukes you know nuc nuclear
bombs that USA began.
So the the white you know I don't
understand what they you know what they
are thinking. Meanwhile they are
thinking oh we going to take over China
US military but they but they don't you
know can you code? No I don't like code.
You know the the tech the big tech bra
[ __ ] them. We don't want big tech.
Funny. Okay. So so yeah. So let's get
back to the point. So the the Google
store my website. So where's the uh
proof? Where's your receipt? You know in
the past few years they like to talk
about receipt.
Okay. So so let's see uh AI meaning of
intelligence after chat bots. Okay.
Donald Guth on chat GPT the year of
intelligence 2023.
Uh, AGI versus sentience. Sentient AI.
The unstoppable tech is unstoppable.
Chat GPT on Kasar site site in Google C4
data set for artificial intelligence
training. You know Google declared
you know Google which site you are
stealing
list them. Okay.
Then
and one of them is kasali.info
and kasali.org. There it is. The
websites in Google C4 data set.
They grab and store.
So now my tutorial is like nobody visit,
you know, because you can just ask AI.
Of course, not just my website, but the
entire Reddit the Stack Overflow died
overnight, you know.
Stack overflow you know one of the big
side it died overnight.
Uh okay so that that is what I want to
show. Thank you for mentioning that
God's son.
Okay. So I think that's it for today. Uh
uh what what else? Uh
are you Chinese? Can you can you tell?
Can you tell?
Do you understand?
You know, don't don't say don't say I
don't know who you are, but you don't
know stuff because you know Trump. Yeah,
of course Trump is investing AI, but you
still it's a mentality. Okay. It's it's
just like there's this cultural
mentality. Okay. Oh yeah. So you are
talking about 15 kilobytes. So Ferrison.
Okay. So here's a website. Here's a file
that's 48 kilobyte. Let's open it. Do
it. File Logitech you know spin wheel
you know.Mmpp4 is larger is large 47
maybe bytes.
Really open it. Yes. Okay. So here is a
file that's 48 mgaby. So you can scroll
down, you know, it won't stop in this,
you know. Okay. So now you go to the
directory. That's the file. Open the
file by itself. Okay. That's the video.
That's 48 megabyte. And I just opened
it. So there's no problem. So I don't
know what you're talking about.
Okay. That's a demo of this mouse. I'm
using Logitech uh Logitech
502.
You can buy it from the link on my
website. That's demo of the infinite
spin mouse. Okay,
that so so which file is using this
video. So, let's search close that uh go
to
Kasan keyboard and search for this
Logitech MP4 thing.
That's it for today. Thank you guys for
watching. Donate to me, okay? Go to
PayPal. Go to.info info. If you like my
stuff and if you are a good man, you
think I, you know, you like my stuff, I
showed you information, I taught you
stuff, pay me, okay? 20 bucks, 10 bucks
for coffee, 20 bucks for dinner, 100
bucks if you are programmer working
professionally
in some capacity. Okay, so here is the
links. So, open it, close, you know,
there it is. Logitech G502 mouse. Okay,
this review is like 10 years old.
Anyway,
so that is the video there.
So, opening 48 mgabyte file. No problem.
It might be because XML mode. Yeah, it
could be uh stream more than 1 hour and
we pay you. Why? Like because usually
one hour is like too long. People don't
want that. People like short. So I don't
know what you your question. By the way,
I already streamed
for
Oh, it's you know it's barely just it's
one hour right now. Okay. But I think
that's it. But any any other questions?
Okay. We I think we shut down. So
anyway, so here is Logitech. Okay. So
copy the page. Close it and close this
and go to uh close the keyboard.
Actually paste the link. So Logitech
mouse and reopen the keyboard blog page
showing browser.
Go down back to Emacs. Copy the file
path. Close it. Paste there. Link it.
Make a list. And here is like a bunch of
uh wait here is a bunch of you know huge
files deleted that came from this uh
PowerShell
and let's make a uh screenshot of this
PowerShell and uh but let's make it
small
list large files by the way if you want
that code powershell you can get it okay
So let's go to PS1 PS1 my PowerShell um
PSPS PS1 my PowerShell profile and list
large files that will be in file util
open it search for large there it is now
do I have a URL there it is there's a
URL open it showing browser PowerShell
sort files by size okay so you can grab
it
and you can thank me. Okay, close that.
Close that. Close that. Sound talk show.
Paste that. Link it. Make a list.
Showing browser. So those are the things
we talked about.
And that's it.
What's up? What's up?
just
sub pop up on my recommended. Just
stopping by real quick to say hi. Have a
nice stream. God bless. God bless. God
bless you. So tell me, can Emacs be
modern idol for Go or is it not worth
it? Modern IDE for Goland. Yes, of
course you can. You can drop the IDE
because the IDE doesn't mean much. Okay.
So, but anyway for some programming
languages, Emacs is very good at there
are some programming languages Emacs is
not you know not too good. Okay. So that
would be Java. So if you code in Java,
Emacs is like you know some a lot of
people would say it's not very good for
but for Python for any non-compile
programming language and for Goland
which is a compile language but you can
also run it as a script but anyway so
Goland I would say EMAX is very good
in fact I have a package for it
uh which I actually rewrote this live in
live stream
mode. Okay, we wrote this in live
stream. So, uh you guys don't know. So,
because you know because YouTube, you
know, I have been doing YouTube for five
years. So, there's a lot topics we
talked about. So, if you just go to
si.info, info.
Go to Emacs blog. Then go to YouTube
tutorial.
Then here is uh Emacs tutorial v uh
video tutorial. Then Emacs workflow
efficiency tutorial. Emacs lisp from
groundup tutorial.
Each one is one hour video. Emac writing
a major mode tutorial. So there one of
them is goland. So there it is. Star
Talk Show 2021
November 27
which is four years ago. Emac this
tutorial writing a Goland mode from
scratch.
So we I coded this Goland mode
you know four years ago from scratch.
So anyway, so Golan is, you know, so to
answer your question, Emacs is very good
for Golan.
Emacs can filter by size. Yes, you can.
Yeah. Okay. I don't think you know
Emacs. Okay, you are a newbie. So you
know like what kind of question? Why do
you need why do you need PowerShell? Why
don't you use Emacs? You know these
stupid questions.
Then then some people say oh but why
can't you use some other tools you know
you know
why why do I have a powershell script
because you know I want to be a
powershell script where I don't have
emac script installed that's a proper
job for powershell for shell okay for
bash you can easily do that for bash for
powershell it's more complex you but you
don't have to but you can
you know you don't have to use a script.
You can just type it, but it's it's more
things to type. You know, it's a proper
job for PowerShell.
You can do it in Emacs 2. I can write
this on the fly in five minutes.
And I already have like a few hundred
command. Do you know them?
Okay, let me show you. Let me Where's
the Where is the receipt? Where's the
proof? Let's go to S diet. There it is.
Then the list m marching lines defend.
So there are 42 functions.
Diet scale image image auto crab to JPEG
to PNG. Rotate image optimize PNG. SVG
optimize PNG. Show image metadata.
Remove all metadata in JPEG files. Like
where do you live? Like you take a photo
and you upload to the internet and you
forgot you it shows where you live
and sort open marks to zip file open in
inkscape open in [ __ ] open info view you
don't even know what info view is you
open in qua open open ms paint open in
notepad text edit VS code and you know
and uh unravel directory file to
directory python open python doc.
Okay. So let's let's call that open
Python doc. Do it. There it is. Python
3.12.7
documentation locally not on the web.
Okay. When when you are a serious coder
you want you want documentation locally
so you can easily search it. Okay. Then
Python list emac backup list empty files
you know ignore the something list uh
delete empty directories delete emac
backup delete empty files. So, you know,
I already got lots of things. You don't
know. Anyway, that's the life of
YouTubing and streaming. You know,
that's just a situation. Most people are
not
really serious. So, this is for
entertainment.
Did you get a laugh out of it? You did?
Thank you.
Bye, guys.
Close.
Close. We shut down in one minute.
Softly keys. Close. Close. So, this is
all uh this is today's talk show. Let's
remove uh let's remove that show. Okay.
So, lines to list. So, I need to update
that
um this this page. So, you get the new
page. Okay. And then let's combine this
uh yeah combine this typewriters
actually delete. Well, leave it. Combine
the list. Okay. Combine. Combine.
Okay. And actually we don't need this
section. Remove that. And also merge the
list. So you just got a bunch of list.
And the next what is this? Uh untitled
close.
Okay, Cass talk show that's today and
this Python file and this is writing a
Goland mode from scratch. Okay, paste it
there so people can see it
and go back here Emacs
video tutorials. Let's put it for
marketing purposes because when people
see it, they maybe they'll look. If they
people don't see it, they too lazy to
look for it.
Uh,
okay. Close that. And PowerShell sort
file by size. Let's Let's Do we already
have it? Yes, there.
Okay. Close that. Bye.