welcome to another episode of s talk
show today we coding Advent of code wam
language
2024 day four I believe part two this
morning we did day one now let's have a
drink this is eggn egg
KN white man thing so let's enjoy the
holiday
spirit okay that's like 200
mL and my keyboards are glove 80 one of
the best keyboard ultimate hacking
keyboard one of the best okay let's
switch
to the code window so you can see my
code
and let's
begin so on my website cali.
info 6 hours ago we did event of code
2024 day four and beautiful girl wolf
girl oh she is so alluring the word the
English word the proper term is
alluring uh you see there's a women's
magazine called
aure fitting word
uh that's what women are for the most
part A you know essential it's important
uh so here's a code for part
one uh we have a scratch part scratch
Pad showing how it works then the real
code is
here uh it's a bit longer than I would
like okay it can be shortened uh but
maybe it needs a different algorithm but
anyway today so now we go to part two we
didn't
finish uh took me an hour over over an
hour and uh if you are here say hi if
you are not here skip around and play at
1.5
speed so we doing this live uh usually I
haven't read a problem yet but this one
part two I did
so let's go to part two soent of code
you can see can you see it yes St four
series
search uh part two okay so basically you
are
given you are given a block of code like
that and you want you need to
find all the word xas forming across
okay it may be top left to bottom right
or top right to bottom left or the words
may be bottom left to top right or
bottom right to top right top
left okay so let's see let's start to go
to part two okay so part
two
uh
what wait this yeah this is part two so
actually so yeah so this is so let's
begin
w f code and remove that and uh showing
browser okay if you are here say hi if
you are you know here say hi okay so
here is the
code this is the toy input I assume we
have this same toy
input okay let's start to code for real
wait uh no let's re again in
okay part two okay
[Music]
so so you want so actually can you
actually do this fromat to
example X ma x x ma a um
so wait a
minute and are they the same m
m Ms Ms Ms Ms MS m yeah okay so the
total input is the
same yeah so you want to find a cross
okay like like over here
uh without X just max okay
so okay so let's write it down okay
let's go slowly and and write it down
things problem identify all
MX Mas
s what's
m that forms a
cross okay for
example so you got Mas and
M
okay so you want to uh count so each
cross count as one
occurrence problem is is find all
occurrences okay and uh and the problem
that we have the user input uh advant of
code
index day four part
one so we have the user
input okay
so yeah so the user input is there let's
copy
that so open the file so that's what the
file looks like
okay
it's 140 characters and 140
rows okay and uh
so so now we have to figure out the
algorithm how do you solve the problem
so the
problem you essentially
identify all occurrences of a the letter
a such
that it's not on the border of the
Matrix okay because otherwise if if a Is
On The Border you know you cannot M you
cannot have m
it would go outside of the border so you
want to like just basically go check
every element find all occurrences of a
that is not on the edge of the Matrix
okay so once you find a you just need to
check its Four
Corners if one is M the other is s
then then then that works but then you
try to find the other Corner if that
also is the case then you got a
cross okay fairly simple if you think
about it
okay so that's one approach
um identify or occurrence of
a that is not on the edge of the
Matrix then
for each check its
Corners if
the if the two
diagonal h d i a g o n a l
Corners uh X and uh s
order doesn't
matter then it's
valid
if both of
the two diagonal Corners are s
and x and S okay let's check uh wait not
XM okay so yeah so okay order doesn't
matter
so
okay let's see so that's one way to do
it I mean that I mean that is the what
you need to do
okay uh but the actual coding you see
the actual coding involves how do you
identify you see normally you identify
you consider this as a
matrix then you identify by The Elements
by their index so when you want to check
the corners that that would be you know
for example the upper right corner would
be index + one the row index + one and
the column index minus one okay so
basically the four corner would be plus
plus + one + one - one- plus + one -
one- - one + one - one and uh Min - one
+
1 yeah + one
minus anyway that's you know four
logical
possibilities each spot is either plus
or minus and you got four uh two spots
so four possibilities total two * two so
you know that so that that's how you
identify the elements in The Matrix so
that's kind of the naive
way naive approach you basically just
check the index and check it's either M
or X if it's m you mark it as M then the
other one the other diagonal must be S
so if you found s first then the other
one must be M okay that's one
way um let's make
sure okay Ms you see so you know it's
easier to draw a
diagram uh you know it's kind of easy to
draw a
diagram but it takes more time however
it's fun to do so for example let's have
a diagram
so you got m a
s okay m a s so how many how many
possibilities so you know you could have
let's
see s
m so each diagonal you have two
possibilities you know maybe the order
is reversed so the other diagonal also
two possibilities so you have total of
four possibilities you know basically
the Four
Corners
um so basically two of them must be M
the other two must be S okay okay so
that's another way to
judge two must be S two must be M let's
see no that still doesn't work because
you could have a situation
where this is a this is s for example
this is s this is M this is M and this
is no good
even though the counts worked
out
so so you can just you cannot just rely
on the count you see that cuts a corner
I mean that
reduces that means so the algorithm
cannot just simply be counting okay so
you you really have to
um okay let's think about this so this
is one way to go this is going by the
Matrix index like
like the naive
approach in just about any language now
is there some like some more smart
approach uh let's think about it
comments hello
GCS you know it's interesting there are
Speed code ERS who finish coding this in
2 minutes or
three I'm not such people person you
know I don't know how to how they do
it but no do I want to be like them I
mean I mean that's a skill certainly but
it's not something I
Aspire because coding involves you know
coding
the you know I'm starting to digress but
the the core the most important value in
coding in programming is not about speed
it's about solving complex problems the
problems can almost become infinitely
complex because they fundamentally they
become computer
science uh well lots of coding sty lots
of coding expertise skills that's one
thing
skills but then a lot of issues involve
actual computer science
so and in real life coding is
arbitrarily fairly complex so you need
to so speed coding you know the speed
element of
coding is a valuable thing but it's not
very of heavy importance because for
example in real life
coding speed is not that significant I
mean not not not like these speed
coders of course you can't be too slow
you know but the real value in real life
coding depending there are many
different kind of codings but in real
world for example if you work at Google
Microsoft Amazon or any or small company
or doing you know other things in real
life coding the the most utmost
important value is
is about knowing the different it's
about no mastering the language you know
all the construct of the language right
away like you you code it so much you
you don't have to look up the
documentation okay that's one thing you
you need to master the language in real
life usually it's not just one language
you know it's a language if you work in
a web you need to know CSS so well HTML
JavaScript so well and python so well
that's master TR the technology okay
that's one thing but you also need to
actually Master bash and G and the you
know so that's real what but after that
then then you also need to master a lot
protocols like HTTP protocol Json
protocol uh and lots of like almost you
never heard of until you working a job
so the real value the real value of a
skill in coding is about Mass saying the
Technologies like almost like just by by
Road like for example the Unix Unix
shell you just you just remember it and
you can type it out okay but it's not
about
speed
um yeah we are coding but and and also
some thinking okay so that's one aspect
of real coding of course then there's
scientific coding or engineering actual
engineering for example if you are
coding to design a engine for car or for
a rocket or for airplane aerodynamics
analysis that's that's like Beyond
coding okay that's part mathematics so
you need to know a lot mathematics like
using wolam language so that's a
entirely different kind of field
scientific programming
field uh and especially today you got AI
technology a lot most coders actually
don't know how to code AI nor do I but I
you know I have some familiarity you
know I studied it a little bit so anyway
so anyway so anyway let's go back to the
problem okay so you got so you got this
um they are not Engineers yeah that's
true the speed
coders um I mean well yeah that's true I
mean but some of them are you know I
mean I don't want to I mean you I like I
despise them but but some of them are
actually pretty good you know and uh
anyway let's go back to the
problem so you got this situation so we
already know one algorithm is just naive
approach just you know using the Matrix
index check the diagonals so but is
there some kind of like um more um
like more maybe holistic like can you
somehow like recognize the pattern let's
see how
many so they they um two possibilities
of the diagonal two 2 * 2 is four so for
each of the cross each of the valid
cross there are four pass four possible
patterns
okay
so is there some kind of like like one
shot way
to like cookie stamp to
recognize uh all the crosses in this
thing okay so I'm so I'm kind of
digressing a little
bit another interesting thing about
solving this problem this Advent of code
problem is that
typically you see it's one it's one
thing to just give the answer you know
like now I'm wasting time if speed is my
concern I'm really just wasting time
thinking about different
approaches but given a problem you know
so in this problem you seek for answer
right there are many there are many many
actually different
algorithms
um you can arrive at the answer by the
most naive way or
sometimes the concept is similar to
Brute Force you know you just you know
just try all
possibilities and you'll get answer but
um but if you but if you look at other
approaches that even before you code you
know the the the trying
to recognize other
approaches is fairly time cons assuming
you know that that's kind of like a task
by itself for example you know let's say
a interesting question how many
different approaches are there given a
of code problem that's an interesting
issue by itself um anyway I'm I'm
starting to become philosophical so
let's get back to this but so is there a
way to kind of just find the
pattern um
this uh this happened in many of the
Advent of
code problems in the past where you
simply just like be able to find the
pattern for example regular expression
you see regular expression you have a
buildin technology that allows you to
quickly identify string patterns which
which is a sequence of
characters you are able to use regular
expression technology to quickly
identify them without regular expression
it'll take you you know
days to to boot force it you see so
that's so regular expression is kind of
like one level like one one technology
out
there so similarly you know in wam
language you got structural patterns um
and depending on language you have
different kind of features for example
progue allows you
to solve many kind of logical or logic
oriented specification of the problem
easily um so anyway so is there a
pattern like can we so can
we is there some kind of
two-dimensional
pattern technology that
simply let you quickly
recognize for example what we want to do
you know recognize this
course uh anyway
so yeah you know so I'm thinking so
actually so we can find so so if we turn
this into a matrix we can find all
possible submatrixes of 3x3 sub
matrices okay so you just simply call a
command I believe I'm not sure but maybe
there's a uh a wolam language
function that simply given a matrix it
will return all
possible
submatrix 3x3
submatrixes then then you simply go
through each one and check if uh
if if they have this um this corner
patterns in there uh yeah that's that's
another different that's another
approach so instead of going you know
add one or minus one to the indexes you
can
just yeah so that's another so actually
I I find that interesting so is there
a submatrix so is there a so let's see
uh question mark Aster
risk sub Matrix let's see if there any
is there anything
no uh is there a subset Matrix
subset
uh okay no let's see Matrix sub
set okay so let's try again sub Matrix
okay no there's no such
um but it might be named uh you know
depending on the math it might have a
different name Matrix form Matrix matx
function uh hbert Matrix G Matrix
weight I'm pretty sure there is
a sub Matrix function box
Matrix so is that isn't that called when
you do
determinant when you do determinant you
need to get
submatrixes so let's look up
determinant okay I'm kind of the wasting
time uh question mark question mark As
risk
determinant
okay assume determinant
nistic what
there is
some okay I think
uh let's look up the documentation okay
I'm wasting my
time okay experimental I don't want
experimental orthogonal Matrix unitary
Matrix Okay so
normalize uh Matrix predic
Cuts okay so Square
Matrix diagonal matrix upper triangular
Matrix
Matrix symmetric
Matrix can we use symmetric Matrix on
this
no oh but we can do diagonal oh
yeah so if you get di oh yeah so we can
use the diagonal function again which
just return the
diagonal that's right okay that I found
okay so here's another approach so given
this
Matrix we find all diagonals just like
like the part one we find all least of
all
diagonals and we also re uh
and also we reverse the rows and also
find the all diagonals so that will give
us the other diagonal anti- diagonal
that's called so we can find all
diagonals
then then we just check this uh check
the string to find
any m a s o s a
m and and mark their
position then do the same for the anti
diagonal and if the position if in in
the two results
the the intersection I mean if they
share the same position for each element
then that is a
cross that's another approach
okay uh
which is which
is can you know which is maybe it might
be simpler than the naive
approach well the naive approach is
simpler in
concept yeah but then you have to do if
statement don't
you check you know check the next check
the corner
then you have to register a state if
it's m or S then check the other
Corner uh then compare the previous
state it must be the other
one then if that's if that work out it's
another state then you check the anti
diagonal okay so you have to check four
states
basically you okay so but if you do with
the diagonal
approach I think I like the diagonal
approach okay so do you see do you guys
see what
I'm uh thinking so let's see
Matrix and matrices in linear
algebra cross product. product
gome now another issue is that could we
change the letters s and m you know
change all the letters in this in The
Matrix to some
number so that we can simply compute you
know dot product or
something and if it returns zero then we
know we found item that's another that's
another thing to look into actually it's
it's very possible
okay
so constructing matrices okay so um so
now this
normalize uh
dimensions in inverse what does inverse
do oh the that gives you the inverse
Matrix that's not what we
want there is it there it is determinant
just
D okay
[Music]
so so determinant oh minus that's the
one I want that's the what that's the
one gives the minor sub Matrix basically
that's just a submatrix
okay uh wait am I is
that no wait a minute something like
that
no almost okay AB good now what is what
ises the band
mean band means represent the sequence
of positions on a on the diagonal band
that start with a
j okay I'm not not
sure create a band diagonal matrix okay
so okay so let's
Bend
uh okay I'm kind of going nowhere right
now you know exploring this in a
different
way which
risks ending up two hours and still
haven't solved the solution if I start
to code it you know with a naive way I
will have a solution in 30
minutes um
but so what do you guys think you
know okay yeah let me just go through
the interesting approach
minus gives the minus of a matrix now
what what is minus I don't remember
minus of 3x3
Matrix is kind
[Music]
of that's not what we want
okay but we do have
um Abate what is
adjugate adjoint or the adjunct Matrix
okay okay so that's
not that's not what we want we want some
kind
of advanced Matrix operation Matrix
operations okay
we want some kind of
submatrix Matrix rank new space Ro
reduce pseudo inverse
transpose conjugate
transpose oh conjugate transpose that
gives you the other
diagonal probably um or maybe
not okay let's go back uh Trace now what
is Trace
okay
no lower triangular upper triangular
symmetrize
okay
Abate
okay 54 Abate actually just
swaps the
positions and the ne negative part of
it
okay inverse times the determinant okay
so I don't
care
uh permanent what is what is permanent
of a matrix
so what we
want Vector in Matrix you see what we
want is the
um cross product of two vectors no table
array identity Matrix no Dimensions
column Matrix form
uh Matrix power transpose angon values
okay so we uh drop and take testing
searching results okay no that's not
what we want so make Matrix vectors in
Matrix okay so this is
tutorials now we don't want want
tutorials we want the related guide
Matrix
operations rank of a
matrix we want to find submatrix
okay okay so I think we need to look
into arrays okay instead of Matrix
because when you talk about
matrices most mostly they are talking
about mathematical
Concepts basically involving so the
elements of the Matrix are
numbers there are many
properties so that's when you talk about
Matrix
Matrix but what we want is a like
computational operation on arrays so
basically nested
arrays uh linear systems so we we need
to go to a page about arrays okay new
space minor Ro reduce uh yeah so those
are matrices linear Advanced Matrix
operations Spar arrays okay array rules
okay find position value rules for
elements in Spar array array
plot
uh spend
array pad is kind of useful for advant
of code it just pads the array
okay uh you see here is a pattern kind
of
thing uh very interesting
so this is about padding an
array okay so we are getting close to
what we want path right path left Center
array array
flatten uh structure matrices and
convolution kernels okay Center
array creates a list of length n with
elements of a that at the center of or
and zero elsewhere Okay C Center
array uh Center array okay it just
creates yeah it can be arbitrary
arbitrary Dimension basically you create
array in N Dimension and with the center
element
given
uh okay
uh constructing lists
Center array uh so we don't want to
construct we actually we want some kind
of
subset we want the subset all possible
subsets of a matrix okay
[Music]
so so this is not
um oh God select
subsets so let's think about the problem
we want all
possible sub Matrix of a given Matrix we
want all possible
3x3 submatrix okay so the question is is
there a building move function to do
that
and I think
so uh but the problem is just finding
it okay finding uh building symbols so
you can write
it Tech notes related guides
what uh see also
subsequence gives all subsequences
containing
between minimum and maximum
elements does
that
subsequence okay so
no but we getting close so
subsets so those are constructions we
don't want
constructions we want actually we want
permutation uh sequence cases given a
list of sub list in list that match the
sequence pattern okay sequence position
sequence count
sequence so sequence alignment in
comparison okay what is
that now again we want
submatrix we want all possible sub
Matrix I'm not getting anywhere so
let's go here core language
structure Graphics numerical computation
and symbolic
computation uh machine learning stuff
data manipulation
geometry system operation okay so
usually it's a red graph and network
image geometry
linear algebra tensor algebra
um okay tens algebra again we want all
subsets of a
matrix okay it's you need to think about
it subsets or subsets of a
matrix of given
Dimension that must be a common
operation I'm I think so so there must
be a function
um but where is it though Tech
notes God Tech notes tensor array Q
Matrix form array
depth
um outer transpose inner okay inner
forms a generalized inner product with
the
multiplication we want we want just all
possible sub
meses out in a flatten
uh Matrix
power
normal yeah what the
what is cross Matrix cross Matrix gives
a matrix whose elements are one in a
centered cross-shaped region that
extends all positions along each index
Direction
okay
okay dis Matrix you
see Diamond
Matrix okay no
no structure matrices and convolution
[Music]
kernels okay what are
these I think this has to do
with image processing linear algebra or
other
applications okay like right now the
status is that we know the algorithm to
solve this
but we are trying to why we are trying a
particular approach that is find all the
possible submatrix
matrices yes find all possible sub
matrices then it's easy to
determine uh and this approach is
actually much less efficient than the
naive approach appr because the naive
approach all you have to do is you know
all you have to do is to find all the
occurrences of
a okay but if you start with generate
all possible
submatrices then that is actually much
more inefficient yeah okay so that so I
I think let's not do
that no comments
okay okay so uh so I think shall we
actually still
try but
um
but but it bugs
[Music]
me that we don't you know we I need to
find that function I
think will partition work actually
partition might work array reshape
multicolumn
grouping uh what does grouping
do gives a list of all possible
groupings
okay okay
subsets no
subsets okay so maybe not let's not
okay so
now we just do the naive approach okay
so yeah it's already 1 hour okay so we
if we do the naive approach we
yeah
that's I don't want to do the naive
approach well let's start to code it
okay so here's our
Matrix is still
going okay let let's use
[Music]
the let's use the
toy
input okay toy input got a
problem why is that because you haven't
uh what oh yeah you need to name it
input that's
why
okay then do
it okay so you got that
so we turned it into a
matrix uh cases okay it actually turns
out
easy so we so we want to find in this
Matrix expression
all occurrences
of a
okay run
it okay so you need to actually to
specify a
depth Infinity means depth one to
Infinity okay so we got that so we find
all occurrences of this pattern a we
which is just a okay so but instead of
returning it we want the positions
okay give us the positions instead of
just returning the thing okay so
positions of of all occurrences of a
there they there it is okay now let me
double check on the
argument the third argument pattern
level spec that's right level spec to
Infinity uh actually we can just
say negative one means the
leaf okay so that's the all the
positions of a okay so you can just like
do it here we don't need
cases okay so
that that's all positions of a and for
each one
so we we can just Define it so for each
position map to the
positions uh what you want to do with
each you write a function of
course uh so
if the
function the function is going to have a
argument something like that okay okay
wait okay the functions argument is
something like that so
if so actually this not use function
let's just um cases okay let's extract
the
patterns
um extract all the patterns Okay so in
this positions list you want to extract
the pattern such
that you want to extract the pattern you
want to match this pattern such
that this is
not
one uh and
uh so you need also length okay
uh column
count
R row count in column count equals to
dimensions of the Matrix okay so that
gives you the row count and column okay
then then you want to say all the
possible
cases uh this this occurrence of
a position
so so the row is must be not
one and also
not not R
count
okay so
that's and the
column and the
so that's the uh that's the first
element the second element must
be the second element must be not one
and not column
count that's right now did I use not
correctly I don't think so I think it
should be
except yeah so let's check so if except
is one of the pattern it will match if
the element is not whatever the argument
okay
so so in instead of not you should use
except okay so basically position
takes two required argument the first
argument is just this list of positions
of a
then the second argument is a pattern
where the first part is not one or not
the r
account and uh I need to double check
the US of end because you need a
pattern so let's go to uh my wam
tutorial to the pattern matching part so
you go down pattern matching
and uh then you need to go to pattern
syntax and you need to find how do you
express
and conjunction of patterns like two
patterns that both of them must match
okay so you search literal expression
any
expression then go down name a pattern
okay uh sequence of one or
more uh sequence of zero or more
repeat the pattern one or more times
okay repeat the pattern zero or more
times pattern with conditional test no
we want end okay
Alternatives pattern negation except
which we are
using
um wait how how do you say end
oh all not
all uh wait it must be
end so both of these pattern must
match so wait okay pattern gets
confusing how do you say
end you need to think clearly so you got
two
patterns both must satisfy I for I don't
remember what is
it pattern sequence sequence of patterns
so empty sequence okay
uh
except alternative wait how do you say
and condition
okay maybe you should use
condition pattern with condition test
okay pattern and uh a pattern that would
match if pattern P match and the
function works
okay now that is pattern test the the
other one is pattern condition
Okay match pattern P if pattern P match
and test expression evaluate to
True oh
God yeah we can make this work but
oh I got it so we simply put this inside
alternative that's right so we put one
and alternative here and there okay so
that means the pattern the first element
should not be one or the row count okay
and here is the same we put a vertical
line where is the ver IAL line there
okay then column count okay then do that
that that okay that that is our
condition will it work that will remove
for example that will remove the
18 also remove 88 uh also remove 68
because
eight there are total of eight numbers
let's see 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 okay not 8 10 10
so anything involving 10 it will be
removed okay so let's eval
it fantastic you see basically here we
reduced the edge
cases reduce the
a the that are on the edge of Matrix
okay so that
is that
then
uh then we just go through each one of
these and uh God okay let's do
it uh
so so you can map okay you map uh we map
that uh you map a function to it
okay you map a function to this a uh so
for each one so what you're going to do
function oh God Advent of
code you know I I look at Twitter it
seems it's not very popular Advent of
code uh not many people are doing
it by the way I find this girl who is
doing this Advent of code animations
fantastic you see this is actually
yesterday's problem we solved it
yesterday you know don't and do so so he
she created a animation for it that's
interesting that's that's a different
thing uh
okay
stop and you know when you search for
Advent of code hashtag actually most
result is me that's
funny you know that's funny
that I don't know if there's treat by by
us showing my own results
but but my post is only few hundred
views so I mean if you look at the top
it's only
7699 700 point of view uh
views so the event of
code is really not popular I guess you
know and and uh it's not that trivial I
mean it's it's it's more difficult than
the need code in in you know then lots
of these programming exercise so anyway
so
we so you map a function give them a
position you want to check four things
okay uh you want to check
God the tedious coding you know that's
why I don't like the naive approach you
know you need to check the Four
Corners yeah function Exposition
so exposition plus plus
one yeah I don't like
it we can push
on but
um you know so basically the positions
you need to check is
that let me show you the four
possibilities one one one
1A one
one11 okay that's the Four Corners you
need to check and uh actually these two
needs to go together uh wait
these two needs to go together because
then it's the it's
the back slash diagonal these two needs
to go together because the it's the anti
diagonal okay
one wait one negative one yeah uh the
negative one uh
what one and what
one
one1
1 then one and
uh one and negative one so this is the
upper
left1 what okay maybe I'm
drunk now this is the first number is
row
so
one down a row negative one so this is
upper left that's right wait lower left
this is lower left
1 and
uh what this is upper right so this is
incorrect lower left oh okay lower
left wait lower left go to upper right
that that seems to that's
right yeah so that's the four corners
and uh then what you want to do is that
if you want to check if that item is
M oh
God then this item must be S or if this
item is s this is
M yeah t as
if that is true then also if this
is true then then that position should
be there it returns true otherwise
false okay yeah let's just push it
through now
it's 70
minutes I'm doing the Sur r
the pain of coding this is boring you
know this is boring who else is watching
nobody is
watching drinking expired
[Music]
milk you know we got some other coders
you know this guy this this guy is a
nerd this is zel Zelda something like he
like he doesn't read he didn't see you
know my live stream nor did he see my
Twitter post about my code and he's just
like oh but I refuse to read Twitter and
I turn off
preview yeah but you are on my Forum you
refuse Twitter oh that's so great
but then who I mean why should I read or
talk discuss your
code uh anyway so let's go back to this
I don't want to solve this so
you so you check the
element S and M you know interesting you
you got the word
SM with the a in between so it's like
you know SM is a word uh and then you
got
Sam then you got
Mass
H now what about Ms Ms is that a word
well that's a word too
Miss and there's a magazine called Ms
women's magazine
so anyway so you got to check so how do
you do this like in a efficient
way you know the the the naive way is of
course check and register it then check
and compare the state um so one of them
must be M the other one must be
S order doesn't matter okay
so what is like a short way to code
that let's do the long way because I'm
tired
if you know when you start if then it's
all
if if position plus plus that okay uh
yeah that then then you got extract you
know then you got this Parts okay
actually you just say
Matrix M Matrix okay
then
parts let's say three three let me show
you okay uh actually you need
to H where's the
Matrix and we don't have the Matrix
defined we need to generate a matrix
okay so let's say a matrix matx
is 1
2 3
4 okay that's a matrix so if you say a
matrix and you
say
uh first element second element I think
that's no actually I think the
no no wait let's try it again one two
which gives you the first row then the
second column okay that's two now if you
do uh wait yeah okay so that's how you
do
it okay so I mean that's how you extract
element in a matrix okay so back to here
you want to get the Matrix element what
you need to do is
that
yeah
what so what you need to do is that
part
at that okay that will return
that will return the uh element let me
show you okay so for example if your
Matrix
is uh wait a
minute it's more
converson okay so let's go to parts
let's see let's go to parts let's see
let's go to wam Language
tutorial go to
list the fundamentals of list then
positions in a list create list this
operations get parts of
list so
that okay so here's how you
get so when you have at least you just
get uh multiplicities which is which is
not what you
want so you don't want that least you
know
Annoying uh so what you can do is you
can use the position argument
instead okay so let's
check uh not position you want to take
yeah you want to take okay so you want
to
extract extract is a
function that takes a expression and the
position then it returns that element
okay so you extract this Matrix and uh
let's say the position
is one one we will get one because
that's a row one and column one okay so
if it's one two we'll get Row one column
two which is
two uh 2 two will get you four because
that's row two column two okay so here
you want to use um you know the position
yeah you just place the position here
okay that's what you
want okay copy that go back to our here
uh instead of parts so this part is the
Matrix and the part is just
this okay so this returns letter you
know one of the
SMA and stuff then you have to do if
this equals to
A yeah tedious
GCS law are you are you like
finding this funny
now two people
watching
uh so do we should I push on I guess
because if I stop then it's like no
result talked for two hours you
know talking for 80 minutes and no
result
am I am I is my video like
going
well view stream Health good
okay so you can see the this is how you
extract the element so now you have to
say okay so now here's what you have to
say
um yeah you have to say where is the if
statement okay put the if statement
here this is lower right okay so if
this you know this element
is equal
to M for
example uh or equals to S you know one
of these uh
and uh you know and and all and and
all and or all you know
right actually actually this needs to go
together
so okay so it's going to be like
that if
that okay
and okay something like
that or this two needs a
bracket okay Brute Force naive
approach
or
or reverse
order it
so basically that's what that okay so if
you know M and
S you know like one like this so this is
what this is this is this this direction
so if if you got m s o you got M and S
okay then return true
else
Force this pain the ass code this is
like C
style
uh
yeah in fact well you know then you
actually uh
okay so actually more than that okay so
then then you got to do copy the whole
thing okay then the lower La okay
so
so okay so we going to get this
right this right
okay delete that delete DD okay so this
is now this this and
uh that or that that and in fact the
whole
thing put in a parenthesis you
see in fact this whole thing and this
whole
thing is
all so that whole thing
okay if that this this thing is
true uh actually should be end
okay yeah so you need both end so
end
so got so this part is true
and this part is
true
then it's
true okay so now you know since it's a
buing expression we don't even need the
if
statement you see we
simply you know we don't need the if
statement like this expression returns
true true or false by
itself and remove this okay so you
got this
function this and if if and
if so if you know so that is true true
then then it um then what does it return
it returns um okay this are the testing
code remove remove okay testing code
[Music]
remove can we run it yeah okay I think I
can run
it run it and see what happens one shot
coding no Arrow
fantastic now you just
need now you just need to count the
number of true okay
count what does count do well count you
take a list in a pattern okay
so okay let's write a
function count X is the argument and the
pattern the pattern is just true
okay and the apply the function to this
thing to this
this map result okay I think that's the
answer oh God
it n is that
correct is it so n
times it
answer for total input is
nine now we can try our real in you know
actually the code is just a little the
code is not much at
all but uh but that's not El elegant
code that's you
know um but anyway so let's try the real
input you know let's test if we
actually got it
1936 okay it says
1936 my
friend what what what what what what
what what
what
cut do I need to double check no I don't
give
a that's the right answer of course
okay eventually we saw up it because you
know going through the
painful naive approach okay let's let's
come down let's put the code
back um you know and let's review it a
little bit showing
browser cute girl and wolf wolf girl so
we got part two we got lots of
explanation code the
algorithm uh and uh you know we got the
output sample so the code is not you
know not not that
much
uh you know the code is actually not
that much can you can you like shorten
it yeah let's try Okay since we are
already 90 minutes let's do a short
code so first of
all scratch pad
with explanation
explanation okay
EXL
Nation okay that's
uh scratch Pad
code
okay now the real code which we're going
to
shorten uh yeah yeah okay problem
delete identify something
delete uh input The Matrix okay then the
Matrix okay count is is RO count used
yes it's kind of used okay remove remove
remove
uh
positions so do we need R count yeah
kind
of actually no and we can reduce it I
mean we can eliminate
it okay so actually
actually that's
the you know that's the code
now you see now the you see this this
this thing is kind of long can we reduce
it
yes you can reduce it
in in a few ways you know so
but we are already two hours I mean 90
minutes into it I think
let's let it
be okay
so yeah okay I mean that okay yeah let
it be that just that okay so here's a
code
you know let's let's let's do this in
wolam language and uh let's see how it
goes
paste okay let's start over uh okay
let's start from the beginning
paste run
it okay there's the answer
okay okay thank you guys for watching
bye
guys I think like two people
watching I think that's it we did it at
least we
persisted bye guys zen
zen Jang Zen Jang thank you for watching
bye