Hello everyone. Welcome to another
episode of talk show. We are going to
learn F and uh I'm going to write my
learning F tutorial notes.
So this is probably boring for you. If
you want to learn F, there are a lot
nice video tutorials out there,
but I'm just doing it on my own. So, uh
I'm going to write a my tutorial for
learn uh F. And so, you also going to
watch me work with my Emacs. So, this is
kind of Emacs workflow and learning how
to uh learning about F.
If you are watching this offline, play
at two point uh twice as fast. Uh if you
are here, say hi. Okay, love to see your
comments. Let's see.
Okay, so learning F and uh Emacs
workflow. So I'm using Emacs.
Here is my today's talk show page. And
uh the pink window shows all my command
calls and the keystrokes real time
keystrokes on the left. And uh I'm using
a Vorac keyboard layout.
And I'm using a Kafly keys. So if you
don't know what is Vorac keyboard
layout, you can go to my uh Kawar
keyboard blog. Let me show you quickly.
Uh keypad normal laptop keys. Fun
history go history design key cap
special keys layout. So ergonomic
keyboard layout so you can see
this is qui layout most people use and
this is war layout and I'm using um
safly keys. Here's a source code. You
can get get it on GitHub. It is the most
efficient keybinding system for Emacs.
Okay. It's a model keybinding system
like VI. But the command names and the
the command mapping, the key mapping,
the key binding are based on frequency
of the command used. So here is like the
layout. So you don't have to press
control key or meta key. Okay, that's
fly keys and that's war keyboard layout.
So uh let's
close close
showing browser keyboard blog close. So
so let me post the link here so you can
see keys F learning notes ergonomic
keyboard layout. Okay. So let's let's
begin. So I wanted to do
formatting string. So uh wait not
formatting string allow long line char.
Uh there is something I want to do.
Okay.
[clears throat]
Comment print string. So I'm making a
lot progress at F. Format string. Uh no
not that convert string string
operation. Uh
uh escape sequence. What? What was it I
want to do? Uh
comment print
string
string sequence add sign print dollar
sign in string dollar sign as prefix
template interpolated string string
escape sequence.
Not that
uh
oh string
wait there is something I want to do. I
forgot
types. Okay. So yeah. So this literal
types I want to do. So let me show you.
So this literal types those are like
basic types like primitive types in F
and this is from the F documentation. I
want it right now it's formatted as a
table. I want to turn them into code. So
let me show you the uh the documentation
the official documentation. Uh by the
way there's f.org.
That website sucks. Okay. If you want to
learn F, the best resource is the
Microsoft.com.
Learn F. So,
uh, let me show you Fsh
website. So, let me talk about this for
five minutes. F.org. It sucks. Donkey
ass. First of all, you got this logo.
Okay. F logo. Can you see it? Yeah. This
logo is the worst logo because it does
not represent F. does not make you
remember or associate with F or
programming language in any way. This is
just a generic like pretty geometric
modern design. It has nothing. It you
know it there's no f there's no lambda.
There's no programming language there.
Nothing
is designed
um
uh I have a web uh I have a um blog
about it. So this is about logo design
in software industry. So you can see
PowerShell logo. It's a great one
because this symbol is the prompt.
So you can see whenever you have a
shell, you have that prompt and so it's
reminiscent of you know the terminal. It
you know it's a PowerShell. It's a
shell. Okay. So PowerShell logo. So GNU
Emacs logo is also great because GNU
based on the recursive acronym GNU is
not Unix GNU but GNU is this uh cow ox
category of animal so it's a animal head
glue you know and bash logo is also
great because again you have this dollar
sign underscore
reminds you of a prompt pearl is ugly
they choose this logo is which is also
fitting.
Firefox shows a fox windows shows a
window. Guac
uh logo design is also fantastic. Here's
a evolution of guac logo design.
Guac is a slan from nerds from a scient
uh science fiction written by this uh
moon is a beautiful mistress. Um
and you know he wrote a lot a famous
science fiction writer. So he coined the
word guac which is commonly uh used
among the Unix
kind of people elite hacker types you
know guac it means to understand kind of
like a feel like you you can read
programming code and you can get a feel
of uh what it does. So [snorts] uh kind
of like uh empathy for understanding
that's what guac gu
is the eleusk's AI engine. So you know
actually we are looking at guork here I
ask it about f question.
So you can see that's that's gu okay you
see this logo. So gawk lo the meaning
and then logo it began with a slash then
uh it evolved into this symbol. So it
reminds you of a G stylized uh
stylized G and this symbol is also the
symbol for black hole because black hole
kind of look like that you know you got
event horizon so Elamus posts
um frequently about these black hole you
know images.
Guac logo which is also great
and uh so these are great logos. Python,
you know, you know, two snakes, you
know. Python. Python was named after the
the British comedy show
uh called um
called uh uh there's a
name uh
anyway, it's named after Brit, you know,
the the Python. What's the name?
Python
British comedy show. Okay. Why is it
named Python? Oh, Monty Python. That's
right. I think Python is a part of the
person's name. I think I don't know
exactly. Some some of them are very
funny. Okay. Monty Python's Flying
Circus. Okay. So, Python programming
language is named after the show because
the Gido van Rosam the creator of Python
love that show. And then you know after
10 20 years then 30 years then 40 years
he got tired of it uh of it but anyway
that's the origin of Python but
eventually but people don't know about
the show most I mean for vast majority
of majority of people they when they
hear Python they think of the snake of
course because that's a snake's name. So
eventually Gido van Rosam the creator
gave up and adopted the you know say
okay you know let's just stop adapt the
snake logo so they
choose a cubed double snake you know
Python okay so and it reminds you of
Python you know and some micros
systemystem that's also a fantastic
design okay some micros systemystems um
okay I need to change the link uh
because it some micros systemystems
now it's bankrupt it you know that's
that's a guy that's a corporation that
created Java the programming language in
it went it got it it got bankrupt or
sold to Oracle you know the database
extremely evil corporation so they they
are famous for Solaris operating system
which is part of Unix but anyway the
background of Sun Micros systemystems
they came from Stanford University which
is 20 minutes drive from where I live.
Okay. In Palo Alto here we are in
Silicon Valley. Google is 10 minutes
drive you know uh then Palo Alto. So
ecosystem is 20 minutes drive. They from
Stanford University I believe originally
they are named the the company is named
um Standard Stanford University
Networks. So anyway, their logo is made
up of several U's, you know, so but they
kind of spell su n. You see some micros
systemystems fantastic logo design. Now
these are some of the classic logo
design and Solaris is for the Unix
operating system. Of course Solaris
means sun in in French or other um
Spanish related uh languages. We have
the word solar. Solar power of for
example.
So great logo design. Okay.
Hello coffee some ecosystems. Fantastic.
And Linux famous for the penguin. Why
penguin? Because Linux Linux towards the
guy who wrote uh Linux. He likes
Penguin. he likes some kind of a fat
sachiated penguin. So that's where this
uh Linux logo came from. Okay. So he
explained, you know, why he choose the
uh penguin about like 30 years ago in
1990s, early 1990s or late 1990s.
So penguin is for uh Linux and FreeBSD
is uh associated with this Tikeke this
little uh demon monster.
Now I'm not sure how exactly the logo
originates but it is related associated
with this uh demon repres you know demon
is a background process in Unix that's
called demon it just means in windows
terms it's uh it's called background
process like
like if you look at the windows uh task
manager you can see a lot background
processes like you don't you don't you
normally really noticed but there's a
lot running in the background. Okay. But
in Unix or Linux they they call it they
call those demon. Okay. So demon which
is the English word demon you know. So
you have this for example these comics
back in 1980s 1985 a t-shirt you see you
see this bunch of uh demon tikes making
fun and fork and pipe that's all Unix
things. Okay. So the BSD uh logo is also
fitting you know you got a fork there
you got a demon.
So this and Mac OSX you know so Apple
that's another story uh also very
fitting OSX which is uh following the
convention of Unix operating systems
ending in X. For example, you got Unix,
you got
Pix. Pix is the standardized
specification of Unix. And the the name
Pix P O SIX came from Richard Storman.
Richard Stoman the guy who created Emacs
and GNU compiler, you know, he suggested
the word parics. Okay. So, Mac OS X
today is known as Mac OS just but back
then is it was known um M OSX X is
actually stands for 10.
So there's lots of pun going on. Mac OS
XX is the Roman numeral for 10. But X is
also you know following the Unix
convention. Unix, Pix, Mac OSX, HPUS,
uh, HPUX,
IRX from Silicon Graphics. Another
great, fantastic logo, Silicon Graphics.
They also died around 2005 or so. They
um 200 I think early 2004. you know
their logo is a illusion of a you know
you it looks like a hexagon but it's
actually a cube
okay 3D cube SGI so they they are famous
for computer graphics used for example
in uh in movies for example the Jurassic
Park one of the most popular movie
Jurassic Park is created with you know
by silicon graphics Okay, they are
special effects.
Okay, so these are great logos and next
computer from Steve Jobs Apple B O uh
kind kind of dead uh year and I you know
so because they are a media they are
supposed to be a media operating system
from the ground up designed in the in
around 1996
to to to be the vision that we are not
going to carriage uh old baggages of
operating system we're going start fresh
because now is the era of media like
audio files and video files like today
I'm doing uh YouTube live stream video
so that's the story of BOS
that's the uh like a fresh new operating
system designed for media and video and
audio okay uh then and so these are all
great logos and there's of course the uh
lambda the lambda from uh the uh
functional programming languages lisp
scheme you know they all have lambda.
Okay.
So anyway, back to so Java of course
reminds you of the like coffee the a
special type of coffee Java
and GNU again a GNU head GU Emac and
Hascal. So all these are great logos
fantastic and deno for the uh oh I I I
need to make some fix because you see
this logo is not linked.
Let's fix them. Fix them. Okay. So, we
digressed, but um so Deno is the um C
and O. Okay. So,
okay, there's some inconsistencies in my
in my HTML markup. Let's see.
That should fix it. But let's let me
check something. So I don't want the BR.
Okay. So I don't want the BR. Search BR.
So SciHub logo. Beautiful.
And Deno logo. You can see it here in
Emacs. That's why Emacs,
the graphical user interface of Emacs is
much better than running Emacs in um in
terminal.
You see we started Emacs in terminal but
then you don't have you cannot view
images and several other things. Okay, I
have an article on that. Just search
on.info.
You'll find it.
Okay. So, search for BR.
Wait.
Okay. There's no more show in browser.
Go back and go down. Go down. Go down.
Go down. Fantastic. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
F. There it is. Let let me talk about
that. Deno. Okay. Deno is the new
JavaScript
uh compiler and engine from the guy who
created
um
NJS. Okay, N.JS got corrupted by the MPM
guy. Very cor in my opinion a bad guy.
So Deno
uh by Ryan Dah who created NJS he
created a new one Deno about five five
seven years ago. So Deno is the I
recommended Deno. Okay, don't use NJS,
use Deno.
So all these are great um great logos.
And we got Razer kind of also fitting
because that's for gamers and gamers are
typically teenagers and they like this
kind of snake or horror stuff or school,
you know, teenagers, you know, for g
gamers.
So, and this is particular this side
herub is very beautiful logo
[clears throat] a car with stars but the
F logo is the one of the worst okay
because it doesn't show it doesn't you
know it it does not
has no character okay it's just a
generic logo this logo
was created around 2014
that is the era of social justice
warriors, you know, they they promote
feminism, they promote women STEM, you
know, women must work in corporation.
Women should go do programming. They
created all these misery, black life
matters, trans. They say men can get
pregnant. That's that era. Okay. 2014,
like a a little bit before. So, you
know, they are massively promoting women
and they are pushing, you know, they
they are debasing men, especially white
men, okay? Because they
anyway, this is a movement from USA deep
state because they want to control
average citizens power in USA, which
means in USA the average the most
powerful is actually the white people.
So, they want to suppress them. That's
the movement. The whole feminism,
gay, then then LGBTQ,
then trans and black women and lesbians,
they all promote that. The one thing
they don't promote and in fact they kick
is normal white male. You see why they
promote female not male? Because female
female usually they don't have power and
they don't want power. Okay? Usually
it's the males that control everything.
For example, the USA government, the top
let's say 50 heads, they are all white
male. Okay,
almost all all. Okay, so anyway, so F
logo was created in that era and and we
got this very ugly bad thing.
What about some other bad logos? You can
see these are bad logos. You know bash
this is bash logo back in 1990s they
don't have a logo yet so it just say
bash because it's computer render they
thought it's beautiful but remember this
is 1990s not like today you got 3D
engines you got like 20s of them you got
you know all sort of technology and but
back then so for example this herd logo
herd from GNU Richard Stman which is the
vapor wear for like 50 years.
[laughter]
So anyway, back then, you know, they
rendered a 3D uh ball with her. They,
you know, the technology is like very
fancy. Oh, you can do that. Well, I
didn't know like ray traced or whatever,
but but it's not a good logo because it
doesn't it's just it doesn't have any
character, no spunk, no spirit. It does
not associate with whatever the software
the product you know the ident's no
identity okay I heard these are bad
logos and CVS
is the dead technology CVS is the kind
of like like git okay the version
control system back in ' 90s up to 90 up
to two 2000 up to 2010 it's still widely
used for example Ruby the programming
language their logo
uh they are I mean they are still using
CVS even like I I think even seven years
ago they are the last one I'm not sure
did they ever actually switch I think
they did switch to git because git g
eventually took over so CVS is one of
the original uh version control system I
used it like for 10 10 15 years. So, and
Python early early on when Python
doesn't have a logo yet, but people want
the logo because for example, if I'm a
Python fan, I want to promote it, right?
Oh my god, I love this language. I I put
it on my website, but I need to like
some graphics to show it. So, that's why
the people So, all these Python logos
are created by fans. They are not
official. Okay. So for example, this one
is the most popular in 2005.
Python don't officially have a logo but
people created them. So this one is most
used this one. And then there's uh some
others. Okay. Then Python powered. And
here this 16 ton like ink block like
this uh ankle how do you call this thing
that is uh used for Mac Python icon.
Okay. So you guys here uh you guys
comments. Okay. Happy new year ACP
2006.
Hey, does he read chat? Of course I do.
Just slow. Okay.
What do you think about the U web
browser in Emacs? Coffee. Coffee. I just
talk about that for like 20 minutes in
in uh one day ago or two day ago. So
anyway, I do video very frequently
almost every day. So usually I talk
about all sort of things you guys
may have missed or you just search my
website. So let let me let me let me go
to my um
you just click on the search. Okay, then
EW
you will find a complete article on
that.
telling you how to do it. What what what
are the configs? Where are they? Where
is cookie files located? You know, this
is part of my Emacs tutorial. Okay. So,
what do I think about it? Okay, let's
not talk about that because well,
anyway, two days ago or a day ago, we
talked about it. That's the uh why don't
I show you instead of just talking about
it.
Okay. So, talk show go to talk show
homepage. So here is a index and uh so
yesterday that's wam language a demand
of code then two days ago it's learning
f find replace script and here three
days ago episode 739
on January 7th is write emacisp write a
lookup web command and in this video I
demonstrated you because you know so we
have a command and that look up
Wikipedia or Google whatever but show in
you browser. Do I have a screenshot? No.
But uh no but anyway you can watch that
video. So I talked like 20 minutes about
you.
Uh yeah that's not that's not a problem
because because there are literally like
millions of videos. Everyone is doing
videos you know as as life goes on as
the technology goes on like almost
everybody will do a video and nobody can
watch them all right and even you know
there's a lot uh well-known programmers
and also mathematicians and professors
they all all have videos uh and usually
their video is like 300 views
1,000 views not many people watch even
though they are like professors really
uh great programmers for example I I
learned about this this programmer a
very
uh advanced very well-known game
programmer okay uh this guy Casey Mur
Muratori
I I just learned about this guy about a
week ago two a few weeks ago okay so in
fact I have an article on that about OOP
That's what I learned um from him.
Uh Murato just search for his name.
Okay. History of objectoriented
programming by Casey Muratori. So this
video is about an hour I think. So I
watched it. Uh it's fantastic. So this
is the first video by this guy I saw
told to me by my friends on my discord.
Uh we by Lunarus and by Bruce. Bruce is
a great professional gra computer
graphics low low-level computer graphics
programmer
you know he like he code openg like GPU
he code GPU stuff and Ronaris is a
expert in like lots of PC hardware and
Mo this guy Mo is a uh expert in uh
large language machine models
chat bots, AI chat bots and mukovert is
a Unix kind of C programmer expert.
Okay. So anyway, so
uh where will I so I was talking about
this guy. So this is a gamer. Okay. This
is a very well-known accomplished
uh game programmer. Okay. Casey
Muratori.
And I noticed today so he he has a
project. Oh my god. very ambitious.
Okay. Uh but anyway, I noticed today
some of his videos is got like 300
views. Look at look at this. Okay. Like
so this is this is him. So he did a s
series of videos uh Babel on Babylon.
I'm not sure what that is like talking
about science fiction maybe. Like
usually every of his video is like one
hour or two hours long like mine you
know but you know some of the videos
like three years ago 300 views 400 views
200 views like makes you feel sad you
know 1,000 views.
So some of my videos if popular you know
I got 1,000 views or you know the most
popular maybe 3,000 5,000 views. Okay.
So anyway, so what I'm saying is as
you know, and but but also notice
there's no click clickbait, the [ __ ]
clickbait from the Zuma [ __ ] and
the Zuma idiots and the late Malayan.
There's no clickbait in his videos.
There's no
the open mouth, you know, shocking
oh new discovery. Oh, learn this trick
to save your professional life. Then
[ __ ] them the scumbags. Okay, I despise
the zoomers. Anong, you know this these
zoomer they they are that way because
their brain got washed by the deep state
for for for over 10 years.
Zumas they they are like that. So
anyway, this is
uh Casey Muratori. What an odd name uh
Muratori because that sounds like uh
Japanese. So anyway, that's a this this
is a great video. Okay. So, and he has a
a very I I learned I don't know about
this guy, but I just learned you know in
past few days he has a tremendous uh
ambitious project.
So, we can go there. Let's let's, you
know, let's digress. So you go to you go
to his uh YouTube
and then stop that. You go to his So
that's him
>> and part one. What I'd like to the
operational ideas of.
>> So you go to his YouTube homepage.
I got that. It's named Marley Rocket. I
think that's his company or with his
wife uh something. Marley Rocket. That's
uh Casey Mola Tori's uh
homepage v uh YouTube homepage. But you
click on videos. Okay. There's a lot
this, you know. So he did this project
called Handmade Hero. Handmade hero.
Let's open one of them. So So you notice
each one of them is like two hours long.
>> Two hours or you know at least
>> one hour. 2 hours. 2 hours. 2 hours. 2
hours 30 minutes. 2 hours, 1 hours, and
50 minutes. So, he's got this project
called Handmade Hero. Okay. So, let's
open one of them. Random.
What?
Go back. Hand handmade. Uh, not that.
Not that. Okay. Let's open one of them.
Handmade.
Handmade
hero. Day 661.
>> Welcome to Handmade Hero. Show.
>> Okay. So it's all code. It's all this is
C++.
So this project handmade hero is a video
game
>> and he he is basically live coding it
from scratch. No game engine, no physics
engine, no nothing like completely from
scratch.
And as he called, he teach you how it is
done. He explained everything and it
turns out I didn't know, you know, I
just learned about this like two days
ago. So there are about 660
episodes,
one per day, one hour per day. And it
began like 14 years ago. Was it 14 years
ago? you know. So, so he's been doing
this one hour a day from scratch,
writing this game,
one hour a day or two hours a day like
every day for over 10 years. My god,
this is a very big ambitious project.
Okay, you can you can ask guac about
what is handmade uh
about you know you can ask guac what is
handmade hero and guac will give you an
introduction what is you know it is
about so it's amazing you know this guy
uh Casey Muratori
fantastic okay handmade project date 654
so that's that's him so you look at his
videos. You know, one I want to
emphasize again, there's no [ __ ]
clickbait of the Zuma [ __ ]
There's no like, you know, the memes
like the big mouse, the the the the
drama, the [ __ ] None.
Okay. So, excellent.
So, digress.
So, I digressed a lot. So, let's go back
to I was talking about I digress into
talking about logos because
because the F logo sucks sucks donkey
ass. Okay, that's I haven't finished
yet. Okay, that's about logos. But I was
going to talk about why uh f.org
sucks.
Sucks in every way. Okay. Like, okay.
So, you go to the, you know, when you
search F, usually this website shows up
first. Okay. Apparently, it's a
communitydriven.
You know, F is a project of Microsoft
beginning around the year 2001.
So, that's like 25 years ago. Okay.
Microsoft is a blood sucking
corporation.
Fair fairly evil. Okay. They don't
really care about like they just want
money.
But since about 10 years ago, they
became like open source. They became the
biggest open source. Okay, open source
basically been taking over. So if you
are a open source fan
and you know if you are open source
fanatic, if you are open source fine fan
that's okay. But if you are open source
fanatic like shut then then then then
shut the [ __ ] up. You don't like you
don't know what you're talking about.
I've been I've been telling this story
many times in my video. Okay. Anyway,
because the open source people like
today, they have no idea. They they they
just push for whatever the deep state
told them to like like this f.org, you
know. Anyway, so let let's go back to
why this sucks. Okay, so you go to this
site. First of all, the logo is very
bad. Okay, then you got this use f like
what the [ __ ] What does it mean? Use F.
Like typically for programming langu
language website doesn't matter it's
Goland, Python, Ruby, whatever for
programming lang language website
their audience are programmers or
beginner programmers or students. Okay,
you go to the programming language
website. The first thing you want to
know is like download why where do I
download it for my Mac or Windows or up
you know whatever maybe Android on the
phone you know download is the most
important then another most important is
where's the documentation and tutorials
okay download and tutorials and
documentation okay
and possibly another thing important on
the homepage is like um uh testimonials
like maybe you'll show some other famous
programmer oh great F is the best
language I have ever known you know they
have some of that here okay like uh and
also this sponsor you know usually just
like 100 logos this is this this came
from the web framework the JavaScript
not JS MPM [ __ ] so almost every website
they at the bottom you have like one
1000 logos you know like
anyway F Microsoft is is a very uh kind
of
uh poor money organization okay but
anyway they have this website forg so
but so you go to the website then you
got you got this use f okay and you see
you click it nothing happens why because
you they required uh JavaScript
which is which is not a big deal you
know if you choose these days you know
you you you kind of it's necessary
but but but so many other things added
together this website really sucks okay
so now you turn on JavaScript and you
you look at this use F like what the
[ __ ] does it mean use okay oh so
download is here must be F on Mac on
Linux on Windows so that's f Okay. Then
then F for desk desktop apps. Like what
does what the the [ __ ] does it mean?
This is a programming language. Okay.
And most if you are a programmer, a
serious programmer, you are on desktop.
So you download it, right? So what what
why do you have a F for desktop apps?
What does it mean? F for mobile apps.
F# for web apps,
F# for Jupyter notebooks, F# in browser.
So what does the is that? So this is the
is does this mean like a a place you can
try F# language which is also a very
good thing, right? But you don't but you
don't organize it. You shouldn't
organize it, you know, like use F# like
what the [ __ ] use F?
Just download. Okay, download F. Try F
on a website a link not not hidden
behind like a button. I don't want to
click. Don't make user click. Okay, they
click. They don't see nothing because oh
by the way you don't have JavaScript.
You turn on JavaScript then you click
and you don't know what the [ __ ] are
these things. You want it to be clear.
So download try F on the website and
testimonials all the people you know you
might have a SC you know great computer
scientist says F is the best language
you know something like that and then
then documents and tutorials tutorial
first then documentation like API
documentation like for professional F
coders right that's the things you want
the most important okay download link
try it right away and you might have a
code example page somewhere. Uh then uh
download
download link try on the web
uh tutorials and documentation and
testimonials. Okay, these five things
are the most important.
But F# lousy logo then okay I'm not done
yet okay not done yet they got things
you know the concise like Python so this
is part of this this section is part of
the marketing they want to tell you how
great they are in connection with the uh
testimonials so they got testimonials
on this page
not good okay so like Michael Newton who
who is Michael Newton like who
Atala soft is that the guy who create
like github website you know who are
these people then
if they are not too famous remove it you
don't want you know don't don't have
this testimonial occupying huge space
read more about test testimonials in the
dice is that supposed to be random link
anyway so I'm not done yet. Okay. So,
you go to So, so, okay, I want to learn
I want to learn F. I'm a newbie. Okay.
Go to learn, by the way, on the on the
tablet on iOS. Okay. On Apple's phone,
you when you have JavaScript on, you
click the learn, nothing happens. Okay?
Like it doesn't pop up. Like you click,
nothing happens. You click any of these,
nothing happens on the Apple iPad.
just sucks. Okay. Okay. But anyway, um
we are on desktop. So I want to learn.
So you go to learn. Then you got very
confusing bunch of [ __ ] Let me tell
you. Okay. So let's say you know they
got okay learn F then books
documentation. Okay. And papers and
publications. Okay. From academics
uh and video. Okay. Then FSSF. What the
[ __ ] that is? I don't know. Video
community. Oh. So you got like uh you
got this FSSF something channel. Then
you got communities videos. Anyway, I
want to learn. So I click learn, right?
Then a bunch of [ __ ] confusing bag of
[ __ ] It's all here. Like you you you
don't know what which is what. I'm a F.
I I want I heard good things about F. I
want to learn. just just show me one
page or you know here are three
tutorials
try you know try them and see which one
do you like you know maybe three you
don't you don't want a like everybody
every random Joe throwing a link you
know hey F can you include my tutorial
that's what this this page is like okay
F# basic you go there
you go player then who oh god
did I turn uh you know then you went to
Microsoft the [laughter]
okay you go back so it doesn't end here
okay so let's go back so wait you go
back then beginning F video series wait
didn't you didn't I just like you have a
special section for video right why why
you have another video here like is
repeated and from the ground up course
like who wrote this like
and F# for C# you know UDI okay Udemi is
a commercial organization you have to
pay is that right
commercial video like they they are like
tutorial organ uh corporation for
teaching programming look at look at
this look at this this this is um By the
way, you see this kind of thing that's
called um there's a name to that. That's
from the JavaScript late Malay genen.
Malay genen [ __ ] Okay. I have an
article on that. You see this thing?
Uh Jesus.
Okay, let me digress. Okay. So, so
kasali.info info my homepage. So, what
you want to find is a web webdev
history. Okay. The the industrial
uh idiots.
So, go down go down go down. Programming
languages tutorial hacker code. That's
what they are. History of web uh tech.
Okay. User interface design. We spam
scam SEO. Google crimes. Let's see. Uh,
history of web tech. Is that here?
No, it's MPM FI fiasco mware and that
steals Bitcoin, you know. MPM
uh lots of and Apache rewrites history.
Why is it named Apache? Okay. Lots of
story of the open source. I believe
that's user interface design. Yeah. So,
go to user interface design. You got
there skeleton screen. Okay. Now, by the
way, this is called they call it um
Oh, yeah. They call it skeleton screen.
Okay. It began about 2018. So, it's a
Zoomer thing.
And one of the first one who started it
is YouTube. So when you go to a website
before they load everything they show
this gray boxes first okay by this guy
this idiots this like designer okay they
like they are like oh I'm from Google
I'm the headmaster of design this way is
better okay mobile design detail avoid
the spinner okay Luke
Robleski okay that's his name I don't
know anything about this guy Okay, this
is my opinion only. But after I
discovered this very annoying thing
beginning in 2018, I looked into so I
found out that is this guy who began it.
He was the
product director at Google. Okay, this
is my opinion only. Okay, I don't know
anything about this guy, but I think
this skeleton [ __ ] it's a crap this
design. Okay, so that is why you see
this um
let's go back to what we
this this thing and and it's going to
flash you like a like a classic TV or
something.
this UDMI,
you know, UDI began about like 15 years
ago when when the um when the online
programming tutorial start to spread, it
began by the [gasps]
uh what's the name? Do you
[clears throat] guys know? Do you guys
remember?
Okay, comments. Okay. Comments
began like what's the what's a
corporation the first famous corporation
that began the online tutorials?
Um I have a blog on that but I don't for
I don't remember.
Let's not search. Okay. Anyway, I have a
blog on that. I can search it. I can
find it. Let's let's find it.
Uh okay. So show start talk show search
UDM.
Okay. Uh
online tutorial. Okay. Let's search for
review
book review
patterns of software 1996 by Richard
Gabriel 1998. I wrote it. Richard P.
Gabriel is one of the uh founder uh one
one of the pioneer of common lisp
programming language. Okay. He is also
kind of the father of x emacs.
Okay. So what I want to find is the
uh what was I going to find? Uh
oh yeah the first like the the the
beginning of the movement of online
programming tutorials especially video
tutorials then it became a huge industry
about around 2010.
Okay so I have an article on that there.
Okay. Stanford University computer
science courses. Now two this is written
in 2012. Now you have to remember
history. Okay. 2012 is the kind of the
beginning of like iPhone or phone you
know uh handheld smartphone become very
popular for every person to own it and
then it's also when YouTube become more
and more popular you know. So that is
the era 2012. Now 2012 is I believe 2012
or 2011 is the beginning of um of this
rampant movement of online programming
tech tutorial videos. Okay. And many
many commercial organizations sprang up.
Okay. Stanford University is like one of
the kind of one of the first. Okay. So
when I was reading about it, you know,
back then this is news, I look at, oh,
oh, new things. So you they are they
actually have a video course on computer
science now, you know, it's like free.
So I was, you know, looking into it 2012
when I was like that was the year around
that era. I was dying of hunger
because I was just coding emac and free
open source. All my packages are free.
Um anyway, so I was looking into that,
you know. Oh, this is new thing. Let's
check out, you know. So, you got
computer science 101 from this professor
and these are YouTube thumbnails. Okay,
let's click on that. This this course is
about human interaction.
Now, we are actually kind of looking at
history. This is 14 years ago. Okay, 14
years ago. And only 13,000 views. So I
don't think this is very good. This is
human computer interfaces. Okay.
>> You'll learn techniques for human
centered design
>> you know compared to today this is not
good. You just talk. Oh this is only
talking for 42 seconds. Uh so this just
an introduction. Okay.
Uh so close that. So
and and then you have this machine
learning guy. This this guy is kind of
famous. Okay, Andrew NG.
Now, my opinion, I think he's not a good
person. Okay, again, this is my opinion
only. He's one of the guy he's he's one
of the guy who's founded Kosera. Kosa is
one of the first like online video
tutorial. They are they are like for
profit. I believe they are. Okay. But
this Andrew NG guy
in my opinion is a bad person. Okay.
Anyway, that's history. Back then, by
the way, so I wrote this in 2012. At
that time, I don't know who that is, but
now I kind of know a little bit. Okay.
And Okay. Anyway, so so but the
corporation that began it all began this
kind of movement is the uh
uh so you see some of the videos are gun
we are looking at history some of the
videos are deleted for one reason or
another okay so why um
can [clears throat] academy okay this is
the beginning can academy there is a guy
a very talented guy who started to do
YouTube videos teaching you all sort of
things on programming on basic
mathematics you know on trigonometry so
this guy kind of began can academy he
became very famous okay what's his name
uh
so I was you know so this is 2011 I was
like this is novel at the time so I was
looking into it what is this you and
kind of write out my review and uh
summary
uh K Academy. Now what who is the guy I
did I mention it? I forgot but you can
look up. Okay.
So I was saying
so we digressed all over into different
topics. So let's go back to the F. Uh
yeah
ui. So that's why I started to mention
it. Um now some of these course online
course there's lots of controversy you
know they are they were doing nasty
things um like there's also stealing of
courses you know like lots of that going
on
so anyway so I was talking about the
f.org or so they link to UDI.
Why do you do it, you know? So basically
they they just link like all sort of
link. By the way, this F cheat sheet is
very good. Okay, because it is kind of
summarize the entire F in one page. I I
I started to uh know about this uh last
week.
Okay, F cheat sheet. Anyway,
so I think that's it for about that, you
know. So this f or website is sucks.
Then you have
then you have guides, you know, very
confusing. So what what are guides? Like
typically you have guides means a
tutorial, right? like you got tutorials,
you got documentation or you got
documentation API so-called that
you know the beginning of the fad of
mentioning documentation as API began
with Java in 1995.
Okay. Anyway, so usually you have
tutorials and documentation and also
less commonly needed is the language
specification. Okay, they also have it
here. Uh I believe you know again it's
very confusing like I believe it's
papers and uh papers and publications.
You need language specification for
those you know want to implement it.
It's not here you know. So this is very
lousy site books learn F books
documentation. So is it in
documentation? Yeah language reference.
Okay, not too bad. Okay, so anyway then
so typically guide means tutorial but
this guide is what what what is this
guide about?
[laughter] Cloud data access uh data
science enterprise
guide. Okay, let's see cloud guide cloud
programming with F. Okay, some some kind
of guide.
Can you know this should be part of
tutorial like practical like
uh professional level you know part of
the tutorial section that's what they
are and testimonials okay and community
okay oh they got discord I didn't know
uh and then there it is code of conduct
okay
I think that's it for Today I talked for
1 hour exactly.
Yep. And uh I was going to do,
you know, I was just going to do some of
my um writing my tutorial on F, but now
I digressed into
lots of other things. Why f.org the
website sucks. I digress to logos,
history of logos. Um, let's see.
And so that's it for today.
Let's see. Am I popular today? How many
people watch?
Eight people. Okay, not too bad. You
know, when I talk about random things,
usually more people watch.
Um, so that's it for today and I'm just
we're going to shut down in 1 hour and
I'm just going to put some of the links
back to my website. Okay, so back to
today's talk show. Okay,
so we are going to do this but uh forget
it. Uh, okay. We talked about logo. So,
let's put um
Yeah, we talked about a lot of logo
stuff.
Okay, bye guys. Any last words?
Do you use Helex editor? No. Like every
few years there's new generation. They,
you know, there's new editor coming up.
Helix is one of the latest. It is
written by is it rust.
[clears throat]
Okay. Helix matrix. No, we don't want
matrices. Uh editor. Okay. See, I think
it is written by Rust. Is it? Helix
editor is a modern. [ __ ] modern like all
these things idiots they will call
themselves modern modern today not
modern tomorrow you know it's like the
word modern something is kind of
ephemereral
you know by the time
you know you you know by the time you
grew out of teen age it's no longer
modern whatever you are doing uh
terminal based
not
model text editor. Okay, it's like Vim
inspired by Vim and coi
I don't know what that is. Designed for
speed. Well, wait. The most important is
it written in Rust? Yes. [laughter]
There. There it is. You know why that is
the key? Okay. Why? Why Helix blah blah
blah? Well, it's because it's written in
Rust. It's written by Rust fanatics.
Okay, that's why this exist.
Rust fanatics.
Will it last? We don't know. We'll have
to see. Like every every five, every 10
years, five years, every time the new
language come up, people going to write
in that language. For example, 10 years
ago, 15 years ago, about 15 years ago,
there's Hascal,
you know, complete programming editor
written in Haskell. There's actually
more than one. The one is called uh E.
It's dead for a long time, I believe.
Yeah, there it is. Is it still alive?
Let's see. Ye editor star 1.5,000
fork 199
last commit two years ago four years ago
it's still kind of going last commit
three years ago two years ago
you know
the amazing editor written in Hascal the
most advanced language you never heard
of
this is like this is like almost 15
years ago, you know, every five years.
Oh then then then then then then then
the closure then then then there's one
written in closure based on web like new
new thought complete new uh vision you
know that was very popular for like few
years like every every Joe is talking
about it okay that's a history of this
this kind of fat
which
you know which which is just what
happens. You you got fat going on. Uh
okay. But will we or it last? Is it
really good? We we don't we don't know.
I don't know. We have to see. If you
last, you know, then you might be
something.
Uh so actually there's an editor that
was a fat and new and that lasted. Okay,
that editor is called
VS Code. Okay. It was begin it began by
GitHub
about 15 years ago. They have a a
vision. You know, they going to based on
modern programming language JavaScript.
You know, we think Emacs is respectable,
but we think there's a room for
improvement. So we gonna create a new
editor that would com compete that would
you know that would uh you know be you
know
be as good as Emacs with a embedded
programming language JavaScript the
modern programming language that was the
origin of VS code created by GitHub it's
called Atom
okay search for uh not here search for
Atom editor Okay, new page. Atom editor.
Then the GitHub people. You see a
hackable text editor for the 21st
century.
By the way, it's dead. Okay. Atom editor
is dead. It it it it died killed the
project is gun about three or four years
ago. So let me tell you the story. So
Atom editor they began about 15 years
ago. JavaScript JavaScript because
JavaScript became the universal language
you know everyone need you need
JavaScript. Okay.
Then they start in the process they
created the framework JavaScript
framework called um electron
then electron became a project by itself
because it's useful. So electron then
Microsoft take the electron they created
VS code. So they kind of kind of forked
it, faked it.
And now
in 2022, three years ago,
GitHub pronounced atom dead. Okay? No,
there's no atom anymore. Instead,
they recommend, you know, just switch to
VS Code. And VS Code survive. VS Code
not just survive. It's successful. It's
like today the like almost the most
popular text editor VS code. Okay. So
this is a story of text editors. One of
these you know let's create a new one
and this we're going to you know we have
a new vision. Well that VS Code
succeeded VS Code
uh head uh well we don't know. We'll
have to see. Okay. Bye guys. That's it.
Now, if you like if you like my stuff,
enjoyed my show, go to my website, okay?
Talk show kasali.org kasali.info
kasali.info.
Go to all the way to the bottom here is
uh chatgp describing me because they
they all know about me because I've been
writing blogs for 30 years. Okay. So, go
to the bottom pay Patreon me, Amazon
gift card me, PayPal me. Okay.
Bye, guys.