good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
talk show today is 2020 august
13th 7 30 in the afternoon
time allen says we need to say
california time
instead of san francisco time because
san francisco is a
screwed up city but actually that
applies to california in general
so uh my thumbnail my thumbnail so
today's thumbnail let me show you gnu
logo latte
oh yeah latte so here is the new logo
like hey today today's artwork
now this is by a japanese artist you
know this
latte art was popular was a thing
like 10 years ago but now i guess it's
it went away it subsided so there's this
japanese artist
yuko hongdae uh she created
a huge number of uh oops not here okay
she
she created a huge number of
latte art uh all
for all programming language logos or
technology company logos apple logo
microsoft logo linux logo bsd
daemon logo bsd demon attack
and golan logo and and things like that
she has and github logo
so uh where she where is her site though
i mean she has a website that collects
all these let's show
let's see gunu latte
art let's see if we can find her site
now
she has a dedicated domain name
uh okay maybe here
there okay let's show you so there was
the lisp logo
so you see all these logos logos
take programming logos git geek
latte okay that's her uh
okay so let's talk about today's things
close that
go that we're gonna talk about i guess
emacs or keyboards
pic pic pick a choice are we gonna talk
about emacs or keyword like pikachos
right now
we have to begin um okay
pick a choice now
so good morning alan good morning
vernon good morning good morning good
morning
uh so clear thanks for recognizing
california
time california california is going down
okay so what vernon from hong kong
greetings from hong kong
japanese can digest latte they can only
appreciate its appearance
okay so no topic okay amazing
emacs emacs okay so we have two person
saying emacs let's do emacs then
okay so emacs i have i don't know what
to i mean i have some ideas of what to
talk about there is
uh let's go to topics to talk about okay
there's some emac stuff okay
so let's search for emacs emacs emacs
okay there's a dedicated emacs section
let's do some of these
so um
let's see which one of these should i do
update coding star talk show
okay let's let me just do something i
need to do okay
so first of all start star start command
log
mod so on this pink window you can see
all my commands and key strokes i type
so for example when i move cursor when i
uh
delete the paragraph undo and so on
okay and if you found a command you can
look
up on the web usually yours you'll find
my source code
for that command annoyingly yesterday
you know yesterday i did a talk show
about
gnu emacs 27 features you know it's just
a random chat about gnu emacs 27
and i up you know after a while it
becomes a huge rant
you know beginning mildly melodious
voice
we talk about we are thankful of the
of the open source and free software
foundation people
then gradually a little by little it
becomes a huge rent
for 90 minutes and someone annoying
you know someone annoying they made a
comment idiotic uh
john john guy john johnson or something
and he says you know one of the things
let me show you this
sorry youtube should we show it okay
let's show it
since we are starting to talk about that
uh study youtube
let's go there
let's see how am i doing check voice
check video check
so yesterday so yesterday is this
talk show
and then there is a comment
okay a new comment
this idiotic idiotic guy
you know i i shouldn't be so harsh you
know
so he says uh wait yeah
so he says you know start you know john
he he's this guy's john johnstone are
you watching
john stone listen okay i'm gonna give
you a listen you idiot
john johnstone says 14 hours ago start
by
pitching about windows software install
methods
then illustrates how much of a fail
it is in macos you know
he's criticized he's talking about my
video then barely touches
on emacs features too busy moaning about
emacs naming conventions and culture
which we
all know is due to history no
you don't know nothing idiot it is
typical this is fair some somewhat
typical okay
typical replies i get from these tech
geekers
then he says emac smart not mod and i i
guess i pronounce the word mod
wrong like major mode i guess
but you are wrong you are a
idiot you
do you speak english let me show you
okay let's
let's let's see let's see if i'm right
or wrong let's go toward the blog
my wordy blog on literature on logic on
linguistics okay
open a new um section and the mode
okay let's look up the word mode um
okay search uh
in fact let's let's let me show you
since we are doing emacs let me show you
my fantastic comments
you know this guy claims i know nothing
about emacs
he claims you know later on he posted
two comments
you know the second comment says the
more i stepped
in the more i step in on your content
the more i realize you know little about
emacs
[Laughter]
that's entertainment for me
so let's look up the pronunciation
of the english word mod mode let's see
how it's pronounced
so i'm going to call look up
all dictionaries because i look up all
dictionaries
now it will open the browser open
five tabs of different dictionaries why
let me show okay let me show you it's
there
so we have dictionaries so we have uh
here is google dictionary okay google
has their own version of dictionary
since about 10 years ago
now here is the etymology dictionary of
the
word mod major mod or major mode how you
pronounce it we'll find out
in a bit then here is wiktionary okay
wictionary is a grassroots you know like
wikipedia people
you know anyone can edit then we have
the the free dictionary website which is
actually american heritage dictionary
american heritage dictionary is the best
dictionary
why how do i know because i
the number of times i i looked up a word
is more than
more than the number of rice you've ever
ever eaten this
stupid junk guy okay so anyway
literally i i i anyway i'm not going to
go into that so here is the free
dictionary website which is
mostly their primary source is the
american heritage dictionary okay let's
magnify
magnify uh magnify more okay
mode model mod okay now next one
this is stick.org dick.org
is one of the website the free software
or open source phonetics love
this is the open source dictionary okay
they are based on
they are based on a webster dictionary
about you know copyright expired so they
just grab
it then put it there then they try to
modify it like wictionary like wikipedia
like a wiki but they actually didn't
modify
that much so this dick.org
is the open source the basically the
websters they're based on the
uh webster's 700 years 1930
here it is 1913 webster
okay by the way webster dictionary
is different from the merriam webster
dictionary they are entirely different
thing
okay don't get confused and the
merriam-webster dictionary
is actually the most popular because of
marketing like when you
try to look up what your the merriam
webster
will always show on top but their
website
that dictionary is actually based on the
merriam-webster
concise dictionary which is crap okay
crap
uh i can tell you right now okay so so
here is the
uh dick oak okay dick oak is not just
webster 1913 it also contains
uh what's called what net okay what net
wordnet began
around 2000 2006 right okay so
uh what's word net word net is basically
a computer program that's
that crawl the web and and try to um
connect the words and find their
definition by calling the web
something like that it's a computer you
know it's kind of like ai the
early um ai like today's ai fad
machine learning fad so that's what
wordnet.net also give you a dictionary
you know of the definition of the word
mod
then okay so so we got uh how many
dictionaries
wordnet what net webster 1913
we got american hedge heritage
dictionary
we got uh wiki rich chenery we got
etymology we got um google's
dictionary uh by the way i know
merriam-webster because i despise that
merriam-webster
so you have let me repeat again so you
have the command
you have the command um
okay let me show the command cause i
look up all dictionaries okay
in one shot you open five or six
dictionaries and you can look up
and this code is on my web is on mailpad
you can download this package is called
sarlookup.el okay
so um uh
so okay so let me copy that to my um
to my uh so there's a website okay so
let's open the website
showing browser so here's the website
you can
you know it has all these commands you
can you can call
this package is on uh mailpad okay
yep so copy that go but go back to my
talk show and paste it so we can
um uh let's go to talk show okay
let's go back here talk show
today's talk show and paste it here
and let's not forget we are going to
look up the pronunciation
of the word mod to prove the idiocy of
these
tech geekers they think they know
okay so uh so let me show you that okay
i by the way i don't know if i'm correct
you know i'm just
actually i'm fairly confident you know
i'm fairly confident the word
mod or mode can you can be also
pronounced mod
okay so first of all we have uh google
uh
google's um dictionary let's see
you know they they use is this a this is
this
apl i mean is this the um
well i you know i need to show you one
another one of my website is this the um
ipa international pronunciation alphabet
i'm not sure because the americans they
don't know about ipa you know ipa
okay digress digression let's go to my
unicorn website
so unicode saw unicode website magnify
go down go down go down somewhere here
you will have pronunciation
keyboards common symbols punctuation
money signs circles arrows bracket
math math font apl
programming language inverted latin
ipa there it is okay here is the
ipa's international phonetic alphabet
invented by the french you know french
are into standards
so they it's a system it's a phonetic
system that
that supposedly is is it's designed to
be able to annotate the pronunciation
of any human language
okay any it's designed to be that way
so it doesn't matter chinese french
japanese uh
mixed spanish you know it's english
or russian or some african languages
it's you can supposedly you can use this
uh phonetic system to
annotate how they are pronounced but
however the american
our beloved my americans including
myself
well the typically the white america the
american okay they did they don't know
this
uh so you can see here's a table on the
left
on the first column is ipa symbols how
you pronounce the word
for example this is ah dark heart
park car hawk father
ah sound and however in american
dictionary
they don't use this standardized ipa
they use their own they
you know each dictionary they cook up
their own symbol
so in american heritage dictionary the
symbol
similar to ah sound is that with you
know
and in merriam-webster it's also useless
symbol
so this is ipa so now we have let's go
back
to the okay copy copy the
url close it and paste it in my talk
show so we have a
log of what we talked about
so close that now so ipa now let's go
back to the google
dictionary thing okay google so
i'm not sure that is actually ipa or
mod let's see pronounce it
mode okay so it says mode
okay etymology we don't care so here is
the weak
wictionary
mode okay it's also mode
okay now i'll be pissed if the if there
is no dictionary that
that that also says it can be also
pronounced
mod okay
uh okay
they are all mode
mode okay
okay let's see next okay this this this
this is the open source one you know
open source one that is idiotic
they don't you know open source these
open source people and linux typically
they don't
like unicode well they because they you
know they stick to ascii so they are
trying to
you can see they are using this kind of
hack
this you know they love hacks this linux
open source people they use this hack
to represent pronunciation symbols
so anyway the next one okay uh
next one okay so
so i guess he is right that
the word mode you know is is pronounced
mode there's no at least so far i
haven't found a dictionary that actually
say mod
so can anyone do i have any support
does anyone know anyone pronounce that
word mod
oh reaper okay good morning good evening
reaper river is here
okay so so video good
voice melodious uh george edward or
doc's thumb crosses this kind of dumb uh
star russian uh care uh hello world
uh nimshiko hey good morning nimshiko
from hong kong
now mod is for add-ons to programs or
games
mod modification mod so
okay so well i you know so cortez says
it's smart
very different from mode it's very
different from mod you just you
yeah i i you know the meaning is
obviously different
but what i'm talking about is the
pronunciation
so can anyone tell me
have you ever heard the word
mode you know mode pronounced as mod
have you guys ever okay
maybe i'm probably trying to push it
probably probably not okay so he he's
got a point
there so i was incorrect mode not mod
okay
i learned the thing i i have to give him
a
plus sign for that so anyway um
so he says e-max mode not mod then when
new methods tey they do not mean it
works in gui terminal they mean it works
on tty yeah shut up i just i said that
in the video
um and
you see the last line is actually um
suggestive you know he says
you need to grow up and stop with the
unnecessary hate people aren't going to
start using
okay let me let me finish you know
you need to grow up and start with the
unnecessary hate
people are not going to start using
emacs over vs code
sublime because frame windows
okay let me tell you let me give you a
analysis
of this guy's thinking of you know what
he's saying
just just for this sentence okay so he
says i need to grow up
uh and stop with the unnecessarily hate
now he's got a point
okay he's got a point there unnecessary
hate
now you you you not now let me explain
you know he probably have not seen
lots of my videos many of you guys have
you know george allen
and you know many of you guys have
me sorry my life is hate my life with is
hatred
it is hatred that make me
still alive okay now this is you know
to you guys no more people you probably
what like again what the
you know what what a strange idea but
that is kind of true
you know for you know for american
people you know i i don't want to
get into this because i get emotional it
is hate
hatred that is why i'm still
alive okay hate drives me the wheel to
uh
to keep to be alive hate and one of the
things i hate the
other idiotic the unix philosophy the
inca you know
it's not that it's you know it's not the
remember this is important it's not the
people i hate it's
it's a falsity okay first false ideas
lies corruption you lie you
you know you you you you beat people
that that's
that what injustice okay in other words
injustice is the right word i hate
okay and you john
john johnston you are the one of the
idiotic you know
your your post is uh idiotic okay not
not hateful but idiotic
but so anyway let me finish the analysis
so he says
stop with a necessary unnecessary hate
that
you know that's a good point because you
know to be a
human in society you want to prosper and
in general
in general hatred you know deep hate you
know hatred or deep hatred is no good
you want to pass over that you want to
for example the yoda the great
the great yoda of the star wars said
you know uh fear leads to
hate if fear leads to anger anger leads
to hate
and hate leads to uh what what is it
so what he did what was the yoda's line
anyone well okay anyway so hey you know
so he's got point you know you shouldn't
hate so much but he
you see the one thing he does not
realize i mean it's true to say okay
you know don't hate so much but he does
not realize
that hate and love okay hate and love
is part of humanity without hate you
don't really have love they they are
kind of the extreme count
you know they are contrast con you know
the extreme opposite
end of each other hate and love
you know it and it's a fundamental human
emotion
you will cease to be human if you do not
have hate
okay if if the hate the idea the emotion
of hatred does not exist in you
you are not a human you are really
actually you will become
very bizarre you will do uh very you
know things we don't want okay
so this guy you know he's
he's he's a typical i guess he's a
typical nerd where is he come from where
you where you come from
john johnston where you come from how
old are you
what have you done in imax what do you
know are you are you a professor
show your id so anyway the
you know he come and stop with
unnecessarily hate that
that is a good uh suggestion to me
but however not when it's mixed with a
bunch of hateful
you know attacking attacking me you know
he says
he he you know he says a bunch of things
attacking me then
then then he says oh but by the way you
shouldn't you know
you shouldn't have unnecessary hate now
that that's what you are exhibit
exhibiting right now you know so anyway
he doesn't see
he doesn't uh possibly you know he
doesn't see he does doesn't understand
what what is hate he doesn't understand
he
and also i can tell i can tell you at
this moment
this person anna you know just by his
you know the
two paragraphs he wrote i can analyze i
can tell you
he in his life he's probably typical
white american okay he never suffered he
don't know the meaning of the word
suffering he don't he
you know they don't know they don't know
it is these people when they don't know
they
they say this kind of you know oh stop
with stop
stop the hater things you know this like
these people
and they make the world a worse place
they will make the world
uh worse but anyway so that's that part
of the sentence
start with the necessary hate which is
you know a good point
uh and on the other hand he said you
know he says
you need to grow up now that is actually
also a valid point because
me my personality tends to be childish
you know i'm 52 years old but i you
could say i'm still
my personality is kind of still uh
childish not
mature you know mature what is maturity
it's you know you dress with you know
you you put on suits
with thai you talk in a polite way
and you you know uh like trump
but here's the thing what he didn't get
what what he doesn't get
is that they are diverse diversity
that's the word okay in in this world we
have seven billion people
open your eyes okay there are seven
billion people how many people do you
actually know
what kind of personality what kind of
community what kind of you know
uh race have you ever met you know so
many different would
what do you know you know so
so the personality there is so many
personalities some people
let me tell you right now okay some
people are
childish some of the very famous uh
people are childish for example
some for example one of the name you
love okay i'm pretty sure you love john
johnston
that's einstein okay he is he's a
childish guy
many mathematicians and physicists are
like that
childish
uh okay that's that's about that you
know um
child you know so uh there are quite a
quite a lot of examples i can tell you
john holton conway probably is one
one of those uh mathematicians who are
childish in
in his yeah he is john harton conway
who invented you know the his most
famous for
the game of life if you are a nerd or
programmer you probably know
i talked about it quite a few times
scheme of life
john halton conway and he died this year
okay uh very sad he died he passed away
like two or three months ago
of kovit 19. he's the first
person who died of of kovit 19 that
hits me you know because i he he's the
great one of the greatest
mathematician you know um
one of the great mathematician and he's
but also he's one of the mathematicians
i
personally admire the most due to the
subject matter
you know what the type of math he does
you know group theory
kind of geometry and usually beautiful
stuff
john holton conway
childish yeah and you know i i i
actually talked to him
i well not not talk but i uh we have
changed
exchanged emails uh you know one one
time or two
uh in 1990s when i was studying math
deeply so this guy you know he coming in
and then then the you know he made
another reply the more i stepped on your
content the more i realized you know
little about emacs
uh then he says you know then then
stupid things you know the toolkit
chosen is the limitation
for graphical elements being
cross-platform
what the idiot you know i can you know
so he's saying you know he's saying that
um yeah anyway i maybe i should stop
here
okay back to i guess we
keep continue uh talk emacs
the pronunciation okay let me write this
pro initiation of
the word mod okay we talked about that
so the pronunciation of the word mod
okay close that
now what's what's next we're gonna do
emacs and stuff
uh let me read the comments okay i have
been talking for
saudi fan club
now i i realized when i fan the
microphone goes
okay so let's let me read the comments
and let's see how long have i been
talking i've been talking for
i've been renting for half an hour so
today is another
rant
okay i'm gonna i'm gonna just read
comments uh
japanese nerd greetings from hong kong
japanese can digest latte
japanese cannot digest latte okay george
is referring to the
uh the lac la lactose
intolerance something like that but i
actually i drink milk all the time
uh e-max e-max what's the best ergodog
system cluster layout
okay i can tell you that good morning so
i finally catched your live stream hey
oh ro old and roll racks
over them roll racks ergodox thumb
cluster is kind of dumb
don't know what to put where okay i can
tell you
about orgodox uh
everyone says mode mode okay so ripper
uh good evening russian care mode
mode modi's
okay okay okay
okay okay okay mode okay
okay so you guys are saying emacs we
need to talk about emacs
uh acceptable exact quotes is coming out
as a sith
oh yes
uh i'm late to the party papamum hey
lunarius
lunarius greetings to canada
and the kasaka never stopped hating tsar
uh i didn't miss this time so lakasaka i
forgot where you from are you from the
uh
mexican or right
so anyway so that's a bit digression
that's a
giant digression for 30 minutes about
hatred
uh keyboard okay let's let's let's let's
talk
one thing about this keyboard oh god
stumps so
uh orgodox keyboard is very popular do
it yourself keyboard is one of the first
that began the do itself craze in 2013
yeah
in 30 in 2013 and
it so in 2013 this is the year
that the do-it-yourself keyboard begin
almost basically you know it becomes a
fad
then this is the first one and actually
back then
the ergo this is also 2013
that we started to have lots of
ergonomic keyboards
not just do it yourself but from actual
manufacturers
you know the manufacturing ergonomic
keyboards and one of the first one is
truly ergonomic keyboard
now this is their later version but the
first version is this one
it came out in 2013 okay this one i have
now where is it i you know i have it in
a box
uh yeah i have this keyboard um
so alan possibly allen is coming to
visit me
you know i have some alan if you want it
you can have it okay
i actually i don't want to give out this
one
you know but you are a good friend
uh so so 2013
is when all you know when we started to
see
a whole bunch of ergonomic keyboards
coming up becomes a fact
it becomes becomes more accepted
and also 2013 is when we started to have
a whole lot of do-it-yourself keyboards
you know many of them are not
ergonomic many of them are you know
flank
prank a plan came out in 2014
2016. uh so anyway back to the
let me just quickly finish the orgodox
thing so orgodox
is the first one okay the first one they
are mod they are copy they are copied
they are based on um
you know they let me show you my
keyboard again they are they are a copy
i mean kind of a clone of
by of the kinesis uh advantage too
buy it okay buy it for my website
i make a few bucks
you happy me happy we both happy
okay um so
but ergodox has a problem you know kind
of a problem some people don't doesn't
agree like that a few days ago
last week or so we argued i argued with
a guy on my discord you know he says oh
actually orgodox is fine you don't have
some problems
not really i mean relatively speaking
when you compare
i mean what what what does it mean when
i say this keyboard got a problem
that is when you compare this keyboard
to all the other similar
similar that that that
are similar in terms of price and
availability
ergo docs do have a problem thumb key
problem
what is the problem that the problem is
the thumb the thumb keys are kind of too
far
so especially if you have have a small
if you don't have a
if you don't play basketball like
basketball player
if you are average let's say average
asian then
you'll find that the thumb keys is a bit
far every time you want to press space
you have to kind of move a little bit
like that okay so that is a problem
so in fact there is a fan
a big fan of ergodox
who um you know i have quite a few
photos you know like like this is how
you rest your thumb
you know this guy nabi which is on
discord and one day he rage quit
because because he think i argue i
i i argue with him too much
you know anyway so you know he's this
his photo he's a great guy okay so he
this is
you know he you got this uh
that's the place you rest your thumb so
ideally
the thumb key this should be moved
closer inside you know
so it's got a thumb key problem in fact
it's it's quite a big problem because
have there are there are a lot of people
who have complained about it
in fact there is this guy who develo
developed
some pen you know actual pen you're
going to see a doctor
it's going to ruin your programming
career if you start you know if you
don't
fix it some uh some
some key pen so in fact he wrote the
article
uh he wrote the article about it here
his name
you know he's this this guy is a pretty
popular guy that read
on the on the hacker on the geek hack
website gig hack
gig hack website is one of the earliest
website for keyboard phonetics they talk
about keywords
so he was uh he he loved ergodox he
bought
two or three you know then he's telling
everyone you should get an ergo dogs
orga dogs
but one day he started to feel pain
and he's he's not sure what's going on
then then he tried to adjust the angle
then and all flat then pen went away but
it came back
then eventually he realized the problem
is the thumb key you moved your thumb
too much
then he sold he then he he decided he
sold all his orthodox
then he bought he bought you know he
bought the
those he bought this i can tell you what
which one she
you know you can read the article he
bought hold on a second let me copy it
to my talk
show page okay then he bought this
one he he bought this um the the classic
great keyboard uh nissan the
fecal majestic no um
he bought the this port okay not this
one
neoport fc660c very expensive this one
this thing is 250 or something
no good okay i don't recommend it so
anyway that's his story thumbpain so you
want to be careful when you
get orthodox you want to be careful
okay what's the alternative there are
quite a few okay for ex
for example uh this one this one he's
talking
many people have talked about this you
can see on gig hack
or on reddit now and then you know
um so you want the thumb keys to be
like a fan okay like a fan
you know smooth distributed all over the
place
so that doesn't matter which side you
know whether you have big hands or
smaller hands you can find a key that's
right for your thumb
for example like this one actually i
pretty i like this
this design very much you see this these
thumb keys are in a fan shape you know
four of them
uh pretty much no gaps in between
or but alternatively you can buy this
diverge
keyboard it's which is also improvement
of
ergodox you know this you look at the
thumb keys
three is is optimal three thumb keys for
each thumb
each hand is optimal because if you have
more thumb
you have to move your thumb more so you
see
you want the thumb keys to be spread out
and no gap in between so that doesn't
matter which size you have
your hand size you can you have the you
can find
typically you can usually find the right
spot that's one solution
you know there are many others you know
so you can by the way the diverge
is also you can also buy it previewed
okay it's also pre
pre-built and in fact we have so many
uh other ergodog variations you know you
pay attention to their thumb key
arrangement they are all
you know they just like i said you see
for example this one
for this one is ergo dash which is also
a variation of orthodox
you see you know you have these three
thumb keys
there which is okay reasonable
and and also google plex is also good
because you see
now you have a big you know you have a
wide thumb key
you know so that also works
but this guy i forgot his name you know
he's keep arguing with me
he don't unders you know sometimes i
argue with these notes a lot you know i
you know partly because my personality
i'm
i'm extremely competitive and i
am also extremely argumentative and also
i need to correct someone who is wrong
on the internet
okay more than any of you probably
probably okay
so someone is wrong on the internet i
need to correct it
yeah i'm like that uh
you know so but i mean so i argued you
know he's saying
yeah but the organ dogs has no problem
but i always
keep he doesn't you know he doesn't
see my point i mean even i've written
out right there but he
it seems like it just skips you know
sometimes it's like that when you talk
about
religion or politics you know when you
talk about someone who have different
opinions on religion or politics
you say something like that it's almost
you know it what you said doesn't get
into their brain it's like they
it auto automatically skipped
that happens you know that is why
uh you know talking about religion or
sensitive issues sometimes it's not it's
not a matter
of logic you know it's not like i'm
logical you are logical then we can
find a solution or find way you know
usually it's not like that
especially when it it involves
power what does power mean what does
power power mean
basically politics what does it mean
that means here's a piece of
pizza okay either i ate it or you eat it
we cannot cut
it that's politics so when he loves
politics usually you know it's not
resolvable by logic
religion is pretty much the same same
because religion
is deeply tied to uh politics power
struggle
because religion is your thought your
your
well anyway that's getting far that's
getting another topic so
okay so i hope that um that is my
opinion about how
do you use how do you solve the thermal
key problem so by the way
the ogo one of the ergo docs
people they make ergo dogs easy
so one of the maker of orgodocs they
created
you know they they sell ergodogs they
call their ergodox ergodox
easy so they created a new version
this moonlander keyboard
and in my opinion it's no good okay uh
well they didn't fix the thumb problem
so they in this
in this keyboard they have this hinge so
that
so that your thumb can you know this
they have this hinge
so it's adjustable so instead of a flat
now you have like kind of angle so you
can
so instead of thumb pushing down you can
now it's kind of like that a little bit
you can adjust it
but they didn't fix the thumb too far
problem because
if you compare this with ergo docs the
thumb keys
it's not it's basically not you know you
look at the position it's not much of a
improvement
okay so yeah there are so that's about
that so do we have still have time to
talk about uh
emacs or so let's see how long
have i been talking
46 minutes okay let's keep talking then
uh 10 minutes 15 minutes or something
then we can we should talk about emacs
but
today's already gone we can talk about
tomorrow the
spice must flow so alan says
socially acceptable czar quotes star
wars
uh science is coming out as a sith
relate to the party okay no comments
is from guatemala now i remember yeah so
you posted some food there
and yeah before uh
vernon says so take a look at
yape it's an open source
tiling window manager for mac it might
help you better manage
all these open windows are you kidding
are you trolling me uh you know i
don't like the open source window
managers i don't like window manager
you know the linux window managers in
fact that's what being i've been talking
i talked about that in one of my talk
show for one hour oh my god japanese
anime
uh window manager okay
i don't think i like it i don't want to
install anything on my mac
i don't want to install i'm trying to
remain minimum
and i i will not be interested i'm
pretty sure
so yeah buy is a window manager
management utility that is designed to
work as an
extension to the building window manager
of mac os
okay jabba allows you to control your
windows spaces
and displays freely using an intuitive
command line interface and optionally
set user defined keyboard shortcuts
using that and other third-party
software
the primary function of java is tiny
window management yeah yeah yeah
no no i wouldn't be interested
okay uh true ergonomic cleave are being
begun to shift now yes
that's good okay
so we come to a stop what else to talk
about now we can
we you know we digress and it becomes uh
rant and keyboard and
so now we can actually go back to
talking about some emac stuff because
there are some emac stuff i want to do
oh should we you know if you have
opinions post right now post right now
like emacs because i can actually i can
start to do some emacs right now for 15
minutes for 10 minutes why not
uh let's see where okay so go back to
emacs
so i want to do some emacs
open okay so i need to do a commit let's
do that
so i want to go to uh the source code of
html mode so what i do
so so describe key
space space space edge that's how i
go to my uh source code so you see
here is a window the here is the
html
okay let me let me start again so what i
want to do i want to go to the source
code of
html mod how do i do it well one way is
to use a bookmark
i showed you many times yesterday and
before another way
typically when i want to go to any file
that is a source code of emacs lisp
okay source code of emac list you want
to go to
that file there's a trick you don't have
to
create a bookmark for it what you do
is you just call you just call describe
function
for a command of that mod then you can
easily go it describe function or
describe key you know any key of that
particular mod for example
let's say i want to uh let's say i want
to go to
uh size html mod okay
so i know i have a key the key to invoke
so the command x html mod is space space
space
edge okay so now i just call describe
key
then i type the key space space space
edge
then it shows me the documentation for
the mod
uk enemy magnify you see the the
documentation
for html mod now i can just tab
to the link and and press enter here i
am so you see
uh here i am that's the source code of
you know that if we go to the top you
can see that's the source code of
html okay so that's the trick
to quickly open any
emacs leaves this package source code
without going into a directory you know
where is it where is you know what
directory it is you know you don't have
to do that all you
need to know is to know to know the
command name or keystroke of that mod
then just call describe function or
describe key
okay now i'm here what i want to do i
want to call magic okay
so i have the shortcut ms ms
stands for magic status
okay so here we are so you can see let's
magnify
unsplit and go cruiser down and press
tab on this press tab on here
that will expand that will tell me what
has been changed
so i have changed two lines
okay now go back to the file close this
go back to the file i want to change the
version number okay
so copy it paste it here delete that
last part
control u space eu
okay it asked me to insert a date a
format
i say two okay now i have a new uh
date kind of date format
which is 2020 august 13th
and august 13th then 20 20 o'clock
25 seconds and 54
uh decimal seconds fraction
so i updated that yeah that's all i want
to do wait
yeah so it did so you see this this line
is different from
this side although the last two digits
happens to be the same so i updated the
version number
save it go back to match it again ms
okay now you can see another part has
been changed
so i okay i go here tab to collapse it
and i press s to stage
it then i press cc to commit it
okay wait um
uh c c yeah
so now i i need to type um
what did i change okay so
i what i changed
okay
okay so html opening chrome improved
okay let's just say that
minor improvement you know there is no
need to go into detail is because
it's hard to describe so okay now it's
um
committed now i need to push to the
server github
so capital p p magic push
so now it's pushed to my server so
that's kind of a
little a little bit of my emacs workflow
so then close it close it and close the
source code
close it okay what else i wanted to do
here
update the code in star talk show okay
so i did actually so
yeah um okay
let's see the comments and maybe that's
it for today comments and questions
no more comments am i imagine let's see
[Music]
today's drink jamba juice
first energy drink
oh so george says why should a vim user
switch to emacs
vim just works
george george you use vim oh my god
so why should you well well
it's funny you asked that question have
you not seen the power
of emacs have you not
[Laughter]
you have watched so many of my shows
have you not seen the power of emacs
now well compared to vim yes
so i'm implying that emacs is far more
powerful than vim
so you do not agree do you not agree
emacs is far more powerful than vim
so so why should a vim user use emacs
first of all
it's up to your taste you can you know i
mean i mean that's
usually when when people ask that
question it's not a practical question
because in practice if you like rim just
using
you know don't think about oh whether
should you you know which one is better
this
doesn't make much sense you know keep
using whatever you use
you can use vs code whatever it works
for you but however there's a
there is indeed an aspect of improvement
it is possible that you will find
that you can find a better solution
improvement of your workflow
more efficient less keystrokes less
tiring
you know less thinking when you use it
it's possible so
of course you have many choices also it
also depends on what languages you
program what kind of things you do
or are you just a novel writer are you a
novel writer
are you a programmer are you are you a
blog writer
not non-technical you know you write
other things novels for example
or are you a java programmer or are you
a c
plus plus plus programmer this you know
different programming language is if
it's your job
it did it does affect what kind of
editor you use
because for some editors they are more
um
let's say not specialized but i mean
they are certainly specialized editors
just for java
especially java language but in general
general text editors certain ones are
better than the other
for a particular language for example if
you are a java coder
then emax is not good so good okay
in general you know if you are a java
coder
you probably better off using um
you know some other commercial ides
but if you are a web developer okay job
javascript
you know html css emacs is fantastic
emacs is i would even claim emacs is
better than any other
okay so let me finish my point so why do
you why should you choose many different
editors let me summarize okay so first
of all it's not a practical
question use whatever you you're happy
with
then but they indeed you could improve
your workflow or learn
new things so you want to find
you know you can go explore in your
lifetime
you know you don't have to do it today
but you know you know
when you have time over your programming
career or whatever career
so over the span of three years five
years you you may gravitate you know you
may find
an editor that you like better that
makes you
uh that makes that
you like better that makes you uh that's
more efficient for you
that happens and also more powerful for
example
if you if you just each
for example uh commonly people say vi
is great for text editing you know but
when it comes to extension and
extensibility emacs is much better in
general okay
and also but however the emacs default
keys
it's terrible i mean if you all you do
is
text editing you know you don't compile
programs
you don't need to have
many different tools you know like when
i do html you have seen
i can make a list and so on you know
there's many things you do with it
not just i mean by text editing it
doesn't mean
you know you just delete characters one
at a time or some things like that
there's so many
things in power so
and for example for example augment org
mod is a
a great example org mod you know you can
uh use it for your to-do
and whatever and it has lots of features
you know and you can export to
html you can write documentations in org
mod
you can write you know what they call uh
verifiable programming very variable
science or whatever they call it you
know they have a jargon
it's like you know that you can write
augment you know
you can embed code in oak mod so you
have code and
it and words explanation at the same
time so
in other words there are so many
different uses you can run xiaomi max
but if you
are a vim user veeam user typically you
edit in vim
but then you exit veeam to rely on the
shell
and usually at least traditionally
you rely on the shell the unix shell
typically
to do lots of other things
and i know being started to
to have more features like um but anyway
so
so i i hope i guess by now you've seen
you can you can see
there are many different uses so why
should you
use emacs i would say because emacs is
much more powerful
it's much more flexible and it's
much more correct okay it's the
proper way i don't like vim okay well
yeah i don't like the vim
vim came from the root of vim okay vi
not lim you know vin became popular now
you know back then you have vi
then you have elvis you have quite a few
but it so happens the vin becomes the
one replacing vi
anyway vi vi is the
vi is one of the classic unix philosophy
okay it's i despise i despise very much
now back then in the 1980s it's
typically unix
unix versus lisp there are two different
words so these people is one word
then you have the unix people they live
in another world
they are typically an antithesis of each
other
they don't like each other's philosophy
and i
have always uh i always despise the unix
camp and vim vi
is one of the classic unix thing because
it's like it's like you hack hack is the
essence of the unix thing
everything in unix c the language unix
shells unix tools
uh hack you know vi so what
let me tell you a story why is meme you
know in veeam you have
mods you know modes mode mode like so
you switch to insert mod then you switch
to command mod
you know in fact this is a great thing
actually if you really are concerned
about keystrokes
you want to minimize programmer's
keystroke model is
actually the best way the best system
you you have to have model so sapphire
keys is also model
okay stuff like is in e-max
not in vim but i
actually i anyway
so vim is one of the classic unix
roots you know the hack hack is their
essence
so you in veeam in vi you have model
thing
where does it come from you know the
model thing back in 1980s
you know you have a monitor that's 80
characters by 24 characters
so it's like pretty small so it's 80
characters okay show ruler let me show
you what it looks like
so back in 2000 um let's see uh
hold on a second let me show you
okay so back in 1980s
this your screen looks like this this
big okay
well actually that's uh yeah that's
actually more than
where i'm actually giving much more
credit because my resolution is even
more dense but anyway 20 80 characters
80 cap columns by 20
24 lines am i right
yeah so you and it can not only display
text
no graphics so vim so back then you
don't have real-time display editor
like what you do is you type a command
then you tell the computer i'm done okay
press the key enter or something then
you give it another command you type
another command to tell the computer
to update the screen okay so it's like
that
and vi is a consequence
vi inherited that
uh so that's why you have model mod so
it so this
is not you know it is not because
the model not mod the model mod did not
come
because of someone sit down and think
about it oh
you know he think about all possible
ways to create a text editor
and he discovered moto mod and he
decided oh yeah model mod is better
therefore he created a model mod and
created vi that's not like that the vi
model mod came from
you know you have to give a command to
the computer then give it another
command to tell it to update
then give it another command to tell it
to you want to move kusa to the left
five
five characters then tell another
command to tell
the screen to update it so you have mods
so vi the way vi came by is just
happenstance hack
it's all hacks unix philosophy
okay that's it for today that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
bye guys uh we we're gonna we shut down
in two minutes then
do
adios sensa where are you from since are
you in you are
in china right good night thanks for the
show
check shop thank you have a good day
bye guys
we will see you tomorrow see you all
tomorrow and join this code okay
i just showed my friend list
you