hello welcome to another episode of exan
talk show today we are going to code
emac LP emac lisp and maybe some random
chat okay if you are here say hi I'm a
nerd I'm this is talk show I talk about
random things of nerd interest usually
programming programming languages
mathematics artificial intelligence uh
information Wikipedia things like that
and sometimes
sometimes politics American okay uh okay
so if you are here say hi and if you are
watching this offline feel free to skip
and play at speed to or
something okay let's begin uh coding
lisp okay my keyboards glove 80 most
fantastic keyboards ultimate hacking
keyboard okay fantastic newly ATT
trackable okay and uh and again this
thing SM board data hand okay I'm going
to use it but sorry not yet Smartboard
data hand this is most advanced keyboard
This is SV a l b o a r d okay you can
search online search any of these
keyboards you'll find my
reviews and the
photos uh and video reviews okay now
let's begin begin emac this coding so uh
so what I need to do today let's stop
this stop
it what I need to do today is uh uh it's
uh emac this WR a command HTML add
attribute so let me explain first of all
this is uh for example I'm inar HTML
mod here's a documentation jump to the
source code see it expand the window all
the way to the bottom 2,600 lines of
code actually there's more than 6,000
lines of code because there are multiple
multiple
files let's see let me show you you see
there are 1 2 3 4 five six seven eight
eight files because I compartment tized
modulized you know so you have htmr
engine so they are
I think 600 lines of code okay so you
have to pay to buy it because for 15
years all my stuff is free people don't
pay and I become tech support and people
[ __ ] people you know this open source
uh they don't give a [ __ ] so anyway HTML
mod that's what I'm using so copy
the file path close it close it close it
go go right here paste it make a link
make a link and make a list showing
browser so that's allar HTML mod and
today we are just going to add a new
command now let me introduce you to the
pink window the pink window so you can
see they are all the command CES and
names I just called you see HTML
something something command name on the
right side and the key strokes on the
left side there's
no uh control key ever pressed there's
no meta key uh because I'm using Sly
Keys search it you'll find it it's the
most efficient emac key binding system
more efficient than Vim VI Neo Vim or
EVO
mod okay so you don't I don't have to
press control keys but why is there a
control key there CW that means control
W that is because I'm pressing this key
now if you look at my keyboard you see
right here this key or this key you know
that's my Marco key so so watch okay so
I'm going to press this key now okay
first of all move it move the coer to
the um to the emac window okay so okay
now I got press this key so you watch
watch the pink window to see the command
name and keystroke watch the this honey
dual window to
see this window get this you know
something okay I'm going to do it one
two three you see so the command is
called close Cent buffer it says control
W but I didn't press control that is
because this key or this key is doing
marel keyboard marle so let me show you
in emac you do and it just closed my
that emac buffer so I press a key again
you see that's open as Clos that's part
of the commanding soft keys it just open
this again so I
can uh for example showing browser this
key okay back so it's all single key
press there's no control so for example
how do
I make sure convince you that this is a
Marco Key Well I can I mean I can show
you so in emx you call you call this
command called describe key so it now
ask you to press the key at the bottom
you can see so now I press this key
press so you see CW runs the command
close con okay so that's how it all
check out checks out okay so so I have
HTML mod so what I'm doing so I need to
add a new command so I mean the new
command is called s HTML add attribute
okay that's what we got going to write
it so start a new um EAC disp EAC this
so this is part of HTML mod paste it
that's a command we going to write move
the cluer here press the button it pops
it into
AA lisp mod you know into a new buffer a
temp temp
buffer cut that default Define enter
defund oh Define fun fantastic now paste
it okay that is the command we're going
to write today this command will add
attribute okay let's just write add uh
add documentation add an
attribute
attribute let's see you know do you
touch
type A lot of people they don't touch
type they are programmers but they are
shy from Declaration of the fact that
they don't touch type because it is a
stigma
it's a sensitive issue because oh you
are a professional programmer but you
don't touch type what the [ __ ] you know
but it is a fact I think majority of
programmers more than 50% professional
programmers meaning that they make money
out of programming they don't touch type
okay and you should okay uh you know but
but they they they touch type in their
own way like like they don't follow the
stand but they claim they Proclaim well
actually I do touch type I don't I just
don't touch type in your standard way no
that's not touch typing how do you know
if you are
truly capable of touch typing close your
eyes okay for example let's write this
command add an attrib okay let's
document now close your eyes close my
eyes so how can I well I need to put on
a helmet
do I have something like
that no yes what is this let's
see no that's just a string
okay uh anyway touch type okay so let's
see um you know you can just say what is
this
um HTML add attribute
Okay add an attrib rute to an
HTML
tag okay something like that actually to
the to the H to the current okay
to the current something like that okay
we'll have to oh mix missed an a we'll
have to
fix uh we'll have to do
edit um proof read and editing what
what's the what's the name you know of
the the documentation later but anyway
let's keep going on so why do I need
this command so let's pop it back syntax
CCT showing browser okay let me explain
about that a little bit
because inide HTML you can insert any
tag for
example uh let's say dive so you just
call this command you know this key HTML
insert tag you can see the command name
in the pink window so then it pop up all
a list of available legal valid tags so
you can type you know nav then then that
inserts a navag nav tag
okay but what if you want a tag let's
say dive with an ID
attribute okay so let's put the C let's
start over here so you call Universal
command first
which in soft like ke is space V okay in
V layout space V you can see
um you know anyway space V okay so now I
call the command to insert tag so I say
dive like before enter then it asks me
for a class name okay and just say enter
ID Auto enter there we have it you got
the ID uh random you unique ID unique
you know
this statistically speaking V are
probability this generated string is
unique
okay the chances that this string is not
unique is less than the chances you get
Stroke by lightning okay something like
that actually maybe I need to add a few
more digits hello guys good morning
who's here Dam dam hello good morning
good afternoon good evening
damc I do I just moved to comac from quy
it was a pain to leave my 80 W per
minute speed
okay uh what's the context I forgot but
anyway you use coac that's
good us um me be or you can
be okay so we have a command that adds a
ID and class so why do I need to to to
um to to write this command add
attribute that is when you are on a
existing tag for example this this preag
let's say I want to add an ID to it you
know so I have I got to move the CER to
the proper position like here or here
then ID equals to oh okay actually that
expand to
oh that exp to I would okay so but
anyway you add ID like that so so I want
to kind of Auto automate it I mean it's
no big deal but the little things set up
so I just press a key it automatically
move moves my cser to the current TX uh
the current tags so for example if my
CER is here the current tag is that span
class fold so you'll just move my C to
the current TX you know beginning
opening
tag position and properly you know
position inside it then you'll add an ID
or class or whatever tag okay
and uh and we can also make it pop up
just like before you know pop up a
selection of choices a menu of the legal
TX so this will save you a lot of time
so you type D you know then you get all
the Val you know only the valid TX that
contains the letter D okay so DD for
example then you have you know
so if if you add that feature
then it will only add possible
attributes for this specific tag for
example if you have a
image let's let's say let's copy a image
okay let's
say let's make a screenshot okay there
it is now I there's a command you can I
can press a key that image is moved here
you can you see it just added that
block and you move the cluer there open
it there it is this is supremely
efficient if you are a blogger you know
you just do a screenshot anywhere then
press a few Keys it will it will put
that screen image with the proper tag
into your buffer and that command is of
course um that command is here somewhere
HTML move image file and and if you look
at the pink window most of my commands
you can just type of uh you can just
search it for
example search that command name there
it is HTML my tutorial uh there move
image file Oro emx oh stupid Brave you
know stupid Brave is still using my Ogo
emx domain it doesn't
uh you know but anyway the link has
changed you see so here is a source code
you can copy and you will have this
feature too wow this is pretty long
code
uh 100 lines includes several commands
because you uh anyway so if you like
that feature it's there okay so there's
some digression but the digression is
relevant because
you know because in part I'm marketing s
HTML mod you know you pay me and you get
it or you can of course get you know
just get the some of the commands so
there is a uh there it is a image tag so
suppose you know so what I'm saying is
that in HTML for each tag you have
different list of valid add attributes
so for image tag you have the source
attribute but not for figure tag not for
nav tag not for dive tag okay so you
know that's part of the HTML so if
you don't
know oh okay so
wait h
HTML index okay I have a
tutorial of HTML from the ground up
because I've been coding HTML
manually letter by letter tag by tag the
entire thing since
1996 basically when HTML
begin so okay so if you don't know you
can you know check the HTML tutorial so
my tutorial is very
cold uh cold and uh concise and precise
none of the Zoomers fluff like they talk
about things you don't need to know like
oh by the way HTML is very easy uh you
know something something and uh half of
the time incorrect
information such as the W3 schools you
know that that's the website has a story
by itself you know it's it's the most
hated website in since in the early in
in 2000s okay but today the zumas have
no idea it was the W3 schools
website today Zuma is like oh just go to
that website you know but that website
was hated by all the
programmers you know in the 2000s
because it's just filled with incorrect
information information but meanwhile
all the programming website they are
like they are written in a esoteric and
holier than th way using lots of jargons
you know they they like basically
intentionally do it that way so that
they can show to their PE you know they
are superior they are not really writing
it for you so that is why then then you
got the other extreme who thinks you are
a idiot like the W3 school then you know
just the no most basic like uh
information anyway that's kind of the
history of the online programming
tutorials some of it okay so digression
so anyway you like my you know if you
want to learn HTML here is a source so I
was talking
about HTML attributes okay basic syntax
so basic syntax
okay that's a basic HTML markup and then
here's a section on elements attribute
telling you what it is
about okay copy this close Okay so go
back here uh let's paste it here link
and what is this dive selected delete
move here delete move here delete we
don't need that showing browser go down
and in fact this image I don't need so
open it press a few Keys it's deleted
you can see in the mini buper then move
the cursor here press a key deletes that
showing browser okay now we back to code
our
function Okay add attribute okay so add
an attribute to the current HTML tag so
let's just code it we've been talking
enough search backward so you want to
search backward and A to Z something
okay so that's basically the beginning
of the tag okay bound uh we don't care
so search backward then then your
Cruiser is at at the beginning of the
tag then then just forward
okay and uh okay uh okay forward word
yeah let's just do that
then and then your cluer will be at that
position then but what you want to what
kind of attribute you want to
add I don't know
so but let's compact the code eval
evaluate the code we can try it now CA
add HT ml okay for example let's open
today's so let's say my brow uh let's
say my cluer is here so I call the
command HTML add attribute do
it search
fail oh obviously I know why because you
want search backward by regular
expression not by PL text okay let's fix
it research backward
that stands for regular expression okay
so copy that put that here and we don't
care about that delete delete predy the
code eval the buffer go back to the HTML
open it now meta X do it you see it
moves the coer to that right place um so
then you want to
insert should it always at the beginning
uh okay
no
so okay so move the cluer there and move
the CER and move cluer here and add a
space okay that's what we're going to
do so go back close this one go back to
here so move
forward uh so
wait then search forward search forward
by that okay that will be at at the end
of the opening tag okay then backward
CH backward move backward one CH
character insert insert a space okay
then we are ready pedify the code eval
the buffer go back to the code now watch
the cruiser is right here okay call the
command do it fantastic undo let's try
right here color command do
it the cruiser is moved to that position
fantastic let's try it on the UL okay
let's let's say I put a cruiser here you
see Ur is a list unordered list let's
put the CER here let's see what
happens do it fantastic and beautiful
okay that's one step done now before we
code anything further let's add a
keystroke to it so we don't have to
every time uh uh let's add a keystroke
later later okay let's add a key binding
later okay what's the next well the next
thing is that what what kind of thing
you want to add so let's just say for
now uh you know just for uh let's
say insert ID XYZ okay uh let's not XYZ
well let's XX okay now you need to in
inp when you have a
string when you have a double quote
inside the string you need to escape it
so press a key press a key press a key
no that's not that's the wrong key press
press press that's the wrong key I
forgot what's the key Escape
Cotes okay space TR cancel space TR
fantastic
magnify so you need that so that will
just insert ID okay prettyy the code
eval go back here uh let's try here okay
now this H this is
tricky okay so if your Cruiser is at at
inside un closing tag it will move to
the wrong place okay but let's try the
correct situation first okay let's try
it do it you see added ID fantastic but
now if your curer is let's say here okay
it's going to it's going to go
to here which is incorrect let's try it
do it do it you see that's incorrect so
let's fix that so this is will involve a
slight HTML
passing so instead of search backward
you want to okay so let me show you how
to fix this search backward just search
for that and
uh oh
God okay now this is a bit complex it's
not so easy to fix naively okay you
actually need to have a mechanism to
actually
stand the N thing you cannot just
plainly search for beginning of a tag
because if your
tag is at a position such
that it's right after a closing tag then
you need
to move to that that closing tag
beginning tag you
see you see so if your cluer is here you
need to move there
that is your opening tag okay not that
not that okay not that not that or for
example if you are at here
men for example let's call the command
when when when our cluer at is at the
closing of men it will let's see what
happens so ideally it should to go to
the beginning of men oh wait you see
beginning of men you see I can jump to
the opening tag go close closing
tag
ideally uh got wrong key
I okay press press okay press press
because the arrow key is here so it's a
slightly some reach so ideally you'll
move the cruiser here and insert an ID
there okay but let's try what happens
okay call it call it
you see incorrect you see it went from
here to there
so so how do you fix it okay let's go
back to the code so basically you need
to
determine uh it's a bit involved you
need to determine whether your curser is
currently inside a tag inside a closing
tag or end tag that's one case or if
your Cruiser is between
tags so for example if your Cruiser is
inside the tag may it be an ending tag
or may it be
a beginning tag then you have to
determine which if it's the ending tag
then you simply jump to the beginning
tag if it's in the beginning tag then
you are good then you just add the ID
somewhere here okay that is a case
if your Cruiser is inside a opening tag
and closing or clap closing tag now what
if your Cruiser is not inside any of
opening or closing tag but it is inside
some kind of inner text so right like
for example here or here or here or here
or here you know it's not inside a you
know tag so in that case you need to go
to the IM
immediate opening or closing
tag uh well in that case oh God in that
case you need to find out what is the
parent tag of the inner
text oh God
that's that's that is
involved in fact I uh yeah I do have the
code but the code is fairly complex like
50 lines or something
uh
okay so let's write it out
okay first determine if curer is inside
a opening tag or closing
tag if opening then use
that if close
then jump to the opening tag okay then
you insert the ID somewhere
there but
if but if CER is not in any opening or
closing
tag thus therefore it is in an
inner text
you know that's a HTML technical jargon
because there's a property in Dome
called inner text so so if it's not in
opening close closing tag then it's in a
in a text of su tag then you need to
find what is that tag okay now this case
will be a bit
complicated but we have to C it okay
let's I guess let's code it then damn it
damn sick hey
wz n good morning D says try F7 is
equivalent to space
yes yeah F7 is in Sly Keys is the same
space What
uh is it not possible to call the other
side HTML commands inside this one it is
possible
uh yeah it is possible so so I mean the
the situation is that the code is
not
[Music]
too I mean the situation is basically I
don't have a standalone command that
says go jump to the parent tag I've been
wanting to code that for a while so
maybe actually yeah that's one that will
be one live stream so you want to write
write a command that jumps to the parent
tag okay in if you are doing JavaScript
then it's supremely easy okay let me
demonstrate let me show you guys my
JavaScript in depth recently I've been
updating a lot you know last month
so you got JavaScript in depth pay me to
get it on your computer or raw HTML so
you have instantaneous access to about
600 Pages including all references on
JavaScript objects such as array methods
map for each field from you know concise
precise 100% correct and most easy to
understand understand and no [ __ ]
jargons no
open-source propaganda marketing oh by
the way you should open source this all
you know no and no deep State connection
like the Mozilla you know
Mozilla that's another story you know
you wonder why is mosil so popular in
fact about five years ago Microsoft
killed their JavaScript tutorial
Microsoft did and and I think Google did
that but so basically they are all just
promoting the Mozilla you know MD and
the Firefox JavaScript um
documentation well I anyway that's
another story
okay uh but still it's pretty lousy
anyway I talked about that in other in
other video so in so if you are coding
JavaScript there's also Dome there is a
easy trivial command to jump to a parent
tag so get parent not you know not that
parent element you know building in the
browser
engine you know so all these passing
complex HT HTML you know ideally it's
very simple but in fact it's the most
[ __ ]
possible uh but anyway so there's a
building but since we are you know since
emac this is not a JavaScript engine so
you have to pause it so basically the so
okay let go back so I do have a command
that kind
of for example this command is called
HTML select
element so for example if my cruiser is
here it will select the parent you know
so essentially if my cruiser is is in
any inner
text it will select it you know see so
yeah so actually I can use that command
thank you so for example if my cruiser
is inside a closing
tag press it you'll select that whole
closing I mean whole tag but if my
cruiser is at the opening tag press it
you also select it but what if my
cruiser is not inside a closing tag or
opening tag but in a inner text then
you'll just select the parent tag and
there are several cases for example
there's one case there there's a
different situation if your Cruiser is
here uh yeah
because when your Cruiser is here the
tag to the left is a closing tag but
when your Cruiser is here the tag to the
left is opening tag so it gets a little
bit complicated okay so I do have a
command so actually I can just use this
command so let's go back here so um so
so what do you have to do Jesus
God uh so actually so let me show you
the source code for that command
describe key press the
key uh yeah there it is HTML select that
one okay go to it there it is expand the
window so you can see this
is quite a few lines of Co I mean copy
it new buffer paste
60 lines of code uh make it emac this
mod okay so you got color so and then it
is coding several other commands to you
know if HTML tag is self closing tag you
have to check if it's self closing or
not then get tag name you know you need
to get tag name get tag position and
then you you know if it is opening tag
is true then you do this and then you
skip tag forward and you also skip tag
backward
there uh
then then you check if self closing not
so you you got several cases you know
so yeah but I can yeah okay yeah
actually we can use
this let's let's use that okay
fantastic okay let's go back here go
back here
so so what is it we want to do now ch ch
thank you
Chris
heavy do you have any questions Chris
okay so let's let's continue with the
Lis uh yeah let's finish the lisp it's
been 40 minutes okay let's
um so
so okay so let's see because is inside
inte tag cling
tag yeah we can just do this so this
will actually
guarantee yeah this yeah
okay X begin
X and okay
then call this
command okay uh and hold on a second
sequence let
wait sequence set okay set two
variables this two
variables okay here these two variables
to the result of that that returns a
vector
okay so now we got the position of the
par you know
whatever the parent tag or whatever is a
tag of the current tag B basically the
beginning position of the current
tag and so we don't need this search
this manual search things anymore uh
actually we we
we then I mean over here we go to charm
go to char X begin go to the beginning
position of the opening tag okay uh
there's one more thing we need to do we
need to this actually make the region
active so we want to deactivate the
region uh what does that mean uh okay so
you can go to emx blog emac this
tutorial and section Mark and region
uh so deactivate Mark that's what that's
a command you want okay close that
deactivate Mark
okay deactivate
Mark there it is okay is there an is
there argument no you don't need okay
then go to the beginning of the
position uh then then you just search
forward to go to the end of tag then
just everything like before okay so that
is it shrink a little bit that's it eval
the
buer okay eval the buer then what do we
do we can try it now
so you know let's see what happens if
you call it now you see so right now
your tag
is an in the in the tag I mean in the
text of the men so if your curer is here
or here it will actually add I mean the
proper you know the expected lo location
is actually here because the parent of
this position is the main okay let's try
it do it do
it
incorrect what
okay let's try it again do it do it
incorrect did we Evol the buffer Evol
the
buffer try it again cor it do
it okay in correct wait oh wait actually
if you select it yeah that's right
actually this is a better Behavior you
know you don't this is a better Behavior
you want to
you you want to the current tag is meant
to be the tag the the immediate tag on
the
left and the opening of it so okay so
that is correct okay cor it do it
fantastic undo let's say my cruiser is
here Co it do it fantastic which is
correct okay undo let's say my cruiser
is here code it do it fantastic
undo
magnify let's
say let's say where do I want to let's
say my Cru is here call it it should add
to the pre- tag okay do it
fantastic what about my tag is already
inside a opening tag cor it do it
fantastic correct what about here call
it do it fantastic Okay so that fix that
next right now I'm we are always adding
an ID element but should it always be ID
of course not sometimes you want to add
class or or so what do you want to do so
I mean so this is uh first the first
thing to think about is design Choice
what exactly you want you know suppose
now you are guard you can flip a finger
and have the design IR code but what
kind of thing you want to do that's the
first thing design issue okay do you
want to like prompt user what kind of
tag you want to add or do you want
automatically just add an ID or you know
whatever is the most commonly used just
inserted it because once you insert the
tag let's say for example let's put here
Cod command do it you see most of the
time you really just I I mean like 99%
of the time you just want to add a class
or
ID yeah 90% of the time 95% of the time
at least you just want to add ID or or
class or style okay that's yeah ID class
and
style so in that case
we can just add them all together in one
shot okay let's just
say then user just delete the things
they don't need ID class is almost
usually always already there uh yeah but
this is not
good
because sometimes often the tag already
has a
class so you don't want to add class and
besides if you add all these you know in
one shot then every time user calls the
command for example let's let's
just do it okay eval the code go here
put the cluer somewhere call the command
do it you see it just adds that but so
every time the user calls the command
they have to like go and delete one of
them or something and then also if the I
if the class already exists or ID
already exists so okay so now the next
step to make this better can you make it
better please yeah to make it better is
that we have
to need to get all current
attributes so you need a command you
need to write a command to get all the
current tag attribute for example if I'm
here if this is a current tag I need to
it need to return ID and
style okay so in other words we are
getting closer to a HTML
passer which is which is kind of
complicated
thing so I don't have this command you
know I don't have a command that gets a
current tax attribute
um you know be you need that because you
then you know if ID already exists you
shouldn't add ID okay and also we
haven't
decided also we haven't
decided what is the
interface uh havent decided what is it
for for
example do you want to prompt
user for what tag to add so you you know
one of the most simple and common way is
just to prompt user for example CH
Ching Chris thank you
again in previous stream you searched
for a pattern of text recursively in all
your HTML
files yes can you show that also how you
open link form HTML in emx okay very
easy two
questions okay we're going to we're
going to okay let me uh continue with
the prompt let me show you about the
prompt okay so let's common that out
let's just say uh
uh uh there there are many ways to
prompt user okay so one easy way is just
go here emac this
tutorial and get perpose string work
with lines text processing no get user
input that's a section we want get user
input click ask for file name ask for
directory ask for stream that's what we
want read string okay read string
fantastic what tag to add okay let's
just say uh and uh
let's let the use a tag type the
tag so xtag
name let's say xtag so let's say
set that
to this the result whatever the result
user typed okay and of course we need to
declare a variable now we have a new
variable here
tag okay okay prey the code and I mean
okay so once you get the tag then you
need to insert X tag okay fantastic EV
go back Ando let's put a CER here Cod
the command do it you see now there's a
prompt what tag to add let's say s tag
you see it just insert that so we need
to again
modify uh you need to insert that then
um this back quote [ __ ] something okay
eval the buer go back here and do try it
again code the command do it what tag to
add let's say what actually is should
say attribute let's say style type style
enter there okay now next step is we
need
to modify this so it enter something
more appropriate so anyway so it's a
problem here so back to the qu question
two questions one is how do you open
link from HTML in emx so inside HTML mod
you just move the curer there
enter there you are so the command is
called HTML open local links I believe
that's what you are asking if not let me
know okay Chris how do you open a link
for example this there is a CSS file
let's just move the crer there press
enter CSS file is open you can go to the
directory di jump there it is the CSS
file you can go to the top you can see
the file path close close Okay
so close open press enter to open close
it enter to open close it and the
command name is HTML open local link so
now back in here describe key enter so
it says return runs the command HTML
open local link okay then jump to the
source code HTML mod there is the source
code and do I have it on my website
no uh I thought I do but I guess
not so all you have to do is okay well
yeah but you see now here it deal with
URL fragments so that makes it a bit
complex so that is why yeah that's part
of the reason I don't have it source
code on my website because then you need
to include that then that might call
something else you know and also
anyway uh but the command is pretty easy
to write very easy to write okay very
easy to write and I covered it something
like this a thousand times in
s emac live stream you can go to emx
tutorial and there it is video tutorial
so all the best ones are here on emac
this from the ground up on emac on
efficiency workflow how to uh emac this
from the ground up and writing a major
mod you know I've done 100 more than
100 videos on emx okay so that's one
thing that's how you go to open a link L
from oh okay so indeed I mean with your
browser on your current HTML file to
browser oh you just well you for me I
mean there's a build building command so
you just call
uh
browse
buffer okay so that's a building EMA X
command browse URL of buffer okay Enter
there it is for me I'm using S something
similar okay I'm using this
key HTML open in browser okay go to the
source
code expand the window scroll down there
it is so it
automatically it just call
this this building command
uh
what let me do it again
so there browse
URL but I added some more feature for
example if you have a you know local
local URL then we'll open that too or if
you
are um if the current buffer is not a
file it'll tell you so and uh
um and you also have some hooks for
example every
time let me show you you see there's a
lot empty spaces there but now if I show
any on browser it will clean up that
empty space for example showing browser
you
see back to emac you see empty space is
gone so that's a hook I added so that's
uh that's about that
okay that's one question the other
question is how do you search my files
for example right now I'm me in this
directory S Talk Show there are 900
files go to the top okay so so let's say
I want to find the word hascal in all my
past S Talk Show so press a key hascal
press enter which directory this one yes
uh what file path regular expression.
HTML yes there it is expand the window
you can navigate by pressing the right
arrow or back left Arrow to go back or
you can navigate by file by pressing the
down arrow file file file file or up
Arrow to go back to previous file so
these are you know there are the all
these occurrences of the world
hascal okay and if you want to get the
list of all files press this
key that's the that's all this the file
path whose content contains the word
hascar okay so quite a
few uh you know 33 files okay let close
that so where do you get this command so
this is part of thear find
text okay uh well I mean this this is
this
this this is part of this is my own
package okay find text jump open it this
is a source code go to the bottom chick
Ching thank you go to the bottom 800
lines of code and go to here homepage
open it by the way that's another
command to open any file path so you can
see the name of that command is open
file at CER and emac has build in too so
the emac one is
called uh
find
file at Point okay so you call
that and then then emx will ask you know
in the case of URL emac will ask if it
if it's that one yes then it opens the
URL so the behavior is a bit different
because in the the building find file at
point it will open a URL if your Cruiser
is on URL but my
command checks if the URL is is your own
URL if it is it will go to the
corresponding file path which is this
one so open it you see the same file
except this one is you know the you go
through HTTP you know um on the server
well this one is
local so anyway so about your question
emac you know I have been I was
demonstrating my own command let's do it
again okay so let's go to keyboard blog
showing browser so I've been busy
writing a lot keyboard every day you
know but but today especially today I've
been writing for example an article
about alas layout
what is the history of it what's or
engine why is it good or why is it bad
what are the keyboards that uses Alice
layout why is it named Alice layout
Alice in Wonderland you know so I wrote
this article today and
also some simple explanation about what
staggered
layout where it came from who the [ __ ]
created a keyboard with this weird you
know this weird slant they are not
exactly hex hexagonal nor are they like
every key is like 30° and then why 30°
why not you know 45 degrees you know
like the proper diagonal who the [ __ ]
created the keyboard like we used
today this is the reason this is okay so
anyway I wrote this been working on my
keyboard okay
and then there's grid layout also known
as orthol
linear okay and then there's symmetric
inward stagger keyboard so for example
let me show you that's a Japanese
keyboard uh okay so anyway I wrote a lot
I work on keyboard all the time okay so
yeah we are here because let's go to the
diet so right now there's 1,100
articles so let's see let's say I want
to find all these articles that contains
the
name Crystal
okay do it CH i i s o do it yes
yes there it is expand the window so
again one occurrence another
occurrence thanks to crystals for photos
let's open that one show in browser oh
fantastic thank you Crystal so Crystal
showed me you know he bought all this
ergonomic devices and he took photos for
me so I can put on my website you know
this you know you know some many of
these uh
devices so you can see this's one
occurrence another occurrence one one
one one one one one one one one one
quite a few
okay about 10 10 or
15 uh and uh many several of these very
interesting for example this fantastic
track boy spins this is another crystals
video I think no this one uh one uh
maybe one
maybe not these two but
others I think this is a video video
right I forgot to put the name
there so anyway yeah so oh okay so that
command is you have to
like buy it you have to actually buy it
for
me uh s and replay actually I'll just
send it to you okay but if you are in
emx if you are not using you know sine
you know my package how do you do it's
you can do similar okay uh similar so in
that case you go to emac blog okay let's
go to emac blog and that's it for today
so emac block you go to emac
tutorial then you go to so sections
quick start download show version launch
emx exit
emx uh unlike VI you don't know how to
exit but actually for emac it's also
idiotic you know control X control C
what the what kind of [ __ ] Keys is
that so that's a problem with emac
anyway F split Windows File buffer copy
paste find text that's the section you
want search text highlight text this
matching line search text in a directory
that's the one you want go there so you
have the you can just call Meta X
GP but however
problem because of the emac the G people
the Linux Fanatics idiots
when you are on Windows it doesn't work
you know let's try it oh grab default
directory oh something grab is not
recognized as an internal or external
command operable program or batch file
got a
problem so you have to install grap but
then you also have to install find you
know but if you are on Linux you don't
have this problem okay and if you are on
a Mac or BSD you don't have this problem
but if you are on Windows or if you are
on a phone Android you probably have
this kind of problem so you need to
install grap you need to install find
but how do you know which program you
have to reinstall actually you don't
know you can search the web it'll take
you an
hour but I have it documented I have it
documented okay like
simply okay but I have too many articles
so I think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching is
there anything else let's
now what is this close
close track boo roller plus okay let's
copy that copy the file path close close
that let's go to back to my talk show
and put the link back here so we have
some idea what we talked about
today uh something okay so put the link
here Fu
jisu roller
place and
Link close that make a URL showing
browser there is track boo roller plus
fuju space for close that what is it
uh search text let's copy that put it
here make a link URL close that go back
go back go back close that go back we
got that
already uh yeah Alice layout copy it
back emx paste make link uh oh make a
link and the conjoin the Tex you see
this is another
[Music]
convenient command Ina HTML mod you see
uh HTML join TX so when you are at the
end of a opening uh of a closing tag and
opening tag and join them showing
browser so all keyboard related things
are together well this one is not so the
this emx needs to go so you you see
press one single key that removes that
this tag so put it here remove the
lii and make a link showing browser
there it is in a separate
line okay now let's put the code back
and that that that should be it today so
okay 1 hour exactly open the
file so we we kind of okay it's kind of
draft uh it's a bit okay so let's put it
back syntax CCT showing
browser there it is today's fruit
okay thank you guys for watching
anything
else bye
guys let's see anything else that's it
pretty much got the
command uh I'll find replace I need to
put that link
here by
by get user input let's put the link
there
oh we also talked about the JavaScript
get the parent tag
fantastic Doom scripting tutorial
fantastic uh array JavaScript reference
JavaScript in depth it's span the
links web dev blog close
okay