hi guys I'm going to show you code
prettify like for example on this page
it's my Python tutorial and you can see
here the code is colored and I'm going
to show you how to how to do that so
well I'm on my website I'm using span
tags like you can see here this part is
this part and you can see like if I if I
show in browser it's not correct but but
I have a Emacs HTML command so that adds
span tags to to the words and now they
are colored so this is one way to do it
but recently I decided to use a
JavaScript way so so we using the span
tag the advantage is that you do not
need JavaScript and it's extremely fast
it's very fast I mean I mean what I mean
is a load time it shows the color right
away and there's no flashing so so
that's the advantage the disadvantage is
that the text becomes incomprehensible
you know you cannot read it if you want
to edit it you have to you have to run a
command you know then then you can you
know edit it so so recently I decided to
try the Google's Google code pretty Phi
that's using javascript let me show you
goal and mod so so this is my goal and
tutorial and this is you can see the
code here is not colored let me go there
so it's here it's over here
pack so so this code the red the red
part is is over here it's it's not using
span tags it's just this part and
however if you run this is fire
I have JavaScript turned off but
if I run this in Safari with JavaScript
on you can see they are coloured let's
see another one you see so they are
coloured and they are calling a
JavaScript the JavaScript is down here
you can see this line running code
purified and this is the JavaScript file
and and they are this is the website on
github code purify and you can use that
let me give you a quick demo but before
I do that let me turn on the global
command mod c om so you can see what
command I'm calling in in Emacs yeah
okay so so this is Google
so yeah let's start a new HTML page HTML
shortcut I want to let's say Python okay
and you don't need that actually so
let's say 25 and okay save it
so show that here it's not colored but
if I show in Safari it's not color
either because I haven't added the
JavaScript file so let's do that
pretty fine doing pretty fine copy the
file path close paste it here make a
link okay that's good go to the Safari
reload it's colored it's color blue so
let's try some big each of us with a big
Python let's say find okay let's try
that so big chunk of code show go here
sure you see so it's it's all colored so
that's what you do that's what you have
to do to color file you just add this
tag pre tag with the class name pretty
print and the JavaScript file and that's
it now you the you can have any code
here for example let's try this let's
try okay let's try some image let's
let's say that okay now show in Safari
showing Safari yeah it's also colored
but it's not colored well because it's
not specifically designed for least code
it only colors strings and symbols right
now so basically the code pretty vibe it
will guess what code you are using
because we are not we don't have any
information to indicate what code what
programming language we are using but it
makes a pretty good guess and if you
look at on their webpage basically order
common popular languages
C and Python
you know they support but they also
support other languages like closure
mumps memory or whatever that is you
know what they support other languages
yeah I think you have to add add a
JavaScript file for that but anyway I
think they also support two declaration
of code explicitly let's say let's say
your example let's say you know Exley's
yeah I like that
so remove that remove that copy that
put it here now that's Emacs this code
right so so the coloring still is not
changing because yeah because you have
to add the extension but what I'm saying
is that you can you can add specific you
know declaration of the programming
language you are using the advantage of
this is that so for example if I have
some code here
it may be Haskell or any new language
now if I read this file I mean if
somebody read this file it doesn't know
what language this is you know it could
be you know Common Lisp or scheme or
racket or you know anything but if you
have a code declaration part that that
solves this problem and you know people
who read the page can see oh this is
immigrants and also if you are
processing files like programmatically
it's also good to have the specific
programming language information okay so
so that's that
so that's code pretty five you know
that's how to use it
you can use it for your blogs in
and other writings okay I wanted to show
you something else that's you know on my
website the tutorials I write let's
close this ok : so on my website but
let's go to my email Explorer let's say
let's say you'll be ok I have a lot of
tutorials for example this is Ruby and
right now they are using spam spam tags
like you can see all these are spandex
so I'm trying to convert them to use
code 35 Google code 35 JavaScript now
there are two things I need to do like
right now you can see you can see they
are using this format this so so on my
website they are currently using this
format but for Google code 35 it needs
to be purified something like that it
needs to be like that and how however it
does not contain explicit information
about the programming language which I
do want because because I have my HTML
mod and I can do like this and I'll move
the code to here to here and I can run
it you know and get a result
so that's convenient let's put it back
and I can you know HTML eyes it well how
do we move it you know if I want but in
order for that to work I need the
information about what language it is
because if I do this you know it's using
Ruby mod how does it not it no because
it's grabbing the information from here
so if I'm going to use Google code
purify hi I also want the code
information here which
the format will be like that so it would
be like that so what so what basically
what I have to do is now I have to I
have to convert all all files of this
format to this format so that that's a
different task you know I'm just showing
you that you know as a matter of
interest you know it's a promise
task you know things programmers do
interesting things you know the things
that I need to do so I have I have lots
of tutorials on my website you know
different languages they are about maybe
500 or maybe 600 pages among among 5,000
pages so you know there so I I have to
so how do you do this conversion task so
so that's what I'm gonna talk about
that's know what I'm gonna show you
so one easy way is to just do a find it
angry face so what I'm gonna do so let's
see so copied I'd remove it
open a new buffer put it here you know
just for backup so so let's look at the
Ruby so there are lots of Ruby file
files and all these are using span tags
and there are not many Ruby files only
40 so what I do is let's see so I want
to replace that so okay here's what I do
it's
so I want to replace that by okay
replace that by that then replace then
replace this thing by by that that's
what I'm going to do and that should
work so let's do that okay so I'm using
I have a package let's just do it so
copy that paste this is what I want to
replace I want to replace it by that so
find that replaced by the head yes Ruby
directory HTML files my changes yes
fixed case such yes fixed case replaced
yes make backup yes okay so all these
are changed let's look at it so now is
it looks bad well I mean you know
because okay let's go back here and now
I want to change three by three code
code three
free by code free
maybe yes yes yes yes yes okay so these
are changes now go back here reload okay
they you don't have the boxes anymore
yeah yeah that looks right that's that's
correct
wait okay I made a mistake so the pretty
fire actually should be this is a
mistake the pretty five actually should
be code Ruby so let's do that again
we verify by that
okay reload
that looks right now.we Ruby and end at
code and the tree oh there's one more
thing I need to do I need to remove all
the span tax so what I can do you know I
have a command that I just call and it
removes all the span tax so that looks
good because without coloring they they
all look red because of my CSS and now I
just need to do these four whole files
of the Ruby directory so I can go here
and I'm going to use a marker to do this
so the current file is Ruby basics which
is this one so I'm gonna start with that
one
Rico Rico day Ruby Rico tomorrow so
let's do that
start Marvell wait okay start Marco
start mark over here now move move move
move three times open and call the
command then save then close and stop
recording Marco so I have a Marco
defined now this file happens just to
not have any code block so that's fine
so okay I'm gonna so now I can code
Accomack call my Marco for this file you
can see this file has one code block and
that's using span span tags you see it's
right here but now if I call my Marco
let's say code
okay I think that's not right
he shouldn't close it okay it's not
working
let's try that again call it a macro
okay
okay that's that fire
and open cooler these curse I don't know
what's going on but let's do the macro
again so let's see yeah let's do it with
this one so start recording stop wait
start recording move open call the
command save close stop recording okay
now let's do we we can look at it that's
good that this part is wrong though okay
I'll fix it later but let's let's
continue so so now I've gone this page
it's called my let's go my marker but
actually this page doesn't contain any
code
actually it does let's do that then
let's not do this page let's do this
Unicode page
oh it's already right so yeah there's
lots of spent attacks so let's call the
macro code the marker okay
something's wrong basics something
because it closed my Ruby basics page
why is it closing that page
you'll be Unicode
okay okay that's mr. again
record macro move move move
open remove tags save close stop marker
tomako okay yeah
it closed my Ruby page for some reason
it closed it and actually added that
anyway so I have to fix it
but normally I just I can just call
normally what I do is I I highlight all
of them and call a Primark or to
regionalize and everything should be
fixed but there's a problem I have to
figure out what what it is let's figure
it up and I mean this video is going is
getting long but you know you can stop
watching it
you know the good stuff the good stuff
is already done but let me figure out
what's wrong so let's try the marker
again we code mark well search for href
okay then three
open call that command save
cuz
stop marker okay then I'm gonna do this
page
it worked you see the spent axons
removed so why is it not working I don't
know something right so now I have it
walking let's try again cool Marco
Kohaku yeah it worked so I can just
repeat this so now all of them are done
yep see there's no span tax so let's
look at let's go over here you see they
are all red because because there's no
span tax that's correct that's correct
now all we have to do is to add the
JavaScript file so let's go to : so
basically we have to replace this by
that okay now let's go back to Ruby so
replace that by that
okay Ruby directory everything yes
now that's good now if I show this in
Safari
is not colored that's not right
oh yeah because it's not pretty find its
goal and what is the word
pretty print not pretty five copy-paste
I want pretty print so 25 pretty print
there will be yes now go back to Safari
now that's working
finally yeah that's what I want
so this way when I work with Ruby now I
can I can see I can see the code without
having to you know do that it's it's
much good so I I have to so that's it
for today I have to you know I'm just
going to go with my website and fix all
these other languages now there is one
thing that's interesting I just
mentioned the last one that is for my
Emacs page let's go to let's say here is
e my Greece basics you see they are
using span tags like right here you know
like here and however there's a
advantage because if you look at this in
Safari with JavaScript on you can move
your cursor to the to the functions in
air show the function you see let's say
truncate list so in order for that to
happen is you know I need the span tags
for example for example let's say go to
the top printing you know so when the
cursor is on a word message the
JavaScript needs a way to know that you
know this is a word and look up for that
word it works because I have written a
JavaScript file
is this file Emacs 2 tips that that
makes that happen but in order for this
to work the code needs to know where a
mouse is on a function name but if you
don't have span tag wrapped around the
function name it won't work like if I
show like if I save this and refresh
here it doesn't work so I need I need
this way so you can see you see all
function is is is having span tag class
name function name and if I save it
reload the new looks
so for Emacs lips this I have to do
something about it
you know I I would like to remove the
span tag but then I need to write a
JavaScript so that you know or modify
the code pretty fighter of JavaScript so
that this words gets wrapped with span
tag okay that's it that's it for today
thank you for watching bye