hello guys welcome to another episode
OFA talk show today we are going to code
emac lisp we are going to write a uh a
function that creates a key map like vak
to Cy to vorak to comac and so on so
let's begin let me show you guys so
here's my keyboard This is glove 80 the
best keyboard there is uh can you guys
see me so here is a G8 fantastic search
my YouTube or my website c.in info
you'll find reviews and this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard version to fantastic
and this is going to be my favorite s
board SV a l b o a r d data
hand so but today let's begin coding
eacp okay so let's go to SW uh switch
screen so you can see okay let me uh
tell you what we're going to do so
yesterday we did a
ASMR edition of writing JavaScript to
create this keyboard layout so you can
see here's a
keyboard uh and quy and you can change
to vak that's a heat map the bigger the
circle means that letter is used more
often so quy vorak
KAC qfm
lwy Workman Norman KAC DH bco 15
homac in grar mini MAAC and so on Okay
so yesterday we wrote a uh we so we we
wrote the function for JavaScript today
we're going to write it in emac
this uh so I'm using flly Keys why do we
need to write it let me show you so I'm
going to explain uh what are we going to
do okay so here's sofly Keys which is a
key binding system for emac you can find
it if you don't know yet you can find it
on my website Sly
Keys uh okay
so in order to have you know so we so
this soft like key supports Cy vak uh
Pac and a bunch of others lots of
supports like tens of layouts 10 layout
also so you see so that's all the layout
is supports and including uh weird ones
Co neo2 Norman programmable ra PT navito
which is a efficient layout for POI Keys
using Brazil so yes quy there quy a and
t actually I forgot what that is is uh
quy Norwegian and quartz and Workman so
in order to have this layout you need a
you need a like a dictionary or hash
table that converts the key like what is
the key e on quy what is it in vorak so
we need to have lots of code for that so
let's go to so let's uh
let's let's search okay so search for DV
o r a okay VX search for it so there
there it is so you can
see we need to have lots of these tables
so this is from quy to oer oer use is
used in France and I believe France
Belgium uh other TB used in
Germany so here's comac so comac here's
comac DH dhm
comac dhk oh comac has a lot variations
so you need this
um you need this dictionaries in order
to convert to know which keys to convert
to
which but so if we are going to add a
new layout for Sly Keys it's kind of
tedious to create this uh this this
dictionary so what we going to do
instead we are going to use um
uh a technique of asky layout so let me
show you that's what we did yesterday
for JavaScript so instead of a
dictionary like that you simply do you
create this asky map so for example this
is quy you know it's just a string
visual layout then you create another
one for example comac DH like that then
you simply have a function that go
through these two strings and map each
key to to each letter to each letter and
you it will return a dictionary like
that so this is
Javascript and uh we are going to do it
for emac lisp okay so let's make a
backup of this file let's begin coding
it refresh and uh and uh let's rename
this to eel eel for emac disp okay so
this this is a e file now emac this so
uh if you have a questions comments oh
we have quite a few let's pop out the
chat uh if you have any emac related
questions today uh it's ask me uh answer
okay UTF let's declare the lexical
binding uh so we need to write the
function um okay this is Javascript uh
we don't we don't want you know uh so
let's let me let me just do this so that
we
have in case we need to uh we want to
revisit so anyway so so EAC is so we
want to write this function so Define a
function and let's just name it uh s
create layout
map and this function will take layout
one takes two layout as argument ask Art
in the form of asky art version today
State okay let's let's quickly write the
documentation takes two strings layout
one and layout
two they are in sard
form
return a what should we return the data
structure it should it be hash table or
should it be uh
associate associative array because in
EAC lisp you have two kind
of uh data structure
for for uh a collection of pairs key
value pairs so let's go to let's go to
Sly Keys let's see push looks like okay
they are associative arrays okay let's
let's do
that return a associative list it's
called associative list in emac okay CH
thank you AV sbq what is a question
thoughts on speech to text dictation
worthwhile uh okay that's very
interesting question I had my first
experience about 10 years ago I tried
the Microsoft buin text speech in fact
we can use it right now uh let's see
voice recorder uh I don't use it I don't
use it much I sometimes use it on my
laptop on the Windows machine so I tried
it 10 years ago so
basically if you are going to do voice
to voice to text okay the text dictation
and if you are speaking if your speech
is a normal speech like hi Mom how are
you today oh happy happy birthday Mom uh
we going to go shopping today are we
going to go shopping today things like
that then it's very
good so Microsoft and Reaper Reaper
showed us this this the I can't find it
now but there's another URL which is
better than Microsoft and Apple I
believe is very good so I mean you guys
younger people using the phone all the
time you know it's good it's it's very
good you know Apple so but so but if you
are if the things you want to say is
unusual and uh like for example coding
or um coding is a entire different
story so but if the things you want to
say for example usually I want to talk
about things uh and for example zumas
you know Zuma forchan type of people
they like to say a lot of joggin like
Chad you know had and uh you know I I
don't I don't want to mention it but you
know lots of Jons of these younger
people then text to speech you will have
problem you know like yeah the other
actually I I I did a recording about one
time I wanted to say red skin you know
I'm Yow you know to describe
people ra kind of race so you have white
people which is very well
accepted but you and black people but
but they they you have just call them
African Americans you know it's it's
it's it's another story but okay anyway
red skin yellow skin okay so I'm yellow
skin you know so using skin to describe
people is very efficient it's very
natural so anyway one one time I want to
record you know text to speech you know
I was saying red skin but it cannot you
know after repeated the red skin red
skin red skin you know I I try to say
the word 10 times it can it it it it's
like it cannot just type it
out so that's an issue okay so that's a
issue when you want to use text to
speech uh so there's you know there's
kind of know they they they they want to
try to prevent you saying words they
don't want you to say things like that
so anyway
uncoding um well we should get back to
the emac this coding because I want to
do that quickly uh so oncode so uh so
there is a famous
uh python coder in year
2013 so this is a python conference you
search it you'll find it first input for
programming year 2013 and this guy's
name is uh is
um you know was very
popular so this is 10 years ago Tavis R
he got injury to his hand so he started
to do voice recording basically he
created a system so you can watch the
video he demon that
so so it's it's like it's uh fast F than
than you when you code faster than you
type for coding so there's one system
but since then there's a few others but
I haven't really uh looked into but you
can check it out okay that is my
experience uh yeah do you know plan n
real sweeping to open Windows no I don't
know what uh I I know what is plan n but
I don't know what is
real and uh I don't I know what is
sweeping to open Windows real window
system okay let's look at
quickly real is plan KN okay so it's
part of plan KN window system it's well
known for making its window management
transparent to the application this
allows running real inside another
window manager okay no I don't know it I
haven't used it I haven't I have not
tried plan n and likely I'm not
interested because it's not it's not
practical if you can if I can use plan n
like right now I install it and have all
my browsers work emac work I love it but
that's not the case you know usually
it's just a nerd interest so I'm not
interested in plan n and in general I'm
not interested in operating systems so
there's a kind of group of people nerds
who are into operating systems I'm not
interested in operating systems for
example there's a lot Linux versus BSD
nuts we have a few BSD nuts who in you
know who says insist how BSD is superior
than Linux and so on but to me when I
use operating system like I said before
I'm not interested in memory ding bit
diding like memory you know the stuff
like that I'm interested shell in Shell
what shell what what shell does it have
is it a good shell power Shell versus
spash I'm interested in programing
language High Lev stuff application
mathematics I'm not interested in in the
bit dling memory processes background
process you know like like the things
you cannot like you know it's like it's
not I don't care about
those okay that's my uh that's what I
have to say about
that so I let's go back I want to go
back to coding so uh coding coding you
know this is Hardcore um I would Rec
recommend you guys you know instead of
instead of uh you know when when if you
are a programmer if you are you know
into Emax VI and all these operating
system do something concrete and useful
you know dive into the the programming
language and code and and best thing is
to create an application you know you
you create an application maybe you'll
become very popular instead of the
window managers and
stuff okay any uh let's see what else uh
C shop no I haven't
tried Acme text editor that's another
popular uh question yes we have a person
uh Emily she is using Acme
okay on inar
Discord isn't Linux Factory better for E
for emac though okay thank you thank you
IV
sbq okay so back to emac this coding so
let's uh so let's close that so we want
to create a function this we are writing
this function T to layout that's right
and uh okay let's uh we can begin coding
okay this is Javascript we don't care
delete that JavaScript okay do that and
this ask asky OD we need but we need to
convert this into a format that emac
emac understand so this is Javascript so
for example copy cut it out so this is
quy this is a layout you know this is a
string so let's make it uh emac this
string so let's do
this okay uh okay make it a string and
then you need to escape the double quote
that's a emac string okay and this part
you don't care
so for example this is a
quy
um asot okay so this this will be used
as a input to our function to this
function so
quy yeah let's quickly just demo let's
forget about you know microft like key
structure let's just get this to work
and now so now this a coac okay let's
coac let's cut cut cut and uh set
Q uh yeah you need a string okay double
quote is for string in emx and uh and
search for double quote Yeah so you need
to escape the double quote okay and this
one is comac D so Q comac DH okay and
this JavaScript code we
remove and this is what we this the
function this should be the output of
our function okay and the rest we don't
care JavaScript testing code okay so so
far so good so we have one quality
layout let's we have one vac layout
let's move them to the
top so that you know constant go first
okay then we write our function so take
two strings L one l two they are in ask
art form return a Associated
list uh
okay and uh that REM Maps key in uh
layout one to layout
two okay that is the purpose of this
function okay so let's begin writing
here so layout one so first of all we
got a ask key so you know the layout
looks like that first of all the the the
first two rows is the number row number
and symbol shifted symbol then you have
the uh the main you know the ask key quy
layout then you have the capital shifted
version so so that constitute this um
you know s art layout then you give
another one then it just it just takes
each you know go through it each
character by character and
uh return a pair okay and in the in the
structure of Association list okay so
first of all we need to iterate through
the string okay first of all you need to
split
string now
um well you you you can split string
because in here each you know they are
consecu cons continuously character
um but actually I realized it's better
to have them not consecutive so uh what
I mean by let me do let me show you okay
so we're going to add spaces
here uh let's see how we so we want to
add a space like that like that like
that but instead of doing it manually
let's do a keyboard marro okay so begin
so start recording keyboard marro and
okay by the way so you can see all my
command Calles in the pink window and my
key strokes on the left I'm using soft
like keys and V keyboard of course so
start Maro let's start
Maro and uh move to the Right add a
space okay and end Mar okay and
uh okay and let's call last keyboard
mark okay that's done Cass CU Mar you
see now the next one will be interesting
that's we call repeat last command okay
which is this key you see the name is
repeat I mean not repeat last command
just repeat so once I call repeat I can
just keep pressing the key and it'll
just do it you see you see now I can
just hold the key and it this does this
magically fantastic okay one more one
more Fant
fantastic so we want the input to be in
this form this form is superior than um
wait why is it not so this form is
superior than the oh yeah so this here
you shouldn't have a space because
that's Escaping The Double quote so why
is is this form Superior than that
because in this form if you in the
future if you want to have a key map
that contains old key Enter key shift
key control key you know the key label
has more than one character so for
example you might have you might add for
example
Ctrl here that stand for control so then
you have you have the space as a
separator so you can do that so you can
remap you know control old you know or
caps loog or function keys but if you
don't have the spaces
then then you need to find some sort of
single Un code character to stand for it
you know so anyway so this way is better
so let's let's go with this um the space
okay so now this part we can remove now
let's do the same for this
coac
uh play call last keyboard Mar and call
the repeat command and just hold a key
and you'll just do it do it fantastic
beautiful okay now remove that space
fantastic now since we have space in
between now it's actually easier to do
now we just split string so let's let's
capitalize them so because it's my
convention for par parameter names to be
capitalized so now we have layout one
you want to split string
okay fantastic and uh separators so
separators will be space or
return okay is that the regular
expression I believe so let's look at
the
documentation
separators uh if separator is a NE
should be regular expression fantastic
so that
will uh you need a you need a vertical
vertical bar and not that vertical bar
so that means all so space or actually
one or more let's put one or more space
one or more or return one or more okay
Aid no uh am no because you know we
don't thank you
CH I help my RSI so much thank
you uh any other question laughing I
answer would you recommend CI keys to
someone who has never used emac yes of
course
yes uh it's up to you so I mean there's
no absolute question so if you never use
emac you start to use emac the common
question is should I start with playing
G emx or can I directly jump to Evo mod
Doom
space Max or S FL Keys there's no
absolute answer to which way is the best
okay you could you know start so I I you
know so of course I you know I can
recommend soft like
Keys uh if you start with PL emx of
course the key by that's absolutely not
good okay but you know but you learn you
learn it you know maybe you maybe uh so
anyway doesn't matter each uh either way
okay split string so we split this
string of course we need to
uh uh save it a result to a variable so
split uh split we split the strings so
uh Keys one okay L1 Keys let's
say uh X X1 Keys okay so that's a
variable and X2 Keys that's that would
be keys from layout two okay so X1 Keys
set the varable
to this split string okay then do the
same for X2
Keys uh let's name name just Keys one
Keys two it's easier that way
okay
uh Keys one just Keys one Keys two okay
that's Keys two layout two
okay is that good yes now pretty fine uh
I think that's
good okay then what so once you split
them what you get the split string
returns a list okay so you just have to
go through the list so you can use uh
map
let's see what do you want to
use map C or map map car okay map car is
just like map in other languages like
Python's map okay so so you map a
function to the sequence X Keys one okay
and uh by this function so what does
this function do so this function will
take
okay so it will uh map okay uh we cannot
use map because for example we need to
create here's what we need to create we
need to create a bunch of cons payers
and the cons paare is a pair okay the
first value is a key X from from layer
one the second value should be a key
from Layer Two but how do you get the
layer two
we can't because actually because we we
need the index so we cannot use map C
but there's Solutions okay so we just go
to um the I go to my emac list reference
which I do use as a reference myself
emac lisp so we need to go to um
sequences okay so
this lisp symbol lisp data structure
function symbol uh
um variable conditional buing this data
structure there and let's go to sequence
type and uh let's go to sequence
functions that's what I want yes so
sequence functions is a collection of
functions all these functions work on
any of this data type or or vector data
type Vector is array okay known as array
in other languages okay so we so we have
a bunch of functions this function all
through all work on um list kind of
stuff so we want one that allow us to um
there's a every okay so let let me let
me see which one I
want insert delete modify items no take
drop no we don't care uh filter no we
want map okay we want map function to
both lists at the same time so delete
Loop iteration uh sequin do yeah we can
do sequence map okay sequence map apply
a function to a sequence return result
sequence okay well no we need to map it
to kind of two
um now in common list there's a common
list Library cl-h there's a function
that do that
but I don't like to use common disp I
don't like anything common disp Al so
there's a question asking me about do
you use
slime uh well actually I never I don't I
never coded common disp I did a little
bit scheme I did a homework for someone
in in racket scheme about seven years
ago but
so but other other than that I don't and
I did closure professionally for about a
year uh so I haven't I haven't used
slime and I don't know what is Sly s y
so anyway back to the question let's get
this quickly we uh I want to finish this
so we we we need to map a functions so
in wam language it will be simple it
just
map or map map
threads so and in Python you call uh
some kind of a function called
zip but uh so in emac this okay let me
let me think
about sequin count sequin contains
sequin find sequence
every uh there it is sequence map n now
these functions are new all these
sequence prefix functions they they they
came out about six years ago they came
out in
2016 oh almost 8 years ago so sequence
map n is the one we want okay there it
is seq map in so let's write so not map
car SQ map n so let's see if we have
a sequence map n okay now SQ
map okay we don't I don't have a
shortcut for that okay so this is a
function so okay so replace that here
okay now the function will take two
arguments wait
uh so sequence map and sequences okay
returns as result of applying function
to each element of
sequences okay okay so you give two
sequences here so it's
easy there so then you got X and Y so so
it becomes trivial now that's
it okay cling up that I believe I
believe that's it for our function let's
try it okay let's try it so our function
let's copy the
function uh call the function and uh
and uh and we need to give arguments one
is qualy okay let's put a x in front
because I don't want
to so that we can track our variables
because in emac in emac this every
variable become every symbol becomes
Global so so if you that's why you put a
prefix to your names that that way it's
easier to track them
okay so that and uh coac that I believe
that I believe that's it eval the buffer
let's try it eval the buffer okay we got
a problem of course warning lexical
argument Shadows the dynamic
what so let's see if this variable is
defined describe variable yes it is
yeah it is defined uh you know and is
this variable defined quy yes okay so
what is the problem warning lexical
argument lexical argument Shadows di oh
okay lexical
argument Shadows okay we got
a oh yeah that's I think that's why we
got the
spelling typle here not 12 okay
so
what
okay oh yeah because we before it it
made a mistake so this became now this
this symbol is not Global so that's a
mistake anyway we don't want to so to
fix that we can restart
emac you know the issue right now is
that because we made a typo in the
variable name it was
12 and we and we run the code so this
variable X key to is now a global
variable it is a symbol now it's like
Global and in it's possible to remove
the symbol it's but usually is not done
so you can just restart emac but let's
forget it okay let's run
it uh again
lexico oh yeah so oh my God this obvious
type of coma just came from JavaScript
let's run it again okay it seems it um
it's done let's look at
um Okay so
let's run it okay
fantastic
wait oh it mapped the delete return
sequence
map yes yes and
uh um those these are varable variables
and function so return value but why is
the return value not shown obviously
it's shown but it's
incorrect you see this return value
is it's not doing it's job you see it's
it's trying to connect
this so this is incorrect okay our code
worked but something is wrong
so the something is wrong is
because
um is because did the layout work so we
can always debug print
messages print this variable okay run it
let's go to messages buffer and see what
we
get okay I don't think the
splits it is
successful ching
ching oh thank you that's not all in
regular expression that's right but in
because in emac you have the toothpick
syndrome very nasty so in fact you need
uh you need two backslash very nasty
let's try it again
there there it is there is our result
but it's incorrect again we we got
something closer but you see we got
bunch of pairs but it's
incorrect oh wait it's cor actually yes
it's correct
because now there's too many of them
it's so the message both are TR TR it so
in order to not truncate you need to
print each item you see it works you see
because this one you see the first line
it's all the same because that's the
number in symbol row so the number in
symbol Row for quy and for KAC it's the
same they didn't change so what we have
to do is
um you know we can actually
print uh we can print this and maybe
will work I don't I don't know if it
does but maybe not it's try fantastic
now let's look at
um now it's better okay copy it new
buffer paste it let's see what's going
on so now let's let's replace by all
right parin by right
paren new
line okay
so we got that that that
that okay so far so good yes it
worked so CTE becomes KAC dhf is that
correct let's go to our keyboard
layout qu is right
here comac
DED is f correct
R becomes B let's check one more time R
is here and col DH is p
wait
quy R should
become P but we have here R becomes
p
uh but I think uh so you know so this is
a matter of like kind of debugging but
basically we
got you know that's what we want that's
a associative list a bunch of key value
pairs that's
right so but now this little bug so why
is
it R qu R
becomes b quy
r quy R right
here becomes chac
DH
what it says P there
d
q let's
try oh wait wait we got the we got a
issue I think our code is not correct
here okay we inherited wrong code okay
let's go fix
it let's go to keyboard block let's go
to layout so this is a page for that and
go to the top go to the JavaScript and
uh uh not not CSS go to the JavaScript
and uh go to search for corat
okay KAC and here's KAC DH did we have
the yeah you see it's p here somehow we
made a
mistake okay so it's p it's not
um
B so Q
wfp
GJ qw
FP BJ okay
what yeah what's going on with this okay
I think I used oh okay so we got this is
wrong too this should be just Escape
there should be no
space uh let's just use let's just use
our JavaScript code here instead of the
so this code I believe is good so okay
let's use
yeah copy that close that close that
close
set okay let's let's try to call the
marle
again okay and the whole thing needs to
put them inside double quote and escape
this double quote and escape the
Escape that's right and also this this
is also needs to be escaped yeah lots of
this you know this Escape thing is the
worst thing in programming languages
when you have a string you know you have
a backslash to escape in a bash you know
it's worse you know so when and in HTML
you also have the m per you know if you
want to escape the the angle brackets
so if you design a language
you never you should never have anything
that has that you should never have this
Escape mechanism you know this begin
from C people and it just spread like
like C is you know Unix and C is the
kind of virus they spread the most
harmful uh thing all
across so right now we are you know we
are facing a damage of that problem
because you see you see this back space
you know if you don't have any Escape
then you don't have any of wor but if
you have any of kind of Escape you need
to go through each of the thing in your
string to see if there's you know some
Escape happen that's what that's the
problem we are facing because we have a
backsplash back backs slash here because
in JavaScript we were using that tick
sign for for the
delator that's the template string in
JavaScript so in JavaScript we needed
that but in emx not so okay so let's
let's just fix it let's not talk um okay
so back slash needs to escape that's
right for slash is okay and uh this
delate delimiter needs to escape okay
and uh okay so also remove
the trading wi space okay so this is our
previous
deleted uh it so far it looks good okay
let's just run a
code run it okay
so and uh and delete print okay
fantastic it seems like did copy close
go to it select all paste okay
replace right bracket by a line okay so
now let's
see okay so that righted bracket by a
line that's right okay oh so another
thing we need to do is that if the
characters are the same don't do
anything
okay okay that's the step so you know if
the characters are the same do not put
it into the uh
list but basically that's
it so uh some characters are different
right yeah indeed yeah so that's it so
now okay let's let's try to make them so
that if the if the characters are the
same don't do
anything uh okay uh Lis is
um
so well if you want to do that then you
you can't use the you know then you have
to you know you you can't use functional
programming right now I'm we are doing
like pure functional programming we use
this um but if you do not if some of the
if the x equals to Y you don't want to
be part of the result then you have to
do a extra step by removing it okay
let's do
that uh we so we use this function this
function is very powerful to allow you
to
remove some sequence of elements okay
that would
[Music]
be this sequence map cat
okay so
yeah so we use that okay uh and uh
the and the
result so we map a function into this
sequence optional type we don't care so
we map a function and what the function
is Lambda of of
course and if the condition is
if the car part of the cons is equal
to the C part of the cons then return NE
otherwise other right wise return itself
clean up the code so clean up the code
prettyy so that is what we
do okay let's just run it run it okay
run
it uh wrong type argument list P okay so
oh
wait
what uh sequence map
cat oh yeah if we we need to return the
list okay
so okay run it
fantastic let's see fantastic copy it
new buffer paste it replace make them
into
lines beautiful
successful okay that that's that's we
did that's the function that's the
function we um want today so we talked
oh 50
minutes how long have we
been any questions post it okay I'm
going to
answer we talked
for 50 minute 50 minutes that's right
yeah fantastic
what's the difference between let and
set Q let just let you declare a local
variable set Q is actually setting a
value now you might be asking is that
what you are asking you you could put a
value in in the Le for example let's say
we have a new variable y y and let's say
we want the value to be three so what we
do is like that okay so you can put it
inside the lead if you want then you
don't need set q but putting inside you
got other issues because what happens if
you the the if if the if you the later
variable when you give a value to this
variable if you want to use the
previous variables value you cannot do
it inside then you have to change you
have to use let Star okay let Star you
know so it it gets uh more complicated
so this these days I prefer to always
separate them so in the let is just
simply variable names then you use set
to to set
value uh opinions on pornography uh I'm
not going to talk about that today emac
Le we can talk about that in some other
time and uh probably not YouTube I'm
hoping to Branch out to uh Twitter
Twitter L musk I trust very
much there are lot issues you know
political issues USA is uh very in a
very bad state so I hope we can you know
help to recover so I'm going to try to
use start to use Twitter
stream uh you know and see and we can
talk about politics over
there so let the varable declare and
secure assignment yes that's right
anything
else okay I think maybe that's it let me
get my drink
we shut down in two
minutes okay so so we let's clean up so
we got this function working I mean the
skeleton I mean that's essentially
that's what we want so but the main
thing is that let's go back to S flag
Keys search for
RAC you know so we got the all these
bunch of layouts b b Bop carox Co ma K
vak Norman and you know all this layout
we need to so you see we need to what I
need to do is to start to remove all
this so instead of this hardcoded you
know key se you know key payers we just
simply
call you know we simply call the
function we Define like like
that and we Define the key MTH like that
you see it so now it's much more better
it's clear you can see the layout so
that's what I need to
do fantastic thank you guys for
watching okay so let's make me copy this
code cut go to talk show
show uh and paste it here so create a
new block new code block paste it syntax
color it showing
browser
great bye guys
ching ching let's try some Emoji let's
let's let's try to play the
YouTube let's see Emoji I have a bunch
of
um there okay let's
see YouTube YouTube
Emoji this is SAS Emoji lunch box
my favorite emojji