Morning everyone. Welcome to another
episode of Excel talk show. We are going
[clears throat] to code advent of code
2025 day five problem one in wufam
language.
Uh okay let's begin. So in previous 20
days uh I've been doing adventure code
almost every day. So check it out on
YouTube. So today let's let's start day
five. Okay. So let's start wam language.
Uh if you don't know what wufam language
is
about two days ago there's a like almost
one hour introduction episode 731.
Okay. So here is wam language. Let's
start the kernel three. Shift enter to
evaluate and magnify. and let's put that
here. Okay, so at the end of code.
Okay, so let's see.
Let's get ready. So, uh, sorry, hold on
a second. So, my Twitter, my Discord,
Wam language, Firefox, today's talk
show. If you are here, say hi. If you
are watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed. Okay.
So, advent of code. Uh, return to your
advent of code calendar. Okay. Day four,
day five. We got a long way to go. How
many problems are there? 12. Oh, god.
Okay. So, this needs to be like over
here.
Day five. As the folk leaves break
through the wall, the elves are
delighted to discover that there's a
cafeteria on the other side of war.
These days, I just skip those. They
don't they you don't need to know them.
Uh but let me just read them quickly.
You can hear a commotion coming from the
kitchen. At this rate, we won't have any
time left to put the wreath up in the
dining hall. Resolute in your quest, you
you investigate. If only we hadn't
switched to the new inventory management
system right before Christmas. Another
elf exclaims, "You ask what's going on?"
The elves in the kitchen explains in the
situation. Explain the situation.
Because of their complicated new
inventory management system, they can't
figure out which of their ingredients
are fresh and which are spoiled. When
you ask how it works, they give you a
copy of their database, your personal
input. Okay. the person input,
excuse me.
So, fresh versus spoiled. The database
operates on ingredient IDs.
It consists of a list of fresh
ingredients ID ranges.
Okay, a blank line and a list of
available ingredient IDs. Okay.
So you got a list of lines. It consists
of
a list of fresh ingredient ID ranges. So
suppose these are 3 to 5, 10 to 14, 16
to 20. That's a list of fresh ingredient
ID ranges. A blank line and a list of
available ingredient IDs. Okay.
Fresh ingredient ID range. So you got
two concepts.
First of all, you got available. Okay,
ingredient ID is a concept. Ingredient
ID. Then you have available.
That's another concept. And fresh is
another concept.
Okay. Ingredient ID. For each ingredient
ID, it can be available
and or fresh. I'm not sure which one is
exclusive or not.
Hi, are you using ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 for good or will you go back
to glove 80 at some point?
I can I I probably will go back um
because because I have, you know, years
to go. So,
um, it depends, you know, I I I don't
have to. So, it's just I'm very
comfortable with either one. So, few
videos ago, about last week, maybe
someone asked. So, again,
both of them, I like them very much. I
can use either one of them continuously
for years, no problem. And uh um so
check out my website, you know, for the
detailed review. And maybe I should
write up a new article about exactly
which one. Um
you know, again, I all I can tell you is
that I like them both very much. Okay,
so this is ultimate hacking keyboard 80.
Search for YouTube, I have reviews. and
the other one glove 80 I've been using
for four years like on my live stream.
Check them out. Okay, so you got
ingredient IDs and available and fresh.
Now the question right now is what's the
relationship between a available and
fresh? Okay,
so the fresh ID ranges are inclusive.
The range three to five means that the
ingredient ids three, four, five are all
fresh. The range can be also overlap. An
ingredient ID is fresh if it is in any
range. Okay, so this is all these are
fresh.
The elves are trying to determine which
of the available ingredient ids are
fresh.
Okay. So you then you got a list of
available
ids.
Okay. And you want to know which one are
fresh. In other words, which one are in
the first list of ranges.
So in this example this is done as
follows. Ingredient ID one is spoiled
because it does not fall into any range.
Okay, seems easy problem. Ingredient
five is fresh five here. Fresh because
it falls into range 35.
Ingredient ID 8 is boiled because it
doesn't occur in any of the fresh range.
Okay. Ingredient ID 11 is fresh because
it falls into range 10 to four.
Ingredient 17 is fresh because the range
16 to 20 as as well as range 12 to 18.
Okay. Ingredient 32 is spoiled because
it does not occur in the range. Okay. So
in this example three of the available
ingredients ID are fresh. Okay. Three of
them. 5 11 17. Okay,
process the database file from the new
inventory management system. How many of
the available ingredients ID are fresh?
It seems like a trivial problem.
You got a list of numbers, you got a
list of ranges, you just want to
determine which of the given numbers are
in the range. So what is the um
how many of the available ingredient ID
are fresh?
So you just want to know total number of
them seems like a trivial problem. See
you know this seems like the most easy
problem
of advent of code is I write something.
Okay. So, let's start
move from language code. Paste the link
there.
So,
so you got this list. Um,
okay. Put it back. Now let's look at
what are my uh personal input
because it's always fruitful to
have a glimpse of what it is like. Okay.
So you got this. So how many lines total
you got?
Okay. So separated by a blank line. Then
you got
174. then the rest uh 1,75.
Okay. So, let's save it to um
let's save it to advent of code. Uh
let's give a name.
So the rand of code day
uh five. Okay. So that would be the file
name. Save it in this directory and this
file name. Save it. Okay. Copy the file
path. Close it and uh paste the link
here. The vin code and uh
remove and go back to browser. Copy the
link
there. There there there
code day five. Okay.
So
seems so trivial problem. So you um
let's see.
So basically you want to
did I answer your question? Track Vega
track vega
say it okay because I I I answered your
question.
Uh
so all you want to know is the total.
Okay, you know, we can write it out and
well, writing it out is like wasting
time. [laughter]
Sorry, I'm still coughing. There's still
lingering code
very miserable.
So given a list of ranges you want.
Okay. So,
so you do two loops or nested loop. You
go through the list of ids.
Then you write a function to check if
given the id and uh and give a range to
check if that number is in the range. If
it is then exit the loop you don't want
to keep going. So then add a tally count
it so easy. So
you given a list of numbers
okay
how many of
how many of them are in the given
ranges.
That's the problem.
So plan solution
uh
what I'll go plan. Let's just say
move through the numbers.
Check if it
Uh if it is in a range
if so
it so there is a problem you see in this
wra language um use kasawa wra language
mode
let me show you.
So, I'm using Kasa Wuam language mode.
This allows me to code wam language in
Emacs, which is what I'm using. And uh
oh, I forgot this pink window shows all
my command course and keystrokes
as I type. Okay, so let's see. So, you
can see I move the cursor. You can see
it says forward button. You see?
So as I type it shows the command name
and the keystroke I type. I'm using a
Vora keyboard layout and I'm using SFly
keys. Search for it. You'll find that
it's a
the most efficient key binding system
for Emacs. It's on GitHub. So and I'm
using the Wraim language mode. So you
can see so you go to layer. Uh so here
is a source code. Here are all my Emac
list packages for Emacs. Close it. Go to
the top. Uh go to that link. So this is
Kasan Wolf mode for Emacs. You can
download it. It's on GitHub. Okay.
So in in this mode, you know, I have
lots of brief. For example, if I type if
so that expands through the if function
template. So if I do table that expands
through table function template
and but I don't want them to expand if
you are inside the comment you know I I
used to turn it off I turned it back on.
So
so actually we can fix it. So open mode
search for a brief. So uh we are doing a
little digression. So is anyone else
watching comments? Okay. Tell me to stop
digression or something. Uh,
so you want to
Yeah. So this be able return true if not
string. Uh, yeah. So let's
So if you do that
then
compile it by compile. No error. Good.
Load it. Yes. Close. Close. And now we
back in here. Now if you type if
you see they stop. They don't expand
anymore.
Okay, that's better. Okay. So I'll go
plan.
Loop through the numbers. Check if it's
in the range. If so, tally it.
Uh
so
imple
implement
implementmentation.
Okay. Implementation.
What? Oh That's a problem about a
brief turning off in common.
input.
Okay. So, God
god, I'm wasting time. Okay. Let's
focus
and let's just start to write a
function. Okay.
is in range. Okay. Uh let's write the
function. So is in range. A id
first argument
range.
Okay. Uh
take two arguments ID and range. Okay.
Now we define it to be
uh
we define it um to be
now we want to know what are the size of
the range. So that because one trivial
way to solve this is you simply generate
all this list of numbers in the range
then you can check membership of the
list if if a item is in the list. That's
the easiest way. Uh actually that's
stupid way
or you just do a comparison of two num
numbers greater than the first one
greater or equal or less than equal
that's so trivial problem. Why do they
have this problem
of code? Uh
and did I am I like dreaming close that.
Uh
so let's look at the uh okay you see the
the range numbers are huge.
Yeah, you know possibly wait 41 you know
they're not very huge. Uh
well sizable let's see one two three
four how many digits? Okay
15 characters. So that's like kilo mega
uh what's above pa something
okay so yeah you got huge number you
don't want to generate the list okay so
okay close it let's see again just how
many
yeah it's just two numbers it's so silly
So,
so in that case you just two numbers
range max.
Yeah, it's so easy so trivial problem.
Let's start just solve it. Okay,
it doesn't make sense to plan. Let's
directly try to solve it.
So these inputs how you want them to be.
So
you you read them as a string then
suppose. Yeah. Okay.
And that's the description of the
problem.
Okay. Then this is x input
equals to that.
Okay. That's suppose your input is a
text file then you need to pause it.
So, so uh
string split by default it will split by
um
by any white space.
Let's see. One, two,
I give you two parts. Then
[clears throat]
Okay, I'm going to do this one shot.
Okay, so
test test. Okay.
split then split by line then two
expression. Okay. So,
so what do you want the result?
Actually, I can do the whole thing in
one line directly. So, let me
let me just do that then.
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
[sighs]
>> Okay. So that will give you
then
then [clears throat]
we are dealing with the ranges right
now.
Okay, that's that that returns the first
uh range. Okay, now the second list of
numbers that's going to be
the second part. The list of numbers is
going to be that
this is uh
range list.
Okay. Something like that.
And uh
and uh we can uh
okay then expression here. Then you can
actually print it.
Okay, this whole expression just return.
Then you need to map expression. So
yeah, number two expression. So,
so because right now they are streams.
Okay. So, second block then you just map
it.
Actually,
you don't even need to map
because let me show you
because you if you say to expression
three
four that will just book even if it's a
list. That's right.
Okay. But if you say four, does it
distinguish? No. Well, then you can just
say first
number Q. Okay.
not number form
it will return true. Okay, that means it
tells us make sure it's a number. So
this will work. So
[clears throat]
same thing here you don't need the map.
Okay,
simpler. Okay. So if you run this,
it's going to give you
list of list of numbers. Okay. Invalid.
Uh wait
with then
invalid syntax in or before uh with
block to Y
[clears throat]
invalid syntax X input
Why is it invalid? I don't know. So,
let's copy it. Select all. Paste. It
seems valid to me.
Shift enter. It works. Oh, invalid
because when I run it, it only run this
part. You see it? You see now if if I
have to now if I run the whole code then
they work. Run the whole code.
You see? Fantastic. And beautiful.
Okay.
[clears throat]
So now we got this
we got them into nice list of numbers
and range and and then we can just uh
Okay. We can tr so trivially do this.
Okay.
Are you using WSL?
Uh what is WSL? I forgot. Oh, Windows
Windows system for Linux. No, I'm not
using that
obviously. Why would you say I'm using
that? I'm not. Hope you have a good day.
Christmas. Hey, merry Christmas.
[clears throat]
I upgraded to Windows 11 last week. I
have a story to tell. I have blogs. You
know, Windows
11's painful. Um anyway
because uh you know Windows 10 expired
then you have to go to your bio you have
to turn on the security chip. Then you
have to turn on security boot in the in
your BIOS or EF something then you know
then install Windows 11. Anyway, so we
we so we so this is very nice and uh
let's start just write the solution. So
let's see go through the ID list. So
let's just make it uh you know one of
the issue of Wuang language is that
identifiers
also known as the variable names or
function names cannot allow even
underscore. So you stuck with just these
alphabets you know so
so you see so you know you
so so
and it shouldn't start with a capital
letter because by convention all bod
functions they start with capital letter
so all your own variables or function
name should start with lower case so you
can you can say
you can say X ID list but then the IDL
you know it's like anyway that's uh like
the issue uh with wam language
so you go through ID list okay
Okay. So we can like we can code this in
one shot you know
don't even have to check anything. So
map a function. So map a function if uh
it's directly this function will tell
you directly that ID
that number is in the range. Okay then
what you do you this is a function x. So
you function
then the function will map again
map the
it will map again
map it to the x range list see so you
map another function
okay this time the local variable let's
name it y okay then here is the meat
Uh we don't want to use map because map
will keep going. It won't stop. We want
to exit as soon as something is true.
Okay. So yeah. So these two map we don't
want map. We want to exit as soon as
true. Okay. So look up the map function.
There is some other function we want map
or map it. We want to exit. Okay. as
soon as something is true.
Um, so
we can use what is it? So let's go to my
woof language. Let's
go to some wra language for programmers.
Search for it. You'll find it on
kasali.info.
And uh let's go to list string number
boolean list and list operations. That's
it.
So you want to
check every item in a list. I mean go
through them but as soon as as as you
find some condition exit. Okay. Because
otherwise um
[clears throat]
uh
So will this list of numbers do they
repeat? That's one of the question like
do they stupidly repeat? Let's look at
uh
you know you can like hack. So there are
1,000 okay there are exactly 1,000 ids.
Sort them. Wait. Sort them. And now you
can easily see if they repeat. Now it's
sorted now. Okay. Now you can Now let's
see. Now delete
duplicate lines. Do it. Okay. They are
all unique because it's still 1,000 of
them. You know, it's tricky because you
don't know if they, you know, they they
might repeat one ID 10,000 times. So
that makes your code less efficient
something.
Anyway,
uh so what what is it? So let me think
about it.
Can we actually just directly use count
um
member Q count pattern level spec.
So delete add drawing sort filter minax
union defense
map
Map with index map to multiple lists.
Okay. Block map.
Subset map. No,
let's see. Do we have to use iteration
then
or do we have to actually use nest
or recursion
tally and group?
Okay, I need to think about this.
Wait, is is there a every
so
yeah there's no such as every
that's not how language name it is left.
[cough]
[clears throat]
So, is there a quick way to do this? Let
me think.
list of ranges. So you got a bunch of
numbers. You got a list of ranges.
And these list of ranges are
Okay, that's what it shows. Okay. So,
show it there.
[clears throat]
reduce
fold fold while nest wire. Okay, I think
I know what I want. So you need to you
go to iterations
and uh mapping a function recussion
next while is what you want.
Wait for wire. Okay. So for and reduce
select cases
given ID and the range you need to
now is there some smart way
check exist is the member. So,
Actually,
we can use select
that way. We don't have to do nest while
or while.
Yep. Because select allows you to return
just the first item.
Yep.
Uh let me show you. Okay.
So what you want to do is this
select
even Q
so that we will return four and six
right but now if you say select
even Q then
just one just give me the first one
okay that then it returns it now If if
nothing is found,
let's say um
uh what
so
then that return you know there's no
even number it will return empty list.
See? Fantastic.
So the way we utilize the way we use the
select function is that we going to have
a list of ranges.
Then
this part will be um
uh wait this wait.
Okay. So it doesn't take a function.
God.
Well, the current ID can be embedded.
So,
the current ID can be embedded in the
function.
Is that right? Yes. The function will
return true or false. The current ID
with the current ID embedded.
Yeah, we can do that. So let's let's
show an example. Okay. So for example,
we we are doing some trial and error
here. So select this is the range. Okay.
And uh let's say the current ID let's
say 17. Okay.
And the function select by a function,
right? So the function we have to write
our own. So the function will have 17
embedded in it.
And the and what wheel does it do? It
will um takes the item then
the 17 is greater than
greater than x
first element
and
okay and and Um,
greater [clears throat] than equal
and uh
or
uh they need to be end. Okay. Then less
than equal
And less than equal the second the
second part
that
okay so 17 greater than equal the first
part less than equals the first part x
is one of this range if that's true,
you'll [clears throat] return true or
false. So if we do this, it will [cough]
[clears throat]
then you need a third argument. Let's
just say the first the first just select
the first. So this will return 128.
Okay, let's try it.
Uh 1620. That's right. 1620. You see
1620. That's right.
Fantastic. Is that beautiful? Beautiful.
So, so here is how we going to use
select to work. Okay, this superb
function. Now, let's
cut it. Put it back. Let's make it a
example by itself so people can learn
Wam language syntax color. Go to the
browser. So this is problem description.
Here is the heart of our algorithm. This
select
you see. So it it will always return um
empty list or a list of length one and
that list will be the range. Okay. So
this provide extra. it actually tell you
which range it is in.
Okay. So,
so if it returns empty that means the
number the ID is
in invalid not fresh. If it actually
return a length one list then the ID is
fresh something like that. Okay. So go
to the next. So
okay. So now we know what to do. We use
this select function copy.
So remember we don't want to use map.
You see this map map? No, let's not use
map. So you now you use the select.
So
uh but first you map. Okay. Then
you map it to the ID list. Yeah, you
need to go through all the ID. Then what
you do is here, select
this part. Okay.
And this part, what you're going to do,
select. Oh, wait. Uh, yeah. Select. So,
this is your whole range. So this is X
range list right and the function is
here. Now we don't want to use X because
the duplicate X. So the first one we can
um
ID. So you can rename it ID. Okay.
So the function that is ID and ID is
that there
you see the current ID and the function
here
a range.
So this can say a range. Okay.
You can make the function take two arc X
min
X max
X max so that we don't need to extract
the first part. Okay. X min and
X max.
Does that make sense? Anyone watching
say hi?
I managed to get free security updates
for a year for my Windows 10. So, I'm
going to stick with it for now.
That's okay.
Uh, better switch to Linux. That's what
I was going to do. Then I then uh I in
then Windows 11 I installed. So, I don't
worry about it. But I was going to
switch to Linux because
you I going to have to eventually
because the Windows just sucks the big
deep state and also Google Google wind
Microsoft you know and Facebook.
So anyway, so at least Linux, Linux is
not like,
you know, safer. It's also like part of
deep state these days, but at least it's
better than Windows. Um anyway, so
so [snorts] this will, you know, this
code will surprise most people because
they've never seen code like this.
There's no loop and there's no even
recursion. This is like using select.
Okay. So it work. So anyway, so
so once you select it, then you need to
do something. Okay. Then
once you select it. Okay.
So this this will give you a result like
um Let me delete it. Um well you
can see here it'll give you a result
like a range. So once you get that,
um, you
once you get that, you want to
you want to turn it into one.
Okay. If it's zero, I mean, if it's
empty, turn it into zero. If it's
otherwise, turn it into one. So, let's
turn this into um
make it into one line. And
if
Okay. So, um there are many ways to code
this. Okay. Well, one way is we're going
to use the width again. Okay. So,
uh make it more readable.
Okay. Select result equals to that. Now
if
select result
equals to
empty
turn it to zero else one
okay can you guys see what I'm
Okay. So let's compact this again.
Yeah. So that is the function
and when this is done you just total it
and you don't need that anymore. Comment
out. Okay. So the whole solution
is just this block.
That's a whole solution. I think I'm
pretty sure
uh should I like if I were coding myself
I would just run it and you know if
there's error there I go fix it. But
if I'm doing live, you know, doing live
stream, usually
I double check that make sure one shot
coding is correct. So let's double
check. Okay, so you got two text block.
Uh so let's rename it
text blocks. Okay, make it easier to
understand. So you got two text block
and you got a range list. So
okay. So you got the range list and you
got the ID list. Uh
okay that's the important part.
So,
so you just um
select
then if select it is empty return zero
else one.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure. Okay. Up here.
Paste the code.
Okay,
please make it work. Oh too many
parameters.
Oh, that's that's right. I got there is
some syntax issue here. Uh
yeah, this this is just one function.
uh select can only take one function.
Okay, I mean I mean select this function
only take one arc. So not X Y. Okay. So
okay,
copy that. So then you have to do
first part then
X range
second part. Okay, copy that back here.
Select or actually go down here. Paste.
Run it. Three.
Is it three? Yes, correct. Okay. So,
yeah. So, so we solved it.
Uh let's copy this so that people can
kind of see what's going on. Okay. And
that's our function. Okay. So, and uh
delete that. Okay. Let's put it back.
Clean up. Uh yeah. So, put it back.
Syntax color showing browser.
So, here's our code.
Here's our code. Okay. And now let's do
the
personal um input. Let's see.
Paste.
Remove.
And now you need to read file. Oh god.
Okay. You need to read the file. Or do I
just uh let's just copy the input here.
I don't want to read the file. Okay. So,
copy the whole thing. Close.
Paste the whole thing. Wait. Paste
again. Yeah. So, now you see now you got
this huge. Okay. Now, go down. Go down.
Go down.
Just run it.
661.
Copy.
Are you sure it's correct? I'm pretty
sure. So, click here. 661 I mean 611.
Submit.
That is the right answer. Fantastic.
Okay. So, do you guys like it? Does that
all make sense?
Um,
does it all make sense? Let's Let's put
it back. Syntax correct. show in
browser. So we did today
problem description
uh example of using using select to
solve this problem. Okay, then we just
code the whole thing
width is local variables. We declare x
text blocks as local variable. Then we
pass them into two text blocks. One is
the range list. Actually they become a
list of numbers of nested list of
ranges. Then id list is a list of
numbers. Okay. So here is the actual
output the x range list and ID list.
Then
what we have to do is just map a
function to this ID list. Okay. And what
this function do the the whole the heart
of the function is this select select of
a given range let's say 3 to20
then use this function to determine if
if we want to keep that
uh wait this select this is a list of
ranges so this is like all of them Okay.
So we want to select meaning field. So
uh
some of them we don't want.
Okay. So but how do you check using
these functions? So if that current ID
is in the range then just select that
range then stop then return that range.
Okay just return the first one.
So this will return either empty list
when the when the id is not in any of
the range or it will return one of this
range. Okay. So if it returns empty then
just return zero. If it returns one of
these range return one okay so that you
map this function to all the ids. The
result is list of one or zero. Then you
just total it. Then you get the number
solution. Okay, thank you guys for
watching. Bye guys. Uh, if you like my
stuff, go to kasali.info.
So
go to your browser x ah e.info
http no s not secure because I'm not
asking your credit card.
So kasali.info info go to
all the way to the bottom. Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me or PayPal me. Okay,
thank you very much. Because money is
the most important.
I don't want to do YouTube ads then
start to have like thumbnails. Oh, crazy
discovery. Oh, this program will change
your life. You know that
Okay, bye guys.
We shut down in 1 minute.
Your last chance to comment.
Okay. So, let's see. Did we Yeah,
everything is good. And uh this is, you
know, let's do a screenshot of this in
Wua language. Looks nice.
We did run into a error that's kind of
like syntax error.
Yeah. So this is good.
Copy it.
And guys,