good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 december 27th
and 8 o'clock almost 8 30
p.m san francisco time
how are you guys hello george from
australia
and we are going to uh do emac lisp
live coding and some random chat okay
so just type your comments in the chat
box and i'll get to it
and well there is a dollar sign you see
so put dollar in my account okay
that would be appreciated good evening
lukas
lucas sambi where are you from
so we're gonna do emac these and uh
and some other random things okay you
talk
i reply okay so first of all star talk
show
so what uh emac these are we going to do
so first of all for you emacs users the
pink window
right there is all my command calls and
keys
so if you see what i'm doing you don't
know you can just look up the command
name
and just search for what search it
on the web you'll find the source code
so today's talk show
open the browser and we are going to
yeah so let's so let's um
do emacs okay first of all first stop
is emac list coding and
what are we going to do there it is so
we are going to do
now you can look at this list okay if
you have if you want me to do some
particular items just say it in a
comment
but i am going to begin to do this one
write html command to delete current
tag pair or prompt to type attack
delete okay so that's the one i'm going
to write
copy it back to emacs so
actually open open the file okay so
you see magnify show the wait
okay open notes and this
is the one the item we are going to do
and we are going to yeah magnify
why don't we so we're gonna copy it
close it okay copy it close it save it
paste it here okay and
and you might be wondering what is the
background image
the background image is this fantastic
movie
the hunger games the hunger
in hunger games breath it all in
children now i love this
i love these
now you may notice the angle my camera
angle is different today because
uh it's you know my wife is sleeping
behind me well she's
watching her chinese tv drama shows
you know so i'm you you are seeing you
are looking at me
now anyway this movie is fantastic i
love it the hunger games
and the hungering hunger games well why
hunger because
i personally have intimate relationship
with that
and it's fantastic movie i love it
because
for many reasons and this is the image
you are
seeing breath it all in children
in fact our society you know america and
let's just say america okay in our
society our society is
approaching the hunger game state
okay it is approaching as you can see
you know she's got this purple hair and
indeed we have lots of these purple
hairs
and people and they are looking for
fashion
you know they are highly elite and they
are
fake you know hypo hypocrites and they
are rich
yes indeed our society is approaching
that
and we have games hunger games you know
forget about hunger for a moment
just think about the games yeah video
games gamers
you guys are gamers so that's the
background image now let's begin
the the seriousness of the emac list
the greatest programming language
okay so write a uh write a html command
to delete contact pair for example for
example i'm on this
line and you can see the li tag here
i want to remove the arrow tag i don't
have a command for that
but i do have a command i have you know
i have for example
i have a command xsa remove
list okay because html remove these tags
so if i press enter you can see the list
tags are good so
let's um let's let's copy it let's do it
here so
this is so this is original
and here is a copy and i call the
command
remove list text you see all the list
tags are
removed including ul and
li and i also have a command for example
i
write right now i make this into a
paragraph i also have have a command
that remove
removes paragraph text so
h html remove
paragraph text enter you can see
paragraph tags are good
now so i can go on and write the command
to remove for example remove
dive or remove a main
or remove footer
yeah but it would be nice to have one
command to remove
you know the attack the cursor is
currently in
so let's begin writing that shall we
george sent me 30 dollars thank you
george
uh merry christmas now that you are
uh s j w
u expert s j
s sjw expert can you tell us where the
history of western philosophy
went wrong oh that's the social
justice uh is
it yeah yeah it's jw okay
can you tell me where the history of
western philosophy ran wrong okay okay
yeah
we can talk about that uh
in fact you know why don't we just talk
about that because today is lisp and
random hey good morning
uh nimshan nimchiko
greetings to hong kong uh
and greetings to sweden lucas zambia
okay so
emac lisp versus social justice which
one topic to talk about uh maybe yeah
let's talk about social justice because
there's
you know this this there's money it has
the money
it is my duty to respond to the to money
so social justice okay let me tell you
about that so about
two months ago uh i
took a project i
okay so let me just you know so
so i studied the philosophy
and psychology of social justice
that's that's just my term anyway i
studied
philosophy and psychology of the
past 100 years so from 19
1900s 1900s basically
you know it's not exact but anyway
basically the past
100 years so i study philosophy and
psychology
of the past 100 years
and with a particular focus on
uh a particular type of philosophy okay
i i'll just call it social justice
because that's what they are
and uh so let me let me check the
question can you tell us where the
history of western philosophy
went wrong that's a good question it
begins there
okay i would say so the first um so
let's do this
let's let's just write it down okay so
we have a record of what
are we doing uh
social justice can you tell us where the
history of western philosophy
went wrong yes indeed it went wrong it
begin
with the hugo guy he go okay
you might have heard of him because he
is one of the
greatest crackpot in philosophy this guy
is a scumbag you know in society we have
all sorts of scumbags
you know we have thieves we have liars
we have bad
politicians corrupted politicians they
die they take bribes
you know we have bad cops
and yeah i mean it it's not necessary to
be a criminal i mean you have
bad guys you know for example even your
family maybe you have a
i don't know your siblings your parents
or your
your your son or your children or your
granddad that
is a bad person you know he always lies
or something or maybe he's got
psychological problems or she
so in society we do have bad persons
why because well it's a complex
complicated
uh complex thing but anyway so what i'm
saying is that
so you have bad persons you know small
bad and big bad
and you know for then then for example
you have
you know the world war ii the germany
certain countries you know there are
certain leaders
and also japan and uh you know so you
know
all sort of areas fields of human
activity
human endeavor you have bad people
so indeed that is true in philosophy too
you know
for example uh you you also have con men
we have a lot of that in today's society
in america
usa for example because i you know i let
me talk about usa because i know it best
you know you have comment who is who you
know who just cheat money who
for example today on twitter they go to
twitter they say something something and
they
they want your donation and they get get
a lot donation but they don't actually
do
anything they're supposed to they said
they're gonna do they you know they just
make up things they like
and they uh you know usually often they
get away with it you know
and today we have lots of uh in usa for
example you have
non-profit organizations is a lot of
them
and many of them make millions of
dollars a year
inc net income you know millions of
dollars you know
and they are typically there you know
nonprofit organization typically they
they say they are helping humanity you
know they are doing
they are good to us this or that
i think you know most of them are just
bad you know
comments and quotes you know so these
are bad things bad people
in in the same way there are such people
in philosophy
hego is one of them hego now you
you must have heard he go because he's
the most famous
uh [ __ ] that you know the doctor go
every time you search
if you have javascript turned off it is
impossible to turn it on
and wait and research it without typing
because right now for example
let me digress let me tell you a problem
about the
the go idiots you know they they are
struggling they want to be popular right
it's a search engine but they are not
doing
a good job in at least in this aspect
for example
i have javascript turned off so right
now i search
hego but i want to do image search you
know
usually there's an image search button i
just click it
but it's not showing up why is it not
showing up
because i have javascript turned off
so if i'm at google if i go to google
for example
let's say google.com google search
engine
and i say i want to search for hego
okay you see even i have javascript
turned off
but google still you know you know you
can still have images
but for uh for dr go no you don't have
that
that's a failure okay you wanted to be a
part you know they want to be popular
right but they you know it's a
it's a bad software you know it's it's
just
one of the bad so but in google if i
want to for example if i click
images so this is what higo looks like
you know he's
a comment in philosophy one of the
greatest
uh comment in philosophy in philosophy
basically he's the one who began this
[ __ ] philosopher
okay this is just my opinion okay
because in philosophy
uh you know it's it's huge it's got big
history so
actually there are other you know
actually yeah there are
quite a lot comment and codes and
uh [ __ ] you know uh also in region
especially in religion too you know it's
it comes with these
kind of fields uh comment in in religion
and philosophy but anyway in
let's say in the past 200 years hugo is
the biggest one
okay and i i would claim it is my my
opinion okay higo is the one
who began if you really want to go back
to trace
trace where did the how did the western
in particular the social justice kind of
peop you know
thing thinking uh began
it i would claim it began with ego
okay so uh and when okay let's go back
to the
doctor go thing so so for google
for example i have um
you know i can turn on javascript
then the difference is that when i click
a link
you'll kind of show me the um
yeah anyway anyway my point about let's
go back to
go so i want to turn on images you
cannot
you can you know you have to basically
you have to
go to the
go and their name is [ __ ] idiotic
they should really change you know you
have to go there
and then change the javascript turned on
then you
have to type you know
okay so lots of digression right now so
so what i do
usually is i click you know i click on
this
and click on that very
tortuous way to to to do this then i go
to the
go home page you know here at the bottom
then now you can see the url is
drcode.com
then i go here then i turn on the
javascript
okay then i shrink the window there
close doctor go
then now if i search doctor go again
now it shows images okay you see these
buttons shows up click images so that's
that's what the hugo you know one of the
great greatest
uh crack part in philosophy now you have
you know you heard of him and people
will usually say
oh his philosophy is difficult to
understand
you know that's a common thing with the
comment you know with the crackpot
philosophers because they they always
have very you know when you don't
understand something they'll just say oh
yeah it's because
you know you don't understand it because
it's difficult
you know it's [ __ ] so you know don't
so when you use next time you see he go
and you see
oh yeah his philosophy is just difficult
to understand
you might think oh you know maybe you
need to study more no not really
it's just a [ __ ] okay it's a pure
[ __ ]
using language to you know jumble them
up
uh you know take uh take the word for me
so that's higo okay but actually so
i haven't studied higo that much and
also he's not
um within the hundred past hundred years
but let me tell you okay
let me tell you the few uh big key words
of what i would say uh social justice
philosophy
the biggest one is actually continental
counter mental
okay so you go there search for the
youtube
i mean search google ad
go to wikipedia now this is the
i would say this is the main line
this you know continental philosophy i'm
going to explain okay but this is the
main
line this is the forefather this is the
pioneer
of of all the social justice [ __ ]
okay all the crap all the
garbage so you can see let me read
the wikipedia continental philosophy is
a set of 19th
and 20th century philosophical
traditions
from mainland europe okay so it's uh
so it means 1800s and 1900s
this sense of the term originated among
english-speaking philosophers in the
second half of the
20th century who use it to refer to a
range of thinkers and traditions
outside the analytic movements
the analytic movements okay i can i can
explain that
so in philosophy you know in 1900s
the analytic movements is a great branch
of philosophy
uh and basically what so what is the
analytics school of philosophy basically
they are science-based okay you simply
put
so you know there are all kind of
philosophy so analytic philosophy
in particular logicism and positive
logicism
uh they are kind of they they are
basically science-based
philosophy uh in short okay i'm not
going to go into detail
so anyway economic continental
philosophy include
okay let me just quick okay continental
philosophy includes
german idealism let me magnify okay
includes german idealism phenomenology
exists uh exist existentialism
okay and and uh hermeneutics
that's important okay remember remember
the word uh phenomenology
and hermeneutics that's the two biggest
key words in social justice in piranesi
social
justice thought okay phenomenology
and and hermeneutics remember that okay
so continental philosophy is these kind
of things and structuralism
and post-structuralism that's another
big one and deconstruction a big one
now we are getting closer uh and closer
to today
post you know structuralism then post
structuralism deconstruction
french feminism there it is you know
coming you know close into today we have
the social justice words now
feminism and psycho uh
and psychoanalytic theory and the
critical theory exactly critical theory
you know you hear it all the time
critical theory
uh and and feudian highland and western
marxist
views okay anyway
so it is you know so i would say
continental philosophy
is the root you know depending on how
how far back you want to trace is the
root of all the [ __ ] up
okay because they and in general okay so
in general these philosophies they
basically they distance
themselves from science from anything
science they don't want
you know they don't want uh they don't
want
imperialism imperialism you know they
don't want to experience they don't want
very
[ __ ] verificat um verification you know
verifiable they don't want none of that
so their idea basically is you know and
beginning in the early days
beginning you know phenomenology is a
big thing okay that that
that is a huge topic and hermeneutics is
also a big thing you know you can go
online youtube there's a lot of people
explaining those things
uh not necessarily correctly and
typically they
are the social justice type of people
and social justice warriors you know
they are
today basically all most of the
young people in universities because
because you know
the entire universities are uh
corrupted you know they are tainted it's
a disease
okay so anyway you you phenomenology
that's a big thing
exact uh and hermeneutics is a big thing
and ex existentialism is also part of it
okay
so what what is exactly is
existentialism that's another
you know again let me let me say again
these philosophies
okay continental philosophy in short
that that's kind of a group word but
it's not a good
good anyway this kind of philosophy
basically they
they share a certain um approach
or way of thinking okay uh and and
uh and and basically they have a
characteristics of
you know so-called difficult to
understand because you read it you you
know you try to read it
phenomenology uh and hermeneutics
in particular you know you try to read
it you you will not understand it
doesn't matter how high is your iq
okay
you know so they are kind of like they
are these philosophies that you
you study you try to study them
understand what they are saying
they go around about you know like it's
like it's kind of in some way it's like
the
eastern uh philosophical traditions
uh for example taoism zen
uh buddhism you know taoism in
particular taoism you know
they they don't talk in the way of
you know uh western logic you know
clarity precision you know following
uh you know arguments you know arguments
you know the
um
a quick you know the the in general you
know in particular
eastern philosophies they don't follow
that rather they it's kind of just a
culture you know
and they and and in eastern philosophy
for example taoism zen
this kind of thing and confucianism they
don't
you know they don't ask you to reason i
mean reason is not the thing
it's you know it's like out of the
question i mean it's not even
it's not in consideration like they
asian philosophies they are not trying
to
reason okay they are not really trying
to reason they are more of
a kind of a gentle way of you know
telling you about
uh basically a philosophy about life
about the universe you know the
big mysteries the questions
they don't really want to try to prove
you know for example taoism says the
word is made of
and young you know everything is dual
duality
and you know it's like a [ __ ] up crap
you know there's no
logical this is not science okay but
but the point about asian philosophy is
that they are not trying to
uh to reason with you like they don't
they will not say oh
we prove why you know here's the reason
why
the word is in yeah they never say that
okay they just present it to you and you
and it so happens asia you know most
china mostly
you know we followed the tradition the
this is the eastern philosophy
you know you don't you don't confront
okay you don't you don't you don't you
don't try to argue you don't confron
confront okay you they do reason but
it's not like the western thing okay so
the the cultural the thinking pattern is
entirely different
but but in western philosophy that's not
the case it's
rather very different so you know since
the asian times
the western philosophy is always about
reason when you say something you have
to prove it
you know what's your reason what's your
rationality you know
because this this is therefore therefore
something something you know these
you know these people plateau can't
uh you know uh and so on okay
so until so in western philosophy then
you have the continental philosophy you
know i read wikipedia you know i'm not
expert about this but i i have an
interest in philosophy since
uh since 1990 what
uh so anyway so in western philosophy
until then you reach this point okay
continental philosophy
this is the beginning when the
the western philosophy started to
not really following the traditional
western way of rationalism
logic you know like like you reason you
proved something
you you know did stop doing that for
example
okay phenomenology and and hermeneutics
they are
uh kind of complex but i'll start to
explain the existentialism okay
i cannot really do a good job of
explaining this
anyway but essentially it says that
if i can put you know forgive me if i'm
wrong
to the professional philosophers but
essentially because basically
like extensionalism just says that oh
uh well you know you look at you know
they look at the philosophy of
different philosophies you know they
think oh
yeah but you actually uh basically they
say you you need to put humanity into it
okay you need to put human you know
humanity like
you know uh into it so essentially they
say is that
instead of thinking about philosophy how
how the word is
you know materialism versus idealism
everything you know materialism
everything is a physical
object so idealism is that nothing
exists
except your mind because that's the only
thing you can prove you know this is
uh two great branches of philosophy
idealism and
um and materialism you know
one is that nothing exists except
physical atoms you know that's
materialism the other school thinks
idealism thinks that nothing exis
exists except your mind you know i think
therefore i am
and they they they try to reason why why
why they think that way
and there are many you know branches of
their you know
school but then comes its uh
existentialism it says well no
you know all this philosophy is too
complicated we need to put in
some kind of human touch so uh
so for you know so he they recommend
something like that
so when you think about philosophy you
you think actually philosophy
you know it's actually it should be what
you think of it so forget about you know
all the
philosophy you know materialism you know
plateau
or whatever they they say you know they
they they suggest you know
they have this kind of uh
thinking they just say oh uh actually it
just depends on you
okay what whatever they say you know it
it depends on each person
you know you exist potentially that's
you know
because you each person exists you know
you must
define you must view the word by
yourself
that's their point of view this this is
the beginning
of the downhill okay before you know
before the past two months i never
understood
exactly what it is but now i have some
some idea
uh began by this guy uh jean-paul
satter okay i'm not sure i pronounce it
right
but you know so this guy began exists ex
existentialism but i'm not sure that
he's a comment i don't know
you know some of these philosophies i
talked about you know
continental philosophy it is not
necessarily true
that the people involved in them
are common okay they're not necessarily
true you know
because philosophy is a very complicated
you know it's about thought it's about
thinking about the universe
so they you know throughout history
people have some ideas but
so for example the hermeneutics okay the
the guy who created hermeneutics
uh by this guy what's his name uh
but not no wait no i'm talking about
phenomenology okay the guy created
phenomenology this guy
okay edmund russell okay he's a
mathematician
so he created phenom phenomenology
originally is too sturdy
you know what does what is the number
that's the original you know original um
happening then gradually
okay where am i going so
okay let me regroup okay so anyway so
these things okay hermeneutics
uh and uh and uh
phenomenology and hermeneutics is is the
two of the
key things that uh that
gave us social just you know bad
philosophy social justice and
other things uh existentialism like
so so all these philosophies they have
um
they have a similarity is that they
distance themselves
they they are more more and more distant
themselves from science okay from
reasoning and logicality
beginning we can see beginning with the
exis
existentialism because the existing
attention reason they say you know
they tell you that you know whatever
whatever philosophy is
is just what you think it is basically
they want the human
touch you know human touch is also
fundamental to all these
things you know they instead of reason
you know for example in western
philosophy typically you know we want to
reason
logic science physics you know but they
don't but
but the logic and math and science you
know there's no
humanity you know there's no human touch
in it there's no empathy
you know there's no emotion it's kind of
cold you know
uh code so this kind of philosophy
they have something in common is that
they they want to put the human touch
back in
so anyway let me focus okay so uh
actually
how long have i been talking okay
so actually i went uh
i went all over the place do i make
sense
so i've been talking for 33 minutes okay
so let me
i'm gonna read some comments and i'm
going to
um okay let me get get back to the
some of the main points i want to talk
about
okay so just remember okay uh
continental philosophy
is is is the beginning
of when the western philosophy went bad
okay and uh you know they say you know
they say it began with idealism and so
on but
but the few there are a few things i can
tell you uh right off the bat
i mean i mean i can emphasize one is
phenomenology okay
so let me open that phenomenology
and hermeneutics okay and uh
also there are uh others post
structuralism okay
post-structuralism you know we are
getting closer to today
and deconstruction so what is
deconstruction
basically this deconstruction is
basically they just want to attack you
okay that's what deconstruction is you
know
you know so it becomes worse and worse
this this continental philosophy
you know over the past 100 years becomes
worse and worse and
and eventually becomes today's social
justice uh kind of thinking
they become they become a you know this
kind of thinking they became
a pure tactic a pure tactic
to overthrow authority
or your enemy okay that's what this
this philosophy is about so for example
today
you know as you are where in in politics
or on twitter someone will tell you
uh you you are wrong you you know you
are a white guy whatever
you are not you know i'm trying to stay
away from
some of the phrases of the you know that
google will censor me
but anyway so today you know someone
will tell you you are wrong they are
trying to get you
um cancelled you know
they'll just say you are wrong and you
cannot argue with them because
whatever you argue they are not actually
into argument as i said you know this
philosophy they are not
about reasoning you know gradually they
become less
less of that they are they are getting
away from any kind of rationality or
science okay
getting away from it so they are about
so so gradually they become
they become a pure tactic a machinery a
a
weapon you know a machinery to overthrow
your opponent
so today for example someone accuse you
of something
and you you think you didn't you didn't
do nothing
wrong and you can you know argue you
know with them you know
you stand up and argue but but your
argument doesn't work
because they are not they are not into
argument in the first place
that's this philosophy is about
it so it becomes a machinery to to
overthrow your
opponent okay uh so
and that began we we may say that begin
with
deconstructionism okay this
deconstruction you know so
what is deconstruction okay so you know
you know you can you can go read
wikipedia you know yeah this
you know jack jack derek a scum
so this deconstruction is basically
suppose you live in a society okay
suppose um in programming society okay
now someone did hard work so they they
they get a higher pay they
become the top you know the leaders they
get more pay and you get
little pay because maybe you don't work
or maybe you are
uh stupid okay but
but they but but but of course you also
want
high paid you know you want more money
than them then whoever
is doing uh better than you so you want
to think of a way to attack them
to to you know to to put them down
and you become rich and powerful to
overthrow the
authority to overthrow the structure to
overthrow
the mainstream theories or ideas such as
you know science okay so
that's the that's what the
deconstruction is about
so this philosophy you know
deconstruction says that
okay when you read the text you want to
um
okay so let's read wikipedia
deconstruction is a approach to
understanding the relationship
between text and meaning okay
it's an approach to understanding the
relationship between text and meaning
it was originally by the philosopher
jack darydus
who defined the term variously
throughout his career it is
in its simplest form it can be regarded
as a criticism
of platonism you see that that's the key
in its simplest form it can be regarded
as a criticism criticism of platonism
what is platonism basically that's the
foundation of western
science okay a foundation of western
philosophy
so so it's a criticism of platonism and
the idea
of true forms or essence which take
precedence
over appearances here is the
mysterious parts so this is the
philosophy you know deconstruction so
basically it's a
attack on western uh philosophy but and
and but further it says it's id and the
idea of true forms
so you see that he you know he's
attacking your idea you know whatever
suppose you are the plateau but not you
know
he's attacking your idea but he's but he
has
so what's his reason so his reason is
that he
you know he he is the true form
your philosophy is appearances okay his
philosophy is truthful
or essence what does essence mean
i don't know whatever it means okay so
he
he's you know his essence and the true
form
and this you know takes precedence
precedence
over appearances so in other words he's
saying
you know okay your platonism or sciences
or whatever
is based on physics you know logic math
okay that's all good
but you are not true form you know those
are not essence
those are appearances and and the true
form
uh takes precedence over your you know
whatever
your logic
so so so this is uh quite typical of
this continental philosophy okay
so it says deconstruction instead places
the emphasis on
appearance or suggest uh instead
so instead of placing emphasis on
appearance
or suggest at least that essence is to
be
found in appearance what
uh would say that the difference is
undecidable okay there it is there it
goes
undecidable in that it cannot be
discerned in everyday experience okay
it's starting to become you know more
and more garbage
so that that's uh you know that's a
trait this
uh with all these uh continental
philosophy
okay i need to finish i guess i've been
rambling so much
and this is and so far i've been talking
philosophy i haven't
been talking about psychology yet
uh and for now uh so i'm not sure i'm
going to begin to explain phenomenology
um again it's just crap okay it's
it's like nothing you can really
actually understand what exactly they
are saying
phenomenology and hum hermeneutics
that's another
interesting thing that's a big thing
okay hermeneutics began even before
uh anyway it has its origin
in bible in studying bibles okay this is
when i'm going to
criticize the christians okay george
georgie and alan this is when i'm i'm
going to quick
criticize the crack parts the con man
in in christian there's tons of them in
fact
most of them are you know you know
up to now like like you know about 10
years ago or 20 years ago
the christians you know the the
the the power they they fall apart you
know they are taking over
they are overthrown by the social social
justice warriors
but before you know christians is all
powerful ruling
all you know most of the western or of
the western world almost
and hermeneutics is one of the
philosophy that
that defends you know is one of the
tactic
tactics that defends the christian
christian
crap okay so so
what you know it's you know let me read
it okay so hermeneutics is the theory
and methodology of
interpretation especially the
interpretation of
biblical texts and wisdom literature and
philosophical texts hermeneutics is more
than
interpret interpretive principles or
methods used when
immediate comprehension fails and
includes the art of understanding and
communication blah blah
okay so basically hermeneutics
supposedly
is a methodology of interpretation what
does that mean
for example you if you read bible or
something difficult
you know like you don't understand it so
there comes hermeneutics it's supposed
to teach you
in what way you can understand it you
know interpretation
it's more than that but let me tell you
the essence
let me tell you the essence of
hermeneutics
that you will not hear from another
mouth
probably not well i'm pretty sure
someone else have
said it before the essence of
hermeneutics just like like i said
before about
about many of these uh social justice
philosophies
the essence is that you know suppose you
read a book
let's say bible okay you know it's
patently false you know it's lord of
[ __ ]
[ __ ] you know they say you know man
is created from a woman's
uh rip you know god made it god pulls a
rib out of adam and
created uh eve from it
bible bible says that and bible says you
know earth is certain years old you know
bible says a lot a lot of things
so so you have a text and that's
patently false
okay lots of crap uh but
but you are christian you know you are
the uh christianity you know
very powerful for reasons you know long
history
but now science becomes popular and you
are under attack
science is attacking you look look these
christians
you know book their holy book it says
you know this
it says one plus one equals to three
at this point what you gonna do so you
are a christian you know you are one of
the
leaders you know the priests or whatever
you know
pope you know and science you know you
are you are being attacked by science
because your bible is
a bunch of [ __ ] what you gonna do
you invented
hermeneutics that's the solution
so so you're gonna tell these science
people okay
actually yeah actually
you did actually you don't understand
the bible you know
because you know you need to understand
that you know because it's very deep
you know you have to you know
interpretation is a big thing how do you
know what you you know one plus one is
what what does that mean so you have to
know hermeneutics
you know the science you know they don't
actually say science but they
they often try to present it as you know
the science of interpretation
you know so so actually you have to look
into you know
why it's written that way and many you
know it's a big
it's this is a huge you know you can see
on wikipedia it's a huge you know
article it is
it's one load of crap
okay that's what it is hermeneutics
so originally hermeneutics is associated
with
interpretation of the bible okay and by
the way you go to
youtube as i said before youtube will
have you know
some people will try to explain all
these philosophies
and and many of them professors okay
these these are people who live you know
they get money
out of this thing that's why i say these
are crackpots
okay i think actually i i i do i make
sense
i talk too much nothing is objective
sounds like chromos okay i think
deconstruction is saying three apples or
three
card sect are more real than abstract
number three
agree just crap crap okay
in in general what people are saying i
think i should uh
shut down soon
[Music]
uh justin allen so alan says
by what standards do you judge good and
bad that's a
you know that's a very complex
philosophical question what do you mean
by what standards
i mean we can talk about this for 10
years and there's no
resolution because philosophers have
done that exactly you know what is good
and what is bad
and what do you mean by okay so you are
asking by what standard
do you judge good and bad okay what
what what what standards are there i
mean what
you know so if you are asking me a
question if
you know if you are asking me a question
what do you mean by what standard what
what kind of standard are there
you mean by what philosophy or by what
school of thinking
that judge is good and bad you know
and again that's a huge topic you know
there's a lot you know you can go to
wikipedia this huge
number of articles you know uh school of
thought on ethics
basically that's ethics and morality
morality
uh that's supposed to be one one of the
four big branches of philosophy
ethics and morality you know how do you
judge what is good and bad
uh and okay uh
oh oh my god look at this okay i got a
ff well the streamer is a
i don't know if he's joking or he
doesn't like my stuff okay
uh okay
[Music]
guys okay okay so anyway so
so that's my um that's my perception you
know that's my view of hermeneutics it
began with
with bible stuff but in the past you
know 50 years
or 100 years it becomes more complex it
it became you know epic applicable
humanities it became applicable to all
sort of anything
you know about anything especially today
for example
you go to um you go to google
scholar okay so today is today's
university they are all doing these okay
you go to google scholar no if you are
not in academia
you then you may not know but google
scholar is basically what you do
you you know it well if you are in
academia it
you know it basically it show it
collects all
kind of publications journals from
academia yeah
and then one of them you know as you
know social justice one
you know they are everywhere in every
university and there's a big
huge department on on social sciences
social sciences you know that that
that's when all these are studied and
you'll find
you know suppose you type phenomenon
phenomenology
okay then you will find just tons of
articles
endless and each one is basically
incomprehensible
and they will tell you they are they'll
talk about all sort of things that
you know you you will hear in the social
justice circles why
why this you know why you are a bad guy
why
if you are something something sex
something something you are a bad guy
why skin color you are a bad guy
why why you are just a [ __ ] bad guy
and they have tons of articles you know
these literature you know they will cite
it
to back up you know the entire social
justice movements
phenomenology okay you can try you know
go to uh
google scholar and search it and try to
read a few
see if you understand you know and you
know okay phenomenology is one thing
the other thing is
hermeneutics you'll have tons of it okay
and also one of the trick is that you
don't want to search
just these words rather you want to
search some particular topic for example
i don't know maybe racism or gender you
know
you know you want to put those as the
main topic then
then also type in hermeneutics or
phenomenology
then you will see a huge ton of uh you
know literature on those things
so i started to talk you know of course
this deconstruction
then post structuralism uh and you know
so i think that uh summarized my um
my answer to the question which is
can you tell us where the history of
western philosophy went wrong
okay that answer is the
continental philosophy that's the term
okay but
actually so if you read wikipedia the
term is not you know it's actually the
english philosophers or the analytic
philosophers they use the term to
ridicule
this kind of weird crap you know men
philosophies they themselves you know
this
these you know these hermeneutics and
uh the continental philosophers they
don't
they don't call themselves that but now
it became became a standard term
continental philosophy
it origin it mostly originates mostly in
germany
and in france lots of german you know uh
and in france so that's why they call it
continental
you know it's not for example it's not a
tradition
of the united kingdom or usa but they
but
by now they've spread over over white
people's countries not in china not in
japan not none of that
none of these this crap okay in china
japan
asia who you know or in russia
uh yeah probably probably true
so you know but they spread to all the
english speaking uh in western you know
based on latin um alphabet countries
so i would say this continental
philosophy
in particular you know so i talked about
phenomenology exemption existentialism
hermeneutics and i
so that's the main thing and there's
also of course post-structuralism
deconstruction
and french feminism psychoanalytic
theory and critical theory yeah so again
as you know
by like today uh if you you know live on
twitter you think about uh
social justice philosophies you might
think oh that's
postmodernism and marxism you know you
might
you know just say those or critical
theory yeah but those are more
you know i'm talking about so so far i'm
talking about a bit before them
of course they of course they you know
critical theory and all that
they are today's you know the in the
proper part of social justice
thinking okay i think that i
should end there and also uh let me
mention a little bit about psychology
okay
psychology psychology is about
understanding the human mind
okay how human mind works now psychology
shares one aspect with philosophy that
is
it is on a subject matter that we
basically have no we basically have no
way to understand nothing
okay we begin today you know starting
like
today like uh let's say year 2000s
we science technology and sciences have
today are advanced enough that we can
begin to study the brain's structure
you know we have you know we study the
brain you know that's that's called
neuroscience you know that's you know
there's a branch of psychology
you know you study the brain by actually
studying studying the
biology you know the chemistry of the
brain you know you study as
the brain as a science so you can start
to
um you begin to have some understanding
you know
but basically psychology is a topic that
it's you know
we begin to understand it from a
scientific scientific
methodology but overall it's still a
very fuzzy
like you can what do you mean what you
know how does the mind work
how do i know nobody knows you know you
cannot touch it
you cannot know what is a soul you know
what is a soul
you know uh does you know does how do
you know what
is what is consciousness you don't know
nobody knows
and so it began with uh feud
uh freud what how however you pronounce
it so anyway psychology and philosophy
they share these things
they study a subject that's
that has really no scientific you know
not solid
the science okay so in philosophy it's
also a rife
ground for all kind of uh cold man
and quack pots floss in psychology okay
so feud is begin you know the feudian
psycho analytics okay then
then there's a lot okay then there's um
uh psychoanalytic theory okay
psychoanalysis that's
that's freud sigmoid sigmund
freud psychoanalysis then
then you have um
uh they there you have quite a lot you
know i
i think that's it for today maybe i'll
talk about it next time
okay anything else let me read the
comments okay and we shut down
uh let's see
so i've been talking for an hour
58 minutes good time to shut down
so george are you still here say
something to wrap this up
is my answer satisfactory
thank you for your money uh
okay bc says went wrong by allowing
third wave feminism and
yeah yeah so we have feminism that's
again the later thing starting uh 1970s
you know then then you have the
intersection
another incomprehensible [ __ ]
uh
again okay let me let me uh emphasize so
these philosophies
continental philosophy they are the
pioneer they are the forefather the
father
of today's you know how the social
justice kind of thinking all sort of
i guess i'm not sure there's a direct
direct relation to marxism i think they
are
okay
then of course feminism and all that
thoughts on written uh uh
wait and gain stan no i don't know who
is that
well i heard of that but
let me see
i
was a austrian british philosopher
who worked primarily in logic philosophy
of mathematics
the philosophy of mind and the
philosophy of language yeah that's a
okay he's a great guy i can tell you
right away
yeah yeah i came across the guy before
he's good he's i think he's a school of
analytic philosophy
i don't know
his teacher bertrand russell yeah
you know any guy whose teacher is
bertrand russell is good because
bertrand russo is the guy who
he's a is one of the main elements of
the
analytic philosophy okay
he's the main uh
person back to
safari
so we see cochito says do you think
that any social justice are aware of any
of these origins no
well it depends on in general no just
like
you know the masses the masses don't
know nothing you know
uh and so these young people you know
who are brainwashed by this
this kind of thinking today left his
thinking
do they know this history of this of
course they don't they don't not really
not really they just learn they just
learn you know
whatever textbooks of you know critical
theory
uh feminism you know social studies you
know you know they just you know
they don't necessarily know
what came before it you know yeah yeah
and this applies in general to
almost anything too
so alan says look into a cultist
connection with enlightenment
and beyond okay that's that's alan's
take um
yeah that's alex allen i noticed
alan has that that's alan's
cook i might say you know i you know i'm
talking i have my quirks
so alan has also a cork so alan's
you know you know don't take my word for
it you know ask scarlett for his
opinions but i think but i think adam
has the
view that
you know for example enlightenment so i
would very much
approved enlightenment okay
enlightenment
is where how the western you know it's a
general in general
intellectual movements in western
society
and we all benefited from it that's
that's a that's my view and and average
you know
general view in enlightenment and all
these you know posit
positive logicism you know the good
philosophies they all
came from enlightenment okay but alan
disagree i think allen disagree so
because alan
you know i don't want to criticize but
adam believed you know allen is a
christian and alan
believed that okay anyway ask alan okay
and george it seems georgia agrees too
okay so you guys have to accept
you know if you want to so you get you
know alan and george if you guys are
still here you ask me a question and i
can kind of
uh i can disagree
or agree or retort or
or comment on what you think about
uh you know your view alan about
so basically you know i think alan is
saying that
part of enlightenment there is some kind
of
occultism you know basically
crap okay that
that's that somehow created a um
so i think in alan's opinion that's also
the root of social justice thinking
because allen is against
uh you know alan you know he's against
anything that's not christian
uh
yes analytic analytic philosophy is a
good thing that's a good philosophy
analytic philosophy
okay that's that's what be ibd
okay it's like religion and you know you
have many different beliefs
and in philosophy too you have different
schools of thinking
which school is right you know
there's no there's no correct answer
which school of philosophy is right
because because philosophy by itself
it's just fussy you know it's not
science you know you cannot prove one is
what you know
this is right or that is right it's all
just thinking
so in some sense you can think of
philosophy or religions
as a power struggle
and in fact that's a lot of the social
justice
pattern of thinking is
about you know they think it's all just
power struggle
uh but i you know anyway
okay thank you guys for watching bye
that's it for today bye
you