good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show today is July 29th in the year of
our Lord 2019 and today's topic is
random random okay so let's begin
beginning at the beginning what are we
going to talk about I don't know we will
just see okay random topic and okay
people come on - so there are some
programming stuff there is some keyboard
stuff there is some lots of things
actually you know it's like every time
there's tons of you huge amount of
things to talk about
let's check I'm alive yes okay let's
let's begin let's go to let's go to
keyboard you know start you know go
let's go over so okay I was looking at
headphone I mean I mean I was looking at
microphones and headset you know I have
a headset
good morning Deon long time no watch hey
great to see you
so good morning then I saw your keyboard
treat today thinking of actually buying
one of those cool which one my keyboard
trade yeah so you know so are you
interested in
ergonomic keyboards or you know these
are economic keyboards fancy ones or the
like the flat PC keyboard so let's talk
about you know random things is up you
know so guys you know type your opinions
questions subject matters anything you
know like type anything then you know
usually the talk gets better you know
it's because I have a goal you know
talk about something so I'm just going
to go random into my blogs you know of
the past week
you know I'm programming and keyboard
and stuff at any time just type your
comments okay and we can talk about that
there's no fix no fixed topic today so I
was thinking you know I have this
headset
this is a cheap Logitech headset so this
is a cheap Logitech headset so I was
thinking maybe I should get a better one
so I looked a little bit yeah okay so
you are interesting ergonomic keyboard
yeah so that's great so as usual I
showed this a thousand times this is my
keyboard Kinesis Canisius advantage too
and with a number pad but I programmed
it to be function keys so okay so and by
the way there you see that video cam
that is Logitech 920 which is the circus
webcam ever you know don't get that
because it has it has autofocus but it
cannot actually focus on anything close
so when I do keyboard reviews you know
it's pretty bad it's you know when you
go closer close up it's unfocused you
know that's Logitech webcam 920 I think
I already I have written here this one
you know it sucks because on the other
hand but if you go to Amazon Amazon you
know what about this I checked you know
reviews Amazon
it's like four stars you know all the
good things you know like thousands of
reviews and also lots of review sites
sites says it's good but but actually
it's so bad you know you know it cannot
do any close up right now I'm using
actually I'm using a
using a the my webcam right now is a 10
years old you know the cheapest Logitech
10 years old you can get it for like $20
now and that is actually it doesn't have
autofocus but actually is better than
this one so you know I want you you
wonder like so why is all the reviews
say good things you know so today these
days you cannot trust much of the review
websites you know a lot of them are just
copycat you know clickbait and copy pad
copycat yeah so you know and the amazon
reviews so so what i'm saying is that
this to actually take 920 is actually so
bad like anyone you know anyone if you
have it you can you you try it you do
any any close up within you know an
arm's length that's gonna be unfocused
so why why is all the reviews you know
positive you know i think you know
there's just a lot fake reviews so you
have to today you have to be careful
especially you know today like there is
one website that focus on hardware
gadget reviews you know why wirecutter
i think i think some of you are familiar
with that site yes type it okay type so
what while wire cutter okay let's see
wire cutter review it's a very popular
we review website you know recommended
i've heard it from my followers you know
from geeks but I think if I recall
correctly on that website they also say
that the Logitech is you know the 920 is
great it's not you know like maybe in
the beginning this website I don't know
how long this website has been around
but maybe 10 years ago in the beginning
usually usually okay organizations or
websites in a begin
they are good you know but once they
become popular they become crap you know
they become commercialized they become
big you know giant corporations like
Google and you know like Google is the
example so yeah and there are a lot of
paid paid reviews so this wire cutter
and and this website is dedicated to
review stuff you know review keywords
and stuff
I have JavaScript off right now so
that's why you don't see images you know
this this is another thing about modern
websites you know if you have JavaScript
off it looks like that sometimes doesn't
even walk so anyway this website they
they possibly in the beginning it's good
and another website that's Tom's
Hardware okay Tom's Hardware
now this is also a website that we view
in in the beginning they review look
when you have JavaScript off it looks
like that it's idiotic okay let's go
through Google Chrome and you can see
okay so it looks like that you know
Tom's Hardware is very old website it
began by this guy Tom something and so
it was in the beginning this is this
this website Tom's Hardware began at
least 2001 or year 2000 very popular
because it was you know it began by this
guy Tom he focus on hardware like
especially for building PC you know get
for gamers so he knows he is a expert
you know building pcs CPUs and all that
and becomes larger and larger and
usually you know the site gets sold off
you know I serve you my website for you
know millions of dollars then it becomes
bad you know and I'm not too familiar
with the wirecutter website but the few
times I checked it's not good
and also they focus on you know
anyway it's a focus on make making money
of course like if you reveal anything on
their website
if you look at their reviews the best
fan ok let's click on that typically
they you know they have links to Amazon
so you so they make a lot money that's
how they make money but as I mentioned
you know usually this kind of website
when when you become I mean not I mean I
think this applies to any person anyone
maybe except me because it's hard to buy
me off but anyway so this websites you
know it's like we when you start a
website you know in a beginning you know
suppose you are expert you know making
keyboards then you realize if you do
this or that you can make more money in
any way then you know the website gets
larger that it tends to be bad so there
it is what why a wire cutter and Tom's
Hardware I don't think Tom's Hardware is
good anymore I haven't looked but you
know in the beginning like early 2000s
it's very good so so then says I've
never visited that one so then says I
used to go to Tom's Hardware forums
quite a lot a few years ago ok ok yeah
so maybe there forum is still good I
don't know so you know the times I knew
it was in around the early 2000s so Deon
says it's sad how commercialized and
brain-dead things are now yeah you see
that I think the reason that happens is
because beginning with Facebook and
other social media with a like button
you know which is basically a
psychological method to get you addicted
and then because they want traffic you
know the what you know Facebook Twitter
their concern is too
make money in order to make money the
more traffic the better it is so they
have you know psychologists and designed
a website down to the color of the
button or size of the button or position
everything is designed to maximize so
that you know they have test you know a
B test you know they have all all sort
of metrics you know so they they are
designed to maximize traffic you know
get more users on their website get more
users to you know postings and it turns
out you know the more trauma the more
dramatic the more angry things the more
emotional things gets more clicks so so
they maximize you know they don't care
they don't really care you know Facebook
and Twitter they don't really you know
it's not like they are evil you know I
you know they create they create a
situation where everything is clickbait
that's not their intention very
intention is just to make more money and
more traffic but however it turns out
you know the more drama that the more
dramatic you know fake news dramatic
stuff you know emotional stuff angry
accidents those kind of posts gets more
traffic you know more quick you know
because so so you know so so they just
do that you know they don't care they
want maximize their traffic so then you
have more and more fake news click page
so everything you know like today the
the you know most vast majority of
websites including now including all the
mainstream news media or like fake news
you know and they are about to collapse
you know like in recent months you know
there's a situation like they are
collect class collapsing but they are
trying to make more fake news to you
know try to save themselves like for
example on YouTube congratulations on
your 1000 subscriber wow oh I finally
made it
I made it to that let's see
1000 subscriber oh wow
today yay you know I was wondering you
know like that YouTube you have a you
know like make money like there's a
button where you click to to to be able
to make money so I was wondering if I
should you know it's like I'm not sure I
don't know about you know that you know
it's like there's a bag of money on the
street you know you you wonder you
whether you should pick it up you know
but that's not all though because for me
you know I sure I want money but but
there are a lot of things going on with
YouTube and now you know like I'm not
sure you know so so we were talking
about websites ok Tom's Hardware closed
it
let's go back to so what were we talking
about
oh yeah so Facebook Twitter you know so
they want more money and traffic so so
these days everything is you know fake
news yeah I was talking about YouTube
you know YouTube began you know as you
know YouTube is a company then Google
about it in early days like 2005 or
something they began as a website you
know they focus on individuals like not
corporations like me you who ever you
know want to make video so after 10
years you know there's tremendous you
know a lot of people has like a million
followers you know they they become very
rich you know usually millionaires you
if you have a million followers you are
mere mini millionaire so most of YouTube
traffic up by these people like you know
the noncom you know like it individual
mom-and-pops and usually most of them
are young people you know but now
they just in recent month they try to
turn it around so they no longer you
know because all the politics because
it's all related you know click page
then fake news because Twitter and
Google they want make you know traffic
money then censorship comes in then you
know it's amazing you know it's you know
what a circus so you know we are you
know in the AI artificial intelligence
age
the question is is is going to be good
or bad
you know imagining next ten years what's
going to be like you know like imagine
imagine censorship you know like on
Twitter if you say [ __ ] oh [ __ ] you know
they censor that like they put your post
like you have to like this is you know a
questionable post you have to click to
see it okay
that's incredible because you know you
used to because you know at least in USA
you see like in 1990s
it used to be conservatives they don't
want swearing words okay and like even
on dictionaries on dictionaries you look
up [ __ ] this no it's not there because
the conservative people the card
believers you know they they think no no
you you know you don't want you cannot
have that even even in a dictionary that
is this is true
now maybe today's people you don't know
about that but but back then in 1990s
you know many dictionaries you will not
find you know swearing words all or
lesbian or you know phone occasion you
know those kind of you know woods and
but the Liberals we you know you know
dubrow's doesn't mean the same thing
today but we libros we want you know we
don't we don't want that kind of thing
we don't want a censorship so we
actually fought for it you know like you
know so beginning in 1990s to year 2000
you know we start to there's even a book
you know like you go to the printers ink
downtown here you know Castro Street a
mountain view
any you know coffee shop
books bookstore there is actually a book
about [ __ ] you know the world over the
history of [ __ ] or whatever you know
like you know
so it actually published a book before
that you know let's say in the 1980s
that is impossible I mean it is
impossible to find a book that you know
talk about [ __ ] so so we made that
happen you know so we can say [ __ ] you
know you in especially like in year 2000
or 2001 there you know when the.com is
booming there are a lot of rather
questionable commercial commercials that
you know typically from the tech
companies you know dot-com days they
they are very much sexualized I mean I
mean even today it's like this detest
fall you know stuff doing that deal you
know because you have too many of that
that you know YouTube will ban you yeah
you know I'm not going to go into
details but you know there's so many
stories with YouTube if you follow the
news so you know the the you know
swearing becomes common actually so in
let's say 2010 it's like everywhere
every website you can have that but now
like since 2016 the social justice can
rose you know the like the liberal
doesn't mean that anymore it's something
else
you know it's like there's a 100 degree
turn so it's just you know it's quite
something so we were talking about I was
talking about
oh yeah YouTube I mean Facebook and
Twitter so yeah and and in turn though
many of the review websites in fact
today you cannot you cannot find much
good information today like if you I
mean on topics of programming or on
keyboards like let's say which which one
is the best
ergonomic keyboard you know let's say if
you just type you know best
ergonomic keyboard typically you'll find
like tons of these scam websites you
know like like life wire yeah that's one
of them life wire wire cutter there it
is you know the it is let's look at them
I have checked them out before you know
the Digital Trends duo these are
commercial websites like they they are
not quality information they are just
information for for you know the pop
they just want to make money you know so
you you know you look at them Kinesis
freestyle actually this one is very good
i they have updated their website so
Kinesis freestyle edge that's very good
Microsoft scoped that's very good
actually and the cheapest among them
okay ergo docks that's very good okay
they yeah they have updated their
website it wasn't like that
a few years ago so anyway so that's you
know wire cutter then but anyway so I
was saying you know before you used to
be like you know Eddie you know in
2000's there are a lot of nerds you know
like me oh you know you guys like if you
are expert on keyboard or you are expert
about some specific topic you know like
refrigerators you know you you write a
blog and you know that's tense
information that's good but today is
very hard you know it's extremely hard
to find those websites because they are
just buried by like 1,000 more web sites
they all they all want you to go to
their website because they might make
money you know so that's pretty bad
let's see Tomsk ID let's see Tom's guide
what they say
oh this is the now I don't know if this
is this is related to Tom's Hardware
maybe not maybe they are just writing
the name but this is the worst keyboard
you know this one organ are the logitech
wave what is this best economy keyboards
and these Tom sky dad is this site
related to the Tom's Hardware future Inc
probably not you know they are just
cashing cashing in so anyway close that
close that okay so let's read the
comments let's see like button Skinner
box button of social approval Skinner
box what does I mean I know there's a
famous psychologist whose name is
Skinner who created behavior behavior
reason is that what it means Skinner box
so then says yes indeed the like button
began a social evolution sort of of
sorts you know there is one thing that's
good done by Facebook now this is
history so many of you may not know I
mean my my viewers in general when when
they watch my video so Facebook there's
one thing that Facebook did that changed
the internet okay that is real names
with photo of yourself you know Facebook
began that that's that is really good
you know because before Facebook okay
it's almost like a sharpton before
Facebook every nerd every [ __ ]
programmers you know on the web their
idea of the web is that they want to be
anonymous you you know they they have
forums Slashdot you know but you go
there everyone say I like Batman or
some things Batman Robin you know the
it's like that and their picture is like
girls you know hot girls or cars or
whatever or bad men you know and if you
ask programmers you know you know the
programmers programmers my mindset is
that they think of Internet as you know
well kind of yeah they think of the
Internet is kind of like the dark place
you don't want you never want to show
your real names like nobody
well Internet is mostly begin by
programmers then then non-programmers
started to use internet so programmers
idea about the internet has a major
influence you know so in the early you
know in the 2000s you know the tip on
the web you know you'll not find any
almost not any real names but Facebook
change that because part part of the
reason Facebook can do that because you
know the arrangement of Facebook is you
know College yearbook you know you know
cottage yearbook which is you know with
faces that's why it's named Facebook by
the way Facebook the the the the the
arrangement of Facebook is actually just
pretty girls like you know like college
girls you know pretty girls with versus
versus another girl something like which
one is hotter
that's a Mark Zuckerberg scumbag is the
scumbag in in in the one of the worst
scumbag in humanity he's he's not not
just beginning same today and and also
it's funny the way he looks is like you
know mr. data
is his has he has this appearance i I
don't know if that's a coincidence or it
turned out and you know somehow his
behavior or you know made him looks like
that I mean this is kind of
pseudoscience but anyway if it's not
totally untrue though I mean usually you
can Church your person by their
appearance you know
in many ways they are related this is
not pseudoscience okay you can't judge a
person I mean Americans they don't like
to talk about these because they think
oh that's that's you know that's that
stereotype oh oh you cannot judge people
on their skiing or you know American
stuff you know idiotic in that regard
but anyway when you look at person this
there's like thousands of information
you can read off age for example age sex
you know his experiences where he came
from you know that that's an English
idiom where he came from and that's
solid you know it has real-life weeks
you know bases because you know once
once you know where a person come from I
mean typically that means you know what
you know what's your background what's
your thoughts you know what's your you
know perspective on things and what what
does it have to do with like where you
came from because that's actually true
because different people from different
countries or different regions they will
have different perspective different
biases different point of view from you
you know so that's why people you know
there's this idiom where you came from
you know let me know where you you know
so you know I want to find out where
this guy came from so anyways so and so
you know the human experiences you know
lots of them are embedded in the
language so where you came from that's
you know also so anyway I was saying you
know you can look at the person you get
a lot information and for some strange
reason this mark suzuka but he's a scum
okay doesn't matter how he looks he's
like the great you know one of the great
scumbag of humanity oh yeah so I was
saying face but they but Facebook
revolutionized
the web for we are weak you know that's
reasonable to say because because before
Facebook everyone everything is
anonymous
after Facebook you know internet becomes
real in a sense like you know normal
people can go to internet you have you
know you can make contact with your
family or whatever but programmers to
these days still have these sense
especially my followers you know my the
the the community I mean they still have
the sense like they don't want to they
don't want to go online with your names
especially like you can see it on reddit
you know what is redder than YouTube but
I think that's also changing it has to
because for example on YouTube you know
there's a lot people are you know
actually show your face you know like
including myself anyway so yeah Facebook
had that change but but Facebook also
has you know of course lots of negative
you know he did very bad things so
anyway so like button
he also ironic it's also ironic to me
how social media is often designed
pretty explicitly to prevent the
formation of autonomous social clusters
what do you mean yeah I don't know what
do you mean so type it and let's see
hundred subscribers hundred 1000
subscribers is a joke man because you
look at you know YouTube
there are thousand things and thousands
of them have millions of followers or at
least tens of thousands followers you
know I'm not doing I'm just you know
1000 subscribers like it's a joke really
because I think almost anyone okay you
can do it yeah like anyone if you post
out the video a day after year you have
like tens of thousands viewers I think
you know I'm not getting much viewers
because that's because you know I kind
of I kind of know why I
first you know because there are reasons
because I'm you know first of all I
don't schedule it you know nobody know
where I'm on I don't focus on a topic
like you know if I focus on Emacs you
know every day ten minutes you know not
life but Timmy it's focusing on
particular things
I'll get I'm pretty sure I'll get then a
lot followers and don't swear you know
don't don't [ __ ] this [ __ ] that you
don't do that you know just focus on
teaching you know Emacs or keyboards you
know I can have a channel dedicated to
keyboards you know today I'm going to
show you something about keyboard you
know that is a way to go if you if
making money or popularity is your
concern but you know I'm doing kind of
you know you know this random ish so
that's part of the reason I I think
you know and another thing is that you
know often also I talk about math like
if you talk about math that's severely
limited limits your audience like like
one in a thousand one one in a medium
you know you see if you look at many of
the YouTube stars
who's got the median followers you know
you look at their content that's like
they have no content they are like most
of them you know or almost all of those
with one more than a million followers
you look at their content for the girls
usually it's makeup okay makeup and
drama you know who you know drama about
gossip about celebrities you know they
are bikini or whatever you know who who
is their boyfriends you know how do you
know things like that in makeup you know
that's the girls thing you know they
have millions follows and clothing and
you know bikini basically show show of
your body you show your tits and ass how
I like how to show your tits and ass
that's that's what that's a girls girls
thing and and drama you know basically
bitching you know the girls they the
women they they they they fight it with
each other you know that's one of the
things you know anyway they like like
you notice the strange you know the
words like [ __ ] [ __ ] you know and that
you know there's a new word thought you
know you like you look at like the word
[ __ ] and study like I observed you know
it's you know it's almost used by women
you know again each other you know it's
like that you know I remember Britney
Spears like you go to Britney Spears
Twitter or it was sungkoo office you
know the the the the profile photo you
know big splash splash photo is like
it's like your [ __ ] you know you
[ __ ] suck the girls they ever think
like like this is obsession with that
with that you
were like [ __ ] so it can be you know or
internally you know supposedly it's it's
a bad word but then you know it's it's
like dank becomes good then it's bad you
know it's like it's just a drama what
they always use so that's a girls you
know girls do that the guys you look at
YouTube with you know those popular
YouTube stars they are they have no
content they are either video games I
mean video games not even like solid
review or something
typically it's just like you know you
know pretty face or whatever they they
can talk you know they like like stupid
no no content nothing is and also drama
for example there's this h h three guy
okay I'm going to let me treat comments
in case I'm like straying or far but let
me finish it about the h3 guy h3 okay
let's see h3 productions you know this
h3 guy HT guy this guy Ethan I I started
to know him about two years ago because
because another guy fat Francis was
interviewed by him and a fat Francis was
talking about this feminist frequency
[ __ ] there's a scumbag okay called you
know with a with a show called feminist
frequency a scumbag of humanity so the
fat Francis guy you know I'm not going
to go into the details because on
YouTube there's you know huge number of
stories like a bag of history you you
have to spend you know a year to
understand what's going on all these
people but anyway fair Francis I kind of
know so he's view I respect so I saw him
on the h3h3 interview by him I don't
know who the [ __ ] is this h3 guy this is
about two years ago then gradually you
know I
learned you know I watch it more his
videos and so it turns out he's you know
he's okay guy you know he's you know I
would say okay guy and he talked about
that's the thing you know so what he
talk about everyday you know he's a very
popular he's got millions I don't I
don't know how many millions few million
followers they he talked about you know
it's like it just drama look at this so
that that's this is what he's doing now
oh his channels you know this bear death
and this girl like like you know no
content I mean is like drama and crap
gossip gossip drama and you know like
what the [ __ ] these people's I was doing
you know today and and he's okay but
anyway the athan guy I
we got him as okay guy okay but there
there are a lot was you know with medium
followers this this this I know I
noticed this this guy Joey salad he
specializes in pranks you know very
questionable pranks like kissing his
mouth or Oh or fake raped eight or
things like that you know just like this
[ __ ] people this millennial generation
this young people these scammers they
know nothing then they just [ __ ] [ __ ]
around and then there is also Chris with
Reagan I know the kid named Chris Reagan
because he he's a boy friend of the girl
you another YouTube star doing what's
her name
any remembered I need to catch up with
the comments but anyway so you can just
finish this so Chris Reagan so I watched
you know so it so anyway
so in general I watched you know I
checked out especially in the past few
months
now what's you know this YouTube stars
on YouTube with like what are they doing
what they do you know this rank you know
the most popular
you know it turns out lots of them are
just gossip like girls like women's
magazine magazine this is a [ __ ] you
know that today we have the millennial
generation they are all like that the
gameís you don't care about like they
you know the way they talk they talk is
like the gameís land or every day means
memes and [ __ ] cockin whatever [ __ ]
this [ __ ] fast come back you know it
turns out I mean even though some of
them are good person like the Athan but
he's but his stuff is like talking about
memes and you know what you know like
you know not something you would mike
Oxmoor can you shout me out
so are you are you a youtube or
something so okay let me catch up with
the comments okay so so for example
YouTube a friend feature okay so where
it was it you see
Oh Mike Oxmoor you were my my 1000
subscriber thank you and congratulations
to you too hey you should get an award
or something 1000 subscriber yeah did
you know on YouTube and you know they
have that gifts you know like you know
that's one of the technique to grow your
audience like on YouTube you know
YouTube Google itself wants YouTube to
be popular so they do all kind of like
all things necessary like oh by all
means necessary to increase you know
YouTube usage and one of them you can
see is for for you know creators like me
so they have all these like every day
they they plastered to your face like
ideas for you how do we increase your
audience three quick creator tips the
[ __ ]
you know usually with this pretty face
you know what I do that it so they they
want to like help me they want to help
me to make money so as if I'm a normal
person I wouldn't you know I would enjoy
it that so you know I so they teach you
all kind of techniques so I can amass I
can get more popular you know that's
that's you know so anyway one of the one
of the technique I know because I I
write websites for 20 years so I know
about the SEO community and things you
know what they say so one of the
technique is the like gift like if you
go to Amazon you have account like like
for example suppose I have night 900
followers on YouTube then I say the
whoever is the 1000 follower you you
know you get a gift you know a keyboard
you know I'm reviewing key buy a free
keyboard so so that way actually you get
a lot followers and you know many of
these people who are doing that they and
you know they are all doing that you
know it's not room by itself you know
but but on the whole you when you
society like everyone is like that it
just it's it's not good okay so how do I
be talking about I mean like I've been
like ranting and going on random stuff
for 40 minutes okay so let's see um so I
used to go to okay it's also having such
a media so so for example Deon says for
example YouTube's friend features and
messaging which were gotten before the
G+ integration yeah got it
before the G+ integration yeah because
the Google a few years ago about five
years ago six years ago they began
Google+ the the mindset back then was
that if you don't hop onto the social
media thing your company is going to
fail so they really try to push Google+
I would say that's the date you know if
we you know if a historian you know
designate a date where Google began to
go Evo I would say it's it's around that
when Google began Google+ and of course
they failed and they closed the shutter
down few this year Google+ you know like
I have details you know I have quite a
few articles and you know that's a one
huge giant chapter of the internet
history you know you see you know you
can look back and you can see how the
evil things I try to do they did they
pay their an employee like if if Google+
succeeded then you know you get extra
pay you know that's that's one of the
thing they try to do to increase Google+
and so in the first year it's you know
lots of lots of stories you know and
today you can
you know and another thing one of the
things that today you try to find these
stories it's very hard to find because
massive censorship massive algorithmic
control so they are like you know in a
sense they are wiping out history
intentionally they don't want you to
know Google it becomes that bad you know
then it's like you know for example some
you know what I'm saying is that for
example if you are young people you know
so you heard about Google+ and you know
it's part of history you know you could
go try to try to do that so you you are
thinking maybe I want to get get an
overview what's going on and you can't
well actually you can you know there's
Wikipedia which I I think still cover
much of it but there's lots of details
and new ones and all the dramatic
dramatic stories like like like back
then every day there's a you know
article clickbait article that discussed
you know google's new strategy or some
insight inside stories something
happened you know every day like for
several years for many years and you
know it's many of them are just gone you
know the the web page get deleted
because those are just click page so
when was the you know event is passed
they they wiped their you know articles
yeah so in many ways it's very bad
anyway so let's get back to the comments
Isaac
good morning Isaac Isaac Isaac you are
in you are in South South California
right
okay so Deon says like that can you face
say my name Mike Mike Oxmoor Mike Oxmoor
Mike are small it's like Beetlejuice
Beetlejuice beetlejuice Highbury oh hi
boyo Oh
I got lots of people cool
so Dion say is we need to figure out how
to create a distributed services
platform that can funnel money to
individual contributors of content
server space act you know Amanda you
need hacker types you know among my
community a lot of people think of that
but I'm not sure that's the way to go
because you know because the Nerds been
thinking of that for the past 30 years
and are we getting better
no he's getting far worse you know the
phone the cloud you know you know we
know it's been saying that you know
every time you know like master done you
know remember master done remember you
know lots of things you know did we want
distributed we want open source we want
encryption you know every time some new
software or service comes up every nerd
is like oh you know trying to push it
out you know trying to you know spread
it that's a failure you know you look at
today after 30 years it's the society is
far more worse that's not you know why
what you watch the white white why the
open source
you know the nerd idea doesn't succeed
because in my opinion they are simply
like they are like ideology they are
fantasies like close your eyes I think
oh oh if I just you know tell you know
people about mastered and distributed
Federation you know cryptograph think
you know crypt analysis you know
encrypted people we all you know use it
and if I just attack Google every day I
if I just you know say [ __ ] Microsoft
you know every day then society will
become better that's what these nerds
are thinking okay you know the in
general that's my opinion and if I just
seen the old songs of the open source
then you know the Society will be better
know so I'm against open source I was a
big fan I was a fanatic of free software
foundation
datian they'll get back then you know
back in mm i talked about this topic
many times in my video so so but so so
instead of you know so so i so so what
what should we do you know we should you
know you know you want to look at
reality you want to focus on you you
know forget about ideology okay that's
not going to work you know that's empty
ideology then there's communism then
there is the social justice can they are
they are doing their ideology okay the
communism is it well you know what you
know doing it the ideology and you want
to look at you know try to be science
science-based
look at fact look at study look at what
have happened in the past what so what
happens if you you know open source or
systems you know this are not propaganda
you know you go to the any of the geek
websites you know open source dislike
that you know they every day is
especially today for example Twitter
Facebook you have bubbles you know while
you have bubbles on Facebook and Twitter
because when you only see what you like
you know then you like the server's
better
that means more traffic for twitter
twitter makes more money more ad money
twitter is happier same thing with
Facebook so so they create a system
where people only see you know you just
see your things and on so Twitter
becomes you know more reach in facebook
but the society gets worse and worse
because because when you have this
purpose you don't see reality each you
know you live in your bubble you know
for you maybe it's open source bubble
for the Conservatives you know the
social justice can they have the neopor
boast then you becomes angry because
once in a while you see other you know
other people's idea you see what what
you know this is this is naazy you know
this yeah so that's what happens
and you know so so you have bubbles in
the same in the same way the if you are
for open source if you are the nerd type
you know you are seeing all the good
things about open source every day you
know like for example I say I say open
source is good no good okay because I
give some reasons but tomorrow you will
see 10 articles about oh how casali is
wrong because and that's only that's
that's all you see and you in your mind
you are sure you know that's you know
you don't see other things you don't see
failures of open source you don't see
you know for example my story nobody you
know I I rent again it's open source
many times you know in my website on
YouTube everywhere nobody will like it
you know because because I mean my
communities this programmers open-source
programmers they don't click like you
know they they don't spread it so that
means you know the ideas like my
opinions like that you don't never get
you know anywhere on the meet meanwhile
on reddit on YouTube on any any you know
on Twitter anywhere you know this any
anyone posts a story about oh how how I
got donation from open-source you know
thank you so much Oh everyone you know
spread it down how can use [ __ ] you know
the drag like it's big news everywhere
open-source oh yeah oh yeah
open-source you know that that's what
happens you don't see you don't see the
reality so that's another okay that's
another again it's open source so about
you know master then about the the
distributed you know services I love
that you know actually I really that's
what I like but my point is that you
have to be realistic you have to not not
just be realistic what I'm saying is
that you have to like stop you know stop
your Bubo stop looking at you know the
oh those open source
you know phonetics you know news you
know all the web website hacker news you
know how can you see strange you know on
one hand every day is like they are seen
is open source a lot of it but at night
everyone is thinking how do you how to
squeeze money because you know the hecka
news is the you know is for startups
they their goal is to make money so my
hand oh this is everything we want
open-source but on the other hand they
you know what's the technique you know
as a start-up how can you maximize money
and you know and you know like you know
like going to the cloud or how to deal
with customers you know things like that
you know if you really if you really
think about the question how to make
money with open-source
the answer is plain and simple
you know it's patently obvious you know
by by what means however means you check
you will never make a cent with you know
with open-source product you as a
company okay
what you can do while you what you can
do is you go to crowd you know you go to
crowd or you say our hardware actually
hardware you know you know but you know
we anyway so that's about that so are
there silenced mechanical keyboards no
not really
there are a lot of people I'm trying to
make you know that's a big thing that's
speaking everyone want to have but it
seems to me from what I you know
gathered from what from what I've read
it seeks it's extremely difficult to
make a site silent and mechanical
keyboard now by the way mechanical
keyboard means the mechanical switch and
you know there is a lot of there's no
precise definition what makes a keyboard
switch mechanical but however when we
use the word mechanical keyboard we
usually means the the mechanism for the
tactile sensation we so we when we say
mechanical keyboard which usually means
the tactic the tactile sensation is
good you know it's a good it's a switch
with a good tactile sensation by the way
I explained in a design here you can go
key switch so this article is experience
or the key switch mechanisms and there
is a video by this key switch expert at
the bottom if you go to my website you
will see the video because I don't have
it here because I have JavaScript off so
anyway you go to so this this expert
Chris around 22 so he talked about what
is a keyboard mechanical Wayne's a
keyboard mechanical so there's no real
definition
Yammy it's basically impossible to have
a definition of what means mechanical
but but you know generally we just mean
you know keyboard with a good quality
design switch okay that gives you
tactile good tactile sensation so that's
what it means
so what about silent ones yeah so many
people try to have to make that but for
example the happy hacking keyboard which
is one of the most popular keyboard and
they have a silent version happy hacking
but in general but but but they still
they still pretty loud okay they have
the happy hacking Model S okay yes sign
for silent and also they are several
okay okay if you go to the design page
you go to the key switch page and
actually I talked about it there is a
dedicated article okay mechanical
keyboard noises comparison okay there's
a video you know you can see that people
have done comparisons of if you go to
here let's see comparisons of the noise
of mechanical keyboards
you will see that they are all very loud
and you know some of them is better than
you others but in general the hello-o
pretty bad including those you know
supposedly silent once if you really
want silent you go to robot don't okay
you know so this is so this article and
video you can check out okay okay so BF
Skinner yeah BF Skinner invented the
behavior reason yes so do young so that
was from DeYoung and Boyle annoyed is
that but not but not the old I think
that's a French name so anyway Boyer
says it's possible to find a okay
mechanical keyboard under $60 oh yes
there's a lot all of them actually you
go to my keyboard block the keyboard
section and for example this one
waterproof waterproof mixing they are
like fifty dollars okay cheap so if you
know you know so usually the worry is
that you know many people worry about oh
these are made from China they think
they're gonna break you know after one
month that's not true
you know you look at Emma's I have a
blue house ins of reviews you know so if
you want to get a cheap mechanical
keyboard this is one of the choice they
are quite a lot you know usually and
this happens to be waterproof too so
it's actually very good or alternatively
you might go for this optical switch now
this is fantastic
okay this is optical switch for some
reason it it wasn't very popular I don't
know why but from you know because I
look at all the keyboard forums what
what this keyboard phonetic say they
don't seem it doesn't seems to be very
popular I mean you know like I would
think
this would mean this began about three
years ago so I would think you know it's
optical switch you know so they use a
infrared or optical so the advantage is
that you no longer have dust you know
it's more dust proof more waterproof and
also there's more no electrical contact
so it's more it's a last longer
so there's many advantages take a deist
technical theoretical advantages and so
far I haven't seen you know much
negative reviews
so it's you know should be pretty good
and it's not expensive either it's like
III forgot like seventy dollars fifty
dollars 72 dollars okay but foot so I I
thought that this is gonna be like a
thing you know if it becomes very
popular it turns out not I don't know
why but so anyway so you can you can get
this one you know cheap yeah they are
pretty cheap you know in China you know
China is tremendous like if you buy so
these are from China
these oh these are from China but if you
actually buy in China it's like five
times cheaper yeah like everything and
you know five times cheaper it's amazing
that in China so if you go to China you
could you know pick up some of these you
know the cheap electronics so okay so
[Music]
yeah look let's look at you know
pictures Mark Zuckerberg I guess you
guys haven't seen the pictures of him
you know he is very bad person so this
photo is from wired okay so the end this
photo is from Time magazine okay so that
meaning that you can trust the photo is
not you know photoshopped you know so so
for some reason he looks like you know
these creepy you know it creepy guy you
know so okay I think I'm about to end
the stream yeah one hour that wow it's a
good time so if you have questions
comments posted okay I'm gonna talk
about that for me another ten minutes
let's see I'm still going okay yes so
not only does he look like data he
behaves very robotically oh I didn't
know you know he's one of the richest
guy today you know like being rich
obedient you know he's like multi
billionaire you know being that which is
funny thing you know I like you have to
think about what it is like you know you
know so he you know he owned Islands
kind of like in Hawaii or something you
know he he could if he wants he can buy
a entire country you know like and you
know well
so so JB does it so Boyer says I have
done 1000s one JB does Oh does it says I
kinda want to make another account and
subscribe so I can be subscribed 1000 V
subscribe and also so Dan says tens ace
math plus Emacs
who on earth could not be interested so
Barrios says SAP and to talk about
Mathematica Wolfram language your
experience work working their tutorials
so talking about Mathematica Wolfram
language I talked about that two days
ago three days ago I did a one one hour
talk act yeah so you should check it out
so go to my channel two days ago two or
three days ago actually in two days I
did two videos least syntax and the
meaning of symbolic language you know
like Lisbon Mathematica so that's two
hours was talking about Mathematica now
I haven't coded Mathematica for 10 years
and I don't have it on my machine so I
cannot actually really do any teaching
or Mathematica you know Oh demo and as
far as working at Wolfram there was long
ago 1995 you know I worked there for
half a year
I mentioned it I talked a little bit
about it but anyway this you know I I
don't think there's much really to talk
about because part of it it's long ago
you know it's like it's like 30 years
ago 25 years ago but but I didn't wrote
an article that's interesting which is
okay sorry master
language in ten years something like
that
okay no sorry Peter Novick okay
okay let me find the article okay so
that's because that's the interesting
article actually I I talked about it in
one of my video a while back but I don't
member win so so let's just search for
go to my computer programming blog
search for Novick I will find the
article
oh okay so let's go to : this is Golan
and this this is Novick okay such that
string in all of my websites so what's
his name Novick
you know the he's a popular very famous
common base programmer and one of the
early research in artificial
intelligence was he Peter Novick or
something Novick you know he wrote
common list
book
[Music]
ain't oh okay and oh that's right okay
so that's why okay so hold on a second
so that's such savvy and Novik
okay there it is okay I have from saw
find out put mods so let's see English
speaker
Peter Novick English Pegram Warrick
versus komak okay oh there it is this
one yeah so I actually talked about it
in April 30th saw talk show function
function function parameter idiocy
Packers no form Lisp vs. Mathematica
Peter Novick Nassim Taleb NASA NASA me
Talib is a scumbag it's a you know
anyway so big you know because in you
know in the past few days there's
something going on on Twitter he turned
up again so anyway there is an article
Peter Novick so you can you can watch
this video if you like but okay here is
New York oh the condition of industrial
programmers learn Lisp in ten days now I
wrote this article as a reaction of
reading one of Peter Novak's very
popular essay called teach yourself
programming in ten years this article is
very popular extremely popular it's one
of the party article on Hacker News or
Slashdot you know and it's very bad
article so anyway so in this article I
discuss something about my my my initial
experience it wolf I'm research anyway
you can read about it so that's you know
so let's see um yeah so I'm not I don't
think I have much to say about actual
teaching about Mathematica but do check
out to check out the video two days ago
that is pretty good I think yeah so can
you imagine Athens from HP talking about
oak Maude you know as they yeah so the
main culture annoys me so I think about
my name is a so Mike Oxmoor open-source
has become a tool for wealth
centralization yeah thanks for the tips
and yes French okay so that's it for
today I think so what anything else you
have ten seconds to type it yeah so
today I was going to go over my blogs
talking about some Perl stuff you know
there's more than one way to do it and
but yeah so it's over an hour and yeah
so that's good random chatting
bye guys