good morning everyone
good morning everyone good morning
everyone welcome to another episode of
talk show
today is 2021 march
11th noon san francisco time
excuse me and today we are going to talk
about
mathematica we are going to i'm going to
do a demo a live
demo of mathematica and you can see
start was
a new documentation so
so let's begin okay so if you have
questions just ask it okay
the background image is a mathematical
logo and
let's go to documents okay
and the documents we're gonna go to
we're gonna open um okay open this one
uh open it so
so here is mathematica i finally
downloaded
it uh and uh
well let's let's start to do demo okay
hi guys
uh z trunk crazy hi is this one crazy so
uh so let's see
check check audio check video check
okay uh what we're gonna do okay so
we going to run mathematica okay let's
see a new window okay
and what am i going to demonstrate i'm
going to demonstrate
uh the fantastic uh things about
mathematica
let's say pi okay uh pi
now you need to let's magnify the window
uh let's say 150 okay that's let's say
200 okay
so there is pi and let's compute
pi to 1000 places let's say 100 phases
okay there it is so
now let's see let's see if i still
remember the key bindings
i haven't actually coded mathematica for
like uh
for 15 years so now pi to 10 000 places
uh ctrl enter there we have it
okay uh instantaneous
so that is mathematica so that's uh you
know uh
and you know any so you see the n
that means uh the end function means
gives
the numerical result okay so let's see
how can i
uh
okay there there
so here's the documentation for n let's
magnify
to 200. so
any expression uh you just give it the
function
n and you can say how many decimal
places you want
any any computation and you
return uh guaranteed that many places in
decimal
so let's see let's see fee okay
fear fee is another um
constant okay uh no
golden ratio okay so it's called golden
ratio
okay so golden ratio you want to apply
n to it uh you know just wrap in
let's say 100 faces there you have it
uh any compute any computation let's say
golden ratio
let's say let's say pi raised to the
golden ratio okay
pi raised to the gold ratio try that
in python there you you have it 100
places
now i'm going to show you know i'm just
going to do random demonstrations so
uh you ask me questions i answer okay
comparison to other languages
or you know in last video you know make
sure you
uh also check out my talk show
about few days ago let's say this one
okay
where okay i talk about characteristics
of python
lisp languages and mathematica and also
i talked about stefan wufang the person
you know he's
uh his personality and what he have done
so if you have not seen it you might
check out that one
that one is not technical but i give you
an overview of
uh different languages and the kind of
the characteristics of mathematica but
without
learning mathematica today i'm actually
running mathematica so
i'm going to do a lot of demos so first
of all that's a numerical computation
uh okay and uh and any computation in
mathematica is symbolic okay so
let's do fraction okay uh
3 over 4 plus let's say 7 over
some number let's say multiplied
let's say plus
okay divided by 77
okay so enter so that gives you
a fraction by default and if you want
a numerical result just like before you
put
uh n to it okay slash slash
slash n is a special syntax that's a
post fixed
notation uh i have article on that i'm
not going to show it but
but you can you know just say the normal
way
with the bracket so there you have it so
okay that's a numerical computation n
factorial oh let's do a factorial okay
that would be fun
uh first of all let's do factorial
factorial in javascript okay
let's let's you know
i know i in many languages when you do
factorio
uh oops pretty soon you run out of
uh let's say javascript okay
save this as xx.javascript and
console.log and magnify the window
and let's say factorial now javascript
doesn't have
factorial notation let's run it okay
error
expected you know in syntax error so in
order to do factorial you have to
write a yeah you have to write a
function okay yeah okay
uh arrow function x uh so x
so uh
array i haven't been coding javascript
for a while already reduced
so let's say write
a function to do factorial okay
uh arrow constant error function okay
let's do that
so here will be array
reduce i think
okay alright reduce i don't have the
okay let's go to javascript
exciting javascript tutorial
just search for it javascript object
reference
okay then we want array
and we want reduce i haven't coded uh
oh yeah i know what it i know what what
um
array prototype reduce
there it is so array dot reduce okay so
you need to write
we need to write here
uh this should be a number okay
so yeah okay so javascript actually it
takes
it's quite painful to write a
factorial function uh because you have
to generate a
array first uh okay so let's generate
array okay javascript in depth array
basics
go to
go to array basics
so go to array
create array so array function range
function so let's
you know javascript doesn't have
and let's just copy my code
okay so here's the range function
and then
then we want to write a factorial
okay factorial function and first of all
let's say and
constant
array range x
okay that returns a array of
x element then you want to reduce
yeah you want to reduce that
by uh
okay it was math you know so you you
need to write a
factor in in javascript and it's a
little bit involved even
just a simple thing as factory actually
is uh
let's double check okay is there a
building factorial
unless i made a fool of myself i don't
think so
so math functions we don't have
factorial okay so you have to write it
because factorial is that is actually
not a function that
um that is uh
that much used so am i doing okay so
comments questions
hiker where would you like to travel in
a world have you done some road mapping
road tripping or do you plan something
no uh
i have barely traveled okay i'll talk
about that another day
focus on mathematica this episode
yeah we want to do mathematica so
so we are writing a function in
javascript a factorial function so how
do you do it so
array reduce uh array reduce takes a
function what is the syntax of
a reduced i haven't coded
javascript for a month or two
for several months for three months so
uh reduce yeah so reduce uh object
reference
array then you want to go to prototype
then you want to go to reduce okay
okay a function and then you need value
okay so a function
this function takes to the function
takes
two um yeah
god this is getting complex a
and b okay so here's a function that
takes two
arguments uh and
the result will be a times b okay let's
let's just
i mean suppose this works i don't know
if that works
but let's see factorio three okay that's
uh to begin with let's do it
ah syntax zero invalid array length what
the
okay let's just make sure that xr range
works
okay console log
xr range let's say three okay
comment this out comment this out
granite
what oh yeah okay so it takes two
arguments that's right so uh
star range takes two arguments so 1 2
10. run it
there is a result so star range is
correct
now let's go back to work on the
factorial so
uh 1 2x okay so comment out
and try the factorio again run it
undefined undefined my ass
okay so what is going on so uh
reduce okay so you need to return oh
yeah
my god javascript i forgot okay so but
we can
simplify compact this thing
by just putting that we don't need the
constant okay
so and uh so we just this line
we don't need that so that work okay
run it factorial three is six
now let's check double check mathematica
three factorial six okay
correct now let's say factorial
let's say nine okay three six two eight
zero
now go back to javascript factorio 9
there it is now let's just try
javascript let's see
uh factorio 20 okay
wait run oh still works factorial 30
run okay it's getting uh big results
okay let's try mathematica factorial 30
okay
uh
okay not too big a number uh
you know javascript is pretty uh soon
run out of
steam let's see javascript factorial
100.
oh it's still pretty fast yeah but you
know you lost precision you don't have
the
other digits anymore so factorial
mathematica 100 okay let's
do that
there you have it the number is not too
big but javascript is already
uh done for so and this
this applies to python whatever language
you see you know try it
see python java javascript uh you know
uh golan all the same they you know they
cannot do
uh infinite precision numbers in
mathematica everything
is building you see the one of the major
philosophical difference of mathematica
and all the other languages is that
mathematica is um oriented to
you know it you can also you can almost
think of it
as a ai language you know artificial
intelligence language you know
like in most programming languages
uh you know it's built upon you know
uh how you control the bits you know you
have to control everything
you know the bits especially
non-functional programming languages you
have to tell it exactly
where you want place a bit you know uh
how do you control
you know things like that float whether
the bits you know the bytes is a float
or into a long you don't have to control
all that
in functional programming languages you
don't
worry about much of that you know you
most worry about
what's the input what's the output let
the programming language do it for you
you know you don't worry about the you
know the
the the detailed steps how do you arrive
at
the answer for example one of the common
functional programming
function is sum for example some
let's say x square okay one over x
okay now one over x you want to submit
let's say from uh one uh x from one to
ten okay run it so that's the answer
now if you want the
but by the way you can make this um
you can make these two format in the
rendered in mathematical notation okay
now i haven't
used mathematica for 15 years so i don't
remember the
key strokes okay shift ctrl n
let's see shift shift ctrl n
yeah so you can you you you see
now i'm going to type uh i'm going to
talk about type
type setting later on okay and i'm going
to flame the
out of the latex and take crap you see
this is mathematica so
you can see so let's do it again okay
uh ctrl shift i
for input form so this is how you type
and you can press a button
and it becomes you know this form and in
fact you don't have to press the button
you have to
yeah you press a key stroke so anyway so
this is sum okay let's
let's do a and you if you want numerical
uh solution
you know numerical answer you just do
that or if you let's try another sum
okay this one
this time it's easier one two three
let's say
you know n n plus
two uh one plus two one plus three
you know uh so that's uh so so what i'm
talking about so uh we got 16 people say
hi ask your questions okay
alex says i believe there should be a
package for it
yeah that's right uh you forgot to put
return
oh yeah in javascript is it possible to
run mathematica in production yes of
course
you know mathematica the mathematica i
know
you know mathematica has this giant um
well i i digress so much okay
i digress so much let me just finish
this okay because i we
i got lots of things i want to uh show
you okay mathematica the 3d graphics
uh type setting in mathematica uh
you know i'm going and and interactive
graphics for example
when you are plotting a polynomial for
example if you are plotting this thing
sometimes you want to change the
parameter and you want to see it
in real time so you know like there's a
slider you can trick the slider
so normally if you write this in you
know you you cannot even write this in
other applications in scheme
in python in haskell then you have to
load a gui library
you know or in java you have to load you
know what's the name
you know the java crap you know you have
to write you you have to write the
application you know you have to load
the widget for you know controlling the
slider and all that
in mathematica it's one single line okay
so anyway i have a lot to demo so let's
just continue with this
uh factorial right now
so yeah so i was uh talking about
infinite
precision uh you know building so yeah
so i was talking about mathematica
you can think of the language as you
know uh as a ai
kind of language you know in other
another way to think of mathematica is
think of it
as a api now api you guys are familiar
with today
especially today or especially
javascript uh
coders you know young coders you know
you don't worry about
how it's implemented you you rather you
when you look at some api
you just you just see at least the
functions you call this function
you give certain parameters and that's
that's what you get
so you think of the you know in java
in you know in lots of javascript python
golan you know
you have lots of libraries and they are
they present
themselves as api so you only
you know think of list of functions and
what they return what they do
in mathematica and similarly in many
math oriented languages such as
matlab or julia
you also you think of the entire
language as api
you know for example when you call some
you don't want you oh how it's
implemented is it a array or is it the
linked list underneath or how is it
efficient you know
you know you never worry about that
thing you just worry about all you think
about as a programmer
i want to do something okay and oh
there's this function that does that you
just call that function that and the
return
value is what you are concerned you
don't concern about
oh memory management garbage collection
int
float you know that that's a c
unix type people they love that kind of
thing in float
and rust memory you know especially just
they you want concern about memory so
it's all automatically
managed for you so some
so but by the way this is a famous um
so and also when we do some for example
i can do
infinity okay uh actually let's
let's change this to input form okay so
let's say instead of 1 to 10 let's say
infinity
so here you are uh computing an infinite
series
so it's telling you some does not
convene uh converge
okay uh you know try this in python you
know or haskell
you know they they come out crap
so some infinity let's try a series that
converges
now this is a famous harmonic series
so there you go one over x squared you
know
add you know to infinity uh you get pi
over squared
six this is uh i think we
found is the first one found the value
anyway anyway the name of that is
harmonic series i think
you know i haven't been doing math for
uh for a long time
no not this
harmonic sequence harmonic um yeah i
forgot
and there is a harmonic sequence okay
i want wikipedia i don't want none of
the other crap
okay also math words by the way
uh wait what is this methods.com
okay let's move on so actually i want to
yeah i forgot my mathematics this is um
you know this is the basic calculus
gamma function no this is not the one
i'm looking for
anyway this one you know the one i'm
looking for is
got very interesting properties and uh
um i i i want to find it
i'm certain i'm pretty certain it's
called harmonic series
okay
integrals yeah in fact infinite series
okay let's see infinite series in
mathematics
infinite series is this or that and that
partial sum divergent convergent
um
power series and trigonometry okay
calculus you know this
is uh calculus 101 i forgot
most of it
geometric series hyper hyper geometric
series arithmetic series where the
is that
yeah okay let's do let's do this okay
i need to get over these
pi so the result is pi
squared over six okay let's see maybe i
can find that
yeah okay so it's called harmonic series
you know but
in wikipedia you have to say math okay
so that is the uh
you know so this is one of the
very interesting oh wait uh
okay that's not this one but anyway so
so anyway so let's go back to
mathematica so you can compute that and
what else
let's see i think declarative would be
more suited
than um api yeah you get well yeah so
you can think of mathematica the
language or math oriented language as
declarative language
yeah you could think think of that
the whole point of functional
programming is that it is declarative
well not necessarily so well you know so
let me answer that question so actually
you know there are um
you know actually the whole point about
functional programming well
you you could say it's declarative but
they are actually distinct okay
so because you know functional
programming they
is declarative but they focus on
functions functions without side effect
that's the main thing that's the
that's a gist of functional programming
functions without side effect
why why you want to do that that is
because then
the programming language becomes uh
becomes a
you know mathematics essentially you
know you can
use math theories manipulate functions
but however i mean even in haskell the
most pure functional language
you don't you know so so that collective
programming is actually more powerful
it's a more powerful form of functional
programming
so for example uh haskell is the
function of programming pure functional
programming
you could say it's also decorative but
on the other hand
logic programming languages for example
logic programming languages
oh my my neighbor upstairs is
um anyway so logic programming language
prolog okay prolog is one of the
earliest logic programming language
now that is declarative so
so in a sense you can say mathematica is
declarative okay
but it's rather different from
functional uh
you know they they differ in detail
especially haskell
haskell is not decorative
anyway so i want let's talk about
something else so there is factorio
there is some
so let's do some uh
okay let's copy that let's do let's go
back to
uh my talk show okay
cut close that close that go to back to
the
talk show page and let's put that
let's put a javascript code here so you
can see
there is the javascript code
okay so let's do let's go on symbolic by
result
demo fractions i did uh show function n
so i mean this is just the random you
know random demonstration
not following any specific so let's do
some graphics
shall we
okay let me check the comments
geometric transformation of the plan
okay plane
okay i did this like 20 years ago let's
try to plot some of these
okay
uh let's do let's do it here wait
where is it close that
okay so paste that
oh i got a uh what oh it's okay i forgot
a parenthesis mathematica tells me you
can see there
paste
okay so that is uh that is that let's
see
so yeah so what i want to do is i want
to this is a function of x
y
wait how do i plot this vector plot
okay this is actually
this is a function okay this is a
function of two variables
x y this is a vector value function
so the input is a vector x and y and our
output is also a vector x and y so
this so input is a two numbers and
output is also two numbers
so in order to do that you can so you
know
so this page for example i wrote this
back in
uh 1999 also i have to
program it myself but now after 20 years
mathematica has this building so but i
never used it before so let's see
uh let's see vector plot okay
i never used this before so but
okay so that's how you use it
okay so let's so let's copy our function
here
copy it paste it here so that's our
function oh that's our function and here
is the parameters i mean
x goes from negative 3 pi to 3 pi
and why do the same so let's try that
run it there you have it
okay so so you can okay this is
interesting so the
we are plotting this one okay this one
so how do you get it to look like that
okay so i wrote this myself so but now
it's using you know it's using arrows so
you need to start with a grid
and i haven't been coding mathematica
for too long so i
cannot do it right off i cannot just
write it
uh off the bat can i well
it will take 10 minutes
so but but anyway mathematica has quite
a few variations let's see if we can get
it to
uh work okay the vector density plot
uh stream plot contour plot let's try
that okay let's try all these
vector density plot why is that not
working
okay that's not working i don't know but
uh let's skip that stream plot
probably because okay stream plot
plotted this way
that's not what we want least vector
plot
line integral convolution plot
let's just try this
wait why is stream plot not uh
wait why is string plot doesn't seems
like a function
did i spell it incorrectly okay let's
spell it correctly nevermind
vector density plots
oh i spelled it wrong density okay
there you get it you there you go so
okay it adds a background
that's not what we want now
let's try the stream plot
okay for the stream plots uh generate a
stream plot a vector field as a function
of x and y
okay it's gonna be similar yeah that's
not
what we want let's try
contour plot okay
uh what why are we loading contour
why uh why is it connecting to internet
that's not what i want you know
if you buy if you go uh go to woofam
website they have lots of product
you know they have the it's starting to
become confusing
20 years ago or 15 years ago it was just
mathematica you know you just buy it
you install on your computer you can run
everything there's no cloud
but cloud becomes became you know the
thing
since 2010 everywhere and yeah in fact
you need it because if you are doing
molecules
you know suppose you are a scientist you
need to
get all the molecule data or protein you
know data or dna data or all the stars
astronomy you know you want you want all
the stars
database of all the stars configuration
or whatever
uh then then you need the cloud because
you cannot store all that data inside
you know
software you know so you need to so
so since 2010 also from you know
language has
started to have a lot of functions that
just get you the data
but you shouldn't need that for contour
plot i'm not sure why you need it but
anyway
so here the contour plot is starting to
look similar
uh to the one i have there now
you have to note the coloring i'm using
here the coloring i'm using
is that the more places
i mean the further away the point moves
from the original position
the more it is colored uh red i mean
green
you know uh blue so that's how i uh
you know this is like a wave
so anyway so contour plot so anyway so
we you know so there is some
there's a contour plot let's see what
else we can try
let's go back let's go back uh
sliced vector plot complex vector
okay so that's it for that
uh wait so we can try to plot some of
the others
let's try this okay let's try this one i
want to i want plot this one so this
will be
complex
okay so complex vector plot what what is
the
it takes a complex function okay so
let's see what i have here
there it is there is a complex function
uh and let's do it
options expected uh what options
okay so instead of x and y you just
need one
wait complex number how does that work
uh
hey yeah i forgot
so let's read the comments uh where's
your eye patch
uh you misspelled density did i
oh let's try dense density plot because
density plot that that one is
interesting it's a
dnsi density plot
okay this one is not so interesting
let's say
nine let's go to knight
pi
okay you can kind of see you can can you
see the
wave let's say 90 okay
where does that angle come from
three let's say two
yeah you cannot really see the wave but
i believe there is great lines
try that no that's not what we want okay
so anyway
lorraine hey good morning break the
loops
my density have brought me to you how
does mathematica compare to other
popular languages
in terms of speed parallel computation
uh well in term speed wolfram language
is typically slower okay
now in terms of parallel computation uh
wufam has
lots of technologies you know the
wolfram grid
you can use uh i think you have to pay
so
you know just like amazon server
services or whatever you know or google
google's grid or whatever so you you run
suppose this function takes you know uh
one month to compute on your personal
computer
but you if you have if you bought the
wolfram servers oofam grid or something
then it runs on you know a massive
number of
cpus so you can do that
i'm seeing mathematica in action for the
first time and looks
really impressive i have no idea how
they implement the symbolic computation
uh well the symbolic computation is not
you know it's a known it's not
a novelty okay you know in order okay
you know mathematica originally this is
known as mathematica
so it's called uh you know computer
algebra system
you know look up wikipedia they have
article on that computer
algebra system what does that mean that
means basically means an application
that can do
symbolic mathematics such as
such as let's do another example okay
since i have mathematica now
i can uh i can show you
my you know my
20 years absolute knowledge of
mathematica
something like that so uh x let's say
x squared plus y times
x third power plus
four let's raise the whole thing to
fifth power
there you go so you know
so this is this is what it means uh the
computer algebra system that can do
this is the same simplest example of
doing
uh symbolic computation now this example
is actually
easy to implement you know you can i
mean easy in a sense you know you can
actually
i mean it's actually you can do it you
can you can write a function
that does this expand symbolic you know
polynomials
in python or golan you know let's say in
a day
okay but this is just the same the most
simple example
then you have to do integration let's
say derivative okay
uh let's say derivative then an
integration that then that
becomes very professional and you know
you can spend years
to implement just you know the
integration function
let's say the derivative x third power
with respect to x
now if i got the um
let's see if i got the syntax correct
okay i got the syntax incorrect let's
try again
so we are going we are actually doing
derivative with uh
there it is okay d just say d okay so
derivative of the polynomial x third
power
with respect to x is you know 3x squared
and you can do integral okay so
integrate uh x okay
three times x squared with respect to x
then you got three okay now let's uh
okay so so let's do next uh
let's see let's do next let's move on to
some uh some next interesting things i
want to do some
okay so let me show you one more thing
okay now when you do these kind of plots
you know one thing you want to know for
example polynomial you want to change
your parameter
and you want to see how it affects the
the graphics and mathematica today you
can do
fantastic okay so let's see let's try
this example
that's gonna be a beautiful example okay
so you want to do
let me show you okay
manipulate that's that's the function
you want this is new
uh i haven't i never used this before
this is
new around 2008 or something
okay so wolfram
so manipulate so we are going to call
manipulate
on this whole expression
okay so you can see how it works oops
okay and why does it
give me yeah so manipulate
on the oh yeah so i got this
cut it should be here
there it is so manipulate that thing
and the second argument will be
let's say s from
0 to 5
instead in step of 0.1 okay
so let's add a number here
s okay s times the whole thing
so enter so now you got a
slider there it is
fantastic oh this is fantastic
now you need uh now you
the resolution is not so clear oh
you have to wait for it to compute okay
so you see this
is beautiful this is what i'm doing
mathematica for
you know just for this power alone
it's worth to pay three thousand dollars
i mean
three hundred dollars so a thousand
dollars
but okay i'm running into a problem
because
you see you have to stop
for it to compute the high resolution
but what i want is you know i want to
just move the slider and
use the already computed form so
so so how do i do that you know so
that's getting into detail i
you know so i never used manipulate
before this is new around 2008 or
something
so i mean so this is you see how
fantastic is this function so you know
maybe you have a 3d plot
maybe you have a planet moving around
you know so
described by a complex formula you know
this formula can be a thousand lines
but you want you wonder how how a
parameter affects the whole
thing so you can do animation and you in
fact so
here is a interactive um form
and you can also generate the animation
of it and save it to
a you know mp4 you know format
let's try let's see anime image okay
maybe that's the one
uh no it no that's not one anyway
animate image is another new function i
haven't used
so over the past 20 years wolfram
language has
they've added i think at least at least
five thousand well is that correct
well let's say three thousand i think in
the past twenty years
at least three thousand functions has
been added
yeah the slider you know this this is
what i really love you know
so this is added around 2008 or
something okay
and this you know let me show you
article okay so this is um
this is what you need when you when you
us uh
engineer or scientist you know you
explore molecules or whatever
you you need to know how are parameters
or several
you know you can have more than one
parameters you can have more than one
by just adding for example let's add
another one
uh let's say ss2 okay from zero to
five let's say zero zero
one okay actually let's increase the
density actually
because i'm annoyed about so before we
add a second
slider first of all i want to add
i want to make sure it's computed
correctly
uh so what's the option i don't remember
so you have to you know
so then it starts to get into
you know so i'm just doing this for
memory
uh you know from year 2000 so here are
the options for the manipulate function
um
and uh so you know
so it you know it is you start to get
into programming mathematical
programming
so anyway let's add another slider okay
so s1
so let's see s1
[Music]
uh let's say times s2
raised to the power of s2 and s2
from 0 to 1 increased by that
so s2 is actually
s2 begin from 1 to
2 let's say okay so
s okay
now let's see what does s2 do wow
okay so that's the fun part
okay so that's some of the graphics uh i
want to
show okay i want to show you
a article i wrote about
um you know and also this one we
you know we might we might uh do this
one
i wrote this one like 20 years ago
and today you know so so imagine doing
using the
manipulate for this one and by the way
all the images you can rotate them
interactively
without any code you know it just
so i can try to do this one it requires
i it
it does require my package uh you know
but i want to show you a article
um okay so
visualization
uh
who is the article
too many too many articles
this is a important article okay one of
the
there wait what why is it not finding it
v-i-s-u-a okay yeah okay there
so requirements for a visualization
system
i wrote this like 2007 uh where i
give a description what is required for
a visualization system
and one of the requirement is is
interactivity
interactivity for example this one is
fantastic this guy wrote it in i believe
in java but it's dead long
long ago yeah so you can click on the
point so it's talking about complex
numbers
uh mobius transformation so you can and
any mobile transformation there are
a few key points you know the
like they are the core of the function
control the properties of the function
so you can drag these points and see how
the
how it transforms how it moves the whole
thing for example here's another example
here's a polytopes you know basically
regular polyhedron
in more than three dimensions in in
fourth dimension in fifth dimension
they they they project it
to 3d or they slice it to 3d so
anyway so you know so here is the
example where you can see
how the slider is critically important
uh when you are talking about
visualization for scientific or
engineering purposes critically
important
so you could so you can change the
parameters and see how it changes
uh uh the thing
okay so so uh and
you know so here's another example
animations i did this in mathematica
in 1997.
uh here's another example so let me show
you animation okay so
actually we can run this in mathematica
uh this is actually mathematica okay so
here is the animation
now where is my movie okay i don't have
the movie but the movies on my
friend richard palace
professor richard palace a top
expert in differential geometry and
kosher hermann kosher
they are my friends so this is one of
the
this is one of the great theory in
differential geometry heterochord
catenoid surface it shows that
uh well i'm not going to go into math
because i forgot a lot of it
i cannot do an explanation right away it
shows that basically the geometry on the
on on the on on all these frames on
all these surfaces are the same okay
uh isometric yeah the the word is
isometric
so anyways
so you can see okay so
uh what i want to do where is the
animation by the way
so you don't have it here
i think i removed it because it's it was
it's not a good animation
okay so let's run this okay so here is
mathematica let's try to run this
okay let's see how it
goes let's paste this okay b equals
through parametric plot
and let's make these uh select select
select select select
you know another great feature of
mathematica is that they
expand selection by by semantic units
okay unlike for example in emac this
let's say if you have javascript code
let's magnify okay
it doesn't matter javascript python has
got this okay
then you know when you you know you want
to expand selection right you have to
there's no way basically you know
in around 2010 there's this guy emacs
rocks
you know he's a new guy he he wrote a
package but
it's not so good so you so basically you
want to extend the selection
such that the extension is based on the
semantic
unit of this syntax of the language so
for example
if you select that will be that one if
you press select again
it should be that one if you select
again it should be
you know that if you select again it
should be
that and select again you should include
the whole brand you know like that
and select again it should be that
okay so i have article on that um i have
article on that
yeah let's not show it you know i have
too many i have thousand articles on the
on the syntax thing
so but in mathematica it's building
since
uh since uh 1999 1997 okay
look okay let's say start on that select
you
i click again click twice again
okay so let's do click click
click okay you cannot stop in between so
you have to
click continuously it expands actually
oh yeah there is the
uh shortcut control control period okay
watch
control period control period control
period you see that's a unit because
that's
uh of the multiplication that's one term
control period then you got the whole
formula of the
you know one of the function control
period then the whole
uh list okay then the whole formula
control period then the whole all the
arguments of the function
control period then the whole thing
control period you see
so that's the that's a semantic uh
selection expansion
you know that's one of the fantastic
thing about mathematica
now what i want to do is i want to turn
this into a math formula so ctrl shift
uh ctrl shift i is for input form ctrl
shift um
s no not ctrl shift s
what's a keystroke i forgot
n okay ctrl shift n
ah that's not that doesn't look so good
because oh
at least we see the fraction because
there's not much fractions for this
formula so anyway
so let's enter so there it is oh okay
so you can rotate it in real time
okay one thing i don't have is that you
see the one i did here that takes some
coding so i want
only i want to show part of it as a mesh
so you can actually see through
uh do do i have mathematica uh notebook
here
actually i do have mathematica notebook
here so let's download it okay
let's go put this back and let's open a
new window
let's go to my downloads folder
and the catalog so here is the file
let's unzip it unzip
okay so open that
make a copy and also by the way here is
a mathematica notebook
everything is plain text you know
for example when you look at um
you know when you look at this you see
oh my god this is
all uh very fancy you know but actually
if you save this and open it in emacs
for example
this is what it looks like it's all
plain text
okay so what i want to do i want to open
this okay open it
there it is so here is my notebook this
is written
around 2004
okay continue with updated styling uh
revert to old styling
you open that you opened a notebook with
an old default styling
okay okay continue with uh updated
styling okay
okay so let's run this okay let's
magnify
okay let's run this run it
okay so they you see they changed the
default color
now okay you see okay
so now i want to um
okay it doesn't run something when you
know there are some changes i need to do
because
let's let's do that let's remove oh wait
okay it show output
uh okay it does not run
i don't know why well obviously because
this is
from this is a notebook from like 15
years ago
but i can figure out quickly
i think so let's see
i need to split the cell
the right cell shift ctrl d okay
so evaluate that part
shift ctrl d
evaluate that
okay it's not working why is that
oh wait
yeah yeah you know it'll take me some
time to look into what's going on
but let me show you this one okay
so 15 years ago i have to code
manually myself but today let's just use
manipulate okay
use just use a manipulate function
okay so copy the code
let's see
manipulate be
cut
paste okay
then
cut
putting it there
and we want
b so we want
let's say b from
[Music]
0.01 to pi over 5
in increment of 0
0.01 let's say
okay let's try it
oh okay this is a
fantastic
so you can click uh click the play
button
now let's try click the play button
oh now this is smooth okay i think
that's about it for today any
uh any questions so
wait why is it taking a long time
oh because for each time it's trying to
uh also change the s two i think let's
try this
let's try over here
and let's try let's try it
instead of having two parameters let's
just have one parameter
now it's not doing
it's not doing a small it is it's
beginning to become smooth
okay i think that's that's about it for
today how long have i been talking
oh i've been talking for one hour now
and what do i think of r well i is a
popular statistics
uh uh language
package it became very very popular
because
it's free it became very popular since
about 2010 i think
uh but mathematica is far more powerful
so all or life says hakusa would you
recommend mathematica also as a general
purpose programming language yes of
course
do you see shortcomings in it well the
shortcoming is one it's not open source
so first of all you have to pay and then
well because it's not open source then
you might worry about what
what what happens when wu farm goes away
uh so that's that's you know that's kind
of the
you know that's the thing uh but it's
uh i don't know you well you know it
is you know what happens if google goes
away
you know lots of things done by google
are not open source
you know for example chrome you know you
know lots of things
they are open source on one hand but
actually not
for example lots of you know for example
uh self-driving cars
is it open source no if there's anything
that actually has value a great monetary
value value it's not open source okay
so google google makes ai chips you know
is it open source no
okay so are you going to use it well
you're probably going to use it
you know they have open source interface
you know the open source front end you
know to connect to it
so what what what happens if google went
away well
well then you don't you know your front
end your open source front end
doesn't work anymore uh
and can you actually look at the open
source you know google chrome can you
actually look at it
yes you can but can you do anything no
unless you have 10 years
specializing in coding c in browsers you
know that's how complex it is
uh have you seen mr wolfe i'm doing live
ceo of course
i've been watching it quite a few times
four times also in the past
week in particular what bunch of
mathematics keep these sort of
constructs okay
these are not actually you know what
i've shown today
they are just uh tools to for
visualization okay they are not
exactly you know what branch of math you
know for example pi
you know let's say when we compute pi to
ten thousand places what what branch of
math is that
you know it's just computation it's it's
actually
depends on what you mean okay so pi is
the study of pi
belongs to uh you know part of uh
you know it belongs to actually many
branches number theory number theory
uh analysis you know calculus you know
depending on what kind of things you are
studying
about pi and for example this plot
vector fields vector fields is usually
is a complex function or vector function
you know
a function that takes two numbers and
output two numbers or
a function that takes one complex number
and output one complex number
so that is used in complex analysis in
and
and also and which in turn is used in
physics in
engineering everywhere uh but
the plot itself you know so then you ask
the question okay so you are plotting a
vector function which
which is part of linear algebra which is
used everywhere
it's one of the most fundamental basic
math you have to take
even if you are you know physics
engineer or
you know into physics or engineer or
chemistry you have to take that linear
algebra very fundamental
but then you could ask okay so that's
one thing but how do you actually
what what is the math of
actually writing this function then
then you can go into then then it
becomes lots of computers
science kind of wishy-washy thing
because then you have
uh well not necessary
okay so anyway so you have you know you
have computational geometry
you have um
uh
numerical analysis hey what is it is it
called numerical analysis
yeah because when you compute pi to
let's say let's say when you want to
compute pi to
uh ten thousand places how do you know
i mean you can you there are formulas to
compute to lots of places but how do you
know
it will come out exactly that many
places you want
so that's uh that's a numerical analysis
you know no it's not i forgot what's the
name
yeah there it is numerical analysis
numerical analysis is the study of
algorithms that uses numerical
approximations
as opposed to symbolic manipulations so
numerical analysis
is one kind of giant uh
branch of applied math or you can you
can think of you know it's also part of
you can think about as a applied
computer science okay
but most programmers don't know nothing
about this because
it's it's outside of the typical
industrial programming thing like
when you go to see compilers nothing it
has nothing to do with this
uh numerical analysis but when you
compute sine cosine
pi you know how do you get you know
number of places you know or
or when you do graphics you know okay so
then you need numerical analysis you
make you
you want to make sure that the real
numbers of mathematics doesn't get
truncated
when you implement it on a you know bits
bytes long float that java
you know c code as
uh so anyway back to so what about these
graphics so what what what part of math
is that that you know so
uh you need numerical analysis to
implement this
then your there's also a visualization
uh
study situations but anyway so
and the you know the math is complex
analysis and so on
okay i think that's it that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
um yeah so is it actually um there is
one more thing i want to
do i want to show you type settings okay
uh yeah one more thing let me show you
type settings in mathematica
because lots of uh programmers
they think of la tech that latex
crap okay let me show you okay
tech pestilence you know wild attack and
tech
sucks so you know these are
very common uh math formulas traditional
math notation
so in la tech or tech this is what you
have to type
you have to type this garbage you know
and in mathematica here's what you type
very simple and easy to understand let
me show you
let me demonstrate okay
uh let's go back to so let's
shrink shrink shrink okay so let's let's
type that
okay so let's go here let's say sum okay
sum actually we showed this before
1 over n
then n from 1 to
k okay oh harmonic number so
select it wait undo
select the whole thing ctrl shift
n there you have it okay
you don't have to type so instead of you
know instead of typing this
crap this you know tech la tech
backslash
some underscore blah blah blah you know
uh in fact let me so let me show you
actually
the form
so you can actually see both okay so
that's
some then let's say this integral okay
integrate the expression is 1 over x
with respect to x and
from x from
1 to k plus 1.
okay so copy that
uh copy that select
it ctrl shift n
make it you know the standard notation
so that's how you you see that's
that's that uh on the and in la
tech you have type this this crap
so you know i so i hope this shows you
the design philosophy of mathematica you
know
donald gruth he's a great computer
scientist but he's
you know his uh point of view is
very typical of the nerds he creates
this crap you know meanwhile it's very
precise you know this
you know the thing donald grunts created
is very precise like micro
micro points pika pika and whatever
you know the font units so he
you know but in mathematica you you
write it this way
very uh intuitive and if you want the
value out of it for example let's say
this one okay
some copy let's go here
and let's say uh let's say you want to
replace actually this sum you can
actually compute it
oh okay okay so k k is the variable so
let's say
k becomes uh one
okay let's say k10 then you
you actually get the number okay so
so this so you type this
very simple and easy to understand it's
not
it's not just for typesetting it's
actually
a active programming language syntax
okay okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
uh yeah that's it any any more questions
one more minute
i close down which
uh okay so jeon says hexa do you see
in the long term 30 or 40 years
mathematics are still being used
uh
uh 40 or 50 years um we are mathematica
it will still be around i'm pretty sure
now here's the thing okay
here's the thing that uh
that is a humanity thing nobody can
solve it okay
so mathematica is created by stephen
wufen okay so very
famous you know there are great many
people
who have done great things but what
happens if we you know he's not going we
you know
nobody is going to live forever so he's
going to
you know go away so then what happens to
mathematica
okay so you know if you think of
microsoft windows you know what what
happens to microsoft windows if your
biogas
dies you'll still be around
now mathematica depends on what i you
know i don't know what
you know i'm not speaking for wufan but
depends on what he wants to do
maybe he will release it as open source
or
maybe you know in a traditional fashion
he'll just pass on to his
to his uh sons or daughters you know
then his son or daughter will run a
company
um
and also steve jobs you know steve jobs
passed away so now apple is without
steve jobs
uh is apple the same company
without steve jobs no i don't think so
it's not it's a
it's a bit different it you know not in
my opinion it's different
so so in 50 years stephen
stephen wufang will not be around but
mathematica will
i don't you know i don't know nobody
knows nobody knows what you know
uh will happen maybe his son will make
it even
bigger company uh and maybe not uh
maybe you'll just remain you know a
tightly controlled niche company or
maybe wufam will you know
uh go public you know ipo you know
open up his company so it becomes public
traded uh company i don't know
i have no idea
okay thank you guys bye that's it for
today
uh so last last thing okay so if you
want to
um so mathematica you can just go to my
website
you can see wufang language
and there's a section how to uh get it
for free
okay so there are several ways the
wolfram language you can download it for
free
uh or you can buy the raspberry pi
bundle with it but i i actually
recommend it you buy it you know you pay
it
beginning with a 300 version you know
hobbies 300
for i believe it i'm not sure how it
lasts you know because
right now they have so many different
versions of products
mathematica wolfram desktop wolfram
alpha 1 or something you know
it's kind of confusing before it's just
mathematica so
anyway i recommend you just buy it 300
you know just
just you know if if you are interested
in math
or or you know i'm sure you are
interested in maybe not math but crypto
crypto analysis you have it's like
6 000 functions built in you have you
don't have to worry about which package
you know i haven't loaded a single
library anything you know all 600
functions or it's just right there you
don't have to
search for libraries and worry about
which library does you know is good or
bad
or they went away or who wrote it you
don't have to worry know about that
and everything is consistent and well
extremely well documented
so even just for the
graphics uh features of mathematica
i would buy it for three hundred dollars
i i
you know back in 1992 i bought it
i don't remember it's a student version
i bought or a full version you know back
in 1992 it was one thousand dollars
or was it two i think i bought a student
version for like
200 or 300 why why do i buy it because
back then i was going to be i want to be
one of the best mathematicians so
i want i need to i want i want the best
tool
okay so that's why
so i i do recommend it
okay bye guys
you