good morning guys welcome to another
episode ofan talk show it's been a month
how are you guys so today's topic is
that we are going to I'm going to show
you my keyboard kesis Advantage 360 now
I have super light switches pink
switches they sent me you know this so
so I'm going to talk about that kesis
kesis 360 keyboard and I'm going to do a
review after a month a full review uh
and I'm going to show
you glove 80 box okay can you see it uh
glove 80 case Okay so that's the second
topic on keyboard then I'm going to talk
about um so I'm going to announce we I'm
we are going to do a Advent of code for
this year you know Advent of a code is a
code
exercise uh 12 of them or or 24 I forgot
but basically you so I'm going to do it
starting tomorrow with wolam
language uh and a live stream okay so
that's Advent of code uh and then I'm
going to talk about RSS web feed I
updated all my RSS for my 12
blogs we're going to talk about that
then we're going to talk mention emac uh
feed reader okay then I'm going to tell
you about my new phone iPhone 13 I'm a
reachman
now and and this girl's cute
case made in China you know the the
girls case
fantastic iPhone 13 okay then we're
going to do one of the B gospers
mathematical identity in wfam language
okay that's uh advanced math then uh
maybe something then Unicode okay so
let's
begin how are you guys and I'm drinking
uh I need to show you this today for the
happy holiday seasons I'm having one of
these Kalua drink this is like chocolate
liquid or coffee liquor okay
fantastic sweet
wonderful okay uh let's have a
sip I'm going to gradually get drunk
over this live stream actually you know
half of it is milk this is not enough to
get me
drunk so and uh today I met one of the
guy Bruce from our s Discord okay
fantastic meeting he's a programmer
fantastic okay so let's begin so I'm
going to tell you about so the if you
watch my last live stream we I talked
about kesis 360 keyboard this one okay
heavy uh and they they sent
me now they finally they send me uh the
pink switch 35 G activation Force by the
way this is my
Chinese
T know uh toing balls exercise your
hands RI fantastic if you want buying
advice I have a web page for it just
search for
an.org and you know search for hand
toys kali. info or kali.org search them
both you'll see buying advice for these
Chinese um you know I have a few
actually so I have
like you know two metal the the metal
ones they make Chimes those are not good
okay don't buy those I much prefer the
stone ones but these are too small you
actually I want the larger one so when
they are so
small you know so you use three of them
so you can either two
them uh with them touching each
other in either direction or without
them touching each other in either
direction okay so that's fantastic
so you can walk around uh and T these
balls oh by the way there's a Chinese
kung fu movie that's a great you you'll
see the dragon
hand uh should I show it yeah uh well
let's not let's so this keyboard they
send me kesis 360 search my website I'm
going to show you my blog later so kesis
360 they send me the pink switch 35 G of
activation Force so so that's fantastic
okay and this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard I also have a super light
switch I think 30 also 35 G I forgot
it's on my website okay so that's about
the keyboard yeah oh before we go then
let me show you the ultimate uh this
this this glove 80 okay I got to put my
drink
away glove 80 send me the case fantastic
carrying case so you can
see uh okay my it's all crammed here so
but anyway so this case so let's let me
show you let's open
it and open
it okay opens and you you can see it's a
casee for the glove at keyboard
yeah okay you pack them like that one up
and one down and you got other space for
mouse or
something
fantastic now if you are a g spound you
need
this so this is glove 80 keyboard I have
a video review glove 0 just you'll find
it on my YouTube on my or on my
website glove ATK is
fantastic okay let's go to my website uh
let's see yeah are you guys still here
say something hello Q intent hello
Ben hello
Jake okay so let's see
let's talk show let's go to today's talk
show on the pink window is my Emax or
the emac command as side type any key I
press you can see they update on the
pink window and you can see the key
switch I'm pressing like T
N uh you know and the command name so
I'm using sofly keys and I'm using a vak
layout okay so
today's this is s talk show so let's go
to today's
entry and by the way uh few days ago I
have a new podcast new podcast you can
uh the topic is aan and privacy you know
I [ __ ] despise this Zuma forchan type
of people they they want to be aown they
use you know bad name names on Discord
on Twitter on everywhere Reddit they
cancel account create new account when
they get banned they don't care they
they want to be a so this podcast St
talk show on Anan and
privacy I tell you why I think uh this
anang is bad and some history of it and
so
on okay so close that back to talk show
let's go to today's talk show uh so emac
fantastic Aladdin says I wish a case
like this comes with uh Advantage 360
yeah uh yeah well yeah Advantage 360 is
kind of bigger
uh
it's significantly you know bigger and
but they are more rugged so you you can
just put them in a back back uh
backpack I think that'll be
fine okay so today's topic so so you see
we are talking about we talked about 360
uh let me show you some pictures kesis
keyboard review actually I did two of
them the this one is last month and this
one is unboxing several months ago uh
you know I got beautiful nice photos and
full review every detail of it you can
read on my blog just search for kesis
360 keyboard review okay now go back now
glove 80 as I mentioned you know that's
the one I was using now I'm going to use
the kesis 360 for the next next three or
four month I want to give them some
business you know that's why they give
it to me for review so and after I
already used it for a month already it
this has been my man for the past month
and uh then after a month then I'm going
to do a full review on this uh Kinesis
360 okay some of you probably going to
ask me which one you prefer okay you
know they are just different okay they
are different
different uh they are different okay
so there are many aspects that makes
them different uh for example the size
the weight the key switches for example
the glove 80 is um low profile okay
that's a major difference this is the
kesis 360 is full profile so if you want
one or the other you that that makes
your choice okay
so so what I can say is that I love them
both okay I have no problem at all I
love them both okay uh you know either
one so anyway so this is glove 80 okay
fantastic uh then next topic uh yeah
Advent of code if you guys don't know
it's this website it's just Advent of
code.com it's some kind of Christian
thing so every day up till until
Christmas you you have one puzzle uh C
coding exercise you can code in any
programming language your favorite
programming language so I'm going going
to start to do that tomorrow with wolam
language ch ch hello Ben thank you for
the
money I
noticed a lot of people put their Mouse
between glove 80 is that standard what's
your preference okay yeah that's a good
question I don't like put my mouse there
uh let me show you okay so when you have
this split keyboard a lot of people put
a track track pad touchpad trackpad or
track
ball or sometimes a mouse but usually
track B you know in the
middle uh the the idea is that you know
since you have split keyboard you have
the space in the middle so so you can
you know but actually I never like that
I never put the track B Mouse and not
not Mouse for sure because with mouse
you can't move much so but usually track
b i I do have a track B anyway
so I don't like that okay so I prefer on
the side on the
side it's very close unlike the
traditional keyboard you have the number
pad so you have to move all the way
that's not good so but with the on the
right side it's very close all you can
put on the left side okay so that is my
opinion I think people do that is just
because you know naturally you think you
know now you have a space in the middle
you put in the middle though I don't
like it
myself let's celebrate their fifth super
on a live stream what does that mean is
that something something Google
showed uh okay
so
Ka Senai now I know what Senpai means
but what's coma
Wang I'm Chinese okay
so yeah so you have to say suu now
instead of the Senpai Japanese thing you
have to say
suu Okay so next topic yeah let's talk
about the RSS okay so in the past month
I've been working nonstop on my website
of course as you know um so let's go to
for example let's go to kasar
Kar code okay my website so onar code
you can find you know have I have one
two uh one two three four five six blogs
now the unic code blog is new and the
web de blog is revived from Death you
know because I I stopped doing web I
stopped the web de blog I'm still doing
web web dev JavaScript but I stopped
this blog because I I thought I want to
consolidate into one single
block but turns out I find that having a
dedicated you know just for JavaScript
things CSS and and HTML is good so this
web dat block is is for that JavaScript
CSS HTML you know stuff Technologies
font siiz survey very interesting you
know this is another topic I can talk
for half an hour you know today
you go to you use the same browser same
device same computer same monitor or
laptop whatever but one single device
you go to different website their font
size varies greatly so I have this
survey basically I do this kind of
survey every few years because I'm you
know I'm into this technology what they
do so the design issues so but today you
go to different website they are found
size very greatly some of them are like
huge like a idiot you know when you see
huge fun it's like looks like it's for
children and and then the worst is
Wikipedia
Wikipedia and actually another website
popular website that's even smaller than
Wikipedia is The Hacker News so I did a
survey of the you know top 1,000 popular
sites kind of so you know so the the
font size problem okay so anyway that's
web blog so anyway in the past days I've
been updating all my uh SS feed now what
is RSS feed for example if you go to my
Emax blog you can click subscribe feed
okay it's basically it's a XML file
that for news kind of information every
day regularly periodically you have a
snippet of new information and this will
go on for years right so you have like
news typically so so the web feed or
code SS is a standardized format it's in
XML for these purposes so when you
subscribe or some other machine they can
periodically check your web feed and get
the latest snippet of info and aggregate
them so anyway that's about web feed uh
in fact I have an article on that okay
so I just wrote an article so anyway my
point here is that you know in the last
week I update up updated all my blogs
web feed because before nobody read web
web feed anymore like social network
took over Twitter Instagram you know
thousands of them you know then there's
uh there's one for women in well
Instagram is mostly for girls to show
their
body oh yeah so and what's the other one
so let's go to Discord now if you
haven't already join join Discord you
okay you can find the link ons.info okay
so um video don't mean d yeah so there
is so many you know so-call social
networks social networks they are
um so what's the one I want to mention
women's
stuff uh you know we got a bunch of
memes here and we got what's the one I
want to mention okay maybe
oh they have like they have like um LD
ads okay so here's another ads on cali.
info very weird
stuff oh yeah aled okay so one of the
thing yeah aled is a good one so today
you don't have much ISS readers Alit is
one of them for emac in fact let's
install it okay so uh uh list packages
okay oh your fifth donation okay
cool
Ben uh so let's see
Alid now Alid is a guy you know he he's
a Lis emac list coder I really respect
that guy he's he's a great coder one of
the
greatest e
uh Alit there it is what's the
secretarial God e f e e d let's list all
of
them oh God there's so many addon for
Alit now what Alit score Al protocol
aled org Alit goodies oh
God Al web kit what
the what happened to Alit it seems like
a huge addon now oh there it is okay so
let's just let's just do the AL feed the
most basic one
okay so install it yes so Alit is one of
the best RS reader for emac so you can
subscribe to different websites they are
collected in and you can read them in
emx okay
installed uh now how do you how do you
turn it on I forgot so go to the aled
website magnify
magnify okay let's subscribe some um SAR
pages okay so I have 12
blocks uh introducing Al feed emac web
feeder tips and
tricks these projects extend out feed
with additional features lit or Alit
goodies Alit protocol okay I don't care
so Global set key outfit no I don't want
I don't want that m
going so anyway L this guy uh this guy
skito skito he's a one of the imag this
expert extreme expert also he's also a c
you know he can call C unlike me I
cannot C C++ you know he's one of the
hardcore hardcore coder as opposed to
The meenen Zuma
coders mpm
JavaScript
crap so anyways so uh set up so how do
you subscribe L feeds okay so let's see
that so let's just turn on L feed let's
see okay empty close it close it let's
go to talk show let's go to today's talk
show uh open it show the pink window and
let's let's go to Let's showing browser
first so you can see it back in emac so
I'm using the automa keyboard for
keyboard Mark so you can see I switch
how I switch windows and so on so you
can you can switch to the next window
previous window uh and so
on okay so Al feed so let's add a emac
this code put the code there pop it into
a buffer by itself so LED feed yes okay
I'm going to add some feed let's see web
comics uh so what is the format okay so
the format
is no Auto tagging what the [ __ ] is this
H
weird you see it's got a strange this
this line is different from the others
uh strange okay but anyway I'm going to
post some kadi site okay so let's go to
kinfo my local page and
uh uh search for blog okay so actually
oh God I have to add each one of them so
s keyboard block go to the top search
for RSS there it is okay copy that uh
actually open that uh wait open it
copy it close close back here so let's
paste paste the link now this link is
now local you see you
us I'm I'm going okay so now you call
command Kar site that turns this local
link into the kar domain URL okay so
what you want is you put a parenthesis
then
oh you just made common like a symbol
here okay so
s keyboard block
uh okay so that's one
example now okay before we do anything
let's just try it okay actually remove
this okay now evaluate it
fantastic pop it
back make it cified showing
browser that's our code fantastic now
let's call L
feed Al database empty what
yeah use l feed add feed uh
okay wait didn't what why is
this why is this example Auto tagging
tag can automatically be
applied to entries discovered in spefic
in specific feed through extra syntax
okay I don't know what that is okay so
apparently you
use uh you use the L feed ad okay so
forget about
this so anyway go to Al feed okay split
the window open a new buffer
uh and
paste paste the S
keyboard okay now copy that line now
let's
see L feed add feed
okay default that's right add
that
done there it is s feed let's look at
short hand system
open fantastic now let's look at so uh
let's let's look at short and system not
found what the
[ __ ] well it may
be wait did they yeah that's not
good well that's because now this is or
mod
right God so let's look at my S short
hand
system and I don't
know I'll fix it okay by tonight so
let's close it let's um anyway so that's
that's about L feed okay uh you know
I'll fix it I'll find out what's the
problem so that's about RSS feed yeah
actually we I haven't talked about it
RSS feed okay so if you are so here is
my you know 12
blogs and uh 10 reasons you need to
subscribe I need to refresh okay in Al
what's the key to
refresh uh but
anyway you know it's got this problem
and I think I know why is the problem
happening is
because it's
because you know there's
a well let's go to my keyboard block and
let me show you okay so for example here
is my keyboard Blog the latest item is
this phone case now the phone
case you know the phone case they have
several issues you can when you want to
buy one is the handle or the grip you
can buy some kind of like a circle a
ring or or this kind of
or you can buy them with the case or
sometimes they can they can be they can
usually be bought independent
independently you attach them to the
case with a group so then some of the
case got got a ring so that allows you
to put a trap or a necklace or whatever
I want that okay so what the the the
things I need for my case is a handle I
want that and but I can also buy a
handle separately and and some kind of
hole so I can pach a lyard or trap a
strap so so that's what that's what I
need now in in some other the cases you
got a W uh wallet or you know for credit
cards and uh then some of them are
compatible with the chi charge so you
don't have to a charger you don't have
to plug in you just place it on it you
know kind of
air wireless
charging so anyway that's about the case
so if you want to buy it there's a link
so okay uh so look let's let's look at
the S keyboard blog okay actually let's
go to emac blog okay so showing browser
so you can see there's RSS feed there
now that's this line okay so if you go
to that blog so actually let's subscribe
uh let's subscribe this blog okay Al
feed okay
then then what you do is uh L feed add
feed okay then paste the
link yes okay so you got lot so you got
so let's look at this one emac HTML
command open Okay so this this is my
update so that's this um you know that's
all that so you can see emac WP
paragraph text that's a emac list
command
open not found you know what the [ __ ] so
okay so not found so what is the problem
so let's go fix the problem so you can
see that entry is this one okay HTML
command in the first link here do you
know why that happens it's because I'm
using relative link okay I'm using a
relative link and is my base
correct yes my base is correct you see
this XML base
so amazing Al has this
bug you know this SPG is common in ISS
feeders you know according to the spec
of ISS readers that you have this line
XML base that's your base directory
so every Link in
the atom RSS feed every Link in it if
it's relative path then it should be
relative to this this base directory
okay uh so but what happens with Al feed
is
that it didn't respect it but this is
this is strange because like five or 10
years ago he actually you know he talked
to me and resolved this
problem so I don't know if the bug came
back to L feed or is there something
wrong with my
feed uh very annoying you
see but I don't think something is wrong
with my feed let's let's double check
okay emac
blog uh go to the feed feed so go to the
top so you can
see the base link right the base link
now it's valid because it opens it so
the base link is
there yeah I'm pretty sure there a
problem with Al feed it's a bug because
it's a bug okay uh it's a nasty bug
because like 15 years ago actually have
a Blog about it so I can show you so if
you go to my emex blog click on the atom
web feed tutorial now if you are a Blog
writer and you have your own website you
need to learn how to create a web feed
and here is a tutorial and the other
tutorial is a emac list command that
allows you to add a entry to the feed as
you write blog so you can read it so
anyway let's go read
the atom web feed tutorial so it's a XML
file like that it's pretty simple okay
and here is
entry and
uh uh then you know by spec if you have
this line base that's supposed to be the
Parent Directory and if whenever you
have a relative link it should be
resolved according to the to the Parent
Directory
now you see web feed reader bug on
relative link now this bug is very
common uh this happened in 2006 okay so
here's my blog I documented
it so you see in
2014 Christopher wellan that's the
author of aled you know he he's got this
bug and we talked about that is supposed
to be fixed so just what the [ __ ] is
going on or is it something wrong with
my with
some you see support XML base attribute
in atom so this is should be
fixed uh wait what
wait let's let's uh let's try it
again open link
okay
so sko Clos this as completed in 2018
but it went
back uh I have no idea what's going
on so anyway that's uh that's the issue
I don't think I have a I don't think
it's on my
side um I mean I don't think the problem
is my okay that's it that's it about
that uh web feed okay so
next got a new phone so we talked about
that already uh let's do one gospel
identity okay in my last live stream we
talked about the bog gospel
mathematician
fantastic uh I'm supposed to do some
work on it but I didn't but I got
distracted I'll get back to it but let's
do one of the identity in wam language
okay and that would
be okay we are only 37
minutes so let's do one of these
identity amazing identity okay let's do
them in wolam language okay let's start
wolam
language anything else what's going on
guys everything so far so
good finish my
drink nice
new notebook W language the mo most
powerful language on
Earth shift enter to run it okay now
magnify so you guys can see okay so now
uh we want to do this one to see if W
language knows the answer okay we did
the first one last
video so this one okay so how we going
to let's do it here so
okay but
we so this is the identity of fractional
Powers okay that means like
root so this should be easy to verify
because it's all numbers it's it's not
symbolic okay and let's start wol from
let's go to talk show uh go to today's
talk show open it go to the bottom
and let's
do wolam mod so we code we code wolam
language in Kar in emx Kar Wan mod is
free
uh so you can see ex W mod here open
it expand the window go to the top so
here's a URL open the URL showing
browser so that's Sai mod you can get it
on GitHub it's free okay so it allows me
to type code in emac much faster than
the the the wol
language uh notebook so let's close
close close okay let's start to type
that
equation okay 3 rais to the power of 3
over
5 then minus 2 ra to the power of 1 over
5 then the whole thing raised to the
power of 1 over
3 equals
to okay so that's one expression let's
let's do
a so this two supposed to be equal on
the right side
is 2 ra to
1 over 5
now let's do this okay so let's make
them
uh let's change them all to X so I can
easily so -2 to 1 over
5times 3 ra to 3 over
plus 2 ra to 3 over
5 okay times 3 ra to 2 over
5 uh let's show the Ping
window plus okay
plus three
raised to 1/
5 plus 2 to the 2 over 5
power okay so this whole
thing divided
by 5 raised to 2
over3
copy back to wolam notebook paste let's
shift enter eval okay so copy the input
you can press control shift n to format
it now let's double
check oh okay so we got this wait did we
got this wrong yeah we got this wrong
this one over by power you you forgot a
parent okay so let's delete that delete
that paste it do it copy the output
control shift n to format
it let's double check
215 335 2 35
minus 3
[Music]
25 wait
uh not minus this is times
okay
so 235 325 235 325 so that's
times okay then 315 21 225 over 5 2 3
okay so these two should be equal now
let's
see
eval okay now Mathematica doesn't know
if they are equal or not because you
have to say
numerical so you want to force them to
be numerical so N means the last input
SL sln N is a function to foral
numerical result do it
true okay fantastic we did this one so
this one is
true now let's think about what it means
okay so 3 to the 3 over 5 power
minus um
you know so so what does it mean this
equation what I mean why is it
significant in other words why is this
significant it's bunch of fractional
Powers now if you don't know if you
forgot your Calculus you know when you
have a power integral power that's power
right that's a number times itself now
when you have have a fraction such as 1
over three that means the third root I
mean that's just a different notation
for the third root so when you have 3
over five power that means you raise to
the third power and you take the fifth
root okay so that's what this means so
this
thing now I don't understand why is it
significant you know this is one of the
BPA
mathematicians um I identity so if he
put it out obviously it's
nontrivial
uh so why is this uh is there a pattern
with these Powers 3 over 5 1 over five 1
over
three yeah I cannot tell I don't
know okay so we did that one great
fantastic so this is uh great now copy
that now we don't need
the uh
wait okay we we don't need the alter par
and change this to equal and
uh and
just and uh the other way another way we
can do this is that instead of saying
numerical we can just
say simplify okay if that works
no uh okay
so apparently this is fairly complicated
yeah so this identity is fairly
complicated because when you say
simplify it tries to simplify these two
sides
symbolically but wam language cannot do
it when it cannot do it it returns this
you know the same thing but when you say
numerical result it returns true now
what what is the um what is the actual
number let's
say first part uh let's
see okay the first part then
numerical uh wait wait what is the oh
yeah I forgot okay so what we need to do
is so change them to a list of two
things let me show you so
so now you can see it's a list of two
things now we say
first okay that means take the first
element which is this part then
numerical okay so that will give us a
numerical
result this one is got syntax Z so
delete it so shift
n oh okay so you have to to put this in
one line it doesn't
yeah okay so the re so you know one side
is
0.922 yeah interesting
but you need to
know I guess number Theory to understand
why this is significant I don't so
anyway so that's it for that uh
fantastic okay so put back showing
browser so we did
that so let's see
questions s do you write a c and C++
code no I don't I hate those languages
and I don't know anything about them
well I know something about them that's
why I hate them but I don't never coded
them if so do you use any software to
profile yeah I don't know C or C++ next
question
Gabriel I'm stuck with my code don't
don't know what to
do uh don't know what is causing not
desired Behavior okay yeah but I don't
know what's your
code uh zensen hello zensen long time no
see do you use GPT on daily
basis uh yes almost actually not daily
but I use it
often so you know you can see my recent
you know GPT you know I had a lot very
very fantastic okay so and it can also
understand Chinese you know I asked it
how many people in Shanghai and and
zai uh and uh then one of the
interesting thing do women you know I'm
just asking a bunch of weird questions
like when I read Wikipedia do women have
colder body temperature yes okay um and
uh yeah very interesting thing okay chat
gbt and you know one of the amazing
answer I got recently is about
mathematics you know you know one of the
interesting thing is that I asked
it
um
um well so I so I asked so why is this
kind of slow
why is this scrolling kind of
slow yeah so one of the question I ask
is what does sar mean by human animal
that's a phrase I like to use often so I
like to check I like to check if we if
uh chity knows what it what what it mean
or what do I mean indeed it does it says
referring to human as human animals is a
way to emphasize the biological nature
and shared characteristics between
humans and other animals Kali might use
this phrase to highlight the common
commonalties in Behavior instincts and
physiological aspects that humans share
with other members of Animal Kingdom
exactly okay then it goes on you know
the term human animal acknowledges that
humans despite cognitive abilities and
social complexities are fundamentally
biological thing beings subject to
evolutionary physiological and
instinctual influences similar to other
animals
exactly so that is why I use human
animal but in fact I'll just cut cut the
chase okay why I use human animal it's a
pulling a rug out of
chrisal term human being okay human
being because nobody you know if you
look at English nobody say human animal
what do you mean animal you mean a beast
you mean a a a evil immoral person
that's what when people say animal
that's usually what they mean you know
you are not a human being okay so but
the question is what what the [ __ ] is a
being you know when you say being it
implies kind of implies a higher being
it kind of imply God okay so when you
say human beings you know oh this you
know we are human beings so therefore we
should be care about other human beings
and so on and so so
on being what does it mean beings you
know in a sense we humans we like we of
course we are selfish so we heighten our
soul by using by calling you know
addressing us as something else we are
above you know like we are beings like
what what is a
being okay that's a a little bit D
digression um and you know and so
usually the moralist okay the moralist
type of people fake moralist you know
they are moral people but they actually
they do the most evil they are the type
of people that likes to use the human
beings or being polite and you know all
the whole
thing okay I think that's about it today
that's
it
uh that's about it
today why are you trying to fix
something like that uh harmful
uh so
guano says s chat GPT if it knows the S
block oh yeah it does in fact you know
when CH chat GPD came out let me show
you
um it it wrote several P poems about me
okay so go to S search artificial
intelligence okay actually just go to
my. info website you'll see the one of
the top link chck gbt
on okay so apparently it knows me and
knows my website and wrote a poem so
this is
February someone you know as CH gbd s
your name that Rings s a name that Rings
through the horse of the internet things
a pioneer of tech and code his legacy on
endless OD old Odie or whatever
each keystroke he blazed a trail pushing
limits refusing to fail his wisdom
shared for all to see a gift to the word
given freely from Emax to JavaScript
sar's knowledge is vast his passion for
computing clear a master of the craft
without
peer through his writing we all have
grown from newb to expert he's shown a
word beyond what we once new thanks to S
Horizon group and so on but you know the
interesting interesting things about
this poem and a few others there's also
a lme rck is that it actually shows that
gbt knows about my character you know
because I wrote a lot right on the
internet and but also because I'm
controversial you know I don't you know
usually my writing is not like normal
you usually I swear and you know
controversial in you know so and gbt
chat gbt you can tell it knows you know
some actually you'll say directly you
know K is a controversial guy um and
apparently because it knows about me
because you know uh chat
gbt uh let's see where uh social
commentary machine learning social
commentary on AI Mis commentary
uh
um yeah so the Google you know s site in
Google C4 data set for artificial
intelligence training so there's a
website you can you can search for the
Google C4 database apparently my website
is both there so so chat gbt you know
grabbed all my website
stuff
yeah uh and AI is incredible it's uh
incredible can close an aisle I won't
finish uh how do I deal with having to
program 20 24 hours in Java for my
University assignment well if you are in
University you are like uh actually
that's easy I mean it's not like when
you are out in on a job if you don't do
it
you don't have money to live uh in a
university it's kind of like a toy
environment yeah it's still you know you
still worry about your exams you know
passing the grade but compared to real
life uh you know once you have to be on
your own it's much
um
friendly so for JavaScript for Java if
you have to do Java code you want just
get on you know to program 24 hours in
Java for my assignment yeah you just
have to do
it okay I think that's
it cross eyed the paper is C he slightly
crossy
what so what yes I do have slide
crossy I talked about before for example
you can see looking at you with my left
eye and right eye left eye right
eye uh so what is is I try to get it to
trip over itself okay that's it for
today thank you guys donate okay don't
forget to pay
me okay that's it bye guys let's
see
58 okay 1 hour exactly okay bye
guys yeah so tomorrow we're going to
do uh we're going to do the code Advent
of code in wam language and every
day let's see how you know how we go and
join
Discord uh yeah I was so I was talking
about women's websites you know there's
uh
you know this this is so many so
many
uh oh yeah temu ads temu is a Chinese
shopping
site you know attractive women and uh
and this Shir it is just me or idiots
multiply quicker than normal
people okay that's it for
today
bye