hello
guys welcome to another episode ofan
talk show uh we going to do wfam
language coding Advent of code
2024 day
three okay I'm few minutes early so I'm
going to begin if you are here say hi if
you are watching offline skip around and
play at 1.5 speed because I ramble a lot
so event of code wam language day 3 2024
okay let's begin reading the
problem so let's put this here so wolam
language let's make a new
notebook new notebook three launch the
kernel and uh Advent of code number
three
okay
okay so let's see let's just skip right
down to the problem Oh there's no input
there's usually there's a block of input
but there's none here okay so you got to
read it day three mo more at over our
computers are having issues so I have no
idea if we have any Chief historians in
stock you are welcome to check the
warehouse though says the mildly
flustered shopkeeper at the North Pole
too Gan rental shop the historian had
head out to take a look the shop the
shop keeper turns to you any chance you
can see why our computers are having
issues again the computer appears to be
trying to run a program but its memory
your personal input is corrupted all of
the instructions have been jumbled up so
memory is corrupted okay it seems like
the goal of the program is just to
multiply some
numbers that's a goal it does that with
instructions like Mo XY where X and Y
are each one two 3digit numbers okay one
two three digigit numbers more XY okay
that's a uh that's an important part uh
for instance more 4446 multiplies 44 46
to get a result of
2024 similarly multiply that that would
be uh multiply that by that however
because the programs memory has been
corrupted there are also many invalid
characters that should be ignored even
if they look like part of the
multiplication instruction sequences
like more four
star more four comma night ban question
something or more something do nothing
okay so okay so you got to check
basically so you have to check the
syntax that's a input uh okay for
example consider the following section
of corrupt memory so okay so that
seems so we got this
line okay so only the four highest only
only the four highlighted sections are
real multiplication instructions okay so
that's
that and uh do not move that okay
then that okay so that that that's like
four of them adding up the result of
each instruction procedure is
161 okay scan the corrupted memory for
uncorrupted multiplication instructions
what do you get if you add up all of the
results okay so it's some kind of
passing problem it's not exactly pausing
it just well it's called pausing so
let's see so um part one let's begin
wfam language part
one okay x uh variable X input equals to
that okay so what do you want
is so you want to
grab let
[Music]
see
uh yeah okay so this is W from language
you want to grab something like that
let's see what what is the valid
input
uh so let's write out the valid
input so the valid input will contain
the word more for sure okay so let's
highlight it
so you can
see so we can actually just split by
more then needs to be followed
by a
parent parent digit
comma uh then closing parent okay
so so these are the four two4 55
11885 2 455
11885 okay so you just need to extract
uh this so simple this is a regular
expression uh are you sure yeah I'm I'm
I'm I'm I think I'm pretty sure
okay valid ones okay so some comments so
let's begin regular expression okay okay
so you want uh okay regular expression I
can do this in emac Pro python Ruby
JavaScript but I can also do it in wam
but wam I forgot
um wam language has regular expression
in the traditional syntax if you don't
know go to search for cam Language
tutorial and uh you can click on
download it's free uh and and you have
the full tutorial on from the groundup
so we want to go to uh regular
Expressions okay so let's see uh Basics
common print string regular expression
okay so wam language supports a
traditional regular expression syntax
but it also supports its own syntax
called string Expressions which is uh
actually easier to read so so you want
so we want to do regular expression we
want
to pass okay so this is a string right
so yeah let's make it string no wonder
that's why I was wondering why no color
okay so you got a string of uh you want
to pass it so the question is which
function you want uh you want string
cases
okay uh you know if you you can
find you know my tutorial has has um
stream functions and the regular
expression
uh let's see string string functions
string replace regular Expressions
string expression string expression
pattern syntax okay so you got uh all
kind of string functions there but
anyway the the one we want is string
cases okay basically that will
extract the patterns you
want so go to w language
documentation okay the network is slow
am I like
healthy okay something's
wait it should be good
but it's am I good guys hello
GCS so am I am I streaming okay
okay so this is a string cases uh string
and pattern okay so we
want um right so what we want is we want
to in fact we want to
um yeah X so string cases take two input
the first one is a string the second one
is a pattern so the pattern let's just
say
uh let's give it a regular expression
okay and uh so the regular expression
what we want is uh let's
see the regular expression is going to
be
more then a digit digit is um is back
slash D then Plus for one or
more then another digit okay and in fact
you need to capture the digit so okay so
we need to look up the regular
expression syntax there it is that's a
function
um capture okay so D digit is back SLB
slash D okay
so but how do you
capture uh usually it's parent but do
you
require back slash stream Ming the
sequence okay
so yeah well let's look at my own
documentation string
expression say hi say hi okay so uh
string so we uh regular expression okay
insert into string delete sub string uh
what are we doing here we want string
functions we want regular Expressions
okay so let's just go to regular
Expressions so there it is and example
string cases okay uh and uh yeah
so now replace stream by captured
patterns okay we don't want to do that
we want
um okay so we don't I don't have the
documentation for the wolam language
well there there it is
capture Okay so
where is the capture let's maybe we can
just try it okay so that so
actually just runette trial and error
coding okay empty
um well that's because that's a capture
is that right minute
empty no that's not good let's try
something simpler
okay
some thing okay so now regular
expression is just going to be uh digit
sequence of Digit run
it okay we got it so that's digit now if
we if we do
it with a parent would it capture
run
it yes so parentheses capture so now why
is this line not
working
uh digit is uh slash slash per capture
okay
[Music]
so m
l input okay so I don't understand
why is that not working so we got to put
that here run
it empty why is that uh is it because
the back
slash uh I don't I hope it's not like
emac yeah it's like
emac you see this is interesting because
in emac in emac
this when you have a regular expression
regular expression is represented as a
string data type so there is no special
string to represent regular
expression such as in Pearl in
JavaScript in in Python even so in these
languages Pearl JavaScript python they
have a normal string then they have a
string for regular
expression so that you don't have to
have like back slash back slash
toothpick syndrome this is called but in
wam language and emac this wam language
is a lisp so including scheme lisp and
common lisp they don't have like two
strings one for regular expression they
only have one string data type so in
this one string data type the back slash
is escape so when you want a backs slash
in a regular expression you you have to
have two back slash so this two back
slash there represent one back slash and
that you know then you have parent which
is to escape the parent because
otherwise parenthesis means capture okay
so we want a literal left parenthesis
here then we want a capture we want
capture the D
here and we want also capture the D here
okay so let's do
it okay it Returns the whole thing uh
how how can I just return the
captures
um let's not let's let's not let's just
get it to work
okay okay so here is the output so far
so good so and okay so you know let's
just make it work X2 equals to that then
all we have to do is just
um just uh let's you know do more
passing one more passing again
so so you just get all numbers
okay something like
X3 then here is X2 then all you want is
just numbers
okay let's see what it get you need to
remove the semicolon because because
semicolon suppresses the outputs okay so
you got that then you just turn that
into
a uh two
expression okay that
will that will um that is like string
two number in other languages okay so
you got a real list of numbers okay then
you just um then you all you have to to
do is just uh multiply and sum okay
so uh
times you want to map the times
function so that's slash add is a
shortcut for map so you map the time
function to
X3 uh
let's
[Music]
see it's test no I don't think
that's no that's not so you want to
actually you want to
um
okay let me show you
trick you know trick things like that
you you would you you wouldn't
understand okay you know then that's it
then just
um total that okay
rette 161 is that the correct
answer answer for toy
input so is that correct let's check
161 correct correct correct in one shot
fantastic what's going
on okay so here's our solution let's
remove the testing code so it
um should I well
test test run okay so this is a test run
and now we going to do a real code here
so real code we don't we don't need all
this uh comment so we can uh simplify it
much so this is
X2 X2 occur there
well okay let's leave
it okay and this line you can the the
more formal way to write it is let me
show uh let me show you okay so the more
formal way to write it is map so map
X3 and map a function and this function
is going to be
times um in fact
apply apply times to the X so this is
actually the same you know so this line
and this line is the same uh we can run
it and
see uh okay you can you have to remove
that 161 you
see correct
okay okay
okay so that's that
um so that's the day one solution okay
uh oh yeah so you need to get your own
input showing browser so today this is
our code uh my own input get your
personal input okay big humongous
humongus
scrap okay
so let's save that so this is my Advent
of code for 2024 index page we did
yesterday's and uh uh so let's go to
advance so I have it here new save XXX
okay and go to diet and rename this
to Adent of code day
three okay open it
oh that's uh okay so you know some lines
are big wait okay they they also include
uh line
returns interesting okay so anyway get
it close close
close
um yeah so that's today so we're going
to continue do this so we need to now
this is uh URL actually this is a
file
uh
read read string okay read
string read
string input equals to read string this
this string open it then okay that's
good so we read the string then do the
same before is that is right so let's
think about should be but let's look at
the so this is actually your problem
testing your regular expression
skills there it
is okay we remember we have a
um we have a
day two I mean part two problem so let's
quickly get this done submit
yeah that's the right answer of course
let's continue to part two okay part two
can you see
it no actually you
uh okay
so fantastic
okay showing browser that's our code
today there so let's get on to part two
break
drink am I doing
good okay part two
you scan through the corrupted memory
you notice that some of the conditional
statements are also still intact if you
handle some of the uncorrupted
conditional statements in a program you
might be able to get an even more
accurate
result okay there are two new
instructions you need to handle the
do the do parenthesis instruction
enables enables future multiplication
instructions the don't instruction
disables future multiplication
instructions only the most recent do or
don't instructions
apply so at the beginning of the program
multiplication instructions are enabled
for example okay for example that
one uh for
example okay here
it
says so you got a multiplication there
then you got a don't so that means
disable that
one okay but
then when you have a don't it
disables uh Future multip Okay it
disable them all until you reach your do
something like
that so this corruptive memory is
similar to the example from before but
this time the multiplication 55 and
118 instructions are disabled okay there
because there is a don't instruction
before them okay once you see a don't it
disable all
until you reach a
do the other multip multiplication
instructions function
normally including the one at the end
that gets re-enabled by two okay this
time the sum of the result is 48
okay okay so when you see a don't when
you see a
don't uh
okay the the the part one is easy
trivial but the part
two is do and don't so yeah
am I going to code it yes I suppose so
let's do it
then where is it okay
so copy
it part two okay
so so actually you have wait you have a
[Music]
new test input
okay
copy now I believe this one is different
from you see you want to highlight
don't uh let's see highlight do
wait okay and
don't okay so we got don't and do
highlight
it okay and uh then if we open this
file let's do the highlighting tool
okay so it kind of look like
that each line is kind of
long
then also highlight don't by
Pink okay
okay so
[Music]
now yeah I forgot lost of my color
anyway okay
so so what you can do is you split
you want to split for each
line wait are they are they line based
or is this just one whole single line
it's supposed to be one whole single
line because it matters because let's
say you have a line and the last item is
don't then you have a next line do you
you know do you consider starting a
fresh or is it still
don't so so the question is do you
consider the input the whole as one
single
blob or is I mean or in other words does
the don't
continue to the next
line so does it say the don't
instructions disable further
multiplication instruction so they
didn't mention anything about lines
so I suppose you can consider it as one
single huge
line okay so what about uh what is your
approach well we can so we can read the
whole
thing so this is a new uh this is a new
input
okay so this is a new
input and uh the input is
different the to input is different but
the user input is still the same uh so
you can read the whole thing and uh you
can split
you can
split
by by a regular expression
okay uh
what not
input pattern okay
okay so we need to think about this
actually
let's show
space so whenever you see I don't so
let's see let's see highlight do
so does it continue over the line you
see here is
important don't and the do
okay okay let's let's just do it
okay okay split stream
regular expression and we have
don't and we have vertical bar or
do okay so now so you need slash back
slash back slash to represent a literal
parenthesis so you split by that and and
uh and
uh okay
so the answer for to input is
48 okay so let's
okay so let's see what we
get okay
so this is a huge
stream okay this is how
to like
debug so you you got don't and do okay
so you got a bunch of don't and do okay
so
split so
anything between don't and do you can
kind of remove does that work does that
does the logic does that logic work so
whenever you see text between don't and
do you can just remove it then just do
the normal one like the part one I think
so
yep so here but over here you need to
also need
uh uh let's let's test okay so you know
whenever you have issue you can just say
something test uh TT
XX so we want grab XX or
TT okay run this
line that didn't
work
uh so the old sign is special no that
didn't work
um oh wait so well
uh let's say
T9
h8 M okay let let's do this AB b c a b b
CC so eight and nine so we want to split
by either number eight or number nine
okay and
it that worked okay so that means the
the vertical bar is a alternative syntax
you don't need back slash okay so we got
that figured out so that means we don't
need that so okay so let's run let's put
it
here and
uh so we take the input and regular
expression and uh so don't don't let's
make sure this
don't stupid
don't yeah let's just R
it okay so we
got uh it's annoying because the
original input already have Lo L breaks
so let's
let's okay let's do some uh string
replacement okay regular Expressions
let's go to string functions string
functions each string length join string
uh we want
to delete substring
not byad character okay so we want
stream
delete
okay so stre string delete string and
pattern okay so the string is X input
and the pattern is going to be just
um
that okay
it so now this should be one giant
single line that's what we want
okay so this will be named
X2 equals true okay one joint single
line
then then so so this is for testing code
yeah let's put the test code there
so so then we do this okay then
uh okay run
it now each line we'll start with
a do or don't let's
see okay so
well well it's hard to read there so
let's try the wolam language Notepad
oh that's right when you remove that you
you also remove the do and
[Music]
don't let's do something more okay
so X2 equals to string delete
string delete can take a list to do
multiple
delions and uh let's do some stream
replays because the do and don't is kind
of uh complicated
so uh string dream string drop string
get substring convert format stream
match stream replace okay stream replace
parts
y okay so we here we want the string is
X input we want uh what is
it replace string by position range
no uh
oh yeah so stream replace not not part
so string replace which is replaced by
pattern
okay copy
that okay some dogs X
input then we got uh you can
then you need a regular expression okay
so let's
see
okay regular
expression uh first of all let's just
replace replace this empty
line first of all do that then we want
extra
replacement
then
[Music]
don't replace by
something like that okay
okay
so search for
nnn doesn't occur search for NN does not
occur search for y y y does not occur
that's good
so so if we do that then
yeah
sure for
okay let's look up the documentation for
string
split because string split
will because we need to keep the don't
yeah so there it
is fantastic okay so we got a new uh
this power of wol language so instead of
two
here uh the second part is going to be a
list okay then the list is going to be
one two two items the first item we
don't even need regular the expression
okay so the first item is just don't
it's uh
simple okay the second part is just
do okay so you got to list so this is
much
simpler and
then then when you replace you actually
want to turn it just no no no okay
uh then here also
replace yeah yeah yeah
okay so there it is simple so we don't
need
that yeah so and we don't need we don't
need this
elaborate uh
replacement
either
so it's just that that that that
okay remove that let's put it back
that's the backup
code
okay so now string replace replace the
new line by empty make it one single
line then this you don't also you don't
need that
neither then just um
okay then do
it okay so now every time you see yes
yes
yes oh okay
so yes yes yes becomes a new entry
okay so no no
no so basically you want to
remove so basically the problem
becomes if you have a
list let's say one two
three um let's say whenever you have a
no for whatever
number and uh
yes whatever number so when you have a
list like
that you want to remove
any sequence that's followed by no to
yes can you do that yes
yeah okay
so well that can be easily done by
pattern
matching so we can
say X3
replace or
X3 a
pattern anything
n this is going to this is going to this
is not
efficient
uh maybe we stick with strings okay
actually do the stream replace
okay some kind of do the stream replace
okay stream replace also take a list as
a second argument
yes so
you the second argument is going to be
uh oh
God okay this is
not no that doesn't work
neither
how am I
doing two people
watching okay
so okay work on this
problem yeah let's give me some water
okay
so split is a good solution okay so but
um
when you
split you get the you get a situation
like that and
uh maybe maybe we just do with the p
pattern matching okay
zero or more and zero or more
and and how do
you so this is the thing
okay parti
okay I kind of know what I want but uh
the issue is how do you do
this now let's think about string if you
do it
[Music]
string you got the nasty issue of
regular expression
because you want a don't you want all
characters after the don't and delete
them you want any character after the
don't then delete them but the problem
is if you use regular expression
yeah so the problem is very simple you
just use regular expression and you want
to remove anything between don't and
do that's right you just remove anything
between don't and
do okay and but to do that you have
to yeah you can do that you can just you
know use a DOT Plus
yeah you can do that I
think yeah maybe it's just a simple
regular expression
thing for
maybe so whenever you see that just
remove
it
okay you know so this expression
just simply remove this St and don't
crap okay so
just
there stream
replace and anytime you see don't
followed by one or
more
maximum match and until you see your
do just replace it run
it okay so search for
do you still have do of course wait but
you still have done
because then you
uh
what okay so this needs to be
X2 this needs to be X3 run
it should be one single line that's
right oh now it's much simpler let's see
highlight don't
yellow no one
occurence
highlight two
pink okay then all you have to do so you
removed all the between don't and do
but uh you need one last
two yeah let's just P one last
two what what is the String join string
or P string functions convert format
stream
match uh
string string
replace okay string functions string
Escape stream functions length join
string
join yeah we can do
that string join that
then just add a do
okay that's right then you
just then you just um
then you just do
this run
it okay that's the output now highlight
let's highlight
um copy let's highlight
two
yellow let's highlight don't pink
there it is so now you just do as before
so now you just do um the same solution
we did
before like part
one copy okay I believe close that I
believe that's it
so wait so let's go clean up a little
bit so this is going to be the new input
um
let's clean up
here what
let's see part one function
yeah
there okay I think that's
it so we got Y
2 then
Y3 you know the X2 X3 is just same as
before then we got X3 then yeah I think
that's
it okay shall we run a
code let's first of all the
um for 48 I
think
incorrect yeah it should be 48 but we
got
eight
so that's
incorrect so let's remember remove don't
to
do don't to do
so remove don't to
do remove don't to do so what is this so
you should be 24
A5 24 A5 so so it's
48 uh why are we getting
eight so we got two four for sure
probably but we we don't have
A5 okay so time to check what is the
what is
X2 okay now what is
the what is the Y3
okay so something got cut
off the A5 got cut off why s
oh because yeah so your algorithm is
wrong so I mean because of because of
the special Edge
case because of that
so you don't
uh oh yeah so that is a tricky part
that's that's the design of this problem
tricky
part it's the about the edge cas is off
by one problem so
basically so you want to remove all the
don't between don't and
do okay so once you do
that you might also have some
don'ts you might also have some don't
that does not have two
at the
end so let's not append for example if
we
don't
don't do that okay
so run
it 48 you see
you see
so but that
means but it won't work when you
have uh you see that's tricky because
the example doesn't show this
issue it won't work if you
have actually it may work let's just run
it run it okay let's just run it on the
personal problem personal input
because the Advent of
code because if you think too much it's
going to punish you okay so let's try
this let's
just try without being super careful you
see imagine this is a nuke button if you
you know you cannot just let's try out
any error like the most programmer
idiots because if you push the button
the answer is incorrect somebody died
you know suppose this is m mission
things like that so I mean there's
different type of programming is
different levels of class of seriousness
you know how bug can be
tolerated for most industrial
programming like the web programming the
web idiots the JavaScript or the python
it doesn't matter you know you can just
try try it uh but for other issues you
know designing or engine or rocket then
you really have to be careful but let's
just try it that's not the right answer
you
see yeah I
know so when you remove so when you you
see when you remove the in between don't
and do what happens is that you may have
a last sequence of
don't that do not come with a do okay
okay so so what you want to do is over
here then you add
it you know then you add the
DU let's just say that you know this is
not functional programming because you
are overwriting the value I don't like
that but but you know let's just get it
to
run so once you remove
that then you add the
do then you run this again actually
idiotic
this you see this is this is not
functional programming you don't want
that yeah but let's just run
it okay did I get the same so I think
that's what I get
before no it's TR
again
uh what I'm not
sure toy input is still correct okay but
let's just try it
one65
one65 899 that's the same answer
no h
very close very close
let's see what is
Y3 2 485 that's
right uh 2
485 but
uh but let's see if we use
that then here's see output copy it new
buffer um close it reopen it
text highlight the do and
don't you see we got the don't there
so what does it
say the don't we should
remove no no no so
okay yeah the problem yeah the problem
is H you see it's a regular expression
because
this this plus dot
plus it may cover actually many
dos yeah the regular expression
you I don't think you can do
that oh yeah you can say minimal match
but we added a do why didn't we delete
it I don't understand we added a two
here
and so there's two
issues one is that you need a
minimal minimal
match so normally that would
be would be a question
mark
in in normal regular expression s tax
okay
uh yeah the short is consistent stream
that match
so
actually this is shouldn't be should be
a zero or more not
plus very tricky
and
uh zero little more
don't so there is one don't there search
for
two there is
[Music]
two
several but but for don't there is just
one
don't okay so there's one
don't occurs there and there is no to w
after
that okay so you need to remove
that
so so what you can do
is don't append because append is sloppy
you can
just one or more more maximum to the end
of line which is dollar sign okay dollar
sign means the end of string or line
okay yeah so if we do
that
evaluate okay here's the output copy new
paste search for
don't no no occurrence search for
two
okay uh
but but why is
that you see before you got how
many
2,000 uh 10,000 characters
okay but with the don't appear at the
bottom don't how select
one okay but if
you to replace that oh wait this is X ah
idiotic this should be X3 that's why
it's wrong
that's why got a code error all
this
time search for don't okay not to be
found
now
10,600 characters search for
do there's a lot okay that's expected
but search for don't there is none okay
that's that's so that is good
that is good then we just check the
total okay run
it okay now that's the answer hopefully
that is the
answer this should be the
answer do
it that is the right answer hello guys
solution correct so so here is the
solution for part
two fantastic uh that's 80
minutes
yeah okay thank you guys for watching
good H good
exercise nightberry he thank
you yeah that's it for today
so all this
while we didn't make any major mistake
the mistake we made is just syntax
errors so we forgot about you know the
regular expression well I mean regular
expression is Tricky by itself very
fairly tricky so we forgot to use
the
um you know zero or more instead of one
or more we should have zero or more in
well actually I don't know if the
matters but anyway the other big thing
is that
we you know we didn't delete the last
don't to the end but I mean the major
mistake is that we are using the our
variable was wrong you know this uh Y2
and Y3 we supposed to update the Y3 not
using Y2 so that was the mistake but
anyway here the code Here's the final
solution and it can be simplified a lot
for example this
um this this two lines can be combined
to one single string replace in fact all
these
three can be done in one shot actually
let's try it shall
we so all you have to do is change that
into a list so instead of three calls
you just you have list of three items
okay so that's one item that's a second
item and that's the third
item okay I
believe uh wait uh why so you don't so
you don't need
um we up so much so this is
just Y3
directly I think that work so
run
it uh
no uh because yeah because they are not
done sequentially so
anyway yeah but still and do and do and
do and do and do and do and do and do
yeah let's run
it SE you can combine these three lines
into one but anyway that's it for today
thank you guys for watching put it back
color it showing
browser and there we have it today's
code
bye oh woof we got a wolf here
nightberry a wolf head