Hello. Hello everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Sun Talk Show. We are
going to call JavaScript just like it
two days ago or uh last week. JavaScript
in depth. Okay, let me introduce my
keyboards. Ultimate hacking keyboard
UHK80.
Nulia track ball and that's Logitech
mouse Logitech 502.
This is Nia uh Nulia something 507 I
think. 505
model name 505.
Fantastic. That's my favorite track
board. And here is the SWA board. SV A L
B O A R D. Okay. Magnetic key switches.
And press SWA board. SV A L B O A R D.
So you can search them. I have video
reviews on my YouTube. Okay. So let's
switch to my normal screen and so you
can So let's uh begin coding. So I'm
just going to code. So let's switch to
my normal screen. Now, if you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5 speed
minimum. If you are watching this live,
say hi. Okay, say hi here. Love to see
your comments.
Okay, so we're going to uh do JavaScript
coding. So, uh uh so here's my website,
kali.info. x ah.info.
Uh and uh talk show. So, today's talk
show. So uh I introduce you uh
JavaScript in-depth that's the most
in-depth easy to understand tutorial on
JavaScript. Okay, there are about 700
pages. Okay, JavaScript in-depth uh and
let's go back. So then then you got
JavaScript uh style guide which we did
live two or three days ago. Uh and so
unic code search uh we was demonstrating
that uh yesterday. So we don't need that
link. So let's let's start to code.
Okay. So actually let me move this here.
Can you hear me? Okay.
My microphone. Okay. So talk uh search
for unic code. Uh we don't need to show
the unic code search. Okay. So ultimate
hacking keyboard that is my uh keyboard.
So there is video reviews one hour uh
and textual review and with lots of high
quality photograph in every detail of
this keyboard. Uh one of my favorite but
it's quite expensive. Okay. Ultimate
hacking keyboard UHK80.
And uh if you don't know I have a
keyboard blog where there are about like
there are over a thousand articles on
all sort of things you want to know
about keyboards especially ergonomic
keyboards. Okay. And uh I particularly
like to shout out to Glove 80.
Fantastic. Okay. I've been using them
live for like three years in the past
three years. Uh and 360 also pretty
good. Okay. And uh Kinesis Advantage 2,
I've been live blogging it uh I've been
using it for almost 10 years and uh on
live stream in the for like two years.
Okay. And uh expose I also highly
recommend. So search for keyboard uh
blog you will find it. So there's a
blog, there is a do-ityourself
keyboards. There is uh normal kind of
keyboard or kind of fancy keyboard.
There is pen input which I'm right now
using this one uh with that one is
Huyang H60
I mean H640P
drawing tablet very cheap. Okay.
So that's what I'm using. Fantastic. And
uh okay that's enough about keyboard
introduction. So just search my for my
uh website
let's show okay so uh and nia track ball
so you can see all sort of uh so this is
nia track ball I'm using here and uh can
you
okay so let's see okay now so now you
can see and you click on track ball so
you can see all sort of uh track ball
reviews okay there are few hundred of
them and also track wall history. Uh so
let's magnify
uh old space s then give them some room
to show extra row. Okay.
So all track balls and then you can go
to track ball history. Then you got like
you know 1,000 small track balls.
And one more thing I want to show you is
the keyboard layout. So that's another
obsessive topic among certain groups of
nerds.
So there's laptop keyboard layouts very
interesting uh very interesting detail.
For example, Microsoft started to remove
the staggering. So on Microsoft laptop
keyboard the stagger is uh smaller than
the normal the typical you know stagger
like the slant of the vertical column of
keys less. Okay. And also Chromebook
also has a major revolution because they
removed the caps lock key and they
removed the old the like the window key.
So you so they make it made it simpler
and basically they remove the function
keys like do not include the function
keywords.
Okay. So so that you know there are some
evolutions um of laptop keyboards and
one thing I wanted to mention so there
is a keyboard history. One thing I want
to mention is the keyboard layout. Okay.
So uh actually so many things I want to
uh keyboard layout. So I'm using
so you got quarti which is normal for
everyone then you got vorac coac then
you got
newer ones like like uh homemac a
grammar canary you know so keyboard
layout and another popular topic is key
uh is about uh mechanical key switches
okay so you can find that by key
switches so There's like tens of
articles on everything you want to know
about key keyboard key switches.
Okay, so that's my introduction to my
keyboard blog. There are like a thousand
pages.
So you can see there's uh 1,400
pages on keyboards and everything about
keyboard layout, mouse. Okay, so but now
now Okay. So now let's begin. Can we
like begin coding JavaScript? Let's see.
Okay, let's start. Okay, I'm using Emacs
as you know, of course, the most
advanced powerful text editor. And as I
type the all the commands, course you
can see on the ping window, you see. And
the keystroke on the left, I'm using a
vorac keyboard layout, which I was going
to show you. Vora keyboard layout. If
you don't know what that is, you go to
uh saw keyboard blog, then you go to
keyboard layout. There it is. Then you
there's a ergonomic keyboard layout. I
am using Vorac. You can see the circles
are frequency of the letter occurrence.
So normally on quarti you have to move
your fingers all over. But if you use
Vorac or COMAC or any of the other
ergonomic keyboard layout, it's more
efficient. So I'm using Vorax. So you
can see so what whenever what I what
whenever I type something in Emacs you
see the keystrokes are shown on the left
on the pink window. Okay. So okay let's
let's start to code JavaScript. Okay for
those of you JavaScript advanced this is
uh actually this is advanced JavaScript.
Hello infformat informaticist
you should do zero ad mods people would
like it.
Uh zero ad mods. What What does that
mean? Z A I I know what's a home mode,
but what is zero AD mode?
So why not Linux? Oh god, are you
trolling? Because that's, you know, I've
been answering that question a thousand
times
in the past five years of my live
stream. So just go to YouTube s my name
search for Linux or or Unix you will
find quite a few videos one hour long my
rant about that topic Linux or which
operating system is better should you
use Linux or Mac or Windows or uh or or
the you know the lots of like which DRO
you know that kind of Linux questions
like are you trolling are you are you
saying that because you seeing people
like trying to ask me that question. So,
uh he thinks Linux Linux is a scam to
rip off developers getting them to work
for free. No, that's not exactly that's
not what I think. That's and I don't and
I don't think that's true. Anyway, I'm
not going to talk about Linux today. So,
love co Mac. Okay. So, let's do
JavaScript. So, this is advanced
JavaScript. So every hour or every hour
also I I have alarm clock set up. So
every hour I get up and walk back and
forth to and fro and take notes on my
iPad. I read my own uh tutorials because
I have like uh 10,000
pages on mathematics and programming
languages written over the past 25
years. So uh so I update them often. So
let's go to JavaScript in depth. So but
I need to update them, you know,
sometimes improve it. So every every
hour or two I walk I walk back and forth
and take notes. And these are things
that I need to change. Okay. So let's uh
work on them. So let me just work on
them. As I work on them, I will give you
guys some tips what I'm doing and about
the technical details about JavaScript.
Okay. So that is the uh introduction to
what I'm we are doing in in this video.
Okay. So let's begin.
So do not uh dot notation associivity.
So that there is a interesting question.
Okay. So let's go to Okay. So let me
just start to work on okay let me show
you
uh uh wait.
Okay. Copy the link. And uh so
uh so let's paste the link here and
search for that. Okay, new. Good. So
there's an interesting question. Now
look at this. Okay, very interesting. If
you say X.X.Z,
does that mean X doy I mean if you have
X doy.z,
does that mean X doy happens first or X
do.Z happen first? You know if x do.z
returns a value then x dot that that key
returns another value. So so the
question is look at the quiz you know
which one it returns first. Okay that is
the question about this these notes.
Okay now what I'm saying to myself is
that I need to add link to this page
notation associivity right or left very
interesting JavaScript test yourself.
Okay, if you are a JavaScript coder,
look at the screen. Test your knowledge.
But but I'm going to tell you the answer
kind of. Okay, so if you go here,
actually, I'm not going to tell you the
answer. Okay, so anyway, this this I
just wanted to for myself. I wanted to
to make a link to this page from the
page about property dot notation versus
bracket notation. We'll talk about that
later. Okay, so this one is done.
delete. So number is none. Okay. So
there's a bunch of things I like to do.
So let's see. Showing browser. So close
back. Close. Showing browser. So this uh
let's go to the top section. This is my
webdev block. Okay. Associivity.
So we did that one. And uh so is none.
Okay. So search for none. So copy path
close paste link linky make a list show
in browser. So we got a is nan. So on
the nan page. So so JavaScript got a nan
value. Nan is a literal value. Literal
means you can just type it. Okay you can
type it. So shift uh you know shift
control I to start the browser console
and you can just type n a n and uh
n
what why can't I type anything
okay so n a n does it okay none okay so
you should completion
so you if you enter that so that's a
literal value So that nan which stand
for not a number and that value this
value is part of is belong to the type
number just like one 1.2 or three. So
all these are number values type number.
Okay. So nan is one of the one of the
number. Okay. And this number means not
a number. Okay. So this value typically
is returned when you have division by
zero like one divide by uh one divi
divided by zero sometimes that returns
infinity I forgot which one. Okay. So,
so nine is one of the value.
So, you can uh what I want to do is uh
so actually I need to do this quickly
because there are so many. So, all these
pages special literals. Okay. All these
are special literal values. I want to
change the um
the console log to console uh assert.
Okay. So, let's open the name page and
uh search for topic. So this all these
topics show in browser. So you can see
all these topics. Now press a key. Press
all the links are extracted. Now press
the key to close it. Now go down here.
Paste it. So the here's all the links.
Now linkify them all. Okay. So it's now
all link. Now make them into a list. Now
go to the top. Now we don't need the
nan. So actually um did the nan but go
to the nan page show in browser and now
go back and uh update the date. Search
for log pop this out. So we got this
code evaluate it. So it says true.
That's because we are doing uh
console.log.
Now change that to console.assert assert
which means it will print only if the
value is not true. Okay, if it's true
that means it's okay. Don't print
anything. So console log assert run it.
So now it doesn't print anything. That's
what we want. So we are replacing
console.log by console.assert
because this way is more clear on what's
the intention of the code. We are just
saying that this should return true. If
it returns true then don't do anything.
Everything is good. If it's return is
not true then actually print. So if you
say for example uh so if you change to
something let's say 33 then run it it
will say assertion failed. You see
so okay. Okay. So we want to clarify. So
convert a string to number uh xx
constant convert string if arc does not
make sense result is nan.
So this is this result is actually none.
Okay. So
yeah.
So so that makes it clear. Okay. Run it.
Fantastic. Put it back. Syntax color
showing browser. So we made a change.
Okay. Uh
so so we want to make this console log
to console assert on all these
navigation box pages. Now all these
articles are related to special literal
meaning that like a value literal a
literal expression literal means you can
type that value directly directly in the
programming language such as true and
false in JavaScript and undefined is
also a literal value undefined you can
just type it
you know literally it's a value so
that's that's what this literal special
uh literal values are and these are
special ones. You got undefined, you got
new, you got um so undefined in general
in JavaScript is just anything
uh if you access a array
you know let's say you have array one
two three uh but you access array item
number you know 100th it doesn't exist
that will return undefined instead of
error in many programming languages it
will return uh error it will say index
out of bound but in JavaScript it it
doesn't generate error it just return
undefined. Okay. So lots of like anytime
you access non-existent
index to a array or out of outbound out
you know also known as out of bound
array or if you access a key in a
property that doesn't exist the key
doesn't exist it or return undefined or
when a function uh when a function
doesn't have a return value uh return
statement it return undefined. Okay. So
you can see the full detail like is
explained on this page. What what is
undefined? Okay. Type of undefined which
undefined the value literal value
undefined. It's a literal value meaning
you can type it directly and the type of
this value belong to a special type
called undefined. The only type of that
value is undefined. So that's so that's
that. Okay. And then purpose of
undefined you know variable doesn't have
a value that's uh return undefined
nonexistent property accessing array
element that doesn't exist you know when
function argument is not given uh the
the parameter is undefined. Okay the you
know the yeah the parameter received the
is undefined or the function return
value is not is not uh defined. So, so
there are so then examples showing them.
Okay.
Does that make sense?
Uh
0 AD is a video game like 100% of the
game logic is in JavaScript. Oh, Z
really. So, uh let's see. 0 A D
0 A free opensource game of Asian
something
uh a realtime strategy video game under
the de development by wild wild fire
games. It is a historical war and e
economy game focusing on the years
between 500 BC before Christ and 1 BC
before Christ Jesus Christ. Okay, that's
what BC means. And they are trying to
change it to BCE
by the way a bit digression. Okay, so
you see so 080 okay is real time G. So
what is this JavaScript and C++? Okay.
Uh, so what are you saying? I should
What?
Oh god,
I might have missed it. But is your
keyboard configured for quart?
It's Vorac. I was talking about Borak.
Vorac.
So 080 is a video game. Like 100% of
game logic is JavaScript. Okay, that's
interesting. So, uh, free and open
source composed entirely of free
software and okay. So, but um
Oh, that's interesting though. It's and
uh so
h
began in 2001. Wow, that's ancient.
Okay, so I we'll check it out later.
Okay.
So I'm going to talk show. Okay. So we
uh we digressed you know we haven't
started to do our thing yet. So this is
going to take a long time. So anyway
today's talk show we added the link
about the zero ad. Okay. And uh I fed
your website into claw code and created
an agent that codes like you. How is it?
So I'm mostly a functional programmer
and uh my code is typically extremely
functional and uh kind of clean. So
so how how does the cloud come out?
Is it impressive? You know I don't trust
AI. I you know AI is very smart today.
You can ask it lots of technical
questions about programming even about
esoteric topics. It will give you right
the right answer. For example, I know
about JavaScript
and I do you know sometimes I have
questions you can ask uh the AI AI will
come out correctly. Okay, even esoteric
JavaScript questions. But but when you
ask it to code
unless it's like a toy problem like how
do you generate an array you know you
know but so for toy pro problems often
it'll work like how do you create a
array or how do you do something but for
something like a project that when that
when it's a little a little bit involved
usually it just come out wrong the code
won't run or And it will be elaborate
like you hear sorry you generate entire
game or changed refactored all your
files you know tens of files 100 files
it all looks nice but it doesn't run
it's like just one up So
that is my that's what I heard and as
far as my experience goes that's also
true. When you when you when it gets
slightly complicated it's not going to
work. Okay.
So I hear a lot of people talk about
claude. I never used it so I don't know
anything about claude. The only
I use AI a lot like tremendously. In
fact I think you it's beneficial to
force yourself to talk to AI. So like on
Twitter for example on Twitter every
time you talk to you know whatever you
do on Twitter you know you you browse
you know you see posts right you see
posts one after another about all sort
of things about programming about
politics about dating about history
about you know anything
vast majority of it is just okay it
just like it it it it um
trampit your brain it it just destroys
your brain okay So everything, anything
you see. So make it a habit. Here's what
I want to tell you guys about AI. Any
topic on anything, okay? Like if you are
on Twitter, I don't know if you are,
maybe you are not, that's a good thing.
But you, but there's a lot of other
social networks or or you know, but
basically here's the thing. Anytime, try
this. Anytime you hear another person
may be online especially online or even
your friend or your family anytime you a
person
you know are saying something about
something you go ask AI about it. Okay,
like just keep like write write this
down and and and check you know today
whenever whoever you talk to whatever
what is the topic ask AI about it do
this every day you'll be surprised
you'll be surprised what kind of things
you you'll find out okay because you
know first first of all on social media
such as Twitter 90% of the post is just
okay and especially those because
if it's not it it won't spread.
Okay, that's because algorithm the
algorithm will only spread things that
that are dramatic, clickbait, anger or
fake news or blatant, you know, claim,
you know, like discovery or some
something. They only make those popular
or girls, tits and ass or whatever,
okay? Or or violence. Okay. So
by by by by the nature of the algorithm
because only those because human we have
you know by evolution we we simply pay
attention to things that is more
dramatic because that
uh more relates to danger. Okay. So
anyway
so anything on Twitter 90% is just
But even besides Twitter, even when you
talk to average normal people, your
friends, your co-workers, you know, the
human brain, the humans knowledge of
things, it's like minimal. It's like you
it's like pitiful. Okay, you can kind of
think of it. It's like pity pitiful. And
today we have AI, you know, when when
you talk to AI, the AI knows not 10
times more than you, not hundred times,
not a thousand times. It's like it's
like the AI knows like not even a
million times. It knows things that you
that it is incomprehensible to you.
Okay, that's what I'm saying. So today,
why am I saying this? Because you you if
if you are on Twitter or or other online
social media like Reddit or whatever,
you [snorts] will hear people like
that's today's reaction. they will say
oh don't you know I stop interacting
with anyone who uh you know do anything
with AI AI slob you know they their
opinion is that you should never talk to
AI that that's idiotic okay it's not
just it's their reaction those people
who say that they they are just they are
like they are like the brainless they
are they are a movement with the flaw
you know they are like the brainless
kind of you every every era you have
this you know it's common you they are
just brainless people they just pass on
okay that's a common opinion when you
talk to especially among programmers you
know oh I I you know I I I you know I
dislike anyone who talk to AI you
shouldn't use AI those are idiots okay
I'm telling telling you guys this
special interesting story so not just
you in fact you
force yourself to ask AI questions.
Okay.
Now, of course, there are lots of you
need to pay attention about the uh
truthfulness of AI answers. You so you
cannot trust AI, of course, but that's
but that you know that's that's also
important. Um but that um that gets you
into
basically that get that is not um that
is a bit more complex. It's it's like
who can you trust like when you talk to
a person can you trust that person and
what kind of things can you trust that
person for example I'm talking about
programming I'm talking about right now
AI or I'm talking about JavaScript
coding right can you trust me how do you
know how can I you know how do I know
you know I my advice my tips about
JavaScript is good so that's about
JavaScript that's about me but what
about other things about lifestyle about
what books to read about what you know
what to do about dating about your
life's plan who can you trust so that's
a broader question about
you know about AI or about person so
that's the so in fact so if you think of
this way then you can kind of get idea
when can you trust AI just like a person
you know you you when you when you have
when you think about like the topic What
is the topic? Who can you trust? You
apply that to the person whoever you
talk to. It may be your be your family,
your teacher or your friends or whoever
online random people or it could be a
machine. You can just think of it this
way. Then you your like immediately
realize what kind of things from what
source you can trust. Okay.
So anyway, that's a huge digression
about AI. Are we are we going to go back
to code JavaScript because because now
we already talked for
30 minutes about like AI stuff.
Um
so let's see AI have lots of errors also
you need to learn how to check
information exactly and what's subject
subjective or not. Exactly. So very
impressive um interesting. Okay. So
agent code very functional and
inspirational today agent coded abus
fibon nasi. Oh really?
Oops.
Okay. So
fibonasi that's some next level stuff
like freaking quantum. Fibonacci is
Fibonacci is the most elementary coding
problem.
But one day AI will start recommending
their paying sponsors. That's true. You
see,
so I've been, you know, I just
recommended you like you guys to
interact with AI. But of course, there's
another aspect.
AI is this massive brainwashing machine.
Okay, it's on on road to become
basically they are the most powerful
brainwashing machine. they the
especially the nasty huge mega
corporations like Google, Facebook uh
and the deep state you know tied with
USA government
this it's a very extremely nasty okay
because just just like you know imagine
uh Google search engine you know before
we had AI three years ago you know
before the chat GPT the chat bots AI
bots became popular but we have uh
Google web search right and Facebook
this massive amount of censorship
brainwashing
okay going on including controlling you
know controlling the USA election okay
we are starting to get into into
politics so massive and and and and
actually directly why all this misery
why do they lie well actually it
involves
ultimately it involves some for
killing people. Okay, that's actually
what it traces to. And why do they do
that? Because money. So they want to
make more money someone. Okay, so that's
so these corporations, you know, USA and
uh and and elsewhere.
So and AI, you know, since three years
ago, Chad GPT and AI, you know, um
became very powerful. So AI is now
taking over uh Google web search like
today very you know fewer you know web
search is basically replaced by AI now
right so Google Facebook they have very
powerful AI and also the one I use is
from Elamusk guac okay I use squawk the
the most and sometimes I you use also
brave I recommend brave browser okay for
example if you search anything
search my name Brave browser and you can
ask you know ask AI brave has a AI
called Leo Braves you know AI is called
Leo is a self-taught programmer
something something okay so all these AI
you know AI become tremendously useful
but they they are also
a a very powerful brainwashing machine
because this is this is going to this is
um in a way it's going going to
the the most massive brainwashing
machine possible and the most powerful.
They just going to control the earth.
Okay? They control every information. So
the the the situation the scenario is
that people stop reading books anymore.
Like we don't you know you don't talk to
like like you know we we we don't talk
to people anymore. We don't read books.
We don't read Wikipedia. We just ask AI.
AI is so convenient you know anything
you can just ask AI so gradually or even
um
you know you know in a way so AI is
going to lie to you and you don't even
know it that that's already happening of
course that's already happening when you
ask certain things about uh politics or
sensitive topics when you ask
for example on Google's Germany Google's
AI bot or the Facebook AI bot Okay. Or
the chpt what kind of questions any
question related to USA government
policies or or for example about the
trans issue about you know feminism
whatever.
So you get you get you know the result
the answer you get is let's say not
exactly fair. Okay. And also what is
fail exactly that's a very comp complex
question. Okay.
So AI is this massive brain brainwashing
machine. Of course you you need to it's
very critical. You need to pay
attention. I'm not telling you just to
listen to AI. So you but you need to pay
attention but you need to know who is
behind what AI in fact you know there is
a big war going on between Ela Musk and
the Chad GPD guy. Uh what's his name? Uh
he's a extreme scum. Okay, the chat GPT
guy Sam Otman. Okay, his name popped up
right here. Can you see trending Sam
Otman is one of the most extreme scum
dangerous person on earth. Okay, I would
say I would say even even more than Bill
Gates. Okay, the Sam Oldman.
Okay. So, Elamusk is also the richest
guy and he is right now having a war
with Sam Oldman because Elamus idea is
that he's going to create AI. We need a
open-source AI because AI is becoming is
is becoming extremely powerful and
dangerous.
So, we need according to Elamusk we need
an AI that's opensource.
So any person can open source and uh
supposedly open weights which is another
critical thing about AI.
The the most important thing is about
the weights actually. Anyway so Elamus
idea is that you we need open source AI.
So that he
you know he and Sam Oldman he uh
contributed like donated millions of
dollars to to begin the open AI company
you know open in the name open AI
meaning we started this company so that
we the the goal of our co company open
AI is that we have open-source AI
machine that can anyone can benefit so
we can fight the corporate closed source
AI. So when AI become very powerful, we
also have a you know our AI machine open
AI that
you know we can bite you know whatever
lies may be there or right but but
Samman sold out you know Samman
closed it the opening and and basically
sold his soul to uh Microsoft
but I think he's more than that he's uh
in my opinion okay all these are my
opinion only he's extremely evil and
ambitious guy his score is not just like
you know getting some money from
Microsoft he's more than that okay very
extreme scum in my opinion the Sam old
man okay they they you know so this is
very actually dangerous because there
are people dead there's an employee
who supposedly suicide
uh that's a big big topic Okay, if you
guys pay attention, you know, but you
don't know if how exactly he died. Okay,
that that guy that was a guy who worked
for Open AI. Okay, so there there's a
you know, Ela Musk and and this guy is
is right right now is um uh doing big s
law
anyway. So, okay. So I don't I don't
think we're going to go back to
JavaScript because we started to mostly
talk about um AI.
Yeah. So but in summary I wanted to
you know I just wanted to talk about
something about AI such that you know I
recommend you should you must you should
talk with AI you know if you someone
tells you oh you shouldn't do anything
AI they are just idiots okay you should
you should get involved with AI in fact
you should ask so much you should force
yourself to ask AI questions
okay about programming or anything just
like ask AI questions okay that's one
important thing you you want to get
involved you want you know that that
will AI will increase your learning
abilities by two times at least okay it
will increase your learning ab abilities
by twice as fast at minimum okay it's
like you know if if it's like if if you
don't use the right tool for example if
you're writing code and if You all you
can use is a note not notepad no you
know notebook
you know you are not going to go far
okay tool is very important critical if
you are a programmer and you you are
forced to use the you know the the node
um [laughter] the Microsoft note you are
not you can't do anything okay
significant so AI so what I'm saying is
that you should ask AI make AI useful to
you for you. Okay, ask you know just
keep asking it questions it will
increase your learning abilities
twofold minimum
that's what I'm saying the on the other
hand it is also very critical to know
that AI is a massive brain washing
machine in a massive scale so they can
control the thinking of all human
animals on earth
and it might happen right now we don't
know yet you know but you you could one
day it's like we all live in a lie you
don't know
so that is also very um very critical so
what you need to know you need to kind
of know who is behind what AI what sort
of questions you can trust so so you
know you need to pay attention on what
kind of things or what kind of answer
you can trust AI or not or from what AI
just keep that in mind okay so that's
the two things uh I want to recommend to
people.
Okay, I think that's it. Uh I was going
to do JavaScript but um you know I I
wanted to do a lot of interesting
JavaScript but I guess that you know no
you know there's a lot JavaScript I want
to do you know to do this will take more
than one hour uh actually one hour so
but
okay that's it let's let today just be
AI stuff Okay.
On the topic of learning. So, have you
ever use any kind of flash card system?
No, not really.
Yeah, I just I never used flash card. Uh
I suppose it could be useful. Yeah.
Uh Otman is so amazingly arrogant and
deceptive. Yes, very dangerous guy.
uh smaller local models. You know the
problem you know another thing
interesting about AI is that local model
is that one time about half a year ago I
did live live stream installed local
models of AI. uh we installed
you know you can look at my past uh talk
show
some talk show and so past year so we
did uh 2025
and search for uh deep
so we in 2025 April episode 648
and several of them we I we install
deepseek okay seek or lama
So it turns out one problem with the
local model is that
it's puny you know it's like you know it
because you need powerful GPUs and and
and you know GPUs and CPU but if you
don't have like $10,000 machine or
20,000 or actually 100,000 machine
whatever you do the local model the the
quality the AI answers because their
result is not comparable to you simply
ask you know the web version like the
very significant did the difference is
very significant in their quality okay
so
so that so that made me um so I so
that's a issue with the local AI so I
don't
so I don't you know so that's a problem
with the local AI Okay.
Uh
recommendation for how to study coding
or anything you want to learn. Well, I
mean so the first the foremost thing is
just the desire to learn something if
you really want to that's the foremost
importance. Okay. Once you have that
desire everything just come just uh just
comes. Okay. So you know recommendation
study coding um you could there are so
many aspects like what resource you can
you know there's video how do you choose
books or should you uh watch videos
instead or do you should you have a
schedule or whatever um so many aspect
okay but the most important is like
do like where does the do you have the
desire do you really like do you really
have strong desire to really you want to
know something if you have that desire
everything just solves itself okay
that's the most important so if you want
to study coding why is because your
parent told you to your friend told you
to code is interesting or is it
something you just somehow find yourself
interested in or if you want to get into
something but you are right now not
interested did for example let's say I
want to know about law you know lawyers
are they are always powerful they are
actually the most in general lawyers are
kind of the scum type of people on earth
okay lawyers because lawyers by nature
by definition they are the type of
people they have the most power because
and and that's what they want okay
that's for whatever reasons
family background upbringing you Certain
people they go into law lawyers or some
people you know go to coding
programmers, mathematicians, scient
scientists like us. Some people go to
carpenters, some you know they're good
at that. Some go to acting or whatever
whatever you know all sort of trades and
walks of of life. But there's a group of
course they they are lawyers and they
they are um so for example if I want to
know more about law right I
how how do I get interested in that I
don't know
usually you usually there is something
right if you just force me to I mean
I don't have the interest you know I
don't I don't really have the interest
in learning about law much right but but
if there's something something happened
uh let's say I got into an argument with
landlord or whatever and they I started
to you know maybe in the beginning I I
wanted to know some answer how you know
what what is the law regarding this
situation then I got involved you know
then then maybe I started to want to
know more so that's one example how how
you get into how you started to have a
desire for something.
Uh, okay. So, that's an example. Okay.
Uh,
okay. So, uh,
is it very important to learn or keep
code well organized and structured to
write code that is easy to search
through?
Uh writing code in patterns is important
because when error occur you need to
fix.
It is very important to learn to keep
code well organized and structured to
write code that is easy to search
through. Writing code in patterns is
important because we because when errors
occur you need to fix it. Okay. I guess
that's your opinion. Okay. Um,
okay. I think that's it for today.
So, for those of you who installed local
models, how do you how do you deal with
the problem? Because local models it
runs on your machine but your machine is
usually not powerful. So
So uh how do you deal with that? Who who
was that? Um
per ghost
pose.
Okay, bye guys.