good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is 2019
December 13th Friday Oh
today is December 13th Friday and 12
o'clock 17 minutes in the afternoon San
Francisco time and today's topic is
Japanese keyboards we are going to I'm
going to give you a introduction to the
Japanese writing system and Japanese
input system meaning how do you type
them and Japanese keyboard layout now in
Japanese keyboard you know it's just
like English you have many different
type of layouts such as you know in
English you have vorak you have koti
barack Commack and so on so that in the
same way in japanese keyboards you have
quite a few layouts so I'm going to give
you an introduction of that and let's
begin hey ten more is demo as I asked
you before but where you from if you
don't mind to say I must have asked you
before but I forgot and the you are are
you in this Court
if not join discord okay guys so let me
show you my discord and we are going to
get on to the topic quickly and let's
finish that topic the Japanese input
system and so on in about 20 minutes or
30 then we gonna chat random ok so this
code so those of you have not already
joined this code and Brazilian but want
to move to China or Japan
oh ok right buzz Brazilian right so
sorry discord okay so that is my discord
join invitation so yeah that'd be great
so anyway so I so we let's talk about
the today's topics language so I'm gonna
just give you guys
production of the Japanese input system
and then after 20 or 30 minutes then
we're gonna chat random and that would
be it for today whatever topics come up
okay so but let's begin so Japanese
writing system so you need to know
Japanese writing system before you can
learn about the Japanese keyboard
layouts for example let me show you some
of the interesting things okay so you go
to so you go to my blog sorry
keyboards it's just such for that you'll
find my blog so here is the Japanese
keyboard layouts okay we have quite a
bunch of fascinating things let me show
you okay so this well what you see here
is kind of the standard QWERTY keyboard
okay this is actually the most commonly
used standard QWERTY keyboard and then
you have this slump shift layout system
I'm going to explain that okay this is a
system you got to shift keys left shift
and right shift they are not they are
different from the you know the English
shift keys and this left shift and right
shift they are positioned under your
thumb so this is another input system
invented in 1980 and and I'm gonna show
you so it's quite a lot interesting
things this is we are talking about
keyboard history so we are talking about
Japanese language writing system and
also we are talking about the input
system I'll tell you why we need that
for Japanese because you don't have
enough keys to input Japanese you have
thousands of characters then you have
the so you have the input system then
you have the keyboard layout all these
things kind of go hand in hand so when
you have a system you tend to have a
specialized keyboard to go with it for
example these keyboards these keyboards
are originally designed for the shift
thump shift
the thumb shift input system look at
this one
coaches now this keyboard is from 1994
1984 I think this one OS is 100 TP so
yeah so you see very interesting we are
looking at 1992 ok 1992 you have this
this keyboard 1992 and you see you have
two thumb shift key so I'll tell you
about what the others the keys are when
we come to explain that so you then you
have this model from year 2001 from
Fujitsu all these are from Fujitsu you
have left shift left thumb shift right
thumb shift you have this conversion or
no conversion keys okay then you have a
modern version this one is from 2010 you
know when the thing keyboard laptop
style so you have you know again left
thumb shift and right thumb shift so we
gonna talk about that so this is this
this particular one is called thumb
shift then you have M type system n type
is another input system for Japanese
let's look at this gorgeous keyboard and
this keyboard this pocket particular
keyboard is from what year I forgot that
1983 so you see they have competing
systems by the way these are not you
know although to you it may seem oh it
just looks like the thumb shift key
keyboard but actually they are entirely
they are entirely different
okay so so you have this code M system
input system and you can see this
spectacular keyboard this spectacular
keyboard this any see you know in mm
system so the Japanese system you know
the fascinating then you have this one
ji a x JIS x600 4 so chair is X 6000 for
system
that's another system and this is just a
diagram I'm not sure there's an actual
keyboard that come with it I don't I
don't think so
but it's a generic system that can be
used on any keyboard then you have the
trunk spectacular trunk trunk keyboard
this is trumped by the way Charlie
there's a rich history to trunk trunk is
also a operating system of Japan you
know Japan created a operating system
called trunk and it's at one time at one
point it is in fact the most popular
operating system used in a world why
because all the little devices in Japan
they are using the Tron system and
there's a twisted story to it because
United States the Microsoft the United
Scavo meant you know the you know
Microsoft talking with the United scum
and then they talked to Japan then they
say thou shalt not use strong or else so
because you know Microsoft you know us
and Microsoft they want the world to use
the Microsoft operating system so there
is a little threat to prevent the
transferring system become popular so
anyway this is a spectacular keyboard ok
the trunk the trunk keyboard it comes
with a trunk input system different from
the others we talked about then you have
the new sticky so basically new sticky
is a new one okay so invented by by this
guy by this I think it's amended by this
guy he's on Twitter this is a new Ezreal
new keyboard okay so this this keyboard
is so we have so many different Japanese
layouts those are layouts so before you
understand before you actually
understand about you know to understand
this layout you need to know a little
bit about how the Japanese writing
system how is it written okay so we are
going to give you let's talk about that
the Japanese writing system what
characters are there so Dan says it's
Japanese writing system good for
programming no not really no the length
the the well the language that's good
for programming is basically English
partly because computer you know
computing technology is mostly created
by USA Americans we you know created it
so it's in English mostly and it's a
fast it's it's quite interesting to me
that that USA since 1960s developed the
the the most of the computing
architecture in software
nowhere else I mean you know if you
compare you know basically nowhere else
either the vast majority of computing
technologies are created by USA for
example we went to the moon right in
Pedrosa also went to the moon moon we
have nuclear bomb but Russia and China
in in few other countries also the work
developed that however the computer
technology it seems it seems to me other
countries didn't do much with it you
know they you know you don't have for
example you don't have a operating
system well you have one Japanese
submarine system you do have a few
languages invented in Japan for example
Ruby which is nineteen by that that is
already 1990s okay that's that kind of
doesn't count
I'm talking about 1960s 1970s you do
have like but basically it seems to me
the computer technology are mostly I
mean I find it strange that how come
some other countries didn't develop much
computer technology in operating systems
so anyway of course there are a few are
they were so I mean I there are few
languages so yeah so so anyway so in
yeah so let's get back to the Japanese
language okay the Japanese writing
system now first of all realize that the
particular language and it's writing
system are entirely different almost
have nothing to do with each other
now two days ago you know you check out
my youtube video I did we did a talk
about that how the writing system of a
language and and the speech the
listening and speaking of a language the
you know the the the how do you say that
is the audio part the speech father the
language is entirely different so you
know go watch that video we talked about
why kind of why why and how they are
entirely different so anyway in song in
Japanese so Japanese you know they have
a language but however they for a
thousand years or more they do not have
a writing system so they borrowed the
writing system the Chinese characters
from China so so okay so let me just
straight talk about the Japanese writing
system
okay so Japanese writing system is made
of several components first of all you
have this kana okay what you are looking
at are the kana now kana are a phonetic
basically a phonetic alphabet so each of
these symbol represents a sound you know
for example this is ah ah these two both
of them the red and blue are and this is
e ooh oh these are these are air and oh
you a oh yeah ah ooh
oh that's how you I think I'm pretty
sure that's how you pronounce it in
Japan Japanese and this this column
would be
K ki ku ke ko okay and this column is
going to be some shi su say so and so on
so this
Kanha these are phonetic symbols each
each one represents the sounds and why
why are they that like they are to say
there are two sets of them one is the
red the red is called hiragana and the
blue is called katakana so you have the
red hiragana and the blue katakana they
so that you have two sets of them
however so almost for each character you
know each symbol that you have a
corresponding symbol in the other set
why is that it's kind of like a capital
letter system in English not exactly but
it's similar so you know so you have ABC
you have capital letter case so it's
it's kind of similar in Japan so so
anyway so you have these both of these
is called kana and so kana have two sets
hiragana and katakana now the katakana
the blue one is less used they are used
for place for place names for imported
wards firing words for place names
company names imported words emphasis
and so on you know basically similar to
capital capital letters so that's a blue
one katakana and but normally you write
in hiragana these phonetic symbols now
remember these are phonetic simple
symbols so let me summarize Japanese
writing system is made of several
components one of the first one of the
component is kana
they are phonetic symbols and you are
looking at them and of this connor there
are two sets hiragana and katakana okay
they are kind of like lowercase n
capital K is kind of okay so these are
the phonetic systems kana so that's one
component of the Japanese system so you
use these phonetics phonetic symbols to
to notate how something is spoken you
know so
you know how to say something you can
write it down in hiragana or katakana so
that's a phonetic system kind of like
English alphabet so but that's not all
the Japanese writing system also use
Chinese characters okay literally I mean
basically Chinese characters they came
from you know like I mentioned Japanese
writing system are powered from Chinese
so a thousand years ago they imported
you know they you know there's a contact
so Japanese borrowed almost the entirety
of Chinese characters the track Chinese
writing system however the Japanese
language and the the Chinese language
they are entirely different they share
no root okay so there are entirely
different languages and Japanese they
just borrowed the Chinese characters as
a writing system for their language this
just so happened okay it's kind of
strange because these two languages does
not share anything the grandma is
entirely different like totally
different but they just said but they
borrowed the Chinese characters now you
can see so what is Chinese characters
okay so I actually I have an example so
let me show you some examples okay so
demo is oh you are t4n okay so I think I
talked to you before so let's see let me
check if I'm doing good here where are
the people will spot okay so let's go to
sorry
Chinese character okay let me show you
quickly what Chinese characters look
like no now we don't want a drum
keyboard we want common check unicode
characters here okay
okay not not this page so anyway this
here is an example of Chinese characters
let me magnify so this is Chinese the
Chinese characters look like that okay
and let's open this page so you can see
okay so these are Chinese characters now
so so so let's go back to Japanese so
the Japanese they power Chinese
characters so in fact all this almost
all of these characters you see here you
they will appear in Japanese text too
and basically the meaning is almost
exactly the same like 90% is exactly the
same so it's kind of funny so today when
I read a Japanese text for example I
don't know Japanese but I know Chinese
so when I read Japanese for example here
is Japanese text from Wikipedia you see
here so you see so some of the
characters are complicated for example
this one let's magnify okay
let's see if we can magnify so so you
see that character and this character
in this character in this character and
these three actually this for those are
Chinese you see when you see fairly
complicated characters those are Chinese
characters and I can understand them so
well be the any Chinese when they when
we read Japanese text we can basically
make up what it is trying to say I mean
what kind of things it's trying to say
for example might be this I see in that
means English okay
force machine finger press character or
language information or symbols
you know symbols deliver model language
written language and entered into force
something like that basically machine
operate or use and so on
and it says for example Japanese
keyboard language so where are we this I
you know it goes like English machine
fingers press characters symbols deliver
model up written language pressure basic
machine operation or use okay and
Japanese keyboard language both of them
originally same European characters and
music music instruments use mechanical
through model electronics machine so so
when Chinese reads
you get a sense what is talking about so
that is that is why you know so this
here is a example where Japanese the
their you know their language the
region's writing system is actually half
of them is Chinese characters in that's
today okay so by statistics you can if
you look at the statistics of articles
there is information you can see now the
Chinese characters in Japanese they call
it kanji okay so in informal texts like
newspapers or magazines or books 40% of
the characters are Chinese 36% is kanji
I mean the hiragana 6% is katakana the
capital one and others are punctuation
digits and English letters so you can
see basically forty percent are Chinese
Chinese characters the other forty
percent are the phonetic symbols of
Japanese phonetic symbols this kana so
that's that that is actually so that is
about the Japanese writing system now
where does the kana came from they are
derived from Chinese characters now I
don't have information here you go to
Wikipedia then you can there okay so you
know there's a Wikipedia on Japanese
writing system you can read in detail
Japanese writing system okay so so
anyway that is about the components of
the Japanese writing system so in order
to type Japanese you you must be able to
type or the scanner they are about 40
each you know there are 40 hiragana and
hiragana and the 40 car econo so it's
all together about 80 of these phonetic
symbols then you also need to be able to
type English letters now English letters
in Japanese you know the alphabets they
decoded
Roman Chi okay here yo man Chi basically
means Norman characters because that's
what they are Latin was using Roman
characters Latin off a bit so you have
you need to type the the kana symbols
eighty of them and you need to type the
English letters 26 lowercase force 26
uppercase then you also need to type the
Chinese characters they are about in no
more Chinese education you know if you
grew up from you know if you finish high
school in in Japan you should know about
2,000 or 3,000 okay you need to know
3,000 Chinese characters so it's very
hard so okay so so that's a summary
that's how that's that is introduction
about the Japanese writing system okay
that's so that's one thing so next we're
gonna continue to talk about the
Japanese input system that is how do you
actually type them and then we're gonna
talk about Japanese keyboard layouts
okay how to type Japanese so so you type
them by so there are many inputs
different input systems one of the most
popular is you type you you know you
just use a u.s. keyboard any any quality
keyboard okay for example on a Mac we
can switch to we can add a input system
let's go there open keyboard preferences
and you can go to let's do it again
wait
oh they're so so I have us have peeing
you can add a Japanese input system
let's see jump Japan
there I have added a Japanese input
system now we can let's try to type
Japanese okay I haven't done this before
so I don't know what's gonna go on
so I'm gonna mock magnified to the hell
of it okay so so so let me talk about it
first
so you type an English red letter on any
keyboard then it will be converted to
kana you know hiragana of the phonetic
symbols then after you typed you have
some cannot entered you press another
key there's a key on it there's a
special way let me tell you about that
okay so anyway you press another key
that says convert then you have a
selection of choices involving Chinese
characters then you can select them then
it becomes Chinese for example this
character you see that's how it becomes
Chinese character for example here's
another example so that is how you type
Japanese you press key on your keyboard
QWERTY keyboard u.s. keyboard then it
becomes kana
okay it becomes the phonetic symbols
then after you have a certain phonetic
symbols you can press a key or you can
press a key then your pop-up this
selection that lets you to convert to
Chinese characters that's how you enter
them now if you want to type English
letters or or numbers there is another
key that switch you to just the US
layout so that's how you type Japanese
okay so let's try okay III don't know
how to say what to say let's say Japan
okay I believe Japan the word Japan in
Japanese Co is called Ning home okay so
let me try it and I okay so I need to
switch to Japanese first okay so you can
see okay so you can see there is the
Roman G when you add a Japanese input
system it
three of these so when you are in here
it's Roman gmod okay it means it means
it types ABCD just like English keyboard
okay Roman G Roman characters then if
you go here hiragana then that types
hiragana
let's try okay so let's let's try Ning
home okay Ning Oh
maybe that I don't know I don't know
Japanese okay we have it correct
I got it correct so that's the
apparently that's the con on you know
the phonetic symbols for the word Japan
Ning home
how do I know because you see there's a
Chinese there that's the Chinese
characters for Japan so so let me
explain so once I typed in an edge and
that those kana showed up then I have
two choices either I choose the Chinese
character or I choose the the the
English Ning hole okay so actually I
have several choices several choices so
oh I can stay with whatever I had you
know the the phonetic symbols so let's
try that okay so let's try that
oops ready to go okay maybe that I think
that's that Oh hmm how do I enter
okay so enter then enter okay that's
done so let's try again n.h okay wait
and I H oh there it is okay so let's
choose that wait what did it say okay
when you have when you choose Chinese it
actually give you explanations
okay so let's choose that Japan okay so
Japan enter and
okay enter so there we have it okay so
there so that's example of how how do
you enter Japanese then you can also
choose katakana which is the kind of the
capital case of the hiragana okay so we
have talked about the Japanese writing
system and we have talked about the how
do you input Japanese now we have pretty
good so the next thing to talk about is
the Japanese keyboard layout so we're
gonna do that and let me take a break
could read the comments and so on
and another thing we we're gonna talk
about is special keys on the Japanese
keyboard so you can see here is a
Japanese you know here is an apple
keyboard in Japan so they they are are
okay they don't have special keys here
but on this keyboard a happy having
happy hacking keyboard you can see they
have some extra keys this when you see
this double circle circular circle that
means convert so when you press this key
it means you want to convert whatever
kana you typed into Chinese and if you
press this key this means no conversion
that's a slash over there so that means
when you I think if you press that it
means just okay just go ahead move on to
the next input you know what what you
have there is already good so you have
these two important keys one is called
Han Khan Han Khan means change or
convert the other one is mu Henken which
means no change don't convert so that
that's about the special keys on the
Japanese keyboard by the way they have a
few other special keys like hiragana mod
cutta cutta cutta kana mod we have seen
let me show you okay so you see they
have a few other special keys but they
are
necessary because for example we have
seen here on the mag you just choose
this instead okay so let's go back here
so you can see there are keyboard
shortcuts actually you see there's
keyboard shortcuts so but um in Japan if
you buy some special keyboard they have
a key is so you know that corresponds to
the keyboard shortcut for example this
key here this key to the left of the
space that those are Chinese characters
kanji and it means English and numbers
meaning alphanumeric mod so when you
press that key then then the keyboard
will behave just like a u.s. keyboard
and but in our case you know we can also
press you know this no man G you know
this control shift semicolon for the
same effect so anyway so that's good so
let me just watch the comments and let's
see where we go so good morning but but
but are you on this code yet Ning Hong
okay so know me hyung so Matt good
morning Matt good morning Zhi Zhu borin
intend good morning to Japan I think so
you are are you japanese are you
japanese oh are you Japanese in America
like where are you from
so okay let's move on to let's move on
to yeah so we are let's talk about the
let's move on to the keyboard
impulses of not yet ok great part so
let's let's start to talk about the
keyboard layouts this fascinating ok so
okay so let's go ahead let me just go
talk about keyboard layout okay the
Japanese keyboard layout fascinating so
we'll be in 34 minutes that's good so
cool so Japanese Kibo layout first of
all they have this what is called core
TJ is now j is stand for Japanese
industrial standard something like that
okay so the core teacher is layout is
the standard name for basically us Cote
layout so and this is in fact what
Japanese use most of the time I mean
vast majority of Japanese like nine
ninety nine percent of Japanese FIFO
they just they use this input system
co-teacher as layout
now this quadratures layout is basically
exactly the same as a u.s. keyboard like
no difference no difference at all so
you just use whatever keyboard you are
using like right now on the Mac on
Windows or if you are on Linux you know
just us keyboard then you go to the
system preferences use you know use
change the input to Japanese then you
can start to type it and in fact this is
vast majority of Japanese that's what
they use by the way those zetsubou
renton if I'm incorrect correct me okay
so I you know correct me if I'm wrong so
not you know 99% of Japanese people they
actually use this input system just like
we have demoed before you you know you
type English letters they become scanner
then then you press a key to possibly
choose a Chinese character you know you
know that's how you do it and this
system in fact this system for writing
Japanese is the most inefficient system
but you know that's but most Japanese
use this system just just like English
you know in English the Cortile out is
the worst
layout as far as efficiency goes you
know Vorik Commack you know the lease
are much more efficient but because of
historical reasons in the convention you
know people don't want to change you we
are already used to the season so you
know in a same way the Japanese you know
they just use cottages which is very
inefficient because you remember you
have to type English letters first you
have for each two English letter you
type it becomes one kana okay so for
each kana you have to type two
keystrokes then you type you know then
then you then you have a word then you
have to press another key then you have
a bunch of selections you know that lets
you choose Chinese so this is very
inefficient but however the fact is that
you know this is what most people use in
Japan in fact similar situation happens
in China to any English and in French
you know so the saw the keyboard layout
actually so almost like the whole world
is using the keyboard layout the worst
season possible and it just so happens
we are stuck with it so just just like
programming I mean this happens this
happens in lots of areas like in
programming we are stuck with c and c
plus first two of those worst language
possible but we are just stuck with it
you cannot change it you know you some
people say oh just go use Cola or just
use you know roast audio use has cow or
uses something or camel or F sharp yeah
but you can't just force it because this
whole industry already using it you know
things like that and history and you
know you cannot change and also old
people people don't want to change your
habit for example if you already if you
are you know older people you already
programmed in C or C++ for 20 years and
now there's new language like o has come
Oh Julia oh you should use to do you use
use stay in some days away but you don't
have time to learn you gotta get on with
your life you know you got other things
to do so you don't want to change
so change happens slowly very slowly
until basically by generation like one
generation ties you know the newer
generation like today's people young
people many of you guys young people in
but ok you you don't know the old things
like see see first first you don't know
but you only you when you were born you
started to learn the new things so for
you for you it that's that's that's your
habit you know so that's how things
change slowly so so ok so we talked
about the quota chairs chairs layout so
actually let me read come a common part
so bar says what I hate about Japanese
is that like 90% of people speaking
Japanese on the Internet are actually
some wanna be we Bose who learned mangas
mangas speak yeah that's true well
that's not totally true you know because
if you go to Twitter actually the
Japanese people they use a lot of them
they use American social networks like
on Twitter you have significant number
of Japanese there I mean they are just
talking with Japanese people there I
mean significant like I don't know what
10% of all Twitter users you know that
if I remember correctly vast majority of
Twitter users are not American you know
contrary to what do you think oh what I
you know we we think you know like I
think American like English you know
American Twitter users
USA is like 40% something like that you
go to internet you can find you know you
search for treat a demo graph you can
find you you can find the maps in
statistics anyway America is like 40%
off of Twitter users and then you have
other countries and Japan so happens is
like quite significant like 20 percent
or 10 percent Japanese people they have
very fast internet faster than USA and
you know and you know they are very
technology co country so so yeah a lot
of Japanese people use Twitter right so
I mean if you are not Japanese you don't
see them because you you you know you
usually follow your friends but a lot of
Americans for reasons I talked about
this in previous video for reasons they
they want to you know they watch young
people especially when they watch you a
lot of Japanese anime and comics you
know animation and they they start to
like follow the Japanese fashion and you
know Japanese words things like that we
are booked that's what they caught
that's what is the code we about sohbats
says you love julia julia raise star
with index one I know I know sleepy
first first that is why I know it's
cancer okay I just know we're both
always go to Japanese restaurants to
feel more Japanese whereas real Japanese
tourists from actual Japan go to fish
restaurant that is not reiated Japan
anyway you know that we are both well
that's part of that is internet culture
you know it's not it's you know it's not
actually it doesn't really I don't think
it's really happen that much I mean you
basically you just got this small niche
group of nerds who are you know doing
this kind of thing and they are on
Twitter
the chemist and they spread it but in
reality I'd I don't think this really
that many people doing that because it's
kind of silly but actually you are it's
a phenomena phenomena so math cubes good
morning
I still don't get how we are still using
the same physical keyboard layout yes
exactly
so I have Chinese people on github and
steam yes Chinese is everywhere in you
mean Chinese people in Germany or so
anyway let's go back to the let's finish
this okay then we let's talk about other
things so Japanese input so you have the
core teacher quality GIS layer which is
just like English keyboard then you have
the Nicholas layout this is starting to
get interesting now now Japanese you
know they in the history of Japanese
computer development they they realized
that the you know the this quarry layout
is not efficient so they invented this
one this one is invented in 1979 or 1980
so let me talk about this this one thumb
shift okay so this is this is the thumb
shift keyboard so you can see many
historical models here now they are
invented by Fujitsu Fujitsu is a giant
company okay and invented so this is
called thumb shift and it is also known
as Nick Nicola layout anyway so so in
1978 this person yes so nori
kondeh invented this thumb shift
keyboard he's a lead inventor and when
he is working for Fujitsu so Fujitsu you
know he invented and then later on about
five
ten years later it passed to the
Japanese input consortium and they
renamed they get they gave a standard
name for this layout so it's called Nick
Nicola layout it's the same thing
basically the same thing
thumb shift system so so in 1980 that is
the era of word processors we we begin
to have home computers but but mostly at
the time it's what processors so they
created this word processor you know
very expensive and and this is the first
keyboard that uses the thumb shift
system so let me show you okay so this
looks like that okay so so you have two
keys you know left thumb shift and right
thumb shift anyway and as we showed
before you have this fantastic one this
one is form this one is from let's let's
stay this for a while okay so wait so
so bosses what do you think of Japanese
companies Sony Panasonic I don't know
math cube says what just a cup of online
friends so a math cube says I really
hate that top keywords cuz all of them
sucks I know quote Ian Walkman layout
okay so parts say okay so what do you
think okay so the spacebar is really a
waste of space yes indeed the Japanese
Kibo they don't use space bar as much
those are not by the way these are so
this is a left thumb shift this is right
thumb shift and here the at the bottom
it's no conversion on the right is
conversion to convert to Chinese
characters basically so okay so here is
a space bar yeah it's pretty big I don't
know why so anyway so that's the thumb
shift so we have several models okay
let's just look at them so this one is
from Fujitsu year 2001 and then you have
this one from year 2010
okay thumb shift now should I go to
explain how it works okay so let me
explain okay yeah it should I should so
why is this efficient first of all you
got some shift which is much better than
the shift end up at using your pinky
okay but that's not the point the main
thing is that this system is spaced on
Cana okay now this system is based on
Cana that that is when you type a key
like one of the key here it shows us on
your screen directly a Japanese
pronunciation symbol like you don't have
to convert from English to the kana like
before when we were doing it we have to
type for example n I to characters to
get one
konna symbol but in this keyboard each
key is a kana
already so that already that that saves
you you know twice of the keystrokes
already then then for each key let's see
if I want to so we don't have a big
image here so then in just so then for
each key you have like two symbols on it
okay okay so how do I explain this okay
so let's try to focus on this key okay
this key on the right-hand J okay right
hand J key chunk of Corti so when you
press this key you got the symbol on the
lower on the lower row row yes so if you
do not press any of the thumb shift you
got a symbol on the lower lower row but
if you press the thumb shift on the
other side okay then you get a then you
get a
then you get a okay so if you press the
thumb shift on the other side then you
get a variation of this kana basically
they add a they are two dots to it okay
like like that like this okay you see
this this is called a voiced voiced
symbol those two dots
it's called voice symbol and if you
press a key but with the same sites
thumb shift key what you got is the
upper upper row symbol okay so you got
that got that so you can press a key it
will become itself but if you press it
with the other side sound it becomes it
adds the you know it comes out a symbol
with a voiced mark that that okay that
is called the Kooten that Kooten
kakouton basically your symbol for
voiced mark that that's used in Japanese
okay it's like accent you know in
English kind of but if you press a key
with the same side of the thumb shift
you get the symbol on the upper row so
each key basically depending on whether
you press the thumb shift or left thumb
shift or right thumb shift you have
three character variations so that is
how these keyboard works so I mean the
thumb shift system works so let me
summarize thumb shift system also known
as Nicola layout it works by such that
each key correspond to a kana symbol
directly and you have to sum shift keys
under your thumb when you when you press
them they will change the kana into some
other
single basically okay so this is the
kana scene and also one important thing
to note is that the kana symbols on this
keyboard they are arranged in a ficient
way that is the most frequently used
connor is on the key that's most easy to
press for example this this one's in
deck press by middle finger and index
finger we can tell right away this these
symbols are more often used then than
those symbols on the side here or here
so it's arranged efficiently so that
that is about this film shift layout
also known as nickel alia okay so we
finished talking about that again let's
look at the keyboard just to just to
just to refresh refresh our minds you
know you see you see this keyboard you
got two thumbs shift keys then you have
the convert or don't convert keys don't
convert on the left convert on the right
that is when you want to convert the
corner into Chinese characters so a
vision it's a vision system okay now we
have talked about the Cottagers layout
and we have also talked about the
niccola some shift layout we can now
talk about m-type layout now it should
be easier I'm wondering I talked too
slow
yeah I talk too slow so so let's see
what's the comments the space one is
really come on a engine key was your
sucks cause it's doesn't conform to how
to your hands hmm well yeah but I mean
it doesn't suck
you know because you how far you want to
go well if you want to talk yeah I mean
then you could say all keyboard sucks
because it's not a
system where where you directly connect
to your brain you know that system is
coming you could you just connect the
USB to your brain whatever you think you
just type right there that's more
efficient system so depends on the hog
what level you want to go you know so
this is efficient so you if you are
thinking oh the keyboard is not split
you know it's not tainted or it's not
you know bone shaped like my like my
like you know that like the one I'm
using the Kinesis advantage - yeah
that's but that's that's a different
thing you know and remember this is 1980
1980 1980 1979 when she when Japanese
created this thumb shift you know in USA
you don't have that yet the you know
anyway so so we finished talking about
that layout so let's read the comments
Oh a bit gonna leave early okay well
have a good day Matt yeah if you are not
gone yet so poor dura they had pinpoint
tablets in the 90s pain operating system
okay still better though yeah
Matt cube math cube says is Nikola
keyboard still popular in Japan no or
have they converted to american-style
keyboard yeah like I mentioned before
99.9 percent of Japanese more than that
99.99% of Japanese people in Japan they
simply use the qua teacher as layer
basically u.s. keyboard okay that's
that's why that's that's why I thought I
mentioned this before it's really
inefficient but people just use it
there's nothing you know just like USA
you know we are still using quote e what
yeah so they don't know they don't have
the know you they don't have in Japan
most keyboard are just like that for
example this is Apple keyboard Japan you
know and this is very popular happy
hacking keyboard the Japanese version
they don't have the thumb shift keys
they don't have that this one is just
like this is just English keyboard
I mean u.s. keyboard except that they
have smaller space bar they have this
change key and no change key then they
have extra the kaneki that's all I
suppose when you press the Connor key it
toggles between English and and the kana
input yeah you know like it doesn't do
much like you don't you don't actually
need you know on keyboard when if they
don't have this change key or no change
key basically you can type space or
enter like usually space is for no
change enter is for change I think okay
this is something like that sometimes
they do shift enter things like that so
okay so actually let's talk about let's
continue to talk about M type system
yeah so we talked it let's talk about in
M type then trunk a little bit then it's
done so M type is another system
invented by ng C okay so so let me show
you what is M type now M type this one
you are looking at it's based on not
kana input system it's based on English
input just like just like the one I try
to type before so but however the
English alphabet are arranged according
to the efficiency of Japanese kana for
example you look do you look at this you
see EUI AO on the Left home row and on
the right here'll you have K s T and H
you know you might think that's strange
it's
the way that it's that way because they
are arranged according to the efficiency
of entering kana so if you type K you
know so you again just like before you
type two keys to English letters to
create one kana
however this this time the English
letters alphabets are arranged
efficiently for the kana
so you type two letters you get a Conner
okay then yeah that's that's about it
about this system this is called M type
system
there are some keys on a nickel don't
conform to your hands they what what do
you mean they kind of they do they are
in the middle they mean for Japanese
they kind of they do I think so anyway
so this so we are looking at M type
input system okay so M type so the the
good part I mean the the thing about
this system is that it's English based
but the letters are arranged efficiently
for Japanese that's a good thing about
this keyboard that's the important thing
about this keyboard so let's have a look
everything else is just the same so
again so this one is invented in 1983 so
apparently the AEC AEC is a big company
in Japan like a huge huge industrial
corporation NEC Fujitsu they are all
huge companies so apparently it seems to
me they are in competition because
remember the thumb shift system is
invented by Fujitsu in 1980 you know
that's the date when they have keyboard
using our system but NEC came out with M
type you know so apparently they are in
competition you know and any NEC came up
with this keyboard and you know it's
pretty good it looks pretty fancy and
look they are using mechanical keys Alps
a RPS switch and apparently throughout
history you have several models of the
image agency the end system keyboard
yeah so you have you know historical
books on it you have this you know I
don't even know what what computer is is
NEC Mini seven okay
machine the
terminal or whatever then you have
another one
a variation M type now remember it's M
type okay because how do you know it's M
tight because you look at the
arrangement of the letters on the on a
keyboard right so it's supposed to be
EUI a o on the left hand home row GUI a
oh so so look at this one EUI a oh okay
it's they change one key or something oh
there it is EUI oh right and this one
EUI a o again oh yeah so actually right
so let's look the UI oh yeah so they
have several quite a few versions so
that is M type that's that concludes the
discussion about the M type system EUI a
oh okay let's all go at this giant
picture for for a minute okay so that's
M type then the next thing is JIS x 6000
for layout now this system okay so this
system this system is kana based so that
means when you type a key it enters a
cannot directly and the kana is arranged
efficiently you know the most frequently
used is phrase on the home row by the
index by the strong fingers
okay and there's a tryst now they have a
shift key now the shift key you know
just like the u.s. keyboard shift key
they function as a prefix key so that is
you press the shift key release it then
you type whatever color you know then
that color will be different then if you
don't press the shift key so in other
words you don't have to hold down the
shift key and the left shift and the
right shift have the same meaning so
that's about this system yeah that's
that's about this system JIS x 6004 okay
then you have the Truong system this
this is a Tran system the transom is
kana based input and however the layout
it has a safer layout to type English
and that is using Borak and okay let's
look at the big picture okay so again
it's Connor base you see Connor you see
those Japanese symbols those are
phonetic symbols Connor so when you
press a key that symbol appears on the
screen directly you don't have to type
in the English letters first to get that
so Connor based and the Connor are
arranged efficiently the most-used
Connor
you know pressed by your strong fingers
so that's it however the other thing is
that it has the you see you look at the
English alphabet you see a Oh EUI here
so that's it that is actually for AK so
that means when you switch to the
alphanumeric you know the Roman G
English layout the layout is actually
for AK so it's sufficient for when you
actually type English letters so that's
the main thing it also has other special
things like the it also have left and
shift system using your thumb you know
so you know I'm not going to go into
detail about that but basically it's
somewhat similar to the thumb shift
somewhat okay not not exactly the same
so zoom well says the Trung is my true
endgame yeah it's it's a fantastic
keyboard and in fact we have some videos
of people typing on the trauma machine
okay let's let's have a look so this is
a full Tron keyboard apparently they
also have a some sort of optical input
system for pen input I've never seen
people using it so this is the keyboard
and this is someone typing on it
so remember trunk came out in 1987 so
now remember the thumb shift came out in
1980 then you have the M system mm type
M system came out in 1983 then the trunk
1987 all of them are quite different but
all of them are designed to be efficient
for the Japanese input system now I
don't know exactly which one is more
efficient you know I'm pretty sure if
you are in Japan or if you read Japanese
you can they are perhaps studies and
I've talked to some of the Japanese but
I didn't get a clear answer like like
maybe do they have competition to show
which one is exactly more efficiently
and then the others or they maybe they
have computer analysis today for example
today in English language you know we
have websites that compare corty Borak
Commack you know Coleman Walkman Norman
you know you compare different layouts
and you have computer programs that do
analysis and tell you which one is
supposed to be more vision I think
similar must similar Themis exist so
that you know they can so you can tell
which one is more efficient the thumb
shift or the M system or the you know
trunk system but but I don't know what's
the answer so anyway so that's about the
trunk keyboard okay the trunk system
okay okay I think that's it
now there's another system called new
Stickney Stickney I this system appears
to be invented few years ago like five
years ago I don't know exactly well yeah
so I don't know the history about this
much but I think it's invented or I
don't know that system see
three well but it seems have to do with
this guy the guy who created this Israel
new keyboard you can buy this keyboard
and it's very good there are people
American who you know use this keyboard
and and compared to for example a go
ducks and truly organ Amish and they
prefer this one they think this one is
better than over dogs for example and
this is about five hundred dollars US
dollars you have to buy in Japan you can
buy it now like you know they I think
they shipped to USA but anyway you have
to go to their website so this guy is on
Twitter and I've been emailing him you
know I've been you know he's been
chatting helping me sometimes about
these my questions about Japanese
keyboards and input so it's very good so
anyway I mean yeah the keyboard is very
good and he's helpful so you can see
here a comparison of truly economic
versus the Israel new and also
interesting thing about this Israel is
that they have two different sizes so
for you guys who have smaller hands or
women you can you know if you want a
smaller keyboard you can go buy this one
but $500 expensive so anyway that's
about it for today for the talk about
the Japanese language writing Japanese
writing system introduction and the
Japanese input system how do you type
Japanese and Japanese keyboards layouts
you know the variety of them so that's
it okay so that's a long talk okay so
I'm thinking what we gonna do now
one hour and 12 minutes but I use you
here
also mad math cube says so what happened
to these layouts why did everyone
abandon these for QWERTY JJ is what yeah
so so all these efficient layout it
turns out nobody uses it
just like actually the situation is
comparable to the English situation
quote he was a small rack versus Commack
you know Commack is much more efficient
code is much
I mean Warrick is much much more
efficient quota sucks but most vast
majority people
99.999% of people who use a computer to
type English they will still use squaty
they don't even know about virág they
don't even know about
Kobach that's a situation so why what
what so we said we have a soul you know
efficient system for work and Commack
why is nobody using using it well it's
because you know the it's just habit and
the things that how the things are habit
for example why why people don't know
about work because first of all the
keyboard we buy it's all quality labels
you know yeah but we nerds we know we
can study we can you know buy blind keys
or whatever we can learn but for vast
majority to your people your mom your
factory factory workers in Chinese
restaurants dishwashers those who mop
toilets at McDonald's or lawyers
businessmen they are not nerds
you know they buy a keyboard they just
type it so they just see Cody they never
know what the is for AK why do you
need a kilo that's a situation so you
don't get to change you don't that's
it's not easy to change for the Japanese
case basically the the reason it's the
same you know the reason is the same you
know so there is some they are nice
group of people in Japan who know about
this
nice layout and they use it but it's few
it's just like us nuts you know it's
just like those of us those of us who
choose to use war rack or those of us
who choose to be on your own keyboards
you know very few one in whining 100,000
one in 1 million people you know very
few so in the same way Japanese you know
this they they didn't catch on for
reasons just just for the same similar
to the reason Borak didn't catch on when
when Barack is invented because there
are some other issues you know when when
Barack was invented there's already
quality you know typewriter typewriter
machines already popular people don't
want to change you don't want to change
habit by the time you know it's too late
you know too late in the same way there
are different reasons for example the
thumb shift when it came out you know I
read the history of the thumb shift
which one this one this one for example
this these keyboards okay when it came
out its popular actually it became
somewhat popular in 1980s okay so this
these are uniting 80s you know but at
that time its word processors you don't
really you know the home personal
computer is not is just beginning to
happen
so when personal computer happened then
most people you know it also relates to
you know us a because personal computers
you can buy you can just buy from us a
right not necessarily in Japan I mean
you can you know so you can buy maybe
cheaply from USA or something but most
of them are made just you know with Cody
keyboard you don't have the thumb key
you don't have a thumb key like you know
that like that so when the personal
computers becomes more and more popular
and this word processor kind of thing
they become lesser less than populist
puppy
because you know the personal computers
you can put our Microsoft Word you know
just replace these dedicated word
processors then but the most majority of
home personal computers they come with a
coding keybo keyboard so therefore this
becomes less and less popular so it you
know it eventually just died out that's
that's the story I read for the therm
shift system it is that that is the
reason it you know did kind of just died
out and for other systems such as the M
type I don't know exactly what's a story
but I guess it's a similar M type and
then you have the motor on I mean the
trunk you know for similar reasons they
just died died out like you know it's
funny like few years ago three years ago
I asked Japanese people on Twitter which
one is your favorite
input system you know you know I show
them you know the M type you know the
some shift and most of them I mean they
are programmers okay I think many of
them are programmers they choose they
choose the court EJ is the most
inefficient system you know I don't know
why it just so happens that's that way
so okay that's it
but are you still here I think that's
about it so somewhere says the price
would stay high since you only produced
a for niche market yeah okay I think
that's it for today we shut down in one
minute one hour in 20 minutes so like
you can go to a local Walmart and and
get one off the shelf yeah so
so I wonder why don't someone
mass-produce these good keyboards so the
price will come down like you can go -
yeah yeah very low demand yeah for
something this specialized yeah they are
not it's not really specialized now it's
you know it's not like for example you
if you ask yeah I mean I mean you are
saying why don't they just come out the
Fugees through or NEC this big
Japanese companies why don't they just
create just like Microsoft you know they
create a Microsoft version of keyboard
like that with the world they did that's
back then but every time you do that you
there's a risk I mean most people don't
care I mean they don't want to they
don't want to change and I think that's
the reason I mean if you if you are a
big company you of course every company
they are interested in making money
if so therefore if it's a great idea if
they're gonna create if they are going
to create you know we reintroduce the
trunk and everyone is gonna buy it
they'll be rich they will love it
but I'm pretty sure they've thought you
know they know it's not gonna work they
introduced this keyboard they spend huge
amount of money millions of dollars to
make this you know a new version come
out spend huge amount of time in
marketing and it will end up nobody is
buying it then they wasted few million
ten million you know one hundred million
dollars I think that's the case
when you know they yeah
okay that's it for today where is spot
but okay so bye guys if you like my
stuff support me okay PayPal you know
good you go to my website you will see
my paper my amazon gift card and patreon
okay
so support me thank you guys bye