good morning guys
welcome to another episode of exotic
show and today we're gonna talk about I
don't know
today is August 25th 2019 Sunday
California time and let's say good
morning breath love you Jay Simpson and
good morning good morning
Seema's slack and Goodman is e-tron
crazy Seema's slack is that is that how
it's pronounced or C amaz CMAs CMAs okay
it's a it's their what their take way
says come on integrase hike so thanks
for your email reply I did post the link
in last stream in YouTube but it didn't
show up okay yeah
YouTube is problematic you know the
censorship stuff so Dec way he was
showing me a japanese tokyo keyboard
congregation keyboard meet japanese
mechanical keyboard Meetup
you know there's lots of photos and lots
of do-it-yourself keyboards from japan
you know maybe I should show up to show
the picture post a link again or
something
so what's the topic today good evening
from the Netherlands hate Netherlands
okay Nicolas good morning
CMOS okay
so what is the topic today
so should we do JavaScript or should we
do typescript live coding or should we
do go LAN or should we do maybe some
Python or Emacs stuff like he's doing
vim golf beat the [ __ ] of the van Gogh
we must yeah or should we do some some
Emacs tips practical Emacs tips you know
that's usually used for two people or we
can do some practical Emacs Lisp coding
and I'm gonna teach you Emacs Lisp the
power of Emacs Lisp and all other stuff
it can be it can be non-technical you
know if it's non-technical it's over the
place it's going to be you know then
Google is going to pammi
so battle me says I want to inform you
that you should not worry about swearing
on the channel nobody will get divided
yeah that's true swearing is fine but
well you are in Germany right so I don't
know how much you you follow the news of
the culture war so-called culture war in
USA it's really bad so if I do swearing
that's okay you know not too much though
because right now I don't have I don't
make money on YouTube but I'm at the
point where I can press a button you
know it's like apply you know because I
have not 1000 followers I can press a
button and say apply I'm not sure I want
to do that
you know because well anyways so
swearing too much is a problem if you
sweat too much then you yeah you know
you're gonna be a being a great list
also but when you talk about other
things there are certain things you know
it's okay to talk about in any non-white
nations I mean it's but not you cannot
talk about it in USA or a white white
countries eMac Lisp
okay so you
at least : Elise okay so we got two
words for you Magnus and one for :
sabaton amuses I know a lot about
culture war but I know really I know
reality from my personal experiences as
well so my recommendation of flat earth
dumpster fire see it with your own eyes
occasion of the to see yeah it's you
know if you guys don't know about China
Cultural Revolution you should check it
out look it up okay China Cultural
Revolution and there's a great film
called farewell farewell fail farewell
my concubine okay let me tidy it up
so saw talk show and what is is showing
browser oh my starting up Firefox
but I was thinking of a plan to die once
whisker scream and always use so large a
fan so that they cannot be always seen
okay that's a line from Alice in
Wonderland Alice in Wonderland is one of
the work that's cited by mathematicians
in logicians all the time and often by
programmers too well not not so much if
I program as well in math okay so let's
see Emacs Lisp so we shall do south
shout to eMac listen yeah okay so let's
to maybe make this plane my vote is for
20 votes was I'm soaking with Chinese
people behind the Great Firewall on the
oats net on alternate so what's the oat
net okay so let's do eMac this so if we
do you know that maybe we you know let's
not talking to other things you know
technical so you may at least what well
usually you see my problem is picking a
topic you know like if we were talking
about something then you know I can
start talking a lot about it but you
know from from scratch I would have to
pick a topic you know usually I asked
you guys to give me a topic usually that
doesn't work because you guys don't know
what to unless you know like know what I
mean nobody you you you don't have like
you have to think about a topic or if
you are working on something then you
know at that moment you have a question
you know oh I want to know how to do
this so how do you do this thing or that
but in general audible proof you ask
Emacs people what's your you know
questions you have people cannot tell
you know even though they do have a lot
of questions so maybe today is
whoa chatty it's just and you know I
chat to you guys it's like this is a
real live session you know that talking
to people talking to people from Germany
from Netherlands
you know Netherlands I never got the
Cree idea where that is but I do now 14
years now
you know net net like it's to like so to
ASEAN I guess oh you know actually this
is true to any people you know far in
places like outside of your area the
further away it is you have no idea
where they are
so yeah so for example in in Chinese
people in China they wouldn't know you
know the general location of New York or
San Francisco oh you know it's just it's
just a big city in USA meanwhile you ask
any American
where is Beijing or Shanghai like with
the with the relative location you know
these these two are the biggest cities
half of them wouldn't know you know and
not to mention other cities you know
Chongqing you know so many cities and
similarly for Europe you know if you
haven't you know if if you're if you are
in America you never visit Europe you
don't know what are the locations anyway
Scandinavia you know that's the northern
Europe but Netherland is actually part
of the main European continent like to
the west of Germany
well that that probably sounds silly to
you guys yeah of course
[Laughter]
okay so alternative internet zero net
okay I don't know what said haven't
heard of that I need to debug my copy
paste function okay do you have a
question like what Nick good morning
Nick
my topic 8:55 p.m. battle Mucha y : is
so good your topic you you you have a
YouTube channel feel free to post it
okay
Nick says you copy two lines when you
then when you paste there is an extra
new line after the first well yeah that
depends on how you coded you know if you
if you like you can post your code and
maybe we can debug it so Nick is
actually from Brazil maybe even more
mysterious to the average Chinese yeah
you could say that but I'm I'm somewhat
for me with with Brazil because I live
in Paraguay for half a year for a year
when I was 14 in 1984
so battle misses by the way anti-chinese
let's talk about technical topics so
yeah it's focus on technical topics
today
okay here's a question a question from
kick Eric Eric says on Lisp you said in
the past I believe one of the one of its
main limitations is the restrictions of
the Emacs engine can you just run goon
kiya in it is compatibility mode to
break it free yeah you can
the thing is no guile has been around
for like 20 years
and it's not mature yeah so you know you
can you can do that you can use smoke
I'll say Emacs Lisp engine but it's like
building a Linux from scratch you know
like well beta comparison is use Windows
you know just buy a laptop Windows
already install just use it oh you can
use Linux first of all you buy a laptop
you have to find out you have to do
research on whether you know the laptop
is compatible or not you know them even
from the Linux side you know there are
some Ubuntu official Linux website they
say oh this this this these laptops are
compatible okay you buy that then it's
not actually well yeah it's compatible
but then you you start to install you
got problems you spend half a day two
days then your screen wouldn't light up
because that's my experience actually
let me show you you know and i've been
i'm not you know i'm i've been doing
unix admin for 20 years well 10 years
ago at least you know there's a swing
one show up then you go go to stack
overflow you spend hours majority of
those answers are like 10 years old
ubuntu linux you know then you all got
the the quote and whatever you know the
boot in the end then you start root read
about them you read them you know
yeah and eventually you put it up you
know oh then you turns out okay try try
this distro then do this and do that go
to the go to that you know that the the
would console you know the single mod
uses a single user mode then you after
you set up then whenever the Linux goes
to sleep wait wait it won't wake thank
you more hours more hours fit that's
like yeah that's the state of glue kya
you can try it you know you can try it
yourself what what you really want you
know is for Kyle to be you know just
like people can download Emacs okay this
is Emacs compared with pinocchio
download it just use it just like you
know just like no more you max that is a
way to go but that's not going that's
not happening that's not happening being
that's not happening being 20 years 20
years you know the good new dev you know
they fighting over it before it was you
know common least vs. scheme this you
know the people fight this was you know
it's like Emacs versus V but in Emacs
community there's common these versus
Kim DS but that's a big flame war fight
by the way do you see is my lip-synched
is my lip sync to my voice is it alright
because sometimes I noticed the the
video like God it's not synced so let me
know it is it is synced or not
so anyway so it looks like you guys
still know about God
you know Kyle has been 20 it's 20 years
old okay Kyle Kyle okay my cyborg
bathroom you says yes your cyber body
body manages to sink your lips well to
your internal speaker that's great okay
great so maybe we can I can tell you the
story about Kyle because I'm impatient
guy oh okay guy out my god great talk
Kyle that's well I'm not sure whether we
should talk about that because then it's
gonna be 30 minutes about about the free
software foundation the you know the
Utopia vision of you know free software
back into the year 2000 that's the
engine of Gaia okay year 2000 the
language the most popular language is
Perl script scripting language
now today scripting languages for me
familiar to us you know you have Python
you Ruby you have lots of others even :
can act you know work as a scripting
language you know you just type it and
just run you can use it to do you know
clean up directories you know seesawed
mean you know minor stuff and stuff but
back in year 2000 scripting language
scripting language is kind of new you
know the higher higher language when you
have lists of course let's see that's
the this days of the list everyone so
this is this great thing anyway
so you have prepare especially only one
so and then then then tickle TCR become
popular actually I'm not sure I want to
talk about this because then I'm just
going to show you lots of my websites
and I talked about many times you know
in my videos it's history you know its
history but anyway
that pearl is the most popular scripting
language you know it's the first one
popularize everything then you started
to have Tico
TCL okay TCR by this guy okay and he
it's you know suppose they say it's a
Swiss Army you know sory Swiss Army
knife you know that like program was
idiotic program so they like to say
those these kind of things all the time
every every day you see it every day
like like today today you have something
else you know JavaScript o types good no
reaction so can give a [ __ ] they taken
out they're gonna change the world
yeah so in my back then pearl was the
most popular then you have T code
you know the Pro is constant you know
people say Swiss Army of knife grueling
grueling language like you know so
useful for everything and back then the
main language is basically C C++ Java is
beginning to the be there you know some
Microsystems spent millions literally
million dollars on every magazine anyway
C C++ Perl that's the three top most
popular language C C++ Perl c-sharp is
not amended yet okay did you don't have
thought net dotnet came around around
2004 or something
Java began 2000 in 1995 and Sun
Microsystems put huge amount of money on
advertisement so anyway Perl
then you have Kiko TC out you know
that's competing then and this is year
around year 2000 okay this is when open
source just began becoming means one to
starting to you know become mainstream
because Linux and Perl mostly three
things
Linux Perl Apache okay you know back
then you have the you have the phrase
lamps stack okay lamp
OMP OMP so let's go through talk show
ways my talk show my talk show page and
go to such four sections and
go to this is today so whatever today's
topic la MP okay that's the acronym
that's that destined for Linux Apache M
is MySQL and PL that is a stack everyone
uses you know that's that's that's been
a case for at least five years like you
ubiquitous you know that's the main
thing because I mean they are open
source the open source movement just
began and spearheaded by this basically
this for a P P is PHP actually not pro
anyway lab came after so this is even
before well before lamp so Linux Apache
MySQL just began you know before MySQL
you have M SQL okay M SQL that's all
that's before my MySQL it's open source
database okay so so open so it's just
you know and and Netscape around 1998
they released their you know their
browser into the open source you know so
that that is the first industry major
open source movement by a company by a
dying company who write by that time the
Netscape is already dead you know is no
value basically when some software
project you don't have value anymore
you become open source that you announce
it oh we believe we deeply believe in
open source we are going to release our
software and they did that and this
obviously is no help
eventually they became Firefox Firefox
took off that's that's five years later
2005 anyway so so you have Perl and you
have TCL and the open source the free
software and open source they are
enemies okay in free open source is a
like a branch of the free software there
are enemies anyway
the Richard Stallman back then you have
a new new word a GU no new word okay
that I subscribed to that online
magazine you know the vision that utopia
is that open source you know Microsoft
is going to be dead in ten years and so
we you know we are singing a songs of
the new the new new new what well I
should show some of my articles then
okay let's show my articles because
there is a lot there's like tens of
articles about all these things you know
then I'm just going to show a lot old
articles should I do that do you let me
know okay if you you want if you like to
see that say yes because I have a lot of
articles about these things then you
might read the details about this
history so anyway so in year 2000 open
source
you know just begin to start it to
become mainstream and and there's a
scripting language you know the language
popularity is CC prospers Perl in Java
okay maybe Java that's about that's
that's about it you know back back then
also know like today everyone knows
several languages back then you know one
or two that's all you know you're you
you've been programming for forty years
you know like you know mostly that you
are you know you are master of just one
or two languages you use one language to
do things anyway so the soap so the glue
they want you know they that the
thinking is that they want they need a
they need a language for the new
operating system okay is that's 40 years
vaporware the heard
okay so let's see what what so what
topics you want to say want to see so ok
Apache groove Apache groovy - a Patrick
groovy ok I don't know much about Apache
groovy a Patrick Goofy's a I think it's
a based on Perl kind of like you know
went into Java language is impaired
alike see of scripting languages that
depends on what do you mean this well
the syntax is like it's a mix of C and
bash and more more on the bash side you
know it's like okay yeah PP in lamp is
PHP yeah I'm grinning in picture we are
walking into the hood together when we
were that being stable yeah heard is a
vapor where I don't you know it's not
like we're never going to happen you
know I was a deep believer of heard [ __ ]
does Richard Stallman you know I I was a
deep believer in heard you know I
despised UNIX and I you know and so I
despise him I'm into Emacs because it's
to me it's you know it's proper you know
it's better you know correct you know
you you think about things you think not
and thinking and thinking that's a UNIX
see that's an thinking well we are the
fast fastest Oh sloppy you know Pro that
[ __ ] so I was deep you know P do banging
hood anyway so that's known history so
I'm not sure we know she'll know I
haven't heard of nutshell the thing is
you know today since 10 years ago there
are new things every almost every month
you know this great fantastic thing I
mean it is great you know there are many
new shells and stuff you know I think
there's one called fish you know there's
so many now it's like every day there's
a new thing you know this is
this is a result of technological you
know exponential growth you don't even
know it and and many of these are you
know they are good and you know as you
know there are so many replacements you
know they each you know each each one is
faster than previous one every three
years
but we came to the point where you don't
you don't care anymore like you know
this patch and and also this kind of
this shell kind of things you know the
programming has moved on you know you
don't you don't live in Chou anymore you
don't that's not important you know the
important thing is you know Python the
goal and the let programming languages
you can you can write any toward like in
five minutes you can write a grip in
colon or any any others you know in
Python I because I have done you know I
have a butcher in Python and goal that I
showed in one of my talk you know one
hour showing all those you know yeah
because you know I just so try now I'm
not sure what to talk about because then
because every disease almost like every
sentence I want to show you ten links
website for example I can show you my
goal colon grapes script this is this is
my goal and grapes script okay so it's
just hundred fifty six lines you know if
you know Golan you study going on for a
week you can write it too and let's
let's show let's show some examples okay
so go to cut out show go to kiss on top
show page copy the file path okay hold
on a second let me start the Emacs
command saw start command not much so on
the left window you can see all my Emacs
command okay such as move forward
backward apply previous on line next
line DD line and do you know things like
that showing on the left window so copy
the fire path of this buffer go to the
goal and grep script
and such for such for weight search in
this directory okay Santosh oh and let's
search for Haskell because it's not the
most dramatic word programís okay now I
run a program run it okay here's a
result now expand the window and put in
saw find out mod so we got color they
impress the arrow keys you see this is
occurrence of Haskell occurrence
occurrence occurrence in this file next
file next file so three files contains
the word has cow so let's look at this
one press ENTER jumps jumps to the file
location you can see has got what is
here and showing browser okay so this is
the actually the main page so let's show
some other so let's see let's go to this
one open wait okay enter open showing
browser so this is saw talk show March
fifteenth emag B's sitemap python syntax
van design type theory Haskell okay so
anyway so that's my grab you know so so
back to the topic so grip you know you
can even came with right acquit you know
these people like to say oh you they use
arc silver or whatever whatever the grip
you know the yeah so anyway so what so
what is today's topics anyway so oh yeah
so let's go back to the cairo history of
gaia now so back in 2000
you know if Rho is the most popular
language and and the free software is
beginning to become you know they start
to get mainstream recognition then the
richard stallman the free software
foundation they want a scripting
language for the operating system for
their you know hood you know for their
system so they decided it's going to be
gaia so what is kya kya kya is just in
from
a nation of skin this okay scheme is a
one of the Lisp programming language and
back then there was a war between Common
Lisp and scheme this very extremely
heated war you know
comment-list camp and and and and this
what happens in Emacs to to this day you
know because every time you know this
this been happening you know for for for
twenty years
a beast and still so he max you can you
know
so anyway kya kya is a implementation of
scheme you know when you know why
implementation is supposed to be the the
scripting language for the new operating
system the vision is that you can you
can you know the kayo is designed you
know it's a it's also vapour where it's
vapor where for for 20 years now kind of
you you can use it but it's not it's not
stable okay so the kya is supposed to be
you know the vision is that okay you can
cut your code or anything everything in
kayo
sky o is so powerful you know the least
language is so powerful that it was just
compared to compared to see compared to
whatever you know you can compare to
pearl yeah to it yeah it's actually said
you know you can compare to power or TCI
other languages things like that it
supposed to be the the googling language
for everything well as time went on now
20 years sky or is dead you know it's
the state long time ago it's there ten
years ago you know the the gue new word
the glue I'm not sure I phrase that
correctly that's let's let's look up my
articles
let's see if I can find it so such for
that and also such folks oddly scheme
history of scheme
I don't know well let's see
okay go sorry my programming experiences
sorry my programming experiences okay so
wait sorry
scheme okay let's see them I'm trying to
find my essay I write essays here
programming language programming
programming skin and failure this is
written in 2009 okay okay here is
someone says how do you explain that
something as inferiors Python Pete Lisp
in a marketplace despite despite
starting four years later this is
typical okay this is a typical thought
from this Lisp phonetics you know
there's lots of the among complan TARDIS
that's a new school new school you you
may not know it's a dead it's like a
forum online forum okay new school I
don't know if some some of you probably
know it's still maybe you use it even
you know but to most programmers they
don't know what that is so anyway how do
you explain that something as inferiors
Python be teased okay that says that's a
common thought okay Amanda Spurs fan
attacks they believe that because they
believe this is truly the greatest
language but but why is the why is
Python becoming popular you know and
then the rain rain Josh Rick let me tell
me tell you who he is okay he is a
common lisp phonetic he is the mole
among all common lisp fanatics he is one
his probably top three
the mother phonetic among the common
lisp
Fernandez and here's what he says he his
answer is the same way like VHS speeds
the film formats for home video the same
way it will be beaten you know so this
is also very typical and common very
popular answer to this quest
these type of questions you know and
this this VHS thing I don't know are you
guys familiar with VHS probably you know
if you are young probably not today
because VHS you never seen it maybe it's
a tape okay it's a video tape you know
you have CD you have DVD you have DVD
right DVD playing videos movies right
but before DVD I mean DVDs or you know
absolute already today is so streaming
right so DVD before DVD you have VCD
video discs you know v CD popular in
China but not in USA but anyway the big
thing before that is video tape
VHS videotape now so what so what what
is they saying here well when when the
video tape just got invented they are
different competing format formats
why is VHS the otherwise by Sony called
something I forgot what's the name 8mm
or something you know so okay so hope
that from you you are okay so so anyway
there's a war you know like DVD like a
blu-ray okay well after DVD then you
have the blu-ray versus what's the other
name and in blu-ray is also absolute you
know oh my god we are so old so blu-ray
versus this another one but what's the
guy's help me out what's the blu-ray
versus what's the other one
yeah well we can go to Wikipedia but
that's gonna take time so blu-ray versus
what write about DVD is something called
something
like that oh god do you guys don't
remember hd-dvd yes that's right path
Romeo thank you so so when when so after
DVD then then you have the new
technology blu-ray versus HD DVD you
know more capacity more resolution every
everything then the HDD so that the
industry you know they move the movie
houses they make both you know they want
to sell and the machine makers but
eventually HD d HD DVD lost lost the war
so blu-ray is that you know everything
is just blu-ray but even but today
blu-ray is there to you know almost like
very few people use blu-ray anyway so
this is one one about war but before
that with videotapes you have this VHS
versus beta now supposedly the pattern
so these are how they look the bottom
wise VHS the top one is beta I never
have actually never used or seen it the
beta so this is 1970s I was born in 1968
so this is you know I was like under 10
years old so anyway so there is this was
supposed supposedly the PT is much tech
is technically superior but however VHS
one for reasons ok and also if you guys
know the Mac versus PC that's a big
topic you know frame war back in 1990s
and even in 2000's you know Mac versus
PC Windows and of course Mac is not
popular it's always like 10% 5% 10% 5%
yeah you know population use and when it
comes to Mac people that's also what
they like to see like they like to say
you know it's all biased they like to
say oh look at your VHS is versus beta
oh another way they say is that look at
cockroaches you know cockroaches are
they popular yeah so popular but are
they do you really want to be a
cockroach you know the site's nuts you
know
they say but truly it's really actually
idiotic you know you like to believe you
know so if I believe in emacs of course
Emacs is the best most superior you know
editor but but there's a question you
know what why is Emacs not popular why
isn't he you know everyone using Emacs
oh I got a lot reasons for example most
people are idea that's why and of course
Microsoft they do evil things you know
they killed Emacs oh look at P you know
look at VHS vs vs beta you know beta is
the superior one but you know or do you
want to be a cockroach you know that
that's what people say they don't you
know you don't really actually look at
the true reasons there are reasons of
course you know if you look at
everything how things are in history
there are you know plausible reasons I
mean this this is not like physics where
where you can actually find the answer
to something this more exact and it can
be verified but if but but if you
analyze historical things you you know
different people will have different
interpretations but still you can kind
of if you retry you can kind of come up
with you know the reason why but in
general this popularity thing you know
Emacs or editors or programming
languages or you know VHS they are they
have good reasons mostly social reasons
you know the timing of the you know for
example why why why is Emacs let's say
Emacs vs. vim
okay typically they are more much more
vim users than Emacs they are ten times
more vim users in Emacs why is it
because whim is actually better no but
there's a good reason why because first
of all I can tell you why because VI is
bundled with every Unix but not Emacs
that is why that explains basically 90%
over the thing Lin
and you know after eunuchs you know then
Linux Linux is bundled every Linux is
doesn't matter what distribution they
are bundled with VI or vim you know of
variations VI and this is a major reason
that you know universities in academia
professors teach they gotta teach you
know did well yeah you can always
install Emacs but that's one extra step
so you know people learning VI
especially in India I know because I've
no Indian program especially in India
they teach VI as part of the you know if
you study Lin UNIX you know it's part of
the you know programming computer
science education you know that is when
people don't people are you know habit
is a strong force so once you learn Evi
maybe you heard that Emacs is more
powerful whatever but you already know
VI you know just you know just move on
you know you got better things to do you
can you need to find a girlfriend you
gotta you gotta climb the ladder you
know you know you need to find a job you
know do programming you you know so that
is why but that's not the reason
Emacs people think you Emacs people you
know just like any code or bias they
think oh you know that's crap the same
thing happened here you know exactly
like the Mizpah people this these are
the things you hear every day
you know and this happened today to
today's you know different things about
how javascript or you know if you are a
JavaScript code like the few few days
ago last week we talked about as some
young JavaScript code they are thinking
they are thinking o-jama Scooby is truly
the greatest language it's the future
okay probably we are not talking about
any technical eMac this today because
it's you know as I know it's gonna
happen you know now it's 40 minutes but
anyway in general you know when you
watch video
you you know I'd like to do technical
you know because my blogs you know I I
really like to do really technical stuff
in math you know : or whatever and
usually my my language essays they are
not you know there are some language and
language issues that you cannot find our
Stack Overflow
so you know it's like anyway say and and
you get you don't get reader so you know
have a know most first of all people
don't know what you're talking about
because you have to learn the stuff for
a year then anyway my point was that
when you go technical even that's what I
like because because I like it that way
because that actually shows you you know
I like to do something that's more
important you know somewhat because that
means I have done work you know I have
done this work and I show give a
presentation about whatever as opposed
to you know the lots of YouTube stars 1
million two million ten million
followers you know that that that guy
just got ten million followers that that
guy who sees name you know the most
popular YouTube you know you look at
them they are just drama oh you know
every day [ __ ] playing games video games
they got they got the viewers anyway so
so let's go back to talk about this
drama drama then okay scheme failure
okay so in this article okay let me read
it a bit a bit okay so I say wishful
thinking take kicking idiots always
think that it's a psychological defense
mechanism when you are the loser you
enjoy a fancy attaches to comfort
yourself the smack people these people
and UNIX people when it comes to
Microsoft always caught the same old VHS
VHS vs. beta in my life experience and
interest on this issue in the past five
years I found that the word is space
be pretty fair all things considered
successful are successful not because
they are devious successful people or
products in any industry may be
computing singer musics software
business are due to reasonable causes
social and/or technical for example the
mundane hard-working good price versus
performance ratio and good advertising
talent and with perhaps a little what we
have to court fortuity and also that's
that's what I think you know I still
believe that is true you know successful
people or companies not because they are
oh that they are doing evil empire you
know that's not true
you know when maybe when when they
became successful when when they become
hugely powerful then they become evil
maybe okay Wow actually that's probably
true Microsoft Google we can see
Facebook began Evo in anyway and Twitter
began good okay and but now it's evil
well anyway in general to become success
successful it's not it's not devious
things okay it's rather you know hard
work and you know you know the right
adverb you know the good marketing and
part of it is luck okay oh no second I
think my roommate is back I mean close
the door
okay that's my roommate
so actually so anyway that's my
complaint about scheme and yeah another
common misconception is that lease
people they always like to say everyone
is copying this you know when Pearl come
up with it least you know Oppo is just
copying this and did a bad job
the in Python come along there's the old
pattern
you know then some people idiots you
know programmers they say oh python is
this you know it before he was / was at
least this is common by the way this is
not you know one once in a while this is
you hear a lot programmers say it
okay Inc in programming communities you
know when Pro is popular is a purple is
a lisp power is a you know or sometimes
you hear is per list and right it's well
maybe maybe not that one for pearl but
Python okay so sometimes you're here is
per Python is leased plant turn right or
sometimes you know Python is a lisp
truly idiotic I I did a video last week
that I talked about this the whole
entire 100 is about Lisp what makes a
language Lisp when can you say a
language this okay that's one our talk
so check it out check it out guys on
that the video is about this and you
know then then Ruby you you will hear is
Looby is Ruby a list you know like you
can search right now you you'll find it
Ruby your list you know or python is
Lisp this will be will be usually it
happens in in you know like for example
this one on Quora which language is more
similar to this Java Scooby anyway you
you are here that Ruby is this or Python
so this often
usually happening in forums like hacker
news Slashdot you know the comments we
already you know idiotic you know it's
extremely do idiocy
everything is at least and and and by
the way it is true that many programming
concepts originates from this ok this
includes least okay at least you know
today every language has least macros
okay this mark was a lot language has
list markers today you know they they
try to have it closure
you know the closure is also a concept
from this I yeah originally from skin
less lexical scoping that's also from
this from skin exceptions that's also
from this okay or engine re but but but
this exception has nothing whatever to
do with Python or Java exception those
idiotic people's factor programmers in
fact UNIX philosophy [ __ ] the UNIX
people anyway so let's read the comments
let me keep continue know the
conversation is there any editor so so
Kate Carrick says speaking of Python is
there some editor that is to Python what
Emacs is to this yeah there is basic but
yeah there is that's called that's
commercial that's commercial software
you have to pay
it's called anyone remember the name
from this company okay so let me read
the comments keep the comments coming
okay so let's see how many people are
watching 13 okay so maybe 10 more
minutes random talk about let me read
the comments
so you're talking about you want a good
Python editor yeah there is a good
Python editor I tried it for like one
hour I'm not impressed
I'd rather just use Emacs but it's a
editor dedicated to Python coding and
it's commercial it's made by I mean by
the way this company is great they truly
do great editor you know their focus is
on editor
anyone knows the name type the name fees
for example they have a editor for Java
for Ruby for Python for yes IntelliJ
IntelliJ yes thank you
Oh Lake good morning or like IntelliJ so
IntelliJ is a company name but they they
know the brand shop I mean they make
dedicated editors for Python for Ruby
for web coding you know for Java and
JavaScript
I mean JavaScript typescript anything
web coding one editor and they have that
and and let me mention okay I tried the
Python one and I prefer Emacs okay I
tried the Python one for a bit I am NOT
impressed at all impressed you know I
find nothing nothing of it is better and
I prefer Emacs for the Python language
now let me make sure this for Python but
however the intelligent Ellijay company
they produce editors that in many ways
that's far beyond Emacs okay far beyond
what Emacs can can can do I mean you can
you might still like image here's why
okay because they actually create static
analyzers for the programming language
or in many cases a compiler a parser so
let's not let's forget about Python
because in a python case I prefer the
Emacs then they are Python editor okay
let's go to their website
they have several editors you know each
one has a different special name for
different languages like storm this of
this a PHP one there is the languages
okay let's go to languages just just
just show me the editors which page is
it tours okay let's go to tools
okay so many here AB code CD on data
load data grip what the [ __ ] are these
Oh : okay coal and gold land is for :
phpstorm is for PHP Tai Chung is for
Python yeah I tried that I don't like it
Ruby mines for Ruby right I am not sure
what writer is wave storm is for web you
know JavaScript typescript and so on you
know so they have like one for each
language now but let me say because
because they are company a commercial
company they make money and they hire
professional programmers so they are far
better than open source okay they
because they they have they have passes
in compilers they create customized and
what's the point about that because in
many languages you cannot for example in
Emacs let's show you a Emacs code okay
so for example okay so here is my Emacs
code let's go through top news you know
so here's Emacs Lisp code you know you
have syntax colouring and you know and
so on and you have completions but
however those are you know the
technology of Emacs is all turned by
regular expressions okay that's the most
stupid you know like a poopoo means way
to to cynics a dirty highlighting so
let me explain so it's done by regular
expressions meaning that you just you
just find the words and you color it and
you use regular expressions to find
particular pattern and you color it in
southern way that's that's all as
opposed to you actually have a parser
for the language when you have a parser
for the language you know you you
understand every word you know every
string every sequence of symbols what's
what what is their purpose well whether
it's building or whether it's from the
library you know you understand a lot of
that as in particular you understand
variables when you see a variable for
example in Emacs
for example let's see if I can find a
function with okay my function typically
don't use variables okay so here here is
example you know delete forward bracket
pairs you have a variable you see its so
if you syntax color by regular
expressions there is no way to know this
is you know global variables or a symbol
from somewhere else or it's a parameter
you know function you there's no way
okay or extremely hard you know you got
extremely difficult if you syntax color
by regular expression now here you see
it's red because that's because I'm
using the outside that's a that's
cheating okay so I put its my own
convention when you have a head sign
something that means this variable is a
parameter of a function okay so you can
see you know it because in these spaces
so anyway but if you have a proper
posture for the language then you know
you know a lot about that about it and
and you can color properly you know you
can color if you it actually happens in
one of the intelligent lgj editor where
they actually call up properly this is
impossible without a parser that is a
key so on average engine and by the way
this parser will is not
going to be the same as the compiler
that's a different thing because
compiler you can you know it's quite
different because when you compare our
language you write a compiler and parser
is part of it
you know the first step you know you
pass it then you compile it but that
parser is different for the purpose of
when you want to do syntax highlighting
or understand static static analysis
that that pasa is different you cannot
just use that you know is so so they
actually have dedicated parser to to do
these kind of things that intelligent
lgj so I have article I showed that I
compared all these different editors in
the syntax hydrated hydrogen so let's
show that I compared Emacs vim and
intelligent Ellijay and also browsers
for example JavaScript in browser they
also sync as color okay so this is not
the Oracle this is another article but
[Music]
this is another article this this
article is about this article is about
creating a language for force in task
for syntax coloring so there is a
article where I compared syntax color
yeah it's it's buried somewhere so how
to write a major mod for syntax coloring
so you go to my Emacs website you go to
miscellaneous so Emacs means
miscellaneous then you search for usage
for syntax coloring in editors
so here this article compares syntax
coloring of of like five or six editors
so we compared Emacs JavaScript mod we
compared Emacs JavaScript to mod from
Stevie X we compared wim we compared G
edit from Linux we compared atom editor
we compare sub supply the Microsoft
Visual Studio then Firefox then webstorm
web stomp is from the intelligent
Ellijay what's the result the result is
Emacs theme jeah that they are idiotic
okay they are syntax coloring our
idiotic they because the you know they
are all basically based on the regular
expression I actually don't know about
them how its implemented
no G edit but I can kind of guess you
know I know you max one yeah III can
guess they are just based on sloppy
idiotic sing regular expressions which
create inconsistencies because for
example if you have a global variable
named X then you have another variable
named X inside a local variable in a
function if you syntax color without a
delicate deposit there is no way to know
they are different there's no way they
are just X you know and also whenever
you see X you don't actually know if
it's a variable because one of the
symptom is that typically they color a
variable only when the variable is
declared like var something like var
something for example here var text
element that text element is colored but
then elsewhere the text element is not
colored and because why of course why
because it's based on a bigger
expression because it's easy when you
use regular expression you see var
something oh then you know that thing is
a variable you color it like a variables
color but when that thing appears
somewhere else you don't know you cannot
color it you don't
you know you know for example the return
text element that's not color that's
technically wrong you know this you
should color all you know takes elements
variable so oh these are done okay so
the one not that are good ah I don't
remember the details you have to read
the the Firefox Firefox and webstorm
okay if I recall correctly needs to do
them correctly and especially webstorm
from the intelligent IntelliJ they can
actually they actually cut up you know
they cut a lots of things basically that
can only be done when you have a proper
parcel for the language and this is why
for each language you have to have a a
posture dedicated for a language for the
purpose of static analysis you know
that's what they call it static analysis
this this concept is popular today
because like Haskell everyone wants to
have a language where you can know a lot
info before you actually run it so you
don't have so you reduce compile time
errors or you turn any compare time
errors to I mean you you you reduce
runtime errors you true you want to try
to move any runtime error to compile
time error so that you can you know know
it
okay I think I'd like that grass a lot
like randomly I don't know where I am
now so yeah so let's just random chat
let me finish the okay let's copy copy
here so type comments okay questions let
me go over the comments quickly I don't
know I don't remember what I was talking
about why are we talking about editors
comparison IntelliJ oh yeah someone
asked dedicated Python editor
so this PyCharm but I'm not impressed
for that one so just for Python just use
Emacs speaking on Python okay so Kay Kay
weak okay that's that's my answer
so character I think there is Luca
Python right I don't
okay I guess that's another one so Emacs
is like atom text editor but from the
80s I don't know about that so yeah yeah
dad Taku yeah Tucker I used evolve in
emulator on top of Emacs that's great
steam Seema's says face for my keep see
why to pasting Firefox yeah chicks Pig
Emacs that's right alright
IMS gets all the ladies you know if you
like you can go
IMS he has his own website personal
website you can read it I haven't been
reading it for full of it for 20 years
but he but no no and then you know I can
I go see it and he has you know he is he
is very you know he's he's a nerd right
like me he's a nerd but he is he is now
he has no idea he's doing pretty bad
when it comes to publicity like you know
one time he picks something from his
foot and eat it you you guys you know
have you guys seen the video have you
not hey if not you know maybe you can
check it out so he I mean this new dress
you know you just you know you dress up
yeah you know even a t-shirt but but
he's doing things you know he's saying
things that's you know any public you
know find it abhorrent oo 'king about
girlfriend stuff you know like he like
like you know I'm you know my name is
IMS I am something something I like
dance and and if you like if you share
my something something get in touch so
case the windows is evil stuff that is I
love plastic defense oh that's a low
plastic defense a low plastic adoptions
let's see what that is a low plastic
adoption is a form of adoption where the
subject attempts to change the
environment when faced with difficult
situation okay
okay so IntelliJ yeah so something from
that family yes hello sir hey Oleg
PyCharm for 1500 what do you mean
so what is PyCharm for 1500 what do you
mean editors eat a lot Ram yeah I guess
yeah the well yeah one advantages of
Emacs is that hey you know it's Lee its
Lee you know back like 30 years ago
Emacs is known as you know and see Emacs
eight megabytes and the constantly
thrashing and C eight megabytes and
constantly S stand for what it means
like the disk is swapping in and out of
the virtuous constantly swapping yes
that's one of the equipment a joke about
Emacs and back then eight megabyte is
like the biggest you can have you know
that which you know anyway today Emacs
you know compared to all the others the
others uses ten times more memory than
Emacs because I've tried you know I want
one day right in crisp it clicks is one
of the worst
okay so simisage a crisp ide has proper
not which make your expression highlight
okay but however in my opinion he chris
is one of the worst is it's written in
java when you launch all your cpu fans
started to hold any any java things you
beginning a java if you do java dev you
know you start the java virtual machine
or your cpu fans started to work that
you know that's you know i don't i don't
have money so my machine is like
typically four years old that's what
happens with eclipse
any imaging Java I hate hate Java and he
creeps yeah I want a mic impaired or
virtual ode or the Microsoft Visual
Studio you know Emacs today you download
is it's like 120 150 megabyte you know
you download you unzip it you know or
you know conceive it you know they it's
hundred fifty megabytes wait no no no
when it's zipped it's hundred 20
megabytes something like that oh yeah
hey Java don't you know bathroom you you
didn't know that Java is the worst [ __ ]
possible that and that is why I don't
like closure you know otherwise closure
would be great but closure is like it
tries to integrate itself into Java in
every way this to such a degree you
cannot learn closure without you
actually have to know a lot Java stuff
including the package the environment
the JVM machine the heart booting you
know it gets complex you know you have
because every time you start Java
machine at any time you run Java program
including closure you start to compare
closure you have to eat you know because
it's written on Java so use you actually
start the Java Virtual Machine and that
takes you know just takes a while you
know more than Emacs it takes a long
time you know start travel machine and
immediately it sucks in your memory it
sucks you know several I don't know how
much now but it's xx half of your entire
memory then okay so then you know so
then you quit you know after you done
comparing it it quit when you want to
compare again the whole thing repeats so
people started to think we you know so
there's a concept of hot booting meaning
that you you always have the Java
Virtual Machine running but then you
have to setup configuration anyway I
don't like Java at all then there's a
Java you know the environment because
for example to to to do any closure you
have to download close your jaw
then then you have you have to have this
linic on which is like entire package of
config and [ __ ] you know she'll
scribbling again is a shell script and
then you have this this that then you
have Java files in a temp directory then
then you know and and I've talked to
closure people just like every other
code idiots you know they you know you
sometimes you say that you talk to them
they I mean they are part of the list
fans okay
typically these people want to learn
closure and they say Oh a closure is
great great and they owe you don't need
to know Java at all that's patently
false in order to actually understand
closure to some what a good degree to be
a good programmer to know the crucial
language you have to know Java quite you
have to know actually quite a lot
details technical details of Java
because closure in documentation
everywhere they expose Java they it's
you know when I start to learn closure I
was thinking oh great this is at least
you know family you know I love you know
I like this you know even I I complain a
lot but in general I like the you know
nested parent and it's simple you know a
function them yeah and it's functional
programming I love it
so I done closure you know I was
thinking oh it C implemented on top of
Java that's great because Java is very
popular and then you have all the median
Java libraries available to you and also
so you know we can you know so it's
great but it turns out it's a that's a
pipe dream but it turns out that the the
main problem is that closure is you know
it's so called a hosted language like
JavaScript you know it's not like
language by itself it's so cold
you know technically they call it hosted
language that means it's a language it
lives on top of some other environment
thing you know in the closure case you
it lives on Java Java Virtual Machine
and there's a version on Microsoft
Arnett okay so it's a hosted language
anyway but I'm thinking you know at
least you can do it in you know I I you
can it is a independent you know I can
just learn culture I don't really have
to know Java you know that's not the
case because in every way actually I
found out later on intentionally they
tried they make Java as part of closure
it's like one thing you know it's not
this but the thing is you know when you
talk to close your fans you know people
like bias this is what I'm calling you
know bias encode they don't they don't
see it they don't agree like when you
say oh crochet is in you know you have
to know a lot Java they say oh no no you
don't have to get off you know you to me
okay I don't know about you okay but but
to me that's like patent patently force
that's like one plus one equals two
three in every judgment you can ask any
person outside US when you want to some
you want when you want to get some
judgment you know a fair judgment
usually you get opinion from outsiders
not associated with any closure java or
political party then that is one of the
way to to get you know to to get a sense
of what other people think you know
anyway anyway however you look at you
know closure is like for example
entirety you know an intertwined with
java you cannot know closure where well
without knowing very some complex things
about java okay for example let me just
give you one simple example in closure
when you want to manipulate string let's
say take the first five characters out
of a string you cannot do it okay you
have to call a java class method let me
make let me make this clear
you have to enclosure i have a lot of
articles okay i have written about this
you know it's such focus sorry
Crozier such folks sorry Crozier Java
get such for that sorry Crozier Java
you'll find it so if you want to train
strain or take the first five characters
of a string in closure you have to you
have to write your code in a way closure
has a way to code Java classes Java
methods this it's a particular syntax
okay let me show you okay
sorry closure kochava method okay so you
have to you have to write this then call
the Java string class okay and in those
method that is how you want how you take
a substring in other words closure do
not have its own string library
[Laughter]
imagine that you know you want to do
string string string is the most
fundamental every programs you need need
to manipulate strings you could like
take you know you call you have to
create a new channel class you know the
it becomes oo P factor okay you know it
becomes so you have to use a Java method
now by the way I think I read last week
I think you know I just happened to see
I think maybe they closure they have
their own string libraries now I'm not
sure I haven't done closure for a long
time but well anyways this is an example
okay closure
let me sorry closure Java okay lots
about articles I want to you know
because okay this talk is getting very
long so these two articles okay closure
call Co Java method closure closures
popularity or tongue tangle with Java
and close your magic characters that's
pretty bad closure why closure is dense
okay here's why I explained so you know
I came to closure out of you know
I would love it because it's functional
for women because it's this but I hate
Java okay but and then it turns out you
know closure is like it's not just like
somewhat based on Java it's like in
intent this is intentional like
intention intentional deep integration
with Java and later I understood why I
understood this this article you know
trapped in Java train northbound is
closure southbound is Scala so why does
we cheeky you know in you know dragging
Java into closure because Java is the
number one you know the top number five
most popular language you have turns the
programmers Java in the industry Java
industry is typically enterprise
programming you know very boring but a
lot of money you know the databases you
know financial or whatever transactions
you know very boring enterprise coding
large of our programmers typically Java
those programmers they are not
interested in functional programming
they are not interested in you has cow
what is that you know that's what they
are
no Java so closure intentionally mixed
wing with Java because then you can tell
this Java people hey come to closure you
know we are you know we are everything
you know applies you don't have to learn
much you know almost everything you know
this is like Java but with a closure
library you know that is why it is you
know this is how Crozier is popular this
is the main reason one of the main
reason okay
closure become popular it's because this
Java you know ingratiating you know with
Java so I was deeply I was rather you
know I learned crucial I coded for like
altogether for one year I was deeply not
satisfied you know not because the
design you know I think he's design you
know okay something maybe I don't like
something I like
now rich Hickey not because that be good
but because there's actually you know
heavy intentional Chavez to stuff in
closure now by the way if you are a
typical programmer maybe you don't see
it because I see a lot programmers there
they going around they are you know
hotshot programmers they are the CEO
oh I'm the you know CEO or the you know
tech you know the CEO executed seed you
know the the the the the tech tech head
okay of a company or startup you know
there's oh yeah they are you know our
company may use Scotia but typically
they don't they are not like me or my
type okay um or maybe you guys okay they
they don't when they do a language they
just they just they just code okay they
don't really understand the details they
just they just code and you can walk you
know you can you can you know you just
code and do things create software and
including I would say including book
writers you know because I've read a
book of crochet you know he says oh I
you know he's I think he's a start-up
some company he so he learned closure
and he wrote a book I read that it's
like you don't learn things actually you
know you what are you teaching you know
there's nothing there you know in fact I
can tell you you know you ask any
closure offense today you ask them they
don't understand the details of how a
closure you know the sequence in any way
he is you know at least how he exactly
works because it entails Java it
intell's the Java interface then the
Java interface the Java sequence
interface that means you have to
understand the Java interface thing well
you know that because Java Java is this
giant hierarchy op3 where you have the
interface you have interface inheritance
being of the classes you have instances
you know the anyway that's closure okay
so that's
so what what are you talking about I
don't remember yeah I was reading the
comments okay so yeah so then yeah so I
was saying one day I was you know I
download it I think it crisp and I also
you know download it you know I think I
tried to visual studio any and and you
look at I forgot which one I think both
you know when you start eclipse without
any fire you know you open an empty file
it's already Freddie like two one chica
by memory usage
well you Emacs you know you can have
Emacs 24 days 300 buffers open it's only
five you know that's how much you know
not much RAM much less you know but
increase or visual visual Studios things
like that hey when you beginning it it's
already you know 100 megabytes hundred
gigabytes okay so two more minutes I
guess then then then that's it for today
that's we say let's call it a day
yeah oh [ __ ] proper actually company
which I think's editor called JetBrains
actually the company which makes the
editor is called JetBrains you are right
yeah my mistake it's a jet prints not
the IntelliJ is it is their Java IDE
Java IDE
yeah jet jet prints so okay let me read
the comments and that would be it for
today that would be it for today so we I
think I remembered a lot and yeah we
were talking about new kya you know kayo
is like this 20 years old vapor we're
kind of oh yeah jihadi that's right
fifteen hundred
now what about this new language server
stuff yeah so today you have the idea
which is called I forgot the name
language server I have written articles
sorry which that sorry
Emacs Oh Alize okay
this article is my criticism of the
institution as impose language service
thing in Emacs because basically it is
killing Emacs beasts here this article
okay eMac this sucks donkey ass
preschool Emacs and eMac this not
external tools because today there is a
fandom there's a enthusiasm who lets you
know this language server protocol this
new thing came up in last five years or
so so it's a protocol so so so that so
that means this allows IDE of front-end
such as Emacs editor you can use this
protocol to connect a server so what the
server does for example Chavez what the
server does is that it has engines you
know dedicated parcels compilers for
different languages for Python Ruby Java
you know go and whatever so so you have
this language server protocol so editors
you know shrine sublime Emacs beam can
talk via that via the protocol to these
dedicated language service so if Emacs
wants to do syntax coloring you can talk
you know via this language server
protocol you can talk to a dedicated
let's say JavaScript server
you know this JavaScript language you
know parsers server to whatever tools
then the server will give you back some
answers
then emails can color property without
without Emacs itself having to do the
static analysis of the code you know so
that is that is what it is you know
language
server protocol so it is you know it is
a great tool it's one of the new
technology is great but then this is
this is the death nail for for eMac
Emacs that's my opinion
it's you chaos Emacs because the Emacs
power so far you know because because
the power of Emacs came from eMac this
email is you know because everything you
know I you know in every my mod my
coloring whatever I coded see my beast
that's the power which doesn't happen
much in other editors you know Adam is
written in JavaScript as far as I know
it's not like he might be it's it in
anyway that's another topic but anyway
back to so we haven't seen improvements
in him at least for like 20 years wow
this is this a little bit but basically
eMac be stagnated you know it's there's
no it's so bad it's very bad no
namespace I did a I did a video like two
months ago to three months ago
check it check that out that's a good
one that's the title is why eMac this
sucks you know it's one hour
I give detail why eMac this is the
circuits language possible here okay
one of them this one okay yeah both of
them they mark great you know if you
like my stuff and if you are interested
in this check you know watch them both
each one is one hour more than one hour
in detail those are technical details so
eMac this P is pretty bad no namespace
no no libraries no no nothing so and
it's not going and now people are you
know happy you know people wants you
know the language server protocol oh I
want I want the Python mod you know for
OSP you know so that so once you have
this you you killed the you know one of
the outstanding power of Emacs because
now every editor
well Emacs you know just like every
other editor you can just
use this whatever that dedicated wait
okay my logic that's that's not a yeah
language server usually the server also
runs on your own machine blaming my
opinion about this is that this this is
posing a great danger of killing emag
bees you know more and more you will not
see eMac this you will not see
non-trivial you know heavy you know
major progress complex coding Emacs this
anymore
rather the code will be focused on you
know these passes in written in other
language you know they then Emacs with
you you just have simple eMac B's to to
talk to the servers that's that's bad
okay so that's that's my opinion about
this but to most people you know most
people who don't know things you know
who are not who just you know who just
see this oh yeah I like Emacs oh this is
great I want you know I want some mod
that uses this so in my opinion this is
bad I what I really want is I want
people to write [ __ ] writing eMac B's
you don't need this language servers
okay they are you know I have given a
list of great programmers who has all
written passes and compilers in Emacs
Lisp okay but if a Mac this is actually
capable then then you know then gimmick
this is far more powerful you know but
but now with language server you know
they'd write you know they write other
languages you you write these passes or
compilers in other languages because
email is is first of all six times
slowed and then they even Python it's a
[ __ ] [ __ ] problem then you got other
lots of problems need no namespace and
this or that problems and then the new
devs got lots of social and political
problems there is no way to change them
until the Richard Stallman steps now
unless you know unless he steps down
then you know so problems
so I like you know I could make this -
he's pretty bad language you know
contrary to this phonetic phonetics you
know and I know a lot of friends some my
followers some are my friends you know I
actually I've met them I talked to them
and they following me on Twitter and you
know they are also you know so they also
code list you know many of them has
great very popular packages but then but
also meanwhile the they don't see the
issue the way I see it okay they they
are still think miss miss eMac this miss
Quade you know they don't see this they
don't have the point of view like I am
have you know I think you know like me
Mac this B's pretty bad it's very bad
language if you really look at you know
compared to all the languages compared
to Python PHP will be okay even compared
to JavaScript today with JavaScript 2015
eMac miss miss possibly was it was then
PHP even PHP has grown a lot you know in
the past 20 years you know you know look
at you know look up look look at my
those two YouTube videos you know you
watch them so it is feels so bad anyway
so they don't see things you know the
way I see but anyway so that's a lot and
I'm talk so that thank you kid Drake so
if you like my stuff and put put money
in my bank okay I got PayPal and you
know patreon or buy my Emacs book by my
JavaScript book JavaScript in depth and
thanks to Alan I think Aaron's another
guy who has you know pod might you know
website and and some of you donated
thank you guys
okay so let's see what what more
comments the links are on my website
somewhere you know you can easily find
it just go to my blog you'll find my
and stuff ningke's yeah like so that's
about language server insulin I don't
know much about that I forgot what that
is it crisps ideas probably okay so
actually company okay
pour it up fates okay
show that what is that until so that's
why you use groovy and Grady to do
dependency resolutions what is cuvee is
the per like language on Java right I
don't know what is Grady CMAs and what
do you mean dependency resolution I'm
not sure what that is so bathroom you
say is is Java by the way another there
is another major problem practical
problem when you use regular expression
to pass to do syntax coloring this
happens often for example in this file
if I I missed a quote let's say or the
syntax coloring becomes wrong in the
rest of the fire when you miss a quote
and also when you have a regular
expression for example in JavaScript or
Python when you have a regular
expression complicated that tends to
screw up the whole the rest you know the
rest of the buffer syntax coloring these
are problems you know these are
limitations Emacs you know syntax
coloring I I know how it works I mean
you can walk around but this a lot walk
you know you can you can walk around so
that doesn't happen but it gets very
complicated to write you know to do the
eMac based code so
so let's see what else CTO yeah that's
the word CTO
Oh God more comments than I thought I'm
gonna answer all comments so starting
with CTO okay so starting here Deon say
is that okay so tech beats are supposed
to be experienced programmers that can
artfully artfully navigate technical
problems yeah if you have a question for
me type my name our answer those oh god
II is a beer system for Java it's
written in groovy okay looks like you
are a groovy coder
Seema's CMOS where you're from what
country or city so Deon say is my
interaction with such people are limited
and I guess some of them know what you
are doing other stones
I would guess leaders just good and
programming CTO are typically you know
programmers turned turned you know the
lead programmer essentially well in a
small company the whole company is just
five people okay so so if you have five
people you have CEO the founder okay CEO
then you have you know let's say three
programmers if you are the lead
programmer you are the CEO okay then
there are another guys salespeople
marketing whatever you know things like
that you know in Silicon Valley it's a
startup world it's like that you know
back then in 1998 I'm in a company brain
power the whole company is like five
people so I am whatever title and
whatever you know whatever title you
want
okay that's it for today I'm gay I'm
getting tired so that's it anything else
in so if you have a question you have
ten seconds to address you know sorry
something then we're gonna close down we
shut down in 30 seconds so Beyonce is
famous product that he made money of
Emax so SEMA says I'm from New York USA
hey so New York New York USA if the big
decimal fits were it groovy I guess