good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of s talk show today we are
going to do Advent of code
2024 day five
fantastic so I have cleaned up my code
for example yesterday uh day four part
two so it becomes one single line so you
can see this is the day four uh part two
solution uh every solution can be made
into one single
line so the wam language solution is
actually the shortest solution including
you know you including those programming
languages A J and K you know J and K are
derived from APL I believe they like the
new generation of APL a is very TS but
Wen language still beats them
uh yeah if you count you know because
the fun wfam language has Long Function
names so function names should only
count as one character so the best way
to actually count the shortest code is
you consider the code as a syntax tree
so you only count the
knots so anyway let's begin today's uh
event of code
2024 day five okay let's uh am I check
video check One Last Time video check
audio check okay
emac mod uh let's begin day
five okay so let's see the for example
this example and uh okay long long
description uh satisfied with their
search on series something the North
Pole printing department is busy or
something the elf must recognize you
because they waste no time explaining
that the new slide new slay launch
safety manual update won't print
correctly failure to update the safety
manuals would be dire indeed so you
offer your services safety protocol
clearly indicate that the new pages for
serving manual must be print every space
must be printed in a very specific order
the notation X vertical line y means
that if both page numbers X and page
number y are to be produced as part of
an
update X line Y okay uh are to be
produced as part of an update page
number X must be printed at some point
before page number y okay X SL uh uh y
means X comes before y the Al has for
you both the page ordering rules and the
pages to produce in each
update okay page ordering rules such as
this and the the pages to produce in
each update okay your personal
input okay the pages to produce is this
um so you got a
hello so this is ordering this is the
pages uh but can figure out whether each
update has the pages in the right
order okay seems like you need to
reorder this bunch of
numbers okay the first section specifies
the page okay so the first section
specifies the page ordering rules okay
one per line the first rule
4753 here um means that if an update
includes both page number 47 and page 53
then page number 47 must be printed at
some point before page number 53 so you
got got two
numbers um if the numbers are in this
you know number sequence if
okay
um okay so if the numbers both of
them are in this number sequence then
the first one must appear before the
second one okay the second section
specifies the page numbers of each
update because most safety manuals are
different the pages needed in the
updates are different
too the first update
7547 6153 29 okay that's one line means
that the update consists of page number
7547 okay to get the printers going as
soon as possible start by identifying
which update are already in the right
order okay uh now this bunch of numbers
they are separated into lines so the
question is what is the significance of
the lines are they like different
um so to get the printers going as soon
as possible I start by identifi
identifying which updates are already in
the right order okay so you got a bunch
of lines each line seems to be
independent of the other so you just
need to say which lines are the right
order given this bunch of rules in above
example the first update that is in the
right order uh 7547 61
5329 it's in the right order because 75
is correctly first because there are
rules I put each other page after
it okay you got to be careful here 75 47
75 61 75
53 okay 47 is correct correctly
second uh because 75 must be before it
7547 and every other page must be after
it according
to
uh
47 okay yeah
okay so 61 is correct in the middle
because 75 and 47 are before
it okay and 53 and 29 are after it 53
and 29 53 and 29
okay then 53 is correct fourth because
it is before page number 29 okay
29 okay okay let's look at how many
occurrences is
53 it also appears here so these pairs
of
numbers they indicate that the first
number must come before the
second okay now is it possible for these
rules to conflict itself yes you know if
you have two you know if you have seven
53 then you have another that's 53 75
then you got a problem so it's possible
this these ordering rules conflict with
itself but in multiple ways not just one
reverse pair because you could have a
cycle
uh let's say you have one two then you
have 2 three okay then you have let's
say another number
31 that
conflict you know so you know this this
list of rules pairs must be consistent
okay we have to watch out for
that um do we I don't know because the
first update does not include some page
numbers the ordering rules involving
those missing page numbers are
ignored uh the second and third update
are also in the correct order according
to the rules like the first they also do
not include every page
number um okay so only some of the
ordering rules apply within each
update okay the ordering rules that
involve missing page numbers are not
used uh within each update the olding
rules that that involve missing page
numbers are not used
okay so some of the pairs may contain a
number that's not in one of these line
that's something like that so in the
above example okay so let's see uh the
fourth the fifth update is
61 61 1329 is also not in the correct
order since it breaks the rule
okay okay some of them are not some of
them are the last update is not in a
correct order due to Breaking several
rules so for some reason the elves also
need to know the middle page number of
each
update being
printed
complicated uh they also need to know
the middle page number of each update so
One update is just a line so they need
to know the middle page number so does
that mean the
update are always odd number of
pages
uh so let's see uh okay
so in above example the correctly
ordered update are these three and this
have middle page number of 61
5329 okay adding this page number
together gives that number of course you
need to be careful the actual list the
page ordering rules is bigger and more
complicated than the above example of
course determine which update already in
the correct
order what do you get if you add of the
middle pages okay
so given a BN a pair of a list of pair
of numbers and also uh list of line a
sequence of numbers a list of sequence
of numbers I mean several list se you
know several several sequence of
numbers you want to determine which of
these sequence is in the right order
okay so pick those then for each one you
pick the middle number
then you just add it
up okay that's a problem let's solve it
okay uh begin coding X input this is a
toy input so let's
copy let's begin to code wol frame
language
copy uh so this is actually two parts I
mean this you know this
you know you might have
to do string
split um and uh so a short
description given a list of pairs of
numbers and
given given uh list of lines is
each line
contains a sequence of
numbers uh pair of
numbers pairs okay uh and the okay okay
so anyway so you for for
each um so we describe the problem
meanwhile this description also kind of
give you the algorithm in one shot you
see that's one of the you see when you
program one of the major problem is to
turn the problem like typically it's
fuzzy you know you you want to specify
the
problem into a some kind of mathematical
Precision you see once you do that if
you are able to do that the problem is
already half half solved so you know I
try to block about the Advent of code
and I try to skip you know to simplify
the wordy eles you know but that's not
easy because part of the problem very
significant part of the problem is
actually to specify the problem in a
mathematical way because once you are
able to do that the problem is almost is
basically half solved so that's a
important element
because once we describe precisely what
is a problem we almost already have
algorithm you know you you know um so so
anyway so this bunch of numbers now for
each
line uh check if it is
ordered it is ordered if or
pairs if all numbers in the
line that appears in the
pairs are in the same order as the pairs
okay
now take the middle number of this
line um of all
ordered all
lines uh for each now we are running
into a technical writing issue you see
that's why I'm going about which way is
the best way to describe the situation
so the way I uh would say is for each
ordered
line then for each order line take the
middle number
sum it
up this sum is the
answer that's the answer we we need okay
so what about the algorithm so that's a
here we got a description now how do we
start to do
it so we know we have to to process each
line by itself so line line line line
okay so let's start with one
line for each line you want so the line
so now there's a question about
efficiency is this bunch of rules larger
or is is this lines
because we want to start with a smaller
one like do a for each that would be
more efficient I think I'm not sure but
so let's look at the personal
input you know what is our personal
input okay copy it have a look at that
and uh let's go
to Advent of code
uh index I need to save this
here okay open new buffer paste it copy
that save it paste it and uh this is
stve five
okay there it is day five okay so 1,300
lines okay so okay
so 1100 lines of the pairs
then
um then just 17 I mean 170 lines of
numbers okay so which one
is so let's look at
this you need to process one line at a
time at
least uh let me see the comments
comments okay comments start your own
gold M eating salty bread and listening
to uh go ahead
Louis what
go ahead is what Jan says the problem is
indeed too
ridiculous uh do I agree okay so anyway
so we back to the
problem so for each line it's there's a
bunch of numbers you want to determine
if it's the right order so what is the
right order the order is deter
determined by a bunch of
pairs so you see some of the pairs the
number appears multiple times this is
this is
idiotic you see they are not ordered by
canonical order of
integers you know two does not
necessarily mean it comes before
three the order is determined by these
pairs of
this uh which
is this this pair of list is very
silly because there's a lot of
redundancies it will be
good it would be good if this pair this
of pairs is Rewritten so it is become
simply a sequence of numbers by the
order
okay yeah so let's look at the example
let's see uh for example let's
see you see this
32 I mean this 34 25 so that means 34
comes before 25 so it's not the normal
order so let's think about you see
there's a lot redundancies you see 2121
repeated so many times so it be
nice and kind of and relevant to the
problem if you just rewrite this into
just a sequence of numbers by the
order okay that's let's let's keep that
in mind okay then let's go back to
this so how do you so given two numbers
how do you know if they
are you know in order
to determine if this line is
ordered with which essentially means you
can sort this sequence of numbers by a
order okay and the order usually comes
by a function the function takes two
numbers you know it returns true or
false okay so so this sequence of pairs
is effectively the ordering
function okay so actually that that can
easily translate to programming
languages because many programing
languages when you sort they take the
ordering function okay and
uh and uh it's easy okay it's easy to do
so let me just think about the I I'm
already there so
yeah okay so I got it I think I got it
now now now there's another requirement
the middle of the line the that mean is
always R number of
um num you know our number of total
numbers in each
line I assume but you know we have to
check but it's not trivial to
check yeah we can do it but it take two
minutes um but okay
so okay let's start to code so what you
going to do
so I need to think about this a little
bit
more I can start to code as well but
um so each line you want to determine
whether it's ordered or
not in order to do that you can you know
there is a woan function which allows
you to do that easily uh what is
this uh yeah a wolan function um you can
simply
codee ordered okay let me let's look up
the
documentation okay that's
um that will return either true or false
okay and uh and P is the ordering
function okay P you know we need to give
the P function second
parameter uh and what is uh what does
the p function do the function takes two
numbers okay and either
returns
uh one Z or negative 1 or true false
okay so one means E1 comes before E2
okay okay so this is a tricky
mathematical issue you see some of some
programing languages their ordering
function
takes uh return value must be three
possible values one Z negative 1 uh the
other some other functions is just true
or false
okay uh so
yeah but wam accept both both ways
so so this is so simple
um but how you want to do it you want to
order it okay so let's see so we don't
need to turn this into a sequence of
order numbers we can
simply turn this list of pairs into a
Association list or also known as
dictionary and hash
table okay so but
um but wait but what about reverse uh
for example let's look at
29 so does is it true every second
element in this pair also occur as the
first element
uh yeah I don't know
so so if we look at
uh you know so if we look at this
oh God this this is you know this like
1,000 of
them so if you look
at
98 you
see so if we got a
number uh
uh yeah we can turn this into
Association list that's easy you know I
I think maybe I should just start to
code because talking too much is not
good for live stream so let's begin just
start to code okay and and and worry
about things later okay so
let's just worry about one line okay so
this toy
problem uh let's just worry about this
one single line This toy problem okay
and uh ordered and this needs to be a
Association okay let's do let's turn it
into
Association I
mean a dictionary Okay so
okay that's how you do it uh so
let's so each number Association you can
refer it
to just just just turn it to Association
okay so let's just do that
replace that
by okay and
add add a comma okay and basically cut
that okay and you don't want the last
comma and uh so
dictionary equals to
that and uh
when so if we have
29 so if we got two you see you got two
numbers okay so usually so here you got
two numbers uh function let's write the
function this is ordering function okay
ordering function takes two numbers and
must
return return true or
false true means they are in order false
means they are not okay so the the
question is to write the function and in
order to write this function the
function will use this this this
dictionary for efficiency so so you know
um since since we already have you know
pairs
so so this function return will return
true or false true means in order so
suppose given a number
29 you know it it when given n number it
will pick let's say uh you know
7547 so is it true or
false easy if you find an entry of
75 and you find another entry of
47 then you know it's true I mean if you
find the pair
7547 then you know it's
true there it is you see we actually
found
it
7547 there is the sear pair so it's
ordered
but but given let's say
4761 what you going to do
4761 uh there is also
there
idiotic now what about
7561 it's also there stupid oh
well yeah that's because
um what what about if you have 6175
okay then you don't have that entry
okay
therefore this pair of sub numbers is
not sufficient for this
function uh you know so if you have a
number
61 but you but you don't have a entry
that's 75
five so that means you need
to use
inference so in other words this
sequence of pairs of numers is not good
okay it's just not
good this sequence of pairs of
numbers seems you know it's seductive to
programmers because it looks like oh you
can just you know that's just the
ordering predicate
function but not
really because if you are given a number
61 and
75 you cannot directly determine their
order you have to have inference so in
other words this sequence of pairs this
set of pairs you need actually like we
talked before you need to turn them into
just a sequence of ordered
numbers okay so we have to start to
think about how to do
that okay let's make sure that is the
right
approach
61 may or may not be
there and even if it's there the second
value may not be
75 so when the second value is not there
what do you
do
uh what do you do you have
[Music]
to yeah you it's very hard you you need
some kind
of more
complete list so that you can compare
any pair of numbers
okay so another way to do it is let's
think about so because these numbers are
not each line is just a
finite item of numbers okay now let's go
back we need to go back to this to the
yeah uh we need to go to the Advent of
code list okay I mean the
input okay we forgot to grab the input
copy it close close
close back
here we need to
say x input equals to
uh read string
okay so we can easily refer to this so
if we go here let's
say each line is just
finite you see what I'm getting is that
you do not necessarily have to create a
complete list of
orders because each line you only really
just need to do a few weight but
actually but then you do the next line
the next line all the lines have
different numbers
so so you actually need
yes so the first thing to do is you
actually need to
generate a fairly
complete sequence of numbers by their
order specified by these pairs
okay
so yeah so we need to build that
God because this is what this is day
five okay day five is a bit complex
cheers this is coffee and
eggnog with alcohol
so you want to get
uh let's see uh
well function you you want to determine
if they are ordered or not okay
but when you have a number that's not in
the list what you
do so
61 you got a entry of
61 uh you got several some on the left
some on the right but do you have a 75
do you have this pair there it is 60
6175 so wait
so it is there in this example
but you see this is tricky because the
whole universe of numbers may not be
just one to a
thousand it may be missing you know it's
basically each of these number you don't
want to think of them as numbers you
want to think of them as just a thing
like those numbers are just a label for
the thing
so the all possible things is not just 1
2 3 4 5 and so on it may be one 2 and 9
and 23 24 25 and
1,001
so the you know the the universal set is
not just ordered sequence of
numbers so meaning that which means
that this this
Association appears to be you
know spotty but it may actually be
complete for for for this uh these
numbers yeah okay so it's getting more
complex uh I
mean so this is really you know this
about all the theory all the theory is a
complete branch of mathematics
uh so let's focus on on what to do so
61 the first number check check if this
pair okay so the first
issue first
issue given two numbers
first check if
there is a pair
of these numbers in the
dick order does not
matter order of the pair does not matter
okay then if it's there then it's easy
you know if the
order if the order is the
then return true meaning they are in
order if the order is not the same
meaning they are out theable the return
return Force so that's
done so but what
if one of the number is not in the
deck okay
and there are two
cases the first number is in the key of
dick
but uh wait the first number is in the
key
the other case is the first number is in
the value of a dick uh it's starting to
get
[Music]
confusing
so what if one of the number is not the
dick in in the dick so one of is not so
there are two
cases the first number is not okay so so
again actually there are two
cases
okay uh then the other case is the
second number not in the dick not in in
keys or not in values okay
so each of these is two
cases okay so okay so let's just let's
just spec this out
because uh the first number not in
not in the
keys okay
okay something like
that so they are total of four cases
first number not in a
keys not in
values so when the first number is not
in the
keys however it is in the
value what does that
mean it doesn't mean anything because
you for this function to work you really
need both numbers to be in the
pair
okay um
okay
so so when one of these number is not in
the in the key or
value then you cannot directly determine
whether they are in or
not however it's still possible because
there's uh in
inference um and the other
case is what
if both
numbers are not in
the
dick not in key no value
then that's a problem when this
situation happens there's a error with
this
problem that means the event of code
up what what if both numbers so given
any two numbers from the line both of
them are not in in in the key value so
that means
that means we have no way to know whe
whether they are in order or not so that
means Advent of a code
up
okay so it just needs you know the
situation is
um you know is both numbers are there or
one of them is not okay
oh God one hour to analyze the
problem okay but um what's
next so now we
know so I think we do come back to the
original
intuition that we simply just need to
rewrite these pairs into a ordered
sequence okay let's think about how how
to do
that re write the given list of pairs
into a sequence of ordered
numbers that way given any two element
we can tell if if they are in
order by
comparing their
indexes okay so we need to turn these
pairs of numbers into just ordered
sequence that
would um
yeah that would
um that would be much more efficient
yep
so okay so you see this is tricky
because it's you know it's possible both
of the numbers are not in the pairs at
all so that means Advent of code
up but actually not because that line
containing both of these nonexistent
numbers
you can just say it's not
ordered so it doesn't count so so when
you write code in C or C++ you you got
mysterious error
errors uh okay so back to this any
comments comments
questions okay so you need to turn this
into just a sequence of numbers okay
let's think about how to do that
how to do this
okay this sequence okay
so start with each pair then you just
um then you just
43 add them to a
list uh you need to insert in a proper
position
uh
9713 so for each
pair if the first number is not in a
existing list add
it then you want to add the second
number so the question is where do you
insert
it you
inserted just write after the first
number okay so the first step we have a
list of 47 and
53 then Second Step 97 is it already
there
no
uh so you need to add
97 and uh it's greater than 13 is 13
already there oh God you got so many
cases so if 13 is already there then it
matters the 97 must come before
13 so but if 13 is not there if both
numbers are not there then you just add
that uh you actually you need to add
that if both of number are not not there
then you simply add 97 and add 13 in
that order you can add them in the
beginning or in the end doesn't
matter okay
uh is that
right so you know when you when you got
a pair you got two cases actually you
got four
cases the first number is in the Leist
or not and also the second number is in
the list or not so you got true true
true false false false false true you
got four
possibilities oh God you have to think
about each
one what if both numbers are already in
the list then you just ignore
it right
so and what if both number are not in
the list you just add them both in that
order in the front or in the back okay
let's start to write it
out given a
pair a a
BB
check
if if a if both not in the list add
both in the old a a BB in front or end
okay uh beginning okay let's say
beginning or
end if both are in the
list ignore this pair
wait if both number are already in the
list ignore this pair is I
right oh wait not ignore you cannot
ignore mod the list so
that they are in the
same so that this two so that a a BB in
the list is the same order as
the
pair that is swap
them if needed okay
if AA is
in the
list but not BB then what you
do AA is in the list but not
BB so that means add
BB where do you add it you add it after
uh A8
or just add it to the to the end add BB
to the end of the
list
okay
um you see now there's efficiency issue
because when you have this list you need
to arbitrarily insert items in the list
or swap two
elements uh and in different programming
languages you need different data
structures for it so it's not
Universal alternatively you can use a
hash table to represent this order list
in that case the value of the the hash
table will
[Music]
be will be like a uh floating
number but
uh yeah no no that's not that's
no to determine what floating number
that is is not easy so maybe not do that
so anyway so if AA is list but not BB
add BB to the list after
AA a is in least but not BB so add uh so
a comes before
B BB is not in the list so you can just
add
it okay
so if AA is not in the
list but
BB
is ADD AA to the
list
before BB okay so in other
words if both of them are not in the
list just add both of them in that
order if one one of them is in the list
but the other is not add the one that's
not in the list
and in the order you know so if if you
got a a
BB if AA is not in the list you need to
add AA before BB if BB is not in the
list you need to add BB be after
AA okay and if both of them are not in
the list you add them both uh if they
are already in you ignore
it or either ignore it or double check
if they are in ordance
okay this this
um if both
are check if their Leist order is the
same
if
not if not that means
there is a
conflict okay you don't even need to
modify
it okay so you got four cases
okay so after you do this then you got a
sequence of
numbers that is in the order given
specified by the pairs that's
right yeah you can start to code it I
suppose
so okay let's comment this out
uh am I like boring uh probably who who
is watching
nobody
okay yeah but I need to continue
this because there will be some someone
watching okay so you need to turn this
in uh this this
um okay then's
start okay
[Music]
so so actually we already have it here
so let's try
that okay something like that
[Music]
actually uh let's just say
right
okay and uh
okay we get this aairs like that and uh
this is not Association anymore so this
is just
um what copy
history this is just the list
okay not the dictionary so pairs
map
pairs map a function to
Pairs and uh you need to Define
old the list equals to
this okay so function for each
pair God
this are of
codes
uh all the Beast so
you see in wam language it's fairly
costy if you keep creating new list or
append or prepend to it or
insert because I believe every time you
do it recreates the list because in wam
language the
list data type wam list is actually like
a array in
C at least that's that that is a case in
the '90s and
2000s I don't know if today they
optimized it they must have in some
special cases but in general I don't
think you can
determine you know how the list is
used So to avoid
a pending or prepending or adding
inserting elements into a
list you
can oh God this
is oh you can use a spar array is that
right
no oh
God
God let we get into the situation
and
where I'm kind of tired 1
hour yeah you see but this list is
long let's think about did I do
something wrong is it
uh or
maybe actually all the pairs you
possibly want to compare is in the least
no not like
in the pairs
now so actually yeah so you do need to
construct this very interesting
problem
uh you need to construct this ordered
sequence okay
so okay let's not worry about efficiency
because how many items are there you
know not many because you can just look
at the maximum number 99 you know
so at most the sequence of the length of
the list is just 99 you see all these
numbers is just two digits okay so so
let's not worry about a pending or
prepending or insert okay so the
function map two pairs
[Music]
uh you have to determine then the other
thing is you have to determine is if a
element is in the
list uh you can do that by member Q
Okay so
got this is
painful so there are four cases
here uh
a b b c c d d
yeah I want I don't I want to
break oh
God so member CU if it's not you add it
you
know uh member so a so you got two pairs
both in both not in so you need
to add both
okay you know so you know we can just
like
um uh you know we can just like naive
just Brute Force for
example we can just write
if
that
end if if both are in uh yeah actually
there are four conditions okay
true
true or
you know we can do that
then
uh
that
then that
kind of like
ugly yeah but when you if you do this
it's inefficient because then you are
doing this member CU multiple times
repeatedly and you know even if you use
a condition so the best way is actually
to do this and do this then you don't
need the rest okay you need to local
variable then
no we can do like that
like local variable okay with is local
constant so a exist and BB exists yeah
then what then then you just
got that
B okay you got this ban variable
ban ban means not ban ban is a shortcut
for not and ban
ban so we got four
conditions okay uh what do you do with
these
conditions uh and which of these
conditions is more
common
because you because you want to put the
common case
first that will improve efficiency
because you don't want to test a bunch
that doesn't little concerns little
little
Petty efficiency
concerns okay so but anyway this you got
this
so uh so if both
exist something like
[Music]
ignore yeah if if if uh if
both not
exist add just a pend
okay append
to append to what is the old X element
okay
x x element okay so app to what is X
order the
list okay element is uh what is the
element AA exist is
X okay can you append two things at once
no
it okay
something like that okay something you
need to like have
break uh so if both not exist then aend
and aend okay
let's change this's rename
that old the sequence shorter and more
semantically
correct uh okay so if both not exist a
pend if a do not exist B exist then you
append then you just wait append and
prend append okay then you just append
x a does not exist you append to the
front Okay B
exist wait not ignore here
uh check
order if
not if not correct
swap a exit yeah actually this this is
this is what we should do yeah not
[Music]
ignore uh
swap not conflict swap
okay wait you can't you can't just swap
it because if you swap it you up
all the other
ERS oh
Jesus if both are in the least
you can you cannot swap
it okay because I think
uh I think so
okay so now if if B doesn't exist just
prepend append uh if B doesn't exist
append if a doesn't exist prepend
okay if both doesn't exist then just
P okay I think that's
that we don't need
this yeah I think so so this member Q we
don't need clean
up so we are constructing the old the
sequence okay
okay and uh
with so now you got four
conditions okay and uh let and uh
to to code conditional in wam language
is is switch statement you have a switch
and witch statement so they are part of
the branching construct so you go to
branching list expression atom variable
conditional yeah code conditional so you
got if statements they are actually
functions not statement if expression so
and uh then you got um true false buing
equality test if function name ending in
Q number comparison bulling operation
wait switch
statement uh wait
what why don't I have switch statement
here so there is if which and switch
conditional there so
which okay which and switch the
difference is
that which statements require a bunch of
tests in other words Expressions that
return true or false while switch
statements allows you to match a pattern
against a given thing if the pattern
match it's considered true so
in our case do I want switch
or which we want which because it's not
a pattern
okay actually we can use a pattern if we
want to but
um but actually remember Q takes a
pattern yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah okay so
anyway let's just do uh which okay so
here you're going to have a
which which
one
okay uh you got okay so then cut cut cut
going to be this going to be part of the
witch okay so if that
then then do nothing okay
uh no is do nothing
okay
okay now if that then you do
that okay so if B doesn't exist you add
B which is the Y append append is the
bottom I mean the yeah so if a doesn't
exist you
prepend okay then if both does not exist
you do uh both of them this okay so I
think that that clean up clean up clean
up clean
up okay so you got kind of
now we are making progress not too bad
yeah but those people finish the problem
in five
minutes
uh no
comments so this should construct the
ordered sequence yeah
mhm can we run it let's see what
sequence do we
get oh wait this is for each remember oh
God so this is just one
Loop you got to do this for each oh God
so
this map this function to these pairs
and what the function do the function
will do this
thing okay so XY is the
argument
God let me look up something okay map
thread
the second Mar okay map thread let let's
let's use map thread don't ask questions
okay this is easier okay so
anyway so function
XY
uh we change to map thread because that
way the function can take two arguments
and uh instead of mapping to a list of
pairs we do a transpose so the pairs
becomes like column one a bunch of list
and column two a bunch of list so it
becomes a list of to this instead of
this pairs you know transpose so then we
use map thread and we map a function of
two arguments you know so it's so that
way we don't have to map a function of
one argument then the first part equals
to the first element the second part
equals to set element things like that
actually we can easily do that
by yeah actually so okay let's not
do we can just
[Music]
simply you know uh let's say Arc yeah
but then we need to declare U
we need to declare a variable then okay
so let's let's do map
thread
okay so convenient emx okay so map
thread this is a function this function
and this function takes two arguments X
Y X is the AA and uh uh let's rename
them let's just rename them a a and BB
so it's more
consistent AA means the first element in
the pair
okay wait
okay and uh same thing for
y That's why I always like to use
variable names that's
unique unique identifier so you don't
have the problem of receiving through
English words so
anyway if a exists you know uh
BB exists that then which a exist BB
exists this case it's a special case
actually we need
to check
later B doesn't exist at a a pen B A
doesn't exist a pen
a oh this case must come
before okay so yeah this case need need
to come
before if both doesn't
exist it doesn't matter okay so let's
just run a code let's see what happens
I'm getting tired
okay we got that well the new is do
nothing
um so
actually map thread we want this value
okay evaluate
it there it is let's see how beautiful
it is
oh God this
this so this this sequence of numbers is
supposedly that
represent this represent
this God okay
[Music]
9713 uh where is
13 wait got 13 and
61 but 61 comes before
13 so you are not correct 61 comes
before 13
so
what
61 and 13 which come first 61 comes
before 13 but our list got it wrong
oh yeah we need to
swap right
remember so if both of them are there
then then check
if uh
if the
position of a
a expansion pattern okay if the position
in the ordered
list and let's see
let's see if I can do
this
order wait you know in the wolam
language is there is there a single
function that turns this pair to this to
the list we want there might be so we
Wast it on hour
uh numerical
order let's see
[Music]
ordering gives a position in this each
success you see the problem is that we
are
given is
pairs um that represents the order we
need to
canonize
somewhat I don't know where to okay so
let's just manually code
this if position
and let's
say what what does this be turn
it
[Music]
doesn't
God so if this is true then do
nothing
else else you need to swap their
position
low
levels low level wait this is linear
algebra thing no that's not what we want
swap symbol values
see resource function no that's not what
we want
those all those are resource functions
to so right now the qu the problem is
two given two index in the
list we want to swap their
values uh
well we can manually do it by
God you need
to for
okay it's 90
minutes oh maybe that statement
makes sense this problem is indeed too
ridiculous okay I'm going to take a
break I
think so I suppose nobody's
watching oh six concurrent viewers are
you
kidding nobody saying anything
this T TS code if we can just finish
this uh if we finish this line that's
not done yet if we finish this
line it simply means
we have
completed constructing a sequence of
numbers that represents this sequence of
pairs for
order and
that's that's that's like
80% of the problem then you just need to
determine if
each uh line is ordered okay
so right now we just need to swap two
values but I'm kind of tired
yeah because it's because it's tedious
then you need to create temp
variables oh you don't yeah you don't
let me see okay so all you have to do is
something like this okay equals
to A and BB
so BB and
AA so this is
the uh wait so something like that okay
kind of like that take a break hello GCS
okay maybe that's a good idea thank
you okay I okay hold on a second let me
try to finish this position order the
sequence so you want to swap values so
this so you get so what you get here
is uh you you need to know position
actually it would be nice if you have
little local variable
here to store yeah you can do that but
then it's more
code
um you know this this if statement
let's let's
add local variables then okay so you got
all
uh AA
position BB position okay so that's
position of AA
equals to
that and BB position equals to
that so you got
two cute local variables
then then this part is just a a
position okay you take the first part of
the the position that gives you the
index why what's the difference between
position and
index because in normal languages such
as python JavaScript C C++
crap their list is usually
flat so it's sufficient to to know the
position just by a single number called
index you know the index of a
array but in from language you typically
deal with nested expression like this
like for example this whole source code
is one single nested expression like
lisp so in order
to specify an element in a nested
list one single number is not enough
because one single number means that you
know a flat list you know that element
but that element is itself nested so you
need another number that indicates which
position you know what index is that
then another one if it's nested again
you know so until there's no nesting so
in general to pinpoint any atom in a
nested this you need a sequence of
indexes that sequence of indexes is a
list and that is called position in
wolam language
so you know so I can you know I can you
know for example let's let's have a next
L
three
7 and a let's say you know you can have
arbitrary so here's a list and you you
want to know the position of seven you
run
it that means that gives you a nested
list so sometimes because seven may
occur in multiple places that's why
first of all you got the nested list
okay
then this is the position 2 to one that
means it's a second element the second
element then the second element of
that uh
what which is this then the first
element of that then that's that seven
you see so if you do you know for
example
B
evaluated you get just
three even it's one single number it's
but it's still in a list because that
way it's consistent doesn't matter your
list is how how many level of list
nesting or it's flat it always return
a list so that's what position means so
that's why here the position you need to
get the first
part why we want to get the first part
because then we can kind of like do
numerical comparison okay here so anyway
here this is uh
[Music]
B uh
wait BB
position okay if a is less than BB then
do nothing
otherwise
um then do nothing otherwise
you you set
you set the order okay
here to you so that
[Music]
the AA
position and
uh and uh this here BB position
is equals to bbaa reverse
it
yeah it's nice you don't have to create
a middle man like C or python or
JavaScript like you have to create a
temp middl man variables because
otherwise okay so anyway so that's how
you
swap there may be better ways you know
in wam language but anyway this is good
enough for us so delete that so we don't
so what are we so let's get back
here uh if yeah so we don't need
this yeah so here is the if
statement let's compress
it okay so this here is our little
nested local varable
position so this this is a case when a
exist and B
exist okay and then comma okay actually
remove
this this
thing okay then you okay now we are back
good to go let's evalate let's see what
happens
uh put this here EV
let's compare now it's valid code that's
good now before we were checking 13 and
61 ah you see now 13 moved to the back
fantastic looks like looks like it's a
Improvement uh let's go to the top and
compare
so 13 is the last looks like
right okay I think you know maybe that's
correct so we got so we constructed this
order sequence specification
okay uh what so this one we don't need
anymore yeah that's
incorrect uh the code is not too bad
I guess but it could be better you know
in wam language you almost can always do
better let's paste it so that's what it
looks
like you know why is a pen to cannot
take two
arguments wait a pend and a pend both
both
exist aend is to the bottom right yeah
so a b b but you cannot
take okay but anyway
so so that's that we constructed this
list and uh now break
okay break for 10 minutes
okay uh yeah
so stop recording
so we got three more minutes break
let's see if I
can do a pushup
you want to
show
yeah
okay okay let's do some
pushup girl
two three
four five six
seven8
for for
okay I think I'm
back
check okay I'm back let's start to code
again
so so let's see audio check video check
my w language yeah
so okay so here is uh we got these pairs
then we
got now
um okay we got our ordered sequence
suppose it's correct
then we have to do
uh actually ordered
sequence is equals
to now this is not functional
programming
yeah yeah this is not this part is not
functional because you are
constructing this ordered sequence each
time you append to it
so ideally that's not good usually I
don't like to do that so you want
to
um do this in a functional way how can
you do that yeah you can do that by by
first of all going through all the pairs
if the
pair uh
just you know actually we can try it let
me show you okay so pairs equals to
that then
just flatten the pairs and uh and remove
duplicate
okay uh let's see delete
duplicates Okay so
so so this will give you a list of all
the unique numbers in the pairs then oh
this is much simpler I think then you
just then you just go through the pairs
like
before uh and uh you know according to
you know then you don't have to check
exist or not ah Jesus this is much
better you don't have to check whether
it exists because it's always
exist if it doesn't that means you know
you got a
problem um you I mean the the problem is
not
consistent so so you don't have to check
exist then you see uh let's let's try it
okay so here's actually taking a break
give you fresh insights so here's a
pairs then you just flatten delete
duplicate then ordered sequence just
equals
to
uh uh equals
to uh okay so but you still have to swap
swap is not technically functional
programming yeah
yeah okay let's forget
it because you improved a little bit but
it's not still
so
uh yeah let's forget let's not do extra
stuff okay for now let's just get it to
work okay so forget about the pairs
Okay so anyway you got the all the
sequence then you
just you then you just map
to this list of numbers okay God this
list of
numbers uh dictionary do you still
needed okay so let's so here is the
numbers you
want and
uh this each one is is a list
okay okay so for now we manually create
this
list instead of passing so this is a
list uh input list something like that
okay input list and uh what we do is
that we we map a function to it of
course
um check so we map it to X input
list
okay check if it is
ordered uh here this needs to be a
function so
ordered if x is ordered and what is the
predicate function so you need another
the function that takes two
things uh a a and BB using uh variable
name
convention a a
BB then then
if
God okay so so this function if AA is
so you got two conditions okay
so if
position uh is there some simpler way
than position let's
see uh
first position okay so actually you can
just
use First Position
yeah sequence
position okay oh then you got position
index you got several possibly more
efficient things instead of position so
actually we can replace our position
here with the more efficient way so the
POS first position you just return the
first
element uh in our
case we presume it's Unique
yes because when you have the same
element happen twice then you know it's
a problem it's a logical error so this
can be replaced with first position okay
so first position is one thing then what
is the sequence position list of list
give list of the starting and ending
positions at which sub list appears okay
sequence position you want to find the
position of a sequence that's not what
we
want uh position index given association
between unique element in this and
position which they occur okay actually
this is what we want
um position index okay give a list give
a association between the unique
elements in list and the positions at
which they
occur okay so the key is the unique
element and the value is the positions
they
occur okay so for
example
uh for example this a b c a c a you'll
see this is
fantastic position Index this much more
efficient so we can use position
index and
uh
then give that returns Association okay
so
yeah so let's go back
here um
oh
God position index equals
to all the sequence okay
ordered
sequence right order sequence is a list
then this gives you a dictionary of the
position
index so now whenever you need to find
if two numbers are in the right order
you just say
you just say position now how do you get
the value of the key I believe just like
that
key okay so actually
um okay so which W Language tutorial you
need to go to Association list which is
Association list which is addiction AR
in Python okay and once you have
Association list how do you get the
value of a given key okay so get value
add key so get add so
Association uh bracket
key or you can do you can use lookup
then key okay let's use lookup because I
prefer
functional syntax
so look up X position index uh which is
the dictionary and the key so if you
want to
know given AABB is in order
do so look at position in index then key
AA
is less
than BB
okay if that is true it
returns uh it uh returns
true equal or uh equal
or uh less or equal
uh what is less or equal I forgot what
is less or equal I believe
that uh less equal than there it is less
equal than okay okay so you can actually
just do
that functional approach
okay so less or equal then it returns
true otherwise it returns
false okay so yeah so that is what you
want then okay then you don't need that
then so this is what you want
and you want to put it
here
if
that okay then yes and no Okay then if
so if that and yes otherwise no so you
don't even need the if statement because
this expression already returns true or
false
okay
okay so the function is is
this uh where does that
go yeah okay so
maybe so what does this do so you go
through that
and
uh it should return a list of true and
false okay so let's try
it okay we got uh less than equal uh
less than equal so we use the wrong
thing
so we need to find out what is exactly
is the
operation let's see what is the
functional form for the operation it
doesn't
say because the wo from script does
not less okay less okay so what what if
it's less than
equal shift enter L's equal okay that's
what you want less
equal okay
[Music]
so let's
just you be simple
okay
uh yeah so this this will return let's
run it
true true true true true true now that
is not true because we
know true true true true true true we
know according to the toy
example
that only three of them is
true right
okay so the
ordered what is the input
list input list is that
[Music]
then okay so let's try
that true true true true true true
that's not true true true true true true
true no uh why is
that we
can let's say so which one is true which
one is
false the correctly ordered is
75 then
9761 the second one then the third one
the last three is false 1 2 3 4 five 1 2
3 4 five 6 7 so there are seven of them
1 2 3 4 five 6 1 two 3 4 five
six why do I get seven of
them
copy one two three four five six yeah
six one two three four five six
six yeah so why is one two three four
five six one two three six how did I get
a seven I don't know so six lines six
lines 1 2 3 4 five six and uh
the so only three of them is correct
order
75 97 and uh 75 29 13 the last three is
wrong okay the last three is wrong so
you should get true true true force
force
force okay and uh so this order function
when you apply to this should get Force
okay so
ordered that
shift
enter it returns true so that means
something is not right let's try
again let's try you know some random
number shift
enter uh apparently it seems like it's
always returning true now what is X
position Exposition index shift enter
oh it
returns oh you forgot it Returns the
index so you need to
remove oh yeah that's right you you need
to look up then get the first element
okay uh
yeah okay let's try to run it again
true true true force force force
beautiful now for each one that is true
you
just
um if it is true
then you see this
ordered okay if this is ordered if if
this is true then you just take the
middle number Okay so so rename that X
to be X
list uh X line okay let's just say
line line makes
sense okay so the
line so the line if this line is true
if this line is
true then you take the
middle God
there is a function uh I don't think
it's medium but it's called
Uh something in statistics called
um uh wait is it mean
no
quti okay okay not mean you basically
you want the middle
thing mean midpoint there it is
midpoint gives the midpoint of the line
segment no that's
geometry what what is
the in statistics What what is the
what what is the middle value I forgot
but but however it's easy to compute it
okay
so you want the middle number so
length at X
line divided by two
then uh let's
say
a
b c
okay
so so supposedly it's always odd so
divided by two you take the seing okay
seing of
that okay then you just
return that
element
okay so if it is ordered then you take
the middle element
otherwise uh zero okay then you just
total okay total
okay I think that's it let's just run it
let's just run it I'm tired of this
problem part one 143 is that even
correct 143 one shot coding no Tri out
and
error fantastic
answer for toy input is okay now answer
for personal input is what is it well we
need to go to the top and evaluate this
input string
wait search search
uh oh we for we need to do passing now
we need to do
passing yeah but you already almost done
okay oh God we need to do passing so the
inputs pair part
okay something like that equals to um
then
line spot something like that okay so so
string split okay split the
input
by by two empty lines okay is that right
yeah
so okay so actually
okay so we got that then then then you
got P oh God this is tedious this
pairs should be in what
form okay let's just just do coding okay
imperative
code uh string part equals
to yeah it's kind of
copy this time split string by that
then then do a split string
Again by that and uh here is X
pair okay so you split by line by line
then you got a bunch of lines then you
split by the vertical
bar uh vertical bar is that okay I
believe that is
the
wait uh wait
split string by a vertical by a uh line
and
by then you need to map Jesus
split
[Music]
then then
you then you split
then
you flatten
it then
you partition it
okay that I believe that is that pairs
okay and the line the line part is kind
of
similar line part
you you split by uh line return okay
actually it's not s it's not
similar you split by line return then
you got a bunch of list then you just
need to
map you need to map a
function uh
yeah
split X you split by
comma
okay then you got list of lines you map
this each string I think that's it so
remove that remove remove
remove okay actually
let's let's test it out this quickly
okay new save
XX language okay so you got firstes
input and uh read it from my
input okay and actually don't read it
use a toy input okay you
split string by that then the
the pair part is going to
be the pair part is going to be the pair
part you split by new
line okay so that's not okay so you
split by new line or
or a
that
okay then you just partition okay you
you don't need flatten okay you just
partition
okay so and the line part equals to
actually
the line part is going to be you split
then you
map okay so X
pair evaluate it let's see what you get
empty okay you got
um let's let's do let's show them all
show all results let's see where we went
wrong
so what
no okay
so so that's seems
right let's put
uh okay so
empty okay so something went wrong there
so you want I believe this is
alternative there so try it
again no wait you split what do you
split by
a new
line a new line
or a vertical sign
[Music]
so so the vertical bar is it literal or
not in emac lisp
it is literal
so you know the problem is with this
okay so you don't you don't know which
is it oh if you want regular expression
you have to say regular expression
let's see oh I can just use a list
of
items I forgot to record my video
string pattern yeah okay
so yeah so this is actually
simpler you switch on that or a vertical
bar okay run
it there it is they give you the pairs
and each of these is a uh string you
want to turn it into a number Okay so
so that means you can just
say two expression here
yeah so we got the pairs part correct
okay
cut and always good to put it there so
the pairs part uh now let's work on the
line part the line part what we
get no okay no is not
correct wait actually it's correct okay
so uh again you need to two string two
expression
okay so remove that
EV that seems right okay so so this is
the line part okay so good we got the
pairs part and line
part copy back to our
code uh and
uh and we can
like put it here replace
that okay let's make
sure remove
that
now now actually what if we use our
personal input will it
work run it
it
works huge amount of numbers okay and uh
if
you yeah let's shift enter tab a to show
all
result okay
so right so this is
this is just uh oh yeah this is just the
line part so
actually show the pair
part fantastic okay so we got this
correct now copy back to our
code paste it
there input
delete delete
uh delete
delete delete delete okay we got the
line part we got the pairs and the
dictionary we can just
remove the
dictionary we can yeah I don't think
it's used anywhere
explanation explanation
explanation then
this
explanation pairs this is our pairs
so deleted go to the top search for
pairs
okay so instead of pirs
we we
say pair parts is actually
pairs actually
wait wait this pairs I don't like
hold on second so it should be X pairs
okay
something okay
so pairs rename X
pairs there ignore ignore ignore ignore
ignore
rename rename okay now go to the
top search for pirs now pairer Parts
rename to
xays do
it do it do it okay
so you can delete that in Lin's part
also we have a new we have our name here
which is uh input list okay so that
should be named the x lines okay so
let's see x lines is it already
used no okay
so input list should be renamed x lines
okay do it do it do it yes careful go to
the top now the lines part will should
be lines okay name it lines part x lines
okay do it do it do it okay make a
backup actually this is that's it
um that's it that's the code so we got
the lines we got the pairs we got the
lines okay then description of the
problem uh then R description and
algorithm and then
turn the pairs turn the pairs into
ordered
sequence uh we are constructing this
sequence okay and that's the result
example then then then
we uh this
remove yeah remove that okay so remove
that we should have saved but we forgot
uh anyway so so then so what so what is
this position index we can
remove uh oh yeah we need
this position index yeah because it
makes it much more
efficient uh this part is wrong so
let's let's modify it
yeah that is
correct okay so we map then we map the
function if it's
ordered uh uh this is actually this is
just a toy
example then we yeah so I think that's
it
so cut that put it here go to the top
make sure we are reading uh personal
input go to the bottom run
it zero what the
oh God
no it's like uh I don't know what
debugging
I don't know what amount of debugging
will that
be we can
be
persistent you know we can just let's
say let's print what is
this this is our position index does it
look beautiful let's let's copy it let's
see so change comma to new line
okay not many items you see this is uh
what is this this is our position Index
this actually not many numbers
there 49 incredible there's only 49
items in the
universe even though they use numbers
like 89 but there only actually 14 n
entries
okay but uh this is the index now let's
check if they
are
like oh this is their order can you see
that you
[Music]
see yeah this sequence is actually they
order
um yeah so actually this is interesting
problem but because you can see in order
to generate the input it takes
some coding you know actually the the
Advent of code it takes a lot coding to
create yeah it's okay it's pretty
good
um so but we got a problem uh
what our problem is that so we got this
this is a position
index uh what is the input and Pairs and
lines okay let's print
them okay we got a a lot NOS that is
that
because
uh wait let
J
total go to the
top so you got the new
here you see where does the new come
from what are we printing here
we got a lot NOS uh okay new is not
good oh this map actually when we
construct you see when we construct this
map thread it Returns the so you don't
want it to return so put
a that and uh all the
sequence okay comment that out
now save it okay make a backup put in
the back to the HTML showing browser
here is our code so
far uh not many code actually so now
make a back let's refresh redo this so
we get rid of the old color and now we
can like freshly color the things we
need to see so you got pairs you
got Pairs and uh lines so
lines okay
then
[Music]
then and this map what does this map do
oh this is the answer okay so let's say
[Music]
X answer equals to okay so you got so
let's print pairs print lines print
position index print answers okay
evaluate
it okay expand let's go to the
top so let's pay
us copy it new buffer go to the
top so that's pair
that's
lines that's position index I
think uh wait what is
this wait we are printing pairs lines
position
Index right so this is position
index then the last part is
incorrect it's all
zero all zero means none of them are in
order
God this then it means this line is is
incorrect now if we try
the you know the toy input let's see
let's use the toy
input run
it the toy input is correct okay so
there's some trick there's more trick
involved am I am I still recording check
good
status
so how many people watching Four Z some
people
so the toy input
worked okay 6 61 59 29 that is what
what is
this yeah I was doing something so
like back
143 yeah 143 was their answer for the
toy input
143 uh but um okay so close
that yes okay but when you use your
personal input you got a
problem now of course the equation is
why
when you use personal input you got a
problem so that seems to indicate a
logical
error yeah because it's
[Music]
tricky let's let's remove that equal
sign okay maybe lucky maybe we got lucky
they'll pass
okay let's go here do that run
it okay it's Z all zero that means they
are not
ordered okay so we can what we can do is
we check one of them simply check one of
them you see this problem
is is difficult it's it's a good problem
you see it's a good problem because you
cannot even like manually check what is
going on because this obscure ordering
ordering
thing it does not give you um let's see
where is my
input you
see delete that let's see where is my
input you see if you open the input
let's
see if you open the
input you cannot easily check you know
which line is
ordered you cannot do that manually
so so it's hard to debug you in order to
debug you really have to rely on your
code
logic because how do I know is this line
ordered or not I mean what is the
correct answer if I know then I can you
know use this
line and uh check right so
but you see we can we can try
here ordered on this line this list of
numbers
to see if it's ordered or not and even
if it works so if doesn't work it
doesn't tell you which part which pair
got wrong then you have to you
know
okay I suppose this is a good problem
day five I I suppose I'm guessing a lot
people stumble on on
it but you know the word is uh you know
the word is typically filled with
amazing people there's just amazing
people they solve this in few
minutes
uh and you would go you know
what so wait let's go back to um code
what is this this is input what is this
this is the
passing part okay this is a passing part
do we need it
no and what is is this is a input
personal
input and uh this is our page this is
our
code yeah so if you run this
order run it
it says it just say
forse and well that's because the wam
language you are using ordered other
programming language don't have
that so you have to sort actually if you
want to debug then you want to
sort do we have the sord PED cut yeah we
do have
you
know let's write a sord predicate so
that we can uh debug
it okay so you can just say that you
know
that sort PR predicate okay that's a
function function and the function is
pretty much just this okay the function
takes two things a a BB by our
convention and it just look up that that
that that
that yes I think that's that's
that so if less then let's see we need
to check all so let's just to be sure we
didn't get the sign inverse
okay the pred
cut either returns true E1 and E2 are in
order that is all right
so all fource they are out of order okay
so this if this is less than that
or
equal that means they are in order okay
so look a position x a
a take the first
part is less
than take the first
part that should be
right
okay cut
that so this is our
predicate okay the function takes two
arguments let's name it or the predic
okay and
then then we can just replace this by
all the prod so we don't have to have
this this
line simplify simplify if that is true
let's let's for now if if it is true
just return that line okay that way it's
easier to debug
okay it still returns all zero
so
so something obvious this is wrong okay
when you get all
zero something obvious is
wrong did we turn turn string to
expression did we forget to turn string
to expression no we
didn't we are we will
correct so this little minor
problem J says just ask correct query
and only if a solution wam database will
be held
correct just ask a correct query and
only if a solution is found in grr
database will it be held
correct if a solution isn't within the
database then your query is incorrect
yeah you're talking about wolam
alha which which is
a Compu computational based
AI uh like logic based instead of neural
network
based so if it whenever wam Alpha
actually answers your question it's
guaranteed to be correct unlike the
artificial intelligence you know the
neuron network based AI such as chat GPT
and so on so for example if you ask chat
chat GPT
to uh add to numbers you know
like
like plus you know let's say add the
same number you'll get it
wrong because it's neural network based
basically means it's trying it's kind of
guessing based on you know many past
examples of lots of numbers yeah let's
try it you know let's you know let's try
G is even better than chat GPT
so
uh work I try to generate a bunch of
pictures those are not
good uh What is the answer of actually
just paste
this here's the sum okay let's see if
that's
correct let's go to w
frame
and
paste paste paste and delete that
number shift
enter oh now it's becoming
smart it did it can can can can you do a
multiply let's
see so I
believe G is actually calling out python
to do the computation it
improved yeah okay
wait yeah oh God G gr is becoming
smarter
it actually call
python you know
um you know one of
the for example let's see if this is
correct false it got it incorrect
so what is the correct answer
see
796 last three digits so G got it wrong
even though it tried to use Python for
verification yeah but uh let's
see uh
okay so let's run it you see python got
the correct answer 796 the last three
digit
796 but
gu gave you the wrong answer even though
it suggested the correct python code to
compute it so that's AI you know that's
that's because it's neural network
based artificial
intelligence which means it's actually
kind of trying to guess based on seeing
one gab billion you know
examples but the wolam
alpha is a logic based AI symbolic AI so
they actually tries to compute so
whenever if wam gives the
answer it's correct
um but if you ask a general question
like uh what's going on in a world you
know should I get a girlfriend or you
know my wife is not happy but uh because
of this what should I do then the neuron
network based AI will kind of give you
some suggestions like WR me a
poem but the wolf I'm logic symbolic
base computation it will not be able
to
so you know this so This p and cons and
we don't know which one is going to you
know so AI is a big
topic so anyway let's get back to this
so you know let's get back to this
little digression
so let's get back to this we you know we
talked about AI a lot which is very
interesting thing
okay now now let's get back to why is
our code not work okay so we got a
little bug because none of these lines
are in order according to our algorithm
it works for the for the toy input okay
it works for the toy
input but it didn't work for the user
input and uh uh
why it's hard to see
um it must be something trivial because
none of them returns true so it must
[Music]
be it must be something trivial I did
wrong some something
but however it works for the uh
for the toy input so why is
that or maybe there's logic error so
it's hard to
say yeah if it works for toy input but
not for the personal input then it may
be some logic
error uh you
know really
really annoying problem so here is the
pair
of orders you know ordered pair and here
is the list of
lines okay so so far so good yeah seems
right let's see copy new
buffer so that let's make it into a
line actually
you need
to
replace uh this is
painful replace that comma by a new
line
okay so now you see this is
this this is the pairs we get okay that
seems right and this is list of
lines okay and then here then here is
the
positions the order sequence we
generated
okay but then it say is none of it
is now okay let's debug now let's find a
short line where we can actually somehow
visually see if it's ordered or
not okay 41 42 99 65 12 okay maybe
that uh
wait where is
it yeah okay so there is this line let's
try to
see if this line ordered 41 42
41 where is 42 wait is
see
42 should be in
it no but it's not it it is not wait 42
is there
okay 41 42
99 65 12 okay now you got colored 1 2 3
4 five colors one 2
3 four
five 99 41 65 42 12 five of them okay
they will got a key so you got all the
numbers in it so 41
is is here but then you got a number
that's
999 99 should be in
front
so so this list is not ordered okay so
for example let's search for
99 99 comes before
42 okay
99 comes before 42 so this line is not
ordered okay but we need so you know our
programs return
zero but we need to find the line that's
ordered according to
this good evening Mr I'm new here
oh so we are doing the advance of code
if you search for aand of code you'll
find the problem online every
year in December from December 1st to
25th I think they have you know they
publish a programming problem so we are
doing it today and we are doing the
problem of day five and so far two
hours we don't have a solution so that
that is what I'm doing
I know it just carries the python rule
so as far as I know wam only carries one
part of python
based on thre part
rules I don't know what you're talking
about when part of python I don't know
so so we need to find a a input line
that is actually in
order so but this problem is nasty
because you don't know I mean how do
you such a failure such a failure but
it's a it's a difficult problem
so what is you
[Music]
know and this is only part one okay so
let's think about so it worked for the
toy
input so wait what what happens if you
have a number in in the
lines that's not in the
pairs right if you have a number in the
lines that is not in the pairs what do
you
do you ignore
it oh God so that so I think there's
another
step you know because they did
mention if the number is not in the
pairs you ignore it did they mention it
somewhere
you see this this Advent of code they
highlight the wrong Parts you know they
they try to highlight some phrase or
words but those are misleading that's
not you know that's not what you want to
know they highlight the wrong
words here you want to know if a number
in your lines is not in the
pairs then do you consider how do you
deal with that so let's see I remember
they said
somewhere first ofd dat does not include
some page numbers the ordering rules
involving those missing page numbers are
ignored okay the first update does not
include some page numbers so the
ordering rules involving those missing
page numbers are
ignored so first of all in order to
check whether the order is correct if
the number is not in
that in the ordering I mean in in the in
the
ultimate order
sequence
you ignore it yeah so so that
means the old the predicate
needs to be
modified so instead of that so first of
all you need to
check okay you need to check
if if me
Q wait wait let's do this wait so
if uh let's look up let's look up the
look up
documentation if key is not present okay
so
look up key default okay so yeah okay so
if look up position of a and uh Force if
it's not there return
Force okay oh
or or
BB uh wait if
it's true
if one of them is true that means one of
them does not exist in the old
sequence
then simply
return negative
1 wa
wait okay so wait a minute
so if one of
them if this true if that means it's
not it's not in the order sequence then
return negative one then return false
okay that means it's
not
ordered otherwise then you then you do
this
thing okay so
if one of them is not then you return
false then you check if they are in
order if one of them is not in it then
you just return Force okay so now this
is a modified predicate
function I think that's it
minute there it is there it is so we now
we don't get all Z zeros okay so let's
see yeah we get now we now we now we do
the total okay now we compute the middle
line compute I mean compute the middle
number then total
it prefix notation okay so you don't
need the pairs you don't need the lines
you don't need the index
just print the
answer okay I think that's it this is a
tricky part you know this like nasty
tricky part so so let's try the toy
input would our toy input still be
correct run
it what uh
278 wait
who input those now is
wrong what
what now the toy input is
incorrect what the what God this
problem is so
toy problem total okay forget about
total and
it 2 three four five then they returns
them all now the to problem is incorrect
it returns them
all and let's check all the ped
takes two
functions
if position index AA is
true or position index BB is
true returning true means it's not
there oh not return force it returns
snake uh
wait yeah it return return for is it
correct or the
predicate oh you did it uh not sure yet
God I'm not sure yet almost okay we
almost did
it but
uh maybe greater than
that
no yeah God
[Music]
so if if it's number so the predicate is
wrong
so let's just fix our predicate
something wrong with the
predicate
uh order function
so can you check if a thing exist
return the value of the key if it's
missing default use the
default if key is
missing so get key value by index Okay
add key delete key check key exist so
you can use that key exists Q
okay
so so instead of that we could use if
key
exist uh key
exist what is the association and key so
if that
exist
and if both of these key exist then
remove that okay
if both of the key
exist then you look up
otherwise you look up and you compare
that maybe that's simpler uh should be
the same
though
um but at least the code is more clear
with this dedicated
function
okay now but if we run
it oh now the correct I got the logic
wrong you know it's like some trivial
thing so now let's
try oh yeah now you need the total so
let's say the
total
total at
run
it oh yeah yeah then you need to uh
this uh
what that's interesting what's going
on uh why is
that what something wrong with my emac
common package oh
okay it works there you know it works
something okay so that that then you
total okay
so do
it
143 okay now let's try the personal
input okay now the personal input
uncomon run
it yeah now it's zero God
[Music]
Jesus oh God
something here is
incorrect what I don't
understand am so
close now it says zero
what's
this
God old prut
uh this zero is just not
good means all are zero so
good luck thank you
so right
now this situation is that either the
toy input is correct
but the personal input is incorrect or
the other way
so I'll be right
back be back in five minutes okay break
test I'm going to stop okay we
failed we didn't finish it's very close
but something is
wrong but I've been coding for close to
4 hours so it kind of
failed failed uh yeah yeah
yeah so I'm going to stop and uh I'm
going to update my page so you
can uh you'll see the fix code for sure
but but for now I'm giving up you know I
have to have to go and code later and
then tomorrow is another day another
Advent of code and we haven't done the
part two yet uh it's it's tough okay bye
guys