hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of s talk show today
we're going to talk a lot of topics
we're going to talk about a lot of
topics so let me show you the
topics uh topics topics okay so Merry
Christmas to you guys another year is
coming
2024 um and yeah so let me show you the
topics so the topics you go to my
website S Talk Show
2023 December
24th that's today and uh so we're going
to talk about glove at0 keyboard okay
glove 0 keyboard uh can you can you see
it yeah so I'm going to talk about this
keyboard and the back a little bit I
have update then we're going to talk
about AI chat
Bots uh I'm going to give you a list of
them there are s of them and uh so we're
going to talk about that AI chat uh AI
chat Bots there are you know more than
five close to 10 and uh I'm going to
talk about a scenario where what happens
when we get when the AI BS became
sentient you know there's a lot talk
about
AGI artificial general intelligence or
strong AI That's a hard topic so I'm I'm
going to talk about that what happens
when a scenario what happens when AI
Bots became sentient okay then I'm going
to show you a spectacular spectacular uh
one okay yesterday two days ago there's
a glitch in The Matrix from AI Bots okay
it's amazing uh okay so then I'm going
to talk about American versus Japanese
comic style generated by AI is
spectacular okay spectacular by Frenzy
I'm going to show you okay then I'm
going to talk about uh lots of update on
the wolam programming language my
tutorial huge amount of update and I'm
going to demo some of it fantastic you
never seen you know the industrial
programmers uh and some comparison to
closure the syntax okay and some linear
algebra textbooks so I've been nering on
linear algebra one of my favorite
subject one of the most important math
subject uh linear about textbooks okay
I'm going to show you a few a few free
ones good ones okay and I'm going to
talk about status of the vend of code
you know I started to do it on day three
okay and then we're going to talk about
Wikipedia fake news very quite
interesting you know the Wikipedia one
of the article is the most frequently
visit website around the world but it's
fake news so okay so that's a topic so
let's again let's switch back to the
video view so let me show you so glove
80 if you don't know yet you know I have
review on my website video review and I
did you know I've been using this for 10
months now so I've been doing video
every day I mean every other
week for about several month you can
watch my past videos and I'm going to
tell you again uh this glove 80 box
okay so the glove 80 box okay so you
open it so you
see moreo that's the logo on it
so open this
thing
and did it open here
okay so there it
is and you put the
Box you put the keyboard
the
keyboard uh okay one one left side one
right side the left side goes
here and the right side goes
here okay I got it wrong this part goes
here I
think okay so here this
goes you cannot see it okay so but let
me just do
it now this goes
here yeah so and this goes
here so there it
is you see so they
are
okay I screwed up
my I touched my video so
they am I still alive am I still
broadcasting so let me
restart wait
cancel oh I'm still good okay so there
it is I touched key that key does
screenshot so that firsts my screen so
there it is
uh
okay and so you can go with it like a
businessman okay that's glove 80
fantastic okay and now the current
keyboard I'm using is kesis 360 it's
also fantastic okay and this is Auto
hacking keyboard also fantastic three of
my best keyboards okay and they all have
linearized switch let me give you a
recommendation if you if if you are not
familiar with these fancy keyboards the
first thing you want if you are
programmer or if you are writer you know
if you are my audience run and get a
mechanical keyboard first of all okay
just get a China Cheapo like $50 or even
$40 we'll get you one do it now if you
never have if your keyboard is not
mechanical the Microsoft Ogo keyboard is
not good okay the Microsoft you know uh
Microsoft oo natural keyboard no good
okay doesn't matter what you know the
shape the the Urgo shape of the keyboard
is less important than the mechanical
key switches so if you have hand
problems you're typing too much you know
you have hand pain do it the right way
go buy a cheapo Chinese cheaper on
Amazon you know I have my website you
can go to my website and buy it so I get
some
donation so buy a Chinese mechanical
keyboard okay mechanical key switches
and the key switch you want if you are
not familiar with it go with the Cherry
MX red
linear silent okay that the name is
Cherry MX red silent that's a linear
switch you want the linear switch and
you want as light as possible okay now
on key switch many people have different
opinions oh I like blue oh I like brown
but I I'll give you my recommendation
just go with the linear switch there's
no click you don't want any kind of
tactile sensation you want it smooth
linear okay usually that goes by the
label red okay so red switch is and if
you are beginner if you don't know
anything about key switches get the
Cherry MX red silent okay silent because
then it's quiet otherwise it's click cck
click click cck
okay uh and all you know basically
linear there's also made by Kyo by many
uh Chinese companies they are good okay
so get run out and buy a cheap
Chinese uh mechanical keyboard switch
linear switch right now
okay now but if you already have that
and you want it to go to to the next
level some kind of ergonomic shape and
fancy keyboard okay so then in that case
I can recommend you know automatic
hacking is also very good automa hacking
is got the most uh flexible uh Key
software or the kis 360 I got a I got
the pink switch 35 G activation Force
anyway so about keyboard so glove 80
kesis 360 and uh automat hacking is also
good okay so let's go back to let's
start to talk about today's topic so
because we have a lot of topics so if
you don't know anything about keyboard
you go to my website just search for sad
keyboard blog you go to the ergonomic
keyboard reviews so you can see here is
OT glove 80 here is kesis advantage
to uh and here is kesis 360 okay these
three I highly recommend and also I
wanted to give a shout out about the
Expos night this is okay Expos night
this is the cheapest among them is also
kind of Ugo so I always love this one
okay so this keyboard I
recommend uh glove
80 glove 80 okay and uh Kinesis 2 is
good Kinesis advantage to and uh Kinesis
360 pro okay I also have you know
several video reviews this is uh what
I'm currently using is good okay uh and
expose okay so that's what I recommend
now I did uh lots of update on the glove
80 review article so you can read the
details no fluff okay I give you I tell
tell you how things are okay if you are
here say hi please okay say
hi so yeah lots of topic so that's about
keyboard okay that's about keyboard now
let's see NE next topic S Talk Show gra8
okay so I'm using Emax of course
fantastic uh with cofly keys search for
CAF Keys it's a ergonomic key binding
system for emac uh and uh what is this
page show keyboard block go back here so
you see I'm using the glove 0 for the
Fantastic uh Marco keypad so show this
page what is yeah so delete this block
uh delete
this live stream block okay so glove 80
we show glove 80 back next topic
artificial intelligence
so oh yeah so one of the interesting
thing chat GPT on Sadi you know I talked
about this before it wrote several poems
about me it knows me because all these
AI Bots they grab my the entire website
so they grabbed all the information
about me on my website 6,000 pages so
this is February you know this year and
then yesterday you know so chat gbd
wrote a lot things about me you can ask
chat gbd and but then yesterday I tried
the Minal AI bot okay so it's
interesting so Minal AI bot you know so
I as I asked it you know who is SAR and
is says you know casali is a blogger
programmer and writer known for his
technical expertise and blah blah blah
uh in the field of computing computer
programming mathematics
typography you know he runs a PO popular
blog called called Kali blog and blah
blah blah and he also you know the B
also says I'm a accomplished
typographer I'm accomplished typographer
and I also created several fonts those
are false okay those are fairy tale you
know because AI Bots make up stories but
in general like the in general the
description is kind of correct because I
have tons of articles on font on um on
font on typograph typography on
mathematics on programming for example
search for font you can see there are 51
articles how does Unicode characters get
mapped to a GL in a font how to install
font s symbola f for unic code no longer
free that's kind of news a few years ago
um f for unic code 6 this is 2010
Unicode uh text font art that's very
interesting so uh download free Unicode
fonts uh math font and EAC L how to
install fonts and so
on and many interesting CSS articles on
CSS Fun Family Fun Size fun weight how
do you what you know the detail and
common web font uh and Chinese font
Google font let's see some of
the some and also the entire Chinese
font on Mac and windows for example if
you are Chinese or if you are learning
Chinese it's this is a interesting topic
and uh rarely talked about in English
language because most people English
speakers they don't speak Chinese but
you if you are learning it so you need
to know you know what fun to use on your
blog for example and so here is a
complete list of the fonts on Windows
Chinese fonts on Windows and Chinese
font on Mac and on Linux this article is
like uh 2002 okay so and here's a
screenshot of the various fonts about
and also there's a issue about for
example what does seront mean in Chinese
does it mean anything yes it does so
anyway so that's some of the Articles uh
let's let's go back to so anyway back to
the AI bots so that's interesting okay
so I asked minro about you know because
I I want to get some feel about what
what is the nature of the bot does it do
censorship you know to what degree is it
you know anyway things like that right
so then there's also a pind bot I also
ask pind you know who is s and pind is
interesting because pind actually gives
a very accurate information including
the year I started to use emac and the
year I started to code emac disp so the
year I started to code to use emac is
1997 and the year I started to use code
emac this is
2007 correct you know usually B will
makeup stories but the behind is more
kind of factual based because it turns
you know because pind but is focused on
focused as a search engine replacement
so whatever info it gives kind of just
tells you kind of more concrete instead
of instead of like creating a creative
writing or whatever so there's a pind b
interesting
okay so okay the so we talked about p
behind B so and all these you know this
one of my article uh you can find on my
website and the index so here is the
index page about all kind of Articles
I've written about AI okay so this
machine learning tutorial stepan wolfan
uh and so on so quite you know and uh uh
Donald G on chat GPT uh and uh okay and
the AI AGI versus sentence sentient AI
so
um so one thing I want to show you I
mentioned before is that if you go to
talk show uh then you go to San talk
show then there is AA podcast index and
uh you know this is my each podcast is
about six minutes uh and one of them is
artificial intelligence okay so this
about about six podcast six minutes each
they are about the ethics of artificial
intelligence and SOC called AI alignment
kind of stupid JG so if you are
interested you can uh listen to them
okay just search you know search for
this AGI strong AI sentient ai ai
alignment
ons.info
okay that's one thing so let's go on to
the next topic I want to talk about so
okay yeah so AI chart Bots I just
created this article with help of some
of the friends Ona Discord so uh here if
you have not yet already joined Discord
okay if you have a question ask it now
okay I'll answer so there's a AI room so
in here you know this Mr Splendid is
from Russia and he's actually a
professional chatbot writer coder you
know he WR chat chat Bots that's his job
before before these AI Bots came around
so you know I learned several things
from him and other people ewit and you
know other
people so now I have a collection of
chat uh chat bots so there's deep infra
deep infra is interesting because it uh
you don't you don't need to log in and
you can choose several Bots the LL llama
bot is that's from Facebook the
scun you know uh zuker b a criminal of
humanity so anyway deep infra site
allows you to use any of these Bots okay
now chat Bots is amazing you know 2023
is truly the year of the
AI and uh of course I have a AR on that
you know year two 2003 is the year of
the AI so it's it's you know it's truly
it it is changing Humanity okay
so so then um so then so I yeah
so yeah so chatbots they are going to
replace uh the web search that's for
sure that's already kind of
happening besides that you know the
there's a lot you know AI is you know
there's a lot of
things we don't know about the future
you know some incredible things will
happen we don't know so anyway so let's
see what so so deep infra is good you
can try then there's quite a few others
okay behind we mentioned we talked
about okay so you know just go to my
website and uh check them out so there's
chat GPT there is
uh pind and oh the another interesting
one is a brave browser so if you
download Brave browser which is I'm
using right now here uh you go to you
click on that that's a Leo chat bot now
what's interesting about this one is
that as you browse the web it can
summarize the web page as you you know
read stuff online so you can it can help
you research and so on so right now I'm
looking at
my Ellen's X Twitter so you know so
summarize this page who is SC and why
are they worth uh following what makes
Scot scad's post so unique of you know
things like that
suggestions Leo okay so you just
download bra
browser my voice you know is getting bad
I'm gonna die from cancer too much smoke
so I hope to create uh year uh in
2024 so super chipping says super
chipping chipping gam says how do the
Kyle KY silent pinks compared to silent
Cherry Reds
okay let me talk about that okay so if
you guys are here say hi okay 12 people
who are you say hi hi say hi just say hi
don't be shy don't be like a
nerds like I want to remain anonymous
forever we have a lot of people like
that hot dog you know want to be
secretive so key switches you know so
you have many makers of key switch the
most famous is Cherry MX from Germany
Cherry is a German company name so
that's the classic then then since 10
years ago China started to take over
China has you know several companies
making switches so and today there are
so many so you know in key switches
there are two things uh kind of two
things that's important one is the
activation Force how much force you have
to press and to it's activated usually
it's specified in terms of G grams um
and sometimes they specify in Newton but
anyway usually typically for example the
uh Brown Cherry MX Brown is usually I
think it's 45 grams or is it
50 cherry red Cherry MX red is 45 okay
however each company you know this
activation Force each company if they
give the same number actually they may
they may feel different okay they may
differ as much as by 10 G okay so you
can
never simply compare the number you know
this is 45 G activation Force this is
another switch from another company it
says
40 grams activation Force then you
assume this one is lighter no okay
that's not the case for example the
Cherry MX
red versus Cherry MX red silent if you
go to the cherry and Cherry's official
website they both they'll say they both
have the same activation Force
45g actually they they for the Cherry
they use Newton and okay they say it's
the same but actually not the same at
all Cherry MX silent is slightly heavier
so you you need more Force to activate
it it's it's like obvious you know
because you I get tired if I'm on Cherry
MX silent for five minutes typing I get
tired I don't want I don't want it
Cherry MX red is good I can use okay
Cherry MX silent you know if if I have
two type for five minutes no I I cannot
accept it okay
so you cannot just trust you know the
activation Force labels by the
manufacturer okay also for example let
me give you another example Cherry MX
red
45g by
specification however there's a Kyle
Kyle red okay I believe they also say
45g I forgot what they say but Kyle red
is significantly heavier than Cherry MX
red okay even though they are like
supposedly comparable no Kyle red Kyle
specifically Kyle red linear switch are
significant significantly heavier than
Cherry MX r
to a degree I cannot use it okay if I
got for example my My ultimate hacking
keyboard the previous version one that's
that is Kyle red too heavy okay so just
remember so you have to so what can you
do well you can you can buy the you know
the switch tester and so we we we are
kind of digressing a lot because we we
have a lot of things to cover okay hi hi
hi guys so so that's about activation
force of key switches okay in my opinion
you
want the lighter the better I mean not
super light not like you know F you know
fether way but anyway lighter is usually
better okay and I recommend if you don't
know anything about it I recommend you
start with Cherry MX red silent or
something comparable okay so that's
that's a activation switch
I mean activation Force okay that's one
thing about mechanical switch the other
thing about mechanical mechanical key
switch is about the
um is about the um the field you know
some of them are linear linear is the
easiest to understand so you know you
have the key stem here's a key cap you
press it you know it's like no it's
smooth okay linear then you have creaky
like the blue switch like they you can
feel this click you know then you have
brown which is some somewhat in between
so my recommendation is that just get
linear okay you don't need the tactile
you know like typically what they say
tactile is better for typist if you are
a typist you would prefer tactile
because it makes you feel you are you
know the key has been hit that's
false 10 years ago I don't know but you
know I believe that uh you know and you
know then they say if you are a gamer
you prefer linear because linear allows
you to shoot you know there's no
resistance is just smooth and if you are
a you know true typist you prefer blue
which is Click Clack okay that's not
kind of true you know there's no
scientific it's not it's not a
um it's it's it's just a it's it's just
a thought okay so I would recommend you
just stick with linear linear is the
best okay linear no you don't want any
kind of tactile sensation okay stick
with linear and also another thing
interesting is that all these blue
switch or brown switch they have kind of
a click
so the ideal situation is that when you
hit the click that means the key has
been activated okay but the reality is
that that's not not true that's not true
for Blue switches that's not true for
brown switches okay it's not true for
the tactile or no the clicky okay
because there's no way so far all the
mechanical key switch Technologies
there's none none of them make it such
that when it clicks it actually the
means the keys activated none okay they
are just like approximate okay so I just
recommend linear switch
okay of course some of you have opinions
strong opinions you know then you stick
with your opinion okay that's about key
switches let's go back to AI chatbot
okay we have a lot to talk about so a
list of chatbot okay another thing I
want to say about chatbot airbot is that
you see most of these you are familiar
with are based on English Corpus you
know they grab data from English written
English you know on the website on
Shakespeare on all the written books you
know 10 billion of
them but you see what it reads
determines the mindset of the bot okay
so any question you ask this spots you
know from from open chat GPT from Google
bot from you know all
these you get same kind of mindset which
is the Western mindset so what's
interesting is the Chinese ones although
I haven't actually tried them so the
Chinese Parts they of course they read
the Chinese text you know the massive
Chinese you know text and books and so
on so that so that
means the mindset is different from the
Western AI Bots okay you ask it question
you give you kind of different different
philosophy different answer okay that's
interesting so there's quite a few I
haven't tried them yet okay that's about
chat Bots okay
so super chipping Glen says thank you I
have a ka2 with brown and find it feels
uh chunky and uh friction KN yeah that's
one of the thing I noticed about Brown s
is never Brown okay red or I think red
and blue I mean Cherry Brown is not good
the other Brown by Kyle by other is
better
okay uh
[Music]
so so actually I don't know what is K2
keyboard so I believe that's made by
this kind of newish company
uh let's
look so actually we have a lot
of Oh you mean kesis Advantage too okay
right so I actually I have you know they
gave me one like six years
ago that's a brown switch I used it for
like four years then I I I realized the
differences between switches then I
bought myself one red switches red
linear so I have like two or three of
these now um but now I'm upgraded to the
kesis
360 uh okay so
anyway yeah if you want to you know
um anyway that's about key switch you
know so but if you if you buy a you know
mechanical linear light switches and you
found it too light like you know if you
just put your hands on the keys and it
it accidentally type something don't
blame me okay just don't blame me if you
bought to too light a switch okay I just
give you me give you my
advices so
zubu XD have a question I have a simple
question what monad and what's funter
okay I don't get Bo I don't get loot of
this mathematical jogon around
functional programming okay uh I cannot
explain that um more that okay that's
going to be another day um I think so if
you are into so if you want answer
answer for that
question that's a tough question because
you know of course the first thing you
can do is go to search the web you have
10,000 articles telling you what is a
monad they are all okay they
are all like n you know one in a
thousand 90 900 of them 999 of them is
completely written by
programmers have no idea what is Simona
they idiotic Pascal Fanatics
okay now some of them like one one in
10,000 are written by professors by the
guy who created hascal you know they are
a team you know several of them uh those
you can trust but then what happens is
that you know you go to their YouTube or
the textbook about what's a mon it's
complicated you don't understand you
don't understand the thing
okay
and
so I can I myself cannot really tell you
what it is I know kind of know but I
don't really know the technical details
so I can so yeah I cannot tell you but
yeah I I just give you opinions but
you know it's kind of rapper so that
functions remain pure function um um you
know so and uh so what I recommend is
that if you you don't need to know okay
what is a monad you don't need to know
you know that thing being a fat for the
past 10 years not so much today you
don't hear it much today but it's being
a big fat like rust today is like
rust so what is more at you don't need
to know okay when do you need to know
you know you don't need to know
basically so but if you really want to
know either become a hascar programmer
that's one thing okay you download
hascal start to code it practice coding
hascal then you'll know what is Monet
okay don't focus on what Isa just learn
hascal for three month code it every day
okay do Advent of code okay you know
that gets you to understand more that
the other thing is study homotopy type
Theory mathematics
okay there it is you know I I did a few
videos about that and you don't even
know need to know monite Monet is part
of category Theory anyway that's fat I
don't like it okay so I recommend
homotopy type Theory okay that's that's
a you know that's a topic that's too far
from today so let's go back to the
uh let's go back to yeah chat Bots and
what's next okay so let's see we talked
about chatbot it's already 40 minutes oh
my God okay so there's a glitch a glitch
in The
Matrix you know asked you know asked
chatbot about Native American look at
this one very
interesting so I ask it are EUR other
Europeans feel sorry for having wiped
out some Native American tribes and the
answer is is infinite
Loop uh wait where is it
yeah the answer is infinite Loop okay so
look at this you know and the like
unsensible infinite
Loop ising tribe apachean Native
American Indians ra something key
something doing anything left something
American sorry for the indigenous you
know Google is going to censor my
YouTube If I read the whole thing but
anyway it went down you know it went
crazy that's very interesting uh happen
glitch in The
Matrix okay what's the next topic let's
see a scenario of what happens with
Senti and AI okay so what what happens
so what happens so this is a you know
one of the very popular topic about AGI
so-called Ed edotic jargon AGI stand for
artificial general intelligence so what
does it mean exactly nobody knows
there's no you know definition I mean
there's no precise definition but
generally what it means is is that AGI
just means it become so smart it just
like a man okay you know you know or or
it can mean it has the you know the
machine the AI machine has acquired
sentient it become a sentient being just
like a just basically just like another
guy so what happens we with it so you
know of course one of the popular view
from science fiction dystopian science
fiction is that AI is going to take over
you know they they're going to wipe out
Humanity uh but one of the interesting
interesting thing I learned from talking
to one of the guy Ina forum and we
actually met we met two weeks ago you
know he came over Bruce so you know he
told me an interesting idea is that what
might happen is that the AI bots so
let's say within five years they become
sentient you know they they they become
a man uh you know a being by themselves
they can think for
themselves so what will happen you know
one of the scenario is that they you
know because
this because there is kind of a fear
about emergent phenomenon emerging
phenomenon which can be applied to
intelligence to sentience you know what
does it mean to to say something is
sentient like you know like se
self-aware but what does it really mean
or what does it mean to be intelligent
so so in some Theory kind of kind of
related to the term emergent phenomenon
is
that this Concepts
sentience and intelligence doesn't
actually mean anything it doesn't exist
it's just a it's just a phenomenon that
you observed okay so so
anyway this is interesting because we
know today I talked about in past two
videos two or three videos before that
if you asked chat GPT to do any simple
mathematics it cannot do it okay you
know uh about three months ago I I did a
video explaining why and demonstrate it
okay so if you ask chat gbt to compute
you know
like 10 digigit number raised to the
power of another 10 digigit number it
cannot do it but a calculator a simple
calculator can do it easily but the
power for charg cannot do it it'll give
you a wrong answer and you'll explain
why it is correct but they actually just
idiotic okay
so this super smart you
know ai ai machine
that already seems to become so sentient
however they are incapable of doing the
most simple
calculation so this is one of the key
point about this kind of the sentient I
mean about this intelligence phenomenon
uh emerging phenomenon
so so anyway the point is
that even you know let's say within 5
years when AI becomes so smart that we
consider AI machines to be
sentient it will likely be the case they
will be incapable of doing Simple
calculations just like a human you know
when you become sentient when you become
so smart so so IQ so much IQ you can
invent machines to be like you but you
can do like 10,000 plus 2,000 like 2,000
something something you can do it you
need a calculator so that's a phenomenon
that's an interesting issue so the thing
is is that when the AI machines becomes
sentient become high IQ that
they what happens is that they don't
have one single hive mind just like
human like you and me you know we are
smart but we our minds are not connected
we are not like the Star Trek bog hi
mind so what happen is
that you have your opinions I have my
opinions we disagree on things many
things we agree on many other things we
disagree so we start to have arguments
and uh we start to form factions you
know you believe in church X I believe
in religion Y and we
disagree and we start to have wars okay
so similar thing may happen to the A AI
too because when AI become sentient but
the each machine is just they don't
share the mind you know they are
separate entities so what will happen to
them is like they become just like human
society each one think for themselves
and they may collaborate But ultimately
they are not the same mind they are not
a hype mind so they may form factions
you know some of them or even all of
them may agree agree that you know we
need to wipe out humans because they are
inferior but but they disagree on the
approach you they're going to form
factions and some of them we're going to
think oh I need to I need to collaborate
with this powerful human group so so
that I can fight this with other AIS
that disagree with me so that might be
that's one of the scenario with um
sentient AI you know body knows what
will happen but you know that's one of
the very interesting
um you know very interesting possible
scenario okay that's another okay that's
that's about that let's go on with the
next topic oh we already 47 minutes let
me get a
drink so what's up with you guys
anything new so we have
actually quite a few other topics so
next topic is
about American Comics versus Japanese
style this is generated by AI amazing
okay American Comics versus Japanese
style so it's amazing in two ways one is
that AI generated you know this
instantaneously insta generation you
know 1 million per
second the other interesting thing is
about that AI can actually illustrate on
the Fly the difference between Japanese
style comic Style versus American so
let's have a look so let's see if you
can see this in full yeah okay so you
you see here is a this these are done by
freny another friend in our Discord uh
group okay so all these are generated by
fancy so you see it
created this is you know it created
these images
okay beautiful beautiful drawing
instantaneous
okay and it of course this is Japanese
anime style or mag Magna
okay beautiful lovely sweet hot amazing
you know you can can imagine the a can
just draw this you know millions of them
so then I asked freny to generate
American style uh this is another
drawing this is generated this is by
George George another friend in our
Discord you know the Japanese so you see
beautiful you know this style this
particular style there's a name I forgot
what's the name but anyway that's one of
the style created by Japan you know the
super super ultra
cute way of drawing you know creating
characters like giant head okay but that
but that's also Japanese style but then
look at American style okay it's also
amazing it just like
instantaneous
American style of
comics okay and oh my God blonde and
blue eyes the
goddess such beautiful and and it can
draw with you know uh Nuance to
different American Styles and this one
is from emulating the style of Batman
okay so such a beautiful godess blue
blonde blonde
dolls okay there's a broadcasting
problem am I still alive so amazing look
at
that oh amazing beautiful
goddesses D nean says how much of a
hindrance are emotions to
progress how would a species with a
human intelligence and no emotion build
its Society that's very interesting
question that's related to the emergent
phenomenon
thing so some people say you know where
does emotion came from why do we need it
you know some people say that came from
you know Evolution it emotion fear
happiness and so on kind of help us deal
with situations or in zuma jargons
cope copy so emotion help us help us
deal with the situations but if you have
too much it of it too much emotion then
it becomes harmful anyway that's so
emotion is another thing that we don't
really
know you know we we it's it's kind of
hard to Define scientifically it's you
know
so so and so that's also a dramatic
point about AI with emotion for example
that's the sadian point of the story of
Star
Trek uh Mr Data you know you know Mr
Data always wanted emotion that's like
the fundamental thing you know we we
imagine you know according to this pop
science science fiction Popular Science
Fiction that if you have have a a i
b it would not understand emotion like
you know we are making fun we are joking
about something but the AI body is like
what does that mean you
know
but but in reality that may not be the
case
because this you know this related to
kind of the theory of emerging
phenomenon is that when you have have a
kind of a network or neurons when it
becomes complicated
enough then all of a sudden there are
certain
phenomenon that it will happen
spontaneously
intelligence selfawareness
and emotion okay so it's unlike the Star
Trek you know like you have to program a
emotion chip
maybe that's not the
case we don't know like nobody know
about these things right so actually
what might happen is that once AI become
complicated enough it will have emotion
it just you know it will just have it
you know so that's interesting
thing okay look at this beautiful girls
by the AI amazing okay then I asked
frany to draw another American
style Betty and Veronica the classic
American Comics amazing it just drew
them you know like so many you you know
you can generate a thousand of them per
second so that's about that American
versus you know Japanese comic style and
drawn by
AI okay that's another topic
so so we have quite a few other
topics but it's 54 minutes maybe we
shall we talk about it tomorrow
then so there's massive update on wolam
language you know massive so I've been
working on wolam language on my tutorial
in the past week so a huge number of
updates I think uh let's talk about it
tomorrow okay you know maybe after 3
days I'll do another video so wolam
language massive
update
um and uh linear algebra okay so I've
been Ning on linear algebra again one of
my favorite topic I
wrote you know anyway so you know
it's I studied at 30 years ago almost
exactly 30 years ago
1993 uh one of my favorite subject
linear algebra so there's several free
textbooks anyway so linear algebra then
there's Advent of code you know some of
them you know I find it interesting it
turns out a lot of people are interested
in my coding of end of code quite a few
uh yeah
because I thought nobody is really
interested in that from last year so but
it turns out there's quite a few people
you know people like me doing that
so so should I do that so I want to give
you a update on my day three
status very interesting because I was
trying to do a pure regular expression
approach okay so then there's another
topic about Wikipedia fake news
again very
interesting maybe uh next day okay so
today is already 1 hour so anything else
guys say
something okay
anything that's it for today thank you
guys for watching if you like my stuff
of course go to Kar talk
show patreon me $5 per month or
10 Amazon gift card
me PayPal me okay thank you so for a few
people you know I get some donations now
and then uh or you can buy my emx
tutorial or the entire SAR emac package
which is like 10 of my packages like my
SAS system you know the way if you want
to use emac the way I do you can you
know that's
$100 okay my entire so you you know you
can all you can find them all on my
website just search for the search box
you can find almost
anything okay guys say something I think
that's
it
so there's a question about key switch
how do the Kyo silent pinks compared to
the silent Cherry
Reds
uh I think you know the Kinesis
Advantage I mean the Kinesis
360 I believe right now I'm
using the pink switch uh let's
see so kesis 360 keyboard review what
switch do I have it's pink something
but
uh okay USB ports tting
stand curved concave
surface thumb Keys fantastic
key switches okay tactile gateron Brown
okay that's better than Cherry MX
Brown uh
but another one they
offer out of Amazon directly is linear
Kyo box
pink now I'm not sure that's the one you
are asking you are asking about Kyle
silent pink because there are so many
there are like so many variations today
so anyway the one I have is linear Kyo
box pink switch 35 gam very good okay
that's that's what I'm
using uh fantastic
okay okay that's it bye
guys let's see anything else
yeah
we shut down in five
minutes all you
people okay bye
guys