good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is 2019 October 27th sunday
nigh o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time and today we are
going to do a impromptu JavaScript plus
SVG coding live coding we are going to
plot a math curve now this is impromptu
now my my skillet my sleeping schedule
my video not talk shows schedule is kind
of in the mess okay so I was not
planning to do a video today but I woke
up and it's the right time you know you
know when you wake up after two hours
that's the best time that's the best
time of your day so usually I choose
that time to do the video so no money no
more it's it's something like ten
o'clock in the morning or noon but you
know I figured I'm going to do a video
so you don't you see you know every time
I think of many people who especially
but who wants to me to stick to a
schedule but I'm thinking you know I'm
doing everyday I'm doing a video every
day and that and for I know for a lot
people that's too much you know they
don't have time to just spend one hour
90 minutes to just watch my video
you know this there's millions of videos
out there so so but it would be I mean
it's great there are some people who
like to watch my show every day but you
know I'm putting out a lot so I so I'm
thinking you know what it doesn't really
matter if you cannot catch it live you
know so so anyway I mean that that's my
excuse for my random chaotic schedule so
so today it's going to be very simple
okay today we are doing
just going to do a javascript live
coding that I did not finish last time
stop is okay so JavaScript was SVG
coding and we can finish it in 40
minutes
last time we about 2 days ago we tried
that and we did not finish but this time
we will we will start from scratch and
do it so so okay so that is the premise
so what are we going to do today now is
to write a JavaScript code to create
this image this is created in
Mathematica and it's a PNG file as you
can see so it's static I'm going to
change this to a live JavaScript code so
open the file so you can see this is the
source code for that file and this is a
PNG file right there
some start command log mod okay all my
Emacs commands you can see on the Left
window here for those of you Emacs users
so we're gonna create this in JavaScript
so first so actually that's let's go to
my directory okay actually I have a
template here let's start from scratch
okay so we are going to create a new
file new file in HTML mod and HTML
insert a template JavaScript first SVG
fat math curve okay that's what we're
going to do and we're gonna insert a
random dive tag with a high D okay SVG
so this is our random tag and also we're
gonna okay show in browser okay I need
to save this X X 2 dot H
email X X 2 X X X X plot let's say
JavaScript prod okay
now showing browser it's empty now let's
see title h1 okay now we got a title
now we're gonna insert a insert a
stylesheet ok style and the style is
gonna be ID SVG that okay and switch to
CSS mod and let's say border
sorry think way okay switch to HTML mod
showing browser there we have it it's
empty therefore you got you get a line
and the next thing let's pop this out
the next thing we're going to do is to
okay so what we have so we're gonna
create a SVG so we're gonna create a
JavaScript file okay so paste the file
path name it JavaScript and call Emacs
command to liquify it okay then open the
javascript file is its new okay create
new and put a date okay
there we have it now back to this
showing browser okay there we have it
and in JavaScript now we begin to call
JavaScript now we want to constant
create a constant this name and we want
to say document get element by ID okay
and we have that ID then we need to
create okay close this hold on a second
we open magnify go back here
showing browser now we need to create a
SVG element okay let's go to my SVG
tutorial because I don't remember what's
a command so it's what's a function so
let's we are going to create a SAS Viji
element and here is my tutorial
scripting SVG and basically here is the
code to create the whole thing so let's
copy it and let's go back to JavaScript
and let's paste it here okay so this
code we have a function here then at the
end we call the function here and the
function first of all create a SVG
element so let's do that let's okay how
now second so let's create a SVG element
there SVG element then we okay let's
copy that
okay then we set the SVG hate and wait
okay then we create a circle element
then we append the circle element to the
SVG element then we append the SVG
element to the to the dive SVG part
which is that way
so document.getelementbyid e actually so
we attach it like that the pen child and
now we can delete this function we don't
need it function we are coding
everything directly so now we go back to
the Java Script showing browser now I
have JavaScript off here so I need to
show in Google Chrome so let's do it
because I have JavaScript on the test
okay good I'm good and now so let's show
it in him in Google Chrome so
open opening Chrome browser okay so
enter there we have it so we have a
circle of SVG element now all we have to
do is to remember it needs hold on
second let's copy this copy the file
path close it go back to go back here
and add a horizontal line and paste the
link here and showing Bowser
okay refresh that's good move it here so
we want what we want is actually this
this graph this graph is what we are
trying to do so let's go back let's copy
the graph over here so copy it close it
paste it showing browser so this graph
is what we are trying to do so let's
begin let's start to create what we want
so go back to the javascript file and
okay so here we create a SVG element
then we set the width and hate then we
create a circle now a circle is not what
we want we want a now two products first
of all we need to define a function for
this function but before we do that
let's just say x squared okay define a
function constant area function let's
say math F so math F is our function so
X so you enter X and it returns math
let's say x squared okay
let's say that is our function so we are
going to first of all try to plot x
squared so how do you do that first of
all for each input to the function we
need to have a output that is the value
Y
but we need a coordinate so we need a
pair x and y that with a sense a point
on the curve so we what we can do is
that we want to map this function into
an input range okay let's say x mean
constant x mean x mean from 0 to x max x
max let's say let's say 3 so plot this
curve x squared from 0 to 3 okay so
first of all we need to generate an
array of elements from 0 to 3 with in
turbos let's say 0.1 okay
so we're going to create a rate of
intervals from 0 to 3 so how do you do
that now in JavaScript there is no range
function in Python you just say 0 3 0
point what that's how you do it in
Python but in JavaScript you don't have
that so how do you do that okay we go
back to my JavaScript tutorial
javascript in depth and you go to the
array section array understanding array
and there's a section or page on array
how to so here is a function range
function to generate a way so I have
written this function it's pretty easy
to understand so let's put the function
here let's put a function here so this
function X range minimum max we are
written of away from Ming to max and if
you give a step you are returned away by
that step basically the way you do that
is just for loop you see this function
is using a for loop in fact for loop is
the fastest way to channel generate a
array that is nature of JavaScript
there's no
thing you can do about that so for loop
is a fast way to generate away in the
most efficient way why am i mentioning
that because typically for a functional
programmer me or those of you who prefer
functional programming you don't like to
use for loops but in JavaScript you have
no choice that's you know that's even
though JavaScript supports functional
programming but the best way to generate
array the most efficient efficient way
is simply a for loop is faster then for
each other ways to do it and remember
the thing is that we need a step because
if we do not need to a arbitrary step
size interval then you can simply do
this this kind of in comprehensible way
with JavaScript 2015 anyway so we have
this function it's not range so let's
just use that so input so we're gonna
call range it's not range and actually
so from X mean X mean to X Max in steps
of okay let's put it here X step see
your point one okay so now now that
gives us a range we need to say waiting
into a variable input okay X range X
values let's say okay now that X values
is the input values to X what's the next
thing we need to now we need to map this
function to X values okay let's do that
so math function which is a weight so x
value is a array we want to map okay and
then we pass the function
constant error function so the function
right not constant error function arrow
function ok the function will take a
value X and return a pair of numbers x
and y ok so the the x value is just X
itself the Y value will be mass F X okay
so this so for each input value of x we
return a coordinate a vector of two
things x and y ok that is that is the
points so we're gonna create a variable
constant pts ok so that's the result of
that is at least the points right so
what is the next thing to do so now we
got the list of points now we got the
list of points we need to let's go back
to what's going on second
so now we got a bunch of pundits refresh
okay so now we got a bunch of point each
point is a point on the curve we need to
represent it by a wait he's here
something that jumps my mouse oh because
my interactive pen is he's on so good
morning George so so folks so let's so
let's do this so we got the list of
points and for each point we want to
generate a SVG circle to represent that
point and show it in this graph so how
we do that okay so first of all so here
is a bunch of points then we map the
points to you see this is how you
generate the SVG circle and in here we
see this that giant circle that is that
but now we got which we need to generate
a list of circles a SVG circle element
so let's do that
so PT has these points and its array so
we're gonna map we are not going to map
we're gonna do for each because we don't
care about the output we only we just
want to generate a bunch of SVG circles
okay but before then then we need to
assign the result to a variable so let's
say constant circles point circles okay
so something like that so we're gonna
map this by a function for each so for
each pair of values we are going to
create a SVG circle like that so for
each here we need a arrow function okay
arrow function and in this error
function
hold on a second so error function the
input is x and y and the output not the
output but what we do with the XY is
that we are going to create a circle ok
create a circle ok let's copy this here
for each X&Y point we first of all we
create a circle we set the x coordinate
to be x ok to string okay and for the y
coordinate
cornered with coordinate we do the same
thing okay to string the radius will be
let's say three point four now and the
circle will be colored red ok so now
let's put some comments for each point
generate a SVG's circle hedeman okay so
that's what this part does so now we
have point circles okay and attach them
to right now attach them to the SVG
element okay
then attach the scg every SVG element to
our to our dive element so that should
walk let's try it
refresh arrow okay it's not working so
let's look at what's going on so we turn
on the arrow log the browser JavaScript
console so he says uncaught type area
fail to execute 9:47 and pain child or
not
parameter one is not of type not okay so
I know what's going on so so for each
for each of these
all right so so point circles is a array
and each element is a SVG circle element
now you cannot append it to SVG you
cannot append child because a panchayat
requires the argument must be a knot not
a array so that that's easy to fix
so what we need to do is so we say point
circles dot for each so for each of one
of them we're going to append okay so
yeah so wait so we need an arrow
function here so for each one of them we
are going to SVG a panchayat
so we don't need that so this is how we
do it
attach it attach attach circles to the
to the SVG container okay so for each of
them append child to SVG then append
append the SVG to our dive element that
that should be it hold on a second yeah
that should be Hana it's a shrink
good morning DM w so okay so let's let's
see what's going on with our code let's
go to a browser refresh he should walk
hey you know this is the show it cannot
read property for each of undefined okay
I think what's going on so what happens
is that so that this value point circus
right now is undefined why because for
each actually returns undefined that's
that's what it returns
I mean because for each is just for a
side effect so instead of for each you
want to use map so let's change that map
so let's refresh browser fail to execute
or paint child are not primed one is of
not type not oh I know I okay now we use
map map will return a away because pity
points pts is away and we map we map
this function to it but this function
right now doesn't have a return value so
it you need to return the circle okay so
that's that's what you need to do so
once you return a circle you got the
point circles is a vector I mean a way
where each element is a is a SVG circle
element then for each of them you do for
each you appended you know then you
should walk let's try there it is we see
something there but something is not is
wrong because you see we run into the
problem last time because right now you
see the red dot on the upper left corner
that's a lot of red dots because this
function let's see let's see what's
going on so the here with so so far what
we have done before it's or simple you
know is we are following the basic
programming of SVG now you understand
SVG you know you create elements you
understand JavaScript you create a way
you create elements you attach to SVG
then you get a graph it's all correct
however here comes the some kind of inch
intrinsic problem of creating a math
plot so now the problem is not about
JavaScript or SVG but rather it's about
the deranged you know the plot range and
your actual things you want to plot
because right now they are all within
that area you have to figure out a
proper you know the proper range plant
range so that they show up for example
let's let's let's let's see if we can
fix that quickly just to show so here we
have SVG attribute with 100 hate 100
let's increase it to yeah that's why
because width is 100 meanwhile our x max
is 3 0 to 3 so that's why it's
everything is showing up in a corner so
let's say with these 4 let's say with
let's say with is 3 hate is let's say 10
let's try it again
ok better but still what's going on
hate 10 ok I know what's going on you
change then ask why am I writing a power
function because that's my job
kind of because I'm trying to create
because I have this math project with a
lot of these friend curves those are
created in Mathematica about 20 years
ago and now I'm trying to replace over
them by interactive JavaScript so this
is the first step towards that direction
yeah but and you know Mathematica is
great but you know I need it to for my
website so JavaScript so okay so so what
so now the problem is okay so let's
let's try to finish this okay today so
just focus on this thing now the problem
is you see our SVG
which is only three that means three
pixels that's not going to work three
pixels you know three pixels on your
screen is too small so what we need to
do is actually there is a SVG thing
that's called SVG coordinate let's go to
my JavaScript tutorial and let's see
let's go through my JavaScript tutorial
so let's go to SVG tutorial so we need
to use the view box view box is how you
control the coordinates within a SVG
element so let me let me refresh now
when you have a SVG element you have for
example here as a SVG element you have
width and hate that's in pixels
now that specifies the canvas the canvas
you know can they call it viewport so
this you see this red box that's visible
you know the the canvas you can say it's
canvas so the width is hundred pixels
Hades hundred pixels now by default now
so that's one thing but however when you
the the points inside the box they also
have coordinates so by default it's also
0 to 100 for X and 0 to 100 for Y from
top to bottom so the 0 is on the upper
left corner okay so there are two
concepts one is the width and height of
the viewable portion you know you know
the canvas SVG size how much how much is
your you know viewport the other concept
is the actual coordinates inside it so
for example I say Wheatland hate ten so
you got this size screen but however
suppose I'm trying to plot x squared now
x squared you know or some other
function that
that goes from 0 to 1,000 so obviously
it won't fit because this is only 10 to
10 you are parting something beyond 10
so but there is that you can change the
coordinate create a user coordinate so
that from the left to the right is 0 to
1000 even though the actual camera size
is 0 to 10 so that's what we want to do
change the code and a user coordinate so
in order to do that you go to the SVG
you see it's called view box okay and
here is the syntax I mean the here is a
syntax with hate and view box so let me
paste it here so let's do that okay so
with hate view box so we're gonna add a
another so with let's say with so with
let's say 600 600 is a good width you
know view port you know something like
that let's say 800 okay width is 800 and
hate will be what what what should our
hate be let's say a hundred to let's say
600 okay so we have a kind of a TV sized
box okay and we can see it if you
refresh you see now we got a TV size box
now you see all the points
is on the top upper left corner so let's
change the radius so hold on a second so
the circle is here and the circle radius
is here so circle radius 30 okay refresh
now you see that's circle radius now
let's change the function so our
function
is x squared let's just change it to two
times X okay so refresh that's your no
good oh because you know X min is 0 2 3
that's too small let's say 0 to 10 and
let's say instead of five zero point
five okay
refresh yeah it's still no good let's
say zero to 800 okay now we got too many
points let's say step let's say in step
of 10 refresh now we start to see the
dots let's say step in step of 30
oops 30 refresh okay now we kind of got
far let's change the function 2x squared
again and see what happens okay so so
now what we want to do we want to use
the view box okay so to do the view box
we set the attribute view box and the
value should be X minimum is 0 Y minimum
is 0 that's the upper left corner and X
width and exhale so what the coordinate
we want to be so let's say a hundred and
hate will be
hate will be what are we hate will be
100 let's say yes let's see what happens
okay syntax error
okay unexpected token oh yeah so we go
back here now it got me kind of okay so
you see here here's a problem the
problem is that we created a canvas size
you know with with hate and we can
specify the coordinate inside it like
from X's from what to what and Y's from
what what but depending our function you
know the the function may output values
you know given an X it may output Y to
be very huge like from 0 to 1 billion or
something very large which will fall
outside of the outside of your outside
of your coordinate or on the other hand
sometimes the function depends on the
function this function made the Y value
may be between 0 to 3 you know very
small so in that case if you plot it you
know in this coordinate you become like
two tiny invisible on your screen so the
first issue we need to do the first
problem we need to solve is we need to
find what is the maximum value of the
function and you know the maximum and
minimum of X and the maximum of minimum
of Y so so what our job now is we got a
range of values we want to find you know
the points we need to find so here's a
bunch of points we need to find the x
minimum y minim x minimum x max why me
why max now x me n and x max we already
already know from 0 to 800 let's say we
are plotting from 0 to 10
x-min and x-max so we are partying our
function s squared so x max let's say 5
so 5 squared 5 squared is 25
ok so step is 0.2 okay now 5 squared is
25 so Y max is 25 so let's hand let's
hand coded it constant Y max equals to
25 and y minimum is y mean is 0 so we
got weiming and ymax and we can we can
let's move this down
let's move this SVG element down so we
first of all we get our points then we
start to create SVG stuff over here and
actually let's put it inside a bracket
so copy copy that cut cut cut cut so
inside this bracket will be creating SVG
stuff there so now we got X min so
here's our function from from X million
Y and Y you know xmin and xmax and then
here is our functions values hold on
second so
okay so the here hold on second so let's
redo these so to make the cold cream so
yeah so let's do this so here's our
function here is xmin xmax and here is
the input values for X and here are the
actual points data so let's change the
name points to points data okay so here
is the actual array each element is x
and y okay then we want to find out
what's the y-min and y-max now we are
hard coding this for now okay now once
you know why me and WiMAX you can you
can adjust the coordinates so we want to
be from so let's do this let's see how
we do this and it's zero zero okay
that's that's how you do it
this is JavaScript template string
JavaScript 2015 so in here you can put
any JavaScript code so the x max should
be I mean the X width should be x max
night- having x max minus X me yeah so x
max minus X me that's a width
okay so let's actually let's do this
here
let's constant X with equals to x max
minus X me okay
so now we can put the X with here and Y
so we need Y with y max - why me okay so
that's why with so Y with should be here
actually dot to string technically
that's true actually we don't need that
so now we have we don't need that line
set attribute we don't need that so now
the canvas width is 800 and hate is 600
pixels but the actual coordinate will be
from 0 to X width and Y width so let's
see if that works
please no reference arrow SVG 1 is not
defined so SVG 1 is not defined oh yeah
because it's about the last line you see
we are attaching the SVG to our dive but
but but you sees you see it's outside of
this scope so we need to move this
inside so move this inside okay so back
to browser refresh oops I know what is
that because now the radius is too big
the radius of the circles you see so
here we are creating a circles now the
radius is it should not be 30 it should
be yeah here is a very problematic part
of hvg because the radius the value
should be is is with respect to your
user coordinate
so now the user coordinate is x width
and wide width you want to find the
appropriate size for the circle for
example let's let's just change this to
three let's see what happens
refresh you know you see it becomes that
so it's actually not three let's say one
okay that's no good
let's say zero point five now I don't
know why is they look like that let's
see where did we go wrong this is a
headache okay I got a bad feeling that
that we are now in good not going to
finish this in 20 more minutes oh my god
I tried this last time it failed so
anyway so let's see what is wrong so we
got our function let's try simpler x
equals 2x so this should plot a straight
line okay and in that case if then
what's the maximum the maximum is just x
max the same as x math.max let's try it
again yeah that's that's correct that's
what we expect now let's try to write a
function so that we generate these
weiming and Max weiming and ymax
automatically so we want to find in the
points data the x minimum and the Y
minimum so actually so to do that I have
written
I have written already the code to do
that so let's try to borrow that code
maybe that will save our time let's
let's find where is the
okay looks like this is a function get
curve min max okay so here is a function
okay so let's we can use that so let's
use that so we define a function now the
our code is getting complicated so here
is our function this will take a array
okay so this this function is actually
not in the format we want so it's taking
a ray where each for each array you have
each array looks like that you have T
and x1 y1 x1 and y1 is a code and not
points T is the actual input to those
current coordinate so in order to use
this function we need to change our
format so instead of just the vector XY
we need to change it to the more general
the input then the x and y let's do that
so this is getting more and more complex
because it's actually difficult to do
too so actually so let's change our
format so where do we change so point
data okay so it's in the point data so
let's do that X X so that's this is what
we want point data
okay so remove that and let's see where
else point data is used okay it's used
here so we also need to change this part
spawn points data points data XY
there okay so that should work so we go
back here so we have this get curved
name max it returns X min x max weiming
y max okay and let's let's let's shrink
it okay so get curve
get curved me max okay we copy get cuff
me max points data and it returns X mean
Y X me X X max Y mean Y max okay returns
that so constant so that is that
and we don't need this year anymore but
what about X min x max okay so there is
a bit confusion so let's change the x2 t
let me show you let me tell you what I
mean
so constant T T is time okay time me
teaming t max tea with equals to
actually this we don't want to change
actually X with we don't want and T
steps okay
so we the team in team ax T stands for
time so basically here is our function
here is a T input is T and output is TT
output is a point okay let's change our
function so instead of X returning why
we change it the input to a tee you know
abstract T value and output is a point
for example if you want to plot T
squared you can just do that so this
would be a function 4x squared and so
now we have teeming t max okay and t
steps
0 2 okay then we generate a range of
values input this this is T values okay
range of T values and then we we want to
generate the actual points T where T
values map X map t XX actually in this
case our function we can just call math
function you see math function here
returns you know takes one value t
number and returns a vector that is the
point of this curve so points theta T
values yeah so Team T&T max t steps and
he T values okay then we we gets the
points data then we can find out the X
min x max the actual x-axis minima in
max maximum
why mean WiMAX and okay so let's let's
Eve
I don't let's let's hope it works let's
refresh no okay because type error
undefined is not a function undefined is
not a function at 925 925 undefined is
not a function
ok so I think this is gonna