hello guys good morning guys good
afternoon good evening good night
whatever and welcome to this fine
episode of star talk show
today we are going to do emac list
coding
for the first 20 or 30 minutes then we
are going to do a fantastic show
of my keyboards and random okay my
keyboards
my new gaming machine okay can you see
it
i'm gonna going to show you okay so post
your questions
in the chat box and
put money in my pocket okay so there
there it is my new
uh machine and this is a gaming machine
and there is
my monitor you cannot see it i have to
turn the camera okay so let me show you
the full size the video
okay so there is my uh new machine i
haven't opened yet
and there is that is the monitor my new
fantastic monitor
now i have money i can buy and you go by
you go by on my website okay
and that is my old kinesis keyboard
brown switch
and this is my new kinesis keyboard
red switch it saves your it saves my
rsi my repetitive strain injury for my
left hand
but first of all let's do emac lisp okay
let's do some technical stuff
uh when while people is
you know here we already have eight
people fantastic let's
begin double glasses yeah so
this i'm i'm a blind okay i'm a blind
bat
this is my near-sighted correction for
my near-sightedness
but now this is too strong i cannot see
so this is my reading glass
so now i can see oh my god now i can see
i'm going blind uh okay so let's begin
okay so
first of all i'm going to do a fantastic
i'm going to show you
emac this the fantastic editor the
supreme
editor supreme okay i have so
uh i believe it was yesterday or the day
i mean the last video or the video
before i
we are doing live coding of a command
and that command is this one okay
let me show you so you have you see i
have this list
and on this on the on the website you
can see the list
you see here's a list for example so for
example the first item is
a delete tag pair so there it is
and uh let's double check okay double
check
check correct yes you can see it
so so last time we we were
coding this but it was incomplete
but now it's done so if you just search
for this command you know you need to
download actually you need to go to
uh html mod okay let me show you so
here's the source code for
html mod the command is in this file
and you can get this file by just search
focus
html mod it's on github okay so that's
the url
so but let me show you this command okay
sight gmail delete current tag for
example
i um i put a cursor on this code
and i press a key and
that tag is good now back to now switch
back to the browser
refresh you can see you no longer have
the red
code tag so if i moved it to
for example here uh let's say let's say
i want i
move it to the li over here okay i move
the cursor here
magnify okay it's okay so i put the
cursor here
and call that again you see it just move
removes the current
tag pair under cruiser now if the tag
happens to be
let's undo okay if the tag happens
uh self closing tag like there's only
there's no closing tag
then you'll just remove that let's try
okay do it
you see so that is the command but
sometimes
uh so that is a html delete tag
pair now but sometimes if you want to
uh let's say let's shrink okay you you
want to remove
all these tags so you know it's tedious
to
uh it's tedious to remove that one
remove that one
remove that one remove that whip sweat
it
where did it go you know it's tedious so
so we can do there
web to remove the all text
you see so that command is this one
because html remove
tags okay now undo now the next one
this is remove html html to text
why because let me show you okay so i
just call it
do it you see normally when you remove a
tag the url is also gone completely for
example
uh this this my exact keyboard blog okay
you can go to it
enter and you can go to my keyboard
block
right so back to emacs but if you remove
the entire tag there's
you know all the url is gone so that's
actually that's not what you want
so instead you want html to text so that
is this command okay
so do it you can see
here's a title casa keyboard blog and
then here's a url so
this is useful when you want to convert
html to text
you know then you can post for example
this on twitter that's what i do
so that's why there are so many
variations of these you can see
uh variations of these removing tag
commands
then there's another another one that
removes the
all the list tags it will remove the ul
the li but not the others okay so let's
try it
remove list tags okay do it you see
the link remain the code tag rene
remain uh it's just that the list is
gone so you can now put a
put a paragraph you can see put a
paragraph
uh then if you show in browser you see
it becomes one paragraph
instead of the list so let's remove
list tags now undo
then there's another one that removes
just the paragraph
tag for example i'm at here i just
want to remove a paragraph tag so it's
you see
so that is why now show in browser that
is why you have all these variations of
html remove tags now let's do one more
emac this
thing and let's go on to uh
my keyboards and stuff keyboards and
machine i think you guys are interested
in seeing that
now is that part of sapphire keys no
because all these commands are related
to html so it's uh
html mod okay you can download you'll
find all these comments
uh informatic in informaticist
says can i use stuff like keys together
with exwm
uh yes you can i believe there are
people doing that
but i never tried that i don't think i
like
ex wm exwm is the idea that
you move the entire x11 windowing system
into emacs
so you know so the emacs phonetics they
want you know so emacs become the real
you know they say operating system uh
but i don't like that
i don't think it's a good idea because
that i think that's a giant hack
you got all sort of hack going on and
you
i don't think it's good okay use emacs
just for text editing that's what i do
you know i've been using emacs for 20
years so in the first five years or more
i've been i've used you know i've used i
read emails in mags i tried all of them
you know
packages email emacs ftp and emacs
sql in emacs uh
uh play music i actually i never tried
that you know but you can play
mp3 you know music audio like a
controller
emacs becomes the interface to your mp3
player
you can do that you can read you know
you can you can you can do lots of
things but i
but since 2006
oh i i since about 2006 i stopped doing
all those things emacs is just for text
editing or
you know programming text
keep things simple okay that's what i do
for example there are lots of problems
for example if you read emails in emacs
then you have to set up that's
tremendous pen
okay you're gonna spend few hours for
sure to set it up to connect to
gmail or whatever then every year
you know they change protocols you have
to reconfigure
all over again but that's not all
because in
in email every few years there are new
features like you can
contact list you can have images you can
have videos or something you know
in the email and emacs cannot do that
you know it's just plain text
uh which is fine and fantastic if all
your friends
and the people you talk to are
programmers right nuts
but you're going to talk to your mom
you're going to talk to your boss
you're going to talk to your pr
department resource
human resource department they they
don't know what you the you
is your needs you know they're going to
send you
spammy html you know formatted uh
emails with microsoft word documents and
all that so you cannot use emacs
you know to to to do those it's quite
inconvenient
okay i'm gonna talk about one more thing
about emacs then we're gonna move on to
the uh keyboard and computer unboxing
okay unboxing of my computers so
i've been talking for how long let's see
let's keep track of the time
only 10 minutes okay great so let's
let's do emacs
so i so next thing i want to do show in
browser
the next thing i want to do is this one
e-max
workflow create a web page for xr
bracket caps
okay so let me show you what that is
okay so first of all go to my emacs blog
magnify so you can see it better show in
browser
this is emacs blog you know uh
lots of things you know i write emacs
blogs every day so i have emacs tutorial
as you know uh and tutorials on init
and all everything you need to know
about key bindings in emacs let's turn
javascript on so this is my emacs
website ergoemax.org
and you go buy it okay so here's emac
this tutorial
and there's an introduction to emac list
and you go ahead by buy
pay okay so so i write
blogs so i'm going to right now do a
a workflow kind of workflow how do i
write my blogs okay using
html mode and uh so
so what am i doing so there is this
command
it's called bracket caps so let me show
you so
okay so let's say i'm writing emac this
tutorial and you know here i explain
emac this
and there's a new command i want to
write about let's say uh
let's say a simple command okay right
char okay i know
let's uh let's say let's say this
command okay
hold on a second forward word okay
there forward which moves the cursor to
the right
by one word okay uh
okay so so i'm going to write
a yeah emax blog so let's go
to let's go to let's create a new
section
press a few keys wait undo show the pink
window
the pink window shows all uh you know
all the commands i'm calling so
press a key that inserts a new section
like that then let's say
forward okay uh describe key
and copy the word here
here forward and make it a square corner
bracket chinese corner bracket and press
the key
it becomes codified and add a paragraph
and show in browser you can see
2021 january 7th
forward word you see that's how i begin
to write the command
so i want to document this command i
want to tell you user what this command
about
so i need to copy for example i copied
this syntax
okay uh okay let's say that
and go back to browser refresh you see
forward option arguments
okay but um
but when you
document a function's parameters there
are certain conventions
in emac this convention the parameters
are all capital letters okay but
in my convention usually let me show you
what what is my convention okay so let's
go to
um
let's go to text editing
okay let's go to lisp list
okay let's show some list okay so you
can see
to create a list write it like this you
you see that green
those screens uh means those are
parameters
while the red is literal you know you
type what when
when it's red you type that directly but
those a
and b are uh whatever you know for
example make least
make list for example this one you see
those screen
are parameters so if i want to document
this function showing browser
uh you know forward word it's all red
that's no good
so i want to i i so i have this command
okay so let me show you again so wait
uh so copy it put it here so i have a
command called xr caps
bracket caps okay start bracket caps
enter
so you see it added this french quote to
to every words that's all capital okay
so what why do you do that because i
have another command that turns this
into a
html markup so watch okay
press the key it becomes that okay
let's undo let's let's do it here
press a key it adds the code
tag and it also uh
change change marked up the ampersand
you know because the ampersand character
needs a markup
in html so undo let's do it again okay
so i'm gonna
call the command which is called um
html bracket brackets to html okay
so i'm gonna do it here do it so it
becomes that
then i'm going to do it here okay do it
then it becomes that then i let's make
them a list okay into a list
showing browser so you can see the
difference you see one is
you know the emax tradition just capital
uh
letters but i want it to be green and
also
utilize utilize is the convention for
for variables variable names so anyway
so i have that command
okay so that is about demonstration of
this command which is called
um which is called
uh here xr bracket caps okay
copy it paste it here
do that okay hold on a second let me
show the pink window okay
uh add that do that do that
go to browser refresh there it is
bracket caps and you know if it's a
building command you move the cruiser to
it it will show you the
inline documentation so okay so what i
want to do is i want to create a new
page
that that that tells user that teach
you know that that tells user as a emac
this
example for people who want to learn
emac this
about this command so let's do it
so first of all uh so this is you are
watching my workflow okay i'm going to
do this
fast so uh so i'll say elise
caps to bracket
uh bracket caps okay i'm not sure i
named the command correctly but let's
say that okay now
do do that make them all underscore
online
dot html and uh
okay so i want to create a new page now
what i do
i need to go to a emac this site
let's say
okay not this one so i i want to go to
an emac this
site so i can use that as a template
uh emac these examples okay
so for example here is a page
about change the paragraph under cursor
to the title case okay so copy the url
go back to emacs close that close that
paste it here so you can see there's a
link okay now
i'm going to create a new page
of that name but using
this file path as a template so so what
i do is i call this command
show the ping window copy
html by link do it
oops uh something is wrong okay
no search file directory what is this
yeah okay
uh something is wrong okay hold on a
second
does not exist create no
okay okay so
actually oh yeah i forgot
yeah okay anyway same plan as before
i it's just that i need to do something
okay
uh bracket two caps okay
okay so i create a line like that a link
to a file
and this file doesn't exist right now i
want i'm going to create it
but using these files as a template
so let's try to open it so you see it
doesn't exist okay
so now i say star copy html by link
do it it's done so now this file is
created open it show in browser you see
just basically a copy of that
file so now i want to change the file
name to
change caps to bracket
let's say bracket caps
bracket cap words
and this should be elise instead of
emacs okay
so show in browser
title is changed bracket capped words
now i want to modify
you know delete basically delete this
whole thing here
back to emacs update the date you see
you see the date is 2017 created created
updated 2017 you see let me magnify
okay so
update the dates and also remove the
remove the you know remove the updated
words and
delete that make it
take you know move it move the code out
delete that file oops uh what's going on
ah okay i deleted the pink window i
closed it by mistake
let's open it again suck
start command log yes okay
pink window go here
and now show in browser
there it is that's uh correct it's kind
of empty
except the templates now i go back to
this file
delete that line make a list
uh okay so i just go to
[Music]
wait where is the file here here's the
file open the file
and uh okay i need to go to the source
code of these
brackets okay
so let's begin to write magnify
it's not bracket caps let me show you
okay
some commands
here's a command to add
brackets to all
capital words okay so
like that add a paragraph
and i want to capitalize the beginning
of the word okay press the key then
then now i want to add the emac this
code okay
add the emac this
pre tag okay now i just
need to insert the emac b stack emac
this code there okay so
now let's look at the source code of
this command
there it is and copy the url of this
page
then go to the source code
here is the source code sub bracket caps
oh oh i already already done this
before you see
there is a url you see okay
so you see this so we already have this
page wait
we don't have this page
okay that's a mistake so yeah do we have
this page
no okay so good so so this
is the actual new url so we are going to
add
by emacs convention document
documentation convention if you want to
a link in your inline documentation
you need to mark it up like that okay
put the url
in front and a and a
backtick and a straight
uh quote okay so let's do that
so that's how you do weight that's how
you do that
url capital remove these
and the version
[Music]
december 8th no let's add today's date
okay january 7th 2021
okay so done so now i copy this
file copy the whole source code okay
copy it
save it close it and paste the source
code here
delete that showing browser there it is
bracket caps okay now i want to qualify
the
syntax okay press the key fantastic
done back to browser refresh
you can see uh that's
that's it that's done now there's one
more thing
we need to add this page to the
navigation because
you see usually when you uh you can
navigate about
so we just created a new page we need
to add that as another a new emac list
example so okay so
first of all where do i want to add it
let's see
so all these are emac these examples you
know it's
uh fairly simple so
this this one is about changing the text
under cruiser so let's say
okay sentences uh cycle hyphen okay
escape quotes remove accent marks
uh straight to curly quotes
then convert english chinese punctuation
okay
let's add it before let's add it after
the straight to curly quotes
yeah you know we try to put
related you know similar commands
together so
add it after straight to curly quotes
okay now go back to emacs
and go down you can see the panel okay
so you see that line that's the
beginning of the panel
the navigation panel so search for
straight
so here is a straight to kerdi quotes we
want to add that so
we want to add that to all the pages
because every page my website is static
website so
you have to add add a new line to
about 10 or 20 pages you know 30
20 30 pages so what i do is
i have a question find package that does
find and replace so what i do is um okay
so copy these two lines
you see copy it
code cuz replace text you see
in the ping window okay paste it that's
the text we want to replace enter
then cancel okay we just put it there
first now
we copy the file path of the current
buffer paste it here
make it at least and linkify it you see
it becomes
a link and now remove the
emac this word remove remove that this
is the line we want
cut okay
now let's call xr find replace again
okay now what do you want to find so we
want to find those
previous two lines we uh we did before
so enter
what do you want to replace we want to
replace by
let's magnify okay so we want to replace
by
paste you see this is a new line we are
adding bracket caps
bracket cap words okay that's the new
line we want to
add so enter so directory
yes this directory file path rejects
all html files files name any html yes
right changes to file yes fixed case in
search yes
fixed case in replacement yes make a
backup
yes so this is
this command you are looking this is the
output okay
so here is all the changed places you
know uh
about about 30 files
so that command we just called is uh
what i what what's going on with my keys
that that command is called this this
one find replace
text okay that's a in a package because
i find basically it's a find replay it's
a
grab and set returning emac this
pure emac list okay so close it
now show in browser
magnify so you can see bracket cap words
so we have created
a page and we have a entry in the you
see on the left side
so we are done uh but we need to delete
this part you see
we need to delete this empty
yeah okay you cannot select it okay so
so the delete empty that's uh that's
that okay delete it
back to browser
refresh that okay so now shrink
shrink the size so you can see the panel
okay so we that's
that's it about emac these any questions
uh let's go to okay so
that's it about emac this well there's a
let's clean up okay so this is my blog
okay now we want to now you see here is
a paragraph that contains the link
now i want to extract the url in a link
so i press a key
paste you see that's a file path now i
want
now make it a link make a paragraph
because i don't want
you know at least i just want a
paragraph so here's a new one so now i
want to add this
so you see this is a new entry for my
emacs blog today
so i want to add it to my rss web feed
so i just move the cursor here press the
key
this is my atom file atom file the
you know so here's the today's entry
you can see okay so
uh you see entry you know
emac this bracket kept words so that's
it so save this
close it say save this go to e-shell
now press a key that runs the macro
this marker came from ultimate hacking
keyboard
okay so it syncs to my server so you can
see ultimate hacking keyboard okay so
this is my kinesis
red switch okay so that's the
so actually so you can see this is my
old kinesis
let's see
so you can see this is my now this is my
new kinesis you can see
the model is advantage to lf
lf stands for linear something okay it's
a linear
it's a silent red switch and this is
ultimate hacking keyboard
pd2 pd2 stands for uh keypad
okay my my all my markers you can see
last window okay last window
let's go to a browser okay
and the previous tab previous tab
previous tab
next tab last window last window
and close tab oops reopen
so it's a efficiency talking
okay now i'm going to show you my uh
okay so you can see all these files are
synced to my web server so now if you
just go to
xrd emacs blog you'll see
today's new code so that concludes my
workflow
demonstration and now we let's go
talk about keyboard and boxing and
unboxing
the millennial generations unboxing
thing
oh i forgot to show you the my
windows
anyway so okay so let's let's do the
unboxing
thing okay close that close that close
that
close that reopen reopen show in browser
that's right and shrink to the normal
size
okay close that uh
okay so
let me check the comments and let's do
unboxing so what
what you guys are saying
or maybe some other related style
extension not sure hello
too long didn't read cake hello
math cubes jack sharp can you see
right now yes of course i can see you
should just get over prescription
updated i think no i did uh you just
create a copy of already existing
article yes indeed
so 15 your viewers say something guys
okay so now let's do unboxing
uh so i got four thousand dollars
from patreon for the for for the past
four
four years uh thank you guys and so i
now have a new machine
i no longer suffer suffer the suffrage
of dinky machines
uh and uh so what are we doing so we are
going to turn on this video
you know i want to make this v uh
this screen larger but if i do that
obs is going to crash so let's not do
that then
okay so i guess i just opened them i'm
gonna show you okay let me let me show
you
a few things first
so you can see this is my other kinesis
you can see it says
kinesis advantage to qd
now what does qd means well it means
the it's dual label okay dual label
it's a volatile verac and quality you
see
for each key you have two labels and uh
but this is uh this is cherry mx brown
switch
it's a fantastic keyboard but i i have
problem with brown suits which i told
you guys many times
such that my left hand here hurts
like right now i mean in the past two
days i've been typing a lot
so it began to hurt again so i was
thinking oh my god i really
you know 350 dollars this keyboard 340
you know do i really want to buy it uh
and finally i thought yeah it's better
than
becoming a okay so
so i got so so you can see both of my
keyboards let me show you
so you see they are exactly identical
basically you know they are exactly the
same you just the switch
you know this the switch is uh cherry mx
brown i
i'm not going to uh you know show you
you know i'm not going to let's see if i
can do that
with my hands
yeah i don't i don't want to do it but
anyway so this is
a cherry mx silent red
and it's fantastic i tell you okay i
tell you guys so
if you guys have hand paint
hand pen you know you suffer from rsio
or you really type a lot like you are a
writer you are a novelist or you are a
type entry clerk you know you type
few hours a day you have to measure how
much you actually type
you know most people think oh i'm a
programmer therefore
i sit in front of computer all day i
type all day no you don't
you know i have article on that search
for sally
how many how much programmer actually
type okay
so the point is that you actually have
to get a key lock
then you know how many characters how
many you know keystrokes you actually
type
and if you actually log it you count it
you'll find out that
you know even use maybe you sit in front
of a computer all day but
the amount of typing can be done in 10
minutes in in five minutes if you just
type continuously
so you don't type all day you only type
five minutes a day you
you programmers but i've been typing a
lot you know
so anyway so that's a key okay you you
want you want to know how much you
actually type
so there are different classes you know
this mom and pop
you know they they rarely use a computer
then there's
maybe photoshop users then there's
programmers then there's writers
bloggers novelists
then there's maybe some gamers some role
playing
text-based gamers you know they they
actually type a lot
then there's data entry clocks you see
there that's your job to type
continuously
that's a key word continuously typing
non-stop for
several hours a day that's typical of
data entry clocks
so so this it's a huge difference okay
between them
you know so some of the device good for
programmers are not good for
their entry clocks so if you are a data
entry clerk this is what you want okay
usually
and you want mechanical switches if you
are a
programmer then maybe you can go for
one of those plank plank or happy
hacking yeah
those are good for you but if you type
more than that
you're gonna get rsi fast
so that is why so so highly recommended
you can buy
it on my website okay so i need to show
you
you go to uh where do you go to you go
to
okay my emacs blog you go to like talk
show
you go to xr keyboard
blog so i'm telling you about red switch
red switches and i've updated my
mechanical switch page you know you just
you'll find it on my website
i talk about i tell you about the
differences between different
mechanical switches cherry mx
or gateron or others red blue
black and so on so i recommend i highly
recommend
you get a linear linear switch and
light like 45 grams or less
okay so that's my story now let me tell
you about why i bought these things
so you know this is my biggest spending
in 15 years in 15 years
and let me let me just
show you okay then let's just show you
the um
let's see comments uh you just create a
copy yeah
okay not much comments do i know any
filipino
hackers no
oh this is heavy
mouse
they included a mouse a stupid stupid
gaming mouse
msi gaming mouse
so that is that
well they have actually a box of
a nylon case to go with it
gonna be some expensive
there it is my new computer
this gaming pc
go
let's see if you can
this gaming pc anyway
i'm not
i'm not much of a uh unboxing
guy so what you guys are saying
so this is the so any questions
that's it that's it you know that's the
that's my machine
i'm not much of a unboxing guy
so i have to now i have to spend
a few hours to
to set this thing up yeah
it's amazing that you have this
case
so there it is there it is my new
machine
and then i'm going to open the monitor
the monitor is going to be great
thank you save me roughly 150 very nice
was thinking about getting ergonomic
keyboards because of hand pain
okay you also suffer from it where you
were you from
lucas sam b look at somebody where you
from
are you in usa but i should do more
research first before appending
so much money yeah uh
first time i caught you live oh
so thunder i have question about fly
keys versus vim
the movement option with fly keys is
quite appealing
but is there something equivalent to the
vim command
and combination such no i can tell you
right off
so stuff like keys is not veeam okay so
it's it's does
it does not try to emulate
vim in any way the only
the only similarities like soft laggy
and veeam are both model
okay so i know most vin people they will
they what you know there's one thing
they want they want like
uh how they call it comp compositional
commands like they can delete
like you have certain keys for deleting
you have certain keys for deleting then
you have certain keys for selecting
select words select line select you know
paragraph
so you can combine them so supposedly
you know i don't think so actually
i will challenge those ideas so
so anyway i'm starting to get into a
rant actually this
should be a proper rant another day okay
so
vim people you know this is frequently
talked about
they they they have this concept of
compositional
keys or commands you know but i don't
think that
if you look in detail that doesn't stand
you know there's only actually
very handful uh keys and commands that
you can combine
very handful okay but anyway i would
claim
soft fly keys is more efficient yeah
than whatever
beam combination so anyway
uh yeah and veeam is great okay so
but you know that's my opinion
so let me finish the reading so is there
something equivalent to the vim
command combination yeah such as ciw for
change
for change in word of uh
i cannot read to change a parenthesis
equivalent of combining operations
yeah no okay look how sami uh seems
quite a good
computer enclosure i spend too much time
studying
those and this one seems good yeah it's
made from
msi it happens to be yeah msi you know
you go to amazon there is
uh you buy power and there's a few
gaming you know very popular it's over
for around a thousand dollars kind of
like cheap gaming machine
i don't play games uh but i thought that
i might get into i talked about last in
last video
sweden okay sweden okay i don't know
what's going on in sweden
i think that's it for today
uh yeah i think that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
okay paypal and patreon me okay
uh 49 minutes
oh yeah open the video let me okay so
so you go to
you go to you know my blog
then you can see what monitor i get okay
so you can see
uh this this is a highly recommended
monitor
okay i read it because i you know i did
some research i read reviews and this is
a
cheapish you know not
close to three hundred dollars you know
not the cheapest but
if you want to upgrade from you know 128
by
by 940 you know something like if you
want to upgrade you know
then you get this one
so i'm going to upgrade so you know uh
and and this is
this is my gaming machine spec it's not
on amazon i've i try to find it it's not
on amazon but amazon has a lot similar
okay
okay let me open the monitor okay so
that's that one
then that's it for today you go by my uh
javascript tutorial javascript in depth
and emac this
tutorial okay so let's
so
box within a box
asus for art
cables
usb
hdmi
power cord
bookmark
the monitor
this big okay this
is i think how many inches
i don't know you go to my website you
can see
this big okay
okay
okay that's it i think that's it
quick question how does one use a
boarding balls
you use it like that okay normally you
just have two of them
you just draw them you can do
them either
okay
yeah okay so you can either do them
by trying to not touch with each other
or touch with each other
and if you buy this don't get
the one with the with
with the tingling you know the chime
okay because it's annoying
you don't want that you want to get
solid
solid uh steel or
stone
okay and usually uh try to get the
larger one
because when you start to use it you may
find it a bit difficult but after a
while
the smaller one you you'll get used to
and the small one is
uh not good you want the bigger one
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
bye
starcraft yeah i'm i'm you know possibly
i'll start to do some game but i
am going to do mathematica okay i'm
going to
start to work on mathematica again
wolfram language i'm gonna show you
fantastic the power of mathematica the
best language
so i'm going to install wolfram language
on my new
uh you know that gaming machine
okay bye guys