hello guys good morning welcome good
morning welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we are going to unbox
the glove 80 okay this is the Box we are
going to unbox it glove 80 keyboard
there is GL glove 0 this is the glove 0
but they got a new Switch new lighter
switch so we're going to unbox it so
this is glove 80 so let's do it
um yeah so let me get my scissors and
this is not open yet
so if you are here say hi if you are
watching offline feel free to skip
around because I ramble a lot all
over yeah
so
that then the
side CH Ching thank you
crysto so Crystal you got a
keyboard but the bad thing is you got a
brown switch Cherry Brown switch that is
fairly
heavy I mean if you haven't used
mechanical keyboard before you know
that's okay but once you use mechanical
keyboard you'll find that that is uh the
Cherry MX Brown or Cherry MX black I
think that's what you got Cherry MX
black is even heavier than brown it's
the
heaviest basically among Cherry
switches so let's open the box
okay my desk is such a mess so
that you got this open you got to open
that
side okay
okay I think maybe that's
it so I'm going to open it now in the
front okay here
is which side there's one more
okay they they glued this you know let
me let me open this uh you know on the
floor so because in the front there's
labels yeah I don't want to show the
labels so let me just open
it oh
fantastic
fantastic so
this just slide out this is a carrying
case this is the best thing by the way
carry carrying case comes free it's
included when you buy glove
0 fantastic so can you see so that that
looks
like at last the best keyboard you can
buy comfortably curved to match your
hands small enough to fit in your cabin
baggage Tough Enough To Survive the
journey strong light and travel friendly
we hope you will love glove 0 as much as
we do yes I
do for eternity yes for eternity
so this is and okay so this is the glove
80 so this is the message and in the
back is the quick start guide since
because I already have it so I don't
need to read it so this is the you know
this is really really nice because gra 0
is hard to put in a bag because they you
know it's kind of
it's hard to put in a bag but
now they come with a carrying case so
it's fantastic let's open
it
zipper zipper okay hold on a second let
me stop the the playe over
there okay so now Sesame open
okay let's
see so let's move my keyboard away so we
got some
room H can you
see brown switch for the brown man hello
hello Dam
dami okay
so ah this is brand new
Fantastic so you know they come with a
pal rest which usually I don't use so
you can just unscrew it to take it off
if you want you know it's just twist uh
off so any questions ask me okay now the
first
thing I'm excited to try is a switch so
this is uh I believe this is 30 G so the
one I have over
here uh you see the one I have here it's
35 G lineus switch okay if you go to my
key uh my website s. info search for gl8
you'll find my reviews and lots of
photos and also I did the video review
one hour
long so and it has become my main I've
been using it gra8 for like almost a
year now or over a year so this is now
my main uh drive so now so the one I
have is 35 GRS linear switch I believe
it's called pink something uh you know
the it's uh anyway so this one is I
believe 30 gr so it's lighter so let's
see okay I cannot immediately I mean you
know I don't I don't feel it's lighter
so uh but technically it should be so we
have to compare okay so anyway we'll
have to see
so there it
is if you have questions ask okay so
that's one
side now the other side now you see this
this case carrying case is so nice so
you know one comes uh so this is here is
the other part there they are so let's
put them
aside and uh two little pouch
oh very
nice very
nice little
pouch I believe these pouches are common
in like 200 years ago or
something you know this is where you put
your jewelries and stuff or
marbles uh F
pouch so wait is it open Draw string p
pouch what's the technical name draw
string
pouch so there is the
cable so that's USB a to USB C
okay I already have and what this now
this must be a bunch of key caps and uh
stuff uh you wonder if Smartboard can
displace grav
I mean that depends on you like for
example if you're going to have a car
let's say you have a family you know you
have a Toyota or something or you might
some you know maybe sometimes you need
to
uh uh Carry Your Boat maybe you bought a
boat you live in somewhere in the mid
Middle America you know so then you need
a truck so then you have question is
your truck going to replace your Toyota
or SUV or whatever Tesla you know or
Tesla cyber truck and you only can have
one because you know I mean you can
always have
two so that is a
question uh so anyway so here is the key
caps for the Mac you know you got in
case you want to change MAC has you know
command and option if you want to make
sure the T is correct and here's a bunch
of of screws these are for ting if you
want to you know by default you can
screw the legs so
that you see uh back here so they are
scre that you know you can screw it so
it becomes
higher so it becomes like higher but if
you want more that's that's when you you
need to use this you know you but but
the most practical way is actually just
put books underneath you see I'm a very
practical U
utilitarian
utilitarianism believer okay so books is
the most practical because you can you
know book is cheap $1 $2 whatever your
book you know you already have or used
book or stack of papers so yeah stack of
paper will also work so you can replace
them you know or change height um so
book is very practical so right now I'm
using a
book so anyway so let's see so yeah I
don't want to press the
keys okay so screws key caps and what is
this oh yeah so the key c cap pullers
and a bunch of legs for the legs yeah
okay that's so very nice carrying case
you can see the moreo logo
there very nice carrying case
okay okay any questions you guys
have so now let's test the Let's test
the uh key switch to
see how much lighter are
they okay my desk is
crammed let's move this up a bit so you
can
see so I need to yeah let's go to
notepad let's open a notepad and let me
just try it myself okay Something In The
Water Something In The Water something
in the water okay now
here something wow Something In The
Water wow Something In The Water
fantastic did you notice
anything let me try again okay now
listen Something In The Water okay
Something In The Water Something In The
Water now
here did you notice it's quiet no sound
at
all fantastic Something In The Water
okay now now the the the weight is
supposed to differ by I think five grams
okay so it is lighter so yeah just a
tiny bit Yeah so
conclusion are you sure yes I'm already
sure I will prefer this one okay this is
the new okay let me show you my where
you can buy it and stuff okay let me
show you my
desktop uh again questions asked okay so
you can search for. infog gl80 keyboard
and there is my website you got lots of
photos and
reviews uh the full glory of the glove 0
keyboard and uh
um and uh yeah so yeah so what what I
want to say is that they got a new
keyboard new Switch come just you know
it just came out so thanks to the glove
0 people they sent me
one uh then you uh so where are they so
let me show you the new key switch okay
you can check out my keyboard blog uh
because I update often almost every day
uh then so the latest news if you go
down glove 80 there it is so hello
everyone in partnership with Kyle we are
excited to introduce small urgo's first
exclusive key switch based on Kio silent
chalk V1 key switch technology
so this is you know so
gl8 uh with Kyle the company that they
created a key for them I suppose so this
is a silent key stroke it's true
fantastic and 30 GRS linear okay so it's
there's a five gram difference uh yeah
but I you know I think I will I prefer
this one for sure the new
one and okay another feature is clear
case to maximize RGB lightness so let's
try
that uh let's shrink that so let's press
the key I hope there's a battery you
know
so okay so you have to turn it
on turn it on it's on okay so the and
also on the right side let me switch
screen so on the right side push button
to turn it
on okay it's
on now the left side press the lower
left corner to to show battery status
press
fantastic now let's
compare okay so this is the old one
press this key
so press this key compare oh so it is
brighter yeah it seems like can
we tell for sure let's
see yeah it is brighter
so can you see you can't quite see
but I think it's slightly
brighter okay so I think that's it for
today if you have questions for me ask
it now and otherwise that's it for this
video uh let's go back to my screen if
you have questions for me ask it okay
let's put this here
now I I am a keyboard review and I have
like on my
website I have over 1,000 articles on
keyboards mechanical keyboards key
switches you know everything you want to
know about keyboards and mouse and track
and other things so for example you know
you have a collection of ergonomic
keyboards and their history so you know
you got and lots of video reviews so
yesterday or two days ago I reviewed
this SW board it's really nice okay it's
a like altern alternative input
device um you know so I review a lot of
keyboards so I I'm kind of well known uh
for keyboard blogging so many of these
keyboard makers send me send me to RW so
so thanks to gra 80 people they sent me
one to
review I was very poor before you know
how did I started to write 1,000
articles about keyboard because I was
very poor I don't have you know $30 to
buy a new keyboard but meanwhile I type
so much I have hand pain like like here
there's a permanent repetitive injury
right here like can you see
me yeah right here so I've showed this
many times if you search you'll find
like a bunch of
History starting around 2005 that's my
first time got repetitive repetitive
strain injury after already 15 years of
typing so anyway this a long story I
have article detailing each so in the
beginning I don't have money to buy so
that's why so I read Amazon review use
but I'm also a nerd so I'm like reading
it oh but this got problem but I so I
check out the other keyboard and you
know and I I I I have a habit to write
notes write things down so that's how
eventually I
became obsessed you know that's how I
became have this uh huge keyboard block
and keyboard
history so that's you know and on laptop
keyboard you know a lot of interesting
things on laptop key laptop keyboard
such as for example the evolution of
laptop keyboards physical Keys layout
you know function keys you know you see
this is 1994 you have function keys in
groups of four very nice today you it's
hard to find that uh unless you buy
ThinkPad I think ThinkPad still do that
so you know so keyboard layout uh
evolution of laptop keyboards they also
used to you know not so much today but
they also used to have the
numberpad uh section on laptop keyboards
and apple and okay this is not Apple but
anyway so you know keyboard laptop you
know layout Evolution and many
interesting details for example
Microsoft they started to remove the
Stagger you know the we have a Stager
this you know Microsoft started to
remove that so anyway the keyboard
layout then we have you know the bunch
of keypads programmable key keypads
extremely useful save hand saver
keystroke saver and you know so I got
you know over 1,000
articles uh okay that's a bit digression
let me answer the questions and that's
it for today
Jason says I'm currently using CC1 as my
M what is CC1 I don't know which one is
CC1 and used to be on a moonlander okay
moonlander is a kind of popular
ergonomic
one uh okay so let's see what's the
difference between this and old one I
just
explained the key diff the major
difference is the key
switch okay so let's see what else
anything
else yeah just switches you know that's
just a
switch um
uh so if you can make one major change
to glove what would it
be it's hard to say I mean you see when
you know like that kind of
question so I suppose you are asking me
is there a flaw what do you think okay
yeah
so it's hard to say okay so because why
because if you you know like some of the
people picking out a keyboard you like
especially many of the do it yourself
people like they you know they didn't
like that one they didn't like that one
so they created their own but but they
think it's perfect but they own got
problems so for example Grava okay so
first of all some people don't like the
looks you know they prefer this kesis
okay I have it there this is bulky and
metallic you know heavy this is like
military you know use so Some people
prefer the you know the the kesis 360
heavy I myself I don't like heavy okay
yeah but so the you
know as for looks I don't care much
about looks so for example so you have
the question do you want that looks so
not but if you have that look this is
going to be sign maybe probably
significantly heavier okay so there's
lots lots of issues so the feed for
example um I think it this feed can be
improved because you know every time you
want to adjust the tent you have to
screw it and uh you know so let's see if
you can focus
okay and it's you know it's slightly
wobbly so that can be
improved yeah but if you so how you
going to do it you see you can't just
change that without changing the nature
and design of other
parts how am I how are you supposed to
Let's magnify
okay how are you supposed to
improve you know you have to be a
designer how do you how do you design
it sometimes you just can't if you go
with this or you just entirely different
you you're just going to have entirely
different design that's not no longer
you know have the advantage of pros and
cons of of this keyboard you it's going
to be all
different so if you ask me is there
something I like to to change with on
the glove at okay uh okay I would like
it to be okay two
things two things that's feasible to
change one is that that I like the
programability to be
improved um to to to make it easier to
program the keys right now if you want
to program the keys you have to go to
the website
okay it's slightly tedious you go to the
website log in then create a new
firmware download it and then you press
some keys on the keyboard and you'll
update the firmware it's not not
difficult okay not difficult but it's
tedious like let's say for now I want
this key to be uh to to let's say I want
to swap these two
keys you know
so so I cannot do that you know I have
to go to the website and and remember
what you know what what you know create
a firmware you know that's so tedious on
some programable
keyboards they have the on
thefly uh on thefly programability such
as this Kinesis 360 wired okay let me do
some comparison okay so kesis 360 is
also great
uh kesis 360 comes in two versions one
is USB wired the other one is Wireless
okay uh Bluetooth glove 80 is Bluetooth
but you can also plug it in so it's
wired but however the two parts still
talk in Bluetooth okay but your computer
can you can turn off the Bluetooth on
your computer so the gra8 still works if
you have it connected like like I do
like here you see but however these two
parts they talking Bluetooth okay so
Bluetooth is the issue do you prefer it
Bluetooth or
not you know if you have to be on a go
you must have Bluetooth no choice you
know you don't want to like plug in
every especially if you have a portable
like you know I walk around you know you
don't want to every time you know plug
it in so Bluetooth is issue so clesis
360 comes in
two uh versions one is is Bluetooth one
is
wired okay now the Bluetooth version to
program the Kinesis 360 it's more
difficult it's more it's more even more
difficult than the gra8 okay so you have
to like download firmware and stuff it's
more difficult but the kesis 360 the
wired
version that is Trivial to I mean that's
extremely easy to program the keyboard
you don't have to go to a website you
just press a few it has the on the flag
programmability so if you want to say
swap these two keys or change this two
Caps loog or change the change this to
tab for example just press a few keys
and there it is okay that is the kesis
360 but for the Bluetooth you don't have
the on the fly programmability so so one
this is one thing I wish grav can uh
improve maybe down the road so far as I
you know the the the you see it's not
easy to do because as far as I know no
other Bluetooth keyboard has this
feature okay important Bluetooth if you
have a keyboard programmable keyboard
that's using
Bluetooth uh I think all of them has
this issue of you know it's a a bit
tedious to program it you have to update
the firmware okay if it's wired that's
entirely different story but you know so
but gravity is Bluetooth so you got this
kind of
issue so that's one thing I wish
to I I wish it to be easier to program
okay and by the way it's open source
firmware so Z zmk I think is all open
source so if you if you are a programmer
you can you can improve it if you want
so that's uh one thing so what's the
other uh thing I wish to improve grav
okay easier to
program uh what what are the other
things I like it very much you know so
now especially now it's got silent key
switches
um yeah so I mean so the feed can be
improve you
know yeah but you know it's like it's
hard to think about how how you're going
to improve it you know it's
um yeah I like it so you know so that so
you know I think that's about
it oh yeah the other thing the other
thing is
that again this is you know you know I I
I wish it can be such that it's
completely wired I mean it you know so
they don't talk you know the two parts
don't talk in Bluetooth so but that
means if they do that that means I need
to every time I need to use it I need to
connect left to the right that's another
issue like too many cables you know like
especially if you are traveling you know
every time you set up your keyboard you
take the two of them out of your bag you
know
um you know they take them out of the
back then plug the wire plug the wire
plug you know it's that's tedious so
gra8 it's Bluetooth so
um and you don't have the wires you know
you don't need the wires in
between okay I think that's it
um let's see any other questions
okay uh model 100 that I talked uh I
talked a few times about model 100 it
was okay let me show you model 100 okay
this is a keyboard iio model
100 you know I think it's a great design
but they went over to the kind of luxury
design philosophy you know what they
call like deluxe you know what they call
they have a word for it they they calls
the
um uh let's go to their website okay
like Silk something they like they use a
special word uh keyboard for people who
take typing seriously okay uh this glove
GL okay so the model 100 designed from
the ground up you know uh
SW and and so on Precision field okay so
um you know I know this guy kind of I
met
him uh he's a old you know classic Pearl
programmer so let's go to
here model
100 they use a word to describe this
Delux thing uh do you guys remember
what's the
word so how long I've been talking 40
minutes introducing the model 100 okay
most beautiful ever made okay let's turn
on JavaScript so that you see many
website they require JavaScript if you
don't turn it on they the website looks
kind of bad
um so anyway so I you know so this gl8
they have this Deluxe Deluxe look luxury
look and uh it's made of wood so the
philosophy of this model 100 keyboard is
I would say the opposite the extreme
opposite of the glove 0 you see glove 0
is a very
like technical you know like Technical
and uh
engineering and uh without any flu so
they don't you know a lot of people
don't like the looks because you know
it's very light super light you know a
lot of people like heavy like heavy
heavy means good quality you know the
glove 80 is just Extreme Engineering you
know they they you know there's a lot of
details for example they made it this
you know height very low that takes lots
of design to make it to to to make this
possible
so anyway a lot engineering went to into
it but however there's
no you know there's no extra concern
about looks on the other
hand on the other hand you know the
model 100 is like you know they go for
the luxury feel like I would I call it
grandfather Clark design elaborate
wooden you know like like like like
classic Baro you know they they went
into that that direction which I do not
like and you know so and and you know
and they they have this octo feed you
know so how do they solve the tenting
problem they come up with this giant
huge you
see this this giant huge feet I call
octo feet and this octo feet you know so
when you want to design the tenting you
know one of the things you want
desirable is that you you should be
adjustable right to all kind of Ting but
not with this octo feed basically this
octo feed is just oneway
tent you know so so that's my you know
that's some of my thoughts on the on the
parts I don't like this this Deluxe or
grandfather design philosophy and it's
made of wood you know yeah you know do I
do I appreciate the wood no you know I
want it to be plastic this the Space
Age chemical physics Material Science
thing I don't want the wood yeah it's
natural all right but it doesn't do
anything for me so it depends on your
taste and taste and preference okay I
got a phone
Let's uh so hold on a second let me see
if I need to answer that
okay that's probably a
scam okay I think that's it for today
now if you guys like my stuff donate
okay go to kadi website c.in info and uh
you know check out you know my keyboard
blog lots of
information and history of keyboards for
example and ergonomic keyboard history
back back to
1935 this ergonomic mechanical
typewriter uh then you got key switch
guide everything you need to know about
keyboard key switches RoboMe Caesar
switch used in laptops and the Cherry MX
which is most familiar to you guys to
you know the keyboard enus Enthusiast
toer switch most famous for the h happy
hacking
keyboard happy hacking fans okay they
love to switch then low profile switch
this kind of chalk switch is what's used
in glove 8
okay uh so I got keyboard so lots of you
know 1,000 articles and uh so if you
guys like my stuff go to donate okay go
to. info and uh at bottom you'll see
patreon me Amazon GI card me PayPal
me uh you can also buy my tutorials to
available is emac and emac LP that's a
extremely Advanced editor if you watch
SAR talk show you see me you know demo
it all the time uh and the other one
more common is Javascript in depth okay
the best
JavaScript the most most practical the
most accurate the most easy to
understand the most
correct and the most in depth you don't
know JavaScript in depth JavaScript
tutorial then all existing website or
books including Mozilla including the
you know the best JavaScript books you
can buy you know actually I would say
there are two or three JavaScript books
that I consider equal equally good okay
about okay one is by Douglas cord his
latest JavaScript book the other you
know which is very good the other one is
by
um by the guy who wrote The Rhino the
the oriles JavaScript Rhino book which
is very thick there's a new version
about three years ago that is also great
another one is you don't know JavaScript
that I think is very good and uh I think
there's another one that's also equally
good which is uh if you search for
JavaScript SAR JavaScript book review
you'll find the list of them okay so but
you can always check out my it's all
online free but if you buy it you come
with a zip file can be used not on your
phone okay but on your computer laptop
so you can have instant instant uh
reference uh for example and D scripting
you know creating the entire web web
page web development without
any without any uh
framework okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
so Roman did I answer your question
what's your opinion about keyboard iio
you have to say
okay okay bye guys