hello everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today is 2021 june 31st
uh june 21st 2021
and today i'm going to do a uh e-max
this
live coding so this is going to be quick
i'm just going to be focused on doing
emac this
live coding plus uh tutorial so i'm
gonna show you what i'm gonna do
so first of all i have this command for
example uh
something another okay so this is html
you can see this is html and i want to
make a list i just call this command
you can see the command i called is html
lines to list
and let's show this in browser you can
see we created this thing okay let's do
it again okay
now move closer here create a new block
entry and uh some thing
then a b c okay
make a list showing browser there you
have it
back to emacs now so this is very con
convenient this uh command is called
html line to list okay and you can see
the command
by going to xsa uh emacs tutorial
then if you go down there's a section on
html
you can see view docs working with
brackets
power editing org mod then html then in
html page near the bottom you can see a
bunch of html specific functions
and one of them is lines to list so this
code you can just put in your init file
then
you have this feature okay uh
wait undo undo undo and do and do okay
so it makes lines least but however
sometimes i want
you know so you know i
i read a lot tutorial so this is
extremely useful but sometimes
the tutorial page is long okay
uh i want let me tell you what i want so
sometimes i want not just line to
list but uh but block of text to list
let me show you okay actually i should
find the example
so let's uh okay let's go to javascript
okay let's go to my javascript tutorial
to find a example so let's see
so javascript tutorial javascript in
depth javascript object reference
then let's go to array okay which
which is the most uh let's say array
push
now we want some command that's a bit
more complex okay
field okay field is a new one so copy
the url
back to emacs open that file show in
browser there you are so you can see
this is a file
and you can see here is a block of code
let's copy it paste it again show in
browser
you can see this is repeated twice okay
back to emacs now i want to let's say i
want to remove uh
wait uh uh well i want to
remove the html i mean yeah the older
text so you can see
so this this syntax does this thing
this syntax does that thing okay so
let's
let me do this okay let me add a period
there and let me add a period here and
and okay here's a yeah so i'm gonna
explain why do i need
uh the things i want so okay first of
all make them into single line okay let
me
demonstrate a few functions so make them
into a single line each line is one
unit okay each one is one uh you know
explaining one thing
so three lines so i can so let me shrink
okay
so now i can make them into a list
you'll see okay
hold on a second before we do anything
let's copy that copy that
so we have three copies okay now the
first one
uh let's see make a list okay done
the second one i want to make it a
definition list
done okay now the third one for now
let's just say paragraph then okay
showing browser
so there you have it so here is at least
an ordered list
here is a definition list and here is
uh just a paragraph now you see they are
not colored but let's let's color them
so
uh so color it color it color it showing
browser refresh
there you have it so i have three i have
two different commands this one makes it
into a list this one makes it into a
definition list
okay so what is it i want to show i want
to do
you know i want to uh do okay undo undo
undo
undo undo undo undo okay and do we are
back to the three copies
now what i want you know normally if you
want to make this
into a list showing browser okay that's
great but sometimes
undo sometimes i have
uh let me let me show you so you can see
okay let's move this so you can see here
sometimes
i have semantic units
that's more than one line so i want this
to be a you know i'd want this to be a
list item
but however you know this this is uh in
two lines but
actually there should be one line so
normally if i want to make them
into a list what i do is i first of all
make them actually into a single line
then i have to
remove the empty lines then make a list
to the browser there it is
you know because otherwise if i call the
make
uh hold on a second let me let me uh
you see otherwise if i make if i call
the two list command
that doesn't work you know that's you
you you uh instead
you're gonna have three lists that's not
why what i want
so i want to modify the command html
lines to list
so that so that when there is a
selection
it will make each consider each text
block
you know like this as one single
uh list item okay let's do that
okay so what we're gonna do okay so what
how do we start to code it okay first of
all
let's go to the well first of all let's
copy
uh these these you know let's
don't screw up this page let's go back
to their originals so okay
so let's go to talk show okay let's go
to
uh yeah talk show today's show showing
browser
then let's work here okay let's put our
code here so we can
have something to work on here so here
so so we want to yeah
first of all show the source code okay
let's show the source code
describe key press the key
then you can see here's a
command sight html lines to list
now go to it here
is the source code now make a backup
copy of this source code
okay so that's not too long okay now
narrow to different
uh wait narrow too different
okay so this code is just 60
lines if you don't count the comment 50
50 lines hello guys nobody okay
so now i'm going to yeah modify this
code html lines to list
so that when there is let me let's write
it down okay
uh make the current block of lines into
uh okay uh
okay let's uh see let's we're gonna
modify this code so what we're gonna say
so make the current
lines or text
blocks into okay here's that's
okay make the current lines or text
blocks into html list
okay if
there is no selection
make current blocks
make lines into a list
if there is selection make
blocks of text
if there's a selection each blocks of
text
becomes a list item okay
first of all if there's no selection
make
each line into a list item
okay if there is a selection make each
block of text becomes a list item
okay so basically that's the that's
we're gonna modify these
okay now if there's a universal argument
is called first
they make an older list inserted instead
of the
order list okay now we're gonna make uh
we're gonna start to change the code
first of all we how do you determine
if there's a uh text selection
okay you go to emac list tutorial
practical emac list so there is a
section
um
writing a command uh mark and region so
this page tells you all about mark and
region
that's emacs jargon uh
active region means there's a text
selection okay emax code region
and there's a active and inactive anyway
you can read this page so what i want to
do now is i want to determine if region
is active so how do you do that
uh there is the answer
uh where is it push mark okay region
mark
region region and push mark when is the
region active
uh mark active okay
all you have to check is check uh this
variable okay so actually i need to
modify this page because this
i need to modify it so that the mark
active is in this format so it's easier
to spot
okay so anyway let's ignore that so
let's back to the code okay
first of all uh we need to somewhere
here
uh let's just type here for now okay
if mark active okay first of all let's
describe variable to see if we are
actually on the right
uh variable so it says mark active is a
variable defining there
local and buffer something something
global something
automatically becomes permanent
something okay documentation auto
documentation the neo means the
marketing region are currently active
okay that's the that's the right
variable we want so if so if
mark active then make
each block of text
as this item okay
otherwise you know otherwise you know do
the
usual each line okay let's let's
write it
okay so pretty fine so this block of
code needs to go somewhere
uh here okay let me let's see uh
get reads about okay uh so
if there is a selection
then do something yeah i mean if there
is a text selection then do this
otherwise do this so normally
you know so so the whole code here
should go to the
um let's let's make it longer so you can
see
so you can see all the code
save excursion save discussion
to here
so by the way you are looking at the
kinesis advantage 2
keyboard you can find it on my website
just search for saudi
kinesis advantage that's this one
and the other one is ultimate hacking
keyboard and this is my mouse
and and pay attention to how i use the
mouse to switch windows
you see there is no click you don't see
click
okay and i don't put you know i don't
do the palm press the palm press damages
your hand
don't touch it don't touch your mouse
okay anyway back to the code so
uh so here we are starting to add the
list items
okay then current prefix something
something if current prefix
something something point mean point max
okay point mean
okay let me explain point mean p1 is the
beginning of selection
kind of the p2 is the end of selection
with temp buffer so
did we narrow to region we didn't with
temp
instead we use temp buffer insert input
string so
okay this is not uh efficient
code i mean it could be do better so let
me okay let me explain
i guess should i explain or should i
just blast through and you know just get
it
done let uh i guess let me explain
because not everyone watches all my
videos
so first of all get started bundle thing
gets a boundary of the current text
block
a text block is defined is a block of
text
defined uh separated by empty lines so
for example here is a text block
uh you know this is a text block so when
there's a
no selection you automatically work on
the current block of text
as the input so when there's a note uh
you know note you know you know again
there's no text selection you do that
so let's see uh
yeah and then so so this returns the
boundary of the current
block of text boundary which is a
cons pair so here car
boundary gets you the first element
which is just an integer
the car cutter boundary gets
you the second element which is the
integer there are positions they are
just two numbers
p1 p2 are the boundaries then you
extract the string you know buffer
string no properties view and p2 that
returns a string then you set it to
input string
then okay then you create a new buffer a
temporary buffer
then you insert it into the buffer okay
let's work with that so uh so
we have the boundary so that's if
there's no let's start to move code
around okay
uh yeah
so
so that is the so that's part of the no
bound
no text selection okay if there's no
text selection then do that
now if there is a text selection
uh well if there's a text section there
are some
so we need to find you see
the way it works is that
you see when there is no text selection
each line becomes a list item so that
means
we go to the beginning of line you know
then insert
like that then we go to the end of line
then we insert this item like that we do
that for each and every
line and where are we doing that let's
let's see where are we doing that you
see here we go to end of line
insert the end of line uh the list item
tag
and at the beginning of line we can also
see it if we search for
uh here okay so you can you can see we
search for that
okay so the code is a bit complicated
because it's also dealing with the
bullet or
asterisk sign or the dash because
sometimes those are used
for example in oak mod those are used to
make a list but when you actually turn
them
into html at least you don't need those
you know bullets
marks anymore so i have code to delete
them
okay so now first so so i guess
when we when i modify the code i
actually need to understand
what are these doing so so first of all
we select the boundary
that's right uh okay bigger
so we got the boundary then we go to we
make a temp buffer
okay this is not
the way i would do it today i know this
in
2000 i wrote this this code is like 10
years old
not 2019 2019 is last update but i wrote
it 10 years ago
today i would use narrow to region
instead but this the code is still
you know pretty good actually um
but but what about but but but what are
we doing god i need to
focus on these okay uh save temper okay
so insert that then go to chart point
max then insert that
then go to then then what are we doing
then
then we uh search for word backwards
okay so this line this block of text let
me show you okay
this block of text is this part is
actually
so if the line basically it says if the
line ends in dot html then
make it a link so um okay should i
explain okay so uh okay
okay so this is getting more complex
than i thought okay so
yeah you know for example you know if i
have lines like that you know i may
i want to make them into a list so if i
do they automatically becomes a link
because let's undo because they end in
dot html so that's more convenient for
me
just press a key then you have the link
instead of
manually to link each item
so that's this block of code is doing
okay uh okay let's go back to the code
so so but
when it is okay let's do this okay so
for so
let's instead instead of uh
it's that's what do we do
let's see so okay let's see
so linkify each line if it ends in html
then what is this go to java point mean
while not
equal line and position point max
okay uh okay
okay so
yeah so the it's then it's looping on
each and every line so then go to
beginning of line
when it's you know the lines begin with
the bullet then delete it
if the begin with that delete it and so
on
and so on then we insert the beginning
tag
then we insert the end tag okay so this
is for line
now when it's a block of text then this
will be different
so if we want to add a
list item to each block of text it will
not
the while loop will be
text blocks instead okay so the
the code logic will be quite different
because the wire
will be rather
uh yeah the the while loop
the test for the while loop will be
quite different
so okay so here let's
let's do this okay copy the entire this
entire block
okay copy it delete it
then just move the whole thing just move
the whole thing here
okay just move the whole thing here
okay and also copy that
move the whole thing there so we
basically have the original code
unchanged
the only difference is that we added a
you know if statement on the on the
alternative so let's
so let's just do this copy this
paste here okay okay let me
let me just code it okay then i think i
explained enough
let me just quickly code the
okay boundary boundary so uh so if so
wait so each block of text so there is
already selection here so you don't need
you don't need that and
there is already a selection so set p1
to region beginning position okay region
beginning position
set p1 to region end position okay
then input string is that okay i don't
want i don't want the input string i
don't want to do this
i want to do instead um
narrow to region okay so
so and i don't want to say this
okay let's okay so wait
save restriction now
to region okay
uh p1p2 okay
then
put the code here
okay
narrow to region p1 p2 and set
result string
yeah we don't we we don't want the
resource stream okay stupid
code
okay now to region and we don't need
with temp buffer okay
also remove that
clarify okay now to region then we don't
need the insert we just narrow to region
narrow to region okay then go to chart
point mean
uh go to char point max and
insert it
no we don't want we don't need that
okay now in i have to keep in mind
now right now i'm keeping a mental
picture what's going on with the buffer
and the
um text so anyway let me try to finish
program uh so then we uh
so move now to region then we go to uh
the beginning
of the buffer that's right okay what is
this block of code
okay so we don't need this block of code
because this
block of code is trying to make each
line
if it ends in html make it link
but now if we have a block of text
for you know to be a this item usually
that's not
just a link so remove that so now go to
chop go to chart point mean that's right
then we then do a while loop let's see
what the
while loop is doing so
so imagine okay so let's let me show you
okay let me show you i have to show the
code
i have to show the
okay so let's javascript so you see
so we want to turn so we first of all
user makes a selection then press a key
then each one of them becomes a list
item
so right now we narrow to region
you know which is like that we go to the
buffer beginning we want to
add a list item then search for the next
uh
wait uh
we add that add that
add that then we go to the end
at okay so we first of all
uh yeah that's okay i i know what i want
to do okay
so while okay so
how do you check the condition when does
it end
why are okay i know while
okay okay here is his here's what we
want to do
y are less than okay
less than or equal
while uh
while the point is less than
point max okay basically
something like that
okay well the point is less than
point max okay so i think
that's that's that
uh no not really while uh we want to do
while search forward
okay no actually i got a better way uh
go to point uh
okay well
ah okay uh i search wait wait i
search
regular expressions search for word we
want to search for what
for two empty lines two or more
okay then then
optional bound neo no error
true count we don't care
okay uh yeah let's put
this here okay so while that
then we insert so let's remove this
these this
okay so yeah so while that we insert a
beginning
um this item
then
then then that's it okay then then
ignore that
let's clean up the code so it looks
clean
okay while we search for word
yeah okay we need to actually insert it
first so we insert it here
then we search forward for two empty
lines so we
will end up here then we insert
again
then search for words then we insert
then we search forward so until it says
cannot be found
so when the cruiser's here then you
search forward for two empty lines
wait when the cursor is here search for
two empty lines then we are here
then you search for two empty lines
again
okay which is here
then there's no more
when there is no more when you don't
find two new
two new empty lines then you don't
insert that's correct
okay this will eventually uh wait search
forward we want it to move closer okay
so move cursor
uh you have to say move this is a bit
complex
yeah so you have to tell it to move uh
i mean you have to give it a argument
anything other than just t
otherwise it won't move the cursor so we
want to move it could move the cursor
so when there is no more to empty line
found the cursor will
should be the end of the buffer like
there
then then you do another
wire okay while research backward
again search for that each time you find
it
you insert a
ending line item okay
then this part don't worry about it this
this is uh if you press
uh control u first then you want the uol
okay so we can still use that
uh okay so if current prefix arc is true
that means you press ctrl u universal
argument first then
then you go to the beginning add ol
otherwise go to the beginning and add
url and so on
okay then yeah you don't need that
buffer string
save restrictions okay actually you
don't want to save
no restriction actually you do save
restrictions
that's for saving the narrative region
then you say
oh you don't then then you don't say dd
region you just
you because yeah then you just get out
then you actually you don't need this
either so simpler code
okay so actually here is our code let's
shrink
let's shrink it a bit
pretty fine
shrink okay so here's the code
now the code if mark is
active here then we do this
part this is today's code we just added
should we just now try it um
yeah we can try it actually
so if i buffer oops i should i made a
mistake i shouldn't evolve this buffer
anyway
let's uh go back here expand
then let's try it okay select select
select
let's see if it works press the key
fantastic
one shot but we have a mistake though
you see
so you see there's a ul item ul
beginning tag and uln tag but the last
one is missing a
ending li so our logic
there is something wrong in our logic
the last line
is main is missing or ending li so
yeah so i know what to do so you all you
have to do is like that
fantastic
fantastic okay so let's
copy evaluate this function let's try it
again
here you know so let's select
this is you know i want to make this
each one of these text block a list item
do it fantastic
correct now we are done essentially now
there's
some you know uh clean up for example i
rather prefer this extra line here
okay so minor cleanup so this uh adding
a url how do i
fix that i mean adding a line
uh let's see
yeah just add it there okay why not okay
now let let's
let's leave out the buffer i mean about
this function again
undo undo undo let's try it over again
fantastic now let's see if we what if we
selected some extra empty lines
do it oh okay so you can see this
is a little bit problem you see it added
an empty
uh list item which is not what we want
but
mostly we've done so how long have i
been talking
uh seven or five that's 35 minutes i
think maybe
we can call it a day hello
btx okay so
actually we almost done but let me i
want to let you know i have 20 more
minutes
uh yeah i need to go to eat
but let's let's let's make this better
let's make this all better
so okay so how do you fix the empty
one line problem so for example
you know so so if i have a lot empty
lines
you see wait that's not good so if i
if i just have a bunch of empty lines
that's not what we want you see
and also it actually is wrong you see
all this
ending tag okay okay
okay okay okay we we we know you know we
want to do something better
change the algorithm instead of having
two higher loops
because when you have two wire loops
they don't you know it
the first while loop will add the
beginning uh
you know the beginning tag the second
while loop adds the ending tag
but however these two while loops are
not connected together
that's that's not good so we
instead we want one single wire loop
okay one single while loop and
add the beginning and end tag together
okay so remove that and
yeah remove that remove that
yeah so we let me show you what we want
so basically we want something like that
something like that
that that that
uh something like that okay
search forward
then actually search backward okay
and since
okay so first we search forward for two
empty lines then we
search backward for two empty lines to
move the cursor back
to the two kind of like the
end of the in the beginning of the two
empty lines then we insert
that
then we don't insert we uh actually we
call
match replace
okay the text will be
that okay optional fixed case yes
literal yes another string
okay so there we don't care about the
others there
so now there's one single while loop and
this loop will be based on searching
searching for the empty lines okay
and then
then that's right in the beginning we
need the one
li and the end we need one now and let's
just try it okay
run the code back to here the test pad
let's try
empty first do it
fantastic okay it's an improvement you
see
right now it's still correct you see
it's a correct match it added to empty
now you see we are actually dealing with
the edge cases because you know
because nobody is supposed to have like
do it on a empty uh you know
but anyway let's let's try the here
let's try the common case it worked
fantastic
now let's try a little bit uh like that
okay it's still added to extra then we
okay yeah so actually we are done you
know it's uh
it works great now how do you fix this
extra
you know you can fix it by first of all
you know before we do before you begin
to do all this replacement
you know uh you know add in the uh line
item tags before you do this you can
first of all clean up
clean up the clean up the
the actually we can do it okay let's
let's do it to clean up here okay
so before anything we
before anything let's do a while loop
search for word
for that and just replace it by
okay so here is the code
we search for word for two or more empty
lines
and we just replace it by two empty
lines so we kind of clean up
the empty lines
then go to cha
okay then insert that okay so that's
that
if another code let's try again then now
let's try empty
do it okay it's much better but still
okay let's try this way okay so let's
try it here
do it that works now what if we have
extra lines
do it okay at most it when it added one
um empty line we can still do better
though
um we can still do better by
anyway i gotta go eat so thank you guys
for watching
uh you know we have the code
by tomorrow you'll have you'll see this
in my html mod you'll be fixed
but basically you've seen how this uh
code works
thank you for watching if you like my
stuff bye
my emacs tutorial okay like this
this link thank you bye