okay now I am live god I'm such an idiot
so let me repeat the whole thing then
welcome to another episode of talk show
and today is today is 2019 October 7th
Monday 10 o clock a.m. in the morning
San Francisco time and we are going to
do 10 o clock in the morning for this
week Monday to Sunday so this week 10 o
clock okay and god I haven't been
talking I'm being muted for the first
three minutes also so if you guys have a
topic type it okay
oh I have some topics prepared I'm going
to talk about them feel free to you know
ask questions and you know the things
you want me to talk right now is the
time you know because once I start to
talk talk usually it's gonna be nonstop
in that direction subject good morning Z
Tron crazy good morning Joss so just you
wanted me to do some eMac B's right okay
yeah let's do some eMac B's so I have
some emag B's now now if you do have
specific questions or some area you you
want you like me to see me do so type it
okay now it's the right time because
once I start talking then it's gonna be
then stop so let's so so so let's do
some eMac B's okay so let me yeah so
it's here
I prepared I'm going to write a command
you know demo of that that's gonna be
pretty short 10 minutes will do
depending on you know if you guys want
to see it more then I'm gonna keep going
on so bottom you says I decide to learn
JavaScript yay you you've been
brainwashed by me destroy Tube join the
Emacs crowd destroyed cube what is
disrupt tube anyway there's another guy
his name is Max Reiter he wanted you
know he apparently he's a hardcore
programmer you know he wanted me to do
more live coding yeah so you know that's
you know I'll try to do more of that you
know because in my past experience on
YouTube whenever I do live coding nobody
nobody is interested you know like you
then you know then it's so quiet and and
also yeah typically that's the case but
and and I suppose partly because I'm not
really good at you know maybe except
eMac B's oh I'm not really good at vibe
coding
but anyway so so I'm going to do some
eMac beasts today but there is also some
other things interesting things we can
talk about you know the yeah so he does
Linux related videos so distraught tube
join the Emacs crowd oh he started to
use Emacs you mean so destroy distro
tube is a account name on YouTube so
bottom you says I wanted to write some
web apps for for example Firefox
extensions and next cloud Oh next cloud
next cloud is a plug-in you know I don't
even trust Firefox anymore in fact yeah
you can chose Firefox Thanks I mentioned
these few times five bucks you know they
they give money to antiva they they do
several you evil things and their
browser is worse and worse basically and
and also Google is the google chrome is
the most evil I talked about this a few
times they actively do just like the
Internet Explorer twenty years ago they
active actively make sure that Google's
own services do not run well in other
browsers they do tactics like for
example you
okay so you know Microsoft actually you
know Microsoft came out with the edge
browser which is an entire new engine
browser engine that's something
non-trivial okay so Microsoft created
edge you know like five years ago each
browser entire new browser engine passes
JavaScript you know entirely new from
scratch almost from scratch then you
know the Microsoft post they say okay
yeah compare you know YouTube we are
faster than Chrome or Firefox and so on
and then YouTube you know YouTube
scums you know they the Google team you
know YouTube they change something in
YouTube so that so that edge browser we
are show of arrow so become slower
things like you know things like that
it's well documented you know you can
search for that on Hacker News and so on
so Google is doing that you know
intentionally make things that only
Google Chrome runs well so we started to
and you know go of tangent now let's get
back
so Greg son can you give a introduction
how to do Emacs these customizations and
how to bind them to custom keystrokes
for beginners I have seen previous live
shows on the topic okay how do you eMac
these customizations that like what do
you mean like like customize some major
model you know some packages you
downloaded something like that that is
that that is usually not easy not
trivial okay like if you are thinking
you know you know the typical Emacs user
you use a lot packages right let me
start Hawkman lock mod on the Left
window so you can see all my Emacs
commands such as moving cursor or
deleting things or and do you can see it
on the left window and and my keys okay
so typically you
if you download lots of you know eMac
packages you use it you know maybe there
are some behaviors you don't like so the
first step is to look into ok so then
I'm going to start to talk about you max
well the first step is to start to look
at the customization supported by the
package like you can do custom custom my
scoop you see at the bottom customize
group you call that a Mex customize
scoop then you know it asks you what
what group you want to customize Emacs
is it's very intuitive so you type the
page basically you type the major mods
name for example let's say soft like
he's okay okay okay so let's say so
let's say it's a fine okay I have this
package which is kind of grep written in
eMac this so I type saw find okay
customize group so find then you see
this window which is kind of say my GUI
then you can customize you know how many
characters to show before before you are
searching for sense stream you know the
context yeah you know so this is one way
to customize it okay so actually let's
start to talk about Emacs
so you actually you could you so you go
to my Emacs website then you go to Emacs
in its setup then you you know this is
actually many lots of tutorials about
how how to set up Emacs and and right
now we want to talk about its search for
custom yeah MX customize so this page
discuss what I just did
okay so let's close that let's go back
to San talk show and Emacs customization
okay so so this is how you customize a
package but however
this customization are only for whatever
the package designed to be customized
for you know like when you don't you
know install a Emacs package it may be
it's a major mod or Manama does
something and it has some settings or
preferences you know a mágico
preferences in Windows you call options
you know like the settings basically
then you can customize it you know
usually there are two basically two ways
to customize it
one is by actual this code you know you
just put this code in your unit file the
other way is this MX customize kind of
semi GUI so you you know so I I talked
about that in this page so that is one
way to customize in Emacs package but
however like us what I want to say is at
least these are just settings supported
by the package okay by design you know
like if I wrote a package I specifically
made sure that you know I have some some
things you can customize I put you know
I create that customize so that's one
way but usually sometimes you know
sometimes Emacs people you know they
looked through these that's not enough
they want some other behaviors to change
you know they want to do that then that
is not trivial okay you know for example
let's go to let's see what package I'm
using okay let me show you one of
pankajam using okay so so the package is
hold on a second okay so the package is
snicks okay you see here the package
this package is called smacks what does
it do it's basically a enhanced version
of meta X you know when you when you
press meta X that is actually calling
this command the this command execute
extended command that's the command name
when you press metrics Emacs is calling
that so
but smacks is kind of a replacement for
that commands with you know much more
enhancements and features so that's why
I'm using smacks okay smacks you can
find it on homeopathy so you know so I'm
using some snacks so this is the source
code of smacks you can see it's by
Cornelius mica you know he's written a
few packages so by this guy and this is
500 lines of code okay it's very nice I
recommend it you know use use mix now
but suppose I found something in smacks
I really don't like so the first thing I
want to do is I call customize scoop you
see we mentioned that so go ahead then
you ask me a group okay I typed sm e X
okay enter there it is
now the custom customers I customize
window show up so let's let's see so
smacks oh toad update um smacks flex
matching on okay smacks history length
you know seven you know let's make a
change let's say history length let's
say I wanted eight okay let's say I
wanted six so once you make a change you
can go back to let's magnify okay so you
see this I made it six okay now you can
go you can either click apply okay they
change the interface over the years but
anyway if you click apply that means you
will be saved for this session but when
you restart Emacs then it's all
forgotten okay
so if you want to save it kind of
permanently you you click apply and save
okay so I click apply and save you ask
me save all settings in this buffer yes
or no okay yes okay now apply safe now
why
cosmics is going to have like smacks
history length of six so what does it
mean exactly is its determines how the
determines on how many recently executed
commands
smacks should keep a record okay there
is a grammatical error I have you know
there's a chromatic error he says
determines on how many recency executed
commands that's incorrect you should say
did you know the UM you should delete
the on word determine how many reasons
we executed commands
smacks should keep a record okay must be
said before in initialization of smack
so okay so I guess it won't affect won't
have any effect until I reload snakes or
something like that anyway so this this
is about MX customize okay so these are
the settings that's all there it is okay
however there's you know some behaviors
of smacks you don't like and you do not
find it here that is when that is when
you need to look at the source code you
know you maybe you want to start you
know this is when you want to modify
some of the source code now this is not
trivial okay I don't know if that's the
question you are asking but this is not
trivial this is you you you really would
need to have like few months few months
of Emacs least coding experience to do
that and it's not trivial for me I mean
even I have you know ten years of eMac
busy it's not trivial because when you
start to read you know you know you know
for example when I started to read you
you you start to spend hours to look at
how these code works you know what it
you know then you can modify change so
it's not trivial okay so I would I would
not actually recommend it okay yeah I
don't even recommend it I do not
recommend
you know the the TV code open source you
know mantra of you know Eddie Eddie Nina
code then maybe you contribute back to
it kid anyway I don't recommend it
because he's you
well the okay these two things this
political opinion about whether I
recommended doing that then there is the
practical opinion about whether I
recommend it or not in fact in both case
I don't recommend it okay originally I
was just saying for in practice I don't
recommend it because you're gonna spend
hours you know it's gonna take a lot of
your time but I mean if you are you know
if you're for open source and free
software you can you can do it okay but
you know you're just gonna spend a lot
of time so rather so instead of spending
suspending the time to read other
people's code to make it you know to
change part of the behavior so so you so
you you can use the package for yourself
but you know you rather rather you spend
the time to study eMac please if you
don't know that that already okay so you
study time to study Mack B's you know
learning it yourself you can start to
write code and typically you'll find
that you know once you you know you know
go read my tutorial okay you know go
read my tutorial pipe I my tutorial
support me okay buy it then once you so
it once you code eMac list for let's say
one month then typically it's a case
that you can just write your own little
functions you can a lot power
okay you you can just write your own
little functions you don't typically you
don't need to modify other people's code
because that day or take hours because
you need to understand how the you know
when someone writes a package there's
kind of the whole system you need to
look into how they do it and you need to
follow that you know but but typically
you can just code your own you know one
little function you know overwrite
something in smacks or something that's
you can do that
in one hour and you have what you want
so if you are not familiar with that's
what I recommend if you are not familiar
with Emax list yet I recommend to
actually learn learn it now if you
already have several years of eMac
beasts then you don't need to ask me you
have your opinions whether you know you
want to edit other people's code or not
typically that's not for me because I
you know the the and I'm not a great
programmer I look at other people's code
that takes days you know they think it
takes it would take days to to to
understand to make the modification then
you know then I see lots of things I
don't like you know I'm very kind of
weird you know I see the other things I
don't like the way they do things so
anyway that's about that that's about
you know add actually I'm actually going
kind of a meta comment on your question
I don't even know if that's the question
you are asking jaws so anyway yeah yeah
like I said it won't start to talk about
something it goes on you know but I
wanted to show you several things today
okay several things today We Need to
Talk
we've been talking for 20 minutes
so I'm going to code this I'm going to
code these Emacs ways it I'm going to
write a new command to do Emacs to
create a command that goes to say
Matsuda chrome okay but there are some
other interesting things let's talk
about those first okay and let me read
the comments
edge transfers edge transfers to chrome
yeah so it's so bad Google is doing
these evil things so that edge team of
Microsoft they decided this decided
they're gonna throw away the whole thing
they're gonna just use Chrome's Google
Chrome's web engine and the code that we
have engine you know the it's the it's
called ping okay google chrome okay I
can start to talk about a history of web
browsers and their engines
you know chrome Google Chrome is from is
based off on Safari
okay all right this is about 15 years
ago 2007 also Google began to create
their own browser Google Chrome that is
based on Safari browser Safari on the
Mac Safari browser began in 2002
something like that around there 2002
and Safari browser is based on open
source I thought I knew you liked it so
it's based on KDE KDE this this this
group KDE in Linux they have called
WebKit okay that's a browser engine so
it's open source so Safari borrowed that
it made it into a safari of course over
the years lots of things changed yeah
it's at some point they they become
different you know then Dignan Apple no
longer like contribute back you know
because you know business you know
corporations they have their own cause
and movement it it takes tremendous
tremendous energy and power to to
communicate and you know the sync this
code back to the to the upstream you
know the open source code back you know
it takes tremendous energy and also in
different teams they have different
visions different cores lead by each
different selfish person for their own
purpose including Linux in fact that is
more pronounced in all the open source
project each each project has one guy
you know they cannot make
money but they can have fame that's
that's why you have all these fights
anyway he stopped he stopped getting
into a rant okay
so Apple created Safari they took the
WebKit engine you know they pero oh it's
open source they you know borrowed it in
the first few years you know they tried
you know they they sent their
improvement back to WebKit in things
like that but even after a few years
they've become totally separate you know
every time this happens you know it's on
the news hacker news you know / thought
how can use this is [ __ ] you know free
software idiot phonetics every time this
happens oh you know what the hacker
types talk about it they die sorry you
know things continue on continuing on
now and here today we have the Evoque
Google Apple you know Microsoft empires
and the open-source [ __ ] idiots are
still singing the open-source songs
so anyway Apple created Safari
originally based on WebKit then Google
started Google Chrome they paid they
borrowed from Safari the WebKit okay
have nothing to do with the KDE the
WebKit anymore actually today's geocode
actually the the KDE engine I don't
think I don't remember if why was it
called WebKit or not oh yeah if they had
the orange don't name but anyway you you
you go to Wikipedia you know go to
Wikipedia search for web web kit you'll
find all the stories and links to and
Bing engine you know the all the
different engines so anyways so Safari
then you have Chrome Google Chrome
beginning with the WebKit you know
borrowing safaris code then they become
separate okay they then Google then
about three years ago or four years ago
go rewrite you know almost rewrite like
it's no longer WebKit they became PIM
their own engine so anyway that's that's
about that and okay
yeah and edge okay so and also another
part of the story is that opera also
threw away their own engine this
that they adopted Google Chrome and they
are dead they are hara browser is known
time did you know they are like you know
app Opera browser they are head they are
leader this Swedish I think it's where
they show no you know the Scandinavia is
always confusing you know what Opera
browser what country was it Opera you
know so Opera browser has this leader
he's askin back you know he's a
Microsoft hater he's a he's the one of
the extreme Microsoft hate hater you
know he he he criticized Microsoft Bo
gate all the time
you know I have articles about that
which we you know his reason is he is
just it's wrong okay it's just wrong for
selfish reasons and then today opera is
totally dead knowing hands in smacks
package is way beyond my window know
enhance okay so no no we Jian okay yeah
Norwegian yeah that's an opera guy he's
askin this by the way he invented CSS or
he's a co-inventor or something
he he's a guy who invented CSS today you
don't hear about him anymore
you know because technology moves on you
don't hear about him much anymore but he
he was the you know he amended CSS so
Benjamin says what's a semi GUI that's
that's just my loose tongue that's my
loose term to refer to this for example
this this screen so it's kind of GUI
because you see buttons you see those
buttons you see and you have you know
but it's actually is somewhat it's you
can also say it's text-based because
everything in this buffer is text you
know AK for example let me copy hold on
a second
okay so I copied above a split new
buffer create a new buffer paste it you
see it's all text
you know so why does it show as a button
here because Emacs has properties okay
that's technical detail if we if I'm
taught you know teaching you eMac beasts
today now talk about that it's it's a
these techniques properties okay text
properties so I'm calling this you know
it's not exactly tech space because
text-based this this is what text-based
typical text-based interface is like you
know terminal but but this is say my
same that that's why I call a semi GUI
okay
so close that close that don't save okay
back to the talk show
let's I have so many I have several
topics I want to talk about but I
already digress into stuff so bother me
says wait write web app okay so who can
you trust if not Firefox you can't you
can't trust it so bad you cannot trust
much any anymore you know first of all
you cannot trust Google Chrome you don't
even know if they like right now you can
be sure it's already know or the
password on my system outside of Crump
you don't know you cannot know for sure
you could possibly they are already
doing that they know everything I
mentioned this before like two years ago
or three years ago they in fact they
have an option like more tools wait not
more tools settings okay they have an
option they ask you do you want to do
you want Google to check viruses on your
hard disk let's see where is it let's
try to find it okay Google Chrome
appearance okay
such changing default browser on start
up advanced privacy and security [ __ ]
okay you know studying you know I see
these topics I'm gonna start to rent and
then start a lock from Syene know okay
don't do that a lot no track what will
ever last site you know no track that do
not
that's another okay huh my god this is
I'm gonna start to talk about this for
one hour there's so many things last
night to check okay so let's not do that
let's not talk about I want to get back
to the other things clear browsing data
site settings manage security keys
manage certificate preload page yeah
outside to check if you have payment
method no I don't want I don't have
money okay spellcheck downloads
accessibility system reset anyway I
remember seeing that
do you guys know like I remember seeing
like there is a preference that ask
whether you want Google to check viruses
scan for viruses on your hard disk
oh yeah brave yeah
so I you know one browser you could
trade trust his brave this one okay
great browser I talked about this guy a
few times so I recommend that great
browser is new web browser secure you
how did secure it's not secure you
browser in Emacs that's a worst garbage
greetings know don't we know agent may I
request you to please not eat my dog
[Laughter]
okay so that's a very browser so
oh yeah 4chan let's talk about 4chan
full channel okay oh it's fascinating
I know some of you guys are on 4chan
green deck come on in green deck Oh
green deck you have some issues about
the arty news website yeah I'm not sure
we are talk about that because we got a
lot of things - what we got a lot of
things to cover so for channel comments
sorry Second Life hamster ball okay so
this
so people okay folks join discord what
new audio device detected clearing up
stone switch or not switch device
discord is tech detected a new audio
input device yeah okay switch device
Kinya device 3 a new audio output device
names 2 by 3 no I don't know what the
[ __ ] is device 3 audio output so you go
to San talk show and now I have this
this is a discord link ok so let me just
post it so guys join this code it's
really nice ok wow if you you don't have
to but okay so what what put is the next
thing ok so so let's see I want to let's
not let's talk about like what I'm I'm
going to what I'm talking it depends on
you guys like who is here like who wants
to listen to what okay not not much
comment let's just continue with Emacs
name let's let me show you so right now
I want a command that I can call and
we'll it will show this page in Chrome
browser
okay must be calm for example this SAR
talk show page right you see here I can
press a button let me show you okay oh
no I press a button you're showing
browser the kind of default browser okay
maybe should hold on say that might sue
me
[Music]
oh no I got my roommate
God is disrupting my professional
service where is your roommate from my
roommate they are phone right now you
know here's a way I have one two three
four four four roommates
so first me is five people they are from
China I I talked about this before they
are you know kind of illiterate okay did
you know they don't do you use computers
I mean that they don't know anything
they don't know what it's about
except you know one of the younger ones
you know they don't know what is physics
math you know programming okay but
there's also no note alternative rock
mod who is your roommate from so we're
we're from China they are from Wow
actually one of them is from Taiwan the
other the others are from China southern
China like like a burb Hong Kong like
right above Hong Kong and so what what
am I going to it's just to the Emax
think okay so so yeah back back to the
Emax okay
Emacs has a command let me show you
what's a command name okay okay actually
I'm using my home so let's look at so so
you max has a command code browse URL of
buffer okay so for example you see this
word browse URL buffer this one so this
is a Emacs command okay so it's building
browse URL buffer that means you call
that commanded score it okay so I MX
browse URL PR o w VI o WS e URL of
buffer okay so that means if we will
okay I call that enter your show the
current page
the default browser which in my case is
five bucks okay so this is speeding now
however I have I have my own versions
because sometimes I need to do some
transformation of links so anyway I have
my own version so I can go it it shows
in browser ok then I have another
version I have another version that's
it's it's called Safari okay so open in
Safari so if I press that it will open
this in Safari browser ok now I have
another version ok it's called opening
brave so if I call that we open this
page in brave browser ok so you know it
has I have different command to do that
and I have two more versions for example
now instead of opening this buffer I
want to show this link this link ok
this this link in let's say in Safari ok
so I call some open link in Safari okay
hold on a second let me show the Emacs
yeah so I call some open link in Safari
ok so you see that you see this this
page in Safari I have the same for same
command for web browser because I use
multiple browsers for reasons what I
want to do now he said I don't have one
for Chrome I do not have one for Chrome
because I don't use you know I only use
Chrome browser for Google related stuff
like YouTube I don't I don't want to you
know use Chrome but however since yes
yes yes bathroom you since since since
I've been doing YouTube
I find it sometimes I want to show this
paging on you know on Google Chrome so I
need that command so let's write it okay
so first of all what I we what we do is
we just copy
copy of the existing command you know
copy/paste it's the most powerful way
it's most to code actually let's see
Safari
open link in Safari okay so let's look
at that go there so here is the code so
open link in Safari and and here's a
code cuz I'll open linking brave now
where is the opening Safari
okay that's somewhere else open link
okay so let's just do oh okay let's copy
that create a new buffer save it and saw
eMac be smart
magnify rename it so open link in chrome
okay and copy the file name save the
file
save us that yeah okay saved now let's
just modify this so it's in chrome so
you were opening chrome let's see how we
do it okay so first of all this is too
long it's let's do that so all we have
to do actually all we have to do is
modify this line you see so how this
works is that first of all it you know
this block of code you see in the
beginning its input string so this block
of code is trying to get the URL oh you
know yeah the URL or file path it will
be ready path you know basically a path
as the input string you want to open
this in a browser this URL okay so
that's this part of code is about you
know your search for is search for space
or tab or new line or one of these
delimiters brackets you know to find out
where does the you are begin or end
then just grab it then then you know
then then you just save that as this
input string okay so that's so that's
this part of the code then once you have
the input stream you want to create a
path variable
you want to derive you know you want to
find the actual full path from an input
stream for example why for example let's
go back here okay change side map so
yeah let's go back to our talk show you
see this file that's a CSS file now I
can press ENTER to open it it's a CSS
file close it now you see what that path
is relative link so so if I'm calling
this for example I can call it open link
in Safari let's see what happens
there it is it opens this CSS file in
Safari okay now back to Emacs now but
how but you need to do pass some
processing because this relating file
this relating path you need to make it a
full path then you tell Safari to open
that so that is this part about you know
if once you have the input string you
replace you know you do some processing
and you get the path okay
so once you have the path then oh is
easy you just call a shell command then
call this command this this is a command
in Mac you know on a Mac you have this
open command you know in shell let's see
let me show you okay so this is terminal
okay so
so let's say it's typed which open okay
wait hold on a second let me magnify
okay so so there is open the open
command so now you type man open now
this is max this is max own command you
don't have these on Linux well you have
you have xpg open you have the gnome
open the [ __ ] mess [ __ ] complete
mess
some of them doesn't walk you know some
of them needs to it only works on this
distro like Ubuntu some of them only
works on other distro there over the
years they changed the names like some
other hotshot came up they [ __ ] it
then then you believe this one is no
better system they and then in some
other unix you know linux phonetic scoop
they decided oh actually we should have
one universal command that open files
just you know on the Mac you have this
open command on Windows it's called
Explorer ok we explore that similar it
does similar so on Linux you have
several like incompatible frac and
changes you know changes every three
five years over the years I have yeah I
have full detail on the and on these and
then every day you hear Linux if your
Linux is better than Windows 10 times
better you have to understand you know
like I know many many of you you know
many of my father you know many people
other people who don't you know they
think sorry is so strange weird opinions
what we are penis you are stupid okay I
mean is do you can you see that the
point I'm making like do you see our Mac
you have this open command okay for like
20 years
Mac maybe they change a little bit but
basically open command it works well
since 20 years ago since Mac OS 10 okay
2002 on Windows you have Explorer okay
not on window machine but the command
not name is Explorer basically it's just
just like open you you know a command
line to open files open stuff so on
Linux but on Linux you have let me show
you what what what what's the situation
with the Linux okay I digressed okay I
digress again but let me show you okay
let's let's go to this page okay showing
browser so this this this is a command
to open file in external app okay
actually I talked about this in my past
view videos you know sorry I did videos
in many past videos some of them are
about Emacs so you guys might check it
out you know the YouTube is such that
you only everyday you have new things
people just want to watch new things but
anyway so so this command you can see
let me show you okay
so do it if out let me magnify so if
it's some windows you call w3 - shell
execute that's a Emacs command then you
call open wait
this is Yuko okay so on windows you also
have a open wait you have an open
command on windows I guess you did you
do now I guess I forgot I forgot the
details you know I haven't been using
Linux is my main machine but dog anyway
so if it's mag you know system type
darwin is if it's a mag co co command
open you know mag and if it's on linux
you know system type gnu/linux it's
wrong to call it linux okay you have to
say new linux so if it's on linux you
have they gets complex you have to start
a process process connection type neil
they start process then then xdg open
okay you see that xdg open
now if you don't know Linux if you are
like you know okay how can we trust you
out like talking [ __ ] it's such it's xtg
open there it is lean on Linux main page
and you go Stack Overflow how does the
xtg open command know which application
to use okay that's a stupid question
xdg open command in Linux with examples
are clinics okay are our clinics wiki's
is the best Linux not documentation okay
anyway xdg open so it's a Linux command
similar to open on Mac or Windows okay
but actually that's not that's not all
because this command I've changed over
the years because xpg
over they are several like this genome
open this also several they changed over
the past 20 years changing changing
changing eventually etc I you know this
you know I saw I read time you know I
spent days like they taste a month you
know over the years month study you know
and they eventually xtg open supposed to
be the the best all kind of the latest
agreed-upon
you should call this but you know that's
okay there it is okay look at this one
showing desktop so if it's if it's on a
Linux system and okay look look at this
code over here okay let me magnify so so
if it's on Linux system okay good new
Linux okay system type can or Linux then
you start the process okay then you call
okay then
you know if G gvfs - open if that exists
you call that okay if that doesn't exist
then you could xdg open okay it's [ __ ]
Linux where did this happen because
ideally you open-source fans ideally you
know everyone we cooperate you know like
the way Richard Stallman like to say we
could cooperate you know he's got
eastern US accent cooperate so you you
know we ideally we can create you know
one system it works so well you know one
command but that's not okay that's not
case because once you go communism once
you remove the money the benefits you
know to each person each one is you
still want each one person is still
greedy you know he's so greedy just the
exactly the same that doesn't change the
person but but you how you are so greedy
you want to do things for yourself but
you cannot say it so you so you you
becomes it becomes a power struggle you
create you know each one of this person
they think they are better and you know
you fight you know so many Linux distros
and so on so let's get back to not
everyone is greedy that's true you can
alias open part of me says you can alias
open xdg not really you know I mean have
you actually worked on this you haven't
right yeah because you haven't then you
say oh yeah you can just alias you know
patches you know UNIX is so powerful
because you have idea so you have it
soft mink or you have howling oh you oh
oh you oh you are [ __ ] all you have
to do is howling you don't even
understand you next I know where that is
going
that's incorrect because if you actually
do this you do that you run into other
problems you know because otherwise they
owe these people you don't want you you
won't you won't have all these so many
confusions and questions you know what
X's yeah okay so open file in X you know
AB let's close that let's let's close
that closer we we talked about that so
let's go back
[Music]
let's go back and talk show index page
what is this okay curse that and I want
to go back to saw talk show right so let
me just write down what we are doing so
copy that
okay and let's get back to the program
the code here let's get this to work so
right now I'll tell our job is to find
out what is the name for Google Chrome
application code in command line okay so
let's go to shell Q to quit so I need to
CD to add okay applications there is
list okay so one of them is Chrome
Google Chrome we need to find out the
exact name google chrome app okay there
it is
copy it so paste it here god
it's going on does copy walk okay it
does okay so there it is google chrome
app now now another shell problem you
need to deal with these I guess
backslash should work you know it's very
complicated problem when you have a
space okay I think that's it though
let's let's try to see if it works okay
eval buffer split the pain go back to my
HTML okay then then let's put the cursor
on this link okay
this link okay I just put somewhere in
the link now let's call the command we
want to Co is so open linking chrome
okay
meta X sound open linking home enter it
says unable to find application name the
google chrome okay it's there it is this
is incorrect
you see they they are not showing the
space you see the space disappeared
so that's why I say it's a pain so you
need to double backslash I guess let's
try it
wait thank you yeah and it's trying okay
you're our buffer back to this buffer
Kodaka man again Cohen there it is
fantastic we have successfully completed
this task now I have a command okay I
think that that that finishes one
subject you know one of the thing we
want to talk about so this command is
great now I now I copy now I cut the
entire thing delete the file curse that
go back to the fire we're go back to the
source code where the Safari file is
that there now I pasted it
oh I pasted it okay so it's still there
okay so so now I know now this file this
file is in saw Emacs miscellaneous this
is Padma in it so now if I start Emacs
this will be part you know I will have
this command so modify the modified
Google Chrome modified the documentation
so it says open UI are under kusa in
google chrome works on Mac only okay
maxime economy and put today state
because you know then you have to do a
version for Linux then you have to add a
version for Windows you know it's
painful it's like like right now you
know I have to add a version for for you
know if it's on Linux what you call you
know Windows but right now I'm not on
Windows this this is just works for me
but once you put it out you know then
other people will ask you oh you know
you need to fix it and you know and and
you get no money
I've been doing that for you know for
the past 20 years say these 10 years you
know every day you know open source so
green deck says I found out I found out
about xdg when I was reading sauce-ii
max command yeah I found out that myself
is it because you know for example you
know
hi I'm writing a command to show a file
in the desktop you know for example let
me let me show you okay so I want to
show this file in desktop you know red
arm on a Mac so desktop it looks like
that okay oh no no no second you know it
shows you know the Mac you know it you
know the you know the in Linux you call
these file managers you go it file
managers Oh Mac this this is called
finder you know because it's called find
out since since 1990 okay it's called
finder on Windows is called its code I
think it's called how do they have the
code on Windows Explorer something
Explorer oh yeah I guess yeah technique
you say it's you know show it in Windows
Explorer so anyway they have different
names you know so what what was I going
to say yeah so I want to write a command
like this right I want to do it and I
was sound in EXO windows so so I'm when
I'm on Linux you know I was on Linux for
four years as my desktop you know I want
to do it so you you know you you go to
stack overflow you search the web then
you find one command then oh it doesn't
work because you know then some people
says oh you come and you know they tell
me you it doesn't work because oh oh
that's because they are on you know I'm
open to Linux I'm using you know XFC you
know the window manager it's gets very
complex but they are using the same note
Alice unknown then you know then you
learned Oh unknown then it's another
command then then you you know then I
dig into Wikipedia then you know usually
there's a lot info Wikipedia are clinics
you know you
spent hours [ __ ] days to read you
know read all you want to do is just
show it you know then you learned about
history oh because this year for some
reason they change or because of some
mime folk you know the sort of [ __ ]
Linux [ __ ] Linux Windows Explorer so
what do I need open for you need open
for you for example you need to open for
for lots of things anyway so so what's
next
today are we done know what's are the
topics so bathroom you and okay new book
new bosses you have made me try out
Emacs but it is very painful at the
moment yes it is by the way do you use
the or text package if so can you tell
us something about it I don't use Oh Tex
package I don't use lot tech I don't use
tech I hate it I hate it I despise it ok
actually I have a video talking about a
lot Tech and take you know you talk
about that I've used to take or not
detect like 10 years ago no you know and
now and then because because when you do
math you have to use that oh it's almost
like you know you just have to so I
don't use I haven't you know I don't
have haven't used it but I know they
didn't try to be positive okay and you
know some people like I know this this
guy Emacs Sai John kitchen okay John
kitchen John kitchen is a professor at
carnage Carnegie Mellon University which
is one of the top university in USA this
guy John kitchen I met him
in my house you came over so he so he
wrote this sigh max package this is a
big project okay tens of thousands or
hundred or even hundred thousand lines
it's a big project
it's oak mod based thing you know okay
you know that like they say you know the
reproducible reproducible publishing
okay I don't like the yeah I had in my
opinion that is kind of silly jargon
it's kind of silly marketing thing okay
he has no actual solid meaning anyway so
he wrote this sigh max package which is
very good especially if you work in
academia or you do publishing or you do
research or math you know he's a
chemistry professor okay so if you do
lots of math you know the research
science stuff this is very good and I
know because he he he did the demo one
time for me also he has YouTube videos
you can watch he do demo of the he's oh
my god there's so many files so it's
okay Matt based so you just like you
just you know a lot of a lot of you like
Oakmont
you know you just working Okla Oakmont
and you can have equations latech or
take you know la tech I think without
needing to you know use that old text
thing you know like you show you
actually you can set it up so that they
actually show images plants to date does
he have some screenshots anyway he's got
YouTube channels I mean what now you
know the name you search for it you'll
find you know demo and stuff so maybe
that's something you you you might like
okay so no comments no comments and how
long I have been talking leave live -
for 12 people watching okay so we are I
think we are about done so what's what's
what's next
so yeah look okay so let me try to maybe
see so summarize so what we did talk
today we did talk about eMac please
write a new Google Chrome yes we did
that and the command name we called is
this one so open linking Chrome okay so
paste it and okay that's actually we
actually there's another command I want
to write because this command is for
opening a link like you know if your
cursor is on a link then you can call it
you know let's let's let's switch let's
switch to something this one one
wandering stars okay let's call the
command so often linking from do it oh
it opened the new tab Jesus now I need
to spend time to modify it so that it
doesn't open a new tab I mean it opened
a new window I wanted to be tab so
anyway so that's one command but I want
another command that opened the current
buffer not not a linking above you know
that's also trivial that's also you know
let's not do that because you already
know how it's done so you just you know
you just follow you know with what we
talked about then you know how it is
done okay great
how can you chat with me well I'm on
Twitter but you are not on Twitter and
my master Dan oh yeah
Master Dan he mastered a nice open
source man I'm a master Dan bathroom you
faster than sex
hey greetings from Europe Ivan Hovind
greetings okay so let's see what we
gonna MX customized tutorial we talked
about that open fire in external app yes
common on Bible okay so George George is
not here today George made a comment on
my youtube about one of my article on
Bible like wonder of the I tried to find
out
now let me stop that okay so that this
is yesterday's video there's something
like that
October yeah that's yesterday so George
made a comment about Bible so apparently
George is have you know X is a expert or
have some expertise on Bible so I have
an article that let me show you okay
Bible
so back in 2006 I was looking into Bible
because you know I came from I was from
Asia I don't know nothing about by go so
in 2006 I wanted to know so what what
are the different versions of Bible you
know what are they like what how are
they different you know things like that
so I looked a little bit you know so I
wrote this article a simple intro to
Bible and it's versions for
non-believers okay now you shouldn't
take my words for granted because I
don't know actually I don't know the
subject and also I'm not you know I have
not Christians so you know but you know
but nevertheless that you know for me
you know I tried to write an article
about you know Oh what are the main sure
you know just the most basic
introduction what what what what are the
major versions of Bible things like that
her brew Bible you know like usually you
hear about James Kings and Old Testament
yeah New Testament okay I don't know I
was curious you know in actually you
know one thing interesting is that there
are many so there are so many inversions
you know American authorized King James
Version revised version American
Standard Version word English Bible
Young's literal translation modern
English Bible translations Jewish
English Bible translations end and in
brick Testament you know this guy lego
guy I hate Lego Lego the most idiotic
thing but anyway this guy he created a
Lego you know he created a website you
know called the brick testament
basically is using Lego to illustrate
the stories from Bible you know for
example you have this thing you know
they became hugely popular you know this
is the early days this is
in 2001 ok 2001 2002 the beginning of
the Internet boom ok and also the it's a
beginning and you know it you know if
you look back at history like today you
know today in the past few years we have
the social justice right I can you know
so I look back if I do you know I can
see there is the seed of these social
justice kind people for me ok anyway so
the you know he used Lego to tell Bible
stories and when I was doing this and I
was writing this in 2006
I also learned for example I think I am
a song there is a rap version of Bible
like you know trap you know the black
people the back little you know that
yeah I cannot do it but rap so there's
all Oprah the talk you know basically
they they write the Bible I don't know
it's a fool thing or not but you know in
the style of the rappers so there's a
lot you know a lot of it of course some
of these will be controversial like some
people will say oh you know this is
sacrilegious you cannot use Lego for
this but meanwhile I mean I'm talking
about among the Christians you know then
I'm guessing I don't know I am guessing
some people will say ok this is not bad
okay this introduces the idea Bible to
the equator population you know to
children for example so anyway so but I
don't really know what I'm talking about
because I just spent a few days you know
but but apparently George gave me some
information and this is 2006 I don't
remember I don't remember what I wrote
2006 so George gave me some introduction
about different versions of Bible ok
that's that's about his comment here but
also a more interesting thing is this ok
let me show you there is this song TP TP
says recommend skip skeptic and notated
Bible calm you know Google sensor that
[ __ ] you go okay
bothering me says the black Bible the
rap you know this is the best
description of music genre I've never
heard the black people of the read how
is that the way I phrase it so ok so
there is this song by this group I was a
big fan
I still like their songs yeah I love
this song
by Portishead no I think she's a UK
English singers her name is her name is
Beth Gibbons she is of the group called
POTUS head and her song her style she
has a kind of a subculture following
because her soul her style is very kind
of this feminine whale yeah I can play
the song but then Google is gonna say
copyright violation yeah just just go to
my website okay such folks oddly
wandering stars Saudi music wandering
stars you see it it's everywhere you
know he's on YouTube and stuff so so she
so she is known for that portishead the
this group they they they so she's a
singer she's the main singer and her
Styles the things she sings is that kind
of this very feminine okay extremely
feminine and also in this masochist
masochist style you know like women she
is like feeling sad you know she's and
and enjoy it you know that's what has
masochism is about you know you know so
anyway so she she know her song says
like that and I was a fan and but one of
her song is called wandering stars this
is hugely popular around around years
with in 1998 something like that
wandering stars okay actually you can
such you'll find out Wikipedia page
about that
due to real-time and Deuteronomy what
does that in a Bible quite grim stuff I
don't know what is that okay Portishead
wandering stars now there must be a me a
Wikipedia entry
okay so wandering stars means quite a
few things but apparently there's a
strong Bible connotation I mean there's
a story connected to Bible so let's see
what we see is a small is us an archaic
or poetic term for a classical planet
okay oh okay
so one in Star so so Pluto would be a
wandering star earth would be a
wandering star okay or is the one in
size assumed by put his head from 1994
okay yeah we're in star so UK song song
song song so one instance a reference to
Christians in Jude 1:13 of most modern
English translations of the Bible okay
so yeah anyway so George he gave me some
information about that so I was you know
I wrote this article about this song I
tried to analyze the you know watch what
is she singing you know so I looked up I
kind of you could research you know I
took up all the words
and you know it's it's actually
fascinating because when you do this
when you do this the the Bible is
several subject matter involved you know
it's linguistics history culture you
know depending on how it has how much
time you have how deep you want to look
into
you can spend few years just by reading
these lyrics you see because first of
you know because so why does a hymn
involves history culture linguistics
easy history because many of these
refers to passages in Bible these lyrics
of lies the needles I fascinating the
needles I husk wandering stars you know
you so so depending on what's your
interest you then you know you can start
to read you know then it invokes you to
read the entirety of Bible you know that
that's the spirit that's of the spirit
of learned men because you are trying to
read this you are trying to listen enjoy
this this this song but she is singing
something you cannot read the lyrics
right so you are you know you read the
lyrics but what the [ __ ] is morning
stars what the [ __ ] is needles i needles
i so you want to understand so oh then
it you you start to learn oh it's from
bible then what is you know bible why
does it you know how it connect so if
you you know then you have to read the
entirety of bible then also jesus they
also linguistics
well okay before we go that you know
bible but once you read bible that's has
to do with culture you know the western
culture you know this heart of it it's a
big part of western culture you know
this is then culture is like you you can
spend your whole life studying culture
but then there's also linguistics you
know
Magneto science stuff and culture when
it comes to culture you have hunting it
involves architecture you know what is
what is this this camel you know this
commode is this unit in this stone Park
that is Meadows I okay that's needles I
then you start to research into the
interpretations of Bible because because
apparently no one is sure exactly what
needles is me for example let's look at
Wikipedia I mean there are different you
know different explanations what does I
have a need of me you know different
explanations well first of all it's just
ice ice of a needle like no doesn't mean
much but it's more than that it's much
more you know so half a reasons you have
Judaism you have Christianity okay then
you have Islam you have you know gate
and you know it's a whole you know you
can spend your life study these needles
I what a fascinating thing the needles I
and I I respect this kind of things you
know I imagined for example sorry lambda
logo to today's juice is ample grapes
okay
today's juices apple grapes and we are
about to end now people say the world is
about to end but not yet this video is
about to end first okay in a few minutes
so if you have last words put it out
and Rockstar Energy Drink
sugar-free as usual - of energy drink so
I've been talking for one hour and 21
minutes 22 minutes
right on time you know about 90 minutes
you know guys don't say come to
controversial stuff okay don't don't
don't go crazy about religion stuff okay
you know because it's controversial
okay back to wandering stars but anyway
mmm
so I find this fascinating okay but
apparently I've been wrong all these
years this article has you know I wrote
this in 2005 over the years I updated
you know but apparently I got I got the
whole thing wrong George tells me so I
tried I tried my own way to write
commentaries and notations about the
whole thing
then comes you know actually there's a
passage of Bible passage of okay of
Bible here and but George tells me okay
let me read George what George said
George is not here [ __ ] George George
says modern stars is a reference to the
sons of God
also known as Watchers who left heaven
to sleep with human women in Genesis 6
this event is alluded to throughout the
New Testament okay I don't know I didn't
know I've been ignorant so he quotes so
he calls Genesis 6:1
for NRSV so a RSV is a new New Revised
something version of Bible something
okay so there is this passage let's read
it when people began to multiply on the
face of the ground and daughters were
born to them the sons of God so that
they will fail
and they took wives for themselves of
all that they can choose of all that
they choose then the Lord said my spirit
my spirit shall not abide in Moto's
forever
for they are flesh their days shall be
120 years okay
the Neff is Nephilim were on the earth
in those days and also after words when
the sons of God went into the daughters
of humans who bore them children to them
these were the heroes that were of old
warriors of renown oh yeah I don't well
I don't completely understand it but you
know you get kind of some sense of
what's you know the story okay that's it
for today
so maokai says so in in this talk show
talk show not the me versus you arguing
in chat box what
buzzer buzzer me says we are the code we
have to be crazy to join a code universe
face you favorite - you're insane reply
you prove it by you insane reply it is
choice you know if you want to argue
meow cat is the best you can argue
endlessly ok that's it for today ok
I think yes I think so that's one more
minute one more minute
yeah thank thank you guys for coming
so tomorrow 10 o clock as a JavaScript
question or whatever Bianca I used your
weeping Linux and loves Linux loves
Linux and free software too much to be
in a coat ok them a trigger you so hot
ok so that's it for today and thank you
guys for coming and bye