Good morning, good evening. Welcome to
another episode of Exar Talk Show. We
are coding Emac list. Today we are doing
uh writing a command to move a directory
up to the parent directory.
So play at 1.5 speed. If you are here,
say hi. Okay, so we're going to begin.
So you know if so in Emacs the most
powerful editor
uh you are looking at and here is my
current directory. So you can see uh let
me increase the window width. Okay so
for example here is a um YouTube
thumbnail. Open it. Okay, that's Emacs
track ball customized track ball with
Emacs logo on it and happy hacking
keyboard. Okay, so this is a file I want
to move it up one directory. So normally
manually what I do is split the window.
Uh wait, so this key split the window
then you go up a directory that's the
correct. So you can see right now we are
in si info and and here is talkshaw
directory. So you move the cruiser to
the files you want and you can select
more than one. Okay then you press
capital R and you'll say where do you
want to move it to? Okay there. Yes.
Okay. So you can see the two files has
been moved here. Now refresh they'll be
they will be sorted you know. So, so now
they are here
and uh now let's split again split the
window and move it back. So, go to
talksh show directory open it now go
down. Now select these two capital R
then do it. So you see you move them
back. So this is a manual process
manual. I want to write a command that
just do it you know I just call move
move move move move move move move move
move move move move up one one d d d d d
d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d do it. So
that's what we're going to do today.
Okay, today's talk show. And there is
another command HTML icon linkify. Uh if
we have time, we're going to do that. Uh
otherwise not. Okay, so we'll see how it
feels the mood. Nobody is here. So
so uh let's begin. Okay. So, uh write a
so write the uh command start emac visp.
Okay. Start it default define a function
and the function name is what the
function name I already have it here
there. So copy that
switch back paste it. Okay. So that is
the command. So move move current file
or marked file up one. Okay that's the
documentation and version date create
created date. Okay then here we're going
to start to code. So the first thing you
want to do so uh this is uh this is the
add. Okay. This is like you you call the
command D I R E
D. I call it I pronounce it diode but
some people pronounce it the ED because
that's what it standard stand for
directory editor.
Uh that's the old old name for file
manager. So close that. So for example,
if you don't know, let's go to the
talksh show talksh show directory and uh
open in uh Windows file manager. So the
model name for this is file manager. In
the case of Windows, it's called um
Windows file explorer. On the Mac it's
called finder. On Linux depending on
what droid you are using but in general
the name is file manager. Okay. There
are quite a few on Linux. So, but in
EMAC it's called the ED or diode. That's
that's how I like to call it diode. So,
you are looking at diode right now. You
can view uh you can view images or uh
other files. So, these are uh my YouTube
thumbnails.
This one is long ago, six years ago. So,
anyway, so we're going to start to write
a command. Okay, so let's go back to the
code. So the first thing you want to do
in a directory if uh is that you want to
get a list of marked files like you can
mark them.
Uh so actually all this so uh wait
a mark all mark all then mark all the
backup files. Press this key. You can
see the ping window shows all my command
calls. Uh wait
cancel the pink window on the left you
can see that's all my command calls and
uh and keystrokes on the left okay so
for example black backup files that's
what I just did so this become red then
I press the key x
that will delete them do you want to
delete them 69 files yes you see all
these backup files are deleted it now to
so the first thing you want to do is to
know the list of marked files. If
there's none basically that's then it's
you know the file your cursor is under
is considered the current file. So in
either case you want to get the list of
them. So what you can do is diode
uh wait. So describe function
uh what describe function.
Okay. Uh mark files uh mark file
subdirectory mark file. So hold on a
second.
My alarm clock is beeping. Let me turn
it off.
Okay. Hello aspiring Windows compositor.
Hi. I hope every day we are coding. Good
to know. Good good uh good hope. So
yeah, me too.
have some red wine uh with some juice.
So the first job is to get marked files
and that's that's the command name for
that is
diet get marked files that one. Okay. So
uh so completion
there that is the command. Okay. Now
look up the documentation. So you say
say option or local builder
you don't care about any op options.
Okay. So create a local variable X
files.
Um yeah. So then you just set the value
of that to this the output of this
command. So you'll get it. Then you can
say
uh you can just say messages. Okay.
Let's just print them. Okay.
So evaluate the buffer
now. Now go to the uh now put it back.
Go to the directory and hold on. Uh,
copy the command name. Go to the diet
meta x call the command because I move
to parent. Do it. Then go to the
messages buffer. You can see the output.
So it only list one file. Can you see
which is that file episode 712
correct? Okay. Now let's try again. This
time let's let's mark several files.
Okay.
metax call the command and you can see
now it
you know the least it list three files.
So open a new buffer paste it make it
one line per file so we can see three
files. So that's what we want. Okay. Now
close that. Now pop this out. So this is
doing things correctly. Okay. So we got
a list of files. Now we just uh
you want to find the parent directory.
So
the so parent directory. Okay. So what's
the command for parent directory? I
forgot. You go to kasali.info
http no s. Okay. So or search for kxali
emac lisp tutorial. Then you go to emac
lisp. Then you go to um so that's all
the tutorials you can read the most
comprehensive online
uh and better than any EMAC books
printed books or uh yeah better than any
printed books you can find because
there's actually none. There's one one
or two but mine is like the most
comprehensive.
Okay. So, so you want to go to uh in in
our case eac lisp
the eis the lisp basics covers
um emac lisp of all the things that's
available in other languages such as
what's a you know what's a string how do
you do string string and how do you do a
list sequence data structure how do you
do uh numbers input numbers or binary
numbers or how do you what is a true and
false in EMAC listp what's a how do you
create a variable and how do you define
a function things like that conditional
if then else equality test and how do
you do loop okay and data structure so
that is the uh lisp basics that that are
things that's available in every
programming language okay then you go to
eac lisp this section is emac specific
things that doesn't exist in other
programming languages such as deleting
you know creating a buffer deleting text
insert text uh things like that. So
anyway in our case we want to go to
given a file path we want to find the
parent path. So that is in the path
section writing a command text
processing co shell command get user
input file and buffer there. So uh read
file read read file buffer functions
uh write file file path functions there.
Okay. So you want to uh file name
directory. That's how you get the parent
directory. Yeah,
I forgot. Okay, so file name directory
and uh
car car gets the first element of a
list. Okay. So that
so this will be so let's create a um
let's say parent the okay let's just say
that okay now set parent directory to be
that
okay
and now let's just delete that.
So you set the parent directory and you
just move uh file rename. Okay. So to
move a file the command name is file
rename
uh rename file actually.
Okay. So rename file. So it
this command can rename a file or move a
file uh following the Unix convention.
So what you guys are saying?
Cheers. Any questions ask me. Okay.
So let's see. Hi. As always, I
appreciate your videos. Thank you. Truly
godson. Thank you.
Uh
I like this time for stream. Okay. So
yeah, usually for the past two or three
years I've been doing in the morning USA
time, usually noon. So that means people
in China, Japan, Taiwan, Hong Kong or
India or
um or much of Europe, you know, and and
uh Middle East,
uh Iran, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, they have
a hard time to watch my video.
So
you know but three years ago I was doing
you know some sometimes I was doing at
this time. So let's look at the clock.
So this I love the sun clock. So you are
seeing the sun clock so that that you
it's a easy way to to have a glance of
the daytime and nighttime of all over
the place. So you see China, Japan,
Australia. Oh, I forgot Australia. I got
a few audience in Australia. So, Africa,
Middle East. So, you see they are now uh
daytime
while United Kingdom right now it's like
um 3:00 a.m. or something. London 500
a.m.
So anyway,
so I I'll I'll maybe uh yeah do more,
you know, uh at night.
Actually have a question. This related.
Fantastic. I can't seem to understand
about dealing with car and cad. When I'm
looking at the nested cells, I seem to
get it wrong every single time I'm
trying to select.
Uh, okay, I'll answer that. Let's see.
I too like this time. Okay.
Are you so uh you are in India, right?
Aspiring window compositor. Okay. Let's
see. India is there.
Uh
no but the name is a pretty common
Bengali name. Okay.
So, let's So, yeah. So, the question
about Kai and Carter um you know did did
you read my tutorial because
I covered it uh you go to lisp basics
and uh you go to you know string
working with eac lisp string then number
boolean variable conditional loop and
data structure. So there's a list. Now
when you are when you go to the list
data structure
uh it will explain car and cer here for
example you go all the way down you will
see a section that's all about the list
data structure. How to create a list?
You know, first first of all, intro, you
know, intro section about what is a list
and uh and length and new.
Then you have a section how to create a
list. You know, you can create them
literally or you can create them
programmatically using make list or you
can create one, two, three, four, five
by calling this number sequence. In
Python, it's called range. Okay. So,
so then you got you know uh you got a
bunch of functions that gets the
element.
So about car and cur that's one of the
ancient um kind of issue in in list.
Okay. So let me explain it. So all you
have to do is you you need to go to the
console.
So let me go to it. Okay. So basically
list in the list data structure in lisp
is not a
uh is not like the atomic data
structure. It's actually made up of con
cell cones. So you can see here list
structure. So when you have a list of
like let's say you have a list of one
two three. Let me write it actually it's
easier.
So you have a list uh and okay so what
uh list one uh wait one two three so
that's a list okay when you have and and
also it's complicated by because this
can also be written like that so that
creates a complication uh that's called
quote okay you can also read about it
here okay so anyway
these two uh
not exactly the same but they are
effectively the same. That's a little
bit more detail. Okay. So, but anyway,
so let's just assume you have a list
like that. Okay. Then what actually it
create you know what what it actually is
is this. Okay. um cons
cause cons.
So it's a nested thing. So So let me
show you. Okay. So this is one,
this is two
and here it's three and this part is
new. Okay. So So let me let me uh format
it. Okay. So when you have a list it
actually is equivalent to that. So list
data structure is actually a composite
data structure. So what you actually
have is this thing. Okay.
Then the car.
So, so basically the what what you have
you have a core data structure called
cons which is just uh a pair okay just
two things okay that's a fundamental
that's a core data structure when you
create a list is actually expressed in
terms of cons in this way [snorts] the
so when you have a cons you got a pair
of things a and b the first part is
called car c a r the second part is
called ka okay so for example you can
you can car is a function you do that
you get a okay so actually you need to
let's not use a let's use one two
because when you use a those are symbols
then you need to quote them then it gets
more the idea gets more complex
complicated okay so anyway conell is a
pair okay Then you call the first part
is called car.
The second part is called ker. Okay,
you'll see it. Uh let me show you. Okay,
cdr. Okay, you pronounce it,
you know, different people pronounce it
differently. I just call it car and cur.
Okay, so car is also a function that
returns the first part of con cell. So
for example, if I evaluate this, okay,
you get one. Now kad refers to the
second part of the con cell. So if I
evaluate that
uh you get two okay so that's so
remember cons is a fundamental data
structure in lisp
not in closure though but in eac lisp
common lisp skin this scheme racket lisp
and in general the traditional lisp
cons is a pair okay that's a fundamental
data structure. Okay. Then list is
actually just nested cons. You know you
nest cons in the in in this particular
way. And with the last
cad the last cons of the kadur part
should be neo. So that tells that tells
emacisp that this lists terminates at
this value. Okay. So these two are
identical. I mean they they are you know
they are basically identical. Okay.
So your question you know when you get
it wrong well you just have to practice.
Okay. That that's that's all that's all
because this this is kind of confusing.
This is kind of idiotic. It's that way
because back then 40 years ago by now
yeah some 40 years ago the list machine
um
uh let me show you guys uh I showed this
many times before list machine
keyboards. Okay. So you can see all the
list machine keyboards. So the first one
the cell keyboard cell s a i l keyboard
that stand for Stanford artificial
intelligence lab
this sale
artificial you know Stanford that's
that's a Stanford University right here
uh 30 minutes drive from my home in in
mountain in Palo Alto
basically around San Francisco okay San
Francisco. That's Stanford AI lab.
Stanford is a university and that was
created in 1963 by John McCarthy. John
McCarthy is the inventor of Lisp
programming language. Okay. So,
so back then you know beginning 1970s
1980s you know the hardware is not like
today like if you have one
one kilobyte of memory that's like huge
that's cost you $10,000 you know so it's
not like today. So back then the
hardware happens to be happens to have
like
it happens to have like some kind of
cell like consisting of two things. So
that's why you got these cons.
So if you want more than two things you
nest them. That's that's how you get
this nested cons to represent a list.
Okay, that's a history. Once you know
the history you it helps you understand.
Okay. So
car
refers to the f the first part of the
con is called car. The second part is
called ker.
Sometimes people call it first and last.
Okay. You can also call it first and
last. Okay. So car is also a function.
So you can extract
the first part of a console. Okay. Now
what if you do
what if you do car and the list?
Same thing because the list is actually
remember the list is actually just
nested car sales. So when you call car
on a list you just get you know the
argument to car is a conell true you
know it's a con cell. So car means the
first element. So when you call that you
just get this one. So we can try it.
You see
so that's how you how it works. What
what if you call kad on on this list?
Okay, let's try
cut.
So again think think of it
you know refer it to the to the
fundamental structure. So so what is the
second part of a con cell? So the first
part of the conell is one the second
part of the con cell is this thing.
So when you call cader list one two
three you will get
you will get um that okay which is which
is just list one two okay so let's try
it
uh two three right so again there's a
complication because it doesn't print
the the least head it just print that so
anyway you you you kind of you know get
get used to it. Okay. So, let's um
Does that make sense?
Okay. Yes, I do understand the list.
It's more so about using the referencing
of the alternative names.
for instance
um cut or even cut
I can't seem to understand when we are
nesting and ignoring Neo okay [laughter]
that's
well the short answer is don't use those
okay nobody use those okay let me
explain
okay now okay so so so what do you so
you know given these So now so far so
good. You understand this part, right?
So far so good. Uh let me remove the
quote because that's another
complication you know.
So now let's say we want to get the
second part. Okay, we just want to get
the two. Okay, so what how do you to you
know I don't want the two and three. I
just want I want exactly just two. How
do you do that? Easy. Okay. So,
do you know how to do that?
Yeah. Don't don't use them. Yeah.
Basically, don't use those. Okay. But
let me let me try let me explain it.
Okay. What are those cutter cutter?
That's that's Basically, like 20
years ago, I complained to the this
communist news group, you know, like
what the is that? Those kind of
idiotic. Okay, that's just history.
So, and people and today basically you
don't use those. Okay, you just use nth
or you use the rest, you know that like
higher level commands. Um,
so back to list keyboards, you know,
there's a lot history. Very interesting.
So, let's copy that and uh let's um hold
on a second. Let me I I'll get to the
explanation. Okay, let's paste the link
here. And we talked a little bit about
the cell keyboard. Stanford University,
Stanford artificial intelligence lab.
You know, this is the father of
artificial intelligence. Okay. Now, uh
this is my todo stuff. Okay. So, now
yeah. Now let's let's um by the way
we'll get back to the move to parent
directory. It's almost done.
Uh but let me explain this thing because
it is you know pertinent to what we are
doing today. Okay. So so far so good
about the sales. Okay. Now so you want
to get just the two. How do you do that?
Let me show you. Okay.
So first of all you want to get uh kad
because two you know kad returns two and
three so you know that's there so you
want to get ka because you don't want
the first one right uh actually so let's
put that there so we can easily see them
both okay so you want to do kad
that will get you two three okay So that
will get you this. So once you have
that, what you want to do to get what do
you have to do to get the two car. Okay.
So you just want to have a car in front.
Okay. That will get you two. Exactly.
Okay. Let's try it.
Exactly.
Perfect. Okay. So, so every time so you
if you have a long list you know every
time you want to get a particular
element basically what you end up with a
bunch of car
car things like that. Okay.
So that's why the lispers they created
shortcut.
So this car and kad
like this way can be written in short
like um
like uh
okay so like I don't yeah you know I
don't even have a abbreviation for that
okay so this you know this is you know
kad
c a d is shortcut for that. So when you
co so when you run this uh run this you
get two you see because they are exactly
the same. In fact we can look at the
source code. Let's see let's see if it's
written in C. No. Okay. So you can see
let's look at the source code. It
basically
it will call car and cut it. It's
defined that way. Okay. So wait,
C A D R lookup.
Go to the source code.
There it is. So you see exactly.
So So then they, you know, they just got
a bunch of shortcuts, you know, uh
cutter, uh wait, uh
c a d, you know, like d cut,
you know, this bunch of That's idiotic
silly That's that's why I despise
common dispers
they fanatics they don't know they
that's their tradition you know. So
let's look at the source code. So you
can see
you know this just the nesting of this
kadaka.
You see that's the CD.
Okay. So
basically you don't don't don't use
those. Okay. So you go back to this. So
here you know this page I explain the
con sales.
You guys should read it. So let me post
it.
Uh so put it back and paste the link
here.
Okay. Then you go to uh get elements. So
use this function nth that will directly
get you nth. Uh does it include the
rest?
No. Okay. So for example
uh so for example let's do this again.
So if you want that element too, you can
just say nth.
Okay. So nth. So because eac list is
zero based indexing. So you want the
second that would be one index one that
will get you two.
Okay.
Okay. Put it back. So you know use these
higher functions. Uh
the only time you want to use car and
cader is is if your um if your list is
you know if you are using your list as a
stack like you always just push an item
to the front or push another item push
one item you know or remove one one item
from the front. So when you are using
list and you should use list like that
okay that's the purpose of list okay
it's a s stack basically all you can do
is just add one item in the front or
remove one item in the front you should
never
insert an item somewhere in the middle
okay or to the to the end never okay if
you want to do that use vector okay so
go to the list
uh and uh then go to vector. Okay,
vector is just like C's array or
Python's uh list. Okay, so you can you
can uh wait vector does not allow to you
to add items. Okay, anyway that's a
limitation.
So I would say this is a limitation of
list because in Python you know there
list is actually array dynamic array you
can add elements to the front to the end
or anywhere in the middle or you know
you can you can it can grow it can
shrink you know uh but in eag you have
vector which is like python's tuple you
cannot once once created you cannot add
more item to it you cannot remove item
from
Okay, that's vector. Meanwhile, the list
data structure
you can you you are supposed to just add
or remove one item from the front.
That's
that's what you are supposed to do. You
could, it's possible to add in the
middle by just you know removing a bunch
then add then add your new item then add
the whatever you removed you know
basically the result is inefficient.
Okay.
So anyway,
so you should use you know the higher
level functions like uh you know get
elements or
uh you can modify elements push and pop.
Yeah, push you know and you know and
don't use car and cu just use push and
pop. Okay, push and pop.
Uh
yeah, so basically the issue is you just
get used to it. Okay. When you code a
lot, you just get used to it.
When when you are tra you know uh the
direction is the other way. Okay. So
when you are traversing the list they
always go from left to right. So when
you are tra traversing the list they go
from left to right. Okay. So even if you
get the length and let's say let's say
you have a list of um
uh
okay
let's say uh
number
uh se sequence okay let's create 100
okay so actually
from zero to 100 increment one. So if we
do that you got two you got a list of
200 items. Okay. So actually it
truncated uh
you know it truncated the uh print
output but you can uh
for example you can do length
uh what
201 because you got a zero in front.
Okay. So when you have a long list, when
you have a long list, even when you get
the length, it has to traverse each
element. So remember that's the thing
about list. You see? So if this is if
this is 2,000, it's slow, you know. If
if it's 20 200,000, it's very slow
because it has to it has to go through
the cons, you know, go through the cons.
Did it end yet? No. Go to the next one.
Is it a neo? Is a cer part neo? No. Go
to the next one. Is a cer part neo yet?
No. So it just repeat until it reach
neo. Then it tells you how many. That's
the length function. Okay.
Slow.
But that's the nature that's just
remember this. That's the nature that's
the nature of the list. Okay. In this is
the case in eagisp and in commonisp.
So
you are not supposed to actually
um you know use it like a array. Okay.
So for example to validate what I'm just
said about the length
today you have a new function. Okay. So
if you want to say if you want to check
if the length is greater than 200 you
usually what you do is um
um
greater than let's say 200
uh you see that's what you usually do.
So let's say uh my list okay length my
list you see you can do that but if your
list is long long that's very slow okay
so now they have a new function
um
okay so you do it this way instead it.
Uh, wait. So, the actually the logic
here doesn't work. Should you use um
Yeah. Uh, it makes sense if you use less
than.
Okay. So, this would be length
less than. Yeah.
Okay. So if you want to know if a list
is less than 200 items, you can normal
normally this is what you do. But this
is inefficient because it has to find
the length of the list first. So it has
to you know go through traverse it. On
the other hand there's a new function
length smaller than you can read the
documentation. So you can see
it basically does exactly the same thing
like that but it's more efficient
because
um
wait this should be not length it should
be just it's more efficient because it
does not try to go through it okay so
that's that kind of validate what I was
saying about how even if you want to
find the length of a list. It it's pro
it takes proportionally longer time
proportional to the length of items in
the list. Okay.
Um okay, that's it. Let's let's get back
to the
uh let's put it back. Syntax collect
show in browser. So that's what we
talked about.
Let's let's go back to that command.
Let's just get it done. Uh, it's almost
done. So, [clears throat]
let me quickly code it. Okay. Any any
other questions.
Okay. So, do we still have people? 10
people. Great. Okay. So let's get back
to uh
write the code that moves the current
file or selected files up to a parent
directory. Okay. So
so map a function map to map a lambda to
list of
files. And what the what does the lambda
do? It will rename the file file name x
the new name will be um [clears throat]
the new name it will be the same. Okay
wait uh wait
the new name will be oh god so the new
name will be the parent directory minus
the current directory. So,
okay, it gets a little bit complicated
because you have to check if the file
actually have a parent directory because
you might be on the root. Um,
yeah. And then you have to do some error
checking.
Um,
okay. So, something like that. Okay. So,
so this part will be something like
parent.
This this part should be
oh path
of parent
with
file name something like that. Okay. And
okay if already exist
no. Okay. So,
so but then you have to check parent
directory. Okay. So,
oh god.
So, this does not check because for
example if file name
uh so you know instead of using car we
should have just used um
we don't want to use pop. Yeah, actually
we use car.
Actually, you can use mth. Um,
yeah, but let's not worry about it.
Okay, so file name directory. So, if you
have, for example, let me show you why
this may not work. ABC AB, let's say you
have the directory ABC. Okay, ABC and uh
my cat JPEG. Okay, let's say your file.
So that will return ABC do it.
Okay. But if you are at the root
directory
you know like that
it will
uh wait what
run it. It will return the slash
because there is no parent directory. So
what this means is that you are the
result of this is not the parent
directory because in the ca in this case
there's no parent directory.
So when you do this this this name is
actually incorrect.
It is not necessarily parent directory.
So you cannot just move it like you know
parent directory here.
You know you'll get errors. Um
so we have to do some error checking. Uh
God
but let's assume
you know so what happens if you rename
file to the same directory
let yeah so let's let's skip the error
checking. Okay.
So,
so the second argument will be let's
let's create this second argument. Okay.
So, the second argument will be
uh let's let's just copy the code
uh file name file name sense the
file name sense directory. Okay, wait.
File sense directory. Uh, file name none
directory. What the what the is the
command? So, let's go back to the we are
coding too slow today. Uh,
so let's go back to the what is this
modify? Let's go back to
um Vmac this file path
buffer functions
file path functions file name non
directory file name directory file name
n directory oh yeah file name none
directory stupid eac list this name you
know what this should be
It should be none dash directory none-
directory
but emac you know so that's like a
naming issue anyway
okay so file name none directory so that
returns the file name so file name none
directory uh that would be
uh let's just make this
first x first file okay so the First
file made
first file. Okay. So
set first file
car. Okay. So now you got the first
file, you got parent directory, and uh
then you got then then then
let's move that out here. Then you got
um the first file current directory.
Then you uh file name
directory. Okay.
Then you want the file name. Okay.
file name directory.
Okay. So anyway, oh yeah, here. So um
concat parent directory.
Uh how do we get this move to parent
directory? So
what?
Oh, so this is actually not the parent
directory. This is a current. So we got
do this twice.
Oh god.
Okay, let's let's just do it. Let's do
it. Okay, so don't worry.
Okay. Current parent. So this is a
current uh and parent uh will be
the directory of the current.
Okay. So, and uh this
uh let's just
print
and uh what god
and x print.
Okay, print current and print current.
Okay, let's just run it.
Okay. So, evaluate the buffer. Evaluate
the buffer and go to the diode mark. We
don't don't need to mark call the
command. Do it. Show message buffer. So,
current is equals to the temp. That's
correct. Parender is incorrect.
Okay. So, the parent this our code is
incorrect. So parent is the
Oh god. So this file name directory does
not remove it. Oh god.
Jesus.
So
do we actually have a parent directory?
File name. Oh, there's a function file
name parent directory. I've never used
it.
It's interesting. I never used this
command. Let's look up. Okay, I think
it's new. Is it new? No, it's in EMAC
29. That's like 10 years ago. Okay, so
cut. Okay, so file name parent
directory.
Okay, so file name parent directory. Uh
first file. Okay,
evaluate the buffer. Go to a diet call
the command. Do it. Go to messageages
buffer and look. So current is temp and
parent is incorrect.
Jesus.
So parent file name return directory
name of the parent directory of file
name.
Okay. So
yeah. So you got the issue. So
stupid Okay, I I think I know what
to do. Okay, so let's fix it again. So
parent this part should be current.
Okay, evaluate the buffer. Go to diet.
Call the command. Do it. Go to messages
buffer. So let's look at there it is. So
now it's correct parent.
Okay.
Uh what's your question
ACPJR?
So I think we we we we did what you know
what you are saying. I think we did.
Okay. So this is good. Um so now so now
this is correct. We made sure we got the
parent directory. Now let's let's do the
actual rename. Okay. So rename file
rename the current file map you know map
to all the files. So okay then you start
by rename it. Then then you want contact
the parent x parent directory.
Uh yeah. Yes. Did we get the slash? Yes,
we do have a slash. So, the parent
directory
then file name. Okay. Then file name.
Um,
yeah. Okay.
So, the parent directory uh then file
name none directory
first file. Okay.
Uh, wait. That's the file name n
directory. That's x. That's the current
file. Okay. So remove that.
So that
okay. So wait rename file that that and
we and what is his file name? N
directory.
Uh no no I think that's it. Okay. I
think that's it.
Yeah. File new name. Okay. If it exists.
No. Okay. So I think that's it.
>> [laughter]
>> map lambda. So, I've been coding too
slow today. Uh, and my back is now
starting to hurt. I think that's it.
Conc parent. Let's check one last time.
Okay. Conc rename file. the current file
X2 a full path and the full path is made
of conc concatenating the parent
directory with the current file name.
That's right. Okay, I think that's it.
So,
so evaluate the buffer. Okay, now let's
let's um let's do it here. Can we do it
here? Let's not do it here. So,
so evaluate it. Put the code back.
Syntax correct show in browser. We got a
code here. Okay. Now, go to the
directory here. Let's do it here. Okay.
Now, let's
So, let's move this picture to the
parent directory. Okay. So,
uh, wait, actually, let's move this
file, AI morality, which is some podcast
I did several month ago. Okay, so wait,
close. So, let's move this file to the
parent directory. Okay, so coette,
make sure the cruiser is on this line,
right? Call it move to parent. Do it.
Looks like it's done. Now refresh. Oh,
it's gone. Fantastic. Now go to the
parent directory. Search for morality.
There it is. Fantastic. We can we you
know we we did it. And now let's move it
back. Search for talk.
Okay. Capital R to move it back. back
here. It's here. Refresh there. Okay.
So, actually, so this command is
success.
Actually, we need to um do extra
checking to make sure there exist a
parent directory. Uh and also print out
some messages about
about the parent directory. It's moved
to.
So, but okay. But I'm tired.
Is it good? That's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching.
Any questions? So, we shut down in let's
say three two minutes. Okay. It's
annoying thing.
I think there's a function to get the
current in diode. No need to get the
current of the first mark fire. Okay.
Yeah. I mean, even it's true. It doesn't
doesn't make doesn't make sense because
actually when you call things in diet
it's more inefficient. I mean it's more
code because diet is specialized.
Meanwhile when you call the um
get parent directory let's say file name
get directory that just um
you know car is is is very efficient. Um
but but actually we don't need this. We
can compact this code a lot. So, uh
yeah. So, we don't need the first file.
I'll delete it.
Then, let's just remove the variables.
Okay. And we don't even need the current
uh let's see. Okay. Delete those.
[laughter]
Yeah. So, current uh we don't need it.
Yeah. It's It's nice to have them there.
So that it doesn't so that it's you know
it's easier reading because you can you
can compact the whole thing into one
single line without any variables. You
can do that and still remain efficient
but then the code becomes less readable
because that because I'm obsessed in
doing that because that's pure
functional style in a way that you don't
even have constants you know I used to
do that to do that a lot in wuam
language in the 1990s
so no use of constant or any variable at
all not even constants so what you end
up is just like one
huge kind of sequential or nested
function call okay with one argument at
the end you know this you know so it's
like transformation it's all just
transformation of one single value you
can do that right here you know actually
I can show you I can try to I can show
you how to do it so you don't you don't
have any variables at all but the The
it's kind of elegant but the problem is
it's not practical because then because
these variables the these constants they
help they actually serve as a
documentation.
You see these these variables they serve
as a documentation as you can you know
as you read it. Um you know
but we can you know let's say let's put
it here. So we can let's try some fun.
Okay, let's you know let's try some
variation. So let me show you. So here
is original and we just made a copy and
let let me try to uh so first step to
make the code more kind of compact is
use less star. Okay wait
uh less star. Okay. So that will allow
you to set subsequent
values
using the previous value. You see
because X files is used here and we are
using here again. If you use the normal
let that won't work because the later
variables
do not have access to the value of the
previous variables.
So if you want that you want to use lead
star. So now we can so and in fact we
don't need this uh we can move this
here.
Okay. So they all become inside the
lead. Okay. So this is kind of more ed
idiomatic. Okay. So you can you can
compare you can see uh it's more
compact. Okay. But we can further
reduce. Okay. Let let's for fun let's uh
let's do this. Okay,
so we we want to remove all variables.
Let's see. Actually, maybe I shouldn't
because I'm already tired.
Uh
thank you. Take care, Balash.
Okay, so uh let me try try a little bit.
Okay. So, um,
so this current is only used once. So,
we don't need it. You know, actually, we
don't need this variable. It's only used
once. Okay. So, so put that there.
Remove that. Okay. Now, it's now just
two constants. Okay. X files and parent.
And parent is only used once here. So,
you don't even need it. So [laughter]
parent is only used once. When it's used
once, you don't you know you don't need
it.
Okay. And here now it become too long.
So you format it in multiple lines. So
there. So now you don't need the less
stars anymore. Just one file.
Okay. Now
yeah, this is good. So this I would do
this. Okay. So this this will go to my
init file. So for example go to my a
brief file go to a directory and for now
search for miscellaneous go to the open
the miscellaneous file and uh add it at
the end. So this this is now part of my
emacs in it have done today. You know I
have this command move to parent.
So I don't have to manually split the
window and uh press capital R then check
what it says do you want to move this
directory are you sure this is the one
you know I don't have to I just call the
command you I can give it a key press it
two or three keys and you just do it
okay fantastic that's today's result and
there's one more thing you see this non
uh anyway let's forget about that okay
so save it go to directory. Go uh make a
backup. Go to directory B4 by compile.
Yes. Is there error? No arrow.
Fantastic. Okay. Now that's good. Now
close close. Now let me show you a new
way. Okay. So let's further. So this so
what we are doing is like the science of
functional programming supreme.
You don't even see the lispers do it
because I've been coding wufam language
for like
you know like 10 years in the 1990s
alone. So uh so the question here is how
do you move this how do you remove this
x files variable
without becoming inefficient.
Okay one easy way is you just duplicate
it. Okay. So you see so we are uh we
made a copy. So we have like you know
the original version then the more
compact version
using the lead star instead of let you
know let star then you have the one
single variable one single constant
version but now we're going to remove
that constant. Okay. So one easy way is
simply just um
simply simply just duplicate there
duplicate there and then you don't need
the lead anymore remove it. Okay, there
you don't have any constant at all. But
however this is inefficient
because
because this you see this the diet get
marked file are called twice.
Now what if that function is expensive?
You are being inefficient
because you are call because you are
calling a function twice.
So how do you make that
you know how do you solve this problem
meanwhile
not creating a new constant okay that's
that's that's the thing I'm going to
show you okay so you you create a
function okay so actually can you do
that it's get complicated
let me just do it okay let me quickly do
it so So, so let's make a new copy. So,
we we have progressive, you know,
progressive um advancement. So, so how
do you do this? Okay, so what you can do
is you create a lambda. Okay,
so lambda
then fun. Okay, so let me just show you
fun.
Okay. Fun call fun call
fun call this function lambda and uh the
argument here. Okay. So the argument
will be
this thing. Okay. So let me show you how
to how to do this. Okay. Uh
this is argument. So we don't need that.
Okay. Fun call lambda argument. Okay.
Now the lambda argument let's call this
uh y okay that's the argument so so you
just so now you just cut that yeah cut
that go to the body part
then this will be just y this will be
just y white y
fantastic
okay so this is how this is how you Um
you know you you re you remove any use I
mean you you remove yeah you remove any
use of a
constant or variable. Okay, you can do
it this way, but now it cost the this
function twice which is inefficient
but so you can fix it this way by
by using a lambda. So the lambda
you know you do a function call
of a function lambda and the lambda
takes the argument y y okay and the y so
let's color it color it so the y y y y y
y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y
y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y will
come
what yeah will come into two pl the y y
y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y
y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y y
actually here is the argument that's
that will become the y okay and the Y is
computed only once but it's it's fed
into two places. So let's try this.
Okay. Make sure our function still
works. Okay. Evaluate it. Um
put the code back. Syntax show in
browser. Okay. So you got so we see uh
our code. Okay. Now go to the directory.
Now let's say let's try this. Move this
AI morality again. So do it. Move to
parent directory. Do it.
Refresh. Fantastic. It's done. Go to our
directory. Search for morality. There it
is. Okay. Fantastic. So now it's
working. Let's put it back. Search for
talk show. Uh uh. Open it. Move it. Do
it.
Fantastic. Okay, our code is done. So,
bye guys.
Fantastic.