Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of talk show. Today we are going to do
F. We are going to code F writing a F
script functional programming language
that does find and replace of text files
of text of all files in a directory and
recursively. And we are going to ask Gro
for help the Gro AI bot because the AI
bot has become so great. So let's see
how it goes. Uh we're going to have fun.
If you are here, say hi. Post your
comments and chat. Uh if you are
watching this offline, skip around. Play
at 1.5 speed because I ramble. You see
here is my screen uh screen. We're going
to code and uh but let me introduce my
keyboards quickly. I introduce them
almost in everyone every one of my
videos. This is glove 80 keyboard. This
is ultimate hacking keyboard. Fantastic.
This is Nia trackable. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. And uh and then I have this I
have hand pen so
much. I have hand pinned so much uh
because I type so much. So, this is
called small board. SV A L B O A R D.
Uh, fantastic device. So, I'm going to
start to try to use it. It's been
delayed for a year. So, for each one of
them, I got a review on YouTube and on
my website,
kasali.info. Okay, let's begin coding
F. So, we going to do
uh Cesame. Let's see. Uh we going to do
gu magic please help me. So the plan
is so what's the plan? The plan of
coding. So are you seeing it? Yes. Okay.
Let's stop
this error. YouTube is not receiving
enough video to maintain smooth [ __ ]
[ __ ]
Uh am I doing good? Am I
Okay. Check. Check. Am I still
going? Check. Okay. I think I'm back.
Okay. Let's begin. Uh, let's ask. So,
the plan is to ask uh Gro for help.
uh plan
ask to write a script in
F sharp to do find and replace of all
files in a okay now if that doesn't work
we'll
then if
that isn't
uh god
So, am am I uh streaming good? It's kind
of
lagging. Oh, [ __ ]
[ __ ] First thing
I Okay, I think I'm back. I think. Am I
back? I will pause.
Okay. So, we are back. I think I just
wrote out the
plan. H [ __ ] It's uh showing that
again. Uh I might need to restart
my internet.
Can anyone say what's going on? Tell me.
So, okay, tell me. I'll see how it goes.
I'll see what to do. So, streaming.
Streaming. Okay. So let's ask
what show a
f script that does find and replace for
all files or
html or html files in
a using rejects. Okay, let's ask
book. Okay,
the no
data. What the [ __ ] is with the no data?
Okay. So, gu answered. So, let's just
copy it. Oh, Jesus. Uh, pretty
short. Copy it. I think my screen uh my
um my stream is [ __ ] zero viewers.
Okay, it's going to
just So now I'm
good. I think I'm good now.
Okay, let's let's just
continue.
So, so find replace. So, this is a
function. Okay. So, this directory name
then pattern. Pattern is
a regular expression pattern. Okay. And
then replacement is a string. So this is
how you write a function. And let's see.
Okay, it's using
spaces. And then
uh let HTML files directory get files
directory. So this is getting this is
walking a directory. Okay. Let files
HTML files that's a file list. Okay.
Then directory.get get files that's how
you traverse a directory okay I suppose
now where does the directory came from
okay must be from the system okay so
directory get files that's how you
traverse the directory and uh then
there's some argument okay the directory
path the regular expression to filter
the
files then search option all directories
okay so that is a way to specify
recursively. Okay, so this supposedly
this is all HTML files then for file in
HTML files. Oh, pretty readable.
Uh so this is how you um do a for loop
for file in HTML files. This is supposed
to be a list then do then try. Okay.
Read file
content let content equals to do file
read or text file. So file read or text.
Okay. That is the function built in
to read a file.
Okay. Uh if you guys are watching tell
me if my internet connection is good. Am
I lagging or stuff? Like post in the
chat like is my chat even stuck?
I don't know. So maybe I need to I just
maybe I'll just cancel this
stream. So now I'm
good. I don't know. So maybe I need to I
just maybe I'll just cancel this stream.
Okay, so let's go back. Uh,
so the Grog result is pretty good. So
content equals profile read all text. So
this is how you read the file.
Fantastic. Read the file content. Okay,
so actually
That's actually very
good.
Okay. So, you traverse the directory.
You stop that. Okay. Stop that. Traverse
the directory.
You iterate the file list. Then you try
then you read the file. So this is how
you do it. Okay. Then file. Okay. Then
perform regular expression replacement.
Okay, that's how you do it. Let update
content. Okay, where is that declared?
Uh, this is a new variable. Okay, so let
update content equals to
rejects.replace. Okay, fantastic
contents. That's a content pattern.
Okay, that's from the parameter.
Fantastic replacement. That's from par
the parameter.
Fantastic. And then only write if
content change. Okay, fantastic touch
because without this it's uh not
efficient. So if content Okay, so this
is how you specify not equal. Oh,
interesting. That's I don't like that.
So if content is not equals to updated
content then file write all text. So if
it's changed then you write it file
update content. Okay, write the file.
file is the file path and uh update
content is a new text. Okay, then print
updated. Okay, else print no change.
Fantastic. So with uh so
now with Okay, now I don't know what
does this with do with um ex print print
error processing. Okay, so Oh, so this
this is a try and width. Okay. Try if
this not successful
then then do this something like that.
Okay. Then entry point. Oh, okay. So
that's how they say the main. So you can
actually declare a man in F. So entry
point let directory. So let's let's
start to modify it. Okay. So make a
backup. Uh let's uh go back
here. Okay. Let's not do anything. Okay.
So actually so uh so this this is a
directory. This is a uh pattern. Okay.
So then main let's start to try to uh
run this. Okay. So but first of all I
need a directory to to find and replace.
So let's go to EMAC block. Go down.
There's a EMAC manual. So Emac list this
manual. So let's copy this directory. So
go back to talk show
uh go back here and uh and uh
then capital C to copy copy to talk show
recursively. Yes. Copy all
files. Copy one file. Done. Okay. It's
not a file. It's a directory. So rename
it xx. Okay. So this is a directory
uh directory of all the files. Okay,
we're going to try to change. So copy
the file path. Close close close. Uh
close
close. Okay. Uh what is this? Emac
close. Okay. So this is the directory we
want. And
uh okay now the add sign means
um I forgot what the f sign
means. Okay so comment that out. This is
the directory we want to go
into. Okay
then then pattern. Okay let's we need to
pick a pattern.
Okay. So pattern let's say
uh let's just say literal this this
line.
Okay. Let's say this line. Okay. So
pattern that line. Oh you need to Okay.
So this involves quote. Let's not do
something
complex. So let's say pattern
that literal. Okay. just okay so this is
a reject pattern to find that's
right okay then you want to replace it
uh with okay let's
say something something new okay hold on
a second uh let's say my stuff my manual
okay my book. Okay. So this is the
replace text redundant comment
idiotic. So now and now call the
function find replace directory pattern
replacement. Okay. So I think we can try
to run it. If it's successful then it's
like
fantastic. Okay. Can we run this now?
Yeah. I think so.
Oh, so now it's okay. Thank
you. It's
uh problem. So you know so to recap to
uh to repeat what we have done we have
asked Grog to help us write this script
in F to do find replace of text of all
files in a directory all HTML files and
gu just give this code it's
only 40 lines of code fantastic
And apparently I went through it's easy
to understand
uh very easy to understand only 40
lines. Okay. And now I'm about to run
it. So I created a temp directory this
one. Now let's actually um make a copy
of that uh so that we can do more.
What?
XXX2 recursively
copy
XXX3 copy recursively. So we got several
copies of of 1,00 files. Okay, those are
text files. Okay, now we are about to
run it. Okay, let's see. Let's hope uh
let's hope everything works. Okay, so we
are replacing this Guno Emacs list
reference manual to just my book.
Okay, please let it
run. Wait,
what? Oh, okay. You got a problem.
Warning functions with entry point are
not invoked in
FSI. Main was not
invoked. Okay. What the [ __ ] is
that? What What does What the [ __ ] does
that mean? Okay. Let's Let's make
it Okay. So
uh
so go to line
28. We wrote this yesterday go to line
number uh the buffer
28. So beginning
here this got a problem. It
says when developing F it's better to
use IDE like Visual Studio not code or
RER I doubt
it. FSX does not use man. Okay. So can
you tell me how to fix this? FX FSX
scripts are not using main entry point
my friend.
Oh, okay. So, I am so I'm totally not
familiar with F at all except I started
to read the manual. I mean the the
tutorial the official one like a week
ago. So, this is basically my first
program in F.
So, so I may not, you know, I don't
understand. Remove just your main. Oh,
okay. Okay. So, the Okay, I I think I
got it. So yeah I thank you.
Um but let me let me go through the
arrow a little bit so I can kind of
learn from okay function with entry
point. Okay that entry point are not
invoked in FSI. Now what is the
difference? What is
fsi and
uh
fsx? I think fsx means script
right? Uh and FSI is what? Interactive
something. Okay. So anyway, execute uh
main in order to invoke main with the
appropriate string array of command. Uh
okay. So anyway, let me just remove
this.
So okay. Yeah. Right. So I don't have
arc, right? Yeah. So where's the arc
come from? Let's remove that. So, but
meanwhile I need to you see I don't like
the indentation
thing. Okay. So, I think that is that.
Okay. Maybe
that. Okay. FSX is
script. You have to remove lines. Okay.
Anyway, what lines? Okay. Anyway, so
let's write uh let's try run this. Okay.
So, run
it. Oh my god, it's it run. So, we have
updated 1,000 files.
1,086
files. Wow. One shot, one shot answer
from Gro.
Fantastic. And thank
you. Yes. So it seems fantastic. So
let's check. Okay, let's check if it
actually changed. It did. You know, GNU
Emac this manual changed to my book.
Fantastic. So let's go. Uh yeah. So
let's see.
Wait. Oh, okay. Wait. So they create a
new file name that's named untitled.
That's
what Wait, something went wrong. Wait,
not here.
Uh, wait, hold on a
second. Oh, wait. So, you got to go
here. Yeah. So, here is our temp
directory. Refresh. Open
it. Change my book there. Good. Open
this one. Changed. Good. Open this one.
Change. Good. So, let's go down. Open
this one. change good so it successful
totally completely successful. Now let's
try some regular expression. Okay. So
let's try you see this double my book.
Let's try to uh change it to something.
Okay. So now regular
expression let's change these two lines.
So the regular expression will be
parentheses parentheses my and anything
uh let's say back let's say uh my book
so my space and uh here we will have uh
lowerase letter now how do you represent
lowerase uh letter regular expression
well in emac is a z that are still work
but uh word. Okay, it's back slashw for
word. Okay, so plus
uh w then plus means one or more. Okay.
So, we want to change that to um let's
say then let's say can So, how do
you represent the
um is it dollar sign one or is it back
slash
one? Let's see which way. So, change my
something my book to book mine. Okay.
So, let's try that. Okay. So comment
this out. Comment this out. And uh let's
just do it. Experimental programming.
Let's find out which of these syntax is
for replacement stand for replacement in
F. You will use your entry point and let
men when you uh when you have a when you
have a
[Music]
regular regular executable. Okay. Thank
you. So, let's run this. Fantastic.
Let's see.
Fantastic. I'm very happy. I'm I'm
actually very impressed by Gork today's
AI bots, how they can just show you
simple
programs. And I'm also
uh Oh, look. Wait.
Uh, okay. This replacement got wrong.
So, I'm also impressed. I mean so the
the F code is pretty easy to
understand but uh right
now why is this oh okay so
parenthesis in normal regular expression
they represent a capture so you
shouldn't use parenthesis parenthesis
here but anyway what did we got now so
we
got wait okay so yeah the capture is
wrong. Yeah. Uh so, okay, let let's
let's fix it. Okay, close that. Close
that. Close
that. Uh undo. Now, this is the text we
want. And let's copy that. Let's uh copy
that. Let's let's
let's change this triple
uh triple
triple
paren my book slash one my okay so that
that is that now I want to change it
okay triple paren so you need backslash
to represent the parin
um and I want the capture somewhere here
so so capture this book word uh so
that's a paren
back slashw for word one or more
plus okay so my
something and uh back slash one uh okay
how do you maybe back back slashbacks
slash one
maybe I forgot what is the f uh x2do
uh so you need to look up F
documentation for string. Now what is
their literal um assign at sign prefix
means verbatim. Oh okay. So there it is.
So close that. Close
that. Okay. So this is verbatim. Okay.
So then you just need one backslash
there. So I want to remove that.
So then change
to change to just that word.
Okay. I mean change to just this
book. Okay. With with
um uh what do you want to change it to?
So that's just
that.
Um so back slash pre previously did it
work
uh okay something so maybe we will try
this okay let's see what happens instead
of parent let's say
uh let's see let's try uni
code see let's let's get a fancy uni
code now let's test the whether F#
understand unic code much. You see this
is Chinese corner
bracket there left corner bracket. Okay.
This is a unic code character there.
Okay. So if we try this it would re
remove the triple paren and the whole
thing into
just into
just book slash one or dollar one book.
Okay. Run
it. Uh, duplicate definition. Yeah.
Okay. Okay. Nice. It warns you. Okay.
So, remove that. Comment that out. Run
it.
Fantastic. So, here's the output. 1,00
files. Let's go to it. Let's see one of
them. Uh,
failed my book. Back slash one. My Okay,
let's open this one. Failed. Nothing
changed. Oh, so it says here no change.
No change. No change. Now that means our
regular expression it's got a
problem. Uh so how do
you how do you represent a par
literally? But anyway that's a little
detail. So I we are successful. I'm
pretty successful.
You can try using string interpretation.
Okay. So
um you will use your you can try using
string interpretation dollar sign
something so that you don't have to
escape
characters right but
um right but right
now I mean right now we got a little bit
confused okay so here's the task
I want to replace this triple
paren something text
by by
just the first word there. Okay. So, so
the question here is something how do
you
um literal okay so dollar sign I mean at
sign means literal so I
thought so let's see let's check the
documentation okay so let's go back to F
let's see F
install click there and there's F
documentation which one
here. So F documentation turn on
JavaScript. I want to see the regular
expression syntax. I believe it is the
net. Same thing as a net.
But so inn net how do you um how do you
represent a literal parenthesis? Okay,
that's what what uh what we need to
know. So you go you go to F# language
guide that's the
best article uh okay so let's language
guide then you go to strings
uh interpolated I don't care now I want
regular expression but regular
expression is a mini language usually
it's not part of so they won't they
won't explain here So I need to search.
Okay. So let's say
f reject
syntax or I can just use ask work much
simpler. How
to
represent a literal parn in
F
rejects. Now is it backslash or tick?
Okay, it's a
backslash. Okay,
magnify. So it's a backslash. So I'm
correct.
Now, however,
uh,
however, how do you represent word? I
think I got back slash
wrong. How to represent a word pattern
in F rejects? Okay.
back
slashw. So I'm correct
here. Then why is my uh capture not
done? So what
about why is uh something you know
something here is not
right? You see, I want to capture that
that
uh but anyway that's a regular
expression detail. I can figure it out
later. But I think that's it for today.
So
So yeah, fantastic. So we got the code.
Let's shrink a little
bit. So we got the code like um you know
very simple to understand. You got open
system open system.io open system text
regular expressions. You got this is a
defining of function find and replaced
in files with three parameters directory
pattern and replacement. So all types
are string. Then here's the body of the
function. You here's how you traverse
directory. Directory.get get files
directory path then a pattern then then
to specify recursive you just say search
options dot all directories you know one
thing I find about Microsoft language
technology which I begin to learn about
the past five or 10 years is that they
you know they they they have a different
way from the typical Unix programming
languages bash python uh emacs Mag this
so they don't say recursive you know
they just say search options dot all
directories which is very which is
descriptive you know because recursive
it just means any recursion so what it
you know it implies a kind of
implementation detail so anyway so
here's how you traverse directory then
here's how you iterate over a list so a
list of path is set to HTML files. Then
you iterate over this list. Then you try
here's how to open a file. Read all the
contents. Here's how to replace string.
Fantastic. Uh then if if they are
different from original, then you just
then you write file
easy. Else print no change. And this is
what happens if there's error. Okay. And
then all you have to do is just define
the regular define the directory here.
You want to go into define the regular
expression and replacement. Then just do
it. Okay. So what one more thing okay so
I want to check the unit code if that
works. So now let's just try simply
this. Okay. I want to replace all just
mine
by sum. Okay, let's see if that works.
Okay, run
it.
Fantastic. Open this
one. S walked unic code. So there's one
issue it didn't mention is that how does
it deal with uh encoding. So I presume
it just presumed uni code UTF8 which is
great. Uh but if you have some other
encoding does how do you uh specify I
don't know somewhere in the read text I
suppose. Anyway that's it for
today. Oh the code is written in a
imperative style. Okay. So, um, okay.
There's a lot of improvement. Let's see.
So, Oh, yeah. So, that's right. You are
right. So, you got this iteration for
file in that's you know imperative
uh and uh let's see what else. So,
function. Okay. So, you get all files.
Yeah. So, here's imperative.
So instead of um I suppose you can use
some kind of map like map map a function
to the file right
uh uh then
uh yeah so yeah well anyway I'm learning
this is great bye
guys thank you for
help let's see 40
minutes. Okay. Yeah. Wait. So, put this
back. Syntax color it uh showing
browser. Yeah. That's it for today. Bye,
guys.