check voice check video check
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
so we are going to do wufang language
coding today wufang language i'm going
to give you an introduction i'm going to
tell you where to get it i'm going to um
uh then i'm going to talk about wufam
language streams mostly today we are
going to focus on wolfram language
strings and text processing
and we are going to code a live coding
of a script
so
wufam language that's the main topic and
i'm going to show you in the beginning
this keyboard this fantastic new
keyboard okay
key move k68 butterfly keyboard now
voice check
check video check check
okay how are you guys this is a great
sunday afternoon
yes fantastic new keyboard so this is
the one key move k68 butterfly keyboard
now they are coming out in about three
days okay so they sent me a copy and uh
and uh you know i'm so
i'm gonna give you a review
five minutes review short
okay so let's turn on
let's see
yeah so this keyboard okay fantastic
a great build quality you know so you
know you can just go to my saudi blog
right now you know i just created this
page today so if you search it you won't
find it but go to you know let me show
you okay so
go to kassadi.info
okay now there's a new search button
there it is topic search click on that
and
you just
type keyboard oh you need to turn on
javascript of course javascript on
then type keyboard you know
as you type the result showed up this is
fantastic feature javascript and and
typescript microsoft typescript
excuse me
i still have a little cuff from code
so fantastic keyboard so search you know
search i did a video you know about last
month on implementing the search so this
is gonna search all the titles of my
you know 4000 articles so you just type
for
key uh keyboard
you know so there are
523 results
now you can type you know there's lots
of star talks your talk show talk show
key work start talk show so you want a
minus talk
this is still 458 results then you minus
windows you know
minus windows
minus linux
uh too many so instead you want the
keyboard uh block okay so type for
keyboard
um
well type for k move k e m o v e
there it is k move k
dk 61 now this is a
same maker same brand they sent it to me
from china you can buy on amazon and
this
first of all they have great fantastic
build quality
solid
heavyish
you know i'm gonna show you okay okay so
anyway this is the previous one
and it's fantastic okay of course
it's 60 i don't like 60 no arrow keys no
function keys i mean they have virtual
arrow keys virtual function keys virtual
page up and page down it's no good okay
so but you know if you like 60
this i recommend
highest quality build colorful you know
i'm gonna show you i'm gonna show you
colors okay
so colors you can see this one they got
um wait what's the key for
switching to colors
uh
you know
so many color variations like like so
many uh let's
and they have the color on the side
but
anyway so
so this is their previous version k move
k uh you know key move dk 61 and then
you go to my keyboard blog
keyboard blog scroll down blog and you
can see today's i mean i just created
this page today
and you have you know they have the site
color as well the strip on the side
and it supports
wired if you want to you know wired usbc
uh plug or
usb wireless
2.4 gigahertz you know you press the
switch i'm going to show you you know
and oh bluetooth and if you switch to
bluetooth
you can connect to up to three computers
okay uh now the color is
let's see what is what's okay so so many
color variations so now i'm going to
oh
oh you you oh you didn't see my uh [ __ ]
i forgot to show you my website page
shall we do it again okay so you know
okay let me show you i i need to i want
to show you this okay so you go to
kassadi.info
you know there it is in the top you have
the topic search click on that
then you can type
k
dental javascript
yeah
k
move
then you have the article that shows the
k move dk61 this is the previous version
they made
and the current model dk68 is coming out
okay
so anyway i want to show you search okay
search you know as you type keyboard you
know there are 500 results you know it
searched from you know thousands of my
articles
so you arrive at the keyboard dk6
61 then click on blog then here is the
new page i created today so you can see
it great
so you know they have the second so okay
now let me go back to the
full screen so let me show you
so quality build okay so they have yeah
so they have the side color so let me
show you you know
let's see if we can yeah
change the side color
uh
oh yeah i know why it's not working it's
not you know you're supposed to press
the fn key then press the caps lock
that will cycle different
coloring of the side strip okay it goes
all around all around it
but why is it not working it's because
let me go you know complicated keyboard
technology you know this exhaust system
so the reason it's not working because i
have remapped the caps lock
took stuff like keys so you get
onto this page this is power toy a great
tool for keyboard and other things so
keyboard managers so you can see
caps lock is now become home that's why
it's not working now let's turn it off
okay turn it off
then go back to the full screen
now let me show you okay
press the function key
caps lock
and press
off and close okay
okay now
wait why is it
so you can change the color by this key
let's see this is turn it off turn on
switch to
great varieties of coloring and what is
this
so this is one shot bomb
okay so
change the keys
so what is this let's play s okay so
that's that
change the settings now what is this
okay
change again now it kind of goes like
that
change it again it's randomized change
it again
okay
candystripe
change it again
this is a color shift change it again
okay let's let's let's stay with this
okay
but how do you get the
side strip to
you know i can yeah let's forget about
it let's see
let's switch to
[Music]
200 i mean 2.4 gigahertz
maybe there
i don't know why is it not working but
um
yeah well it was working before okay now
it works wait does it
yeah there there it is
so now it shifts
you can see it moves around it goes
around
and
next
okay
then next
what is this one
oh this is just a steady
next
anyway the side coloring of the strips
okay let's turn it off because
it wastes battery and
[Music]
generally uses
okay i don't want to move and turn it
off
okay turn it on
yeah okay let's leave it like that
okay so
let's turn the lights back on
and uh
let me show you
so there it is great quality okay
there is the feet you can see
and uh
highest quality keycaps pcb
pcb or pcp keycaps anyway
and uh
it's using thin profile keycaps let's
see
my lousy stupid camera
it doesn't focus
anyway
so i just want to show you
a bit of the keyboard okay
and you can read on my page you know i
have higher quality photos and in the
next week in the next few days i'm going
to
add information and it's fully
programmable
so
it's fantastic okay and it's by the way
it's hot swappable keys so you can if
you don't like this switch you can buy
another switch
you can buy from their website okay
that's it for that let's continue let's
get on to
okay we talked about keyboard for 20
minutes almost let's get on to wufang
language coding
any questions
okay language is a wolfram language
coding
now let's get to the technicality in the
you know
technical computation so wufang language
i did many videos before so you can just
search for xiaowu fan language tutorial
you'll find my page
i did
10 over 10 videos in the past year so
covering many aspects of wolfram
language the graphics the power the
artificial intelligence the generic
introduction this video is great you
know the characteristics of haskell
python lisp mathematica
and i talked about stephen wufam a guy i
admire i admire his point of view and
accomplishments uh so you know i did
several videos so check them out and the
wolfram graphics you know i did this one
fantastic geometry you know so you want
to learn math mathematics real
mathematics not programmers idiotic
programmers
crap you know whenever programmers talk
about math they talk [ __ ] they don't
know what they're talking about
so here is
real mathematics okay group theory
abstract algebra topology those are real
mathematics not programmers algorithm
that's a different thing okay
you know the in general programmers know
nothing about mathematics but however
they adore mathematics anyway so wolfen
language you know so here's the geometry
it's not exactly the traditional
mathematics it's uh but it's
inversion you know it's the inversion
the topic of geometric inversion is a
classic mathematics but however we are
doing
graphical programming and this is uh
by the way this is uh
uh i'm very proud of this one this one
is creative okay you will not see it
elsewhere
uh so
so three times so let me just show you
what i'm called since we are going to
let's do some fan fancy okay i got so
new keyboard so i i don't have the
marker set up so let's copy the code
and let's start
wolfram
desktop
okay so today's focus is actually about
stream you know text processing and
string in language but let me just show
you this okay so here is the wolfram
language code let's magnify
am i doing good
is it interesting
uh
so you know windows idiotic windows so
you see here's the code
you can it's it's
okay let's run it
shift return shift enter there it is
there it is
this is the process of how you generate
this image so i did a full video one
hour on on this thing how do you program
this and what does it mean
and here you can magnify and you can
rotate it
uh and this what is this good for this
is good for a
modern decorative
interior decoration you know if you go
to art school you can major in that
interior decoration so what is this good
for this is good for garden tile design
imagine you have a big house you know
many of you you know those of you work
at google
you know or facebook or microsoft you
know programmers make a lot of money so
you you you're gonna have your own house
and you can have a garden you know
design your own garden tires so this is
one of them now you see this the the
interesting part about these graphics is
that
you can see
kind of circles going on you see
you see circle circle circle circle
that's a that's the gist
that's why this image is interesting you
can see circles going on yet the tiles
are evenly distributed now this is based
on geometric inversion so i won't be
talking about it but you know watch my
previous video you can see you know
geometric inversion of a square grid
then you get that
but however what you want is that you
see this image you notice that things in
the middle
becomes tiny you know
as
when they gets closer to the origin they
become infinitely small
so that is not what you want if you want
a garden tile because you cannot have
infinite this infinite is small although
it's this is pretty but you know so you
want to find a way
so that you maintain the overall
you maintain the overall uh
design you know like circles like that
inversion of a square grid then you get
that
but however you want them to be equally
distributed and not getting smaller in
the middle so
by understanding mathematics
you know you can figure out how to do
that
you know so this is your basic you know
if you have studied calculus
you know like typically you go to school
you study calculus about
speed and you know you learn things
but this is the application this is an
application of the
analytic geometry you will not see in
school but you need to understand it in
order to do this so what you have to do
what i have to do is to create
apply a transformation you know create
you know first of all you have to think
about you have to understand how this
works
how exactly they get their position then
you have to um
once you know
you you you can come up with a
transformation function to the whole
plane then you start with that then you
apply the geometric inversion then you
get this you see now it's evenly
distributed you know these squares
and then you
with wufam language know how which which
is what i'm teaching you today then you
can get the 3d version of the tire okay
interior design so this is uh up you
know consider you know it's part of
applied mathematics
interior design okay you know when you
look at geometry you know let me yeah so
i'm gonna talk random a bit
so sadly
you search for sardi
actually go go to kasali.org okay
saudi.org
[Music]
animation
are you going to make an animation of me
creating my keyboard today
so
you go to xari.org
then
then you go to uh okay i actually um
so then you go to
visual arts okay now i talked about this
a few times the visual arts you know uh
so you have the solar power you know
solar power massive
so visual art anyway visual arts then
you go to
what we want architectural beauties okay
there it is geo geodesic domes
now you know here you have several uh
geodesic domes this is all geometry you
know geometry
so applied mathematics or decoration
interior decoration architectural design
you know so when you study mathematics
when you study calculus you think you
thought oh it's boring but this is a
application of it okay
and we are not even getting into the
engineering aspect of it you know
because once you have design you know
buildings are not just like
you know you you cannot just create any
shape you want you have to make sure
they are stable you know the material
material science you know the
engineering the you know the stress
uh testing you know all you know that's
a deep
engineering
involving lots of disciplines
okay so actually my volume is a bit slow
before right i mean low okay so
so
uh architecture okay so and i wanted to
show you
architectural beauties
okay so these are architecture archi you
know the the beauty you know there are
so many uh
styles of architecture you have the
western style
uh you know
for example cathedrals this is a
classic european grand
architectural design cathedrals okay
years you are seeing cathedral ceilings
they are deeply involved with geometry
and mathematics okay deeply so
you know you have different ceiling
designs all these are this is an old
castle this is a beautiful girl i know
15 years ago she sent me this photo
beautiful she's italian
she's
she's actually
palestinian
and mexican
hybrid okay beautiful
uh so she went there you know she lives
in italy and she sent me you know uh
castle you know
like lots of nuts you know we used to
you know nerds of the 90s are very much
into these things i used to by you know
study architecture you know
and here is the islamic style
uh you know thing again geometry oh
that's all you see geometry so
my point here is that is that
architecture
the gist
the essence of architectural beauty
is geometry okay
so you have the western style and here
again it's a western style um kind of
thing
uh votes how do you call those there's a
name specific name
this is morocco
um i believe it's called votes okay so
anyway so
system yeah it's called system um
you know there's a purpose you know
beautiful fantastic you know look at
that beautiful you don't see these kind
of things today today
so see then you know and we have more
cathedrals now this is the most famous
you know the
cologne cathedral in germany
grand you know this is like a thousand
years ago
grand buildings you know imagine
technology thousand years ago it takes a
few hundred years to build this so again
my point here is that the essence of
architectural beauty you know when you
think about architecture you know many
photographers you know into architecture
you often see them right design or
churches
so what is the gist of the beauty so why
is architecture you know sometimes you
know so many people into it
what's the gist the gist is geometrical
beauty okay that's what i'm telling you
uh you don't hear that much from
anywhere else okay so and then again
another
western architect architectural uh
beauty okay uh grand baroque and you can
see you know
and look look at this design extremely
exceedingly beautiful by the way if you
don't know okay you know because i'm
into math i was looking at this i was
studying these things 20 years ago in
1990s and i did
you know if you go to my website kasabi
math you'll see quite a few of these but
they are pretty old
sadly.info
okay then topic search
then just type
math
uh
math okay so a lot of talk shows so
minus talk okay 105 articles okay pretty
math for example if if you go to my
website you'll see
i have quite a few um
hundreds of articles on
mathematics
uh
you know this is related to a hyperbolic
geometry this lamp
and you know and this is projective
geometry all sort of
uh also the beautiful beautiful things
and this is related to topology you know
the claim bottle and here is related to
tidying and patterns symmetry group
theory okay and this is just a tire
print on the snow but
but it's just
exceedingly beautiful you know the
pattern the pure geometry just by lines
and position of lines and stuff
okay so i have quite a few and here
you see this one
water falling down from this mushroom
structure
and they create they create this pattern
now that's physics okay that's a deep
physics you know in order to explain
this it's not easy
so someone a
physicist professor actually uh
explained this thing water
curtain okay again
for example what what's the purpose of
this
the purpose of this
thing this fountain is exactly just
decorative you know beauty you know
that's why
you know if you just go out your
neighborhood wherever you live okay
usually you know typically in the city
you got you see also the
buildings and and you know buildings and
they have particular design and and
what's the purpose what's the
functionality of their design why can't
they just all be just squares
well because we cannot
tolerate just boring we have to have we
kind of have to have
beautiful design beauty is the essence
of humanity one
one of the first fundamental
core
of the meaning of humanity okay for
example we look at the keyboard
you know uh why should the keyboard have
lights beautiful beauty okay
every just about everything you know
again you know i'm digressing over
so today i'm not sure i'm gonna we're
gonna do wufang language coding we
supposed to
you know because i already talked for 40
minutes about random things but you know
architectural beauty okay and here's
another one in a um
what is this airport dubai airport you
know so all related to all relates to
math
okay so
so but i want to go back to architecture
um
yeah so i showed some of the western
architectural beauty then there is
um
there's modern ones for example this one
in china you know this
this kind of roof kind of for shading
purposes that's their purpose but
however they designed it so that it
forms stars
fantastic
so you know if you are how are you gonna
do this
who who you know what makes you think of
things like this what made you think or
similar all the other all the others
what makes you think this is a modern
church hyperbolic hyper
this one is called
hyperbolic the uh hyperbolic
hyperbola of one sheet okay where is it
uh
okay i have you know i have tons of
material and the math aspect of it i'm
not you know i you know i don't have a
link here
i should have
somewhere okay
that links to the mathematical surface
called hyperbolic
hyperboloid of one sheet this structure
is called hyperboloid one sheet okay xrd
okay let's see sardi
dot info okay so again
you click on the search
then search for h-y-p-e-r
so you have hyperbola
uh we talked about hubert curve
hyperboloid yeah actually we you know i
did
yeah we did a live coding of this thing
hyperboloid of one sheet okay and here
is the article here is the mathematical
uh structure it's made of straight lines
this this curved surface is actually
made
made of completely made of straight
lines fascinating so that's the beauty
of mathematics
okay so and then
then you have this building and you have
this tower and quite a lot of uh
applications okay so
so let's go back to architecture a
little bit let me just complete okay so
architectural beauties hyperboloid of
one sheet okay
that's the kind of modern design you
know this is not this is a church this
is a cathedral i believe catholic church
uh catholics
temple of warship you know
in brazil and uh so it's called
cathedral and then you have you know
kind of modern so this is kind of uh
this one the beauty you know this one is
in china became very famous back in the
olympics china olympics 2008
you know its nickname
is bird nest you know it's uh i believe
it's a stadium okay
but look at you know it's beautiful
so
you know the most most most of the
others
their beauty came from symmetry okay
you got that most most of the others
their beauty for example here's an
islamic
uh
style design symmetry you see because
it's symmetric most most vast majority
of buildings you know this
came from symmetry because you can see
they are there's a repetition there's uh
various various types of symmetry if you
study group theory
then
that is the topic of study of symmetry
group theory okay you study math for a
few years until you graduate you know
get a math major
focus on group theory that's
it's all about symmetry you know you
might be wondering symmetry is so you
know so plan so what what else is there
to study about symmetry you know human a
human face is symmetric you can see
my left side and my right side is
symmetric that's symmetry okay that's
one type of symmetry this star
you know so there are so that's group
theory okay so that you know i'm telling
you i'm giving you the
i'm enticing you
into the realm
the the the beauty of the realm of
mathematics you know because if you go
through
every you know you just go to study at
school math oh
my god it's so boring it's trigonometry
what's what are you gonna do with it
measure you know measurement you know
the distance and it's so
so boring but i'm giving you i'm giving
you the
um the interesting parts okay
so symmetry that's group theory
um and uh
so
i'm talking about this one so
all the others are symmetric what's this
thing this thing is not geometric you
know but it's beautiful but it's not
symmetric
it's like random random lines
that is the beauty you know the beauty
of this one
is
odor within chaos you see if you
actually just just just random just you
know pile a bunch of bricks together
it's not beautiful
but however you have to make it such
that this it's
seems like random but there's a certain
order you know we think
that is this thing that's a that's a
that's the essence
of the beauty of this design okay
that's uh you know that's that's that's
what that one okay then we have the you
know cooling towers you know these are
again
hyperboloid of one sheet
uh then then you have this kind of uh
more humanistic you know it emulates the
shape of a tree this china you know
china is becoming incredible in past 10
years they have tons of these kind of
buildings tons
uh then then you have these
you know this is also beautiful you know
so architectural abu
architectural beauties
the essence lies in geometry you see
this there's a cone that forms the conic
sections you know part of
came from the cone conic sections
okay
uh i think that's that's that then we
have more uh non-geometric based beauty
such as
kind of the sculpture
this is in usa you know
beautiful
okay so yeah so i was saying what
greetings from california arnold hello
and annoyed are you the guy on discord i
think
maybe the
okay
so now
how am i doing
night people watching okay now
let's maybe do uh wufang language now
okay let me have a drink then let's
do firm language okay
pc keyboard let's see
yeah wufang language okay so
uh
yeah powershell my powershot
tutorial
uh how to unzip
you know how to entire
how to earn gzip
you know using powershell so i've you
know i continuously update my
programming language tutorial so if you
like my stuff pay me okay
you know paypal and patreon i have links
on my website you feel like i'm gonna
stop paying me you know e-maxi all these
are great emacs emac this wu from
language tutorial which is what i'm
gonna
uh talk about today
html tutorial visual css
uh all these are great and javascript in
depth
that is the most effort i took
the most in-depth coverage of the of of
the most complex language javascript
more complex than image lisp
uh
you know so this is
you know this tutorial is great i spent
like two years full time writing it and
here is the k move
k 61 keyboard we talked about earlier
fantastic okay
so
uh so
yeah so my you know and golan is my
favorite language
kind of
you know favorite industrial language
powershell is also great powershell is a
magnitude better than bash
you know that
better than the unix xiao crab that is
30 years of baggage
xiao ti xiao xi xiao tc xiao
but you know in the beginning it's a
boon xiao esseg bon xiao then bash boom
again xiao then seashell
trying to make xiao into the c language
syntax because c and unix they piggyback
on each other they are the virus you
know the seashell then c shell is crap
then someone created tc shell which is
improvement of the seashell
bash boom again xiao is improvement of
the boom shell sh you know the original
then you know the a bunch of shells then
you have scheme shell s sc essential you
know a bunch of power shell it's a
magnitude better than all of them
you know from
from a design point of view from the
language programming language design
point of view and from the power point
of view you know what it can do
and and from from many aspects from the
documentation aspect the powershell
documentation is far more superior than
the bash crap the unix [ __ ]
okay powershell in every aspect
powershell is superior okay
i know many of you the linux
idiots they're gonna say oh but you are
wrong
sometimes i get some people linux from
unix phonetics you know they watch my
video then they they came upon a passage
where i
say the unix are idiots you know the
unix operating system are idiocy extreme
they they are surprised okay you lost
all credibility
[Laughter]
no no you haven't watched enough of my
videos let it you know let it get into
your mind let it absorb
listen to what i say carefully okay
so powershell is the magnitude beyond
you know the bashcraft
powershot you know in just about every
aspect okay every every aspect
powershell and now it's open source it's
microsoft open source
the greatest contribution to open source
by lines of code by number project
microsoft thank you microsoft
great great
peeler of humanity the ethical quality
of microsoft even richard stowman you
know stand in microsoft's of microsoft
buildings standing in microsoft podium
talking about microsoft yeah that
happened two years ago
i have article on that
okay i'm gonna start wufam language i
guess
so there's a question would you suggest
using powershell in linux i'm one of the
no you are not okay so with that well
you see
when you decide on a language you know
there are quite a few aspects
now
like
what i said before powershell from a
technology from a technical point of
view
is the magnitude better than bash
okay or tc xiao okay
you know or z
is one of the shout outs you have lots
of fans z-sharp you know these are all
to me because i'm old i'm 50 something
so like 20 years ago 30 years ago you
know i'm
i'm immersed into this debate about
shells you know today most you know you
guys rumors don't know what what do you
what the [ __ ] is seashell you never
heard of what is tc show you've never
heard of oh oh z xiao you just heard of
because because apple switched to
z-shock you know anyway so i'm old
so anyway so i was saying so the
question you know should you use
powershell on linux
so first of all
i say that powershell from a tech from a
design point of view from the power from
the documentation it's
far more superior than bash
but however on linux on linux should you
use powershell i mean it's open source
okay
my answer is that nah that depends okay
here's an interesting part why
because you know if you think powershell
is so great technically speaking
why is it not wait how come you don't
recommend powershell on linux well the
reason is
you see linux is a
operating operating system right
basically the point is that
typically
on a certain operating system or
platform
you want to go native okay you want to
use whatever technology that's native on
that platform and that has a significant
advantage okay that is my reason
okay so
powershell even though it's great but if
you are on you on linux
you are run into so this is a social
aspect
this is kind of social not technical
technically powershell is superior than
bash period okay period
better documentation better you know
power better flexibility better than
bash period the [ __ ] idiotic [ __ ]
[ __ ] unix
bash you know
those of you unix phonetics or linux
phonetics window tiny managers you're
gonna object you know shut the [ __ ] up
you don't know nothing
so powershell is technically far
superior
than bash okay however there's a
there's also social reasons you need to
consider when we when you make a choice
you know of a tool
so what is the social reason because on
you
you you in general you want to use a
technology that's native on the platform
why is that why is that because for
example on linux we use when you know on
linux powershell is not installed it's
not installed man
so
whenever you write something in in
powershell other people cannot use it
you have to tell them to install it
that's extra that's extra complexity
okay they'd rather just start you know
just tell them to type something they
can use right away
so that's a one that's a problem that's
a reason there's a reason there's a
social reason
why
something is technically superior but
there are reasons sometimes you don't
want to use it okay that's one of the
reason
social reason okay
powershell is not installed on linux
it's one one of this isn't this more
so so just like emacs you know emacs is
not installed on linux neither most of
the time that's why there are so many
veeam users you know veeam users
because emacs is not installed it takes
extra step to install it
with that it comes complexities but
because for example oh but how do you
install it oh there are different
choices or you can install by re you
know linux you know the
the ubuntu package system there's then
then on on arc linux or different linux
there's different you know package
system uh nyx os there's another
different package system and then
there's a small complexity because some
of the package systems they don't use
the latest version of emacs
emacs 28 fantastic is released this
month but
in april but many of the packages on you
know ubuntu package or red hat package
they are not updated yet so this is
complexity or then you know that's one
of the reason
so
back to the question so that's why
um usually it's better it's it's there's
a significant
uh advantage when you stick with
whatever that's native you want to use
the native technology so
on linux the native technology is bash
okay
you know so you might you know so that's
the reason you might to consider not
using powershell
so it then so but which one should you
choose then it depends on lots of things
what's your situation if you all you do
is gonna just for yourself
then you might take the trouble to
install install powershell and and
master it
you know so you can have use the same
language on mac or on windows
or on linux
but you see the thing is on the mac the
default shell is tc shell i mean it's z
shell today
you know so it's not bash
so on linux you might use smash but on
the mac
you might use
you know you might stick with
z shell
they are mostly compatible not but not
exactly you know so this is you know
complexities
okay
[Music]
so there's a question why is powershell
better i did a video before
but people don't you know people don't
look into these things in depth
you know like the question gonna come
up over and over again i'm gonna answer
today
by next week somebody will ask me what
do you think what do you think
powershell is better you know
so i'm gonna do it all over again so
there it is you see that link why
powershell why i love powershell here's
a reason okay so you can read that okay
i'm gonna not gonna explain it
today
fantastic thank you reaper reaper has
been
great guy you know reaper has been my
loyal supporter
thank you for the donation so reaper's
question what should javascript or php
borrow from wolf and regular expression
to make regular expression better okay
that's
yeah that's a good question um that
question takes
some time to explain let's see
okay i almost already talked for one
hour
so you know that question is what i'm
supposed to do today
let's see where is my um
wufang language you know uh so i'm
supposed to talk about tutorial in
coding of woof and language on string
text processing which will include you
know i'm gonna
i was going to cover regular expressions
the
yeah okay so
god
okay let's talk about that yeah so
so the question is what what should
javascript or php borrow from wolfram
regular expression to make regular
expression better okay so
you know we talked about uh on discord a
little bit on about that so
but in order to expand them so everyone
understand it it'll take some time so
the thing so
okay let me let me let me do okay
so regular expression first of all you
have regular exp so yeah so let me
answer that question for 10 10 or 15
minutes and that's it for today thank
you
reaper and thank you guys
so
first of all you have regular
expressions so let me show you so you go
to casa di
uh okay let's go to sally info let's go
to the topic search again
because i'm going to show you my index
of all my articles about regular
expression i have like written
40 articles
r-e-g-e-x
okay
so there's 37 results
python regular expression
extraterrestrial on regular expression
wolfram language
regular expression okay
powershell regular expression reference
per regular expression so but there's an
index okay so let me go to it
uh where's my index
per regular expression okay so yeah let
me answer that question and that will be
it today
e max list regular expression uh closure
regular expression regular expression
limits or should you read mastering
regular expression
javascript
expression 10 articles
uh
how to improve python doc okay
yeah yeah
why is it not uh okay so you type
instead of rejects type regular
quite a few articles and here's a great
article this is 20 years old let me show
you that
pearl doctored
idia
zahariavic regularly expresses this is
this is this is article from year 2000
by this guy
very famous
programmer
he
excuse me
so he is a
you know this is 20 years ago so he was
very famous back then he
wrote
much of the regular expression feature
in pearl and perl is the language 20
years ago it makes it made regular
expression popular among programming
languages
okay so anyway let's get back to focus
okay where is my article there it is a
regular expression article index so
here's a collection of all my articles
related to regular expression okay
so what i want to say is so most of you
are probably familiar with regular
expressions so let me show you some um
let's go to my javascript regular
expression
so javascript regular expression syntax
so what is regular expression well it's
a
it's a it's it's kind of it's a syntax
it's a little language it's a syntax
that represent a string pattern you know
you you most of you probably already
know so here's an example of javascript
regular expression syntax okay now
regular expression syntax is similar to
it's similar in
most industrial languages so you have
javascript python
so for example here's the actual code so
so if if this is the text
okay let's magnify
yeah i cannot
so so for example this is a text and if
you want to extract email addresses from
a text file you use this pattern this is
regular expression that will
you know that will
match the that represent the pattern for
the email
uh
form so that's what you use regular
expression for you know very powerful
okay so
all these languages their regular
expression syntax are similar okay
all these javascript python go lan
regular expression here's the example
you want to extract certain things
uh email numbers or image tag or you
know for example in html you have image
tag anyway so you know what i mean
and emac okay
so the regular expression syntax are all
similar okay so
let me let me show you a um
let's see powershot where's where's my
powershell regular expression
oh i didn't include here what the yeah
anyway
uh let's go to emac this okay emacs
regular expression because i have kind
of a summary okay so here is a summary
of the regular expression syntax
patterns for example here's a
match one or more digits here's a match
one or more non-digit
you know here's match one or more
english alphabet letters you know and uh
and
and there's uh also you know repeat one
or more times repeat zero more times
repeat a pattern zero or one time
and so on you know that's regular
expression you know so this the syntax
is similar in all these languages
okay and the other the
so one of the thing people complain
about regular expression is that they
are hard to read let me show you example
um
info topic search so search for tooth
so you got bluetooth you got
emac this
toothpick syndrome
that's the one i want that's the one we
want
so you are looking at regular expression
in e max lisp you see
you see that thing that string that's a
regular expression what does that do
that's
that one tries to extract a link in html
file a link with images
a link
or images you know you need you want to
get the ui out of it so you are looking
at a
regular expression
in particular in the e-max least flavor
okay they are all similar but
imag this you know they are similar so
so one of the common complaint about
regular expression is unreadable okay so
like that
like what the you know like what the
[ __ ] you know what you know it's hard to
understand exactly what exactly is
trying to extract a pattern you know
and another problem is the toothpick
syndrome
like slash and backslash
going crazy
so we we have a world record here okay
look at look at these guys okay you
might this this is uh imac this
you know this is part of emacs i can
actually show you you know this is a sub
uh dot el i can show you the code but no
need to okay
so you know
screenshot is enough so you have the
toothpick syndrome
because you need to escape the you know
backslash is a escape you need another
backslash to escape the backslash and if
you want to knee
if you need to
for example if you need to match
the windows path okay
pwd
uh let's let's go to web okay cd web
okay
let's say emacs okay
uh okay so this uh you need to go to
saudi info
then ma emax okay so you see you started
to see lots of backslash so if you want
to
by the way windows also support slash
for the path separator directory
separator
but if you're gonna need to match this
so you're gonna have
backslash you need to escape it you're
gonna have backslash titus like that
okay
17 backslashes here now is that the
record i have uh
so there is a 17 backslash
and then then there is this is my own
code by the way this one
this is a package for bb
you know a bb code you know the php
php language markup very popular over
you know
in the year 2000s so you have backslash
and like that so anyway
the that's the
problem of regular expression people
complain very common
it's is unreadable okay unreadable and
backslash problem toothpick syndrome
this is known as
toothpick syndrome
okay
so
programmers including myself
20 years ago has been asking the
question
who who designed you know which idiot
designed a regular expression like that
can we
can't we just create a new like more
readable syntax
that is that is the question okay there
are two
two alternatives
one is wufam language
one is
emacs rx
package okay so
uh i don't have a code for emacs rx let
me let me show you okay
describe function rx okay there it is
that's the package okay there it is
so let's go to it so first of all read
the documentation
so it says rx is an auto loaded list
macro in this file okay so here's a
function rx rejects
okay translate regular
expressions in
symbolic
expression form to a regular expression
string so what it means is basically
it provides you
a alternative more readable syntax for
regular expression
so for example
for example in regular expression you
have the
vertical sign vertical symbol for
alternative you know either this or that
so in this package you can say
this syntax to represent it all
so basically
this package in emacs called rx
you can use it
it provides you with a easier to read
this style nested parenthesis this style
syntax for regular expression okay for
example um
so
yeah
now i need to you know i need to you
know i'm using soft fly keys so i need
to
turn on my caps lock
uh remap again so let's do that
so turn it on so first of all
make sure
it's off then turn it on
okay
okay so it provides a
easier to read
this style syntax for regular expression
okay
uh
i want to
what i don't i forgot the command name
uh there there
there it is i want to highlight the
current line okay so it provides a
alternative syntax more readable for
regular expression so that's one of the
solution and this exists in e-mail lisp
okay so if you code emac this you can
use that however it's you know so
basically this
the idea of a alternative alternative
syntax more readable
improvement syntax for regular
expression
is not is rare
so in e-max you have that but basically
that's it so as far as i know it doesn't
um
you know there's not many so
basically
you just learn regular expression and
you get used to it you know it's like
learning a new language you know
after a while
you start to get it um but still it's
difficult to read so
there's another alternative that is the
wufang language okay so where he said
let me show you
so rx is a alternative and wolfram
language is another alternative so
where is my language code
okay
yeah so wolfham language uh regular
expression so let me show you
string pad so this is a new article i
have written woofing language string
pattern okay
so in language you can have regular
expression like that that's a you know
that's how you do regular expression you
use you call the function
let me magnify okay you call the
function regular expression and inside
it you just give a regular expression
string
just like every other language's regular
expression okay very similar but however
wu wufram language provides you a
alternative
syntax
for regular expression okay first of all
let me let me let me show you this okay
so let's copy that
let's evaluate you know since we are
doing this
let's um
where is wufam language
okay
so here's a wolfram language and also i
want to show you
let's turn this into
you know
a mathematical format you know formatted
in a mathematical way
so you can see
so anyway so let's
let's evaluate that
okay
so now we let's new uh let's open the
new
what's
okay
then let's paste that
okay so here so here's a string string
cases is a function it takes a string
and it takes a pattern so the string is
like a
we have here a
you know a unicode and abc and here is a
pattern the second argument is the
pattern and we call the function regular
expression which is a
pattern in regular expression so a dot a
a dot in regular expression means any
character so if you just call that
it will return
that you know basically any one single
character it returns all the matches
that that's that you know one single
character so that's an example of
regular expression in wolfen language
okay
now wufang language provides a
alternative syntax
to represent string pattern okay and
that is called
string expression okay now i'm not going
to into detail but anyway
so here you are looking at
um
let's go to the wolfram website okay
uh where is it uh
[ __ ]
there
so here is the wolfram
website
and uh string expression so he
so this
this is a alternate alternative syntax
for regular expression okay so let's
magnify
so you can see
a single character in regular expression
is a dot but in wolfram you know a
string expression it's a underscore
it means any character okay now if you
want any character repeated one or more
times
that's two underscore
two low lines and if you wanted to
repeat zero or more characters it's
three underscores and you can this is
how you give a name to a pattern any
pattern
you know and
this is how you express alternative by
either using a list or by using a
vertical sign
so anyway so if you want to represent
white space you type that you know wipes
white space if you want to represent a
number you type that number string
you know so so this is kind this is the
alternative way alternative
syntax to represent a string pattern
and the power is pretty much similar to
regular expression except a few things
for example you see this any order
it allows you to represent the pattern
regardless of order
that you cannot do with regular
expression okay
now um
okay anyway so that's the point okay so
this string expression so let me um
like i have code i have showed the
example here
for example let's do the same thing in
wolfram language okay so for example
this one
so let's now paste it
you see
just these two are the same you know
string cases
this string and instead of regular
expression we use string expression now
let's evaluate it
okay you got the same result so you can
see it's a different um different
syntax for string patterns
and they are
almost the same i mean the power is
essentially the same but
wolfram language string expression is a
alternative way
to represent string pattern and in
general it's more readable okay
so let me summarize there are two
alternative regular expression syntax
that i know of one is in e-max
rx we talked about the other one is
rule-frame language
uh string expression okay
so we reaper's question about whether
they
you know what what should javascript or
php borrow from wolfram regular
expression so
basically
basically they don't want to basically
the you know javascript php or pearl
python basically the um
industrial coders
they
they do not need
they are you know usually for them
usually they
do not find a need to do so
it is true
that regular expression is a bit hard to
understand you know it's not as readable
but however
the industrial coders rather stick with
one just one similar you know one kind
of universal almost universal regular
expression syntax
that's that's what i believe okay
now
now you could of course you could
introduce the e max regular expression
you know rx
let's go to rx again
you know you you could introduce the you
know emax regular expression style or
the wolfram language regular expression
style by the way there's a comparison
here okay so here you can see the
comparison between the regular
expression
syntax on the left and the wolfram
string expression syntax on the right
uh in general the regular expression
version is more terse you know it's
cryptic but it's so it's more test while
the wolfram language
analog is more readable but
you have to type more or you have to use
completion so anyway i think the
industrial coders
they are not that much interested in a
alternative regular expression syntax
that's what i think so yeah
okay so that answers one part of the
question let me answer another question
which is more important i i think you
are asking so
when you think about regular expression
one aspect is the syntax okay
you know for example you want the more
readable
syntax okay so you have two alternatives
here
rx emax this rx or the wolfram language
string expression okay
two d you know two alternative syntax
for regular expression now the other
question is the power
of regular expression i mean so people
you know one of the
supposedly flaw of regular expression is
that you cannot use regular expression
to
match anything that can that that has
nested syntax okay
so for example let's go to my talk show
so here's a today's talk show
so you can see
uh the figure
you know that's
so you have the figure tag on our side
then you have the iframe you know nested
inside then you have also figure caption
nested inside so if we gonna show this
in browser
you know it's the youtube embedded
youtube so but anyway it's a nesting so
regular expression cannot
match nested patterns
you know you might see people
programmers blog about it it's like
almost like a revelation oh but oh you
know i just realized regular expression
cannot or sometimes you know
elite programmers they'll tell you
by the way regular expression cannot be
used for matching uh nested syntax you
know they they say that as if
it's a great new theory they they know
actually that's very silly because
regular expression
the origin of regular expression the
meaning that you know where does it came
from who created it who created the
concept of regular expression so the
regular expression background
excuse me the regular expression
background came from
theoretical computer science
of formal languages i talked about this
many times in my past video about proof
systems about proof systems so again
regular expression came from
theoretical computer science
they are trying to you know they you
know autonom automata
the science automation let me let me
random let me um
sorry info
go to topic search
a u t o m a t
automata okay so m-m-m-m-a-t-a
okay so
eight results
so you you know i did a lot
i did several videos on game of life
cellular automata
uh and universal machine europa and bull
greek auto okay so
okay i'm digressing over um
there
the jargon of automata in finite state
automata okay this is very interesting
the
origin of the jargon automata it can't
it came from 2000 years ago greek
greek the zeus the god of the zeus who
[ __ ] every woman
you know and he
you know so it
it came from
the
um the myth of the
uh god so i'm gonna talk for hours on
this i haven't get to my point are you
still here ripper
so i was going to talk about the
semantics of regular expression the
power of regular expression but we got
digressed into the
arrangement of regular expression then
digression into the jargon the origin of
the jargon automata
so i want to so let's just talk okay
talk show
europa and the bull
okay
so europa and the group the bull the
great
greek mythology the origin of western
society
europa that's the name of europe came
from
what is europa she
this beautiful girl that's europa
she got abducted by zeus the god of all
gods the most powerful god zeus
and who [ __ ] every every
woman
so zeus
raped you know that's how they say raped
or or um
um you know the europa because she's
beautiful so so zeus the great the
powerful zeus
the father of oh gods you know he
he changed himself into a beautiful
white bull to
what's the word um
seduce yeah he's you know you can say
rape or seduce you know that's that's
how human women and men relations are
you know you can call it rape or you can
call it seduce you know
a little bit you know i'm not going to
get into that
but
the zeros see you know change himself
into a white ball look at that
so that he can seduce this girl
beautiful girl and
she once she hopped onto it the z zeus
just ran it just ran off you know
there's a great poetry written about it
and great artwork so for example this
thing 460 bc so
2500 years ago
okay and here's the europa celebrating
you know the
europe
okay
you know the modern malaysian zuma's
idiot [ __ ] don't know nothing they just
know about memes means but you don't see
pepe you know pepe and memes and
whatever in social justice warriors but
you don't see this kind of um
this this is this this is this is me
okay this is the
this is the ancient
the real me
and look at this uh this
thanks to frenzy
our illustrious illustrious members in
our inside discord thank thank him for
this photo
that's that's europa that's the ball
that's yours okay
you know in europe you have this kind of
thing in america no how can you do that
the cultural differences you know in
europe what ways is brussels belgium you
have this sculpture under broad daylight
in a translation
you know you have this
this bdsm style europa and the pool
you know that's europe okay
so
so what does this have to do with
regular expression well
zeros
seduce seduced europa took her away
then they had three children okay
great story you know you can read it for
hours
and zeus
gave her three gifts
three gifts
one is a giant automata what is this
thing you know that's the automata okay
so let's go back to this thing
so what in in zuma in today melania and
zuma's jargon that's called the mecca
okay that's called the mecca okay a
giant robot that protector
you know it's a
robot
so that's one of the gift
zeros gave to europa
and uh and there are two other gifts one
is a javelin that we will never miss
and another
gift is a hound dog
yeah so anyway so you can read the
details you know
so
so what does this relates to regular
expression well the automata that's
where so automata
it means a robot okay or a mecca okay a
robot a mechanical algorithmically
controlled thing
so you know back in 2000 years ago
mythology greek mythology
algorithmic
algorithmically controlled robot okay
and the word automata
became
a thing in computer science machine
it means machine okay so it
you know you you computer science today
you know in the past 100 years we
started to have computers and
we study autonomy you know so we
borrowed the name automata
to mean
a self-functioning machine a machine
that works by algorithm you just
you know the cams and your your your run
okay by itself
by algorithm so that's a term that came
into computer science automata you can
look up on wikipedia
so let's look up on wikipedia
okay that's a movie we don't want we
don't want the new generation movie [ __ ]
you know the male engine whatever
an engine zone [ __ ] so let's go to
automata so automata theory
tutorial point a scum site you know the
commercial you know cheap
mostly you know lots of incorrect you
know
for money
tutorial
[ __ ]
if you want to read the tutorial read my
we read my page there it is okay
automatize theory okay
automatic theory is a study of abstract
machines and automata okay let's click
on automata okay there it is the origin
of tom automata
automata or an automaton
plural automata is a relatively self
operating machine or control mechanism
designed to automatically follow a
sequence of operations okay so then the
you have automatic theory you know
computer uh theoretical computer science
okay so we have some examples of of
automata and the earliest of the
earliest uh 2000 years ago
this uh anti-kether
mechanism you know very elaborate clock
and a strong astronomical um
thing
uh analog computer okay 2000 years old
you know automata so automata became
originally it was mythology you know
it's so it got borrowed into computer
science okay meaning a machine
um
okay so then
then we are back to
so so then regular expression
uh where is it
the regular expression is about automata
okay so um
so in automatic theoretical computer
science you have nfa and dfa
dfa means deterministic finite automata
now what are those things those those
things are the
they they are tied to regular
expressions okay but anyway so the
original vertical illustration is came
from formal languages
and they it's a way to pass a class of
language called regular languages and
what is a regular language a regulatory
is language basically a sequence of
symbols such that there's no nesting
okay that's a key point
what is a regular language a regular
language
is a
is a sequence of
symbols that does not involve any
nesting
the grammar does not have any uh nesting
okay that's regular language so regular
used is not for the purpose of matching
nested um
syntax okay that's that's the point
okay that's it for today i guess we
talked about 90 minutes now
so is my answer satisfactory do you have
any further questions ripper so so on
the question you know why can't we
create a regular expression you know
tool that
um does
you know that that allows you that for
example uh html or emac this code that
involves involves lots of nesting even
c code c plus plus java you know you
have the braces curly braces sometimes
you need to match them you know
you want to find for example inner
functions defined inside the function so
you want to find the curly braces inside
the curly braces you cannot do that with
regular expression so the question is
why can't we can we have a tool that
actually do that
you know just like regular situations so
you can easily
you know pass nested thing
well the thing is no it doesn't you know
well the the the thing is it already
exists it's called grammar okay
it's called passing expression grammar
it's called
let me let me go to it
study.info
search
type grammar
and there it is
formal grammar formal language grammar
passa ambiguous grammar so you go to
formal grammar okay so let's shrink a
little bit let's magnify okay formal
grammar so click on that so here's my
uh kind of tutorial kind of incomplete i
was trying to study
i was trying to write a compiler before
you write a compiler you have to write
the password now before you write the
password you have to understand grammar
okay formal grammar form
why formal because it's formal language
it's part of the study of formal
language so you started to get into
these topics
because you know formal grammar
hierarchy
so you have um anyway so
so for more grammar so let me talk about
formal grammar from a grammar
here
bnf okay it's usually written in a
syntax b and f called bacchus norm form
and
several other variations e b and f and a
b and f okay so here is an example
of formal grammar
so
so in short if you want a regular
expression
that can that can that can match
nested patterns
that's what they are this that this is
what you have bnf
bacchus known for okay syntax to match
postal
address okay uh like usa yeah usa street
address
you write it this way okay and basically
all programming languages has a grammar
like that okay you space