good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of guitar talk show and we are
going to do lots of
fantastic stuff formatting automatic
formatting all you needs to know about
formatting okay all you need to know we
are going to code I'm going to so the
the this talk show is going to be two
parts the first part is that I'm going
to demonstrate
several languages JavaScript Python
wolfam language lisp
Golan where you can automatically format
your code okay automatically not line by
line or manually automatically format
the whole code in your entire directory
okay and I'm going to show you
demonstrate emacs integration and I'm
going to show you show you the emac this
code so you can get it and if you are a
emacs user you can use it right away so
audio check video check am I um
so yeah so that's the first 20 minutes
or 30 minutes of this talk okay I'm
gonna demonstrate the Practical all
these practical stuff JavaScript
Powershell and Powershell and Golan in
Python and the uh and the emac beasts
okay automatic formatting okay then I'm
going to demonstrate um
you know the formatting code is very
interesting because it involves a
designing of the syntax language design
language syntax design okay so I'm going
to demonstrate wufam language where you
can have automatic not just automatic
formatting but you can have formatting
in real time
okay and and that requires
to have that that requires some some
particular design of the programming
language syntax and I'm going to tell
you the languages has that property is
is
um so you can see automatic you see
automatic real-time Auto formatting I'm
gonna explain that and the the language
that has that property include this in
general who found language which is a
lisp and HTML XML fantastic and APL okay
so in order to have this feature
automatic formatting but in real time
you your programming language
essentially
has one simple requirement and that
requirement is that
you're the the
End of Line character must have no
significance okay so which is not true
in a lot of languages especially
involving semicolon for example or
basically or C derived languages you
know it's it's crap okay so let's start
the Practical demonstration okay so if
you are a keyboard you know ergonomic
keyboard fan
uh I'm using hello guys so I'm using you
know just search for sorry keyboard you
can see so this is kinesis Advantage
keyboard which is this one and by the
way the the new one comes up I'm gonna
show you in a minute okay so this is
kinesis advantage and on top here is
Ultimate hacking so you can look at my
reviews and
stuff I recommend you buy Kinesis
Advantage okay and Kinesis Advantage
they they uh they have a new version
Kinesis Advantage 360 okay
um I posted somewhere let's see tweets
and reply I
let me show you okay Kinesis advantage
360.
I retreated their post
up there okay so there it is so this is
new
it came out but very expensive 400 about
you know 400 450 dollars
so you know I would like I recommend
this one you know that that one is
pretty good as well
so okay so about keyboard and I'm using
some fly keys and you can see all my
command cores and keystrokes in the pink
window over here and let's turn on the
Highlight current line so you can see
okay let's begin to demo demo about this
uh automatic formatting okay so here is
today's talk show page uh so first stop
I'm going to demo JavaScript okay
JavaScript let's you know
JavaScript language sucks sorry dot info
go to exactly done info and click on
topic search
you can see I have my JavaScript
tutorial here
JavaScript in depth click on search and
let's search for array or turn
JavaScript
turn on JavaScript so you can search now
array
generate uh
range function you know JavaScript to
this state do not have one single range
function that generates an array you
have you resort to lots of tricks you
know very annoying so anyway here's the
JavaScript code copy it
so let's demo okay JavaScript so I'm
going to create JavaScript
um paste it here and I'm using some flag
Keys you see it's a model just like Vim
but more efficient there's no control
you know I don't have to press Ctrl key
to manipulate my cursor and stuff for
example delete undo and so on so anyway
here's the JavaScript code and start
range so let's uh let's run console log
okay Cloud range and the minimum let's
say 5 to 20 in step one run it so there
is the result okay
I'm using dental you see I'm using
JavaScript mod it's all so you can see
um
anyway so I'm using it so you can see
this code runs now I want to reformat it
so when I write the code it's not
formatted like that so suppose I press
one single key to compact file it you
see one single line run it works still
works beautifully because I use the same
icon you know anyway so
so now you see when I write the code you
know it's not well formatted you know
let's say I add a intent you know show
white space you see there's a tab you
know whatever so I want to reformat the
whole file you know it works for if even
if you have like 2000 lines of file
that's 2009 so I press the key
in my case so JavaScript mod press the
key band
it's all formatted for you one single
key the whole page the entire page
instead of the typical you know uh
programming style guide oh you need to
tap you know type versus that's idiot
idiot the idiot Unix Linux edsc for 20
years but now it's beginning about 10
years ago Golan Golan is the first one
that started this trend of automatic
formatting I'm gonna show you I wrote an
article
like uh like 14 years ago about this
automatic formatting okay I'm gonna
explain so so first so so you see undo
let's see undo
you see
press one single key
format the whole file okay that's
automatic formatting now the command I'm
calling is this one search JavaScript
format code Okay so
let's look at the source code
so this is so jump let's you know so
this is such JavaScript format code and
let's jump to the source code so here is
the Emax integration so it is actually
calling the demo format okay here's the
command demo format
fmt then the final name okay that's the
actual command that does it
so okay close that uh so
wait
so let's uh let's put it in my talk show
so you can see it
so go back to talk show today's talk
show
um
this page and I'm going to so here is
the command Dental format Dino is the
best JavaScript compiler okay and it
also compiles typescript so use it okay
as opposed to not JS you know it's
created by the same guy that's a
fantastic guy and ethical you know I
highly recommend it it's fantastic tool
and the guy is great as
opposed to not JS the guy you know
what's his name he created not JS like
10 years ago but not just became uh you
know led by someone else in corrupt crap
npm you know garbage trash so they know
I highly recommend it download dental
and dental format and can do it okay
so this is so I'm doing this in emacs so
let's put the code here so I have I have
a lot to uh talk about so I'm going to
um go fast okay so emac this code so
here you have the emacs this this code
okay and that's part of JavaScript mod
okay if you like my stuff
pay me okay
so let's paste the JavaScript mod there
so you have a link so you can go to it
open it show in browser JavaScript mod
so if if you don't want to spend time to
you know grab the code put in your emacs
in it you can just
pay me you know that you are paying for
as a donation because I cannot make
money with uh you know open source you
know because some you know it's open
source so once you get it you you can
sell it you know that's that's nothing I
can do but it's anyway it's open source
email address okay so
JavaScript mod so close that and here is
the um let's do it again okay
press the key format the whole code
beautiful okay and now put it back to uh
to here HTML and show in browser so you
can see we have the JavaScript code here
and here is the emac this code that
calls Daniel format okay and let's
make them syntax color back to the
browser show again so you can see it's
syntax colored
so anyway so the JavaScript code so
that's a demonstration okay we
demonstrated JavaScript Auto formatting
using this code range function for array
and we demonstrate the emacs integration
demonstrate demonstration okay and we
showed the emac this code you can grab
it put in your emacs init file then you
can have the same feature instead of
instead of instead of going to Shell and
type then no format in the current file
name you know
so
so that's a demonstration of the auto
formatting of the for JavaScript okay
next we are going to demonstrate
Powershell Golan python for each one of
them I have a emacs wrapper so you can
call them in emacs Easy A C code you
don't have to never ever you know when
you code never ever like oh you know
type a tab you know a line you know yeah
you know when you coat never you know
never ever type A type a lion you know
crap that's idiocy idiocy by the Unix
Linux C type of people for for the past
uh 20 years they don't listen they
didn't they don't have a brain
okay so so so okay let's let's you see I
screwed up so press the key reformat the
whole thing and now pop it back to a
HTML page okay so actually we don't need
this because the code is already
um
in this link okay range function to
generate array for JavaScript
okay so that's JavaScript let's go
through the next uh the next one
okay Powershell now Powershell doesn't
have a build in formatting tool so what
you have to do is that let me
demonstrate it first okay so you go to
uh let's go to Powershell
so go to Casa code in topic search
power shell okay why I love Powershell
so let's go to Powershell uh tutorial
and go down you'll see
Dark theme okay so here's a code let's
copy it
so this so let's let's come let's do it
okay so Powershell where is Powershell
here so
start a Powershell code block okay
here's a code pop it to its own window
okay and here's the code so let's first
of all let's screw up the code it right
now it's well formatted okay so let's
screw it up so let's see if I can
you know make them one lie make them
this one line two okay so now I press a
key a single key pen fantastic it's
indestructible you know it's like a book
technology it fixes it itself you know
it fixes yours itself
so but but let me demonstrate the code
what the code does okay so because this
is fun uh this is a fun thing to use so
let's remove the comment okay let's
remove the comment in fact
put the whole code into one line let's
see if that works okay copy it now go to
Powershell there it is you are looking
at the Powershell technology which is
far superior than bash the 30 years 40
years crap baggage Unix baggage okay so
paste this function name
does it work let's try it okay what
oh okay I need I missed the semicolon
that's why you don't want the
yeah so you always always have semicolon
you know same like why because you know
this is an important issue I'll talk
about when you when you're programming
language syntax
when your programming language syntax is
such a way that a physical hard wrapped
formatting
has meaning to the language then it will
screw up automatic formatting that means
you cannot
doesn't matter how complex the tool it
is impossible basically almost
impossible to Auto format it okay so
when you are designing a programming
language you know for the past 20 years
this c c syntax based idiocy you know
none of them do that so you want to make
sure that the physical you know you want
me to make sure that your source code is
not dependent dependent on hard
formatting okay such as a physical line
return okay so for example now I I put a
semicolon
and now I make the whole whole thing one
line by the way
the common syntax is also usually
dependent you know the line based
comment is dependent on the uh hard
physical line return you don't want that
okay so rather you you you want a common
syntax such that
such that it is independent of the hard
wrap that way you can you can
automatically format it and display it
in arbitrary ways you want you know like
narrow or wide you know mechanic
mechanically without manual you know so
you don't want you don't want syntax
that dependent that that depends on a
physical line return okay that's one of
the things you want to uh if you want
automatic formatting okay so now we
remove those comments and make let's
make the whole thing
one single line okay now back to
Powershell
paste it okay function in one single
line fantastic okay
now let me demonstrate so now I type SAR
toggle
toggle dog theme
you see now my website is dark
Dark
theme okay fantastic functionality
so Tonka Dark theme again back to White
by the way dark dark theme is a fad okay
it actually it's
it's harder to read it's more hard
scientifically speaking it it's harder
to read you want a white because I I
actually tried it for three months using
that thing
so and uh okay anyway so let's move on
so
so I we have demonstrated so let's let's
do it again okay so now Powershell we
want to reformat it okay so
uh the keys this one do it I doesn't do
it okay so you see
now this Auto format you know why does
it not work because in the Powershell
case the auto formatter does not work
it does not go all the way it does not
reformat your code entirely you know
this is critical you know
starting with Golan about 2010 you know
they they started to have the concept
where of Auto automatic formatting where
it does not matter it doesn't matter how
your source code looks
after you call the tool it will just
reformat your entire code okay
now before that before 2010 most tools
you know it's called linked or what you
know you know the you know edius edsc
that's extreme immediacy what they do is
that they help you format you know they
make some suggestions suggestions so
they change something but they actually
don't they don't actually reformat your
code that's what you want you want to
you you want the tool that reformat your
code without human interaction just do
it you know whole shot now in the case
of Powershell the tool doesn't uh do
that when you know
so that's a floor Powershell
okay so like if your whole function is
one line
it will not
um reformat it okay that's you know
you know it doesn't for example it will
form reformatted but not not in one
canonical way for example we added a lot
of spaces here for example space then
you can
it'll remove those spaces but you know
this one single line is no good so
anyway that's a problem with Powershell
okay so uh so this is um so let's go
back so let's
pop it back to um
to the HTML showing browser so you can
see here's a Powershell code let's
syntax color it
refresh so you can see here's a
Powershell code okay Powershell code
toggle Dark theme okay
now
now in order to let me show you the emac
source code Okay so
so emacs source code so the source code
is
okay here it is Powershell mod and
here's a source code because some
Powershell format code okay so let's
copy it uh let's copy it and let's
um
let's go to talk show
okay so uh yeah today's talk show there
and let's put it here Powershell
so create a new emac list block of code
paste it there
so that's the emac this code to allows
you to reformat Powershell in your
buffer and you need this tool okay so
you need
you need actually okay let me show you
where to get it okay so you go to
Powershell
uh you know Max search for xrd
Powershell tutorial and at the bottom or
just use a search function at the bottom
you will see
pretty for men okay so in order to have
the pretty format tool you need to
download this
Powershell script analyzer okay once you
download that then you know you can down
you can install it by this line okay
once you do that then you need this
function okay so this function sub
format Powershell script okay so grab it
okay so once you have that then you can
call
format Powershell script and Powershell
script name okay
and then if you want to have emacs
integration you
where's my emacs source code
and do I have it here
okay so let's uh yeah so if you want
emacs integration yeah so refresh then
here's the code okay let's
uh sync color syntax syntax color it so
you need this code
okay that's demonstration of Powershell
okay and then again pay me okay so here
is Powershell mod
um
so here is the Powershell some power
Xiao mod okay
so you can open it show in browser so
everything integrated so you don't have
to nothing do nothing okay so power
Sharma for emacs
open it close that open it okay so we
demonstrated JavaScript we demonstrated
um Powershell Auto formatting now
let's demonstrate now this code we don't
need because that's already
um
so let's clean up a little bit okay so
we don't need that refresh okay so
here's the Emax code now let's move on
to Golan okay Golan is fantastic so how
are you doing so how are you guys
um
yeah today is the change of time you
know I haven't done a live stream
uh at this time for a long time for over
a year now uh so we went over 25 minutes
God I have a lot to do so we need to do
Golan then I'm going to demonstrate
python then I'm going to demonstrate
emac this emac this is problematic you
know very sad situation because lisp the
language the syntax at least has the
best property for automatic formatting
but the the at least idiots the emac
these idiots you know they they they
talk about oh you your lie must not be
longer than 80 characters you know they
focus on oh your parenthesis you must
tuck them in those idiots and they they
write guide they write you know
programming style guide you know for
emac this for example there's a bats bad
slow guy you know a big guy in emacs
community he write a lot you know
programming language style guide this is
community based you know I did tell you
to manually you know how you should
format your idiocy because the
more you spread the more you spread on
the on the on the manual formatting of
code the less the less likely the
automatic formatting concept will spread
okay
but today it's spread pretty pretty uh
fine finally finally thanks to Golan
around 2010 you know go format okay go
line is the first one that created that
that spread the concept of automatic
code formatting so you don't you don't
even need formatting style guide anymore
read it once for no arguments you know
so every every language source code you
see will look the same okay that's
actually a good idea you know if you
don't like the language don't use it you
know it's don't debate about how you
should format you know you know that's a
idiocy spread by the C and Unix
for for more than 20 years you
know like every time you talk to them
they don't they don't understand they
don't they don't get it you know because
Unix my last video about 10 days ago I
talk about the Unix line truncation
because of that the Unix code they
brainwashed people so that all these
languages the programmers you know they
you know this uh Elite programmers
hacker types you know they go to
um they go to The Hacker News every day
or slash start you know 20 years ago
they they think they are the you know
God or priest they tell you what to do
but but some basic ideas they they don't
know okay Auto automatic formatting
begin
Golan go format is the first one that
actually started to spread the idea the
idea exists in ufam language like
20 years ago okay 20 years ago I'm gonna
demo demo okay this it's far it's far
more advanced than all of these Auto
format okay so so so next one okay so we
done JavaScript we done Powershell so
next let's demonstrate
um go land okay Gola is the language
that began this
okay so um go then okay so let's go land
so so
um
okay so first of all let's find the
Golan script to demonstrate it okay so
you go to
Sally info
search
Colin okay uh so we have a goal line
fine string which is equivalent to grab
and we also have a
goal line script to to find and replace
multiple pairs in one shot of regular
expression in a whole directory so here
is a code okay
so here is the code so let's let's put
it um
uh Golan so Golan so we're gonna do
Golan there so code link uh link Phi
make a list okay so Golan
okay that's script we're gonna
demonstrate oh I already I already have
a link
okay so now let's copy the code okay so
here's the Golan
okay so this code will do find and
replace in a directory
uh okay let's do it here so okay go land
let's start a new code block Golan there
show the pink window
paste the code
pop it to its own window there it is
here's the Golan script and now let's
demonstrate let's run this script Okay
so
now I'm not gonna demonstrate the script
let's just demonstrate the auto format
okay so let's you see this let's make
them one line okay one single line okay
and you see this you know you don't you
can have
you see again here is a comment line
based comment that relies on the
physical Hardline wrap that's no good
because if you have that situation and
if you make it one single line then the
whole thing becomes a comment so that's
no good so you don't so as a if you are
designing a language you don't want the
syntax that depends on physical line
return okay so but if we remove that
comment okay now you know now you can
okay
wait uh oh God again you need semicolon
okay so let me show you okay so again
you need semicolon otherwise the code
won't
uh not semicolon you need
and
you need a constant okay
what I I hate I hate this this uh syntax
of constant
I think you need uh there
anyway let's call the command to
reformat it okay so you can see uh this
this is wrong too actually
ah go land so what is so let's look at
the tutorial Golan Imports so import or
semicolon okay so you need actually
semicolon otherwise single line is
invalid
so you don't want that okay remember you
don't want if you if your programming
language syntax relies on the
on on a hot you know uh
line return then it's no good okay but
now this works okay let's reformat let's
just do it
okay press the key
okay oh God
so I think this instead of a comma you
need a semicolon
okay so let's try that again
reformat you see
you see fantastic okay undo you see
before let me make them you see before
this is one line and let's make this one
single line two okay now let's reformat
the whole file okay
do it you see fantastic
okay same thing same thing you know if
you are you know it will just reformat
the whole thing okay for example
okay we we made some changes and do it
let's do it you know
fantastic okay so you can see that
command we called is the
Circle format buffer so let's show the
let's show the um the emac this code
okay
Okay so
uh so the Emax list code that's tab F so
that's this command Circle format buffer
let's jump to the source code
here is a code okay close it
um let's put it in in our talk show
create a new block of emac this code
paste it here there is there it is so
you can put this in your init file then
you have the same feature and but so by
the way it's calling the command go
format okay go format okay that's part
of the golang when you download goal
lines part of it okay
so now
yeah so now we have demonstrated this uh
let's pop this back
to the HTML page and we don't need it
because the file is already here the
goal line go land
script to find replace multiple pairs
not just one by regular expression in a
whole directory so you you know you grab
it okay this is better than
better than the what the what grip
silver Arc beep grab you know rip grab
you know last week about a week or two
ago we you know I had a discussion with
you guys Scott who is posting
memes
so we have a discussion about rip grip
it turns out rip grip the guy he's a
rust you know the Ross phonetic
but he has some kind of a idiosyncratic
resistance to make the rib grab to
replace you know he refused
to add that feature you know so it's
purely for finding files you cannot
replace then you know and that's not too
useful
you want to be able to replace so you
can use this goal line script that will
do replacement not just one and also
there's a feature it's not line based
you know all these scraps set all the
Unix tools website org they are line
based so if you want to find you know
all your files involving these multiple
lines and replace them by something else
they cannot do it because they only do
one line at a time they cannot they are
unable to detect multiple lines you know
that's no good so my script does it okay
so that's score line go go line go
language uh script okay so uh so next so
let's go on so we demonstrated emacs
integration we uh showed emac this code
so where is the emac this code it is
there let's syntax color it
refresh there it is emac this code and
uh and we show the go format command
okay go land Rob Pike is a guy who did
it great fantastic finally
he's he Cola is the first one to let me
emphasize because I this I had this
issue you know since like 20 years ago
since about
1998. you know in because I called
wolfam language for 10 years you know so
I'm familiar with you know
let me let me jump ahead and do wolf and
demo okay so let me jump ahead and show
you what what is this uh automatic
formatting because I'm so used it I'm so
used to it then I started to code in
Unix you know Pearl
Pearl then python then PHP you know all
these industrial languages and plus C
and Java
but then I you know then I'm exposed
into a world where this concept is
foreign to them this automatic
formatting in real time not you know so
far we demonstrated automatic formatting
of the whole file but not in real time
you know what I mean by real times let
me show you okay so first of all open a
woofam language so let me show you you
see so you are so you see this line is
long right
now if you shrink the window
can you see that it automatically
formatted I mean now it becomes three
lines you see
so that is the version that's the most
simple version of all of the concept of
automatic formatting in real time okay
get it you Unix Linux idiots you know
for 20 years they they cannot fathom
they don't understand this is the most
simple concept of automatic formatting
in real time all the other very basic
one all it does is it is formatting the
you know
depending on your window size it auto
format this line okay this is the most
basic version
and this is real time okay
and this is not adding you know
physically adding a line return that's
not you know that's not that's not it
okay so if you don't know what you know
I talked about the line truncation
problem in my last video like uh 10 days
ago
so okay so so so let me demonstrate
wufam language in uh the automatic
formatting
not just in real time but complicated
typeset math formulas okay let me show
you show you
so expand so x squared okay x squared
plus
2 y x third power divided by square root
X plus one okay then the whole thing to
the third power evaluated okay you see
that
let's make it to the ninth power so we
got a long thing okay
now let's magnify okay so this this is
typeset okay now you can see the
automatic let me show you okay
in in real time you know I um
you see come you know this
so you can see this wow this is a two
simple example because every term is
like just nice but
but the point is that it can format
arbitrarily uh nested you know and and
not just
uh okay let me let me let me pick a a
different uh example to demonstrate the
real-time automatic formatting okay and
by the way it's in real time like a zoo
type um
Azure type you know
so we haven't I haven't demonstrate you
see
this is also real real time you see when
you when your window is narrow you can
see you see those intents that's
automatic
you see visual indentation automatically
done does does not this doesn't matter
how complicated your code is here is
your source code you see that that's
your source code okay
now when you narrow you look look you
know it indents them and it understands
the
syntactical unit you know it doesn't
just indent them randomly you see you
see that square root you see this square
root it indent them you know it keeps
this square root in one place
it doesn't for example add a line return
between the power or or here you know
so that's my point okay
and okay so and also let me demonstrate
this okay so if you want to
display this in a um
you know you can just press a key so
Ctrl shift n force uh Ctrl shift n there
it is there it is
okay just press one single key and press
another key Ctrl shift I to return it to
input format okay so that's the power
That's The Power of
of wolfam language but but that's a
power of the simple concept you have to
understand the simple concept of
programming language syntax and the
automatic formatting okay so so so
I hope I make sense to you guys okay so
let me let me so I have I have you know
big
I'm angry with these Unix people the you
know the industrial programmers you know
the hacker types many of them are Ed
hackers you know they are they have
wrote great great programs but they
don't understand it because I've been
arguing with them for for for for 10 20
years
so here's the article the fundamental
problem of lisp okay so you can read
this article and if you you know first
of all you have the syntax
irregularities then you scroll down you
can see you know I explain in detail
then you have the syntax in semantics
correspondence okay that's a case of
lisp okay fantastic but they but the
typical these coders they don't
understand so they screwed up lots of
things they don't they you know to this
day to this day today you know after 40
years of this you don't have this
automatic formatting in this okay
I mean not even for example we
demonstrate JavaScript we demonstrated
Golan we demonstrated Powershell you
know you have automatic formatting press
one button for my whole file you don't
have that in emac this imagine that you
know the Emax is flat phonetics they
think oh emac this is the greatest but
great is my ass because this
equate in many ways especially the this
syntax is the most easy to do
but you don't it doesn't exist because
this the emac these people the community
the emacs community and the this
community in general including the
commonly especially the command is
they they don't they don't
understand it when you try to tell them
they refuse they they say you are an
idiot okay to this day you don't have
the tool to automatic automatically
format this code okay even even given
the fact that
this code is the most easy to do okay
the most easy to do for because of the
nesting because of the order parentheses
you can see
the most easy tool but to this day you
don't have that for example if I but
for example for example for example I
make these uh actually I don't want to
screw up my code what is this
okay so open fire at Cruiser let's open
open a new one so let's go to Kasai emac
this mod so you can see so you can see
this whole thing
you see this whole block of code I can
make it one single line okay that's
still valid code legal that still you
know Works 100 as before
but now there's no way to reformat it
back to the way it was because because
at least idiots okay the com especially
the common these idiots they don't know
you try to tell them they don't listen
they whatever you said with your
specific arguments fly by their head
they don't get it okay see because why
does that happen because of the code
situation similar to the Unix people
okay so undo so however I do have you
know I wrote uh excite this smart so I
do have some
partial Auto format for example I
screwed up my format I can press one
single key uh wait yeah press one single
key and you see now it's nice however
my emac this mod does not does not
reformat the lines you know you it needs
to do that that that's the key that's
that's the most important thing you want
to be able to your your auto format tool
must be able the key
to make it great you know in what I'm
talking about today is that it must be
able to
not just go line by line like the Unix
line based it you know just like
re-indent this line you know if this
line is wrong that line is wrong
re-indent them that's that's that's
trivial that's that's not good you want
to be able to actually be able to if you
have the whole code
uh you know oh wait okay
so for example like that you know you
you want to be able you too must be able
to reformat that into nice ways okay and
this is not difficult to do
well too bad I haven't done it you know
I should I should have since I've been
complaining you know but but I wrote you
know I worked on lots of other things
so anyway so
I hope for you guys you know maybe some
one of you guys will spread the idea
okay tell other people so we have these
two by the way there is a tool so
someone told me
actually 10 years ago about 15 years ago
I paid someone actually when I don't
have money but I tried to pay someone
you know for fifty dollars to do it but
then I don't think the result came out
well but then about three years ago
someone else told me he wrote a tool to
do that
that does what I wanted like for example
it can reformat the whole line but
uh
did I mention okay so I think I
mentioned it on my blog okay so let's
find it let's try to find it
Saudi uh info
uh let's search for emacs format okay
uh convert okay camera case and source
code formatting in emac this okay uh
reformat reformat lines of source code
okay there it is I wrote so many
articles about this automatic code
formatting let's see which one is it
camera case in source code formatting in
emac this
what is this about I don't remember
okay uh
okay this is not it you know what this
does anyway this is not it okay
there it is okay so I wrote this in 2007
for list languages it would be nice if a
programmer can press a button in emacs
then the current code block would be
formatted by a simple lexico scan okay
so I I showed some examples and some
ideas how to implement it
um
okay and here is the you know I read I
ranted about this long ago like like uh
got
where do they hide it 2009 okay this is
yeah here's my message 2009.
in complement dot list News Group okay
so anyway so here is a tool uh this is
not a good this is not a good one I was
talking about but there is
did I mention it somewhere the new one
okay here this one okay so I didn't I
removed all GitHub links so let's um
let's link it okay go to it
so this tool okay format whole buffer so
this one is written by
okay
okay so but I actually never tried it so
this is the desired one so you guys
should try it okay
uh Coffee House Coffee House philosopher
which one are you I don't know what
which one is your uh disco name
so anyway I talked a lot uh okay so
let's wrap up okay so we let's go back
to top talk show and we need to um talk
about
Okay so
because that
so close that so go back to talk show
close that reopen
so we need to we demonstrated Powershell
we talked about the real-time formatting
we demonstrated Golan and here's a goal
line code for emac bisp to be format
your code in emacs then okay let me
demonstrate python
yeah and we talked about the emac this
situation so yeah so let's do Python and
that'll be it today 10 more minutes okay
exactly one hour so let's do python so
for python case so you go here
uh which you know on my website Python
tutorial so you need this tools so now
by now there are several uh two of them
two two uh mostly two of them one is
called yapf
uh yet another Python formatter and the
other one is black okay so on this page
I
I give you details about them
so just like go format just like they
know for JavaScript just like Powershell
so you can call command to reformat your
code all files in your directory or or
source code or python Okay so
so in fact Let me let me Demo okay so
python
so okay so let's let's go to uh uh fine
okay let's just demo okay so python go
to go to a python code so here find
replace python3 so here's a script for
example
uh so for example let's screw up the
line here into one single line okay
that should still work okay now I press
the key
foreign
cannot pass what
oh because uh again because the comment
remember because of the line based
comment when you have a line based
comment which
which depends on a physical new line
that UPS up everything so
let's remove that for example let's make
a backup then now make this whole single
line okay now let's try to Auto format
okay do it you see fantastic now notice
it also changed the code before it was
single quote now it becomes double quote
so let's Undo You See
it was single quote now let's press a
button show the pink window so you can
see the command I call so
do it
you see the command I called is star
python format buffer okay so you can see
the single code becomes
double
so that's the you know that's the style
of the formatter so basically the
formatter makes sure that all every
python source code will look look
exactly the same uh format so you don't
have to you know so so it's more
consistent
and it does the whole fact okay so
that's the python example
um so you look now let's put back my
code I want the comment there okay so
close it close it so we demonstrated the
python Auto format and now let me show
you the
um
let me show you the emac this code okay
so I just wrote this uh yesterday
okay so the code is python mod map okay
so now it's in my uh in my emacs in it
so here's a source code so you need to
specify where the file is
okay so okay so here's a source code let
me just copy it
okay copy it close it
uh okay close it
uh because I find go
close it okay now okay now python we
demonstrated python Auto format now
create a new emac this block paste the
code
syntax color it showing browser okay
that's it for today so we demonstrated
automatic formatting for JavaScript
for Powershell
for Golan and we talked about a bit
history of the automatic formatting and
we demonstrated Powershell python you
know the and for each one of them
you know we showed the tool you need and
the emac this code so you can do it
within emacs then we talked about the
emac this case
and what is the tool this one okay so
yeah actually I didn't do it before
yeah copy that I need to put it here
there it is so there's a link to it okay
then uh we demonstrate the emac this
case then we demonstrated the Wolfram
language case
real time you know not just so okay
that's it for today so if you guys like
my tutorial pay me okay patreon
okay so go to my Excel code
then at the bottom you know lots of
programming language tutorials so pay me
patreon or Amazon gift card or PayPal
okay
yes my keyboard yeah because you know
this is a fantastic feature uh hey good
morning uh to Canada
Justin
so um
so so recently I started to use sticky
keys again it's fantastic okay that's
why it's making the peep but actually
it's kind of annoying so so what do you
do so you have that feature in Windows
okay here's how to set it up on Windows
and also
um
Mac and on Linux okay so let's
show it so
let's go to sticky keys so where is it
ease of access then keyboard then there
it is sticky keys and
play a sound when modifier Keys press
and released no okay
it's becoming annoying
okay so Steve he's uh I yeah that's
fantastic
okay so that's it for today okay
um
that's it for today and what I wanted to
do okay that's it
okay that's it
let me show you maybe uh you know the
automatic formatting in Wolfram language
some more some more complicated code
okay so I did a video on this one before
about several months ago okay just
search for Saudi wolf and geometric
inversion okay this is fantastic so here
is wufam language code let's copy it go
back to farm language
paste it there so you can see that's a
code okay so let's
uh evaluate the code so which will
evaluate the code so you can see you got
the graphics okay
but you see now here is a Wolfram
language source code okay by the way you
can download it free just go to my
website you'll find uh you know my links
um
here download free okay
so here's a source code a Wolfram
language so you can see let me let me
let me just uh highlight but by the way
when you double click it understands the
syntax so they highlight them
progressively larger in a syntactical
unit unit each time increased by a
syntactical unit you know in order to
have this feature basically your
language should
have certain properties the language
syntax but anyway so if you double click
on that you see it highlight this part
because that's the one that's one
syntactical unit for example if you
highlight this one
you know because these two for example
if you click on the plus
you know it highlight that okay it
understands the syntactical unit
okay so so
so now so you for example this this
width is one thing okay now if you
adjust the um the window size you can
see automatic formatting you see
you now pay attention it doesn't it
doesn't wrap at arbitrary places it
wraps the line always at syntactical
units okay you see that you see that
that that's that's a feature available
since 1998 okay by now 24 years ago
but today we still deal with you know
the Unix idiots the python you know the
pi
python JavaScript you know but these
days we have the automatic formatting
that's slightly better but we're still
dealing with a lot of the industrial
programmers here
formatting guide you know that's a
idiocy and the emacs settings
you know the tabs versus Space you know
the tab with settings you know emacs you
spend days to trick that settings and
then we have some idiots who provide
some Auto you know configuration
automatic configuration for veeam for
for for something something the
community community based you know tens
of thousands number and stars telling
you how to set up you know one
configuration so you can
using every editor idiocy
extreme
where does that came from came from the
Unix code okay that's that is my opinion
you know I have a lot of tutorials on
programming languages and talk show show
you how how programming language Works
those are not actually important my the
most important idea what I'm saying in
this one example is the idea about the
automatic formatting okay that's
important I hope I hope I'm
I have clearly demonstrated it okay and
I blame it you know why did it why
didn't this happen to other programming
languages but in wufan proprietary
language why because the industry of
idiots in open source you know lots of
issue code emacs in emacs you have the
Emax code in Python you have the python
code in Unix Linux you have the Linux
code they
they they check they stop your brain
from from wondering about
okay so so this is automatic I haven't
you know I'm not done yet this is
automatic formatting you know you can
select the whole thing
you know
but now you can press the button like
before you you know let me let me let me
make a copy of this so you can see in a
different
um
so I copy the code
press the key Ctrl shift n you see now
it's automatically formatted in your
type this is a programming language
Source Code by the way this is not you
know some some you know you can run it
this code is exactly the same as this as
this one okay now but now it's formatted
in a mathematical typeset instead of the
tech and La Tech code you know you have
backslash slash could equal
you know and slash fracked to you know
in order to do this fraction you have to
type all this crap
okay that's it thank you pay me okay
bye guys I'm gonna read comments for a
minute let's see who is watching today
uh okay dark things Coffee House
philosopher okay uh bash Crazy Frog
hello immortality
Justin
damn Java yeah Java is pretty bad uh
okay yeah Java Java is better than c for
sure
analytic minded okay
who are you who are you guys hello hello
son
uh comment this
uh what about communities okay nice to
not to just forever not we have to argue
about the config exactly
Kenneth Mata I just discovered your
content and have been watching many of
your previous streams thank you I need
money okay money is the most important
thing you know thank you appreciation
that's great but
pay because you know you know then then
we have the open source and you know
then we have Google Empire and Twitter
you know it's free it's all free but
they eat your soul
they eat your soup by the way okay so
now I have Odyssey let me
uh tell you so you go to Saudi
programming blog so I start you know
I've been coding a lot working on my
tutorials Python and you know rework
them and CSS you know in past several
half a year actually in as 10 years so I
reworked all this JavaScript and evil
apple uh in Powershell okay so what I
want to show you now is that I have
Odyssey
which is a YouTube alternative okay so
where is it there it is okay
my soul is now in the net part of the
indelible indelible inevitable
blockchain okay Odyssey so you can go to
Odyssey And subscribe my Odyssey account
okay you need JavaScript
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching
Odyssey fantastic and by the way I also
have locals now so locals if you don't
know
um it's another social media created by
Jordan Peterson and Dave Rubin you know
back in 2019
so I'm starting to have these uh
you know I I looked around you know all
the Alternatives so finally I decided
Odyssey or Libra or Libby like Libby you
know that's great and so I'm trying them
okay
great fantastic uh okay bye guys