good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show today is 2021
december
15th
and merry christmas guys christmas is
coming
um so today we don't have a topic yet
and
if you like to suggest a topic
you know you can see in the description
and post one of these links
uh i mean just type it okay so this is
exciting topic notes just type you know
one of the items in the chat box and in
the first five minutes okay then we will
talk about it
so i think i'm gonna do a technical kind
of thing uh my working on my website
basically and while i do that
i'm going to um
show you lots of tips about emacs about
programming language design
about you know uh kind of random things
okay now since there's nobody here
nobody you know so i'm going to just
start random okay
so again if you have a suggestion you
know if you have one of the you know
type one of the topics
okay so let's see some talk show so
today's talk show and close close that
close that and the show start actual
page close that close and this is the
ultimate hacking keyboard i'm using
uh this is ultimate hacking keyboard
hello telephonist
okay let me let me talk about keyboard a
little bit then
okay again mentioning a topic okay type
of topic so uh you looking at my
keyboard like right here and you can see
you go to console keyboard blog i
mentioned this all the time kinesis
advantage 2 the
my favorite
keyboard my main drive kinesis advantage
2 fantastic video reviews and
detailed reviews here and ultimate
hacking keyboard the best
the best keyboard marker okay so let me
show you ultimate hacking keyboard
automat ultimate hacking keyboard is the
best keyboard it's it's got the most
powerful
and easy to use
um software to configure the keyboard so
i'm using it as a keyboard marker as you
see
you see you are looking at my keyboard
marker for for windows you know i had
one for mac
uh wait so
you know
right now i'm on windows so this is my
keyboard markers you know most of these
keys are defined
you know again i damaged my finger
as you can see my
my left hand pinky i mean not pinky the
ring finger
got screwed and where do i you know it
got bent like that so it's like no i
have chicken claw
uh okay so ultimate hacking keywords
fantastic that's what you're looking at
right yeah so there and in my mouth okay
so
topic topics topics
nice keyboards i met
i met hello i suggest constructed human
languages fantastic topic okay so the
topic is going to be
constructed human languages programming
languages and regularity of syntax okay
matt says how do i really get good at
veeam you know i don't know if you are
trolling or not i'm not a vim user you
can get good by practice of course
okay so let's go go to the um
let's go to okay let's start to talk
about that topic okay so open console
talk show and you are looking at me
operating emacs okay using soft light
keys and i'm using kinesis
advantage
to keyboard
with vorack keyboard layout so vorack
you can see keyboard layout
so you can see the keyboard layout here
and i'm using vorack you are using
quality mostly
quality core mac so there's a key i'm
using voila keyboard
and i'm using emacs stuff like keys
so what is sunflower keys okay let me do
some advertisement
pay me okay that's what i'm here for
youtube talk show you pay me if you
think i talked something you learned
something
or you enjoyed the comedy buy me a drink
okay
so
so you're looking at my emacs and soft
flag keys is a key binding system that's
how i use emacs this video i did it
about a week ago uh yeah a full video a
new video on sapphire keys so watch that
and on the pink window you can see all
my emacs command cores and
keystrokes okay on the pink window
vorack layout
okay so now today's topic okay so let me
show you so copy so you see let me
operate the my keyboard marker so i want
to switch to browser copy the url it
will automatically you see
what what that this marker will do is
that it will do ctrl
l
to select the url field then it will do
ctrl c to copy it okay so i don't have
to control what whatever i just press
this key it does it now switch back to
the last window no alt tab crap you know
no tab crack
i just press a key or move my mouse
without click and back to imax bethlehem
good morning haven't seen you for a
while
[Laughter]
youtube
yes youtube is a problem but
unfortunately we are living under the
google's
uh empire
you know and that's uh
oh that's another story okay so anyway
so what we are going to do yeah talking
about the topic okay so be so let's go
to
so show the pink window
go took some talk show open it
and
paste the link here delete that block
so this is uh
this is the scifi keys
back to the browser okay move the mouse
back to browser copy that back to here
paste
in the last window okay so let's talk
about
this topic okay so the topic is
programming topics
language design formal language wait
what oh here constructed human languages
programming languages and regularity of
syntax
fascinating topic and the big topic okay
for that topic you search you go to
study.info let me show you some articles
because we are going to based we are on
our base our talk
on some of the articles i've written
so here is saudi.info website let's turn
on javascript so google can know
everything what i do
so code you go down then you go down you
go to this section hacker code now this
subject matter belongs to the proper
category is hacker code okay the things
hackers are concerned now hacker the
word hacker has multiple meanings
you know it had you know
to the average person
you know
in usa media you know they hacker means
someone breaks other people's computer
you know you are a computer criminal
that's what hacker means that's what the
mainstream media wants you to know
now now according to the
richard stowman for example or the
classic
hacker you know the
the programmers elite
type of programmers for example unix
phonetics or linux phonetics hacker in
1980s and 1990s and in much of 2000s
uh year 2000s hacker means
a particular type of programmer who are
very interested in hacking you know like
much of unix things okay and that's
related to our topic today hacker
so you know language design that's part
of it a hacker interest okay so that's
what we are going to talk about so this
topic
today the topic is about the
programming language design and in
particular about a
a particular aspect or style of
programming language design
compare that to artificial
constructed human languages design so
so let me let me tell you what is this
is this is about so you see programming
languages they are artificially created
of course they are created by us you
know i mean they i mean we by
artificially created that means someone
sits down and think of a programming
language you know c or c plus plus or
java or javascript or python ruby rust
golan
wufang language the best language wufam
language watch this video okay so
these are artificially created that
means specifically it means someone sit
down and designed it you know
from scratch
basically so all these languages are
artificial languages they are computer
languages all computer languages are
artificial as compared to so so what do
you mean artificial well compared to
human natural languages such as english
french chinese japanese russian korean
vietnamese
you know spanish you know these
languages are natural because they they
developed naturally in particular they
are not designed it's not like someone
sits down and created the entire
language the vocabulary the grammar and
everything so it's not
constructed okay so
human
languages human languages
vast majority of them
in fact all of them in practice are
natural languages you know while
computer languages are constructed
artificial you know they are created but
they are designed by someone
okay so that's about
okay so remember now let's clarify the
logic logicality of things okay keep
your comments going i love to see your
comments questions your comments direct
what i'm talking okay
um
okay it's great fantastic thank you matt
yeah fantastic question you know there's
no
um
you don't need to apologize or anything
you know because i
my talk show a lot of the people are
kind of the you know you know many of
them are young and and trollish you know
they came from some of them
from 4chan you know this so they say
random things yes you know
so usually i keep an eye on that
exactly good point eugene so eugene says
human languages some of them are
top-down design not
bottom-up that's true so that's what i'm
going to talk about so
so but first of all let me clarify the
situation so we have two
so we we are talking about programming
languages computer languages okay that's
one thing
that's a language you you uh
that's a language
for the purpose of communicating with a
machine okay
programming languages now on the other
hand we have human languages human to
human okay
human to humans such as english french
japanese korean you know and so on
now both of them you know they are all
they are languages they have a grammar
okay not
so and so among the human languages okay
that that's true thing programming
languages and human languages two kind
of separate things now
there is a aspect of design you know is
it created artificially so that's
another question so us you have some
languages that's created artificially
such as programming basically all
programming languages
and some languages happen naturally such
as human languages so okay so let me
write it down so
because it's going to get complex
okay so
human
languages okay
language
uh i have a shortcut so let's magnify so
wait
let's magnify
human language language
i have a shortcut but i
recently i changed the shortcut so i
forgot what the
language is okay so
lgj
for that's abbreviation for language in
my course a brief system so for example
i can show you
what
i can show you so here is my
abbreviation system there are hundreds
of them so for example so if you search
for language so you can see
i just type lgj for language i have like
hundreds of them okay close that so
human languages
versus computer
languages okay that's one thing
then you have
utter uh
artificially constructed
versus
naturally
evolved okay let's say evolved because
if you trace if you trace the origin of
human languages basically that's what
linguistics
linguistists do
uh you cannot you know it's hard to find
like a origin you know so you know
because it's
tens of thousands ago years ago or
hundreds of thousands years ago so
anyway so most human languages are
naturally evolved
okay now among human languages such as
english chinese and so on
human to human languages
um
they
so let me let me write it down okay so
human to
human okay computer languages
human to machine okay
by the way now since i'm we are writing
this out it would be interesting is
there a language from machine to human
you see this is interesting as we go on
so since i'm talking you know
i had i never thought of it because we
here we have a asymmetry because when we
talk about human languages it's human to
human both sides are human
so there's a symmetry but
for computer languages on one side you
have human on the other side you have
machine so there is a
two way so you can have a much
you you know you have programming
languages that's human to machine
human speaks from the machine
uh so
it's natural to ask
you know uh is a is there a language
from machine to human
that's that's interesting to think uh
aspect to explore okay but anyway so
human languages and computer languages
okay
now um
now among human languages
we also have constructed languages that
is not natural at all that's not
naturally created for example what are
some of the example of
constructed
languages okay so
examples
examples of
human languages
that are
created
that that are artificially
constructed
okay typically they are called
constructed languages now you know in
the 1990s and year 2000s there are they
are usually called artificial languages
but these days
the more common term is just constructed
languages okay for for example
esperanto
esperanto the most famous one is
esperanto and this lodge bomb okay
in fact i have a loch bond tutorial so
let me show you that i talked about that
in my past videos
okay
uh actually yeah so there it is solo
spawn tutorial but let me show you where
to find it okay so you go to kasady.org
you click on wordy english
so this is my blog the lure of
vocabulary the depth of literature the
question of style the logic of
linguistics
the ears of english and the cure by
writing okay that's my blog
on
all these kind of topics vocabulary
etymology literature
and writing writing style
accents
and there it is lojban
okay so lojban is a constructed language
with a focus on logic okay let me talk
let me uh tell you what that is about
later okay so actually i did a video
before in 2021
april 8th
constructed languages english spelling
reform shorthand system so i'm
interested in these kind of topics and
in fact you see there i mentioned
shorthand system and i just showed you
my abbreviations you know there are
hundreds of them so
right now they are you know some 400 of
them
so my abbreviation system they
constitute a shorthand system you know
i'm i'm creating that i'm using it in
emacs i
anyway so
so that's a topic i'm interested so
so you have launched one language so
losh bang let me explain what login is
okay actually the best way
you know my launchpad tutorial this is
written in 2003
so you know it's like written 15 years
ago and i really have not refined the
tutorial so if you want the best way to
understand what loch bong or lockland is
you go to wikipedia
okay
or also known as
okay so
you know
it was you know there was a constructed
language called lag lan
which stands for logical language it's a
constructed language meaning that
someone designed it
from the ground up okay but then there
is a political infighting about the
copyright status of the language so they
went to court and uh so they split so
the other group created los bang okay so
there it is okay so let me
let's show the open let's open the
wikipedia okay
so you can see this is article on the
lojban okay lojban
is a constructed
synthetically unambiguous human language
created by the logical language group
it succeeds the loglan project okay so
let's open loglan laglang is original so
loglan is a constructed language
originally designed for linguistic
research
particularly for investigating the
sapper wolf hypothesis the language was
developed beginning in 1955
by dr james cook brown okay
with with the goal of making the
language so different from natural
languages that people learning it would
think in a different way if the
hypothesis were true okay that's a
that's one of the big question in
linguistics which
which suggests that um
our thought pattern
you know what's in your brain
is influenced or even controlled
completely by the language you use okay
so for example i grew up as a chinese in
taiwan i speak chinese chinese is my
native language your language most
likely english or spanish whatever right
so
if the separate wolf hypothesis is true
that means
i can think of something you know the
way my brain works is different from
yours because our languages are
different
that's essentially what this hypothesis
is saying
you know it's possible i might think of
something that
you will never
possibly
imagine it because your language is
different from mine and vice versa you
know so that's that's what this
supper wolf hypothesis roughly
there's a strong version and there's a
weak version okay it basically says
the language
either controls your thought patterns or
it influences how you think okay for
example some of the
meme some of the meme example is that oh
eskemo the people in lives in eskimo
they have 100 words for snow
you know
so if you if you don't have a word for
snow can you possibly imagine the
concept of snow that's kind of like
that's what this um
sapper wolf hypothesis is
is about okay
so
so lockland is an artificial language
based on logic okay now that's another
topic because logic you know
the nature of log land it's strictly
based on logic
so it's so what does that mean so it is
it's basically logic meaning like
mathematical logic
so it has two um
you know it's kind of related to proof
you know mathematical proofs and so on
it's v logic okay
logic is a entire branch of science
usually considered even above or other
sciences logic in mathematics is a
science by their own
you know like the goss one of the
greatest mathematician
goss
says that the queen of science is
mathematics okay the queen of all
sciences physics uh
medicine biology chemistry the queen of
all sciences is mathematics
and he also says the queen of
math is number theory okay goss okay one
of the most
accomplished considered usually
considered one of the greatest
mathematician
in human animal history goss okay so
uh frederic what what's his full name
you know look up mathematician goss you
know
one of the top three at least
so
so we are talking about loglan which is
a constructed language then it
schism a schism a political inviting
happen political just like the open
source
open source free software foundation
versus open source and open source linux
distributions so many of them you know
in fighting typing windows managers in
fighting linux distribution you know
your distro versus my distro
ubuntu vs whatever arc linux chain to
inviting so political inviting split
the log land to become a large bank so
it's a
split
and the the launch mark is considered
open source while the love land is
considered proprietary that's why they
split you know in fighting
so
so okay so anyway so we actually we
haven't started to cover what we are
going to talk about the main topic okay
so anyway that so we are talking about
there is human languages there is
computer languages
and there is an issue of artificially
created versus naturally evolved such as
english and french and you know
and among human languages human to human
in the past 100 years in the in the last
100 to 200 years
some people usually engineers and
scientists they
created out of the blue artificially
they constructed
a language from scratch
for the purpose of human to human
communication okay so
so so loshvang lakland there are two
examples of it and the most famous
example is um
is esperanto okay so let's look up
okay esperanto so you can look up
wikipedia so we esperanto okay so let's
copy what we talked about today
uh and you know i want to copy the
star slo juan tutorial okay
okay so esperanto
you know i i haven't learned esperanto
so anyway that so esperanto is a
language
for human to human communication that's
created from scratch by design
by basically by one person then
or a few a handful of people designed it
for the purpose of human to human
communication so why do they design it
why do they design no no here comes the
main
main topic of what we are talking about
uh so
esperanto is designed so why do these
people why do these engineers these
nerds this usually these people who
created the you know starting about 200
years ago so you see
1887 okay
esperanto was created okay
why do they and there are so many there
are several others okay if you for
example on wikipedia you go to you know
your
if you read it you're pretty
you're easily started started to find
lots of others okay but esrando is the
most the most famous
and the most successful constructed
language okay it's it began in 1887
and it's created a bunch of scientists
engineers basically nerds so why do they
create it why do they create it you know
there's already english
with massive number of speakers there's
already chinese
spanish
and even french you know there's so many
speakers why do you create
something new that nobody you know you
have to learn well there are several
good reasons for it okay
because in natural languages just such
as english chinese french
the the grammar is extremely complex
the you know there's
1 000 irregularities it's very difficult
to learn you know you read you know
um
you wouldn't know if you never
learned another language for example if
you start to learn chinese today if you
are american or if you are chinese you
start to learn english
you will start to notice you know oh my
god why why is this english
language
one
bunch
big giant [ __ ]
you know so for example who are you
uh who are you okay so
basic example who are you but in chinese
we don't say it that way so in chinese
we say for example um
you are who you know you are who is a
question mark you know so that's what we
need to say that's what we say in
chinese but in english you have to
you have to kind of reverse it
you know you have to say it that way so
this is
this is one example of um
well this is not an example of
irregularity but it's just the example
of different different differences in
grammar okay that's so that's not a good
example for us but anyway you know you
know for example um
you know there's lots of examples for
example um past tense present tense you
know
i do
okay so i do
i did
you know
i've done you know do did done that's
you know tense differences for example
chair chairs
but woman
but it's not woman's
but
woman more men okay and and
so it's not women's but it's woman but
however you don't pronounce the men as
men you have you have to pronounce it
women so the proper pronunciation for
this word is
women
okay so so
so that illustrates
the irregularity
you know if you were born with in you
know if you were born speaking english
you wouldn't notice you you think this
is natural you know you think this is
this is so natural
uh but to if you came from china or
russia this is one [ __ ] up [ __ ] one
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] up okay and and also
for example
you know i do i did i've done then you
have i read
then i read
then
i read you don't say for example i read
i i read it
okay
i read it
i
have
written
you know so
you know if you say that that would be
much more regular but you know but we
have irregularities one thousand of them
so irregularity is the and complexity
you know it takes so much time to learn
to pick up all these one thousand
thousand
irregularities
that is one of the good reason
a artificial language is created
so you see these visionaries you know
these nerds they have a vision just like
you know google
they have a vision for humanity you know
why don't we create one single simple
unified
simple
language to rule them all you know so so
all human animals can communicate in
peace you know in peace and prosperity
that that is the vision of most of these
people these nerds who created
artificial languages okay that's the
origin that's the spirit
of all these sponge okay
you know maybe i can show some others
besides esperanto okay so
so esperanto
you know so esperanto is one of them
you know you go to
constructed languages okay so
so you can see
this article on constructed languages
they feature the concept of tower of
babel
the nerds kung lang flag now they have a
now they need a flag kung lan flag
you know they they have a
tower of babel which is a concept from
christianity and i believe
probably islamic religions and you know
the
judaism or something as well i mean
because they share one single
uh scripture
so anyway congland so
so on the in this page you can see quite
a few uh other examples and they i
suppose they give you they classify the
different conlan their purpose what they
are created the year they are created
and so on so there are you know quite a
few of them
you know i i learned i started i started
to learn about corn land
in 1990s you know
mostly 1992 to 1990
five or to 1997 okay 1990s i learned
them because i'm not i'm not just like
most of you who watch me i'm a nerd i'm
interested in efficiency i don't want
i don't want these irregularities i want
the most simple
efficient language okay so that's why
i'm interested in con
constructed lens okay it was known as
artificial language but now it's called
constructed land
so i'm interested because i just i share
the vision with these people you know we
want the unified language
for uh so we can communicate efficiently
and
um
okay so there's many of them so in 1990s
there's no internet yet
you know not really not like today so
you i go to
i go to the library i walk
20 30 minutes to the local library here
and you know you borrow books you read
them constructed languages so
i've studied i read you know
you know i read a bit about them
so constructed language okay so one of
the reasons so so let's let's write this
down okay so let's actually put this
into some kind of box
okay so we can see we have a record of
what we talked about now let me mention
um
constructed languages okay
one of the major reason
for
constructed
languages
is that we can have a
language
that has
the most
simple grammar
no
irregularities okay and
extremely
easy to learn
okay that's one of the major reason for
constructed languages
there are other reasons for example this
for example another reason is
neutral uh you know neutral
neutral in cultural bias for example
english is our language right
but english is full of white people's
cultural
affiliations you know
because well it's used by english
speakers in uk united kingdom in america
so
it's part of the you know all the words
in english is part of
you know the
essentially the western people's culture
most well mostly and you know
why you know so you might say why don't
we all why don't we you know why don't
we you know
we don't need a new you know artificial
language why don't we just all learn
english
well to you to me i already know english
so it's that's great that's fantastic
but to other people japanese chinese
um you know the russian or french they
don't want it you know
you know what they they will say why
don't you learn french friend let let
that french by be the universal language
why don't we let chinese be the
universal language you know so there's
arguments
so one of the reason of the you know one
of the kind of the reason of the
constructed language is that okay
okay
okay we understand you know you want
your languages so we just gonna create a
new one
that's
culturally neutral
that is it's not tied to any particular
and partic particular group of people's
culture so that's one of the one of the
um
one one of the reason you know they want
um you know they created constructed
language especially esperanto well not
not a responder actually a toronto is
actually the vocabulary is based on uh
western languages
okay that's a bit history about
esperanto
the
esperanto vocabulary is based on
mostly latin
derived languages such as english french
italian and and so on
none of the chinese or japanese on the
other hand the losh bang
or lag land the the lotion vocabulary is
not
western-centric okay it's
it's based on
you know basic based on like 10 or 10 or
so the most popular languages kind of a
random mix
so and so i'm talking about this so it
shows you that you know
cultural neutrality
is one of the
important element in this
uh constructed language community you
know because
that's true as well you know because
that's a valid that's a valid point you
want a language that's socially neutral
so anyway so back to you know let's
start to talk about the main point today
okay so so i want so
so we talked about um
human languages
we talked about computer languages they
are different and we talked about
the creation of the language you know
one way is artificially constructed
usually by a single guy a bunch of guys
the other way is naturally evolved such
as most human languages english french
and so on
then we talked about human languages
that's that's artificially constructed
uh and we gave example of los bang we
gave an example of lag land and
the most famous example being
uh esperanto okay some of the big
examples
we talked about
why are they created and what year they
began this this concept you know this
concept of
constructed language what year you know
about about 100 years ago
the idea began
so we talked about constructive
languages
then we also talked about the reason
what what are the reason these
constructed languages are created
and you know people nerds usually nuts
are very um obsessed about constructed
languages even today people are creating
more and more because in you know
because i know in my
in the past 10 or 20 years
i haven't really been following in the
past 10 years i haven't really been
following the movements of the
constructed language community but i've
heard you know i know that there are
more being created in the past 10 years
for example some of the
some of the other popular
constructed languages
you might have heard of is klingon you
know klingon from the star trek uh
fiction universe and also lord of the
rings you know a lot of dreams they have
the elfish language
then they also have the
the language of the
of the
of the bad guy you know you know the bad
creatures how you call them lord of the
rings rings tolkien you know the jrr
tolkien is kind of a god among many of
the unix hacker types of elite
programmers
okay there is klingon and there's okay
this is navi from after you know many
many constructed language these are
fictional
and and these languages are created for
the purpose of writing the novel you
know it just you know
yeah so they have a slightly different
purpose
uh
reason they are created okay
so i mentioned you know one so one of
the one of the
reason
the major reason one one of the primary
original reason constructed languages
are created
is so that so that you can you can have
a language that's easy to learn simple
grammar
uh it should
potentially increase
the efficiency of communication you know
those are good advantages okay
so now
yeah so this is yeah so that's what we
saying so this is this is a focus of our
topic okay
so
so you see in constructed languages so
let's talk about grammar okay so grammar
you know i showed some of the examples
of grammar you know complex complex
grammar or irregularity in english for
example
you know we talked about that very
complex
so so people created you know
constructed languages that eliminates
this complexity okay as a betterment as
an improvement you know a desire
for the better you know we don't want
these complexities let's let's create
something that's more regular systematic
okay
now
the main point of the today's talk show
the main topic
that is the
the the main topic you know that is the
the contrast
of
the desire
in complexities of the grammar
between
human languages
and
computer languages okay that's the main
point of today so let's go to so let's
go to so back to cassady dot info
you go to
you scroll down
go to
semantic noodle
okay and let's try to find the article
uh
programming language design
so
programming language idioms in style
and here's permanent languages in their
machine
so what the article we want to find is
grammar okay let's just search for
grammar
okay it's not here
um
okay let's go to syntax okay so go back
to page
syntax soup
so i did several talk shows related to
syntax there it is this
this is i believe here okay there there
is the article grammar complexity of
constructed language and computer
language okay
so
you know all these articles are related
to grammar okay in particular a system
systematic grammar so let's look at this
one
i'm going to answer the comments and
questions in a bit okay if you have a
question for me tag me
my mother native language i don't know
is like i know
no
okay
that's interesting logical okay link
lingala let's see
okay let me digress a little bit so what
is lingala
okay
oh okay so it's a
cree creole
creole what they call and ghana is a
bantu language i don't know what that is
is it's okay it's a bantu language
spoken throughout the north northwestern
part of
democratic republic of the congo oh wow
you are from there
amazing
including the capital
kinshasa and the northern half of the
republic of the congo okay so lingala
is a bantu language
spoken in you know around congo okay
it's spoken to a lesser degree in angola
okay
and okay so that's uh
interesting uh language
okay so now let's go back to our topic
okay so let's you know so this article
grammar complexity and of constructed
language and computer language okay you
can go there you can read it yourself
but you know let's not be boring and
just read it so instead i'm just going
to give you a live version of what i
think about that
so
so the issue is this
in human to human languages
we
we find we find that the natural
language grammar and it's just too
complex it's you know it's one [ __ ] up
[ __ ]
so we
we try to make it better by creating an
artificial language that does not have
this complexity you know where the
grammar is very systematic and simple
okay
now
when it comes to computer programming
languages
the situation is reversed
okay the situation is like totally
reversed for some reason that's kind of
strange
in programming languages
the programmers us
you know we don't somehow for some
reason we don't want a systematic simple
grammar we want it to be complex
so that's a very interesting question
a very very interesting phenomenon okay
to me at least
so in programming languages we want you
know we don't want it seems to be the
case okay
i can't say for sure but if you observe
you know the existing languages c
c plus plus c sharp java javascript
pearl python ruby
you know if you observe
let's go to um
you know let's look at you know
complain perving okay so
so let's see you know programming
language tutorial you know you look at
all these language golan powershell
python ruby pro emac lisp you know linux
you know
bash
you look at these languages
most of their grammar is very complex
and in fact
not just that in fact for example python
for example minis construct you know
you you know you if you are a programmer
then you know among programmers they
tend to even prefer
complex syntax they don't want something
simple that one rule that governs them
all they want more complex [ __ ]
okay so so one of such example is
search for example
okay list comprehension okay i'm going
to explain things um
so here's article python list
comprehension but this this is a
tutorial about this comprehension okay
but this is not
the one we want i want okay i want to go
to this page
white list comprehension is bad
list comprehension is a little language
it's a it's an exception in syntax and
semantics
like
yeah who enter here all words
don't apply okay that's what that's what
this comprehension is okay so anyway let
me back up
if you are not familiar
now this comprehension is a particular
syntax in
in python in other languages okay so you
have a specials
like very special syntax
a special construct you know different
from the whole python language you know
where it allows you it lets you create
lists okay it
you know basically allows you to
generate the list
okay but it's it's using a very
like specialized
syntax just for this case okay
it's like you won't see this syntax
anywhere else in the language just for
this case you have this special syntax
to do this thing
you know in other places you might use
for example range as a function you know
function is very general you you might
have you know
python syntax you know you might have
you know in other places you have
assignments syntax you have uh
you have uh you know if syntax if else
then you have
you know uh calling a function or
different a wire syntax very different
you know
basically almost each one of them is
special
so my point is my point
is if you look at
you know if you are a programmer you
know you've been in a programming
industry you
have been coding
you know you've been programming for a
few years you know you know a few
languages
and you know
what other programmers think you'll
notice that
there's a trend that people the
programmers
you know with their tools programming
languages they do not want a systematic
simple syntax
it seems it seems to be the case that
they want complex syntax okay so this is
a
very different this is the opposite the
opposite
of
what's happening among natural i mean
human languages
you know in constructed languages we
don't want complexity we want simplicity
we create constructed languages so that
we can
reach the goal of simpler grammar easier
to learn
more efficient in communication but on
the other hand when it comes to
programming languages it seems to be the
case that all these programmers they
prefer
complex syntax they prefer
lots of
irregularities spatial cases such as the
list comprehension okay so so let me
show you an example what is the language
that has a more systematic and simple
grammar okay so that would be for
example this
okay
that that would be for example i showed
this many times let me show you my
this code
okay so let's let's go to uh some top so
let's can show some this code so this is
a emac list code you can see
this is this language okay okay so
here's you are looking at list language
you know the syntax is rather very
simple
very very simple it's just nested
parentheses okay so you have nested
parentheses
you have this nested parenthesis you
have this nested you know nested
parenthesis nested you know it's all
just nested parenthesis
unlike
unlike the python where you have if
statements in one way you have for loop
in another syntax you have while loop in
a different syntax then you have
functions you know functions you know
functions you have this syntax then for
this generation you need to have these
this comprehension syntax very
different so that is the main point that
is the
the topic of today's talk show
we have this
kind of strange phenomenon
where
in natural languages
the human seems to want
a simple systematic grammar
without irregularities
such as
esperanto lojban and many other
artificial languages
but when it comes to programming
languages
that's
the opposite
okay that's that's the point
that is the point
i want to make that is today's main
topic
uh thank you for um
so that is a topic
asked by
uh who asked it
immortality
great topic thank you so i think that
concludes it
so how long have i been talking for one
hour okay that's it for today
now i'm going to read the comments and
that'll be it
now if you enjoyed the show
here comes
the to the important part if you enjoyed
it buy me a drink okay
paypal
amazon gift card
and patreon okay
so there's some questions so uh what
inconsistencies
can we find it you know what are some
examples of inconsistencies in chinese
there's a lot
uh it would be hard to explain because
unless
you know chinese
because otherwise it will be hard to
explain
you know and also because i was you know
i'm a chinese i was born
you know chinese or mandarin is my
native language so i don't i don't see
it you know to me it's just natural you
know i don't see it
you know this is a funny phenomenon you
don't notice it
of your of the irregularities of your
language of your mother tongue
until
you you know when you start to learn
another language you start to notice it
then if you
reflect then you think about your
language then you start to see lots of
irregularities you know the the easiest
way to see the irregularities of your
own language
is
you try to teach someone
your language for example let's teach
some people english
for a year you know let's say you it's
your girlfriend
which is the best way you know you teach
your girlfriend the language or she
teach you her language
then you can then then you realize oh my
god what the [ __ ] up language i have
been using all my life you know because
she will they ask
what you know whoever that person will
ask then why why is it this way and but
there you you do it that way but you
know then oh hey i didn't notice that
you start to find that
okay uh luis
burrow hello hi
and uh okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching so this is alan
says alan is out allen is a actually a
certified linguist
here allen has a linguistics degree so
alan also speaks chinese japanese korean
um
[Music]
how great alan
do you have overall positive feelings
about chinese grammar
chinese as well as japanese korean don't
have a lot of the complexities of
indo-european languages yeah i can say
for sure so the question is do i feel
the chinese grammar is
you know better or something
i feel so yes because it's
yeah so i can't really say because i
feel so because i know it so well and
you know i feel you know in general i
think it's simpler than english grammar
but i can't say that for sure because i
do know
like sometimes occasionally you know i
when you actually compare
then you then i start to see oh my god
that's you know
screwed up in so many ways yeah so i
don't
i seems you know so basically what i'm
saying is that i seem to have the
impression that chinese language the
grammar is simpler than english
yeah i guess that's true in general yeah
because in english for example you have
tenses you have
you know plurality agreements
you have tenses
and in those two aspects
are enough to say
i believe that's true
you know those two aspects are enough to
say that the english grammar
is more complex than chinese okay yeah
so i think that's
i believe so
is that true that asian chinese was
similar to today's chinese i don't know
that for sure
okay
bye guys i think that's it
uh can you learn any language that can
be good at them all
uh no they are people okay so the
question yaseen says yasay or yasin
can you learn many languages and be good
at them or
yes i think you can there are people who
have done that especially
because of the youtube age the youtube
era so if you go to you know you know if
you are
interested in languages you probably
know this already so you go to youtube
you search for
successful you know search for german or
or
or french or whatever or chinese you
will find tons of videos
talking about them
and you also start to find
uh poli
how they say um
poly math not exactly poly math you know
multi-linguist multilingual yeah you
know you'll see a lot of people um who
speaks a lot languages many of them
young uh
you know you'll start to see that and
they um yeah
bye guys
you know so let me um so you know i find
it very annoying for these programmers
you know so i kind of despise them
the c and c plus plus in particular
these type of programmers c c plus plus
java rust
they
and and the python and the python you
know so so i i as a programmer you know
we usually have arguments
you know so join this code just join
study discord if you haven't already so
we go there we argue all the day all the
time you know i say past time that's our
leisure for many nerds that's our
leisure we go there and argue argue
about trivial things
and
it annoys me very much
that there are a lot of people
they like this list comprehension crap
they love it they
they argue oh there but but but but this
is so good
but then you see then i drive down you
know i
or
the way i think the way i see it okay so
i
deconstruct it you know i take it apart
so what's happening with the list
comprehension is basically they want
they want
they want a special syntax just to
reflect this case that's what that's
essentially what it is okay
so so that you know so so i i'm you know
i don't like it so that's the so i
i dis deconstruct it to the most
fundamental reasons
but most of these people you know they
don't see it that way they don't see it
because
so why what is the reason a lot of these
people don't see it that way well i
suppose
it has much to do with habit just like
natural human to human languages you
know if you speak english if you born
with english you know speaking english
that's natural to you or chinese you
don't see
you don't see the irregularities to you
is so
so simple so natural
okay
so simple and so natural
such as
let's magnify
this woman
woman's
woman
we men
that's so natural that's second nature
how can it be complex
you know i've read i've read it i've
written
it's too natural to you
so
so these programmers especially the cc
plus first java just these type of
people and the python also they you know
oh yeah oh yeah at least comprehension
you don't they don't get it then there's
these two at least
the least people you know
so for example um
yeah let me talk about this
fundamental problems of lisp
okay so that is my article you go there
so
here's an article the fundamental
problems of
written in 2008 okay
so now as you know as you may know the
lisp is one of the most regular syntax
okay for example i've showed you
uh
you know essentially everything is just
parent okay no special plus sign no
special you know whatever you just
everything is just parenthesis okay this
you know and these people love it you
know they will say oh see sucks oh power
sucks oh python sucks the one syntax the
one language to rule them all is this
why because the regularity of the syntax
you see it's all regular all you have to
do is just parenthesis make everything
so simple you know is everything is just
a function here's a function name here's
a function name here's a function name
here's a function name you know in order
to understand this program what it does
all you have to do is to understand the
function names function
function match string you see
match overlay make overlay overlay put
replace match concat stream stream at
you know so simple all you have to do to
know is just the function names
you don't have to know
learn special
print
the c print of all the other this con
this comprehension you know you don't
have to know that these people will say
that you know they they think they are
the god of languages but however
these these people they never realize in
this
you have this special construct too
you know like like this back tick
like this middle dot you know the dot
between two things what the [ __ ] is that
you have that you have that in this
irregularities okay
these are syntax irregularities in lisp
so you have this
something dot something you have this
back quote
then parenthesis you know normally you
never put you never put something in
front of the parent you see here's a
parent here's a parent here's a parent
you know you don't put something in
front of it
but however
in this you ha you have this special
syntax irregularity you put a backtick
in front of it to mean something
then you also have this
so you you put a quote then you also
have a backtick variation then you also
have the comma variation you know then
you have the comma add sign variation so
this so what are these these are
syntax
irregularities
in the otherwise very regular lisp
languages okay
so i find this very annoying isn't it i
think this should be banned i think they
does this language no good i think they
should be eliminated
you know you get rid of them
but when i talk to the least people
they don't think so they don't think so
they suddenly you know they they they
prefer the regularity of syntax they
think it's superior to see but then when
you add when you talk you know when you
press them to their you know a few of
them special syntax they
all of a sudden they forgot about it
they say oh this is convenient oh this
is this is saves typing oh this makes
things easier to read
the [ __ ] these idiots
why does this happen because they have
it you know they don't think the because
this language language was like that 40
years ago they get used to
okay that okay that's that's it thank
you guys
bye
shut down in one minute
so i'm just cleaning up copy what we
talked about cleanup
so we talked about this comprehension
let me
make a link
close that
python loops okay python loops so this
page shows some you know syntax of
python
and
and let me show you guys one
one language that has least of these
irregularities okay so that language
surprise you would not you know you'll
be surprised that language is
mathematica okay
this language is the most regular
yet the most powerful flexible
why is that
okay why is that let me explain okay but
but that's it for today we are shutting
down okay so we talked about lingara
lingala interesting language
i actually don't want link
uh linguistic relativity actually that
should be
super roof hypothesis okay so let's
let's what do we put that
separate wolf hypothesis okay
yeah
so you are looking at my emacs workflow
so
so here we have what a record of what we
talked about
okay so close that look land we talked
about roshvang we talked about
constructive languages
uh closet
so you know there's uh today there's a
lot youtube you know there's like one
million videos per day
new videos you know so you can watch
learn login login lesson three numbers
this guy is going to teach you those
wrong
uh okay
uh notes you know so nuts so slow down
tutorial we have that practical email
list close that
uh what is this saudi website because it
grammar complexity so copy that
paste it here
we have the link already we don't so
okay so
that is
that is the main topic of today
showing browser
the grammar complexity of kung lan and
kamplan
compared
so that's what we talked about so by the
way another you know what what are some
examples of programming languages that
has a very simple syntax
for example so we talked about lisp
and xml is also one of the example
apl is also one of the example and
wufang language is one of the example
okay these are languages
that whose grammar
is
very simple okay comparatively
comparatively speaking
compared to all the others
basically all the others are c
syntax based c
c plus first java javascript
python we can count python in
python
and c sharp and
in pearl and bash you know yeah well not
bash but anyway
so that is why i i say that you know
that's why i don't like unix and c i
think unix in c is the granddaddy of
everything that sucks
in programming
so okay so closure so we talked so this
uh i'll go close it
okay
elon musk i think he's a great guy and i
think he's a great american
he is a great american that he's going
to save america among the many corrupt
politicians
he is among the great guy you know i
hope
uh okay that's it
bye guys
in stream
donate okay thank you guys