good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of exotics show today is
September 17th 2019 Tuesday 2 o'clock
p.m. San Francisco time
let me get chat ready
so guys pick a topic let's see who if we
are here we are live and live dashboard
ok so no one is here yet I'm just going
to start with a random topic name and
let's turn on the video
okay so saw talk show okay so what what
is today's topic I don't know okay let's
let's let's see let's see what's in my
blog so yesterday we did talk we did a
talk about Emacs yesterday is mostly
Emacs and Emacs Lisp related okay it's
about cheap webcam unicode brackets what
are good keyboard key binding choices
for Emacs and live coding of emag lisp
writing a command that converts english
letters to braille so we did that
yesterday and what is today's topic so
I mean let me get this up here so come
so that's yesterday so what what is
today I don't know ok so let's see what
are the topics are what are some of the
topic so we can do so right a English to
Braille we did that English - Vale
JavaScript right English to Braille
converter okay I demonstrated that
yesterday I did a demo actually IO that
is already written JavaScript we can
explain JavaScript Watts or we can do
JavaScript or P JavaScript objects in
JavaScript below P in depth we did that
three days ago but however that's a big
topic so we can continue on that on some
of the practical issues and some other
topics so if you are here you know look
at the look at the description and pick
pick a topic okay so let's let's see
let's go to let's see let's pick a
random topic so keyboard apartment we
talked about that
what webcam to get yesterday and we
talked about that or that before and for
programming section general and linear
I'm not sure how do you pronounce that
but he is a he's a somewhat popular guy
in programming community he is kind of a
weird guy like Richard Stallman and he
is one of the big person who who is
agonist agonist Facebook against
Wikipedia against the mob mentality and
again is the mob intelligence
you know like Amanda a man you know like
there is
idea that Wikipedia is so successful
because the power came from the
population all the people in the
population that made it so successful
but he so his opinion is a bit different
and he's again is that you know
Wikipedia for example they they do not
respect or they do not give much credit
to Authority or credentials for example
if you are a professor they don't care
if you are expert in some subject they
don't care
Wikipedia is such that they you know
they don't care about that about you
know expertise rather they just they
they kind of want to focus their their
philosophy is that they they want to
focus that you know and anyone can make
contribution and and eventually you'll
be good the the the you see the issue I
mean it Wikipedia is indeed very
successful and much of the technical
content the any article on Wikipedia
that is focus on academia stuff such as
math physics and programming languages
those are very good but however I mean
it's super very good it's almost better
than anything else even better than
professional written books for example
of math in many cases but Wikipedia so
anyway wiki is so successful so
basically Wikipedia do not focus on
professionals or expertise they do not
respect it so anyway so so anyways let
me summarize let me finish about the
chyron linear so he's a very interesting
guy and he's against those ideas and in
some cases he is also against open
source he gave many ideas and he has
written many books for example on Amazon
if you go to
you know if you just search his name
you'll find a lot articles about him and
interviews
apparently he's old like he's old
pioneer for virtual reality I didn't
know anything about him until like five
years ago I heard on Google+ then I
started to know and then I hear his name
so he has written many books for example
ten arguments for deleting your social
media accounts right now okay that one
oh that one is new 2019 and he is
actually he looks almost like just like
Richard Stallman the same kind of build
you know with with a beard and with a
potbelly so he has also written down of
the new everything encounters with
reality and virtual reality oh this is
2018 so anyway so he has written a few
books and if you search online you'll
find many articles about him and many of
his ideas I kind of agree but however he
you see he's against this kind of
digitalization you know so he calls a
digital Maoism for example one of his
idea is that he is against the midi
technology so good morning israel good
morning milk milk at good use real says
my beards is better than no I'm a IMS
you know so you know I am as he's got
news he's over over the news I like to
talk about it but maybe not because you
know that is a very taboo topic you talk
about it and pretty soon the
conversation will go over the place then
the next thing you know you're gonna be
banned on Google about Google on YouTube
you know so because it's very touchy you
know and you know it's a
I watched I watched your video a part of
it because I don't have I just woke up i
watch half half of it you know but I I
think we pretty much agree Israel on
this incident which estimate anyway yeah
let's not talk about that because pretty
because then like pretty soon you know
all the people watching all kind of
ideas will fly opinions or even
arguments among man yourself then that's
gonna be you know that's gonna get into
places that Google is gonna bad then
then this video is wasted you know then
they have to either delete it afterwards
or you know or you know I get bent so I
don't have not sure I want to do that
yet yeah so don't don't don't talk about
that okay don't mention that the guy's
name because you know he because he's
it's this is a big thing that guy is a
big you know billions billions billions
of billions air you know he's connected
to all the power in a world you know and
yeah let's let's not talk about that
that's it's very problem I mean even a
mom I follow us like you know there are
some people who disagree yeah but like
yeah yeah let's not talk about that
because pretty soon you you get into
places then it's gonna be like yeah it's
a lots of assumptions and stuff so let's
let's let's talk about this guy okay
okay Jurong jaron lanier anyway he's
interesting okay well his idea is that
MIDI okay he is against MIDI you know
MIDI is a technique is a kind of a file
format for trance trance for recording
music musical notes like musical
instruments notes piano you know it's
notes so MIDI is a file format basically
it records which notes are being played
which notes are being held
and how long they are being held down
and what instrument is it is things like
that so it's very it's very compact it's
you know for example if you play a piano
piece five minutes song you know or pop
song that's like four megabytes you know
if you MP MP period at five megabytes
but in MIDI
it's something like five kilobytes
because they only record the notes they
don't record to the actual sound they
just record the notes so when you play
bad playback using a MIDI compatible
instrument they are a lot on Amazon you
know piano or this so you can plug it in
and you can play the file so what will
happening is that that the MIDI the
digital piano will just read the notes
you know how long it's last and you know
things like that and it will play the
whole thing the sound came from the the
keyboard itself the synthesizer
so that's MIDI and then once you have
MIDI then you have you started to have
drawn machines like today you have also
lot like drum music is they are almost
automatic like you can create songs
easily as especially drum beats you know
different drum beats like dance dance
songs
so that's MIDI but anyway Jaron Lanier
he's also a musician by the way so and
he isn't interested in this weird you
know musical instruments from different
countries that you've never seen before
he knows some strange flute or some
strange string instrument you know he's
into that and one of his idea is that
he's against MIDI you know I that to me
that city because by in his opinion when
you have MIDI everything his teachers
heart can't quantified you know did
digitalized and quantified mini becomes
a number so according to him if I
understand correctly I'm maybe I got it
wrong but according to him he says that
MIDI is no good
because because then every piece of
music is gonna be the same like seeing
all that music we have is similar that's
his opinion because you know because you
have to encode the music into the
quantified you know numbers just a bunch
of numbers and they are not I think
according to him they are not they do
not express the actual full extent of
music I think that's what he is saying
you know because once you quantify then
it's just these patterns you know these
same patterns I don't I don't think I
agree but you know in anyway that's one
of his interesting ideas so you can
watch interviews of him on YouTube like
I think he did type TED talk and
interview somewhere else like lectures
invited lectures so interesting guide
what you know one thing I agree with him
is that the the the mob mob mentality
like Wikipedia you know that you know so
like so what happens with wikipedia's
today is that you know Wikipedia and
Facebook and Twitter and all these you
know they they only have like five
people one people or five people they
got rich they got super rich you know
like the the Facebook Mark Zuckerberg or
Wikipedia the Jimmy whale guy Wikipedia
okay
the idea of Wikipedia is not really his
idea it's just the right time you know
this is back in 2002 Jimmy well well he
and another guy started Wikipedia that's
another story okay this controversies
but anyway Jimmy whale he was doing poem
you know he was doing punk websites then
you know he tries to hide it now anyway
so he started Wikipedia because he think
you know it's a great idea where people
you know amass the information but
actually that guy Jimmy whale I think
he's not a good person okay
every time he give a talk he makes six
digit income
got one talk when talk he's got you know
let's say $100,000 one talk that's more
than at what I make in 10 years in 20
years but anyway Jimmy well but he you
know he he was doing porn sites and but
now but he tries to hide it that's the
thing did I know you know in my opinion
there's nothing wrong with porn sites
you know but he tries to hide it that's
the thing and also he tries to he kick
you know Wikipedia started again the
with him and there's another guy who is
also very questionable he is a very
quick I think he's a very Christian
concerted conservative to the extreme
you know so anyway I forgot his name but
you go to Wikipedia you know you type
Wikipedia founder so Wikipedia history
you'll find it so Jimmy Wales another
the guy then Jimmy well you know he he
tried to you know erase you know his
history and he also kicked out that the
other founder so to you know Jimmy will
just say oh it just me I found a
Wikipedia that's not you know it's a
wiki video you can read about it so
anyway so Jimmy who is this bad person
okay this is not and you know Wikipedia
so what so I think what he he is doing
is that he is trying to credit
everything to himself and he is the sole
guy who makes a lot money and every year
every two years Wikipedia you know they
they they ask you for donation let me
show you this article okay I think it's
almost like a scam so I do not recommend
donating to Wikipedia so this is their
chart of donation to Wikipedia so in
2007 you know I I donated back in 2006
or so or maybe earlier 2003 2004
something like that I donated like two
dollars
why just two dollars because because I
kind of believe like everyone do
something small which is good kind of
like the idea of Wikipedia but anyway
back then in 2004 you know they are
pretty small Wikipedia and they you know
they have server problems like you go to
Wikipedia that doesn't show up one
minute and shows up in the next minute
so they got server crisis just you know
so so I donated $2 back then and
Wikipedia is fantastic to me because I'm
the type who will just read we keep
encyclopedias every day you know I just
keep reading in psycho video every day
and you know since since 1990s you know
you go to library reading encyclopedia I
read in you know prett annika which is
the V encyclopedia the biggest you know
Britannica I've also read
Americana you know the Guido's Americana
illustrated in cycle encyclopedia I read
a lot in fact I have a lot of articles
about encyclopedias somewhere not here
not linked here but anyway back to
Wikipedia okay so I'm saying Jimmy whale
is is is not is morally bad guy you know
so anyway here's a donation chart of
Wikipedia and the actual spending you
get you know so what I want to say is
that I think you know the Jimmy whale he
is just taking a lot of money he's
actually become very you know he's very
rich you know like meeting here for sure
you know he's one of the very rich guy
and Wikipedia all the people who
contributed to Wikipedia you get nothing
you get nothing you know Wikipedia are
so successful but all the people who
contributed you you don't you don't get
nothing same thing same thing with
Facebook Twitter you know all these huge
corporations they you know they and also
Google you know in many ways that's a
long story okay so anyway so these
companies you know they
we only just a few people they become
super super rich and while all of us we
do things we don't get nothing you know
become and in fact we become poor and
poor because you see you as you know if
you know statistics you know they say
the the gap between wealthy and poor is
getting larger and larger you know like
they say top one top ten percent owns
you know 70 80 percent of the rest you
know wealth in in USA is something like
that so anyway I do not recommend
donating to Wikipedia okay so anyway
back to the point of Jaron Lanier I mean
so basically he's saying is that this
this is what happens you know all the
people you you are actually the creators
in a case of Wikipedia the other good
things on Wikipedia they are actually
mostly majority of the good information
on Wikipedia they are actually just copy
paste from from the internet okay that's
what they do you know you got a bunch of
people who are the Wikipedia editors
typically they are just students okay
they got nothing to do and they they
tend also to be yeah the millennial
generation they are me and they don't
have you know they don't have any moral
character qualities they just mean and
do things to get power so anyway if you
use Wikipedia long enough you edit
articles you know you become editor
so-called editor and you and these
people tends to be you know they they
just hack their you know it's like Stack
Overflow to any of these social media
you tend to have you you can you tend to
create like a small group of people who
are just seen there and watch everything
and they control and they want things to
go their way like their their ideas they
don't be the you know on the on the
surface they they have like rules you
know what should go where but actually
is
you know these people typically they
don't do anything every day you know
they just hard on Wikipedia or Stack
Overflow they control the information
they control how things should be and
and a lot of it is copy and paste
rewarding you know technically Wikipedia
do not allow you to just copy and paste
in some cases you can then they say you
have to give a reference citation but
what but even if you do that like 20
years ago Wikipedia cited a lot of my
stuff but then eventually the site in
citation is gone well because what
happens is because for example I have
some great information I saw from
another website so I rewarded you know I
put it on Wikipedia article I'd rewarded
and I put a citation but tomorrow some
somewhere else can i edit it you know
and eventually eventually soon
you know after year or two the article
will have nothing the you know you see
the main content is still there but but
however the writing has nothing to do
with a citation anymore then you just
remove the citation you know it's
appropriate because when you look at
Wikipedia so Monaco and you see oh this
has nothing to do with the citation you
just remove it so that's in a sense
that's kind of like stealing not exactly
I mean that's that's you know that's
just the way they are I mean on a
surface they say Oh citation copyright
you you know you but what the end result
is basically Wikipedia is just basically
you grab all the information from other
people on a website you know bloggers
you know for example I write a lot you
you know yeah you just copy it and put
on we rewarded put it on Wikipedia that
becomes Wikipedia and and who gets who
gets money you know this one guy
basically one guy Jimmy Wales he becomes
you know super rich and he is going you
know he's going around so he's going
around you know giving lectures in this
you know Stanford University or these
big universities and he's gonna say oh I
created with Vidya you know my vision is
for you know all the information that
that's all [ __ ] you know that's not
just his tactics so he becomes richer
and richer and no there's nothing
YouTube you can do it this is almost
like a open source ideology because when
you have opinion like my opinion I'm
against alternating to Wikipedia but a
lot of your friends will not agree
because they are in their mind they
think that Wikipedia is so great because
is all the information right but
actually that's not you know if we keep
Vidya died today it's supposed if we
keep edia you know ran out of money or
something
they are not running out of money they
have a lot of money in gym Aquila quails
pocket but suppose they run out of money
they bankrupt you know they suppose
Wikipedia went down today I guarantee
you within a year there will be other
encyclopedias that's equivalent I mean
the content is just as good as Wikipedia
you know because you know time is
constantly changing
Wikipedia began 20 years ago 20 years
ago the idea of population contribution
to one project that's that's new you
know so Wikipedia became successful but
today you know today if Wikipedia died
another one was just as good will pop up
right away may be supported by ads you
know or otherwise so you know I do not
believe that Wikipedia is this unique
resource first of all they are basically
copy of you know everywhere everyone
else so anyway that's that's kind of the
Chevron Lanier's idea about Wikipedia so
actually so I think that's about that
guy let me read the comments and so I've
been talking for quite long
reading the comments maybe some of you
already left
let's see 26 minutes okay so let me read
the comments from the top
good morning Kathy meerkats today topic
is Richard Stallman okay give people
what they want throw them in the bread I
love bread how did review no can't
what's up new dose good morning
new dose male cat my butt hairs that's
good keep keep talking male cat usually
maximize your profit No hey what did did
they block my comment yes they did you
know we you know as I said this many
times YouTube all this media because
because social justice the Train you
know I they they block everything now
because you see this comment me okay
check out my video if sorry is a coward
you know I guess they blocked it because
you have the word coward that's that's
you know that's incredible you shouldn't
be blocked and YouTube he's doing that
YouTube you know anyway so that's okay
yeah so Israel gotta go I it's too late
now I also have to sleep okay male cat
miaows says the codification of sounds
through MIDI has certain advantages a
song can be broken up into segments
where each segment can be played or
accentuated differently yeah attach good
morning oh - so did you know what
happened with stolen yeah we were
talking about that but I'm thinking
let's not talk about that because that I
mean you are in Chile right so the what
storm and that you know the the subject
matter is a major major taboo in USA we
if you talk about that also the problems
rise up okay so milk ad says I've seen
video games given Allegro to southern
parts of soundtrack soundtrack depending
on the context in a game if you were in
combat you would give more intensity Oh
Allegro means louder
I forgot Lake Allegro means louder right
that's a music jargon so let's refer him
was she nuts Richard Stallman so Oh
Kathy so Kathy if you haven't heard well
okay so maybe I shouldn't talk about
that so Kathy just just look up okay
yeah Kathy Kathy you are in China so
this is you know this is more kind of a
u.s. thing basically Richard Stallman
quit MIT and he also quit he resigned
from being a free software foundation
president as well because because there
are some people who there are some
activists you know who don't who want to
who don't want who don't like him
basically that's my opinion
yeah so I'm surprised how powerful that
person can be so you know back to the
question I'm thinking you know I keep
thinking in you know in the past few
years if today's society is better than
let's say 1990s I you know and I keep
thinking about that in the past four
years and the answer is I don't know I
mean I couldn't possibly say it's better
or it's worse I just like don't know
it's you know I I feel it's worse
because because today's generation
today's people they don't have they
don't have moral characters
I mean it's kind of it's it's it's well
represented by the 4chan phrase no you
okay
you know the 4chan you know one of the
chair means is the gamer let's not say
fortune the camera means is no you okay
it's it's usually written like that
okay that's such wave let me show you
the meme
now if you are USA you you you probably
know I mean if you are younger than you
know what it means so yeah so this is so
this is like that you know they they use
these kind of means so like when you are
on Twitter or anywhere anywhere else in
game you know when we you start to have
some kind of argument or then you just
say no you that's that's a direct
response you know so I feel that today's
people today's younger people are or
like that because they don't have you
know life is independent you know like I
don't depend on you you don't depend on
me so I don't care about you really I
mean in practice that's what really
happens like you know you don't care
about your neighbors you don't care
about any anyone else you only care is
your boss and your co-workers those
people you know you care a little bit
you know because you see if you
offensive to your boss you get fired
then you don't have money to eat right
but otherwise any anyone else you know
you don't like there is no need to care
about anyone else
so when you read new so someone died
someone you know got sick you don't
really care I mean you could you know
any anything they say that you disagree
you just shut back you know you just
shut back no you you know it's like you
know you don't even bother giving
reasons owed or explanation of your
opinion anymore because because
ultimately that doesn't matter or you
carry said no [ __ ] you you are wrong I
am
okay you know like you don't need to I
mean forget forget about even reasoning
that doesn't matter you know you just
say what you like you know you can say
whatever whenever you know whatever that
doesn't make sense you can do it that's
your life that's becomes that becomes
everyday life because you don't have to
care you know you don't care about
nothing the government you know the big
government or Google you know they're
doing bad things nothing you can do you
know years after years after ten years
you realize there's really nothing you
can do you know every time you criticize
Google Google has you know all these big
companies or politicians they have you
they have parts you know they have like
million million parts on Twitter you
know they algorithmically control you
know so so so you if you go to Twitter a
lot people you know they say anything's
actually a lot of of them are not
actually real persons then you have
people you know for example I'm Google I
pay you you know I pay ten thousand
people to post things that you know that
says good things for me you know that
says good things about me I pay them
cheaply you know let's say five dollars
an hour so I I can't because I'm rich
I'm Google you know so you pay you do
that so on Twitter or you can you know
so you have all these kind of thing
going on so today for example I complain
about Google there's nothing I can do
and this is being for the past 20 years
the I think it's getting worse because
once you say something a for example
about you know anything any any way you
say something then there's nothing you
can do there's nothing you cannot I mean
then even your friends have opinions you
know they start to say no you because
they don't agree with you why because a
lot of them because Google has this
massive TV YouTube you know they control
the information media you know the
companies they spend you know PDS to put
ads you know that's American capitalism
you know freedom you know they have ads
that kind of shape your thought so
so there's nothing you can do the only
thing you can do so so after ten years
of these you become this person that you
know you can care about nothing however
there is still one thing you can do that
is be angry and be me for example if you
cease for example if someone sees me
okay that he sees my opinion he doesn't
like my opinion then he can he can start
to make a Twitter post or something then
that is belong out of proportions like
no reason he just say oh I am you know
all these bad words you know this this
is you know anger then that gets other
people you know get anger they don't
look into why or what really happens
they don't care it's just that something
you know someone is really bad he did
this then everyone is like repeating
that you know that so they you know
these idiots this millennial generation
they they have like jargons they call
this canceled culture you know what the
[ __ ] cancel coach echo it cancel culture
okay so that's what happening you know
that's so people you know so from what I
see these people today it's like they
you know like you can see them they are
so they are pretty me you know they
don't really they are so hateful like
like they don't really care I mean on
the surface they they seems to be all
this all caring person but you look at
their behaviors and they they are just
like me very bad person so so I'm
thinking you know is today's world
better than 20 years ago
statistically everything seems to be
better because we have I think we have
less war we have less you know murder we
have less every everyone is more wealthy
I mean you know let's pour less people
in poverty all around the globe so
statistically I think we are better than
20 years ago in 90 then 1990s
on the other hand and I very much doubt
we are actually better you could part
you know it's possible that the world is
getting worse
any time you know things something may
break up and I'm also worried I'm also
worried that USA and pretty much all the
white people nations USA Canada
Australia UK Germany the white nations
they are collapsing you know they are
basically they are going down I kind of
worry about that as well because you
know because because I'm American
citizen you know for you know I care
about Chinese because I'm Chinese blood
but also American you know I lived here
30 years so that's about that so maybe
that's that's it about today's topic see
so oh so we got 11 people watching so
what else guys post post questions
I mean post yeah questions opinions okay
jaimé jaimé commas you like noodles
alright small that's hard to say I think
probably noodles actually let me yeah
okay let me talk about that
so rice what white I do not like white
rice you know those processed rice for
the same reason I don't like white bread
I almost never eat white bread the only
bread I eat is 100% whole wheat or some
kind of you know grande seven-grain
bread actually yeah let's see I can show
you my bread here
so you see this is my bread this is yeah
so this is kind of like 100% whole wheat
I I always I never ever eat white bread
since like 20 years ago since 1990s I
never eat word white bad and by the way
so here is a tomato juice so white bread
I don't eat and I eat nuts
I eat a lot nut so this is mixed nuts
you have Kathy you have ailments you
have you know some peanuts and know all
kind of nuts so I eat mixed no it's a
lot throughout my life basically not
nuts all good so I tend to eat healthy
diet
I don't eat white bread because you know
those are very bad what white bread
those are process you know you have
grains they they me or the grains that
you know they grind the grains and they
remove the they remove the hull they
remove the husk but they also removed
any way they remove the rough parts of
the grain so that's how you get white
rice and white flour flour that's not
good
what because many of the nutrients are
in the rough parts so I so I don't eat
white bread and in general I don't eat
rice neither because I don't cook but
however big but if I do eat rice it's
going to be brown rice or wild rice okay
let me show you pictures because
pictures is worth a thousand words brown
rice brown rice or wild rice now those
are expensive actually in USA so here's
what brown rice look like like that so
so and I actually like wild rice
let me show you wild rice is more
expensive so it looks like that
this is uncooked wild rice now when it's
cooked it looks like that it's it's got
this pretty rough Shou you have to chew
a lot you have to chew like for one hour
so yeah so this is cooked
wild rice I eat that I like that I don't
so I I do not I do not eat white rice
but however because my roommates they
are Chinese working in restaurants since
since five years ago I started to work
in restaurants washing dishes so I met
you know these Chinese people who are
not who didn't go to college you know
who are just working in restaurants so I
so I they are my roommates now so but
for most Chinese they eat white rice I
mean they eat white rice they may eat
the processed white rice that's just
convention you cannot change that so
they all eat that so now see you know
since five years ago whenever they cook
sometimes we eat together so I just
needed white white rice so but in
general I don't eat white rice and in a
same way I do not I try to avoid any
noodle because typical noodle is white
noon the white floor noodle you don't
have you know so I don't so yeah so
that's about that that's about my my
opinion about rice and noodles so
between what rice and noodles I guess I
eat noodles more often but in general
they are you know that I don't so okay I
do eat pasta pasta I eat a lot a lot
pasta in my life pasta you know
technically you don't call pasta noodles
but yeah I eat pasta you know all sort
of shapes macaroni and you know because
that's
better that's good for you so
so let me see so post post okay post
then then then that's about it for today
let's see how long I've been talking 44
oh that we have we have we have 15
minutes we can talk another 15 minutes
or so
she got a um I'm sorry I'm sorry is how
powerful that person can be yeah so MIT
MIT maximize their profit yeah MIT
you know MIT you used to be you know in
my impression of MIT Stanford Harvard or
these you know top universities so in
the 90s you know I was thinking of going
to a university
so this universities are great you know
I respect them because they are so
famous you know and back then I was much
younger right
I was 20-something so I don't know about
poverty expecting but all I know is that
MIT Stanford you know they are great you
know colleges I want to go there but now
but today at least today this colleges
they are just money machines they do all
they can to maximize money and they pay
you know they have administrators they
are the ministration Department or the
people they get more money than than the
lecture the professors you know so the
mean and the ministers of universities
they become so powerful you know they
just the universities has become just
like big corporations and they do all
they can to maximize money
that's basically that's become their
number one concern you know daddy that
is why many universities are corrupted
and MIT for example I read you know it
turns out they got money from this guy
let's not mention a guy okay he MIT got
money a lot money donation from this
which super super rich guy
that is not disclosed until until you
know you know until the past few days
things blow up then oh you know MIT did
not disclose they they took this amount
of money you know yeah
and he says mm said so he tried to be a
social something despite our saying
Jimmy Wales Jimmy Wales is Network is
one medium one media is rich enough man
moderators yeah Wikipedia moderators
shut up shut up male cats don't say
those things okay male cat you are
dangerous because every time you know
you have comments that gets me into
trouble okay male cats okay male cats
needs to go goodnight male cat hey man
Jamie hey Jamie
so that's newest about rice noodle
versus rice so Jamie
good morning Jamie have not seen you
before where are you from so what do you
eat what do you eat noodles or rice oh
like where do you from what city or what
country like what so I you know so I
know what kind of things you eat so
Peter head says new haircut
new haircut very smart very cool very
very handsome I like it that's it's my
new haircut this okay so you need to see
haircut you need to see the full profile
I used to I used to have long hair like
up to my waist almost all my life and
here I cut it off when I was 45 yeah
around 40 age you know fact about seven
seven years ago I could cut it off and
now I just when it's long actually it's
now a bit long I just take a scissor and
I just chop it it's like it's like dog
bites nuts a pair of nuts you would love
if you got a pair of nuts I would love
no I wouldn't
I'm not gay okay do you like green yeah
I do I actually like broccoli because
it's healthy you know so my diet is kind
of like scientific it tends to be you
know because I wanted to be your
Superman I wanted to be those you know
actually so today let's talk about diet
sorry
diet okay I have obsession about diet
since I was since I was 20
okay I have actually okay one article
meal on P oh okay so yeah tired of sorry
so the here is a picture now this is
this is rich food now this photo is
taken around I think this one is 2011 or
2010 and see how 2009 okay so you see
broccoli pasta macaroni red beans you
know the printed pinto beans that's a
Mexican beans then broccoli and carrots
so my diet tends to be healthy you know
like like I mentioned we
for I'm a schizoid personality and I am
I'm I am this nerd you know who is who
don't care about nothing except kind of
science and programming and you know
math so you know when I was younger I
was thinking I'm going to dive into the
computer become me and the computer and
then become part of the network you know
so I'm very I'm not much of a social
person and but also for most of my life
I wanted to be a Superman Superman
meaning that you know I'm the the
highest I have the highest intellect I
have the I can run that I can run faster
than anyone you know do those so-called
extreme sports you know I used to do
those kind of things like I put on my
rollerblade and I you know hold onto
cars and Costco of so I I actually did
that so I do those kind of things I want
to be a Superman because you know
because I believe I can you know because
I want to be better than anyone and so
that's that's that's my that's kind of
me okay my personality so so as far as
food goes I my food choices are
basically I would for example I would if
there's a pill that provides all the
nutrients every day I would just take
that pill you know that you know today
about five years ago you started to have
this Soylent
okay that's kind of the same idea so
this guide is not guy who who are
thinking okay oh the nutrient you need
you know he's a chemist I think he's a
chemist background so this young guy he
think you can create a powder that
contains everything you need and you
just drink that you know that's it yeah
so this is you know this idea is not new
of course in science fiction you have
appeal basically the ultimate thing is
just you know you just take a pill then
you don't need to eat the whole day so I
was very much into that
throughout 1990s and and even mm so so
before there's souland I used to drink
slimfast or other kind of there are
other kind of things similar to slimfast
in fact in fact soil and is kind of just
like slimfast okay yeah actually you
know the only difference difference is
that slimfast is market marketed to
usually women for losing weight okay
that's that's only difference but
basically the as far as the content goes
you know they all try to be try to be
food that contains all the nutrient you
need you know and soil and is kind of
new fashionable for nerds you know they
eat Soylent anyway so I use I I drink
lots of these you know in night in slim
fast and others and you know the the
power power power power nutrition bar
like and also if you work out in a gym
if you are a bodybuilder you have lots
of that like protein powders let's go to
Amazon okay you will see all kind of
things and I used to eat them
protein bar protein powder okay and I
also used to read lots of these
bodybuilding magazines you know I am NOT
into bodybuilding but rather I mean to
other you know because bodybuilding it's
interesting bodybuilding you know you
see those people with pokey muscles
actually I need to work out no I'm
kidding out do you want to see me naked
I'm gonna you know I'm going to start a
schedule so by next month I'll have
muscles I thought you know I'm going to
start to do push-up and stuff having you
know I'm getting old I haven't been
active you know so most of my life I'm
very active I mean to the degree I'm to
the level of competitive athlete so
usually you know you are unfit you are
fit you are athletic or you are
competitive athlete like professional
athlete
so all my life I used to be until until
I was 14 okay I I can't I'm kind of the
competitive athlete body because I want
to be that that's you know that's what I
want to do so I you know but anyway back
to bodybuilding bodybuilding is
interesting you know bodybuilding you
know you you see those people with lots
of muscles but that's the only thing you
see that's only the only thing body
building is good for physically is that
you look you have a lot of muscles but
actually you are not strong you are not
faster you are you are not nothing
except you you you look with you know
you look you look kind of good actually
bodybuilding they don't look good you
know because they are - they are freak
they become free but anyway the only
purpose of bodybuilding is to grow
muscles nothing else it does not mean
you are stronger or nothing you know you
are you are good at nothing you are not
good at lifting you are not good any
anything the only thing you are good is
you look you know pokey so that's that's
bodybuilding you know sports science is
very interesting it especially today
they are very you have a lot of science
so depending on what you want to do you
want to be a good swimmer you want to be
a fast you know power runner like
hundred meters you want to be your best
marathon runner or you want to be the
best one kilometer runner all of them or
cyclists or whatever you they require
different kind of training so you have
like like very specific training to make
you very good in this particular thing
you know so these you know so it's not
so good swimmers good swimmer will be
very bad extremely bad at running or
other things or powerlifting if you do
powerlifting that's the only thing you
are good for would you just leave you
know 300 kilograms or something
powerlifting that's the only
you are good for you are good for
nothing and in fact so-so modern sports
you know they become very very
specialized and and and and typically
that's not what I want you know III
think maybe it's good for you my
recommendation is that I would prefer to
be generic you know very good but
general purpose like basically like a
soldier okay soldier or special agent in
James Bond double seven you know double
seven movie that's all show okay you
know you have this old guy who doing
things that's kind of like a show but
basically you want to be you know you
can run very fast you can swim every
fast you can cycle you can do you can
lift pretty good you know you want to be
that kind of general that's good that's
good for you
not not become so specialized into one
sport so anyway that's about so so so
about this food you know I used to I
used to take some of these pills like
protein or vitamins you know and you
know these kind of things are athletes
they are into you know and I also read a
lot you know bodybuilding those kind of
magazines so in those magazines they
they talk about this every day
and they show you you know they show you
food broccoli you know broccoli and nuts
you know nice nice professional
photography of you know nice food of all
the veggies they show that every day so
back to my diet so might I'm kind of
very you know nerdy scientific person so
when it took comes to diet I don't care
about taste you know actually I I loved
delicious food I you know if I go to
restaurant I love any of those queasy or
Chinese food or I love them almost any
kind of dish Indian American hamburgers
or or whatever or P
so Chinese food you know fried rice oh
well I love them
I enjoy the taste but however ideally
I'm thinking you know I'm thinking that
I want to be someone who do not care
like the case the taste of some food
does not matter to me at all so I can so
in fact I do
eat you know just oatmeal for example
have you seen The Matrix the movie
matrix oatmeal you know the movie matrix
the first movie in 1999 also they you
see a bunch of guy they eat this
porridge so you buy this oatmeal you
just pour hot water or you cook it then
you just eat it there's no taste you
know I do that I do that so in a sense
I'm kind of like a monk okay so I do
that because I eat it there's no taste
but however I have this mentality that
this is you know I even it doesn't taste
good but I want to force myself like
this is the thing this is the thing I
want to do you know like like Emacs okay
you know I want I want to get good at
this so so so oatmeal I've been eating
oatmeal I don't have it I haven't done
that now but oatmeal you been eating
this diet for like several years for
five years especially when you are poor
this is good especially you don't have
money and this is very nutritious so
instead of eating rice or anything
you're you know white bread you just
just oatmeal you know this is what hosts
hosts and goats and pigs eat too you
know be like them it eat oatmeal they
are good for you just just raw oatmeal
hard water this eat it eat it you know
every day and so so I can't so my
mentality you know I so if it doesn't
taste good I want to keep doing it I
want to train I want to become like I
want to force myself into this this
machine-like person like mr. data I'm
away I'm already like that because I'm a
ski sword you know there's nothing
except logic so if it's this good this
is if this is good for you I just do it
if that is good for you just do it yeah
you know I I used to think human are
like a machine you know you just you can
follow logic and do whatever you want
and become whatever you want that's
actually not the case because the human
brain you have emotions you have lots of
things that's out of your control and
especially for example if you have
dramatic you have post-traumatic
syndrome you know what they call you
know like then then it changes your
brain in a way that it affects you you
know you when used when it comes to some
subject you are unable to you I mean you
are unable to function or you will you
will fall apart things like that that's
post-traumatic syndrome so so this is
this is this contradicts my younger self
idea that human animals is just a
machine like you can train yourself to
be whatever that's not true okay that's
that's not true so anyway that's so
that's that's kind of my thoughts about
diet and yeah
so let's see what other comments we have
here
okay so nuts nuts it's good for you do
you like green yes big nuts what about
juice what about juice what's the name
of your Island
what is the name of your Island good a
good question
can I have chips and curry and and brew
what is Sam brew man bare pig
so manbearpig says with white rice on
the side chips and curry only brown rice
man pea pig you should check out this
guy called Raymond day he does like
speaking to ghosts and stuff very
interesting
he's on a documentary called Jimmy Show
Oh so Raymond day you know I watched the
lemme show you mean Jimmy right I think
you mean Jimmy I watched a few of Jimmy
show I don't like him I don't like it
Jimmy show he's kind of he's not my
thing because Jimmy show he's like he's
like the American thing okay you you you
know I would say so so his audience kind
of like you need to be a white white
person you know you need to grow up as a
white person you need to grow up in
America I didn't grow up in America so I
that's that's my take on the Jimmy show
because he's he's yeah some shows are
like that you know it's just American
culture like not very very American
culture you know like we talk about any
anyway that's that's my so I don't know
who is the Raymond guy ting Brown says
have you heard of Asian streets meet AC
and street me what do you mean
Cathy says I would like to know your
story with wolf I'm finishing reading
the whole manual of mathematics
Mathematica is crazy my story with
Wolfram I talked about this before
I don't know if you are here well I
talked about this randomly like many
times but however there is one video
Kathy if you just go YouTube search
YouTube sorry
such YouTube sorry a new kind of science
no I'm I'm not going to show it but just
search for that in that video that's one
our video where I talk about it's a
technical topic I talk about the
technical details of a new kind of
science that Stephen Wolfenstein in
Mathematica and cellular automata you
know some I and Turing machines so it's
a theoretical computer science kind of
thing it's it's easygoing so it's not
very technical so it's fun too but it's
not about my story woof yeah yeah go
what should i won so I mean yeah because
that one I mentioned some of the
probably interesting to you so Jamie
says I'm from Scotland okay Scotland has
a special ask accent which is how to
understand brother we only eat favorite
meat and sometimes rat tail that's good
leaming comedy show you absolute muff I
don't know what you sing so I get a
sense that I'm getting a army of the I'm
getting an army from some kind of a Chan
Channel that's flooding my YouTube
stream is am i right because I don't
know all of you guys over sudden you
know all these oh you guys new people
always of finished and cran okay I don't
know what you're saying
okay okay okay okay or what okay what do
you think of Terry Davis yeah that's a
frequently asked question I get asked
that all the time and in my video I talk
about that a few of you times because
Terry Davis is this guy who got
schizophrenia you know you guys go watch
my other videos like I have a video
every day for half a year now many of
the things I'm your I'm your type okay
you guys came in from 4chan or whatever
kind of place I kind of know you guys
okay you are watching me you are here
because I'm kind of your type and same
thing with Terry Davis you know he's
he's the unfortunate guy who's got a
schizophrenia okay there's another video
I did that I talked about
psychology tests personality disorders
schizoid and also schizophrenia you know
when I talk about these people you know
ask me about Terry Davis again you know
all the time so anyway there's a video
one now about that on my youtube I think
it's a main you know featured video you
know so go watch that one so about Terry
Davis I you know he's he's he's got
schizophrenia which is which is a mental
it's actually a biological problem you
see illusions use you see and hear
things that's not there and that's
that's something you don't want to get
okay so he's got that and so he's he's
talking about CIA yellow CIA and Easter
and he's you know he's an incredible
programmer so he he wrote this tempo OS
you know operating system is not my
thing I don't know much about it but
I've seen other people discussing it you
know review it things like that you know
and there are YouTube videos of him so
that's very interesting
and it's unfortunate Terry Davis Davis
away and sook
yeah sad okay I don't know what you
saying you know those those are jargons
and stuff not non speed Lance tbh
forbidden you are a nonce I forgot
what's announced means no I because I
studied that that two weeks ago one it
has a tech taken technical meaning in
cryptography oh yeah so it's a one-time
generated random password or string like
generated one youth used only once use
it once and throw away that's nonce and
that the etymology of that came from
English so let's see so let me show you
guys let me introduce you guys the world
of sabe you guys drove you don't know
what nouns means let me show you
properly what nouns means what is a in o
nce so such a onc okay none now such
because I wrote about this last week two
weeks ago n o nce
yeah it's not there I don't remember
where I broke it let's go to my
programming blog that's search for
annual NCE not there okay there are some
other blogs I'd rather not go to my
blogs that is No
so anyway knows means you words use once
right what's you guys meanings are you
guys do you guys have a special meaning
of that so where you guys came from like
a zero a some some Qian Qian Oh someone
told you guys to come over here what Jet
Li wannabe Bruce you try serious math
bra what's serious mass okay Peter I
heard stuff from a bomb okay
I'm gonna delete okay so this so gun
says if you could choose a scripting
language which would you choose
because you had bash you think Python
sucks you know is left is Perl scripting
language you can use Ruby so between
Ruby Perl Python I would call Ruby okay
in fact well you know scripting language
they becomes less less meaningful these
days because back then you have you have
rather clear distinction between strict
scripting language and non scripting you
know but today for example :
even : you can think of it as a
scripting language even though it runs
as fast as C you know it's it's you know
because : I've showed you know some of
my past videos there's a goal and talk
you can you can just run it without
compile so it's it's almost like
scripting language but however it's it's
the code the number of lines of :
is about 1.5 to 2 times larger than
Python okay I know it because because
I've done many codes in both no I that's
that's why I found out it's unfortunate
because I really love : I wanted to go
to use : for everything but how yes but
: if you code : the number of lines
which will be 1.5 to 2 times probably 2
times is a good number to say in general
than Python so actually I think movie is
a good language but again you know like
10 years ago I would say absolutely use
Ruby but now things are different again
because you know the technology things
change very fast change they change
society change you know the industry
movement direction changes so today
today ruby is kind of you know it's
going you know it's becoming not much
known you know it used to be very
popular ruby is kind of you know dying
out you know it's still used in lots of
startups but it's kind of not as popular
and python today becomes hugely even
more popular and so there's a thing
about about main streams also in many
ways going with main stream has a lot of
advantages so there you go so Python you
know although I don't like Python so but
because you know you have a lot more
tools a lot more community a lot more or
not a lot more than Ruby especially if
you are into scientific programming and
machine learning kind of stuff you know
because they are fashionable Python
becomes so become so popular because
Google I talked about these people you
know is because yeah I have several
video dedicated to Python the whole hour
is about Python but anyway python is
popular because history of Python for
example pepper python is more popular
today because Google
Google and google's AI stuff you know so
python becomes the interface to google's
google's AI engine that is why python is
so popular / instead so don't use po so
i mean so so you could use : and then
python then and today actually today you
see it doesn't make it's almost the case
that it does not make sense to say to
ask you know which is the best scripting
language anymore because as i mentioned
this many times you know this is my main
thing main theme of my videos is that we
are in AI h now artificial intelligence
age scientific growth engineering growth
has been exponential in past 10 20 years
so so so what that means is that it
becomes incomprehensible to a person to
you to me you cannot even know what's
what what what becomes you know what
library so what's going on you you don't
you know forget about you you think you
know maybe you think you know actually
you don't know they are like ten
thousand things going on in technology
you never heard of until maybe you talk
to someone okay in that area that this
is what's going on you think you know
maybe you think oh you are following or
the tech accounts on Twitter you know
all the stuff no you don't know there
they are like ten thousand things going
on you don't know you don't even you you
have never heard of okay so this is the
this is the reality of exponential
growth now so when this is happening and
you know you have these tech companies
or all different tech companies going on
you earn and so today it's almost it
doesn't make sense to ask you know which
scripting language is the best you you
can't learn because that doesn't make
sense anymore but rather what what is
the current you know what what is the
current thing you are doing like AI you
are you working for Google you know or
Facebook or something or are you
there's some project you are doing you
know it's kind of become like that and
depending on your background what you
already know and your friends you know
who are your friends it's become like
that so in this area in particular
gaming community there's this thing you
learnt and you just do that
you know you so as opposed to let's say
twenty years ago the idea of where you
have one language that's a grew language
for everything so you know for example
ten years ago you have the Lua blue.i is
supposed to be the glue language for all
gaming you know things like that you
know but today that idea is kind of
going away rather you just just do what
you need at the time you know you know
and and to by tomorrow that language may
be gone then you just move on that's
that's how things are becoming so
climent says i found your blog when you
did the article about i 3wm okay and i
watched a few of your live stream okay
great yeah that's the that's the that's
the drama dramatic article is every year
every every three year to eat two or
three years it goes on a hacker news and
read it and chan you know or the chance
challenge channel and then you know
so many of you guys I don't know you
where you from and I don't know what you
what is your question you know so I
think that's it for today so hope you
guys have a great great day
Gentiles Chile is a stupid guy okay JB
is this you know I can talk about JD I
can tell you you like typically I guess
you know you guys don't know nothing
about Shetty you guys don't know nothing
about Chinese things like I assume you
guys well first of all you guys are
English speakers and you know then I
assume you guys are American most of you
I guess
oh you know UK oh you know Australia or
Canada but when it comes to other
countries like China you don't know you
don't know Jenni except what Americans
is saying about G no I'm American TV
division you don't know about jelly
jelly jelly he is you know when he was
like 13 years old or something he won
the competition of wushu competition in
China now now I have to explain what
wushu is like you don't know what wushu
is because you think it's just confu you
know that's gonna be another okay I'm
gonna stop
okay I'm gonna explain for two minutes
so two minutes I'm gonna shut down okay
so who sue me in general just show you
okay that's how you spell who sue you
sue is kind of a show it's kind of a
yeah it's a small okay it's a it's kind
of a demonstrative sport that they came
from kung fu
okay came from you know so this is a
typical picture so you know you have
this traditional beautiful Chinese kung
fu clothing you have you know this kind
of thing but but but do realize it's a
show it's a 100 percent sure it has
nothing
it has you know it it is it came from
kung fu but however this would sue
people has nothing to do with actual
martial arts hi Kathy thank you for
watching
so so what sue they they have nothing to
do with actual fighting okay they're
it's a show it's a it becomes a
competitive you know China is trying to
get them into Olympics but anyway it
suggests the show it's a you know show
okay it's a show however it requires
very great it's because it's like
acrobatics okay it's it requires great
extreme agility acrobatic skills you
know things like that okay that's what
wushu is and so gently when he was you
know he's his trainers wusu guy jelly
created Oh Kathy fate
kwang-soo anti-g for several months it
was fun okay that's interesting so Kathy
played Kathy played staff staff that's
that's an English for staff anyway so
what sue so JD when he was like King he
he won the would sue competition which
is very hard okay he wants for several
years he's a champion for several years
then he became you know then he started
to be joining a film okay there's one
theorem that made him famous then he
becomes a movie star okay that's his
type story so when it comes to actual
fighting
chetley is not the guy okay I mean he's
not the actual fight you know he's not
an actual fighter okay
in fact in recent years you know since
about five years ago there's a crisis in
Chinese community about Chinese confu
because today what do you think of
Chinese kung-fu much of it is fake you
know and it's also a money-making
machine you know all these kung fu
masters
they teach kungfu of course they take
your money you have to pay and you you
think you are learning you know great
Taichi oh come for you no but most of it
is is not for actual fighting anymore
it's just a traditional thing it's not
good for fighting like any street
fighter can beat us so there's a crisis
in China started by this this is this
controversial guy in China anyway that's
another story
so anyway buh buh who is about that JD
say so Jet Li became a movie star and he
has starred in many Chinese kung-fu
films becomes he is a superstar then he
became then he then he you know some of
those he became a star in Hollywood you
know for some Hollywood films but JD I
don't like JB okay first of all he's
yeah he's soo you know it looks good
that's great you know that's okay but JD
is the guy he he don't know acting at
all many of these kung fu actors they do
not know acting at all like when you
watch them it makes you sick like it's
not acting he's like they don't know
nothing like zero the worst actor
possible they all they know is you know
just these movements okay so that's it
for today thank you guys bye Cannes
bye and bye Jamey and forbidden and and
and tell tell me where you guys came
from forbidden like what channel like
one of you guys pewter and oh you guys
okay bye