Hello guys, welcome to another
episode of S talk show. So we're going
to do geometric inversion again.
Mathematics and geometry
uh lots of code. So wam language uh
mathematics geometry and I'm just going
to go random. Okay. So if you have
questions post it if you are watching
this offline play at 1.5 speed. Okay,
let's go to uh today's talk show. So,
let me double check. Voice check.
Voice check. This is uh perfect. Volume.
Yes. Video check. Am I good to go? Yes.
It's kind of chaotic here. Uh, okay. Let
me put this up a little bit.
Okay. So, my my mouse, my keyboard, the
keyboard is Gulab 80. This one.
Fantastic. This is Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard 2. Fantastic. I have a review,
video review on my website on YouTube if
you search for it. And this is Sarboard.
S V A L B O A R D. Fantastic.
Okay. Video review on YouTube. Uh so
what we going to do is we I got lots of
things to do. I'm going to demo um a
WOFM language package. Okay. So, wuam
language package geometric inversion.
That's what we going to talk about. So,
this is geometry. I talked about it
multiple times in my past in the past
year or two. So, go to YouTube, search
for it. Okay. So, there are several
things I need to do. Um, you know, I'm
wondering, so anyone here? Hello, Dan.
So, what do you guys like to see? like
you know I can do a full tutorial kind
of explain this geometric inversion
uh
you know so it's a mathematic
mathematics lesson but I've done that
many times in the past and uh oh I just
uh going to do random okay because what
I mean by random because I have a lot of
things to do working on my website let
me show you you know random like what
I've been working on in the past hour.
For example, this is G algebra.
This demonstrates that um
this demonstrates that let's see if I
can track move the curve. Okay. So, so
let's so let's demonstrate that if you
have a um Wait, why did why does it go
through the other way?
Yeah, this is so refresh.
So this is a um this is a curve of
course. Uh well anyway this this
demonstrates that if you have a bunch of
circles where the centers of the circles
all lie on the line like a bunch of
circles horizontal circles then if you
um
if you um
let's see if if you if you
go This is this is about the curve track
tricks. Okay, that's a blue line. That's
a line you get. That's basically the
trail of a bicycle. So, if you have a
bicycle and you go straight uh but you
turn your handlebar.
So, you make a turn then the the uh
the the hind wheel will trace out this
curve. Okay. So that that is about the
tracks. Anyway, that's that's about that
curve. Okay. So I'm I'm kind of like
going random. No focus right now. Did
you major in math or in computer
science? Uh well I went to uh community
college for for two years for three
years but I never got any degree. Okay.
So I studied mostly mathematics in
college. I mean in the community college
basically that's the first two years of
college but mostly
um I do programming okay so I learned
programming mostly by myself
okay there's a bunch of curves so you
can see this is a uh visual dictionary
of special plane curves
uh lots of you know
I got so many of them open right now
because I was working on them on the
gegebra
Okay, I'm kind of confused right now.
So, so let let me focus. Okay, there are
a few things I want to do. So, first of
all, wam language. Have I demonstrated
yet? Okay, so let let's show Wuam
language. Let me show some wam language.
Okay, so um did it start yet?
Uh okay. So, let's start it again. Okay.
Click on that.
Fantastic wam language. Now you can get
it for free. So let's magnify.
three shift enter to evaluate it and uh
magnify so it's easy to see and show
today's talk show I want to show so we
did this I think each one of them live
streamed it so for example you can copy
that code
paste it here so that's a code shift
enter to run it so you got
you got grid and uh after the geometric
inversion transformation it becames it
became that okay that is that so that's
one example then there's other
variations
uh we did this coding live sometimes in
uh let's you know let's show so some
others so this one is uh one of the one
of the graphics I created I'm most proud
of. So let's say too big.
So here's a code about 30 lines of code.
Shift enter to evaluate it. So first of
all you draw a bunch of grids. Then you
apply the geometric inversion. So you
got this uh like still two-dimensional.
Then all you have to do is you add a
dimension to it. Then you got this
beautiful tile. Okay. This is the most
beautiful uh and so this is a geometric
inversion of a grid. You begin with a
grid but however here's the extra. Okay.
So so here is the extra. So what you
want you don't want is that you see when
you in apply geometric inversion to a
bunch of grid you got this center which
is a lot of um let's see if I can like
magnify the center or something.
So click on that. Uh
shift no control no control shift no uh
shift click. Oh yeah. So you can
enlarge. So you see the closer wait.
So the closer they are to the center
they became more crowded. Okay. But if
you want this as a garden tile, you
don't want that because they become
infinitely small. So what you do is you
create a way to you find a way to uh the
final result is that you don't want them
to be crowded in the middle. So what you
do is first of all you create this image
on the left. So they become super
crowded in the middle. Then after you
invert then then they became equally
distanced like that. So it's a beautiful
image. So I'm pretty proud of this
design. Uh you know you have to do some
thinking to create this. So here's the
code. Shift enter.
So you see first first of all we create
this image which is super crowded in the
middle. Now why is it not uh a uh
scalable?
Well, it is okay. So you see then then
you apply the inversion then you get
that then you add um you add a dimension
you you make it three-dimensional.
So So here is a whole three-dimensional
code. There it is
about 100 lines. Shift enter. So there's
one there's that there is
three-dimensional image and this is the
final result. Beautiful.
So so you can you can put this in your
backyard as a tiles of a garden. You see
you can see the pattern of a circle
there. Many you know many circles there.
So anyway, I'm I'm kind of going over um
then inversion is always fascinating.
Yes, video audio. Okay, I'm kind of
going over what what is it I want to do,
you know. So I wanted to So that's some
like fancy demonstration of geometric
inversion. And this one is inversion of
a three-dimensional lattice, you know,
like grid lines. So let's paste it. Uh
very simple code. So you can see you
create this kind of image.
You begin with the you know the the the
grid of course. So this one I think. So
let's try that.
Paste run it. So you begin. So this one
is like fancy grid.
Uh okay then. Okay. Then you have the
simpler grid. Then you have another v
variation. This is a grid without you
know the without the edges kind of cube
without the edges but with the cross
center lines. And then you have another
variation.
Uh then here is their inversion. So you
can see there there
fantastic.
Okay. So I just wanted to show some demo
of the inversion so that um
so it gets you interested in this this
geometry and the wolf language. Okay.
So,
so you can download it for free on on
this link. Download Wuam engine
um and turn on JavaScript.
Okay. So, you can find my link uh just
search for Kasali Wam language for
programmers kasali.info. Okay. And here
is a download link and you also you know
just read about them. So
so you know it explains what's the
difference between wam language
mathematica wam engine and wufam script.
Then you also want to download the wraim
the jupitter notebook.
So that way you can get graphics. Okay,
you can you get have graphics
or you just pay for wuam language you
you know you pay for them. Okay, so what
so that's just like that's just intro uh
there's some many things I want to do I
need to do. Okay. So,
uh
but uh it's hard.
Hello. Tid. Okay. So, what what is the
next I want to do? Yeah. So, let's go uh
let's let's go to the directory. So, I
got a bunch of to-dos.
Uh
that's Emacs. So here is uh change of
the syntax this code. Uh here is yeah
I'm Yeah. So I want to uh change some
syntax and stuff.
Okay. So this one I want to redo and
using SVG. Okay. And here is change the
file name. Okay. So, okay, let's do
them.
Okay, so this is just going to be my
work session then. Okay, so if you have
questions, ask me. Okay,
otherwise it's just me working on this.
Um,
so inversion of a line. So all these are
bunch of G algebra applications. This is
the inversion of a line. So that shows
let's see. So this blue line the
inversion of the blue line is the red
circle. So you can see there
now um
let's change the title there.
Uh so all these let's make
add the Jbra title there. Okay do it.
That's done. Go back here. refresh.
Okay, that's good. Uh,
so here is the index of all G algebra
files.
Okay, so what what what uh
Okay, inversion. So I need to rename
that. So
okay, so here is a file I want to rename
this. So instead of just inversion it
should say geometric inversion. Okay. So
I got a command you can see in a pink
window. Press press press press. Okay.
So this should be gmet
metric. Do I have that? No.
Okay. Do it. It'll change. You'll go
through my 7,000 files and find the
appropriate links and change them all.
So, it's all changed. Okay. So, that is
done.
Delete it. So, you can see if you
refresh, you can see and you go through
that page, you can also see. So this
this page shows the most basic
definition of geometric inversion which
is
so given a point P it becomes this point
Q.
So if P is smaller Q becomes larger if P
is smaller Q becomes P if P is larger Q
becomes smaller. So this geometric
inversion is just like 1 /x.
Okay. So this rename is done. Let's go
here. So that that page I need SVG. Uh
there's a lot to do here because I need
to write a um I need to write a wam
language code that converts
that converts to SVG. Wuam language can
do it but however it's got some issue.
So let let me demo. Okay. So let's demo
um this one. Geometric inversion of a
regular polygon. Okay. So close that.
Close that. So this is the Jupyter
notebook. Close that. So this is
download. Close that. And uh here is
let's see where is that? That's
somewhere here I believe.
No, here. Okay. So, you can apply
geometric inversion to these bunch of
octagons. Let's see. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8.
So, each one of them is a octagon. When
you lay them on a grid, you got this
pattern. Kind of beautiful. Then you
apply the geometric inversion to them.
Then it becomes this pattern. Okay. So,
here's a code. You, you know, you can
copy it and copy it and paste it and and
shift control T to make it type set.
Okay, I don't want I don't want this
form. Shift control N. Wait, what? Why
is uh
kind of very uh too large? Okay, so I
mean leave it. Okay. Shift enter to run
it. So there it is. And there it is.
Okay. So what is it I want to do? Yeah.
So I want to demonstrate export to SVG.
Okay. So
um this is kind of too large.
Wait.
So, shift controll and shift control i
to turn it into input form. Shift
control n.
Okay. So,
what I want to do is
if you run this, you get this picture.
You can export it to, you know, this is
GR1. So, for example, GR1 shift enter.
So, that's the output. Then you can say
export.
Okay. Export GR1. Then you just say SVG.
Something like that. Uh yeah, a name. So
wait the name first. So you say uh
octans SVG. Octagons SVG. Then you say
GR1. Okay, I believe that's a syntax.
Uh, shift enter to run it. Okay, it's
done. Let's look at the documentation.
Yeah, file name first and uh the
expression. So, so now we go to download
wait document
I believe then search for octagon. There
it is. So, that's a SVG file. So, open
it. uh in Emacs it shows it but now you
can go uh switch to some HTML mod which
also work works for XML files. SVG files
are just just XML.
So you can see the file size is 88
kilobytes. Okay. Now if you copy it, go
to today's talk show and let's paste it
somewhere here. What is this? Uh okay,
so let's make it.
So paste it that make a link. Okay, it
become then let's move this into talk
show. Okay, so I call a command cassad
rename file. Uh, wait, not that. Casar
rename kasa html move. Uh, cancel
cancel.
Okay, now do it. Press press
HTML move source file path into talk
show page. Okay, then you can see it's
there. Close it. Show in browser. Go to
the bottom. There it is the SVG.
So you can export X SVG. But however,
there's a problem. Now if the image
contains a circle, it
it doesn't export them in the SVG native
circle. Instead of it creates a bunch of
lines to emulate the circle. So the
result is that the the the file size is
going to be unne unnecessarily 10 times
larger.
Uh can we show example? Yeah, sure. So
okay. So let's Okay. Yeah, I need to do
this anyway. So let's do a wam language.
I'm using kasawa mod. If you are using
Emacs, you can search for it. You'll
find it. Okay.
So here is Kasaw Wuan mod. Go to the
source code. Go to the top. Go to the
URL. Open show in browser. Search for
that. You'll find it and it's available
on GitHub.
Okay. So close that. Close that. Now
let's do uh circle.
Okay. Circle. You need a center 0 and
you need a radius one. Okay. Now that's
a graphics. Let's say xxx equals to
that. And now let's say export
uh export
uh yes and uh circle. Okay. Name it
circle svg and xx. In fact, we don't we
actually we can just put the xx in that
expression. Okay. Now if I run it, it'll
export this SVG. Okay. Now run it. do
it.
Okay.
Refresh. Search for circle. Circle.
Wait, where did it go? Uh, it went to
what?
Uh, what where did the file go? Wrote
wrote um
I don't where where did the saved SVG?
So, because let's do it again. Okay. So,
wait. Let's go to download. Okay.
Uh, refresh.
Wait, not download. Let's go to
documents.
Refresh.
Search for Cir.
Okay, it's not there.
So, where is it? So, okay, it's is saved
in the current directory. So, there it
is. Okay, open that. So, that's SVG.
Okay, this is incorrect. It actually
just kind of screenshot the expression.
Okay. So, let me show you. Copy. Copy
the file path. Close it. Put it back and
put that there. Linkify it. Show in
browser. Go down. So, you can see it
actually kind of just screenshot that
text. That's not what we want because I
forgot something. So,
open it. Delete it. remove this image
link and go back to this expression. Pop
it up and and uh so what's missing is
that here this circle needs to be a
graphics object. So we have to do
graphics. Okay, then put that inside.
Okay, then that's what you want.
Okay, there. Then you evaluate this
file.
Done. Here's your result. Go to the
directory. There it is. Copy the file
path. Well, open it first. Then you can
see a circle. Now make it s HTML mod.
Press press.
Then we can see now we can see the
source code. So you can see it's one
single line of path.
So let's say let's make it uh you see
so what this demonstrate is that when
you export a graphics that contains a
circle it doesn't use the SVG's native
circle primitive. Instead it use SVG
path.
So you got this whole bunch of points to
emulate the circle. Okay. So do you guys
know what I'm saying? Am I doing well?
Uh so the question what's the basic idea
behind inversion in general okay let me
explain that uh but I explained that so
many times in my several videos uh just
search for inversion on YouTube
but but I'm going to explain that. Okay
so anyway the SVG so uh if you don't
know search for SVG tutorial on si.info
you'll find it. So SVG is just a XML
file. So here is the most simplest SVG
XML just like HTML. So if you put this
in a browser, you're going to get that
line. And here is a complete source
code. So if you say rec rex something x9
y zero width height and the style field
green stroke blue something something
you get rectangle okay so this x svg
stand for scalable vector graphics very
simple it's just like html okay but they
have so but you have bunch of primitives
you know you have rectangle you have Uh
you have line
rectangle wctck then you can make it
round corner by using you know the
attribute rx r y and you have a circle
primitive circle you can see with cx cy
for center and r for radius. So that is
one of the primitive of a circle
and here is in combination with
JavaScript. So you can kind of draw an
arc uh move up and down and you can
let's say start angle and sweep angle
and what is this? Yeah, you can change
your arc and you can change rotation and
you can do a elliptical art uh here
which is
you know change the elis change that
major radius
uh circle arc. So there is another
application where is it
anyway so that's the basics of SVG but
the issue here it is that when you
export a circle it doesn't use a circle
primitive
so if it does then
oh god I you know I kind of you know
explaining all these things um which I
did before. So let's paste the link.
So So the issue is that if you don't use
the circle then you going to have lots
of you know the file size is going to be
huge. Now where is this one? Uh octagon
documents.
Wait.
Okay. Close it. Close it. Close it.
Close it.
Uh now go back here. So you see
the problem is it use this path
primitive. So it creates lots of you
know numbers in between. But in fact you
just need center and radius.
So you need to write a uh code to export
yourself. Basically, you want to turn a
wam language graphics
like
you know like this line. This line is a
graphics. So you want to turn that. So
basically you want to write a program
that turns this expression into a string
you know SVG string. Can we do that?
Yes, that's what I have to do. Okay.
So you you need to write a function uh
let's say uh export
uh export SVG
uh let's say
you know wam language does not allow
dash or underscore so you need to define
your function so basically what we can
do is something like that okay so that
then you take a expression that
basically returns a string screen that
is this
SVG
but to write that um let's make this
HTML you know to write write that it's
it's going to be a bit involved I mean
that's going to take
uh it's going to take like half an hour
um
you know because So
actually let's rename this uh to SVG
string. Okay. So
well SVG.
Okay. And uh basically return a string
a return a string of SVG code that
represents
the
expression. Okay. Uh the expression expr
here.
Okay, that's a function I need to write.
Why do I need to write that? Because in
my work I have huge amount of um
huge amount of wam language graphics
that requires a circle. For example,
this is sign curve
and uh I want to export to SVG instead
of bitmapped graphics. Why all these are
right now bitmapped graphics. Why do I
want SVG? Because bitmapped graphics are
not scalable. So for example, open this
image. Go to that and uh enlarge. As you
can see, the more you enlarge, they
become more ugly. They become jagged.
You see? But with SVG,
this doesn't happen. You can enlarge
however large you want
and you can see that if you uh you know
I have a lot articles uh okay let me
explain that shall we okay so go to okay
let's open that open that okay sour
search SVG just type SVG
and uh you can see 38 articles about SVG
and one of them is so there's a lot of
talk shows in the past about SVG
uh and one of them is um so you search
SVG and let's see there there it is
canvas versus SVG open that
canv canvas is another technology for
two-dimensional graphics on the web okay
so you can see this here is the
difference between canvas and SVG.
So here is a canvas. You can now let's
enlarge the page. So you can see canvas
remains
fuzzy if you enlarge it.
You see, but the SVG is very sharp.
So that's the difference. That's a major
difference. canvas is a bitmapped
technology created by Apple around 2008
or so. Uh it's not good. Well, it's
suitable for video games. So, if you
which is the biggest market, you know,
if you do video games, if you sell video
games, you know, lots of people, most
people play video games especially on
the phone,
then you use canvas.
Okay. But otherwise SVG is a kind of
much better technology if you need
illustrations and all that. So that is
why because my website mathematics
there's a lot illustration. So I want
them in
SVG. So what so what I can do is to um
so where is my page? Okay. So, so what I
can do is
you know use wir language to generate
all this code easily and this animation
for example then export them to SVG so
that on the web it remains beautiful
and the file size is very small. For
example, right now this is a MP MP4
uh video file
fairly large. So that is the reason I
want to um you know uh ex use SVG but I
need to write this function. Okay. So
how do you do that?
Uh I can do that.
I can kind of start to show you how to
write that program but that would be
kind of advanced wam language coding.
It's not actually it's not too difficult
though. So first of all first of all we
need to um
let's okay let me show you the basics.
Okay clear.
So you want to clear that first then you
want to define it using this way. Uh I'm
not going to explain why but um
uh so what what what is the expression
you want? Yeah, let's just say
h let's just say something graphics.
Okay. And then you just basically return
a string and uh the first part of the
string is going to be let's quote this.
Okay. So
escape quotes. So they become kind of
you know they become a string. So you
need to copy the whole thing.
Cut it. Make it string. Paste. Now they
become a string. Well, except
there's still something
that's
uh
you see you run into the escape sequence
issue. So,
oh yeah. So, that
uh
So what is uh so right now so this is
wra language right now we are in wam
language okay so this whole thing needs
to be a string
and uh
but beginning here something went wrong.
Uh, woofam language string is very
similar to emac. This string
they you know you need a lot backslash.
There's only one way to do a string you.
So unlike Python you can have triple
quotes or whatever or here do dark in
pearl in PHP in Ruby or in PowerShell
you can quote them in se several ways so
you don't need to have lots of this
escape but in
this e emac this and common disp
quotation mark and whatever if you
contain quotation mark inside you need
to escape it. So right now we are
running into that issue you need to like
escape which is very uh nasty and but
now something is wrong I because you can
see by the color some you know the
coloring is not correct that means
something is getting screwed. Okay.
Uh do I want to go through them? Nah,
because but anyway so so so right now
this whole thing is just a string.
That's what you want to return. But
but what we want to do is that when this
argument contains a circle or line, you
want to turn them into uh turn them into
a circle. Okay. So, okay, I'm starting
to get into the direction of how to
write this. Uh, but I haven't explained
uh inversion yet,
but but I did explain that many times
before. Okay. So, let's go back. So, let
me just finish continue uh in the
direction I'm going about writing this
code in Woof language.
Okay. And so what so I what we want
right now is the SVG. Where where is our
SVG uh there? Okay. So we go to SVG. Go
to the SVG basics. You want the syntax
for a circle. So copy that.
So in fact actually
ignore all that Uh ignore that.
Let's redo fresh. Okay. That's basically
that's what we want. Okay. So make it
one line. Make it one line. And now s
escape quotes. Now put a quote. Okay,
that is what we want. But
the coloring is still That's
because
that is because my mod I think my mod is
not working properly. My woofer mod. But
anyway, delete that. Uh actually you
need also you need this kind of uh
I'm I'm smelling something burned. Okay.
So let me double check.
See if I got anything in the kitchen.
Why on earth would it be export uh why
on earth would it be exported as a path
of lines instead of a primitive circle?
There's a good reason for that. There's
a solid
um well there's there's there's there's
a there's a reason for that because in
practice in fact if you look at on the
web
suppose you are God you can look at all
SVG files that exist on the web they
basically all are just using path.
Uh okay so that's a good question. For
example in SVG you do have these
different you know primitives ellipse
you have also polygon here you you know
you have several different type of
primitives circle rectangle
but
in practice if you look at the real
world they are all just using
uh not even a line they are all just
using path. Okay. So here they are all
just using path because path is the most
powerful. They generalize and kind of
the most simple to deal with. I mean in
a sense because you just deal with path
uh and uh and and path can also actually
create a circle kind uh yeah
fairly complicated you know because it
can do the cubic spline and stuff. So,
so basically in practice if you look at
the web they all the SVG are just path
especially
you know
uh computer generated like like
illustrator application they are all
become path
yeah especially generated code the
reason is that because it's most general
you you know you don't have to deal with
all the special cases
uh and yeah and you know for example
when you have a polygon That's just a
path of four points. Uh
uh and al also for rectangle also for
line you don't need a line or you don't
need a line you know it's all path but
in the case of circle and rectangle
and can you like emulate by path itself?
Uh I don't remember. I think so. Okay.
So we have to go check with the circle
arc. Let's see what's the code. Yeah,
path. Okay. So even a circle is just a
path. So the path primitive is the most
powerful. It it generalized. So it can
represent everything.
So that is why in practice every
generated SVG they are all just using
path.
Now, now but it the path is fairly
complicated because if you want to
generate this circle, you can do it like
that or you can just have a path of like
100 points.
So anyway the reason is that path is you
know it's just easy to deal with and uh
in practice and uh therefore
therefore in wam language they don't you
know they don't bother to create a
specialized
uh output for circle that's why
I you know I I so the question is is it
a flaw I mean is is that a imperfection
so if you are at WOFM and if you are
responsible is respons responsible for
writing the export
function you know the export function
can export like literally
hundreds
file formats if not thousands. Okay. So
be you know because they export
SVG you know scalable graphics format
but also any bit map formats you know
such as JPEG, PNG, GIF or GIF animation
or any video formats. There are like
tens of video formats and tens of image
formats and there are three
threedimensional
uh CAD
object formats and there are tens of
them.
So the export actually ex this this
single function export all of them. Uh
so you can see um
and also sound formats there are like
tens of sound formats over the years. So
for example here is all the sound
format. So here is exporting wam
language graphics and sound and okay and
this EPS PDF SVG picked format WMF
Windows metaf file format TF another
image format used to be popular in '90s
like huge you know very rich format t
gif jpeg png bmp that's windows pcx
that's like I think that's idiotic image
format x XBM. Yeah, that's X Windows A
as based text picture images. Then AVI
audio video. Um, so that's about
exporting the sound format. Wave AU SND
AF.
Then XDF that's autocad
three-dimensional
uh object format.
Okay. So this this this export uh
function export to basically effectively
all format that ever existed
and either popular or standardized.
Okay,
export everything. So now so you can
look at there's a uh document that list
all the
possible formats it shows somewhere.
Okay. Uh there it is. Okay, look at this
variable export format. So you can see
um
that okay so we can evaluate it. That's
that's a building constant.
Any name that begin with a dollar sign
that means a building variable. Okay. So
shift enter to evaluate it. So you got
this bunch of and copy the last output
and let's do postfix notation and let's
say length.
So it exports 200
uh different formats.
So I mean so back to the question. So if
you are you know wolf research developer
you know you write this you know nobody
can write this actually it takes
different engineers to because each of
these format TGF you know TGA TGF tRG
you know they have a specification
and so it's not trivial and it also
export HTTP request HTTP response I'm
not even sure what um
h interesting. So each one of these
format is you know very specialized and
they have usually a standard document
you know specification. So
so it's not trivial to you know it's not
likely one person do it do it all. So
anyway, but if you are, you know, a
developer at Wufam, you you so one of
the export format is SVG. So
you need to So the question is
when you have a circle in Wam language,
do you want to do you want the SVG
output to contain using the circle
primitive?
Now the bas basically yes you do okay
for example in our simple case because
in this simple case there's no reason
you know you don't want it to generate
uh like
you know this this stupid path with 100
points right but however it can get very
complex because the wolfam circle let's
look at the documentation the woofam
circle like uh wait Uh okay wait what?
Oh okay so you need to what uh do that
the wolfam graphics primitive which are
different from SVG. So wam graphics
primitive the circle let's enlarge
the circle can also represent a lisp
okay
and also a sector of it
okay and then so you know wam has its
own tens of graphics primitives
so if you want to export circle to
circle then you need to deal with all
the possible variations S. So when it's
a simple circle, yes, you can it
corresponds to a SV SVG circle. Okay.
But when you got a circle with a um you
know ellip ellipse circle, then the SVG
circle cannot do it. Let's see.
So let's go back to SVG circle. So let's
see circle circle path uh basics. So the
SVG circle can only represent a circle.
But if you want a ELISP, you need to use
the Elisp. Okay. So there are two
different cases.
Okay.
But then if you want a sector then the
SVG circle can do not cannot do neither
of them. You need to you need to use a
path.
Okay, that's the complexity. So use you
need to use a path for that circle.
Okay, we got there.
Uh
and that is just the um
that is just a circle primitive example.
It gets very complex because then you
got um
you know you let's say you you go to the
list of all the graphics primitives
let's say for two-dimensional graphics
because you also have three-dimensional
graphics. Now where can we click on
that?
Okay, let's open
uh the graphics function. Then let's go
to a page where it lists all graphics
primitives. Okay, details and options.
Uh so you can have different triangles,
arrows, speed spline curve, basia curve,
circum sphere, disk field curve and this
graphics complex which is a kind of
complex and efficient format array based
then you got infinite line then you got
image which is uh for bit map images.
So if you're gonna write a export
graphics just let's you know limit it to
2D case to SVG then you gota deal with
all of these so it becomes very
non-trivial
and especially then especially then you
have color you know you have color
specification
arrow head different kind of arrow head
shape you know and thickness then
dashing you know what kind of dashing
and the edge age form and you know so it
becomes very complex
and then especially then you deal with
uh hyperlink
event handlers
status area style uh button tool tips
you know so
so that is why okay so um
I believe that's why because I have you
know I because I've actually written uh
things like this before exporting wam
language to another uh math graphics
format
gets very complex because also similar
situation is if you want to export
something to HTML
let's say uh from oak mod it becomes you
know the the possibilities how you going
to do it is becomes very complex
okay That is why that's kind of
elaborate answer to the question why
wuam language doesn't just export this
circle plainly.
Okay, I think I rambled too much. Um
then you have then you have a question
of
how many people watching? Let's see. Is
it just like one people?
Five. Okay.
Well, the question about
what is uh you know what's a what's
what's a inversion the simply okay let
me explain this okay let me explain that
okay for the nth time
uh let's go to inversion
uh there geometric inversion okay just
let's think of the line okay so this you
know forget about that circle just think
of a plain line from zero to one you
know 0 1 2 3 you know a line array
so if you have a point P okay okay so so
let's suppose this circle here is radius
one so here you have a point one so this
O is zero so 0 to one a segment so you
have a point on the line so this point
is let's say X so
if X is one
then the inverse of x that is 1 /x is
also one right now if x is let's say two
okay so x is this p so if x is two then
what is 1 / two well that is 0.5
that is this q you see here okay so if x
is one Then 1 / 1 is still one. If x is
larger
is you know let's say x is 2 then 1 /
two it becomes 0.5.
Okay. So if x is three then you have 1
over 3 which is 0.333
which is what this green dot
position. So but basically the larger
the x becomes
then 1 /x becomes very small. Okay. So x
becomes 10,000.
What? So what is 1 /x is 1 over 10,000.
So that's 0.00001.
Okay. So x can be a million, a billion,
a praillion, a gigab billion, a billion
of a billion. Then one /x is 0 something
something billion ga billion zero
one. Okay. So that's the basic concept
of arithmetic inversion 1 /x.
Uh then are you still here? So does that
explain? I mean you get you know you get
what I mean by that right? So if you are
here say you know say hi if you are
still here you know just make sense so
people can see there's a interaction.
So that's arithmetic in inversion just 1
/x
now so but what about geometric
inversion basically it's exactly just
that but you extend it to two
dimensional plane
so everything is just the same. So the
inversion of a P is this point Q but now
you can cover the entire plane. Okay. So
you know but you can also just think of
you know just like 1 /x but now you can
like like rotate it. Okay. And you can
define it.
So how do you define it? How do you
extend it to like a plane of 1 /x? Well,
you can define it by uh let's see if we
can magnify this page. Yes, we can.
So, you you you it's just any point uh
let's see if we can. So, any what?
Okay. So any point uh let's see can we
yeah any point on the plane
we can find its inversion point Q
and the way you do that is for the given
point P
the inversion point is such that OP the
distance distance from OP times the
distance from OQ Q is equals to 1 which
is the radius of the circle. Okay. So
again OP * OQ equals to 1.
So when P is very large you know very
far away you OP is very large then you
need to time a very small number to
become one.
And when P is very small, I mean the OP
distance is very small, then you need to
time a very large number for their
result to be one. Exactly. Just like 1
/x.
So you know 1 /x is basically just like
x * y = 1, right? So that's a uh that's
idea for geometric inversion in a plane.
And the same thing applies to
threedimensional or fourdimensional.
Okay.
So that is the idea. Okay.
Yeah. So that's a geometric inversion.
And this turns out this is my favorite
concept in mathematics of all math. You
know some some some are more complicated
like manifold
uh uh topology. You know you have very
complicated or algebraic geometry or
differential equations or integrals or
derivatives. you know of all the concept
in mathematics all the the complex
number or the oiler identity
uh you know I equals to you know pi or
the pi you know the constant pi and
other constants of all the concepts in
math all fractals like manda broad said
but I think it turns I think you know I
feel that this this inversion is my
favorite idea of all math
concepts. Okay. And it's kind of like
also one of the fundamental idea because
inversion basically is the
basically from algebraic point of view
it is inversion is basically
from group theory point of view you need
uh you need so it's about multiplication
and identity. Okay, multiplicative
identity. Basically, you got two
elements X * Y equals to 1. And what is
that one? One is like an object that
represent identity. Okay. So, so
inversion of a object is basically such
that
when you multiply together them, they it
be they become the identity. Okay,
that's so so that's kind of uh
fundamental in that way. So this is um
multiplicative identity which is
typically represented by the by by one.
There is of course another identity uh
which is called addictive identity which
is usually represented by zero. Okay. So
that's you know basic algebraic
concepts. So that is why zero and one
they are almost they are kind of the
most most important number in the entire
mathematics. Zero and one you know you
can think of them as numbers. Then you
got zero which means nothing. One is
like one thing the most basic one thing.
So that's when you think of them as
numbers. But however in mathematics they
are like they are not just numbers they
are like the the whole entire algebra.
So zero is actually just a object that
represents the uh arithmetic identity
and one is the multiplicative identity.
So you got these two operations uh
multiplication and uh
uh addiction and together they
represents
algebra you know you know groups and uh
and vectors algebraic fields and and all
that.
Okay, that's uh that's kind of like
rambling some mathematics which I know
some
and uh
but we are not going anywhere
because
uh and I'm like um
because I want to write this code. I
didn't finish writing it. Nor did I
do a good job like explaining wraim
language but I kind of went through
so it's kind of because this
doesn't benefit me. I just wasted one
hour rambling you know. You know the
more ideal is that either I explain some
something fundamental like how do you
write a function in wine language then
how do you can uh you know write write
turn expression into SVG or either I can
just code it uh at least come up with a
result I can show but that's not the
case
okay and then let's see what else then
there's a bunch of other things I try to
explain where wam language export to
SVG. Yeah, we did that. But it's kind of
esoteric. Uh what else? I think that's
it. Okay. So that is so what I'm doing.
This is kind of you know what I'm doing
every day. Uh working on that on them.
But
but usually it takes like tremendous
time just to explain what's going on.
Uh yeah, I think that's it. Any any
else? Anything else?
Okay, I think that's it. We went over
actually wow 70 minutes.
Oh
Uh what are all these? Oh Okay.
Bye guys.
Uh so it's today it's going over it's
fairly technical and obscure and stuff
but pretty some pretty graphics.
Uh this this one is the most beautiful.
This this is actually my you know
because m because this one involves
involves my own creativity.
You can kind of see the circular
patterns hidden there.
Okay. Bye.
Good night. Good night then. Have a good
day.