hello welcome to another episode of Star
Talk Show today we are going to code
Advent of code
in Wolfram language and possibly also in
JavaScript in Golan in emac bisp
uh and uh
python probably not python because
python is very popular you guys already
know there's a lot you know python
answers so mostly Wolfram language
coding and maybe JavaScript okay event
of code let's see how far we can go
okay so what is advantage of code it's
coding puzzle now an event of code is a
Christian thing so this guy is a
Christian he
you know he so I'm not a Christian but
this would be fun oh well there's a time
there's a timer oh okay so at the end of
a code is a bunch of coding you know
programming puzzles or you know exercise
so there are 25 of them and basically
you come to the day of Christmas
something like that it's a Christian
thing
so and and uh so you know 25 problems it
opens like two problems every day you
know until the day of Christmas and uh
so let's see how far we can go and I'm
thinking you know I'm going to do a
series of live stream uh YouTube you
know so I'll be coding wolfam language
and possibly also JavaScript or emac
bisp okay just show you just to show you
you know the language differences you
know because I'm interested in
programming languages so you can see
different differences in how different
programming languages
uh solve this problem in particular
within language emac this these two are
like
uh unusual you know with respect to the
programming industry JavaScript a lot of
people know
okay so event of code
25 problems two problems a day let's see
how far we can go so a series of live
streams and I hope it's going to be fun
you know I'm just gonna take my time and
chat about it and you know go through it
so if you are watching this offline you
know you might want to skip around or
maybe it's boring okay
you know I'm gonna be chatty and talking
to you guys good morning or flamio and
uh
Neo Pagan okay
okay so yeah so the Christian thing so
you know what is advent okay Advent of
code event Christianality
you know apparently they have this
Christian
uh
c-h-i-s-t-i-a-n uh
and let's just say Christian okay
Christianity okay Advanced Christian
Church okay what
I'm not sure what is advent holiday
season scholars believe that during the
fourth and fifth centuries in Spain and
go Advent was is was a
season of preparation for the best
baptism of new Christians at the January
Feast of epiphany
Epiphany that's a that's the English
word so
um
yeah something like that
okay anyway Advent of code okay so let's
let's call it you know is uh programming
problem
so you go to this website or doing an
eventofco.com and you'll start to see
you know the questions so I already read
it it's like a story so it's kind of um
you know it gives you it describe the
problem
in a way of a story so it's not like
math it's it's not like a math quiz you
know just some of these you know this is
input this is up what we want and do it
you know instead you have to read a
story
so I already already uh read it so you
know 25 problems each problem for each
problem you get two stars so if you do
all of them correctly you get 50 stars
that's uh that's your score okay so the
first one
and so far it's already 12 problems are
open okay so those first one you know it
talks about stars so let me talk about
something uh interesting okay so you
know Santa Claus
uh
let's go search okay uh Brave search is
a new search engine that's independent
of the Google's engine or Microsoft's
engine so you might want to try that
you know so every year you have Santa
Claus that goes around every house to
deliver gifts to good boys or good girls
uh so and uh the way he does that is he
rides uh snow uh
sled something like that and you have
the reigning Diaz these are the burdens
of Beast you know helping him going
around
so you have any ideas but you also have
elves helping Santa okay so so for uh so
let's you know that's a story of the
kind of Christian Story I mean if you
dig deeper there's you know it's a
mixture of stuff so but anyway the
conventional the cultural the American
culture of Christmas is this kind of
story and pictures
uh what what is it suggesting me
Roblox okay Roblox is the worst idiotic
game for kids
uh okay so uh what I want to see okay uh
Santa elves
okay so you have the elves helping Santa
to make the gifts then you know the
center delivers delivers them with the
help of reindeer okay that's the
background of the story
okay so you need to click so
let me Showtime it you know I'm talking
too much so 25 problems each problem you
get two stars okay so you need to solve
them the first problem is this the
problem of the calories counting
Counting calories it's a bit long so I
won't be reading it you know just go to
the website and you can read it so
basically
you are going to a trip with the elves
to a forest to collect fruits for the
raining deers okay
and uh but in order to do so you know
each elves have to carry food for
themselves so each elf and uh and you
know they carry food so the first elf
has three food items and and each one
you know one of them has one one
thousand calorie this you know the other
item has two thousand calorie and third
item is three thousand calorie so that's
the that's the one of the elves carrying
and another house is carrying a food one
single food item of four thousand
calories and the other another elf has
two items one is five thousand calories
and another is six thousand calories so
um so you have a bunch of elves each elf
carries one or more items of food and
each item has a number of calories so
your problem
your problem I mean your so this is your
input a list of numbers a list of groups
grouped num numbers your your
what you need to do is you need to find
which elf carries the most number of
calories okay so that's that's a trivial
introductory problem all you have to do
is send them some each group you know
some that some that some that some that
and the return the biggest number you
know so it's very very trivial problem
you know from last year I didn't code it
last year but our friends on Discord
they have coded a advantage of code 2021
last year so they have
created many Creative Solutions in
Python in Ruby in Rust in Oak one guy
did it in Oak you know so it's it's fun
you know
but this year
you know so from what I understand the
problem progressively gets harder okay
so the first problem very easy trivial
you know so let's let's do it in
Mathematica okay so I I was told the
input is a string so let's start buffan
language
uh okay so yeah so if you guys uh
questions comments posted okay so new
notepad let's magnify and let's say
three evaluate it to start the Wolfram
kernel okay the Wolfram computational
engine
okay let's begin coding so yeah there it
is so first of all the input is a string
I was told it's not clear according to
the question but I was told you know you
can assume it to be a string as opposed
to a file or at least you know already
given data structure but anyway it's a
string string so okay so I want I want
to say x x equals to there so uh so we
have the input
Okay so
so first job is that we want to you know
remember we want to sum the numbers
uh and pick out the biggest number so
first of all we need to you know we
cannot work with strings but we need we
want to convert it to a
list of lists okay each sublist is
one else
you know list of calories Okay so
so string two list let's see if there is
a
uh there's no string to list so there is
a split string I think
no okay so Wolfram language
let's see
split okay string split Maybe
okay there it is
string split you can click on that to
get the documentation or you can just do
for example question mark
and it will return the doc the kind of
the documentation short form for what
this function do this is wufam language
now if you don't know if I'm language I
talked before many introduction uh
actually I need I want to show it so
move from language copy the link and go
here and
and post it here link if I make a list
showing browser here's today's talk show
so later on you can click on the YouTube
and go to this page and you can see our
notes okay so we have you know you go so
I did many many woven language tutorials
you can go there download it and Order
introductory information okay it's one
of the my favorite language it's uh in
my opinion it's a magnitude in terms of
power and express accessibility
a magnitude Beyond any existing language
including Lis Pascal or whatever okay so
move from language I've been coding it
since 1990 3. okay so so yeah so go
there and check it out okay so now but
today we uh we are going to
so we got
um what else so today yeah okay so
let's delete this part we don't need
okay so back to Wolfram language so
string split
uh
uh splits a string into a list okay
that's what we want so
okay that's the syntax so you give it a
string XX
okay there it is
okay but actually
um you see
this way it splits by the end of line
character so but what
you know of this string but what you
want is you want to group these three
numbers together you know so each
every two empty lines you want to split
into a group okay so how do we do that
let's see string split
so we give a pattern Street split into a
substring separated by delimiters
matching the string expression okay
let's let's just try it
so now by default it assumes
one end of the line character but now we
want two let's see what it turns up
okay so let's say length
and length
a percentage size stands for the output
above so there it is so length five so
let's see let's go back to the original
problem
so one two three four five that's
correct
but uh let's see
let's see the full structure so now is
so now X list okay let's assign it to a
variable so let's we can properly see
the structure at X list okay uh
so the first one item should have three
items how is this
we want to see the structure of these
but
okay so it
okay we started to see so these three
you see the first item is actually a
string
you know so you need to split
this input stream
into a list
but you also need to convert each of the
number into a number
so you know I thought this is a trivial
problem but they are you know some
things you need to do so
so
let's see what we're gonna do so a
string two least split string string
split
uh
yeah okay let's let's do this okay
now I'm going to
what is this that's this code I'm going
to
[Music]
um
I'm going to code here in emacs because
in emacs I can code it fast with
subwoofer mod so let's code it here so
okay so subwoofer mod
yeah I talked about this before just
search for it and you'll find it so
subwoofer mod is a Emax major mod that
lets you code ufum language easily okay
so that's why we're doing it so first of
all you have the
input let's just copy it here
x x equals to string so here is the
input magnify and okay and we're gonna
string
split okay and split by xx and by
by double
new lines okay now this is X2 let's say
okay
then we're going to let's say X3 now
let's just
Mumbo it through so I mean
um
so first of all we split into
we split a string and we need to split
into a nested list
so is there some easy way
okay maybe there is let's look up the
Wolfram documentation again so pattern
okay
Spirit had any any of the peace into
substrings separated by three meters
okay
Okay so
let's see is there some other
and see sequence split
splits lists into sub-list
okay
I mean the problem is pretty simple but
uh I'm trying to see if there is one
single function so we don't have to do
okay maybe that's getting more complex
Let's do let's just do the most basic
way so first of all we split by double
blank lines
then we
for each of the
for for each of the
string we do a map okay
so map okay
okay map
you okay map a function to F X2 and this
function will be
okay this function will be split string
again
okay and this time is split by just one
single n which we don't need and because
by default it's just split by a single
End of Line character
and here is a function okay so you can
just say that
actually you don't even so here's a
function so
so okay so select that back to from
language select door paste okay let's
have a fresh start done let's see what
is X3
there it is that's what we want
now once we got this we can kind of
purify we can kind of purify this into
one
okay let me show you so this is some
if you are interested in interested in
the expressibility of programming
languages or the power programming
languages you'll be you will be this
will be interesting to you okay so we're
gonna combine them into one okay
[Music]
um
yeah so this part can just be here you
don't need the X2 anymore so coming out
so we can do it this way
okay then but further we can further
further we can rewrite the map by
doing it this way
okay
it's all the same so for example comment
out select all back to firm language
select or paste and let's start
over okay now show X3 there it is so we
kind of condensed make it more elegant
okay
now I think there's actually more
elegant way but let's skip it
okay
okay now you got a bunch of numbers now
you just want to sum each sublist then
pick the biggest biggest number
very easy okay so now you just send
so total you know in movement language
you can just say total and give a list
of numbers that Returns the sum now in
most other languages such as Haskell you
might have a function named sum but you
move from language you also have a
function named sum but that's not it
because the function sum is for you to
do mathematical summation for example
some X
X from 1 to 10.
okay so 55 so let's give it another
example sum X
Sim
let's let's try this okay so
no I want to
oh okay so what I want to do is this X
from A to B okay
symbolic result
okay now if you have you know it
actually gives you a closed form of this
sum but let's suppose you have something
more complex
okay so suppose you have that you can
press the button for it to format format
it in a mathematical way and you can
evaluate it
this one also works out so it gives you
a closed form symbolic solution to this
summation okay anyway we are digressing
my point here is that you know the sum
function in Wolfram language is for
doing mathematical summations okay now
if you just want to add a bunch of
numbers
that function is total
okay Toto needs to take a least okay so
so you need to for example three four
four
okay eleven so I mean this is a little a
little interesting tidbits because in
most other languages they are just say
some and many of the functional language
languages they think this is a
fantastic demonstration of the you know
of the declarative programming but in
Wolfram language that is actually just
called Toto
okay so so interesting so let's go back
to the problem so we want to sum up you
know so we want to do a map again so let
me show you okay map
so map a function
uh what is the function so the function
let's write it out function
okay
uh the function of X and what will it do
so it will just do total X
okay so here is a function
gets a total and map it to X3 okay let's
don't okay so that is how you
sum
each sub-list like that
that
okay
so now copy all
new
uh new window
it's magnify okay
okay
evaluated
uh why is it not actually summing it oh
now I know why because each of these
item is still string
you know when you do total their input
must be numbers so
if you give a input of string it just
returned that so we forgot to do the
step of converting
string to number so we can do it here
okay so let's see so let's go back here
let's see let me show you so
okay so easy enough so all we have to do
now is map again
okay map
a function to X3
where the function what does the
function do he will
string to
a string two expression huh
now in typical typically other languages
it's string two numbers so
yeah we want to convert a string to
number
so why is that so what is a function
let's see
no
we want to convert a string to integer
but
[Music]
um
okay so what we can do is to query all
functions whose name contains the word
string
number two string so there is number two
okay let's
string pad and string length string
format
number string okay maybe that
number string represents the characters
of a number
in string expression okay that's not
what we want
we want string two number
uh I think read string okay
no okay I forgot what's uh what's the
name so what we can do is we I normally
the way I do it I just go to My woofam
Language tutorial
and look at
my own tutorial because there I usually
condense the most essential the most
frequently used functions
so do we have a string two number how is
it done
for my string string to list
okay these two string
okay I think I know what
two expression okay so what we want is
two expressions there it is
okay two expression input gives the
expression of 10 by interpret
interpreting strings or boxes as valid
language input okay that's what we want
for example
three so you want to give it a string
three three there it is now you can say
number Q
okay number Q
that true so two expression is how you
convert a string to a number okay that's
what we want copy it
so two expression function
X2 expression
X
okay so let's say X4 equals true that
okay
Okay so
now
okay that's our whole code copy it
back here
paste it
Eva
what oh yeah this this should be X4 okay
there it is
so those
you know you just summed the subleased
what's up guys
so then all we have to do now is to pick
the biggest item
and that would be Max
okay
yeah Max Returns the biggest biggest
item for for example we can do this
Okay so
that's the answer okay now all we have
to do is to clean up our code
okay let's say X5 here X5 so we you know
we kind of did we did exploration
explorative programming
and the max X5 is our answer let's do it
one more time
there it is okay
now let's go back to the event of code
page
to begin get your personal input
okay so I have to you know this is a
example input so let's get my personal
input okay oh so a lot more oh
okay we're gonna check on that
easy
easy but before we do that let's clean
up our code because this is ugly you
know we are exploration you know
exploring how to do it this is gonna be
one single line okay one single line so
let me let me code it okay so basically
here is the code you want to make it one
single line let's do it okay so let me
call this
so of lamio says
event means coming as in the coming of
Christ oh thank you analytic minded Greg
and dog says orange clothes
this is a friend of my wife's
who gave her this sweater and she think
it's too big for her so she gave it to
me
what you are learning to reference
material already
or flamio start too cold you know do
more coding instead of just reading
that's important uh okay so
so we are yeah we're gonna clean up the
code okay so let's make it elegant
the way I can so
let's see split string
let me split string again
uh
yeah so the input is a list of
uh where is it
okay the input is a is a stream
the input is a string
and
separated by
first first of all it's separated by two
end of character
end of lying characters
then then each subseq I mean each number
in a group is separated by one and
applying characters
so
you know the the one of the the major
problem is you want to turn this into a
list of least and uh each atom each
element in the list must be a number so
you want to turn it into a list of list
and convert the string to numbers now
what's the shortest way to do that
so
let me let me tell you okay we can
simply do one single solution to
expression okay
let's try it
two expression XX copy it go back here
okay let's select all paste
one single
uh line let's see what it does
okay that just returned the last item no
it's no good
okay let's look at two expressions
okay yeah it's in in interpreting
okay they are they are kind of seven you
know there are many ways to approach
this problem I mean this is kind of a
toy problem right you know we we could
just use you know this code to do it
you know in fact let's let's just do it
okay let's
let's just uh
just make sure we
you know first of all let's comment this
out
so copy that
so here page that's a huge bunch of uh
uh things
okay let's copy it
copy it
and uh
paste it so you can see
there it is huge input all right
now
return run it okay
okay big big big now the result is 70
16 okay so let's just
answer
uh
seven zero one and six
submit
that's the right answer you are one gold
star closer to collecting a Nerf star
fruit okay continue to part two
okay so you know it's trivial problem
should we
Let's see we already did 50 minutes so
that's about it today so should we start
to do the second problem or should we
clean up our code to come up with the
most elegant solution
your new haircut reminds me of the guy
being
trapped in the alien's cage in Rick and
Morty
oh yeah
because of the
because the orange
jumpsuit or something I think
Rick and Morty is one of the
it's a great show okay it's but I want I
was going to say it's one of the um
dark humor and uh
uh anyway
okay so let's go to the next one yeah so
good or Flamingo okay so yeah let's not
you know
you know this code is actually normally
you don't
you don't write four things uh in wolfen
language once once you are familiar with
it you use a lot of shortcuts for
example this map for example this scene
you know this slash ad that's a map
so you see that's that's the same as
this map but it's a shortcut so when you
use shortcuts that's very normal but
then people don't understand it you know
so I try to write them in full but
anyway let's let's we got this so let's
just put it here for now okay
okay so oh God this is long
okay so there is the answer but uh do we
have it
do we have the show yeah okay so so that
solves the problem next one
now I don't know I can you know so I can
we can I can continue doing this in
Wolfram language or we can start to do
the JavaScript version of this problem
or emac this solution so that depends on
what you guys want to do so but I think
we are done today
uh let's see how many
people watching who is my
YouTube
okay that's it I think
okay so let's for the sake of let's read
what's the second problem
in case the elves okay it's gonna be a
lot reading in case the elves got get
hungry and need extra snacks they need
to know which elves to ask blah blah
blah blah blah
find the L carrying the most calories
how many total calories is that inside
of carrying that's okay that's the first
question
the first half of this puzzle is
complete oh God this is the second half
part two by the time you can carry
answers to Elvis question they've
already realized that they are carrying
the most calories of food might
eventually run out of snack
to avoid these unacceptable situation
the elves would instead like to know the
total calories carried by the top three
elves carrying the most calories
that way even if one of those helps run
up out of snacks they still have two
backups
in the example above the top three elves
are the
fourth elf
wait in the example above the top three
elves are the fourth elf
with 24
000 calories then the third elf
with 11 000 calories then the fifth the
sum of the calories carried by these
three elves is 45
000.
okay he is referring to you know my own
this custom problem here so what is he
saying
in an example above the top three hours
are the fourth elf
one two three
okay
four
what
then the third then the fifth
so he wants to know the top three that's
so easy okay let's go back to
so instead of just getting the the
maximum you just want to know the top
three maximum okay so you just look up
the documentation for Max in Wolfram
language I believe you can you can
um
turn on JavaScript
so instead of returning the maximum you
want to return the top three biggest
so you can so I guess you need to sort
it then sort and pick the first three
but easier a
easier solution
there it is take largest so you know see
you see wolfam language is like I said
before is a magnitude more powerful than
all the rest industrial languages
so many
problems you have a building function
for example right now we want to we need
to sort the list and take the top three
biggest numbers but you don't need to in
open language you just call
take largest okay you know that will do
it
you know gives the numerically largest
elements in this sorted in descending
order okay so let's let's you know so
take largest
okay so take largest
list X5
and we want top top top three right
what is the problem
top three okay so that's so easy
so yeah so we you know we just uh
there it is okay so copy the solution
copy it
and uh let's see
answer so
do they accept comma
or do they what
wait what is find the top three elves
carrying the most calories how many
calories are those elves carrying in in
total okay in total so you actually need
to Total them up
okay I'm just gonna start to use
shortcuts so
so here is the solution okay
I think so let's just let's just submit
that's the right answer you you are one
gold star closer to collecting enough
star fruit you have completed day one
okay
[Music]
share this Victory or return to your
adventure okay
some of top three okay yeah that's good
okay I think that's it for today any
comments and questions you guys have
about today's you know topics all about
wufa language
because I think the interesting thing I
mean today's problem is pretty trivial I
mean for basically for beginning
programmers but what I'm doing is
showing wolfam language so
I guess it's kind of new to you guys so
if you have any questions just ask me
okay but I I want to clean up the code
Okay so
so let me just let me just blindly uh
start to clean up so because there's a
lot uh to do for example for let me just
show you okay
so for example this one you don't ride
it like that okay
and two expression
uh
let's see if there's a short Syntax for
that no okay two expression at that
and okay
so yeah so we can do that there and uh
map
X3 so
yeah in fact I want to do this in
okay so actually just forget about that
uh is this
okay I'm starting to like
really make them short
so again total
so actually
all you need is total here and
that
so I'm actually
so let me show you guys
Okay so
don't need that you don't need that and
uh
there it is okay this single line
and
this single line and
let's see uh result okay
okay then
Max lab
dead okay
okay so that that's our code let's do it
copy it
back to Wolfram language
select all
paste it
you know so here is the
solution
this one single line then you just call
Max to answer the first question the
first part then that's the second part
okay do it
okay
did we uh oh you have two total I would
we forgot so let's add total
oh wait what
oh yeah so so so here is the total
okay so there
do it again select or paste
so here is the solution okay
do it
there it is
okay
bye guys we're shutting down
one zero one zero what did you say
message redacted
you know I always wondered you know
YouTube comment off often say message
redacted does that mean you deleted it
or does that mean YouTube censored it
I don't know
and uh and in fact I'm thinking of
more ways to simplify this one-line
solution
so
um
oh they deleted on their own okay
okay
um
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching and uh Merry Christmas speaking
of Advent of you know
Advent of code and uh happy holidays
oh yeah okay bye if
don't forget if you like my stuff donate
okay if you like my you know
pay what you like so buy my emacs
tutorial buy my JavaScript tutorial
JavaScript in depth or just donate to me
go to my website you'll see you know my
PayPal in patreon bye guys
close right across