hello everyone welcome to another
episode of casan talk show
welcome to another episode today we are
going to call emac lisp okay so coding
iMac is here's my keyboard glove 80
fantastic keyboard search for sorry
glove 80 review you'll find it on my
website video review two months ago and
hello everyone and so we are going to
code emac this so let's switch to uh my
windows so you can see
so emacs for you emacs fans emacs is a
powerful editor okay
so emacs so let's see let's look at
today's talk show page
so what are we going to do today the
e-max this coding okay so emac this
coding let's see I want
space space e wait I'm on Tab e okay
so what we're gonna code is we are going
to code a command in some fine text that
opens all find files so let me show you
what I'm talking about so for example
you can see here's the directory
uh and the pink window by the way the
pink window shows all my command course
and the keystrokes as I type okay I'm
using over a keyboard layout
any emacs questions this is a good time
to ask me okay do you have a picture of
Mount Zion at home
Jesus Huang G you know the Huang Yuan
from Germany is a Zuma type Hands-On
4chan all the time and the talking
random talk
do I have it what
anyway I'm we're gonna talk about emac
this today okay so you see here is a
list of directories and let's say I want
to find all files containing the word
Haskell okay so I just call this command
you can see in the pink pink window xava
in text okay type Haskell press enter
which directory this one yes and the
final path regular expression HTML okay
Enter wait
yeah okay the the IDS okay so you can
tab or Arrow key to go to all
occurrences and or jump through the all
files that occur okay so you can press
enter and open that file you see there's
a word Haskell and show in browser you
know StarTalk show 2019
September 7th so we you know talked
about Haskell Haskell is one of the
dramatic thing
its utility is just to mention it the
drama okay Haskell and rust you know a
decade a decade ago it's high school
today it's rust rust rust guys
put in a title
uh okay so so what is the problem so
clarifying let me show you that command
Okay so because I find okay describe key
then press the key so you can see
because I'll find text is a function uh
in this file XA find dot El so that that
is um
okay go to it jump to it enter and so
here's the source code go to the bottom
700 lines of code diet jump
there to go into the directory so you
can see here is a list of all my
packages now let's DD those uh emacs
backup files so emacs very powerful you
just press shift Tilda now of course the
problem is I don't know where is the
Toyota key on this keyboard
you know I'm waiting for the light
switches so I can actually okay Tilda is
now in the shift key position okay
so you want to delete all the emacs
backup so you just press
Tilda uh wait did I press or I press the
wrong key now the keyboard lights up can
you see it yes okay any emacs questions
so there it is you see the emacs backup
lights up and press X do you want to
delete them yes okay removed okay so
anyway so we will OnStar find here is
the package go to the top and you can
see here is my website okay of this
package so you can pay me and you'll get
it fantastic utility so this this
package what it does is that it does
grab you know find text grab or silver
or or you know the multi-grip whatever
fastest today we did a talk show on that
comparing the speed that that is very
fast but okay so because I'll find the
square but it also does
um
find and replace which that thing
doesn't do okay so and it's all written
in emac list so what is the advantage
the advantage are multiple one is that
it's independent from any external
utility so you you work on emacs on Mac
or on Windows or on your favorite
operating system Linux we think emacs
itself emac is the powerful language you
don't need
external tools okay so and so the
regular expression is using e-max
expression so it's consistent you are a
emac user you use emacs regular
expression not when you want to you know
find some string you
boom grab you know you have to type some
other Syntax for regular expression not
good okay systematic you know e-max is
very good expression so you can find and
you can you can replace so open the file
and let's list matching lines let's
search for the word different so you can
see
here is all the functions you you have
several you can so the main function is
find text find count which is show
number of uh total count of occurrences
then you have a find replace text and
you have five replace text rejects so
you have a version with plain text and
you have a version with regular
expression Y2 why separate because
sometimes when you want to find a
you know a string and you don't want to
be confused with for example let's say
you want to find some code you know
there's a lot there's back slash the
slash there is back tick you know
so if you and there's asterisk there is
dot you know so if you want to find for
example I want to search out
files containing this block of code if
you want regular expression you have to
escape Escape then that's very tedious
and error Pro so
when you want to find a text you just
call find replace text or find text or
find count okay and if you want regular
expression power for regular expression
you can use you know there's a regular
expression version okay so that's a fine
package if you like it pay me okay pay
to get you want in the prevent Society
from crumbling into
corruption you know that's what's
happening today with Google Facebook and
all that so you want to pay okay so pay
me thank you
and it's open source so you can use it
and uh and by the way so Luis there's uh
update so you can also buy my emacs
packages you know uh
you know for a hundred dollars I give
you the whole thing all the packages 10
10 a decade of code
um this update so Luis if you want it
you know we spotted before so I can
I'll send it to you
um
via Discord Okay so yeah so those of you
like it you know you can buy here so
Ergo emacs key binding no not that one
emacs okay so it contains about 12 13
packages uh all within integrated with
starfly Keys okay
so that is the demo of the command but
what is it we want to do today okay we
are going to add a feature so let's try
again search for Haskell okay this time
let's search for
let's search let's search for Odyssey
okay let's search for the word Odyssey
okay so by the way I have all this
Odyssey account I highly recommend it
Odyssey so to prevent YouTube corruption
so just go search for Odyssey o d y s e
e r the C
and you can you know search for Saudi or
the CEO find my account there YouTube is
very corrupted okay so what are we going
to do so yeah let's search for the word
Odyssey okay so copy that copy that drop
into dial jump to go into the directory
so you can see there are
794 files and let's call the let's call
Odyssey let's search okay find it so
here are multiple occurrences and you
can go down by file so you see uh and
these These are fine yeah why don't I
talk about it because
um disks are fined find replaced in pure
emac beasts suffering.el has several
features okay
um so I explain so
So within pure emac this but also you
have a regular expression version or
plain version so you don't have to
escape a bunch of things and another
Advantage is that you can search for a
block of text not just line okay rig web
and grab and silver and all the others
they are based on lines okay let's
search for it see over okay I've always
forgot What's that package's name
Silverlight quick silver silver uh wait
grab e grab yeah F grab
back silver rip grab that's the one okay
open it show in browser so we did a talk
show dedicated to that
uh in 2022 January 12th okay about a
year ago why Unix scrap sucks history of
regular expression Wolfram language
string expression now that's interesting
that's string expression that's a
alternative Syntax for regular
expression so we talked about that and
so then you know today you know the
Nerds the elite hacker types the Unix
Linux you know they they say RibCrib
what do you think of Rick web have you
tried rib crab
[Laughter]
happens every few years
30 years ago it was egweb f-web okay you
know that you know you guys don't you
have you guys wouldn't have any idea so
that's different you know regular
expression e-web F grab they emerged to
become grep so when you do grab now I
don't have access to grab because I'm on
Windows and I was going to install a
virtual box but then ban bio you know
you have some bio or some virtual
something something turned off so I have
to work with that then I'm going to have
a virtual box so I'm going to install
the Microsoft Windows subsystem Linux
Microsoft Linux
so you don't have to use Linux anymore
just install Windows run Linux inside it
so you so you grab F grab so I don't
have grab here I cannot show you do I
have grab let's see GCM grab okay
no grip yeah I don't I I removed it you
know I installed it before but Unix
so I removed it you don't need it once
you know Powershell
okay I'm starting to ramble over should
I be focused uh
finally you're adding on Odyssey for
like two months but the the issue with
others is that it's fairly technical so
Odyssey
so I'm rambling all over okay so who who
is watching so if you guys Jesus three
people so if you guys want me to focus
on emac Beast let's do that just tell me
okay so let me ramble a bit then
otherwise so Odyssey is great you know
it's um but it's very fairly technical
uh so it's very good for us you know we
we like technical stuff so but one of
the major difference from Odyssey and
others such as YouTube Rambo uh you know
there are quite a few you don't hear
them much anymore you know the the meal
which is the old one for over 10 years
now Vimeo and you know there are several
others video platforms but others is
there's one unique aspect
different from audio
Odyssey is based on blockchain so that
means any video
I'm not sure it's by choice or not but
basically it's blockchain meaning that
once posted it's permanent okay nobody
can censor it
nobody okay blockchain so the protocol
the blockchain protocol is Libre okay so
let me show you okay so I'm starting to
Rambo over so we haven't
um
uh one is my biggest fan yeah he made a
lot for charm means of me
thank you but but
you know you should do something uh you
know I mean the
you know young guys you are you guys are
young guys that's fine you know you guys
are you know hanging out in college
having fun parties you know but keep in
mind do something useful okay
4chan
will rot your brain
once in a while it's fun but don't don't
leaving it
so so I've been branching off to several
topics I want to go back to grab and
stuff and I wanted to talk about how to
see a little bit so let me show you
some programming blog okay so you know I
work every day
um non-stop walk myself to death
JavaScript Powershell so Odyssey yeah so
after C is
Odyssey is the video platform that is
based on the Libre protocol okay
debris open source so library polico is
the blockchain is a blockchain protocol
now blockchain is a very kind of newish
Technology with significant of you know
Society changing applications which is
happening you know one of the most
famous example is Bitcoin and basically
every other cryptocurrency
ethereum
Monero you know you know
cryptocurrency that's another big topic
but anyway so
cryptocurrency they are all
fundamentally rely on blockchain
technology okay and Libre is uh using
blockchain technology so blockchain
basically you know I can explain in one
minute so you have some data such as a
bunch of text you know you so let's call
that a block a block of text okay now
you can apply a function a hash function
so-called hash function which is a
mathematical function which basically
turn this
text block into a short stream
usually you know 128
or 64 characters you know anyway
so you turn a block of text into a
string
and that stream is unique corresponding
to this block of text no other block of
text will have that string
practically speaking okay that's so
that's the hash function so you so each
block of text that's data or a video or
or photo or whatever you know Digital
Data or book you know PDF or whatever so
each file you know it's a bunch of text
you can apply a hash function to
to turn to to get a hashed key which is
uh you know short string to represent
this text okay
so you have a blockchain so you apply a
hash function you got a unique text that
represents this
block okay then you can
then you create a when you have a new
data let's say a new video or whatever a
new block of of
text or can be a video file or whatever
then you also do apply the hash hash
function so you get a key a short string
represent the second block okay but in
the second block
you in a block of text you add a link
you add a reference link to the first
block
okay and that contains so the link will
contain the first blocks hash key
okay so let me repeat let me make this
clear so a block is just a file or a
bunch of text or whatever you create a
key hash key of it so that forms one
block then you when you have a new block
you also has a key from a key but in the
new block you you know in the you you
also add a link to the first block a
reference to the first block but I'm not
sure how it's done but by
but whatever I'm not sure how it's done
it's a link to the first block okay and
that that also so in the second block
that also has the key
to the first block okay then when you
have new data you do the same you create
a new block
you hash create a hash key of it and in
the new block it contains the key to the
second block
okay so it so they forms a chain and
this chain so this sequence of data
information you know this sequence of
files okay
cannot be modified why because once you
modify it you modify any of this block
you know information then the hash key
will be different because remember
each block has a key that uniquely
represent that content if you modify the
content you apply the hash function
again the key will be different so
anyone can tell that's not the key you
know something is change is changed so
anyway so you have this block of blocks
and they are linked
um in this way so and so
so anyone who modified it
you'll be able to know and
and
this Block Chain is distributed to
everyone it's public okay so it's public
so you have a copy I have a copy
everyone has a copy and so whenever
somebody modified it you know their
blockchain you can compare oh
so you know these two blockchains now
are different now you can
try to generate the hash key to see
which one is
inconsistent then that's a bad one
so anyway so blockchain basically works
that way so it's space so the
functionality the the kind of the gist
the power of blockchain is that it
creates digital information that cannot
be modified more more correctly
is that anyone who modified it anyone
else will know so essentially it's it
creates a you know what's so-called um
immutable immutable
um
information you know you cannot do fraud
on it and so on so blockchain so anyway
Liberty is a blockchain based
um blockchain protocol okay and
odyssey or this video they are based on
the library protocol so
so any video you create can is is is out
on the internet permanently
now this is also another one point that
many technicals uh do not want because
many of you you know like I don't know
many of the you know
young people Anonymous they are you know
irresponsible posting memes and all
that on Twitter over so these people on
Reddit on Twitter on Hacker News on
YouTube all the comments are Anonymous
posting Zoomers The Zuma
generation they grew up that way because
the the moment they were born or
everything is like that
Okay so these Anonymous people out there
so they they may not you know like this
blockchain based video platform because
they are worried about oh I don't want
any information to be known
these idiots these are these these are
the people that made society worse and
worse and worse
um and you can't really blame them
neither because they both they were born
that way when they were born the world
you know the the Google Facebook
clickbait is away already like that and
Fortune you know
oh God uh went into a rant so let's go
back shall we
uh so okay so what so let's go back so
okay so anyway I have a count on Odyssey
so this is one thing I'm not too sure
yet I'm still studying you know I need
to read up these um debris protocol okay
so one thing I'm not too clear is that
is it true that once you create a video
it went into the blockchain or is that
um maybe you have to for example
open this one maybe you have to actually
click a button then it goes into the
blockchain I'm not sure which one
because that's a concern for me as well
you know suppose you know like right now
I'm doing a video and students suddenly
I made a mistake I showed my password
you know some important password then
you know right now I have Odyssey set up
to automatically sync so it becomes you
know
maybe my password become permanent
information in the blockchain that
wouldn't be good and so because it's
blockchain you cannot delete it
so what is this uh this needs to be
returned this is another issue about
Windows uh stuff okay so let's copy
okay this is the power of HTML mod
okay so anyway we digressed a lot
um so now
that's about Odyssey and Libre okay so
now let's talk about yeah grip
anyway we did a video on that web grab
we we did I I did actually
um speed comparison of rib grab
somewhere on my website let's see if we
can find it
rip grip you know there it is Rip grab
yeah rip grab the features you know
here's a summary of the features and
whatever and some issue with the guy he
has an obsessed Obsession he is afraid
of
he refused to make rip grip
to do find and replace
you know to him there isn't some kind of
fear you know he doesn't want to make it
to replace because but the problem the
issue is if you don't do replace you
just do grab then it becomes very little
utility nobody needs your speed okay for
most people nobody you know there's only
one Google there's only you know a few
corporations with some Peta by you know
one medium files so you don't need rib
grab you don't need you know these
these um you know
hack to make it fast so if you don't do
find and replace you don't do replace so
what's what's a point what's the point
grip walks grab 30 years old grab works
just fine
so anyway back to sarafine so written in
emac lisp okay so we have that okay so
yeah so let me so let's do it again
because I'll find
um actually we can repeat the command
call let me show you okay this is a good
tip so you can call this command this
web key
this command okay repeat complex command
what this do is that it will call that
command that
ask ask you a bunch of prompt
but now you don't have to type the
prompt so let's just do it okay so for
example repeat you know there it is look
at the bottom okay
so I just press enter
here
to find
you know all the words silver in this
directory okay so I don't have to answer
each question
uh silver okay so actually so we can do
it again repeat okay so you can see the
command is repeat complex command I have
a tutorial on my emac website you can
search and find it okay so let's call it
again but what's better is that I can
actually modify
the here so you can see I change it to
rip
grab okay grep Enter
there it is all files containing the
word rib grab
okay so now but what what is the thing
we I want to do I need to do so I want
to so you can sometimes you have
hundreds of files now I want to call a
command that opens all these just
all these files okay so that is actually
the least thing I want to do so I
already talked for 30 minutes
hello Benjamin Abby so anything you guys
any questions okay let's just start code
emac this net
okay so I want to create a new command
that opens all the files that's found
like one in in one shot you know maybe
10 files 25 or so 100 files right now
you I can just jump to each one and
press enter to open and go to the next
one
press enter to open but I want a command
I just opened them all okay you cannot
do it with scrap you cannot do it with
rip grab you cannot do it with silver
okay so so let's um
okay so we need to write that command so
first of all let's go to yeah so
what
so what is this Excel talk show showing
browser okay uh
uh so now we
describe key
okay now jump to the package source code
so find so we want to add a command here
okay so here's a source code for
suffering text
we want to add a command that says open
all okay
so let's list matching lines the fun
where do you want to add it
any comments and questions
okay uh fine thanks so
let's just start to code okay first of
all make a backup there it is uh now so
let's copy that
actually
it's where do I where do I had it so
let's just add it bottom okay
[Music]
okay and rename this file what named of
the file so
fine open oh okay
now write some documentation
open or
files okay for now let's just say that
okay
and open all files so Interactive
so
we want to open all files okay
big into active Okay so actually
okay let's clear them
so that's the function we need to write
so let's try to find again
let's search for
find
okay
so
here is the output of cloud find they
follow they have this particular format
um
each file is have a separator like that
then
then each occurrence is a on a block by
itself you can see
uh and each occurrence speaking with a
number that number is the position of
the of the first character in that file
the
occurrence okay
and uh
so this is the output format now we just
we just need to open all these files
now
to open all these files there are two so
here's a design issue do you just want
to open it like anywhere in the file or
do you want to open specifically to a An
Occurrence
you know preferably
you should open
at the position of the occurrence okay
so let's close that let's save this okay
let's save this
find okay
so
okay yeah I'm doing video so it's
probably very boring now uh so I want to
let's try let me try to speed it up so
let's just open all files wait
so what are you gonna how do you open
all these files so you know I'll put
you know I put all files are
the limit demarcated delimited by these
special brackets okay
so you can
or
let's see
yeah so they are delimited by that
bracket
hmm
you know this so there's
quite a few ways to do these
you know ideally
let's see go to the bottom okay so
there's a lot of currents let's make
uh let's just search for Char count okay
so find all files contain the word
charcon in this directory okay so how
many so there's only one file okay
[Music]
um
so let's find all
files contains the word after okay
okay so there's a few files
uh
so one way is that
you know there there are there are
several ways to do this okay so for
example let's go back to our source code
so one way is that
okay uh
so you see here's a source code so one
way is that once you when you find find
the file you push the file path to a
list
so that way when you are done you can
just open all files in this list
that's one way
okay the other way is that you just
based on the output
so for example
that's what we
were trying to do so the other way so
the second way is just at the output you
just you just um
for example we can list matching lines
this matching Lines by that bracket so
you can see
all the lines match in that bracket then
so these are the files so then we
process this file then open each one of
them all of them
so two ways to do this
now obviously
the first way
is more efficient
and
yeah because
you know so once you find the file you
push it to at least
but if we do that there is the question
of where do you store that file path
I mean yeah where do you store this list
because if you you could save it to a
temp file but that gets complex because
that creates something extraneous
you could so where do you store or you
can store oh yeah so you can store in a
variable
so I can actually so let's let's think
about that yeah that's still in a temp
variable yeah I mean it's in some kind
of yeah so let me show you okay Define
VAR okay
let's type Define VAR
okay and Define VAR what's the variable
you want to create I want to say sound
find
[Music]
result
file
okay so that so now documentation
uh optional initial value Neo Neo dark
stream
[Music]
so this is a list of the last find
operation
each element
is a file path okay
[Music]
full file path
that contains
the occurrence
okay something like that
[Music]
yeah so
that's great actually so if you do this
every time you find a file you just push
it to the list
yeah
then then the open or will be easy so
the open or will just be
you know basically you find file
uh let me write this okay map C so map a
function to this list and for each one
what you do this Lambda is X there it is
okay
so this is very good however now there's
a problem if you do this this way
then
if you open up some result you know
after a month
this will no longer be available
yeah so that's the issue with this
approach
for example let's let's do it again okay
for example let's do it
find file you know find other words
continue after so you see here's the
result
I can save the result let's say XX
X result okay save it okay I can close
it go to a directory go to the bottom
refresh you see here's a file you can
actually save it okay close it open it
you know when you open it the Top Line
says put this in in the major marks I've
find output and that's how you you get
all the Highlight you can still you know
navigate a month you know around them
so
so you know this is very useful you know
a month after a month you can revisit
this result file
um
yeah so
so
okay so now let's go back
but now if you implement this find open
all
by relying on a
variable
it won't work you know you
um it's let's open the result okay
it won't work because the
the variable doesn't contain anything
so yeah so I don't want to use those so
so I don't think I want to use this
approach this is use this is sufficient
and
easy but
but the problem is that you open some
result file
it won't work
you see the
the list of files is already contained
in the
you know in this um in this result file
okay so so this is one approach I don't
want to do uh yeah
also if you do this
that means you have to modify
these matching lines you have to modify
several of These Fine and find replace
functions to
so that each time they push the result
to this Feast okay
so anyway I don't think this is uh the
way I want to do it okay so another way
let's say open or two okay for now
open all files now this this way is
so the algorithm would be
look for
format like this
okay
that's
a file path
okay so this is the second way and let's
do it this way
so now this bracket is actually you know
that special bracket you know you can
look at the name that special bracket is
called medium left pointing angle
bracket ornament okay
so if you go through my Unicode blog you
can
search for bracket
so you can see also the
brackets
there okay
height hexadecimal
hide ID okay so you can see also the
brackets or you can just go to this page
you can see them
most of the half of them are Chinese
brackets very useful brackets brackets
has a special property that they are the
only character that
embeds semantically embeds the
information of a matching pair in other
words they are matching pair so that
doesn't happen for any other character
not you know alphabet not English
alphabet not Chinese characters but
brackets okay bracket characters they
are unique they have this property
that's why it's very useful in this you
know in this you know the Nestle packets
so very useful so
so now close that yeah close that so
this bracket character if we search for
it is right here you see so that the
variable name is saw find file path
prefix
so you have a prefix and postfix okay so
I actually copy that
so that and
post fix
trying to find where are my keys
yeah there okay so prefix in postfix
that's the opening and in Brackets
okay so anyway how do we
no comments Okay so
okay so I'm just gonna code this myself
then
this is something I need to do myself
lots of work
so you're just gonna
text process this file so what is the
optimal way to get all these file paths
of course you can do list matching lines
but
but that's not you know that's that's
for interactive use that's not good
to call in emac this
yeah and also if you do this matching
lines then you have two parts
um
so what's a way to
let's look at the source code for least
matching lines okay which is a Alias to
occur
okay it's pretty complex
okay
so these matching lines
um
you know these lisp car ah
it is
this is the most idiot idiotic thing
about these
uh
so this matching lines
how does it work though and see
and uh
defines so it relies on
other functions
so the list the list matching lines is
only like 10 lines of code
so it mostly rely on
many other sub functions
so start and in region buffer makeover
list start and overlay occur Original
Point list ol so what is Ol
makeoverlay
pretty simple so actually so you see
here this is the main body occur One
internal function so let's go there
okay one yeah okay one is the real least
matching lines so you can see copy it
copy it new buffer paste 100 lines okay
now make it
emac this mod
so code one is you know buffers in at
least a buffer or overlay so this is
kind of the meat
uh
with Khan buffer curb buffer
yeah that's not we want that's not what
we want too complex it's doing too many
things and occur engine okay this is the
real meat
perform normal code engine so you go to
there
occur engine
so it goes through two layers of you
know indirect core
so a code engine is the actual these
matching lines something like that yeah
oh interesting so that means I I can
actually also use this
occur engine regular expression purpose
output I'd prefer
lines case for the title
uh blah blah blah you see no
documentation I really hate that
you know um
most programmers they don't document the
emacs you know emacs is generally very
well documented I mean I'm talking about
the inline documentation
but even in iMac these many most
internal functions has no documentation
such as
this case no documentation
but so but I every of my commands are
always fully documented elaborately
that's just how
I roll
so anyway so okay engine okay we are not
going to use this we are just looking at
this for curiosity
um okay
so close it
okay close it
so now we are back to our problem we
just want to
get all these lines so we can
okay let's do it quickly let's do it
quickly
let's um so
okay let's we need some variables okay
so let's declare a local variable and
uh list okay so this is a
okay path of a bunch of this is a result
path we want to open so
so what we can do is that
um
this is emac this coding so
Excursion uh save Excursion so
we want to start to move the cursor so
when the command done we want to return
the cruiser to wherever it is so that's
why we do save save Excursion okay so
now so that means whatever we do here we
instant here return the cursor position
to whatever it was
okay then we go to go
to chart point mean go to the beginning
of the buffer then we search forward we
search forward for the opening bracket
okay so we need a while statement
while not wait
while
okay
well
search for word we search for the
opening character of the fire path
so optional bound Neo no error true
come we don't care okay so once you find
it
you don't want to replace but what you
want to do is you want to
okay save position okay so we need a
variable xp1
xp2 those are temporary variables for
Cruiser position
so once you find it
set xp1
point point Returns the current cursor
position when you do search forward
you'll move the cursor there okay any
comments and questions post it okay
and so then we then we search forward
again
okay then
uh search forward for the ending bracket
okay then we
bound Neo
okay this time no arrow is true so if
you cannot find it that means you got a
problem
you should always you it should always
happen okay
so when this error return error
okay then you switch forward then set XP
Point minus one actually so
okay because
you want to move one Cruiser back you
want you want the
you you want the inside you don't want
to include the brackets okay so that's
P1 P2 is the beginning and position of
the file path okay then what you do is
you get uh you buff a substring no
properties okay
xp1 xp2 that will return the string
between those two positions
and you want to set it to
uh actually you don't want to set you
want to push
new element that's a string the path and
the push it to X
path
okay
so we are populating these a bunch of
file path okay now predify the code
okay
fantastic so far so good yes
no
let's see
so you got the path so once you're done
um
where is the wire so why I'll search for
word for search for the beginning and
search for for the end
when you found it push to the path then
repeat
yeah so when you are done this x path
should be populated
then what you just uh what you do is you
just open them all okay so map char
map a function to all this file path and
each one
you just find file
X
okay so that is
I think that's it that's it
fantastic we are done
comments and questions posted okay cool
for school I remember your name
where's your glasses have you not been
in choir have not been anywhere am I I
I'm a technologist I'm I'm con and I'm a
beautifier and you know I'm concerned
about my looks so it's a way a contact
lenses
there's an upgrade in my life from the
poverty of poverty to now I can wear
contact lenses okay
uh uh okay so back to
e-magdish
so I think that's that's the function we
want and let's double check one more
time before we run it
I think that's it let's evaluate it and
uh
so let's clean up the code a little bit
let's remove those clean up the code so
eval the buffer now emacs know about our
new function so now we call the command
uh
uh you know cassava and text after
do it so it can you know it now it
contains all
files containing a word after actually
we don't need to we already have the
file here
close it
go to the Tire open it okay so you see
we found this before here's the result
now all we have to do is meta X
uh call that okay now first of all how
many files all these files okay So Meta
X
because I'll find open all two enter
it works it worked for the first you
know so now let's list
uh list buffers as you see it found the
open demo so now we can close close
close close
fantastic close these two
because sound like he's close
HTML Macross okay
close now let's try something else now
let's try let's go to sound talk show
okay now let's find
text Haskell
h-a-s-k-e-k-e-l enter inside option
directory dot HTML files enter
enter okay okay so you got all these
files right now you can do
least matching lines
so you can see
they are 28 files okay because now call
find open or do it
okay it's a bit slow because when you
are open you know tensor files every
time they open the major mod gets loaded
and the and they started to do syntax
coloring that is very slow Okay so
okay now let's
this buffer there it is fantastic let's
see start talk show files fantastic we
did we did what we wanted to do
fantastic algorithm
so now we we you know we keep pressing
we want to close them all so list
buffers I buffer okay use I buffer
show you so go to emacs blog if you like
my stuff buy it okay go to emacs
tutorial there is here is where you can
PayPal me to get it okay support me then
you go to so e-max this Emax tutorial
you go to uh
file section then there's a buffer
section this purpose okay and you want
to use I buffer okay you don't want to
use the default list of all the details
are there just search for Sardi image
this buffer okay so now this purpose so
you can see all these are talk show
files we opened we press D to mark them
for
for deletion meaning remove them from
meaning close them okay actually this is
a bit confusing it's not actually
deleting the file so now you press X
it asks you really kill 25 buffers yes
okay prep and so yes or no yes okay you
see now we close them all
so except so anyway that's it okay back
to emacs close close emacs blog close
here's the sapphire output close okay
that's it we did what we wanted to do
fantastic
anything else that's it for today
coffee
for people watching that's it thank you
guys have a good day bye we close down
in one minute
ah fantastic
fantastic now let me show you my
glorious face
okay we uh yeah shut down in a minute
and let's let me do some cling up
of my files for today's talk show
so so switch to next yeah so we need to
go back to okay
show the pink window okay close that
show the pink window so you can see my
commands now go to the swipe key press
press jump to the file go to diode go to
the bottom open this result page
delete
and close and now the new function is
here
we don't need this defined VAR anymore
defined by and we don't need this
anymore and rename these two
suffering open or open all files
uh
and also
make the documentation more complete
must be called when in
the result page okay
this command works
only when the result page
okay so that is actually pretty good
actually I'm I'm a little bit surprised
actually it's
so short
and functional so now we just go to the
top is a version It's update the version
version 9. new feature okay and now
let's call
this is a fantastic
um let me show you the command
okay there's a VC diff command so you
don't need magic Okay match it
so press the key so you can see the
difference the modification we made
today to this file compared to the git
so you can see so this is the file we
added this is a feature so now let's
write a feature documentation okay new
prefer paste uh
so new
command okay
okay that would be the git message cut
drop to eshell
git status okay then get
before we do that
you know you see right now we are in XA
Emax all my packages now however because
I'll find it has its own dedicated git
separate from XA packages so we open
that we want to copy this uh change to
to the to the Excel finds on git repo so
you can watch the ping Windows see the
command I call to copy it so press press
press
so you see the command and code is star
sync XE Max packages what it does is
that it copies the current file to the
to the associated you know git repo of
that file so now if you do diet jump you
can see now I mean the fine kit so you
can open that then now you do VC diff
you can see the basically the same
difference okay so here now you go to
eshell
close this instance to again now you get
status okay now you get add
kit ad
find yes and what do you want to say
get commit okay what's the command
message okay
new commands find open all enter
fantastic
okay close
now back in the Excel package directory
so you need to do the same thing
git status
git add
do that okay now git status again
there's some change here
uh oh yeah the the repeat key
made that change
okay anyway bye guys