yes guys looks like I'm late so actually
I'm not sure one to talk about let's see
if people are coming well I'm going to
talk about see okay so go to my MA hey
max frog go to my programming blog go to
my Emacs blog so I might be talking
about okay I can talk about you see you
see I'm studying streaming so I don't
know what to talk about well I have some
ideas so there are several type of
things I can talk about I mean for one
thing I can focus on technology for
example Emacs you know I'm just go on
and answer Emacs questions you know talk
about Emacs like how what is the most
efficient way to open files and things
like that now the other way is to I mean
okay so this technical topics Emacs very
focused specific topic oh all about a
programming language for example
JavaScript or gold and actually I'm not
I'm not really in the position of
teaching goal and where oh yeah you know
a JavaScript well because in order to do
that you have to be you have to be
proficient not I mean even if you
understand the language very well
but if you haven't used it for example
in for a while then I mean then you
cannot because you have to be quick you
know on a spot know the syntax and you
know do stuff anyway so I can talk about
Emacs you know
well Emacs and Emacs Lisp I still do
daily I still called him a Chris
basically Davey and
so very focused technical topic that's
one way to go about videos the other way
is to let's see the other way is to talk
about technical topic like programming
but not necessarily very focused for
example I can talk about programming
community you know Emax community for
example richard stallman now he's always
an interesting character there's always
lots of things to talk about and Emacs
code for example
oh um Xcode that's a huge topic let's
see
oh one guy watching good so Emacs code
is a huge topic you know for example
Emacs let's see Emacs modernization
Emacs fun you know so there's Emacs Cup
you know this is this cup it uses this
my in a crowd bones of steel that's
great line and like that mine is
actually for my poem and it's quoted
it's useless goo Goo's moto but anyway
so back to the topic so I was saying
when you when I do a video for example
Saudi talk-show you know I can do
focused technical topic or general
technical topic like programming
community Emacs culture Emacs community
Emacs people you know what's going on in
Emacs community oh you know then the
third option is outside outside of
technology and over there there's also
lots of things to talk about so actually
you know let me know if you if you are
there you know I got four guys watching
so yeh so you know if you are there you
know just type things out let me know
what you want to let me know what you
want to
to talk about so actually me try say hi
and tell me and vote for what topic you
like you need to talk about so I can
talk about Emacs Emacs this demo for
example oh there it is my message is
great oh oh general programming stuff Oh
I mean language syntax and design and
formal languages now that's my favorite
topic formal languages okay so okay so
those are technical you know all these
are related programming related topics
and then outside of that there is
general social topic for example I'm
interested in linguistics for example I
can speak or write Chinese touch aha
what sort some when you my face doesn't
okay judson when you know for example I
can teach you Chinese you know the
basics I will tell you some general
ideas about Chinese the grammar and how
things are oh you know so these are none
technical topics so I can talk about
Chinese I can talk about China for
example you know China is you know
getting huge today they got they landed
on they went to the back of Moon you
know last month you know and China news
like today oh the you know the longest
bridge the biggest buildings the toll is
that the highest elevator
the biggest fairy squeal or something
you know it's like all the biggest is
like all China now Iceland Jack hi I
know you you are the guy with Oh
actually I'm not sure if you are guy or
girl but I noticed you you are the guy
with the blue hair so syntax for more
languages yeah that's for my but I know
you okay eMac B's yeah so Haskell okay I
actually don't know much about Haskell
you know although I rant about it all
day you know because
okay so Haskell functional programming
but I love functional programming so so
I was going to say yeah what it was a
formal languages so if I'm gonna talk
about formal languages to a Haskell guy
you know he you finna be disappointed
because you've already know much more
technical details you know because you
know if I'm going to you know if I don't
ask ow if you know if you know if
Haskell is a Mac this which are being
coding for 10 years you know then I can
ramble on and on like about the details
but I actually don't know how how you
know so my comment about Hess cow is
just it's actually just general you know
general test flamin you know because
anyway so anyway so let me show you so
so again again let me finish the topic
and so you know I tend to ramble a lot
like you know this this one path then I
go to this direction then there's a
branch and written branch and I had like
reach you know the so in the programming
there's an algorithm a general category
of algorithm called back tracing so you
know it so it's like so you have many
branches and once you reach you
and you know you back-trace so you went
so I go back to the previous topic then
talk about that you know it's like
parentheses in this you know you have so
many parentheses you start a new
Prince's then you finish that you went
back to the other parentheses and
there's interesting thing about that
that that is the you know story within a
story you know that actually yeah so I'm
you know I'm starting to ramble a lot so
anyway so but that's a fun part you know
because usually you know like you know
it's great if I talk about one specific
topic like Emacs you know people are
interested but then sometimes you know
that kinds get boring because and I mean
if you really want to know Emacs you
know specific question is tons of
answers and often you you know you can
just read you know like Stack Overflow
you know if you just go there and read
it so but so I mean I'm guessing you
know the the the purpose II let's see if
I can see myself where's my hand
okay there is see okay there is like
five-second delay so anyway so you know
so yeah so I mean the the I guess the
fun part about streaming or video is
that you see people talk and you know
you talk just about things like in real
life you know you talk to your friends
interesting people you know in you know
various things but anyway so so I have
wrote you know I have you know I have
random interest you know lots of
interest but usually there are academic
things you know like philosophy
linguistics you know usually academic
literature and stuff but in literature
this Arabian Nights oh my god this I
would say Arabian Nights
the you know the Arabian Nights the
version pies Richard Burton who he is a
very interesting guy
now the version he's he's the one who
translated the whole thing in English
without censorship you know passes and
so I mean this book that's a huge topic
you know you know if that's a very rich
topic so anyway he's the first one to
translated and he's he's he's lots of
things he's a linguist
he speaks several languages I mean this
is like in 1800 he speaks several
languages he is also a fence you know a
swordsman he is also a diplomat he has
been and and he is also lots of things
you know so and he anyway so Arabia
you know Arabian Nights or 1001 nights
that's the story where you know if you
are a typical American and you know the
way I mean you the way you understand
Arabian Nights like from Disney that's
all like that's out of shape that's not
reveal night at all so so you know you
want to read this one and and the way I
and I find this book actually I would
say I find the most interesting book my
favorite book book yeah I can say it's
kind of like my favorite book
fiction or nonfiction kind of the top
let's say top five of all the books I've
ever read
so Arabian night that's so it's
interesting the king you know and also
you know the the stories that we are
familiar with the the you know Alibaba
and forty thieves the Aladdin and you
know the wonders of 7c or something like
that and actually those are not
the you know those are not the core of
Arabian Nights anyway so well the you
know I'm talking about Arabian Nights
because Arabian Nights the story is
structured in such with recursion so for
example you know so you know they start
a story and you know this girl
Scheherazade something like that how do
you pronounce her name you know she
started to tell the King a story then
then within that story there you know
people in characters and those
characters started to recount another
story and so on so it's like nested it's
you know it's heavily nested structure
so that's that's that's so anyway so
that's you know I'm mentioning that
formal languages yeah I don't know about
its see mine hug so formal language I so
sure I can talk about that and this I'm
like
oh my god the phone when languages okay
so you know I don't know you know I you
know if I'm not I don't really know that
much and it this just let me just
remember then that because I do I do the
best I mean that's the best thing that's
the best thing I do so so I have a lot
criticisms about programming languages
mostly okay so this this this or these
articles all related to this you know I
you know I have you know so I I was
going to say you know these people you
know especially this today is kind of
dead okay yeah I mean it's not like
before you know suppose in 1990 so mm
there's a huge subculture or group of
whispers you know they want this like
okay in today maybe that's something
like Haskell you know you know a lot
people say oh this is the only way you
know so back then you know this or at
least in the least was you know I have a
lot fight with him
you know I in general I like this but
mostly I like the function of
programming aspects not not any you know
particular characteristics of Lisp you
know this place you know they you know
for example if you talk to lease bus
this bus we would start to begin to tell
you
oh the parentheses is great there is
this Co what they call it this word for
you know like say my mathematical phrase
so that so what does that mean is that
it says the you know the the data
structure in the Lisp syntax is
isomorphic it means something like that
yeah that's it that's it homie Oh
iconicity yeah that's the most idiotic
concept you know so that's that I have
an advance of a lisp you know because
you know in programming community
especially the hacker types which is
most of my readers anyway because I just
you know I just wallow in you know you
UNIX and stuff and you know they now and
then you hear people you know the hacker
type of programmers they mentioned like
mathematical jargons but in fact if you
are a mathematician and and you you read
that homeo iconicity like nobody uses
and and then it's it and that that is
actually not a mathematical jargon I
mean you don't find that in math and as
far as programming goes you know what
does it mean it does it's like it has no
no utility I mean usually math
terminologies each term you know goof
you know you know we can I can you know
start to go on to Wikipedia you know
lists you know math terms you know I so
morphism isometry you know projective
space you know homomorphism or lots of
you know this huge amount of math
jargons they have very specific meaning
you know sometimes you know different
author have different definitions but
but in general they are the same I mean
you can change a little bit like trivial
things do you include zero or not you
know special cases but in general they
have very specific meaning but also they
are practical jargons that you need to
use it often because otherwise you know
you just have to say the whole
definition it's you know problematic but
you know but then you look at the you
know some people like you know some of
the math math like terms you know
prepare by programmers you know
he's never used in its city it's almost
like there's no definition for it
there's no exact definition and even if
you give it a definition it's not useful
I mean it's not so what what words are
useful in programming for example
variable function side effect you know
side effect of a function for example
mutability that that's useful although I
don't like that jargon but you know it
useful useful you know there's a thing
about mutability yet you know
interesting about mutability because if
you have a list you know in most
languages almost basically all languages
if you have a list you know djinji and
you if you assign it to a variable the
question is now is that variable mutable
or not you know that's an interesting
question let's you know let's say this
is not a scow let's say this is in
Python or Perl PHP you see in one sense
the variable is you know if you say the
variable is in mute immutable that means
you cannot assign any other value to X
you know once you assign it to a list
but you could also say it's mutable we
because because the least element itself
is mutable however the list you know the
the the value of the variable is
actually a reference to the list so you
have like two concepts concepts you know
you know what do you mean by mutability
you know do you mean the list itself is
you know mutability or the variable the
value of the variable so that's
interesting about mutability
so back to the so I was saying okay
about jargons you know homeo iconicity
and actually if you look up Wikipedia
actually I probably have an article here
somewhere
anyway let's look at Wikipedia it's
something like that you know it will
tell you actually a lot of other
languages have that property I mean when
you actually hear the other languages
with that property then you suddenly
realize it's stupid you know you don't
no longer wants to say all this has home
home you iconicity you know anymore you
know like all these languages actually
they they used to also include assembly
you know you know so it's like it's
extremely stupid but however you know my
take about the situation you know you
know we're in this you have parentheses
right let's see okay so let's go here so
in this code you have all these
parentheses you know okay you want to
talk about homeo carny city I mean I
mean I don't mean you but I mean the you
know the vistas and they so so but
notice one thing the lease
syntax is not regular you know notice
this one here okay so let me see let me
find the example okay let's go
fundamental problems of Lisp you know at
least people like to say oh we like you
know it's regular you know this has no
syntax you know that's a stupid
expression because every language has
the syntax you know so it's kind of like
idiomatic English you know when you say
something is no syntax it actually means
you know it's kind of like regular you
know so it you know you don't have
exception so you know because lots of
things you know to worry about
but anyway so at least at least these
people you know like to say they have no
syntax so it just means it's very
regular but actually it's not you know
you have special things like that then
you have you know the quote special
syntax then you have you know the you
know the bad quote and then you have
that so they have a bunch of things so
you know I actually really like it to be
regular so in a sense I really like the
high Kong you know homey iconicity idea
so so you know I wanted to be extremely
regular I mean I just want nested
parentheses so in other words the list
grammar can be specified in just like
three lines you know that way it's pure
you know hundred percent regular but in
but actually you know in based almost
order lists out there they are not
regular except Mathematica okay is
except Mathematica in the Wolfram
language but the general is you know
eMac this Common Lisp scheme they are
not regular they have these kind of
things so you you know you talk to these
people you say well you know you show
them this issue then they like they are
like oh no but we need that because it's
convenient you know they like I'm
totally [ __ ] idiotic you know that
you know the reason they it's you know
the reason the disperse behave that way
concocting ok uh yeah I'm concocting
concocts and two native languages have
true homie iconicity well I what that I
guess that depends on what what we mean
by you know but anyway you know first of
all we have to actually define you know
what homeo iconicity means anyway let me
let me finish you so so you see what I'm
saying is that you know I want you know
a lisp language where the syntax is
hundred-percent regular but actually
this you know the comedy's scheme this
bracket they are not they don't have a
you know regular syntax you know but
actually mathematical language has that
property now this is interesting you
know mostly most of you probably are not
familiar with Mathematica but
Mathematica is a language that actually
has that property I mean it's just like
purely nested expression actually let me
show you an example here so it's magnify
so if you look back here okay let me
just go Paige Paige Paige Paige okay so
for example this is a this is
mathematical firm language it has what's
called M expression you know in in Lisp
you have s expression which is you know
the familiar nested parentheses but
actually the original Lisp inventor he
has the concept of M expression which is
a wrapper a syntax wrapper to the S
expression so so you have X expression
and then you go through okay you open
that and open that so let's see
so so yeah so these are expert
expression symbolic expression but em
expression is supposed to be like for
example like that you know so it's a
syntactic wrapper to the S expression
that meaning that it can transform to
the X expression so that's the original
idea a concept of Lisp you know by the
guy McCarthy and but however it just
never came to be but actually but
Mathematica you know the wolf I'm Stefan
wolf I'm guy he he created Mathematica
he actually did the Hemi expression meta
expression so let me show you quickly
what I mean so here is code of Wolfram
language Mathematica and there's two
versions now first first of all look at
this this look at this version that I'm
in terms of the water quick
so look at this version you notice the
syntax is nesting pure nesting so the
foam is you know F being a square
bracket and then that's it that's
basically the grammar so inside that you
can have more of that form more of the
same form and so this is isomorphic to
to a pure Lisp s expression so so the
function name is outside the bracket
instead of inside the parenthesis and
also the separator is a coma
instead of space and that is it and it
is 100% pure there's no exceptions so
this is showing in this this version
here now every expression can be also
converted to the mm expression in this
jargon it's called M expression but you
know in Mathematica its code is just
called
it's not called M expression so in
Mathematica this version
of syntax is called full form like for
full form that's that's a word here and
this version is transformed you know to
this version in this view code M
expression but in Mathematica is just
it's called standard form so so the
these two are there's you know this to
be can be converted to each other you
know just by pressing a key it and they
are pure syntactical transformations
meaning that this form of this form they
are exactly the same for example you
know when you when you write one plus
two in anyway let's say in Python or
whatever one for us to you can add a
space between you know before after the
first sign and in both ways are 100%
they are seen tap sync tactically
equivalent you know that's what I mean
so these two forms although they look
different they are synthetic
synthetically equivalent and you can
just press a button in my editor to
transform one to the other or part of it
to the other so I have a detailed
expansion you a lot of detailed Express
its explanation about mathematical
syntax and you know how these transform
works you know you can read it if you
want
so anyway back to you know after I was
ranting about this book but anyway so
back to the so I have basically these
three sections okay the four sections so
so this section is on this and this
section syntax soup is about many issues
about syntax of different languages and
here is a collection of are costs
related to semantic issues so on this
syntax OOP semantic noodles what a great
name and overall overall they are
complying and okay the other thing about
this you know this this bizarre crazy
about Marcos you know you know this
image I found somewhere in Chinese
Chinese for gaming for someone created
that you know it's so funny
so lispers they are so excited about
these markers I think it's it's the most
idiotic [ __ ] in programming languages
the most idiotic [ __ ] useless [ __ ] you
know also let me talk about Mathematica
you know Mathematica you have pattern
matching you know the pattern matching
in Mathematica is different from those
in Haskell hokum oh okay
no III don't actually know Haskell much
you know I never programmed Haskell
actually except maybe ten lines you know
just learning it so you know I could be
wrong but but the general idea but but
but I know for sure that the Haskell had
a matching or you know camera or other
languages they are pattern matching by
value okay let me back that back up so
no you know you guys probably know in
this view have symbolic expression right
so meaning that this list if is
different from other languages for one
one of the primary reason is that it has
symbols like every character is a symbol
you know the Lisp compiler you know read
your file and they turn those your
source code into actually into a bunch
of lists but anyway so this has the the
concept of symbols you know like when
you say x equals to 3 X can remain
remain X you know as a symbol kind of
like a string you know kind of like
inert string and you can choose to
evaluate least the X or not but in
Python for example if you say x equals
to 3
X is always just three and there's no
way to get you know the you know you
know X as a symbol back so that's that's
one of the major difference between Lisp
and other languages so this has symbols
the concept of symbols and so when you
so once you have a symbolic language
like Lisp in math Mathematica as well so
in Mathematica you have pattern matching
meaning that you are doing
transformation of expressions
symbolically okay that's that's a key
thing symbolically so if you know this
basically that means macros Lisp macros
so this mark or what it is doing
actually is just manipulating the
expression the symbolic expression most
specifically you can hold a value you
know don't let it evaluate hold it and
you know then human manipulated you
transform it into another you know
nested you know expression then you say
go evaluate that so that is actually a
form of pattern matching you match
patterns symbolically okay that's the
important thing
symbolically you take the expression you
know from your source code that's at
least you know a bunch of symbols you
manipulate it then you you tell that you
know the program the interpreter or
compiler you know you you know you say
go evaluate that so this marker is that
but it's not actually you know you don't
quote pattern matching because you know
it's very limited you know oh you oh you
oh you actually do is you know when you
define your macro
oh you actually you just hold you know
the input you know the parameters and
it's very I mean in this way you can see
it's very limited you actually don't
transform the expression much okay but
in Mathematica which is you know a full
symbolic pattern matching language
that's what you do you know you take any
expression any
anything in your source code that's the
actually that's the primary way
Mathematica computes by symbolic
transfer transformation of the
expressions so so so this macro is like
one limited pattern matching but
Mathematica it's you know the whole
thing is pattern matching I mean it has
other things as well but you know the
one of the the primary way for
Mathematica to do computation is by
pattern matching you take an expression
you transform it to whatever you want
and you evaluated that so that's a
mathematical pattern matching now as you
know I looked into Haskell you know I'm
curious you know has caught up had
imagined it also had imagined but they
are not the difference is that they are
not symbolic they don't have the concept
of symbols so they are pattern matching
by you know expression structure you
know for example what these structures
something like that you know so you know
so that's that's it so that's the
difference you know that's so that's
that's major that's very big difference
because you know when you do symbolic
fanta matching transformation
expressions you are you know you are
doing transformation of expressions but
if you are just you know pattern
matching on values you know that's still
helpful but that's not that's a major
paradigm you know that's a different you
know it's not it's not symbolic pattern
match it's not transformation of the
expressions anymore but of course it's
still useful so anyway so so I was
talking about yeah so okay least mark
was okay so okay let's go back to what
I'm gonna say about formal languages you
know so I find myself you know my
interesting language is you know like
every person you know you have you know
maybe you are a fan of Python and you
like Haskell very much you like this you
know
some people like Java you know there
exists this there are there people like
Java yeah I know I think they are you
know but but then so my I find that my
interest you know when I criticize you
know languages you know which I like
which I don't like
I find myself the reason I mean if if I
can summarize you know the
characteristics of languages that that I
like then I think I can say it's because
they are you know the closer the
language is a formal language I like it
more you know I like it to be formal
language now aside from that you know I
also I you know I want the language to
be no exceptions like everything is
hundred percent regular hundred percent
regular syntax you know like this you
know 100 percent regular semantics like
there's no like each syntax doesn't
matter where it is used it means exactly
the same thing so in a sense I like you
know I like them you know so the
language so I kind of like those
characteristics you know those
properties no exceptions
you know pure regular syntax but anyway
so back to formal language now for those
of you who don't know you know you can
look up Wikipedia what did formal
language so here's what I say you know
syntax is the most important aspect of
programming language the quality of a
programming language can be just judged
by how much of it can be explained by
its syntax alone you know if you take
this material you know to judge
languages and if you look at least that
applies very much because when you look
at least first of all you see all the
parentheses parentheses and quickly you
understand that each parentheses the
beginning is a function name and you can
just read that you know the function and
pretty much this
wipe you know what the function does and
it so nested so in a sense this even for
someone who never you know look at a
computer language it before it he kind
of you know tells you already what it
means what they do so that's what that
you know that's advantage you know
that's that's why I like you know this
but for example Python Java especially
Java so [ __ ] up you know and
JavaScript you cannot do that you look
at the program you have no idea what's
going on you know like I mean especially
you know you know so that's what I like
you know Haskell has cow is a I also
like functional you know it's a must you
know I only program basically I only
programming functional forming style
I don't like Opie at all
I think Opie is a scam and also the know
if you have comments you know just you
know come you know comment let me know
you know so let me know where I'm going
you know so I can talk about it so the
other language so I was talking about
yeah so I don't like hope he at all so I
like functional programming and also
functional programming the you know the
term has kind of evolved you know in the
past like 20 years you know before you
know least is functional programming but
today people will say what you know
because this has lots of side effects
you know because today Haskell is you
know kind of popular right so Haskell
you know gave gave the world the sense
that functional programming is you know
without you know he just write functions
and without side effect but actually
except has almost all other functional
languages has side effects including or
camo F sharp you know
ml you know those are all family the
same family
this mathematica you know this is this a
lot of functional programming languages
but they are not like Haskell has cow is
almost you know basically the only one
that actually does you know in the
language in enforce you know the idea
that is there cannot be mutable
variables the so closure closure is also
functional language in and racket yeah
racket racket or comment is fun and
Emacs desktop programming what do you
mean do you mean are they good or bad I
think they're okay I don't like common
this you know but anyway but that's just
my opinion so you can I mean
racket and Common Lisp you can use them
I mean the thing is you know when you
consider I never had the experience with
small talk Oh Pharaoh what language is
that
so I mean the thing is when you consider
which programming language to learn you
know there's a lot it depends on what
you want to do you know if you want to
get a job right racket know Common Lisp
know you know if you really I mean if
you want to get a job and and you insist
on using this family of languages then
go for closure you know that's that's
your best chance you know but even I
mean let's let's say they are you know
this much closure programmers you know
in the industry oh you know basically
these about the same for Haskell
programmers in the industry but you know
you can go work for Facebook you know
they use Haskell
closer to you know in some of the
companies in Bay Area but the thing is
if you look at goal and you know it's
like 1,000 times small jobs then in
Haskell closure combined okay seriously
so that's you know you want to consider
that anyway I'm not gonna talk about
which language to learn because
you know I had talked about that before
and you know that's so let me go back to
the formal languages so so yeah so if
you don't know formal languages you know
you can read Wikipedia
you know formal languages but if this is
your first time you might find it
confusing you know it it can be
confusing to understand what they are
saying but let me just explain to you
know let me like let me give you a
informal explanation of formal languages
so so you know you have you know a
formal language is just a bunch of
strings you know you just think of it as
a string like you know like if you know
extreme programming languages you know
that's so simple so you just have have a
bunch of a sequence of letters you know
ABC you know a sequence of letters a
formal language is just that you start
with a see a stream you know let's just
say stream you start with a stream then
you have a bunch of rules that that it
that though each rule is basically
finding reface so think of you know you
know editor Emacs or vim or whatever
editor you know you want to find
function names and replace the function
name by some other name you know finding
replace that's it so you have several
find and replace rules for example one
of the rule says you know replace Oh F
by y you know just for example then
another rule says we replace our
sequence of XYZ by some other sequence
of you know string you know that's
another rule so so basically you have a
bunch of finding replace rules okay and
then then you are given a starting
stream then at each time anytime you can
pick one of the rule
you know you can pick one of the rules
to replace that to change you know the
starting string into some other string
and basically you repeat
you you repeat the process so
essentially you you you know you have a
starting string you can end up with a
bunch of other strings and essentially
that's a that's formal language that's
what it is okay God don't quote me on
that
okay so I'm you know just go read
Wikipedia you can see you know you can
you can see what I mean you know you
know go with you know because I'm not
you know I'm not teaching formal
languages that's actually that's a topic
I'm still learning that I mean this is
okay so let me tell you why I find
formal languages interesting you know
because actually when you actually study
mathematics for example logic you know
the mathematics there's a huge branch of
logic you know proof systems homotopy
type theory you know proof systems so
the whole thing I mean basically we want
to you know we've been trying that for
you know 50 years we want to create a
system you know wouldn't it be great if
machines can automatically creates new
theorems new theorems and find new you
know proofs you know new theorems like
you know put mathematicians you know
kick out or mathematicians we don't need
them anymore you know the AI system just
create or news new theories for you you
know I instance relativity or whatever
you know the machine will find it you
know after all it's just logic right I
mean if you are a programmer you might
think you if you never studied you know
proof systems you know math logics you
might think you know programmers you
know programming so step by step you
know it's all machine you know it's all
so accurate and precise why can't they
just you know automatically do things
you know we have lots of automations
right you know automation is so hot you
know we also made this in that so so so
we have been you know people have been
trying to find the automated proof
systems that's that's that's very
extremely hard and and in fact you know
that gave us lots of technologies and
math you know branches math and theorems
we have today but but the the question
about how to go about fight finding new
theorems is very hot anyway anyway so
all these has to do with foundation of
mathematics you know like for example
calculus for example one plus two how do
you turn you know we know what what is
one for us through we know what I mean
so x squared equals two you know three
how do you solve you know solve for X
you know we humans understand what it
means but the problem is that you have
to turn this equation into a into a
formal logic so-called or in some form
logic so that computers can do it for
you so and that turns out that that is
the problem that's you know it's hard
how do you turn a problem into a you
know formal logic you know so then you
have formal logic systems you have
different logic systems with their
presumptions and axioms and so on but
anyway all these is kind of in you know
50 hundred years ago it became basically
symbolic logic which is what we are kind
of familiar with we want to turn what
English words into symbols so you know
you know so you so it became you know in
a sense you can say actually you can say
oh math you know it became you know you
know particular philosophy okay it
became manipulating manipulation of
symbols so that's where formal logic I
mean formal language came from you know
so if you want to ask the question you
know how do you stop a problem you know
let's say is it possible to solve a
problem you turn that into a formula
language like you know just basically
strings you know just so symbols and you
have a list of rules and you want to ask
so if if we have this system is it
possible by applying you know this bunch
of rules to arrive at a different string
which is a string we want you know so we
can ask if if that is possible you see
so now this problem has become so simple
simple simple and very specific you can
you know you can start write programs to
do it so that's the you know the gist of
okay let me say you know that's the gist
my in my interest in formal languages
you know symbolic logic the foundation
of math improve systems they are kind of
all related so so so that's what I mean
okay so we've I've been talking like for
15 minutes already so it's almost like
we can call it a good chat so small talk
is father of faro Opie but not in Java
fact that way yeah so so if you want to
learn a programming language you know
not for a job but just for the sake of
learning you have a lot of options you
know actually you have I mean just if
you really just curious about you know
you have a lot of options you can you
know okay this is obviously one you know
one option of course you can also learn
Java Ruby PHP I mean that's okay that's
different from Lisp then you can also
okay now Haskell is another option
because it's very different again it's
you know different Haskell or you can go
with a camel f-sharp they are they are
similar so the the branches of
functional languages you know
in the beginning you have Lisp and
somewhere sometimes around there you
have a different function of programming
different from list basically that's ml
ml stand for meta language and the
origin of ml is to to create a proof
system you know we are back to proof
system again so ml is the father of then
emag became camel standard ml o camel
you know and there's also Miranda you
know it's the kind of year so anyway so
so Mao is a meta language did you know
then you have standard email SML and
that I think that also became you know
okay mo and you know then F sharp is
Microsoft Microsoft's version of you
know okay mo then you have so Haskell
Haskell is kind of there okay it's you
you could say they are the same family
but I mean you could say I mean I mean
if you of course you if you are Haskell
programmer you know you probably know
the history better than me but so anyway
so you know so has come email and then
then what what what was I going to say
about that I forgot so yeah anyway so
yeah the family of functional
programming languages but but yeah yeah
I wanted to say oh yeah there is
something about small talk okay so yeah
I never actually studied small talk but
you know because there's so many
languages to learn you know especially
today there are so many new ones too and
they are also useful
I mean practical in so I mean so you
don't have time to actually learn
although everything you know and also
there's a theory aspect so for me I want
to get into proof systems
in the math aspect you know and that's a
lot you know to study so so you know
this is this interesting thing about
Alan hey you know okay you might read
this article if you are interested so
this is like my my local version of my
website you can just you know wait you
know just so this is some Saudi info
which is you know just remove that and
there is my website you know Alan key on
object-oriented programming so basically
he says you know today what we know is
Opie he invented the term you know he
created a term however he said his
concept above he is entirely different
from you know what we came to understand
you know so he in Java or Python you
know so anyway in this article he you
know he explains what he means but I
don't understand a thing what he is
saying I don't understand you know and
you know and you know he's talking about
you know his idea above he is like you
have sales you know you have cells and
each cells send messages to each other
yeah but what does that mean you know
like programs programmers they always
talk about the fancy ideas but what what
exactly do you mean cells like how do
you you know what's the syntax how do
you actually code it but I suppose if I
actually learn small talk
then maybe I understand but anyway he's
article you know the J's like make makes
zero sense to me in fact I think he's
just a crackpot you know he's just like
so he's like he's a crackpot he started
some weird idea and today so he is just
other crackpots you know created their
own things you know so
odd book odd book so you might be
interested in computer modeling of
mathematical reasoning I don't know what
that book never heard of that book
usually you know usually it's you know
math modeling of computer programming
but this is reverse the computer
modeling of mathematical reasoning
that's kind of strange
I'll look it up so anyway so yeah so I
think that's okay so yeah so I guess I
talked about the stuff like enough stuff
for the day so let me look up the book
the computer modeling of mathematical
reasoning
1983 okay one of the hard book I guess
because there's no like reviews and
stuff I mean no people you know it's
like nope nobody bought it
1983 yeah
interesting
so what else and Steve let's go back
here
great chant hey thanks so I guess yeah
that's it for today you know thanks for
coming by guys