welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
i'm alive voice check video check
good so today we got we are going to
talk about
emacs and uh emacs and keyboards in
powershell
uh kind of randomish i don't have a plan
so if you have a questions post in a in
a
video chat box okay and good morning bot
so bob has a question can you show
examples how
for example python syntax is blocking
true functional programming from
happening okay so
yeah so i yeah so the question you know
about python
syntax so in a few you know i talked
about this before
where python
you know python is not suitable for
functional programming
and and in particular
specifically because python
uh guido von rossen he's an idiot
yes he is anti-functional programming
you know guido van rossum is very
uh he don't get it he don't get it okay
so i'm gonna show you so
so i talked about this before where
python
is not suitable for functional
programming and in particular because
python has a
python has a crippled lambda okay so you
go to my website cassari.info
and here is a bunch of articles
programming tutorials python goal line
and so on
and there's a bunch of essays so i have
a collection of essays about
why python sucks why python sucks donkey
s
okay so so one of the things about
python is that it doesn't support
functional programming well
you know if you ask the python people of
course they are phonetics they'll say oh
we support functional programming
and so on and because there's this
library but not really okay in practice
and also because the python culture they
are pretty much
anti-functional programming because of
guido guido von rossum you know the boss
so if you impact in real life in
practice
so there's another aspect about what
does it mean
when programming support functional
programming so
let me go on okay i rambled a little bit
but let me cover the whole thing
so when you have a programming language
there are two aspects about how
it supports functional programming one
is technical how well can you do
functional programming in the
programming language
okay and the other aspect is social
you know the culture of the language of
the community
for example in python python
you know i would fail in both both parts
uh so so let me so for example python
doesn't really support functional
programming okay
but however if you ask the python
phonetics they'll say we they support it
now even even if python the language
supports functional programming well but
it's not accepted in in real life in
practice because you go out you work for
google google is a company that
where python is their main scripting
language for example and lots of other
places uses python python is
very super popular you know due because
of google i talked about this before
so the other aspect about is about the
community
so for example if you work for google if
you work for some company
where they use python as the main
programming language and you started to
do functional programming
you you'll be kicked out okay you will
be kicked out
because i mean because every post every
you know
in code review or whatever your code
other people will not
accept it they will you know they will
find problems why are you doing it this
way
you should you know they will find your
code weird
so so back to the python phonetics you
know they say they support functional
programming but if actually
but if you actually do use python to do
functional programming style uh you know
in in
a functional programming style you will
likely
run into all sorts of uh problems social
problems
for example let's say you write some
program so open source you know you put
on github microsoft's own
owned by microsoft you know you put on
github
and you started to get issues why are
you doing this way and you get
resistance okay this kind of resistance
is not
it's kind of implicit people will just
not like you
anymore because you are not conforming
to the python communities uh ethos and
guidelines you know they have
uh they have programming style
documentation you know programming style
guide
python idioms you know they say pythonic
is your code pythonic you know this
idiot this
[ __ ] programmer idiots hacker types
you know python is
uh pythonic that's their term pythonic
so any other language has
has also has such terms you know
so anyway so if you so two parts first
of all python does not support
functional programming well
uh primarily primarily because
it has a broken lambda okay so why
python lambda is broken and cannot be
fixed okay
so i talked about the in this article
i'm gonna go into it in detail today
uh because bob asked the question
so python the language does not really
support functional programming well
it can of course it can somewhat you
know but
it doesn't then the other aspect is the
community the python
community they don't really you know
they are not into functional programming
they are not
uh they are mostly object oriented you
know they prefer that way
so why why is the python language has
this you know
doesn't do function performing well
technically and also the community
doesn't accept it well
because guido van rossum the boss you
know in each foreign language
pearl larry roy is the boss python
guido von rossum is the boss uh
closure for example closure closure the
based on uh java virtual machine closure
the beast
language closure they uh they also have
um you know there's also a boss
uh rich hiki you know so um
so let me let me show you uh okay so
hacker code so programming languages
okay so let's go to hacker code uh
foreign language tutorial so here here's
a bunch of
programming languages closure you know
the boss is rich hiki
uh so anyway so each programming
language
they have as a creator okay php's got a
creator i forgot his name he's not
you know the hacker type and javascript
for example the creator is javascript
the creator is
what's his name you know he i [ __ ] i
what's what's the javascript creator's
name i forgot that moment anyone
so anyway so so let me get back to the
to focus okay so
each language has a creator for example
uh language ufam language the creator is
uh stefan wufang which i highly
like and respect in compared to the
others
okay that's another topic but anyway so
let's go back to so for example
by the way uh rich hiki said every
developer
would should buy a copy of mathematica
because it will expand your mind
okay which hiki the creator of closure
said that
exactly okay so i did five videos about
mathematica
about wufab language you should uh watch
them in detail
starting about two months ago so
i digressed so let's go back to python
okay so python
so let's not talk about why python
uh let's see why python sucks okay well
why python lambda does not um why python
lambda is broken
and cannot be fixed and why is it
because of the syntax okay
so let me address this question now now
first of all why python lambda is broken
that's a
you know you can consider that as a
claim you know i claim i claim that
uh not just me lots of people have cl
said that for example here is a
well-known computer scientist uh how
abelson you know how absent is one of
the guys who wrote this
very popular book structure and
interpretation of computer programs
now this book is you know highly popular
it's also i mean you'll see lots of
um okay let's show
some memes saudi s-i-c-p you know
this is one of the one of the uh
meme uh book in you know you know in
programming
so um
okay so wait uh so let me show it okay
so let me digress
okay wizard book you know sometimes
it's known as wizard built book
structure and interpretation of computer
programs
sicp sig okay
so so uh but so let me show you so
here's the japanese version and also
here comes the memes there are quite a
few of them
you know this starting about 10 years
ago let's see
2015 yeah start this kind of memes
began you know there's quite a few uh
began about
six or seven years ago you know they put
japanese anime girls
with uh with some esoteric computer
science books or things like that
so anyway so this book by the way this
book i highly recommend it
uh this book i read in 1998
there are four chapters of this book and
i read the three
the first three chapters okay in 1998 uh
in 1998
i was a top master of mathematica okay
i uh where's my articles [ __ ] okay so
let me show you i want to show you my
articles
so in 1998 i was a top expert of
mathematica
and uh you know and i talked
you know watch my videos okay so
mathematica is one of the least
and so it's in in fact it's the most
powerful
lisp in this family i could you know you
could say that
so in 1998 because i'm i began my career
as a mathematic
mathematica program for about seven
years
uh then i started to get into lisp so in
1998 i read this book you know this book
is using scheme
lisp you know one of the dialect of this
was they was the
uh primarily as the language to teach
you
about concept about the you know it's
it's not
like technical details like like linux
how do you use
bash how do you program python yeah you
know which function to go it's not about
that this
book is about more general concept the
general the meaning of
programming the meaning of uh computing
you know base is kind of a bit more
general
uh on the other hand let me digress
if you read lots of stephen wolframs um
uh if you read a lot of stephen wolfram
stuff
his stuff is more general he starts his
stuff is at the
highest level of computation the meaning
of computation
so in at the top level the meaning of
computation you'll get into
lots of theoretical computer science for
example you you go watch
you go watch many of stefan wufam's
video okay he's on youtube and and
twitch
uh and and in particular go
read his blogs he has tons of blogs okay
each each of his blog is about like 20
50 pages takes takes a few hours to read
so if you read stefan wolfram's blog
it's a very
he you know he's talking about
computation the meaning of computation
at the highest level sense okay
and so lots of things here talk about is
for example
uh combinators combinators lambda
calculus
uh theoretical computer uh computer
science
the meaning of computation and that
that in turn ties into uh formal
languages the
foundation of mathematics and currently
starting up
last year he is now doing meta
mathematics or metaphysics
based you know the what he calls uh
physics wolfram physics project
which i started to look into very
interesting by the way i digressed a lot
i'll get back to python okay very
interesting highly interesting because
the meta you know his project wufan
physics
project
okay you can you can see there's a
wikipedia article
and there is also let me magnify so
there's a wikipedia article and there's
the uh official homepage wolfram physics
project you know i'm not too interested
in physics
you know i i don't know much about
physics but however
it turns out when i started to look into
watch his videos and read
his blogs this project is not just about
it's not really
uh about physics it has a lot to do with
the foundation of mathematics or the
ultimate you know the theoretical
computer science what is computable uh
what are the best foundation for you
know
computer science uh recursion theory
things like that okay
so it turns out you know the wolfram
physics project
it's it's not well it's a lot about
physics but
they talk a lot a lot i mean like half
the like the core of it is about the
foundation of mathematics
so so i highly recommend it you
you go uh you go what uh you read his
blogs okay
so you go read his blogs so getting back
to my previous point
you go read his blogs he's talking about
the highest level the meaning of
computation
and he's into cellular automata as one
of the model
for computation and you know he
okay so that's about stephen wufen now
let's get back to this book
structure and interpretation of computer
programs so this
is also high level but not not the kind
of theoretical this is
a higher level it's not a practical how
to book
on python or scheme list it's not like
that at all
so when you if you read this pro uh book
you will not
learn a new language well you you kind
of but but anyway
so this book has four chapters i read
the first three chapters back in 1998
or in 1999 uh and
it's uh you know honestly it's one of
the great
uh it's one of the greatest book let's
say top five
in uh in related to
uh programming or computer science
okay so i highly recommend this book
is it you know there's often this
question is it still relevant you know
today you have tons of information
um you can read this book and it's i
wouldn't say it's necessary okay you
don't have to
uh and also in particular this book is
not concrete
you know it doesn't really actually
teach you you know
if you read this book you will you know
even if you carefully study the whole
thing about
the whole book you will not become a
scheme
this expert not at all because it
actually it does not actually teach you
a particular
language or techniques of programming
but the
overall the more general concept so is
it
worth reading uh yes or no today okay uh
i still recommend it okay if you
especially if you are younger you have
time uh if you are older
then you're you have less time then
there's a lot of other things for
example math
uh so it's not you know so this book is
not you know the
god you know the book of god like many
of these
memes uh you know like to you know they
you know it's interesting it became a
meme you know they did
and you know let me tell you what what
are the
you know there are several memes about
programming
you know that's over all over the place
so this is one of the memes in
in programming you know six book and the
other thing is emacs of course cmax
and you know when you you know you you
must have heard of you know emacs versus
vi
right emacs versus vi
but when it comes to you know like memes
are interesting okay memes is a
millennial generation phenom
phenomenon starting around year 2005
okay millennial generation phenomenon
mean
around 2005 that's the word meme
begin to got invented begin to become
popular but of course if you trace
history
like often if you trace history of a
word etymology
you will eat then you will see oh it was
mentioned 10 years ago or 20 years ago
you'll find the you know the first
mention but that's not
that almost doesn't count you know
because anyway so
we digress okay so anyway in around 2005
starting to have memes you know
millennial generation kind of creation
then in in in programming there are
certain things of people that
becomes very popular as i mean for
example
on twitter or internet you'll see lots
of cats right
cats cat you know it's all over the
place cat but
you will rarely i mean comparatively
comparatively it's
rare to see a meme of dog
so this is interesting so that means cat
is a better meme
cat is more fitting for a meme than a
dog
okay for for reasons okay
why is that that's another interesting
question we can dive into
you know you can think about it so why
is it why is it
so many memes of you know for every
meaning of dog
or other any other animal they are like
100 more
memes about cat why is that you know you
can think about that
but let's let me jump back so in
programming
related memes it's similar certain
topics are
very more suitable for memes emacs for
example emacs versus vi
now this in programming these two
editors are you know
meme material but if you actually look
into memes there are much
more memes about emacs than vi okay
very interesting so you know you can
compare
the cat versus stock memes and the vi
versus emacs
why is it why you know emacs tends to
have more memes
it's more suitable for memes and
then back to for example programming
languages
also certain languages are memorable so
for example let me tell you you know
languages you almost never see
memes okay uh ruby you don't see memes
much
um not much okay um
mathematica no javascript not really
so but you know let me just focus on you
know
this the programming language lisp is
the best
it's the most popular mean material
among programming languages when it
comes to memes okay
for for for reasons okay now
back to the topic about which meme you
know
why is that certain things becomes more
memorable you know
more uh there's lots of more memes about
it
while others are less that's another
interesting topic but
let's not go into that today okay so
now let's go back to python okay so i
was going i was talking about this book
this book is written by these guys you
know one of the guy
harold alberson you know then back to
python okay why am i mentioning that
uh where is it uh
yeah where is my python sucks page okay
so let's go to
uh let's go to python sucks
camp comp land perving okay so i did
several videos about
pro i mean we just you should watch them
okay uh usually i put on my website
those are
relatively good videos of mine
so python okay python why python sucks
so
so why lambda is broken uh lambda is
broken
and cannot be fixed okay so in this
article i claim a few few things
the lambda you know python is a lambda
function uh but it's broken in
uh python so technically you know
lambda basically means a function and
lambda you know the function the
construct function
is the most the most important element
in a functional programming language
okay of all functional programming
language elements let's say currying
tail recursion
uh no side effect you know uh
uh how they call it um something cannot
be modified uh what's the name for that
uh
[ __ ] i'm getting old i forgot the terms
uh how do you call that something cannot
be modified cannot be changed there's a
name right yeah i forgot
so anyway of all elements in a
functional programming language
uh monad for example monad current tail
recursion functions
functions okay functions is the most
important
property aspect in the functional
programming
and that and in most languages that
function is just called lambda okay
so when when lambda when when you have a
language
python you know you have a lambda and
that lambda is crippled
which is the case in python i'm gonna
tell you what i'm gonna explain
then you can say you can't really say
the function you know the language
support we support functional
uh programming very good very well no
it's just [ __ ] it's a [ __ ]
[ __ ] python phonetics [ __ ]
okay uh
by the way there's lots of you know
idiots in all programming languages
these hackers you know they don't know
nothing nothing about social
social structure about how the world
works
they are just you know they are just
nurse besides these hacker types unix
philosophy
they are just uh idiots they happen to
work on computer
you know technical stuff but they
actually know nothing about word
so that you have emacs phonetics you
have vi for next
phonetics you have unix phonetics you
have linux phonetics
they are the same group by the way then
they of course you have python phonetics
you have uh you know
so these phonetics they become culty
they believed
you know they want to be they believed
in certain things uh that's
like they believe in one plus one equals
to three okay
so when you ask python phonetics they
will say oh python suppose
we support functional programming so
well
so i'm what i'm saying is that i'm not
specifically attacking the python
phonetics the idiots but this phenomenon
applies to quite a few other languages
as well for example it applies to
what is my [ __ ] uh it applies to lisp
phonetics very much you know at least is
another language that has
huge humongous you know there's a degree
of fanaticism in these programmers
very a lot tongue of them these markers
these markers
[Laughter]
okay but their beliefs is bananas
they don't know what they do they don't
know what they're talking about
and and when pearl was the most popular
language
around the year 2000 year 2000 for
about 10 years okay pearl is the
most popular language pearl and c
and c plus first okay for 10 years it
kind of
went away today so you know they come
and go this fashion and fads come and go
and you don't hear them anymore
so pearl has a great phonetism you know
for 10 years
you know pearl okay let me tell you
which one
which languages the level of fanaticism
is the highest
lisp okay this pearl
uh python well
python uh among the the ones i have here
okay so in haska okay
i don't have haskell here and of course
there are quite a lot of other languages
and rust okay and rust is the the latest
edition of the phoneticism [ __ ] idiots
you know the exa what do you think of us
you know we i have
i have followers friends okay you guys
uh who are into those ask me all the
time about russ what do you think of
russ
[Laughter]
so i digress a lot again so let's go
back to python why python
lambda sucks so first thing
python lambda is spoken who said that
how albertson said that you know the
author of this book
you know he says you have to content you
know so uh let's see
so he says you have to contend with
python's broken notion of lambda
but other than other than that it's not
really that different
from teaching computer science using
skim disk okay
so with you know this okay so this this
is uh from an interview
how about send questions and answers uh
in year 2011 interviewed by peter siebel
peter sibel is a well-known uh journal
journalist writing about programming
about uh programming industry especially
the technical side
peter c he's pretty old now i guess 60
or 70s
uh but you know anyway you look up he's
there's a wikipedia article about him
i'm pretty sure
yeah i think so in fact in the 1970s he
wrote
um let's see in the 1970s he wrote
you know several volumes of books about
programming languages uh you know this
is back in the day
and 1970s or 1980s
yeah peter 0 okay so
peter scibel
say bio is either a writer is either
a writer turned programmer or programmer
turned writer okay
after picking up undergraduate degree
anyway so anyway he
so he interviewed um
he interviewed heart abberson and this
is what albertson said
lambda python lambda is broken what
what is the context the context is the
phoneticism of
skin lisp okay let me give you the
background of the all this
of the background of the computing
history
so this scheme this impartial scheme
this
is considered the most elegant
programming language
for about 30 years starting from 1970s
to about year 2010 let's say
yeah for for 30 years you know
let's say from 1980s to 2010
scheme this is widely considered
to be the most elegant the most
beautiful
programming language okay and that's
skim this
and skim this you know lisp is a
functional programming
language and uh including me i'm a fan
of it
but it's very sad sad sorry you know
these hacker types these [ __ ] idiots
with their phonetism about marquez and
the tail recursion and crap
with that when no nowhere okay you you
look at the
you look at the industry what the
language they use c
c plus plus java
python php javascript
the worst [ __ ] that's that becomes the
most popular
now you've skim this is the most
beautiful language in haskell and all
these phonetic
phonetics and facts
you know uh so who is my so
for example this scheme uh you know uh
rust you know haskell these people you
know their phoneticism is very high
they think their language is really best
why is that why the [ __ ] is that
after 30 years that you guys are nowhere
you know seeing this
what the [ __ ] who who what the [ __ ] is
skin this people don't know
but even the phenomena died you know the
language is like
basically dead that's that's
okay it might cause opinion imagine
that's because
this hacker this phoneticism [ __ ] they
have no idea what's going on
they all they know is that they have a
you know they want to promote their
things
you know they want to promote it but if
you insist
if you if your idea is incorrect one
plus one equals through three
and you push that idea what happens
you got [ __ ] that's what happens
that's why
skim dis pascal this
in general they go nowhere dead
dead okay commonly you know dead
while language like php javascript
that every hacker these phoneticism you
know these people the this phonetics
the you know the python phonetics they
despise
php they bad bad mouth about php and
javascript for
for for for about 15 years
but however they become the most popular
language
used everywhere that's a phonetism
that's a harm of fanaticism
and that also includes emacs the e-max
magnetic
finances and [ __ ] they they they
made emacs
die you know these fin you know you go
you go to the online today
youtube you know emacs conference you
you'll see lots of these people
emacs can do everything oh my god emac
this is the best language
but in fact it's the worst [ __ ] but they
don't improve they have lots of problems
you know so instead you know among their
little community like
me me and you guys 10 people
yeah emacs is the best thing but outside
of it the
seven billion uh human animals on the
earth
on this earth what what is e-max they
don't know
so back to python let's let's think
let's focus on this topic for today's
whole
uh talk show back to python first of all
lambda is python lambda is working
okay that's one thing now let me explain
technically why is it broken okay um
so i have so i have quite a few things
to explain
one i want to show you uh with code okay
with code
i haven't coded python for a long time
so
what is this page uh let's go to today's
talk show
so let's go to uh python
let's say python3 okay let's start to
code python
print three magnify granite
uh oh yeah python three you need
parenthesis you know the python idiots
the guido von russo
you know they kiro von russom has a
vision
you know he he think his language is the
best
so so python 2 has lots of problems you
know because
you know every language has kind of
problems uh piles of baggage because
accumulated because when you begin to
design a language
you thought this way is better but it
turns out it's not you know
it usually you have that so how you know
so python so guido van rossum decided oh
oh i'm gonna my language is the best
language for education and
the most clarity and i i'm going to get
rid of the watts i don't think
that's good so i'm going to start a new
fresh python 3
incompatible with python 2. and
the result is turned out not so great a
lot
industrial python code is still python 2
after 10 years more than 10 years now
um so anyway python 3 okay so python 3
lambda okay so i haven't coded python
for about a year
or two uh lambda so python lambda so
so what uh so python lambda sucks okay
it's broken so why is that
uh
how do you how do you uh [ __ ] i don't
remember i don't even remember what uh
how do you
okay this is this is when you go to
python tutorial uh
yeah i don't i haven't coded python for
a year or two for
two or three years actually uh paid on
lambda so
actually i can i can tell you if i think
about it
i yeah i haven't coded python for a long
time so
um let's click on
function okay now wait wait do i
actually cover lambda at all
lambda sucks so bad so badly that i
don't even cover it
um okay so what am i doing i want i need
to code lambda okay
uh do i have example here
no
uh
yeah let's just try okay so let's just
try something okay so let me
anyway so what for the rest of the video
what i want to cover is
actual code of lambda then i'm going to
explain
why is it broken why is it it's broken
okay it's
it's actually crippled it's only it does
only some of the things
that lambda is supposed to do okay
crippled uh it's a crippled
function uh and then i'm going to
tell you why it cannot be fixed
why is that it's because the python
syntax so one of the things i
i say the most often is that syntax
is the most important element of a
programming language okay
and again this is a contrary view
from most uh programmers okay because
they don't know nothing
you know most programmers will think in
fact there's a computer science book
says that they will think that syntax is
not
important syntax is actually just
trivial just like sugar syntax just
dressing
dressing on top you know you can change
any syntax it's like clothing you can
you can put on skirt you can put put
down the shirt doesn't matter
but actually really the real thing that
matters is the semantics
that's false okay that's the most
idiotic idea
syntax is the most important element of
a programming language the most
the fundament the most important more
more most
important uh uh most i would you know
even then semantics okay that takes that
will require some explanation okay
syntax soup okay syntax is the most
important aspect of
a programming language the quality of a
programming language
can be judged by how much of it of it
can be explained by its syntax alone
now i did a video about this you know
you know
why you know i'm not going to explain
now but
it has to do it touches on the
fundamental aspect of
the theory theoretical computer
languages
i mean theoretical computer science that
is formal languages okay i did a few
videos on that watch this video
formal languages okay so it is the
touches the
heart of computer theoretical computer
science
anyway so i claim
syntax is most important so back to here
okay back to the lambda okay so
one i'm gonna going to show you in code
why lambda is broken then
i'm going to explain why it cannot be be
fixed okay
now python lambda is broken that's a
well-known thing okay i i
actually i don't even need to cover it
you know just you
you know if you know python if you have
you know
some experience in python you know as
well
if you know some functional programming
you know what i mean
so because i can cover it now but
you know it's not too valuable
what what i believe is more valuable is
my claim that this cannot be
fixed and my claim that this cannot be
fixed
is because the python's
uh syntax okay because the python
indentation based syntax
they are based in class that is why
the lambda cannot be fixed okay
so actually in order to explain that i
do need to uh
remember the lambda thing okay so uh so
what is the lambda thing
um okay so so let's just try the the
the most easy example is to do a array
three four five let's say
three four five two okay so i believe
that's a array in python
and you want to sort the array okay sort
i haven't coded python for a long time
so what what is the python
uh [ __ ] python3
basics
okay anyway i have a sword i have a here
here
here is a sword okay
sword function you know python idiocy
you know they
python is very inconsistent you have the
sort
method okay then you have the sort
function okay now the function is has
this idiotic name
sorted you know the past tense sorted
that's a function
yeah [ __ ] idiot okay so anyway
let me just try uh refresh myself um
you know so so let's let's say we want
to
print okay right there it is
so we begin with the array three four
five two we want to sort it and here is
the
you know the sorted result okay now let
me tell you
let's try something fresh uh i mean
let's try something
i mean i'm gonna i'm gonna start to use
lambda okay so
this is one way i i remember how to uh
use uh sort so i believe we have a lot
comments
okay so am i still talking let me check
20 people watching okay so how long have
i been
been talking uh i've been talking for
40 minutes okay not too bad lots of rent
continuous non-stop
that the density is beyond
beyond known elements uh
star talk show that's what you're
watching
uh so so so lambda let's this yeah so
lambda
escape back to lambda so in order to do
to use that first of all i want to
um actually another way to use lambda
is
what what is the okay i don't remember
the lambda syntax oh there it is
the [ __ ] [ __ ] the python uh
okay so lambda okay so lambda let's say
let's just
let's say simple okay a function that
returns
uh x plus one okay so that's lambda
let's comment this out
so this is lambda and let's say uh
function you can actually assign it
so now function
let's evaluate at 2 okay now
print it okay
so here's our code so we have we have a
lambda
this function returns whatever argument
plus one
then we evaluate it at number two
okay so here's the result three okay
that's how
that's that is the lambda in python okay
now lambda so
let's let's do another function
uh let's say f2 now this time we have
two arguments
x and y and this time uh it just add
them up okay
so uh
so now
okay so now let's say uh let's let's see
yeah okay let's just go okay so now we
want to add two plus three run it
five okay so you see so that's how you
define lambda
okay that's that's lambda in python and
that is
all okay there's nothing else you can do
okay
now first of all so let's go get back to
the question so
i'm trying to explain why lambda in
python is broken by
actual example so what's wrong with the
lambda here
so the the first of all notice that the
the lambda in python can only be one
single line
you cannot you cannot
uh put two lines okay so hold on a
second let me let me show you okay so
let's say for example
so we have this one single lambda let's
try to put it in two lines
okay so that doesn't work okay so you
see syntax error okay
so but you actually you can make it work
by adding this thing okay
no it doesn't work wait uh okay you
don't you cannot have space okay so here
okay you see now it works you have to
add this
backslash now backslash in in
python means continue like continue the
current line
so that you know that is equivalent to
this line so that's how you can have
multiple lines
to define uh to construct the lambda
function okay
so what's my point so my point is that
lambda in python
essentially can can only have one line
one single line
you you you know you can force it into
multiple lines by using the backslash
but
but the remember the backslash that's
just a
mechanism to to make multiple lines into
a single line so even with backslash
it basically still a single line okay
it's still a single line
so what's the problem with the single
line line
lambda the problem is that you know
lambda in general is a
basic you know it's the meaning of
lambda is to define your function
now so when you limit your function
definition to a single line
and in particular because the python
syntax you know python syntax
is indentation whenever you have nesting
or complex things you have to indent it
that means you have to have you have to
have multiple lines
so when you have a lambda you know
when you have a way to define a function
and it must be only one line but however
however the python syntax
require multiple lines because whenever
you have complex things you need in the
indentation that means you need multiple
lines
so you cannot you cannot
use lambda to define uh
arbitrary function you know
in in a practical way in real life you
know the only
the only time you use lambda in python
is when the function is very simple you
know
like like our example uh
like our example okay so you know you
know adding you know add one or
what x plus one basically the only
in practice the only time you use lambda
in python
is when the function is very simple you
know what
one single line that fits one single
line
otherwise you cannot use lambda okay so
so let me explain what what's the
significance of these
so lambda is a way to define a function
right it's the most
important element in a function of
programming language so
a function so because functional
programming everything is a function you
chain functions together to make your
program okay
your entire program is made of is
consists of function definitions and
evaluation of those
functions so functions is the
core element the central part of your
code your source code okay your program
in your functional programming language
but now you are saying in pi in the case
of python you are saying
all your function must be simple
functions only you cannot have complex
functions what the [ __ ] is that you know
you cannot write programs in this
language okay so that is why
python lambda is spoken so so you cannot
use lambda so when you cannot use lambda
what do you do you use the definition
okay
you know the the more proper way
you know i don't remember the python
syntax okay define
okay so that's how you do it i guess x
plus one okay
so define function uh
x uh f3 okay so this is how you define a
function
properly in python okay let's try it
uh let's try it
okay let's read oh return uh
you know idiotic python so here's
another example
you know python needs a return statement
in a functional programming language
usually when you define a function
you don't you don't have the return
statement
any expression that comes last is the
return
value okay everything in functional
programming everything tends to be
expressions okay
so you don't have return statement the
fact that
first of all python lambda is broken
then the proper way to define a function
you need the return statement what that
like so so that means
you know that supports you know this is
supports my claim
lamp you know python is not a very good
you know it's not a good
uh language to do functional programming
at all
you know contrary to python phonetics
okay so anyway here's how you define a
function properly in python okay return
statement okay
so uh so you run it here you know you
got the results
three three right so
so okay i think that um that covers why
python lambda is broken you know and why
is it because
syntax okay now you can so i've talked
you know so you have seen
python syntax it has to do with python
syntax because
the python lambda is basically single
line you know
uh practically it's just a single line
functions
simple functions the the proper way to
define a function
is actually using the def and require
multiple
multiple lines okay so
so um so
so that so that tells you okay lambda is
broken okay
so in so in practice you you know you
whenever you you use
you use lambda in python you cannot use
lambda whenever you
want to define a real you know complex
function you have you cannot use lambda
so lambda is broken
in python okay now now the second part
it cannot be fixed okay so
now this now this comes interesting okay
so
suppose you are guido rondrossa you know
you received many complaints from the
functional programming
phonetics they say python lambda is it
sucks
you know can we in next version of
python python 3
python 3000 okay here is a you know
here is a guido you know guido is kind
of a
passive aggressive guy you know guido
von listen
you know he wrote the article he wrote
the article
the fate of reduce in python 3000
[Laughter]
the fate of reduce if you don't know
reduce is a
major uh construct in functional
programming
and he wrote the article back in 2005
the fate of reducing python 3000
he's a he's a passive aggressive guy he
doesn't like
functional programming but he he's full
of himself he thinks that
his opinion is the most the best opinion
you know
so i analyzed his blog here
anyway so so and and
you know there's a lot of story about
this blog and the skin
people okay the skin people lambda in
python 3 000 the skinned people
also wrote a a
sarcastic taunt okay
uh where is it okay so where is it
yeah the the fate of lambda in python
3000 versus skim 3000
okay there it is you know so python
wrote the article then the scheme these
people you know the people from that
you know this book you know fans of this
book you know they wrote a
counter a parody the parody okay
they wrote a parody on april 1st
uh april 1st 2005 also the fate of
lambda
in plt scheme version 300.
[Laughter]
or lambda the ultimate design flow
you know they wrote the parody of the
guido van gaal some [ __ ]
the guido idiot okay so let me get back
to the point
why can it not be fixed okay so
so if you are guido von russom for
example you receive a lot of complaints
from
functional programming phonetics they
say oh can you fix python lambda you
know we need
can you extend it so kirov and rossum
actually thought about it in one of the
article here
okay let me show you this article
ah this guido van rosen passive
aggressive guy you know he wrote the
article
in 2006 and the title of the article is
language design is not just solving
puzzles
okay guys you know you i oh you think
language
design is just starving puzzles no you
idiot
language design is not just serving
serving puzzles
okay guido rossum okay
so again i i i i wrote a
uh answer you know retort uh to his
uh idiocy so he you know he passive
aggressive guy guido von russo
and brainless you know he doesn't you
know in my opinion
among the you know among all the people
who have designed programming languages
some are really smart okay now where is
my
okay here some are really smart some not
so much
okay python github listen not too smart
okay pearl larry larry wood not too
smart
okay uh and uh
you know uh and you know and there are
other people you know
it's it's you know you know
it's hard to make one sentence summary
about uh
the creators okay but anyway i in
particular
pearl the pearl leader you know the
creator of pearl and python i don't
think they are too smart
and ruby is not also not i mean i i
don't want to say not too smart because
that's kind of derogatory okay so
let me put it in another way so among
of the creators of programming languages
some some knows a lot okay some notes
you know uh you know theories about uh
programming computer science you know
uh they know a lot about mathematics
they they know a lot in general okay so
they
uh they they know a lot but i mean on
the other hand
many of the creators of programming
languages they just happen to
to become okay for example php
happen to become okay also i would
include javascript
javascript who's who what's the name of
the javascript guy uh
guys uh who you know what what's the
name of the javascript guy
um i forgot that moment i'm getting old
or something
um
ike you know x something in the creator
of javascript
uh in many cases i have kind of talked
with them
you know online you know in many many of
these people
anyway so the people you know most of
the
programming language creators they are
not actually
uh you know solid computer scientists in
fact many of them don't know nothing
about computer
science science okay i would include i
would include
you know anyway i i want to be careful
in the wording of this
because otherwise it's incorrect
so so so anyway many of programming
language creators they are not you know
really
like computer science background or or
such
uh it just happened to be i mean of
course they are all talented you know i
want to make sure
uh you know they are of course they are
all
uh they are or um
you know not just talented they they are
they you know they did great things you
know they did
they they they created things for you
know for the benefit let's say for the
benefit of humanity
anyway so but they are not really uh
you know great computer scientists in
fact in fact many
in many cases they don't know much about
you know theater
theoretical computer science so much
anything else anyway so
pearl python php javascript
these people okay i would say they don't
you know they did you know yeah they did
great things but they don't know
they don't know much okay okay
uh on the other hand in contrast okay
you know of the people i respect much
more
much much more uh would be
you know wolfham language stefan wufang
uh
golan you know golan rob pike
he's great he's got great ideas you know
um
anyway i'm this requires another another
hour
talk in thinking because then about the
creators of programming languages but
anyway
i want to make a point is that it's it's
not difficult to
create a programming language okay
especially today like today
so because you have so many tools you
have compilers written for you
you have lots of information wikipedia
you know
it's very easy as opposed to 20 years
ago
in the 1990s 30 years ago that's much
more hard you don't have wikipedia if
you want to learn a compiler
you go to a library or bookstore to buy
a compiler book
and of limited information written by
you know just a
couple of guys and you know you have to
have a lot of experience
uh not like today you have so many so
many so many so much tools available to
you
okay i i kind of digressed and lost my
um
so i want to get back to the python okay
so what
was i talking i i kind of lost
um
so anyway let's i forgot what how did i
start to talk about that
brendan ike yeah brain like is the
creator of javascript
yeah so in it's created invented and
implemented in 10 days a very very well
known story
and that's true so let's go back to
python okay i hope
i answered the question so why is it
broken so yeah back to the guido guido
so
he wrote article gidowan russo
you know he wrote an article about how
to fix
the lambda in python okay so he wrote
article python lambda
you know language design is not just
solving puzzles
i believe this is article in this
article he
dived into
he dived into there it is you see
uh someone claimed you know for example
today
you know he's he's kind of a passive
aggressive guy
you know so he says for example some
today someone claimed to have solved
the problem of multi-statement lambda
okay
so basically in this article he's saying
you know people he
you know people want him to fix lambda
so that lambda
in python can have multiple lines so
that it becomes an
actual real construct for functions you
know
and he's making fun of people you know
basically he says it cannot be done
okay he says you know he considered all
the
possible suggestions and in his opinion
it
you know it shouldn't be done or cannot
be done okay
so there it is he himself made that
kind of said that it cannot be fixed
and should not be fixed okay in his
opinion
he python guido von russom he want to
limit the lambda in python to be just
for simple functions one single line
functions
when you need multiple lines don't use
lambda that's his opinion
okay so it's broken and why is it broken
why is it
cannot be fixed because the python
syntax
that concludes my uh thesis my claim
okay python lambda broken and why
is why is it broken that's well known
you know
that's a universally agreed mostly
okay and why cannot be fixed it's
because
python lambda syntax okay
because of the syntax of python and that
ties to my claim
that syntax is in fact
very important and you know i i would i
would claim the most important element
in programming language
that needs some kind of context because
what do you mean by
most important how do you define what's
important you know
but anyway so at least i would say so
syntax is
one of the most important thing in
programming language
and here is an example you see right now
python has a broken lambda and it cannot
be fixed
because the syntax you know the choice
of syntax
of python okay syntax is a very
important element okay i think that's
fin
that finished my
the topic for today's talk show uh uh
which is um uh
both question okay okay that's it
that's it today i i guess that's it
today
uh if you like my stuff donate okay if
you find my stuff
interesting put money in my pocket okay
so i have
you know you go to my website
okay uh python tutorial open a new
page open a new page
so you go to my excited info
and you'll see the donation button the
paypal and
you know paypal me
amazon gift card me picture me
put money in my pocket okay that is my
message
uh and of course you can also buy my
emacs tutorial
uh and my javascript in-depth tutorial
okay
emac this tutorial okay thank you guys
for watching
uh now i'm going to read the comments
for maybe five minutes
and talk stuff and uh and that's it for
today
okay so let's see what you guys been
saying
so
so there's a question from now off why
did you
switch to windows okay that's a common
frequently asked question because that's
the most
shallow question i don't mean to
criticize you but that's a you know
like every programmer needs to know why
are you using
windows why are using linux why are
using mac os which one is the best which
one should i use
you know in fact i have a i did a video
talking about that
you know you you search it about half a
year ago a year ago
uh so i um you know so i'm on
windows right now so uh
so let me just give you a summary okay
what i think about that so
which one should you use linux or mac os
or windows okay each one has
problems which each one has advantages
and each one has
problems and uh it turns out
it happened to be that way there's no
like one is much better than the other
because
for example you know okay let me just
cover let me just say okay
for example windows if you play video
games uh
basically you know windows is your only
choice
and you know windows yeah if you play
video games
uh you know if you are a gamer if you
need a graphics card
windows is basically your only choice
okay uh you can get a mac
then you know the graphics card sucks or
super expensive three times more
expensive than
the than windows three times more
expensive for the same ram
on win than with than windows if you get
a mac if you get linux the graphics card
doesn't work
uh the game doesn't work this game
doesn't work then you have to spend 1000
hours to
dig to hack okay this is the way you
know to fix the graphic card drivers
this
linux diddling [ __ ] linux hackers linux
idiots
so if you play video games or if you do
anything mainstream like lots of
uh i don't know uh audio or audio
processing especially video audio
uh games you need windows okay windows
is the best choice
okay now if you don't if you do not play
video games and if you
are really concerned about privacy you
know you are one of the
uh conspiracy nut job you know you
you don't like you know you you are
concerned about big brother and you know
you want privacy
you work in the security sector
or you are open source phonetics then
linux is your best platform okay i
i'm mostly open source
you know i i despise the open source you
know i think there's lots of things
wrong but
most of my technologies linux python you
know
all the languages i know are of the
you know kind of the unix or open source
background so
anyway so if you are
if you are a poor sub you know you if
you are a poor student you don't have
money
and you are you are into open source you
are open source phonetics
you program in golan for example golan
python you love golem python ruby pearl
emacs emac base all this open source
kind of technology
svg uh and you know html and
if you are in git you know and before
that svn
if you are that type of guy linux there
it is
linux is your daddy it's your mommy go
to mommy
linux is your best platform okay it's
free
it's free guys free free like free like
free pizza
but the problem of course if you need a
audio video
it sucks it sucks donkey ass it sucks to
the most extreme
uh you you spend 10 000 hours on stack
overflow
and all the answers you found is 10
years old 20 years old documentation
and and arc linux you dive into arc
linux so gen 2
or whatever the you know the new kid in
town the
window managers which we you know go go
spend your time on
on those things it's good waste your
life on it
linux yeah but if if you are you know if
you are
or you if you are just a dev developer
programmers you know yeah linux is
is it's your best choice now if you have
money
if you have money okay mac is the best
okay
mac for privacy concerns mac is better
than windows
and possibly even better than linux okay
well except apple apple okay
apple also do get your data but you you
can trust apple
in that department not that much
anyway linux these days you cannot even
be sure what's going on
because the fbi the cia the big
government the google they have
they have code inside linux how do you
know you don't know
unless you work with linux kernel for
five years then you
you know you know the the linux you are
using is trustworthy or not
if you are just a student if you are
just the open source phonetic
uh even if you are a good grade python
programmer said
but you don't know linux kernel you
don't see
yeah you don't know you cannot trust
linux because all the big powers they
have things yeah you know
it's not so easy today to uh to know
who is trustworthy anyway if you have
money apple is the best platform
the the best user interface by far
by far than windows or or linux
everything just
works mac okay but
everything mac is twice as expensive
okay
if you want to buy the mouse the same
mouse if you are from the mac community
it's like twice as expensive the same
thing
everything yeah but you know then you
have word garden
everything you know just like rich
people elite you live in a place you
have
you know you have watch dogs you know
take care of your
your garden uh you know and thieves you
know
so that's that linux smack
versus you know um it's kind of that
yeah immune immutability oh god
i forgot the basic word immutable
immutable that's the
jargon immutability when you cannot
change
you know a variable by the way that this
okay that i digressed you know i i might
take
talk another five or ten minutes if i
talk start to talk about that
there's a very interesting okay so here
there's a
very interesting thing about immunity
the concept
of being immutable in different
programming languages
let me just say it quickly okay for
example in golan
and in java the meaning of
and much more than that the meaning of
what's in the immune purity is
language dependent also the concept is
also fishy okay
let me just quickly explain okay first
of all in python for example python you
have an array okay right
you yeah a python you have a ray okay so
where is my
python code so here is a
so so here is a python array
now python in fact in most languages in
ruby
python list in javascript in php2
array usually so when you assign an
array to a
to a variable it actually is a reference
you know that
that that is the content of the x you
know they
they have the concept of references and
pointers the idiocy from c
so so when you have im so for example
when you say
x let's say constant can how can you
define constant in python i
forgot if you can i don't know if you
can or not but in javascript you can
in golan you can also but anyway here's
the question okay when you
assign something to x okay usually the
value of x is actually a reference okay
it's like a number the memory address or
something but then you can change the
array
so if you can change the array element
does that mean
so the the reference does not actually
change
actually in python in javascript let me
show you
okay javascript okay constant okay
let's save this as a javascript dot
javascript okay let's save this file
so here we have a array
three four five okay that's a constant
okay let's not say constant let's say
let okay
so you have three row five though so um
uh
actually let's say constant okay so you
have a constant okay
now let's say x let's say the first one
let's change it to one okay
now print
x okay let's say that
okay so run it you can see we changed it
we changed it you see before the array
is 345.
now the value of the array is 145.
but but you use i said here constant
y it's supposed to be constant you know
when you when you have something
declared a constant
that means you cannot change it when you
change it it will give you errors
for example let's say let's say another
constant okay
okay let's say if i run that you see
error
encode type error assign assignment to
constant variable
you know you see but now but now
you see this array we change the value
but it works
so what's going on well the reason the
reason for that is because
the value of array assigned to the x is
actually just a reference the rest
the reference doesn't actually change so
actually
the x the value of x didn't change but
however
the array itself changed so you here you
run into an issue of
of of a practicality of a
intuitiveness because you thought you
think that you know
you have a ray if i say constant it's
not supposed to let me change but not
actually i can change the elements
so that's wrong so what's going on so so
that's the issue about immutability okay
this happens so
on the other hand gold line if you try
golan it
it treats this issue in a different way
so that's interesting about immune
immutability okay
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
uh fasting says are you upset that you
invested so much time in dying
programming language not really
i talked about that before you know
people see i get mad or something
they think what's going on uh i'm not
i'm not actually
mad you know i'm just that's i'm just me
i'm just that's just my personality
why do i despise the unix the linux or
the
phonetics information in open source in
programming languages
because they are just incorrect okay
you know you heard the expression
someone is wrong on the internet
you know that refers to the phenomenon
or the common very common
uh nerd kind of situation where you feel
like
you have a need to be argumentative
uh oh you know it's kind of a nerd
quality which
exists in lots of you guys as well you
know i know
you argue all the time i i just happen
to be more severe okay i just happen to
be
more severe i'm not like angry or mad
or i have to do something no no okay i
i i despite this despise the you know
these phonetics because they are
incorrect they are patently incorrect
about something and in turn that creates
perpetual uh pervasive harm
in programming in in the field which is
programming
the unix the unix philosophy the
the python phoneticism the e-max
phoneticism
creates pervasive
harm in each of the percep perspective
communities
you know they drag the language down you
know
then in turn they dragged the whole
programming industry down
that's that is why today we have didn't
we have to deal with so much
[ __ ] crap in web programming doesn't
work this doesn't work there's a bug
you know then you go fire or fire or bug
report what the [ __ ] is that
you're not supposed to do that computers
on is not supposed to
create errors on the fly like humans do
computers it's cold it's not it's not
supposed to go wrong
what whatever is wrong is the human
animals you you [ __ ]
the programmer [ __ ] the eunuchs
people that creates
the situation that creates the normalcy
the norm today
where we have lots of bugs it becomes
actually
you know it becomes normal it's accepted
oh it's just a bug
oh go fire fight go go fire a bug report
that's not supposed to be that way
you know it's not supposed to be oh
window this doesn't work oh that crash
not supposed to happen this happened
it happened because new programmers the
past for the past
30 years the [ __ ] the free software
foundation glue richard snowman
[ __ ] the unix philosophy pushing
for crap
you know pushing for incorrect pushing
for one plus one
equals to three they push and push
why do they push part of the reason is
money okay
now now of course free software and open
source
is excluded but anyway a lot of it has
to do with money
corporations they push okay money makes
the go
the world go around so they you know you
push the wrong ideas
you end up bad you end up bad so it has
consequences so that is why we you know
you you hear it everywhere
you know this sucks or that sucks not
just me saying that okay
and i do have some personal opinions you
know which is uh
uh which is particular to me uh
and which is not necessarily right okay
i'm not saying i'm always right
you know some some of my opinions might
be extreme
for example my opinions about how how
how everything if how all the things
that's wrong is
because of unix
and c you know so you know sometimes i
make drama
dramatic claims like click bait you know
that's
that's what that's how i get you you
know that
when it whenever i do that i get more
viewers
okay that's that's part of the
kind of the how human works you know so
some of my
claim is a bit a little bit dramatic
but but actually most of
the time all of the time actually i
believe that
okay i do believe okay now listen i do
believe
that unix
the hacker types and the unix philosophy
they have done tremendous harm to the
computing
industry to this day okay and i i have
explained some of the concrete examples
for example the
obsession about line truncation so in
other words in other words let me put it
in
you know accept a acceptable way you
know today
in many program languages you know they
tell you they have the idiom they tell
you to add
you know your lines cannot be more than
80 characters
so but that idea that
that that idiom that guideline is
actually
bad because it wastes tremendous time
of human effort and also it kind of
prevents it thoughts the progress of
automatic formatting you know so
so that idea where that idea came from
unix the unix
factors pushed that idea all over the
place
it became a standard you know like most
of you don't know
like like you don't know like why is sod
so crazy did we have this
guy crazy he's talking but think about
it where does that idea come from the
line truncation
to this day like when you when you're on
twitter or when you
when you are on discord do you think
when you start to type you think oh oh
oh i'm over 80 characters i must press
the return now do you do that
do you do that on twitter do you do that
when you write email
why do you have to do that when you do
when you write a programming language
you are a [ __ ]
okay where does that come from from the
unix
philosophy spreading patently forced
ideas all over the place
and it becomes the normal it becomes
normal you don't have to do that in
programming languages
there's a thing called automatic
formatting i talked about that
you know in lots of my i'm not talking
about the emacs like
the field column that
anyway that's another topic okay i
talked about that a lot
autumn you know so so that that is why
i'm
angry not angry in a sense that you know
it's kind of my just my personality okay
this
incorrect you know incorrect force ideas
that spread on things that i'm
passionate about
programming you know programming
language design in fact
python is one of the victim why does
python
let me tell you okay since today we are
talking about python why does the python
choose the syntax indentation based
syntax
where does that come from okay you know
we can
explain that in many ways but a dramatic
way to
in my opinion that's because the unix
the e
unix idiocy okay why does python
the guido von wilson i i mean why does
python and in fact lots of python
derived for example yamo
lots of the template languages you know
based on the python indentation uh i
have articles on that okay i have quite
a lot of articles on that
why is it that why is that why does
people do that
that i would say it came from the unix
philosophy the truncation
the truncation of lines 80 characters
came from all the harm all the pervasive
that's why i say it's pervasive huh
so we have not almost all languages are
based on c
syntax why is that because the c [ __ ]
the
the c and unix pervasive harm they
spread
they become a standard you know the unix
people tell you tell
everyone you must do it this way this is
not the standard
it's harmful it's incorrect bad ideas by
technical you can
you can scientific scientifically
evaluate those are bad ideas
but it becomes pervasive it's no it's
normal now
and anyone who do not believe that you
think it's crazy like me
okay so let me go get back so why is
python indentation based
well that came from the one of the idea
of the of the idea that
lines should not be be no be more than
character
80 characters because more than that
it's hard to read but this act
people don't get it the the point is
that you need to have
automatic automated formatting that's
the thing you don't want
actual you don't want actual let me turn
on the
you know you see you see the line return
you don't want actual that
you want you want this
you want flexible formatting like like
for example in mathematica or la
tech anyway uh that's gonna take me
another hour to
to to um uh talk about okay so anyway
that's it for today
okay bye guys
you