good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of what's up show
now it's 2022
today is january 3rd and how are you
guys so i don't have a topic here in
fact i'm not prepared
i am not prepared i'm not am not
prepared so what are we going to do
today so you guys have a topic i mean
not topic suggestion but
like actually if you have seen lots of
my videos you know what do you questions
you have to ask me or pick a topic for
my topic notes
uh so i wasn't prepared today so i went
to sleep like i woke up um
just a bit before so but i we but i have
a lot to do like tons to do so
let's do some okay so
my god my you know my arm hurts you know
the rsi here
it's so bad it's you know
like it hurts right now
typing too much and uh and get in
getting old so this is my kinesis
advantage too and this is my ultimate
hacking keyboard
on top and so
so you know as you know this so there's
a question you didn't watch my videos
the link 0998 the link are you the link
from russia
so
so the advantage 360 you know i talked
about you know so actually
uh i cannot
you know tell you what's going on but
until because because you know they they
are not the final uh product is not
ready yet okay so
i'm not going to tell you uh
about it i'm not going to do like
unboxing like i talked about last time
until they release it you know so
um
but you can trust me so you can buy this
one or the new one
either one is good okay that's all i'm
gonna say you can buy this one kinesis
advantage 2 or you can buy the
advantage 360. both egg both are good
okay so you know apparently they they
they did they started pre-order and the
pre-order is already sold out you know
it sold out in 30 minutes so it's
amazing
so
so um
but i want to tell you another keyboard
i highly recommend okay so but i i
didn't have a chance you know they sent
it to me but i didn't have a chance to
talk to talk about it too much that is
this one okay
so okay so let me
so that's the expose okay you know i got
the new one exposed like okay let me
take
good morning from italy good morning
italy
so
can you see it
there it is no you cannot see it okay so
this is the
this is the xbox
knight okay so let's see
yeah i cannot see it myself
okay it's a bit dusty
so so this so this x
exposed okay so
actually it's thirsty let me
so the xbox i always love the xbox so i
would highly recommend
xbox i mean my favorite is the kinesis
advantage and the expose
so they sent me a new one
uh this is the xbox knight so this is
the new one actually exposed keyboard
knight so this one
and it's fantastic except they sent me
the wrong key switch this is this is
brown but my
because i typed so much
i got rsi so i cannot use the brown was
my daily driver because
of your keyboard makers you send me
something it got the red switches linear
light red switches then i can put it
here i can use it daily
then i can help you sales so i you know
so expose is really great i haven't had
time
to send me a message they sent me the
wrong one so i can't use it
try dwm tag methods
do what i mean tag message so so what
does that mean what's a dwm dude is that
dwm the titling window managers or does
that mean uh
to what i mean so what is the tag method
i don't know
i don't know what's that
so i so i want to do some coding okay so
too bad i'm not prepared today so
let's talk random them coding so you
guys don't have a topic that's always
the case
uh
so eyebrows too heavy for you that's
true that i talked about this many times
how did you get rsi from them
i talked about that many times okay so
you guys watch my videos in the past two
months okay there's a lot you should
watch them
uh you know so one of the questions i
thought the brown ones were good for
typing yeah that's the intro intro
information to mechanical keyboard users
that's what i thought too
which is which are
kind of true you know it's fine until
after 10 years then
so okay so basically so so so okay so
there's a question about key uh let's
talk about let me tell you about the
um
about the key mechanical key switches
okay so let me give you a basic so you
go to xr keyboard search just search for
it then you have uh design flaws you
have key switches this page introduces
you
about all about key switches you know
what they are from you know you don't
have to be expert you can just read this
page so keyboard mechanical keyboard key
switch mechanisms the most popular is a
rubber dome and this one the robot does
mechanism break break your fingers
and on laptops
similarly you have rubber dome but you
have the scissor mechanism that's called
scissor switch okay that also sucks okay
i got the mac
okay let's let me show you again
so i got a mac
air
this is m1 macbook air fantastic
a computer without a fan
okay so let's
let me open it
a computer without a fan
you see
apple design is just fantastic okay but
the key
the keyboard is much better than the
than their previous you know the apple
without steve jobs they started to do
idiotic things
okay so there's a lot of digression so
let's
let's talk about okay random ish
kassad does not want the workspace
that's right so you guys you know
instead of just popping a question to me
watch my old videos because i'm not
gonna because the same question every
day is gonna be the same
question
so you know
so let's go to talk show
so we talked about uh keyboard mechanism
we're gonna finish it but before we do
that so let me show you the apple
apple design crap
okay so all about keyboard design issues
then you have the some of the
fantastic
idiocy of apple okay the word apple is
the greatest design
but in the past several years like
almost 10 years since steve jobs is gone
you got this crap dongle hair okay
don't go hell
and you know these dongles usually if
you buy apple's version it costs you
like two or three times more expensive
don't go hell
then you have this these this extreme
idiocy you know the the mouse and then
you have this idiocy
and then you have this
touch bar idiocy you know so apple
created you know tremendous engineering
into the touch bar and into the mac os
documentation the dev that you know
tremendous time spent on this extreme
idiotic [ __ ]
you know this is this is what happens to
nerds without steve jobs steve jobs you
know steve jobs is the guy who truly
understand design what people need you
know
you know
i talked about i've been an apple user
since 1992 so there's lots of history
lots of things you are using now is
because of apple thank thank apple
thanks steve jobs the mouse the gui the
usb the cd
uh drive the dvd drive you know that's
all thanks to apple the speed you know
the the wireless thank you thank you
apple you gotta thank apple because
apple is of always he the apple has
always been the first to put it on their
computers or all of their computers then
after two or three years then the the
the windows or the linux linux is the
most extreme idiocy you know after two
or three years or even five then the
window the pc started to oh we need we
actually need usb on our machine we need
wi-fi
bld you know
but apple you know so apple began the
revolution you know yeah
then after several years the you know
the rest of the industry followed
but but in the past you know since the
steve job died
steve job died okay
so
so let me show you some of the articles
i actually talked about but
um
okay several okay
so here is richard stowman on steve jobs
death
richard stowman has become a scum
okay so that's one of the article
so steve job died in 2011. almost 10
years ago exactly okay
so i'm not gonna talk about that so this
is steve jobs you know he died in 2011.
steve jobs is the one of the guy i
talked about this many times in one of
my video okay so who who do i admire in
the industry in computer industry steve
jobs stefan wufan
and few others okay but these two are
the primary so i so i've been following
steve jobs since 1990 since 1991 okay
when i was a student you know i read a
lot about steve jobs what's this guy
doing you know so
i admired this guy so
uh steve jobs okay so he died 2011 and
this is a screenshot so this is a record
of history
screenshot of apple website
during at the time okay 2011 then here
is google so you can see google also uh
you know
had a tribute to steve jobs steve jobs
1955 to 2011.
now steve jobs is an
uh orphan okay he's a um kind of he's
orphan
so anyway so then steve jobs so so this
guy really got the vision okay so let's
turn on javascript
and see steve jobs three months before
he died so this is uh you can see steve
jobs before they build the apple ufo
building so if you don't know so steve
jobs this is mountain view for the santa
clara you know they went to the solution
so this is 2011 the year he died you
know just few months ago so he
he is talking about building this ufo
apple ufo building you know he has to
get get permission from the city council
so this is kind of his
last
appearance in public you know this
apple vision ufo building okay so
so i have a video there
uh
then
then the unix [ __ ] the linux
[ __ ] okay let me tell you i i
talked about this a year ago on my video
okay you know one one one of the problem
with doing youtube
video is that you know today there's so
many uh like a few thousand per per
per second every second there's a few
thousand hours of video so
so one of the problem is that you if
you're a youtuber you talk about some
certain topics they
you know people cannot watch every one
of your videos you know
there's a lot there are thousands of
other people right so
so one of the occurring um
i mean people you know so people you
might
found you might find my videos you know
maybe a month ago you like it very much
but then you have some questions you
know
according to my content then you ask
those questions and um
i already talked about that 10 times
you know in the past years so that's
often the problem to other youtubers as
well because you know
many youtubers they've been doing it for
10 years uh they are much more
popular than me and you know they you
all have the same problem
so anyway so
steve jobs this is the unix facts and
linux unix linux they're brainwashed
they're edc their idioc okay their brain
don't know what's going on so
when steve jobs died in 2011
this
meme the malayan idiot [ __ ] meme pops up
over and over you see this every day on
reddit on hacker news on on twitter
and not just that year you know after
you know next year you'll see this again
then people's the linux idiots they
spread it all over so this means says
this meme says you know become a hipster
sell stolen ideas steve jobs you know
placed by media as jesus of computing
you know this
according to these linux idiots
[ __ ] extreme idiots they're [ __ ]
[ __ ] not just idiots they are
morally [ __ ] too
okay so they say these you know they
they they say see jobs oh he's just a
he's just a clown stealing people's
ideas but however he's admired by the
media okay that's what the linux unix
[ __ ] say these idiots
then
adjacent to it you know
uh they say
the denise richie okay denis richie
who you know invented c and unix ignored
these linux idiots
so what am i so so
you know um
denise richie also died in 2011 okay so
as you get old a lot of people you know
uh they they they die you know like uh
even including including you know the
stars you know the singers the rock and
roll bands or whatever all the people
you die was as you get older
but anyway these two
died in the same year 2011. so they
these linux idiots posted these things
over
so
so so so let me
talk about this let me address these
these idiots brain okay so
do you know how many how many
mathematicians you know mathematicians
that created the
without them you don't have you know
people going to the room to the room to
the moon you don't have airplane you
don't have cars you don't have engines
you don't have nothing you don't have
computers
mathematicians okay how many of them
died that you are aware of in the past
decade
okay
so
if you want to think of like this you
know so though all those mathematicians
from a
human animal history contribute
contribution point of view if you want
to like
compete you know if you want to rank
their importance their contribution to
the history of human animals two
thousand three thousand recorded history
four thousand recorded history plus you
know hundred thousands more human animal
history
at least three thousand or four thousand
years of them are recorded
like
by a writing system of human animals so
of all these human in in human animal
history
if you want to rank their contributions
to the prosperity of human animals how
many management mathematicians do you
know you [ __ ] unix [ __ ] it
okay
so
those mathematicians who died who passed
away who died in the past 10 years
almost every one of them is more
important than than than the than the
denise richie [ __ ] then how come you
don't see a meme that's that says oh
you know the the denise richie invented
c and unix he become a god
among the linux unix [ __ ] but
however let's say
um
let's say uh coxter okay this this is
quite a lot let's let's say
coxster okay the the canadian geometry
mathematician
um
let's say
conway john houghton conway okay
there's quite a lot you know
so
they created things
that is far more significant
than this [ __ ] engineer this is a
mere engineer
you know
so where are they so how come you don't
see a meme about that
okay that's my point
so this this unix linux idiots memes
over okay
and by the way john mccarthy also died
that year i believe something
close okay
when did he pass away
yeah also in about the same year
but no mention of it
john mccarthy the guy who created lisp
okay and john mccarthy is also a pioneer
of artificial intelligence that the
technology you guys are dribbling about
every day machine learning artificial
intelligence
john mccarthy who created at least he's
a guy he's a pioneer of artificial
intelligence okay at
you know this relates to lots of things
uh lots of my topics about keyboard
about the origin of the old key
okay let's let's digress okay
and about emac this
and about which installment they all
related okay
so let's go to uh ergo history let's go
to history okay so you you see this
keyboard
so cell keyboard sales key cell
keyboard this is the first
this machine keyboard i mean this is the
father of this machine keyboard okay so
you know so let me show
show a few photos of it and this is
these photos are taken by the
keyboard history expert martin
wyckery okay he used to work at google i
don't know about now but he he's the one
who created google pacman you know
google doodle google pacman
yeah
i'm tying chinese
pac-man
yeah so so there okay so
what
so anyway
so these photos are created by this guy
martin
wyckery he's a keyboard history expert
and he's also a javascript expert among
other things okay so he
and he published i don't know if it's
out yet he is writing a book on keyboard
history maybe it's out already so let's
search for um
keyboard history
so maybe he has a book
okay why is it archive
so i haven't been in contact with him
for a couple of years
so he's writing a book on keyboard
history
uh
but now apparently his website is now
archived so i don't know what's going on
about he about his um
anyway so
so he wrote that and and all these
photos are by him okay so
this is the granddaddy of this keyboard
okay but let me show you so all these
are these keyboards so the mo the one
you are familiar with the most is
probably this one space cadet keyboard
space cadet
because it's the most dramatic okay so
let's go back
so i want to say so the old key
came from this keyboard the idea of the
window key or the mac command key
and you know those keys
originated basically those extra
modifiers originated with these so in
the beginning you have the shift key
then
basically in this order okay in the
beginning you have the shift key first
which is all important because you need
capital letters shift key then you have
the control key control key is all
important because
you need to send control characters you
know
you know it's it's not just about typing
because this transmission communication
you need you know you you are a
programmer you you need you need to send
those
um
control characters so let me copy the
link
uh not here okay so
keyboard blog close
cell keyboard okay
then cadet keyboard
then i want to go to this machine
keyboard okay so
go all the way down
so i also talked about this
in a full video like for an hour
so let me show you so
yeah i'm not going to talk about this
okay so but let me just copy uh paste
some of the links
so here's a list of order this machine
keyboard and their ear
and is it done
stupid
vavaldi browser still have the url not
update problem
so let's here's a summary of what we
talked about so let me clean up this
page okay so let me get back to so any
comment questions posted okay
uh post it and tag my name to it and pay
me okay pay me uh you know pay me that's
what i'm doing videos for
you see the vavaldi
url
not update problem so now i got two of
these
[ __ ] audi
pro book review or camo sucks
camera okay so like lots of other things
exposed so did we
did we paste expose okay expose keyboard
on to do keyboard mechanical switches
we're gonna talk about that we haven't
finished yet
so design of computer keyboard copy it
put it here
close that keyboard switch mechanisms
yeah
then
uh apple the apple idiocy in design okay
so we haven't finished this keyboard and
this video is funny this apparently this
is a uh what a filmmaker okay i don't
know who he is but he's a oscar what
oscar award winner so he
talked about apple keyboard he's dissing
apple keyboard so funny
so you would you know you should go
watch check out this one so apple had
these idiotic designs without steve jobs
you know this touch bar
but but finally and they also created
this butterfly keyboard key switch okay
but finally
from
last year 2020 or 2021
they
they realized their mistake so you no
longer have these butterfly
key switches and you no longer have this
apple touch bar that's a edc supreme
so let's paste that so apple so without
steve jobs they become
pretty bad okay so richard stoneman and
steve jobs
okay so we had dad
uh the day steve jobs died okay
then what's this then the apple ufo
building
that's the last
the last public video of steve jobs just
a few months before he died oh then this
this
you know when i saw when i see this
i'm angry
this is a unix this is the unix linux
propaganda very popular you know among
you linux people are very popular when
you see this you your your reaction is
like oh this is so true this is so true
i need to spread it
this idiot spreading force information
you know the linux unix people
propaganda
and also also you know mixed among them
is the open source phoneticism
why because they don't have to pay they
you know free is free
by day they say oh it's it's about
freedom it's about no it's not about
money it's about morality and ethics we
must be good people we must you know
share
by night they steal movies you know
hollywood movies so i think i'm gonna
steal it i'm gonna steal microsoft font
because on unix you don't have good
fonts i'm gonna steal
then they chant by oh information
good things are free good things are
free no it's actually it's about money
all good things in war in the world is
free
water and air those are free
this unix linux
open source [ __ ] it liars and scums
that's that's
many of you guys
okay then here is a few videos
photos i have um
about steve jobs okay
so this is 2001
when apple store you know when apple
made the news again that they are going
to actually opening a store you know
brick and mortar
motor brick
brick and motor
store multi or however you pronounce it
store
you know 2001 that's a year when all the
brick and mortar stores are closing down
because of the internet but
steve jobs went the other way he says oh
we are going to start to open in stores
so this is
the so 20
2001 is a year apple begin the apple
store throughout usa then throughout the
world so i went there with my friends
uh brian nakomoto
you know 2000
this is around year 2000 so i was
working you know in a dot-com days so i
went there you know so
and so steve jobs you know this is the
apple store in palo alto okay just
nearby
so we uh
we took a few photos of steve jobs okay
so that's steve jobs 2001.
then you have this imac the first
product that again kind of
revolutionized the computing world
colored you know computer with color
okay so
imac
okay lots of digressions then we were
talking about sales keep cell keyboard
okay so this this keyboard is origin oh
yeah we were talking about
uh john mccarthy okay so what's uh
what's john mccarthy's
role here
so this keyboard
is a grand daddy it's a daddy of this
keyboard before this keyboard were bone
okay so first of all you have the sales
keyboard then you have the knight
keyboard which is not even it's not yet
official
so this is the granddaddy of this
keyboard so
the knight keyboard borrowed
a lot from the sales keyboard the say
sail is stand for
sal stands for stanford ai lab stanford
is right here 10 minutes drive okay so
stanford ai lab
and that lab is created by
john mccarthy
that lab is created by john mccarthy the
creator of lisp who died in the same
year or about the same year as steve
jobs and dennis suici okay but nobody
mentioned it this unix
linux [ __ ] okay nobody know nobody
know but then they they they need to say
this because they they feel injustice
okay so
so
john mccarthy the pioneer of ai and lisp
you know in in early days in the 1970s
1980s 1980 1980s okay it when you say ai
is all about this this and ai are
intertwined okay this is the language
so john mccarthy
created the stanford ai lab and this is
the keyboard from there s-a-i-l
okay dated in 1970 about or maybe a few
years earlier
so and this is also the keyboard that is
the father of the
mac command key
or the windows windows key so the order
is shift key first then ctrl key shift
then control
then
let's see
shift
then control then then meta okay
meta
meta eventually became
the max command key
you know it borrow you know
you know by by inspiration you know so
shift
first then ctrl then meta
then
then you have alt
okay
you see on this keyboard you don't have
do you have a hold
you don't have an old yet so you have to
wait until
the night keyboard let's see
wait uh
so let me go to so i'm kind of jumping
over so let's go to the knight keyboard
do you have a old key here so let's
magnify
you know you don't have the old key so
you have meta control shift then you
have top which is kind of another shift
uh
but you don't have alt okay
oh you have old here okay
so back then that old is as far as i
know that old the functionality is
actually that old is actually just
escape
kind of like today's escape but it also
has escape you know i don't know exactly
how it works some people you know some
some of the
you know i know some people lost this
guy okay this guy who dug into the
history of you know he's fascinated with
this keyboard especially this machines
so he dug into lots of the history so if
you want to learn about
these these machines you go to his web
back website he has lots of info and he
also has a github okay just follow the
links and you'll see so he he told me
several you know some answers about
keyboard i have he had he answered them
so then you have old then you have
essentially then you have the mac
command key then on windows you have the
windows key then and windows also
invented the menu key okay so i have
article on all those but i'm not gonna
show it
so we were talking about some of the
keyboard history and john mccarthy so
so okay so what else so
knight keyboard okay
let's copy that
so any comments
okay no comments okay i don't know
i'm doing good
is this a good talk show or not because
i've been just being rambling
and
i in fact talked about this before
so there's google doodle so let's copy
it let's google doodle
the proper order is here
okay close google doodle
okay so i want to mention this guy
who created he is writing a book about
keyboard history
expert of keyboard
then okay close that close that
knight keyboard okay so what is this
yeah space cadet the most famous
okay so
so what is uh so let's finish the topic
we began we haven't finished yet so
just know that this design
the apple touch bar
sucks is very bad and also the
the butterfly key mechanism
also very bad
they are no longer there so the new
macbooks they don't have that anymore
okay and the m1 chip i talked about
the m1 chip apple's m1 chip that's a
revolution that's a i would say
apple's m1 chip
is one of the significant revolution in
computing
cpu industry history
and also as a in cpu history okay
significant
it's just fantastic it's like a few
times better than intel so amd because
they are part of the you know also
they are significant
from a the industry cpu industry point
of view
because
it changes the market you know it
changes you know there's a significant
impact so i think you know
it's significant in in historical
historically significant even
so that's one thing
it
it's significant in the cpu industry
point of view however it is also in my
opinion it's also significant
from
the
cpu design point of view
i mean m1 is not like completely new but
however apple because it's a commercial
it's a one of the big commercial entity
in the cpu
i mean related to the cpu business and
now apple became a you know part of the
c one of the cpu maker
so and this chip
is
why is it significant in the cpu design
because it revolutionized
it it it
i believe it's a milestone
that drives
the beginning downfall of the intel's
x86 architecture okay so
this is a technical point of view so
it's it
it relates to cpu design and lots of
computer science okay hardware computer
science like how computer works cpu how
do you design them what is the
you know architecture and so on so
i think the m1 chip is just fantastic
okay so maybe that's it for today okay
so i wanted to do some coding but um
so
okay so yeah let me finish this part
about the keyboard mechanical switch
so you have the rubber dome you have the
scissor switch no good scissor switch
for laptop no good then the most popular
popular mechanical switch are the cherry
mx okay so there's various
there are
there are different types
one category of types is linear meaning
that when you press the key down there's
no
resistance like smooth linear okay then
another type is tactile or clicky like
when you press down this click or you
can feel a bump
so
cherry mx cherry
is a
company's name in germany and they make
these keyboard switches and they
these these
switch
their model is mx okay cherry mx and
they are color coded according to their
type whether they are linear or they are
tactile or clicky and they have a you
know they have a
force you know specification for the
force required to activate the key
that's the simplified version okay so
you have this is the most common most
popular
so cherry switches has been around uh
they began in 1983
okay
so it looks like that if you
take them out and pull them up apart
okay and here's the diagrams of their
mechanism this is cherry red okay so
so which one do you like
um there's no
universal answer okay which one is the
best because some people like linear
some people like tactile and some people
prefer strong resistance some people
prefer light keys
uh you know depends on your muscle you
know depends on your each person's
physique um
biology
okay no comments today
so how many people are watching 12
actually more more than
what i usually have so comment questions
we ask me questions i'm gonna shut down
okay
i didn't get to do code actually i
wanted to code
i want to code my website because you
know
so um
so then you have optical switch you know
when okay so since we are okay wait this
is this this is not optical this is the
okay so
so in this picture
you are seeing the mechanism
of the cherry mx
red okay
so
the mechanic the word mechanism here
refers to the tactile mechanism not the
elect electronic on off mechanism okay
so usually when you say mechanical key
switch the mechanical part it refers to
the mechanism of the tactile key
aspect of it okay the key
sensation you know how it feels when you
press it down that's what the mechanic
mechanical
means mechanical switch usually okay
so you here the picture shows the
mechanics the mechanism of the
how the linear switch works so you can
see it's different from the
brown the brown switch cherry mx brown
is a tactile so you have this bump you
can see
right there
that's how
it creates this tactile sensation then
blue is also tactile but it makes the
audible click very sharp like
ticket ticket
so the word mechanical
usually refers to the tactile sensation
part okay that's important
but however this picture
this diagram shows you the
actual electrical
mechanism of the switch so it's
based on contact so when you press it
down press it down the string closes it
touch each other so that's the
electrical
aspect so this is uh
this is important to know you know don't
you know this is analysis of the
language of the jargon mechanical switch
you know what so mechanism this is
so there's some
electronic mechanism switch mechanism
there's a tactile sensation mechanism
which is that which
you know you shouldn't call it a switch
but it's because it's actually not a
switch you know the electronic that's a
switch so so this is this is the kind of
misnomer kind of like
when you say
cherry mx switch
the mechanical switch the mechanical
doesn't is actually not the switch
that's just the
mechanism for the tactile sensation okay
then then in the past 10 years you know
it's beginning 2010 also
actually beginning in 2015
you started to have lots of other
key switches from china okay
because apparently the cherry mx
switch
patent or patent they expired so you
started you started to see lots of
uh clones from china and in fact they
are actually better they are better and
cheaper
the china cheaper is
overtaking the world they are actually
better and cheaper
that's what i claim as
you know when it first came out people
don't know like we don't know like
oh china they made it you know they are
cheaper
you know maybe because they are bad
quality it turns out not not really you
know now after 10 years we know you know
not not a lot of people you know
they don't doesn't mean it's it's uh bad
quality you know these these are good
okay
so
but in the keyboard market sometimes you
here you know we use the genuine cherry
mx
you know some like when you look at into
the keyboard you know many of these um
for example
the normal keyboard
you know so all these you know this
commercial keyboard you know some
sometimes they'll say we use the genuine
cherry mx switches then other times
you'll see they say we use the
improved you know the the
the better even better than the the
modern you know the the newer version
of of
of mechanical key switch that's even
better than cherry mx
you know they all say that which is
actually true in my opinion it's
actually true
uh so but they are pretty much the same
okay but then so in the past five years
you see lots of then you started to see
box switch they are all from china
almost china taking taking over so you
started to see new lots of new switches
sparks switch
chalk switch chocolate switch thing
profile then roman g switch from
logitech
then you have then you have optical
switch okay let me talk about this a lot
you know when i see
when i talk to the you know keyboard
community
the optical switch they don't get any
press okay like nobody is talking about
them to me this is significant to me
this is fantastic okay optical switch
but apparently you don't hear them much
you know they are not excited rather
these idiots they they they are excited
about the toppa switch
you know where is it
they are excited about the topper switch
this is the one they eat the keyboard
idiots talks all the time non-stop the
top happy hacking happy hacking keyboard
tofa switch i tried it it's garbage it's
[ __ ] i don't like it you know i i even
prefer turbo switch is very expensive
you know you buy topper keyboard
they cost
david thank you for uh five dollars
pound euro fantastic thank you that gets
me a burrito
so any other questions david so any
questions okay thank you david
so
so i want to say so you see this
keyboard
for example high p happy hacking 300
[ __ ] sucking blood sucker this blood
sucker crap
but
this one is actually 350 something let's
see
356 dollars from japan
happy hacking
switch
crap
if this is 100 i don't want it
don't throw it enough garbage [ __ ] [ __ ]
idiot
happy hacking but lots of the keyboard
nuts love it you know they
well in part because the topper switch
they you know it became a meme you know
topper switch among the keyboard command
community topo switch is kind of the
meme okay so all these keyboards very
expensive and the the au pad you know
the deo pad from korea this one also
using topper switch
i don't like it okay
i don't like like it at all i don't want
it
so we were talking about so yeah so let
me talk about the optical switch so then
you started to have opposite optical
switch
okay so actually
let me copy my pages
so happy hacking
and topper switch
uh keyboard switch mechanism toolbar
switch open it okay so
you see the [ __ ] vavadi open source
[ __ ]
the url is wrong of this page the url is
not that because it failed to update but
now if i refresh you can see the url
change right now it says keyboard switch
mechanism now if i
just refresh now it's keyboard with
turbo switch you see [ __ ] the open
source maybe i should start you know
maybe i should stop using the rd now
yeah maybe
i you know
i keep switching you know the browsers
this this
this url field not updating it happened
it's been around since like three or
four months now by now it's four
four months old still bug
uh so topa switch happy hacking keyboard
so we were talking about okay so let's
yeah so i want to talk about optical
switch
so let me show you optical switch so
today oh okay we already have it so i
think optical switch is great
technological advance in my opinion you
know from because usually i focus on
design i want the design elegance i want
the proper design i don't want hack you
know the unix linux [ __ ] c [ __ ] hack the
hack is what they do oh we have you know
hack i don't like i want proper design
so in my opinion i find i think the
optical switch is great it's fantastic
however i never have have a chance to
use it
so there are a few options and turns out
they are pretty cheap they are actually
not more expensive than cherry mx
switches so there's a video from
from the commercial video
[Music]
okay anyway so optical switch and you
can buy these cheap 50 or something
there are different optical switches
okay
so
um
so speaking of optical switch let me
also mention
uh let's go to my blog so this
switch keyboard switch expert
now there's a keyboard switch expert
this guy
let me show you where okay
and where is it
ah here so this
quail
quite a strong
thomas yeah thomas you know
thomas uh
stupid youtube name but thomas something
okay this guy is a keyboard key switch
expert
you know at least as far as popularity
goes on youtube he's probably the number
one
expert on keyboard key switches not
anything else remember this is important
when we are in the keyboard community do
it itself you know ergonomic and and
then key switch keycaps technology
key labeling
technology and so on he is the expert
focusing on the keyboard switch
mechanism there that he's expert you
know he's probably the top five top one
even
okay i respect his opinions
so he recently did a review
like just this week
of the truly ergonomic cleave keyboard
this this
you know i'm not i'm not going to
comment much about this keyboard okay
um but anyway so
this
this keyboard uses optical switch okay
that's a good part but i believe it's a
this keyboard got other issues one of
the issues is that you cannot program
the key
you can only program
this about you know these keys in the
middle and you cannot
program other keys
now that sucks and this this keyboard is
okay
so i don't think it's a good you know
it's i think it's a great design it's a
great design but it's got major problems
350.
for 350 dollars
you can buy kinesis you can buy any of
these okay you can buy kinesis you can
buy ergo docks you can buy expose you
can buy two of them you can buy a digma
okay though these are all these are
better
you can buy
you cannot buy this one this one is 550
dollars this
israel israel from japan this is this
great anyway so the trudiago
cleave it's great keyboard but 350 50
too much
and also
major flaw is that you can only program
these about these six keys in the middle
you cannot program other key it sucks
cannot possibly you know you cannot
possibly do this
when you have a new design like that
anyway so i'm not gonna talk too much
about this keyboard
uh but this but the guy who sent me the
previous one
that's a revolution in keyboard industry
okay that is true okay the previous
model this one this one came out in 2011
2013 this one
it was announced in 2010 also and came
out in 2013 this
is the first keyboard that began the
kind of the popular
popularization
of mechanical ergonomic keyboard in the
past decade this one this keyboard
essentially beginning
okay
and this is great okay but now
this is even better this design design
wise it's even better and key switch is
also better much better optical but
however
you can only program the middle six keys
that's that's sucks donkey ass and also
they
uh what what's the other issue yeah 350
that's that's not worth it okay
so
so anyway
so the the guy he
you know it's you know a figure
he did a video on this okay
fantastic
okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching bye guys
yeah i'm gonna shut down in five minutes
random so we talked about lots of random
things today um so let's clean up
i wasn't prepared so when i'm not
prepared don't have a topic i end up
just
renting random
i don't know if it
you know in one hour rent uh and i don't
know if you find it great
relative to my other talk shows
or you find it
not as good i don't know
so you have to tell me
so let's see what what are the other
comments okay
so we should shut down in a minute in a
few minutes
track
vegeta
track vegeta says
i have three expos fantastic
um
are you on discord
are you on some discord
yes
so yusuf yes
so all traveller
says do you like zeke language what do
you think about rosenko i don't know
what is the zig language
so
noise says why don't you like topo
switches
from what i hear it's a combination of
rubber dome and mechanical switch that's
correct so topa switch
top switch is actually just a um
just a rubber dome okay so actually so
we close that
let's open
so topper switch
uh
turbo switch is just rubber don't okay
the the mechanism
the key feel mechanism is a rubber dome
and you can see it here
so i have a video here
it doesn't play
okay sucks so you have to
um
it doesn't play
you have to what
okay
opening chrome
so now it plays in google chrome not in
the body okay let me show you some of
the other things sucks so you can open
it
in firefox
okay the video you cannot play this in
firefox the
the video is this one mp4 you cannot
play in firefox but let's show so it
plays in google chrome okay
so you can see that is the topper switch
that's a rubber dome
that is that's that is where the
key feel came from
so
you know if you ask these people the
topper switch fans they'll say
it's a better
robot dome you know unlike the typical
rubber dome this is just better
and feels better than mechanical other
mechanical switches i disagree
and you know you it's to me it's
hard then you have the hit but hit hit
button problem
i don't like it okay that's it so patent
expired you know they are
topper switch apparently their patent
also expired so now you have clones
you have china cheaper clone so this one
so from what i
read this one is also fantastic nice
plume okay
it's using it's using the
you know the top the topper switch the
topper is actually a
trademarked name i believe is a
trademarked name
for
this switch is technique technically
called
capacitance
switch okay
so it's because it's the elect
electronic aspect of the switch is not
based on contact
but rather on capacitance capacitance so
do i have a
so there's no contact between electronic
uh
ports
so anyway so
so technically it's called capacitance
switch okay
electro capacitive so
anyway this chinese cheaper make makes
it but but however it doesn't feels like
topper it uh it it's much
feels like linear that's what i hear
so anyway
bye
you