good morning guys
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 august
20th thursday and
8 o'clock in the morning san francisco
time
and today we are going to talk about
emacs
and e-max leads coding so
let me show you what is the background
image today
so the background image today is this vi
versus vim
so apparently someone at facebook uh
fields but restart you know uh facebook
there's a coffee shop
fields coffee uh you know they
the waitress or whatever they put up the
cups
for tips vi versus vim
and this is back in 2014
so that's a background image and let's
shall we begin
emacs list coding am i alive and uh
yes i'm alive good
okay so we're gonna we're gonna uh hey
green deck haven't seen you for
a while yes i haven't started morning
morning
show for a while uh yes it's been
recorded it's a live
it's a live recording so it's gonna be
on youtube
after a while so today's talk show so
let's start emacs coding so what what we
are going to do
is so we i'm going to code emac this
live and explain it and uh
then yeah so that's what we are going to
do
and maybe after that we talk random
possibly so what we're going to do is
uh i want so i write blogs right so for
example i write blogs so i go to my
emacs blog
i want to sometimes i watch some videos
i want to include the video
so for example let me show you this
interesting video
so we go to youtube open a new window
paste it so this youtube
video
so this guy is actually he's going to
build a chinese typewriter
uh you can see uh he is a professor
at stanford i think and he also speaks
chinese
and he is a expert of chinese typewriter
history
tom mulaney
and he's on twitter so you know i find
this video interesting
i'm a blogger i want to blog it so what
i do i copy the url
i go to my emacs blog showing browser
so i can paste the url here
hold on a second let me magnify excuse
me
i'm gonna find the window and on the
pink window on the right you can see all
my keystrokes and command names
so i create a new section paste it here
so you can see
the youtube url is pasted here now i
want to
press a key to linkify it i we went
through
that code yesterday a few days ago
in previous two or three episodes so
anyway you
you can see now i have a youtube
so you can see get your hands dirty
hands-on history or chinese typewriter
so so now but there's no description in
my blog
i want some description so people can
see so i go to youtube
so i can copy the text here uh let's
copy the text here i
wait not that selected
yeah uh anyway so i copy the text here i
want to
copy the the title
the date and who uploaded it
so i copied it i go back to emacs
go back to emacs go in between the
figure caption
paste it so now you can see it also
included
several of these garbages you know 192
views
and and share and save we don't want
that
but anyway let's show in browser first
show in browser
so we can see here is the
what we pasted so i want to delete
i want to remove part of it for example
i want to remove that
i want to remove subscribers i want to
remove all these
irrelevant info so so this is
this is tedious every time i uh put a
video in my blog i have to do the copy
and paste let me do
let me make a copy of these okay so let
me show you okay
so let's make two copies it so for
example what i need to do is normally i
would have to
delete delete shrink
then i want the date delete hands-on
history that's right
and i want to put a break line break
line break
line break line break subscribers i
don't care dvd
and i don't care about that so that is
what i want okay
so show in browser and scroll down
so you can see now that is what i want
so we are going to write the command to
kind of automatic or kind of
automatically
delete the things we don't want okay so
we are just going to write the command
here
starting now okay what we do is we just
open a new buffer uh wait
open a new file magnify
save the file as wait let's name our
function let's defund
okay uh go to xr emacsd smart
magnify defend that's right
let's see what's our function name
html remove youtube
youtube chunk okay let's just
say that remove youtube chunk
delete miss
miss uh lanier's info
of youtube
uh youtube info okay delete
miscellaneous youtube info
type the version name and today's state
version number okay
then we are going to save this file save
it
right to file dot el
okay now copy the file path
close it paste it here linkify
make a paragraph showing browser
so there it is link to our code
so back to emacs so we are going to
start to write
it so what we gonna do so first of all
before we do anything
let's copy this thing
so we have a reference now we open
magnify now the thing we want
to delete so we have a reference here so
we we can kind of know what we want to
delete
uh so we want to delete the parts we
want to delete our
okay basically things like that uh
we want to delete share save okay so
let's begin
so
so first of all we want to let me show
you okay so we want to
okay let's say a region first of all
let's assume user selected the region so
let's go back to our
let's assume the user selected this part
then we call our command then all these
uh
all these will be deleted okay let's
assume that for now
so p1 p2 is position 1 position 2 that's
the beginning position of the
region okay so set
p1 equals to region beginning okay
that's what we want set
p2 equals to region end okay
then save restriction
okay then narrow to region we
now narrow to region position one
position two why would
we do that so that emacs will ignore
the regions we are not interested when
we do
uh find and replace so it won't screw up
elsewhere
then we say um then we say save
restriction
the reason for that is once the command
is done
emacs will return the user's region
so that's what save restriction is for
so okay so so now we got a region we
narrowed
region then we go to uh go to char
move the cursor to a position to the
point minimum okay point mean okay
point minimum
point mean is a function that returns
the minimum position
in a cursor which is usually always i
think it's always one okay
so go to the beginning of the region
then uh
what we have to do okay so so we got
text
like that we got text like that we want
to
um
so first of all we need to delete the
share and save capital letters
okay so we're gonna go to the beginning
of region
then search forward
okay search forward for the word share
then then
optional bound neil no error true
and count we don't care okay search for
it
then replace match uh
replace match this is how you do find
and replace
okay replace match new text which
gonna going to be an empty string then
fixed case we don't care okay so this is
how you do find and replace
now we need to do it again for the
save for the word save okay now prettify
the code
okay now that so far the code will
remove
this and this okay then
we will also want to remove these views
by the way
youtube you know youtube changes the
description
often well i'm not sure often but but
i've noticed
for different videos you'll have
different kind of things there
so anyway so delete save and
we also want to delete the views here
okay so
in this case we go to um
we go to uh beginning of region again
then we search reach rejects
search for word okay now this time we're
gonna use a regular expression and
search for that
now this 192 is a sequence of digits
so in that case what we need to do is we
need to
use the square brackets and say
0 to nine okay another second zero
tonight that means
any digit plus sign means one one or
more
okay so that's one or more digits
followed by space then views then
bully sign how do i know it's bullied
because you call describe
char and
then e-max will tell you what character
it is so you can see
in this window you can see the code
point
and you can see the name of the
character bullet that's a that's from
unicode
that's one of my favorite uh character
and the command is described char okay
so
so now you search forward uh sequence of
a
sequence of digits and view then
optional
bound uh we don't care for bound
no error we don't care for no error okay
so
remove all the options so once we found
it
then replace match just like before
empty string okay
prettify the code now let's go to the
top of the code
let's move this down okay let's move
these
to the bottom and comment them out
okay so so far this is how our code
looks like let's speedify a little bit
okay and
actually we could um
then what you're gonna do let's try it
okay let's just
run a code eval region back to the
browser
back to the html
file show in browser let's have a look
what we got here
so you see you see this
part shows up like that because in html
that you
when you don't have markup everything
becomes uh
collapsed together so let's select the
region
and let's call the command let's see
what happens okay let's
wait uh what's our command name beside
remove
html remove youtube chunk okay
call the command meta x hold on a second
let's show the pink
pink window call the command meta x
cuz remove youtube junk okay
enter great so it actually did work
um some of them okay so let's undo
you can see redo it removes the share
and remove the save
and also remove the views
okay so once you remove that
then we think about what what should our
code do next
um number so
this number how do we you know we need
to because
essentially we you know there's no
i mean we are just given a bunch of text
we have to figure out
what what is it that we need to do so
this number nine and zero
where does they come from okay so those
are the thumb
up and down signs
am i doing good good morning a lot
people i need one of those bloody
command log
things yeah so that's easy just uh a
male part command lock mod
i talked about that for a few times
uh every time i watch this i must mind
blown
um so okay okay so let's back to the
code
so we're gonna do this how we gonna do
this that's the question
of course we're gonna do it but how so
you got a number you got number
then you got space so maybe let's let's
try to use the regular expression
new line empty line number
empty line number empty line okay let's
try that
okay so let's go back to the emacs list
code
so back here so we're gonna need to do
uh another one here go to
char wait
so we start again let's go to the
beginning
go to cha point minimum
okay by the way you might think there
are
a lot of repetitions it's kind of
necessary uh
you know there's no way around it so go
to the point minimum
uh i'm pretty sure some smart guy will
say actually actually there is a shorter
way
anyway but anyway so let's go to the
beginning of the region
then let's uh
reject search forward and this time
we're gonna need a space
like we said before a space wait
um a space then a sequence of numbers
plus sign
a space a sequence of numbers then
a space again then i mean not space new
line
a sequence of numbers then a new line
let's try this pattern
again i'm not sure it's going to work
always because i've noticed
for different videos when you copy you
know they have
a different a few variations i think
so you know this is one of the thing you
know this is great thing about emacs and
emac this
you do as you go you know you you can
quickly
you know i can quickly write this
command once you know a little
a little emac this you know i so i
quickly have this command
then if tomorrow i find that command
doesn't work or miss
something i can edit it and you know
improve it
uh on a you know on a need basis as we
go
so okay so let's try this regular
expression pattern then
um bound no arrow um
bound neil no arrow true
we want to say no error true because if
you
don't say true that means when it cannot
find this pattern you'll actually stop
the program emacs will say
error okay you know no such stream found
you know
so usually you want to say no error true
in imax
true is
in e-max the only thing that's
false is neil the value neil
that's the only thing that is false
but also empty list is also neo
they are equivalent so you could say the
only thing
that's false is neil and uh
empty list everything else is considered
true
including a string so for example we are
using a string here you could use
anything like typically you say
you can say t or anything
so anyway so let's go on so reject
search
uh you found then replace match
okay oh actually we need to
um
actually we need it's better to put a if
statement but anyway we
replace match okay so let's put some uh
if statement
when we don't need so when
when search okay so it's like that when
if this search is found then replace
match okay so
we are going to put some win uh
when
okay and here
then here too
pretty fine okay so
i need to improve my emacs list
code so it automatically auto
automatically predicts so anyway so
so here is our code okay when
yeah so looks like that's it let's
shrink it a little bit
okay let's try it evaluate the buffer
go back to html code undo
undo so we got the share and save back
there so select the whole region
then call the command size html remove
youtube link
do it oops something went wrong
something went wrong you know you want
to be careful because
because it deletes your whole thing so
what's going on so anyway something is
wrong because the cruiser went out of
uh went kind of far away so what
what's our problem
wait the save restriction okay there it
is
there is our problem you see uh
you see the rest of the code should be
under the save restriction
you know remember that we are narrowing
to region
so this part should be inside the parent
the code now you can see the save
restriction
you see it's inside so evolve the buffer
back to the html code let's try it again
select the section meta exciting
youtube link if i okay
so wait it's
the knight and zero is not removed why
is that let's
check the let's turn on white space
okay wait turn on white space
so so you have a new line
then number new line new line oh
that's right two new lines you see
there's two
uh there's two new lines so back to the
code
there is should be one more new line
okay
eva buffer back to the code
select it call it do it yay
now a little improvement we got rid of
those numbers
um but actually this okay so so so far
so good
now about the things at the bottom
let's also remove that okay the number
of subscribers so back to the code
and we want to go to char
point mean okay
we go to the beginning of the region and
to do this again so
number of subscribers so let's it should
be somewhere here
3d5 eval buffer back to html
undo try it again call the command
do it okay the number of subscribers is
gone
you see before it was here it was here
select that code now it's good that's
good
now no more so this line we don't care
because normally
normally when i copy it
you don't you know you try not to copy
you know the the actual description part
you know it would be nice if we use some
kind of youtube
api uh i don't know i i guess you can do
that
i mean but but that would be much more
involved
i mean if that's the case if we use
youtube
api then emacs can call some kind of
python or program
to fetch it um
yeah and return the data and you know so
it
it returns exactly what we want you know
like the date
this video is uploaded who uploaded
and title of the youtube video
but it would be much more involved
because then you have to learn the
youtube api
and then you have to write another
probably a
program in python or some other language
then
emax has to call that command and get
info back and
it's a bit more involved
but anyways yeah so let's let's try to
keep going with this
okay so once we do that you see
you see these empty lines now we want to
remove these empty lines okay let's go
back to the code
let's continue to push on we want to not
we want to remove empty lines
okay now
reject search forward
new line
uh wait new line
basically a sequence of new lines at
least two of them
so we go to the beginning of the region
then we
find our sequence of new lines
uh at least two of them then we remove
it
yep i think that's it eva buffer
go back to html let's return to the
original yeah so original
select it call it do it
no much better okay now now there now
you see there is a problem here
they
okay so let's see what's the problem so
once you removed it
wait hold on a second before we do
anything let's
let's make a copy of these so that we
have something to work on again copy
copy okay
okay so we have we removed it
and now we have a bunch of
new line and our code will basically
okay a sequence okay so i know what to
do we want
we don't want to re we do not want to
remove all the m all the new lines
we don't want to do that we want to have
at least one
okay so that's what we're gonna do so
back to the code
so replace match replaced by one
empty line okay eva buffer
back to html
and we try it again wait uh
wait yeah so here is our code so you see
we try it again call the command do it
fantastic
[Laughter]
now we are getting closer there's one
more step we need
to add the break sign
uh why no arrow is a string is it not
a boolean yeah it's it's it should be a
boolean but
like i said before in emacs there is
actually no boolean type
uh so in if context
when emax needs to find something if
it's true or
false it basically neo is the only thing
that's false
neo and empty string i mean near
or empty least because these two are
equivalent
so when you have a string that says no
arrow that is true
that's considered true i don't have to
use no error the reason
i use no arrow you know like a string is
because it's
it's more obvious to the programmer
typically
most what people mostly do is they just
say
they just give a symbol t for true
that's a convention
okay so that's one thing by the way
there's a bit more complexity because
when you act when you do a search
forward
command it this
this particular command actually
distinguishes
whether it's a symbol t or something
else
because if it's if something
true but not the symbol t it will
actually move the
cursor uh you can see that by
called describe function okay describe
function
for example here we have the
documentation for the search forward
so you can see there's the option no
error now if you search that
so here is the documentation for no
error
so it says the option the optional third
argument no error indicates
how errors are handled when the search
fails okay if it is new
or omitted then or me
then emit an error okay but
if it's t then simply return neo
and do nothing okay but if it is
neither neil nor t then
we'll move to the limit of search and
return neo so that
so there's a little bit difference
but but that applies just to this
command the search command
because of this particular command is
done that way
so anyway so so far so what we doing so
uh so let's run again so
if our buffer go back to html
undo selected call it yeah so there's
okay so so so far our program is
successful there's one more thing we
want to do
we want to add this br we want to add
this br at the end of each line
you know just like uh the example i mean
the we have a good example here
that's manually done so let's do it so
and do undo undo
and do so we return to the condition
and back to the code so now we want to
add a br
so that's easy so you again go to
char point mean
point mean then again
um when
search forward and when you find
a new line
bound near no error true
okay when you when you find a new line
then
you replace match
you replace match by
a new line plus a br
i believe it's slash or backslash i
think it's
um br slash okay
yeah so you replace an empty line a new
line character by a new line plus the
um wait it should be
br plus plus a new line okay
optional we don't care optional okay
but however there's more than that
actually hold on a second
we need to you know this this thing i
don't like about this
this needs to be inside okay
so here is our uh here's the our code
but now there's one more thing one more
left one more thing okay
so this so we go to the beginning of the
region then we search for the empty line
then we if we found it we do a replace
okay but that only does
one line you need to do all for all
lines
so what we do is we need we we are going
to
add a while statement okay while
while loop so while
this is how we do it so while that
then that
okay so we don't need the
queen anymore pretty fine so this is how
we do it so
this this is uh find replace repeatedly
oh
you know okay prefer the code we
predefine the code um
eval buffer back to html i think that's
it
that should work select all
call the command wait hold on a second
where's my pink window okay
call the command wait magnifying a
little bit
select the region call the command do it
fantastic so you can see
okay there is this we don't want but it
is let's show in browser show in browser
the second one is what we yeah perfect
except the first one the first br is
incorrect
the first br is what we don't want
but we don't have to select it let's
undo let's try it again so
you see we can select it but not include
not include that beginning br
well actually we can fix the code
actually so let's try
to fix the code so
you see here we go to the beginning of
region
then we skip char forward
and we skip n
okay limit let's say 10
there's some garbage truck making uh big
noises outside
very annoying so here is what we do so
that's it that should
work eval the buffer back to our html
select it call it
do it wait there is
there is still um what
yeah the garbage truck okay
i need to close the window
okay how long have we been talking we
are actually we pretty much
done okay uh there's a question
let me answer that we've been talking
for 36 minutes okay not
not too bad can you briefly explain
comments in emac list what's the
difference
okay uh what's the difference between
one semicolon versus two versus three
so let me explain that that's yeah
that's a convention yes
um so in uh let me show you
so you have the comments okay
um okay so so basically
if you have a comment if you want to
stop start a section okay so
if you have a long code you know lots of
code here is another
another um function for example then you
want to
you start a new section then you want to
use three
semicolons okay three semicolons
is the convention for a new section
now two two semicolon is the
is a standard standard comment at the
beginning of a line
okay let me write it
three semicolon begins a section
okay
two two semicolon
is a normal common normal line common
one semicolon is
common at end of line okay that's a
convention for example end of line
let's say we here
go to
beginning of regions for example one
semicolon so that's that's just emacs
convention you can find
the discussion of this in the gnu emacs
list
documentation you just search for new
emacs this
convention you will find it
okay so let's go back to the code so
what what what is it um we are missing
uh we are missing yes skip chart forward
okay
uh
we are missing something
skip chart forward we want to skip it
then
i'm not sure why it's not working but
anyway
but our code is basically done we that's
what we want to do
i mean the bulk of it let's try it again
all right i want my pink window
run it run it
yeah you see this br that's not we
that's
uh i don't i don't want that but why is
it there
uh because i thought this line should
fix
it
skip chart i mean go to the beginning of
buffer
then skip chart forward and
okay anyway let's not worry about that
for now there's one more thing i
more important i want to do for example
in our command we have to uh make it
select the region
user has to select the region first
before you call a command
it would be nice if you don't have to
because
at least for me i mean the youtube will
the the youtube description will always
be between
figure caption uh text
so so the emac list
should automatically figure out where is
the beginning of the
um the region and end of the region so
let's let's call that
let's let's call that okay so let's
so so here we need to modify instead of
region beginning and region end
we just say
we just search for word search backward
search backward
figure caption
then search forward
okay then set point
p1 point
okay then same thing
then same thing uh for
so the p1 is beginning of the position
now p2 is the same p2 is pretty similar
instead of we reverse the search
forward and backward like that and
we do that so we search
forward for the end of the figure
caption
tag then we search backward
so after this search the cruiser will
end up at the end of the tag
then we need to move to the beginning so
we want to
be at the beginning of the end tag
so that's it uh so these two lines
coming up
so so far so good everything is good
what else uh let's try it call it okay
we don't have to no we don't have to
select it let's just call it directly
do it fantastic fantastic
except that we still got a br there uh
we need to we have to fix it i don't
like i don't
you know save you know this saves the
time and trouble
saves so much time and also let's put a
save excursion here
we need a save excursion there because
whenever your command moves the cruiser
you usually want a save excursion
so that you want you want to wrap wrap
it with a save
excursion so that so that
after running your commands emacs
will return the cruiser to wherever it
is
so if you are writing emac this and if
you are moving cursor around for your
own purposes you don't want the user to
you don't need a user to see it you you
want to
add a saved excursion that just returned
the cursor where it was
so that's that's it but we need to fix
that
uh that one more that's um
skip chart forward go to mean skip chart
forward when he said
i don't understand
skip chart forward why is it not
let's let's skip the limit
okay eval buffer let's just try it
okay let's do it call it
it works so somehow when i put the limit
it
it screwed it up it works you see there
is no more br in the beginning of line
now show in browser
fantastic
so that's it for today anything else
comments
and let me know okay comments
concurrent viewers 14 so how long have i
been talking
am i like alive yes i'm alive
so i've been talking for 49 minutes for
45 minutes
uh let's see yeah that's that's about
that's it for today
let me wrap up okay let's so what we did
today is for example we go to this
youtube
for example let's uh let's do them over
again so go to the talk show page
today's talk show page showing browser
so it looks like that
actually let's uh let's add this one
so for example let's see for example you
can see
the code is here that's a youtube but
there is no description
so we're gonna
ah is that stupid actually uh because
that's today's talk show
the description uh let's okay let's
let's try this one okay
so this one that's what we do
did today copy the url back to emacs
and uh and go to the top paste it
okay show the pink window link if i show
in browser
no description so back to the youtube
website
you want to copy the description that's
what i do
usually manually copy it back to the
emacs page
paste it so we got that
and uh type you know just call the
command hold on second let's show that
call the command do it fantastic
showing browser it works
um this minor issue we need still need
to fix we need to
remove the trailing uh
empty line you see that there's there's
trading mp line sometimes when you copy
it
okay let's fix that
okay where is our code uh
our code yeah
so remove the trading empty line um
so when we start a region we
go to the beginning of region before we
go to the beginning of region
we go to
yeah so we go to the beginning of region
wait let's go to the end of region first
okay go to char
point max okay that's goes to the end of
region
then you want then so your point your
cursor is end of the region for example
here
then if the character to the left is a
new line
you want to delete it okay so
skip skip chart
skip chart backward okay
skip chart then that
so you want to skip all the
uh all the new line characters
your your cruiser is at the end of the
region and you want to move backwards
skipping all new lines
basically you want to delete them so
there are so many ways to do it let's
just do it one way okay so skip chart
backward
then let's see let's read the
documentation what did
it return returns the distance traveled
okay
so it returns the distance traveled so
for example it might return three that
means
it moved backwards three times then we
just say dv
char okay delete char
the number of character it uh it moved
so these two lines will trim the
end the new lines at the end
uh lynette i mean if i refer back to the
code let's just try it
okay so let's talk show okay here is our
page again call the command so let's add
more lines for example
well actually i know there's a problem
you see
um you see it works but you see that
so it's not working
let's go to back to the list of code
releases
um
raise our code
yeah okay so what what we gonna do okay
so let's fix this let's get this fixed
so delete char skip chart backwards
let's see very
informative scream watch scream
so george says oh oatmeal truck
delivering raw oatmeal
no it's not oatmeal it's a it's a
garbage truck
a food truck delivering chinese noodle
soups in sauce apartment
no
okay so yeah so let's get this let's fix
this so
we want to trim
so go to the end of the region
then skip chart backward
okay so why is it not working so let's
try it
okay so
it worked okay so it works and uh oh
negative
that's that's right we need you uh
delete char
right this returns a positive number so
when you want to delete backward you
need a negative number
so okay so let's put the negative number
that's how you do negative in e max okay
run the code let's not think too much
let's just
trial an error okay so
[Music]
let's say let's say that much more okay
do it fantastic it worked you see
uh also we can let's
that's it for today let's just wrap up
let's that's it for today let's not
worry too much that
that's it so fantastic we did it
and we did it yeah so so on my emacs
vlog
i don't need this anymore turn off the
uh
white space so show in my emacs blog
html remove youtube junk yeah that's
right that's a code so let's go to the
code grab it
okay grab it delete that or
remove that remove that delete that
close the
emacs blog go back to the talk show blog
and go and and showing browser first
okay then go back to emacs and at the
bottom
here add the emacs list code
paste it and remove these comments
showing browser and go to the bottom
you can see the code there
okay so we press the key to
clarify it back to browser show it now
it's better now that's a code of today
and meanwhile we go to the top we don't
need this
that's it for today guys thank you guys
for watching uh if you like my stuff
go buy my stuff okay e-max tutorial
e-max tutorial and e-max this
tutorial you'll learn e-mac bits from
the ground up
in the most efficient manner possible
thank you bye guys
okay i'm gonna close down in 30 seconds
okay
to allow some kind of 30 seconds
30 seconds okay i'm just going to shut
down
in 30 seconds so we don't need that
showing browser
fantastic and i'm going to put this code
in well nobody is going to use this code
actually
it's just me because oh by the way so
today there's a emacs meetup
guys okay so you go to
today at four o'clock san francisco time
okay emacs san francisco meet
up just search for emacs san francisco
meetup
so there is the link i mean it's a
online meetup online you know since
there's a corvid 19. covid19
so it's today at four o'clock san
francisco time
and i think i'll be there so right now
it's already 20 or 10 days
20 is the maximum
i'm going to get some sleep then wake up
around
you know in the afternoon and i'll be
there
hopefully see you guys bye guys