welcome to another episode of our talk
show so let's see what we're going to
talk about today I'm going to show you
some math books actually I'm going to
show you this math book I'm waiting for
people to come in and meanwhile let me
show you this book this book tidings and
patterns
Turing's and patterns so this is a kind
of thick hardcover heavy ish book
tallien patterns it's it's by Guam bomb
and Shepard
they are mathematicians now this is a
hard core math book actually it's fun to
read
let's see hi guys so that book is fun to
read let me go to my math blog
well actually I need to edit yeah type
of topic type of topic you want to you
want me to cover and we can do that
so today is 22nd it's almost the end of
the month now spring is coming
so our site we we have on my street
apartment straight outside that they
have a plums beautiful plum trees like
Oh in Japan it's everywhere it's you
know pink plum trees I should take a
photo by anyway so this is a book I was
showing you tidings and patterns this is
a math book let's see tidings and and
patterns and it's filled with great
stuff well it's not to show you but hi
there I got one guy watching you say
something so let's go through my math
block I'm gonna show you this I'm going
to talk about this book so go to math
blog and math textbooks for math books
okay yeah I'm gonna show you some math
books actually I talked about this last
time so they are if you are serious
about studying math you want God you
want to go through this page so actually
me to even go to this is the this this
is a programming popularity just updated
javascript is at the top JavaScript Java
C++ PHP Python and Ruby is right there
Objective C so anyway so sorry math
so go to my math blog okay this is my
math page content but let's see if we
can find it
let's say search for tiding okay reading
notes on tithing and patterns that is
one of them and these days I cannot
find my topics hi there say something
so as you show the format is you ask me
questions and I talk about it in real
time actually I mean let me just go to
let me just put in case if you are new
here I'm a programmer for like over 20
years and I'm also into mathematics
I'm amateur mathematician so usually I
just talk about random things that is of
interest to programming nodes or
methimazole you know with math
inclinations so let me find talk yeah so
let's go to the top page and here is a
topic that you can just ask me questions
and any of these or just any question
actually and I'll talk about that so let
me copy that and put it here the info
box hi guys so at the YouTube you should
see it when it updates the information
box this this got wrong
so I'm using Emacs Hopi and joggins yeah
object-oriented programming and joggins
copy that
and put here
so any of these topics you can just type
in the comment box and I'll talk about
that okay so I'm going to show you this
math book but anyway go through okay let
me find it
tiling tiling tidy and patterns book
there it is
so this book this is this is actually my
favorite math book of all math books
I've read this is my favorite now this
book is so what is okay first of all
this book is fun to read I mean even if
you do not have mathematical background
you can you can you can begin to read it
I mean yeah and and but however it's
also a very serious math book meaning
that if you have a math degree this is
still a good book in fact this is this
book is like the Bible of the subject
matter I mean any mathematician doesn't
matter if you are PhD mathematician or
graduate or a professor when you want to
study or research on the subject of
tilings and patterns this is a book you
must have you must read because it is a
comprehensive treat treatment almost a
tiny encyclopedia on the subject matter
so what what does it talk about it's
well the subject is tiny tiny same
patterns like you see all these for
example this is hiding these and these
are kind of like patterns so what what
is there to set to study about I mean I
mean mathematically there's quite a lot
you know in fact it's still a ongoing
research for example
for example let's say if you have a
should I give you example so for example
if you have let's let's just go to
Wikipedia that's easier to talk about
pentagon tiring
okay here is a Pentagon hiding this okay
so the problem the question of this
problem is that is it possible or you
know find is it possible to to tile the
plain tile means you have a tile you
know just like the bathroom tile using
one prototype I mean so you create a
shape okay for example hexagon now
everyone is familiar familiar with
hexagon hexagon Oh tidings so you have a
hexagon regular hexagon and you can tile
it you know in the bathroom you'll see
that often okay but the question here is
is it possible to use a Pentagon you
know not hexagon but Pentagon and you
know find that tile and that that will
tie out the plane now this is a part
this is possible hybrids so the question
is how many are there you know what are
the all possible ones this is one of the
question so he says here in junk
geometry a pentagonal tiling is a tiring
of the plane where each individual
pieces is in the shape of a pentagon
okay that's a general problem now they
are there are other issues let's let's
read it let's read on a regular pentagon
tiling are you cried I am praying is
impossible okay so first of all it talks
about regular pentagon regular pentagon
is you know like the like the US
government building pentagon you know
regular pentagon
so it is impact impossible to use that
shape to tire the pain now okay it says
it's impossible because the internal
angle of a regular pentagon is 1 0 8
degrees not divisible by blah blah blah
then however regular Pentagon's can tell
the hyper bar okay so anyway so so
that's a flavor of the problem about
hiding the plane so you know you see you
see one example of a problem a
mathematical problem about this tied in
subject tally in a plane then you know
on this Wikipedia page it shows you
country I don't think this is completely
solved problem well the problem is to
find all possible Pentagon's that will
tie out the plane so and actually some
of these discoveries like the two of
them is just happened that's two years
ago you know so your job is to find you
know a prototype you know the tie out
the shape of a tire to tire the plane a
single tile she's not single shape to
tile the plane that single tile is
called the prototype okay so you your
job is to find a shape you know that is
pentagon and that can tire the plane now
the question is are these so that
Wikipedia shows 15 of them the question
is are they or more I don't know if it's
solved you know proven that these 15 are
you know or the possible oh is it still
an open question I'm not sure but you
can you can find out by reading a page
so this is very interesting because this
problem it's not easy problem you know
you you you you you know you get the top
mathematicians in the world they cannot
you know just solve the problem you they
can spend years think they cannot solve
the problem but however
so this problem is very hard very
difficult but however in the past like
20 years they are amateur mathematicians
meaning that you know people without any
training in math they have discovered I
think two or three of the tidings using
Pentagon so some of these are actually
discovered by them no mathematicians so
this this example you know math problem
shows that you know some of the math
problem it's open problem but it can be
solved by you know the mathematicians so
that's an interesting example
so anyone here type something so so
anyway so that's so let's get back to
the book so this book you know it's a
it's the it's the classic the best book
on the subject now we talked about
tilings so that's one of the subject
this book covers you see as the title in
price tidings and patterns that's so
tithing is part of the issue now there
are other issues such as patterns what
do you mean by patterns for example
let's go to tithing on pattern okay so
this book has been out of print but you
can buy it so the dover we printed it
you know you can just go to my website
search for saudi tidings for example
here anyway you can find it on amazon
but so it's been out of print for a few
years but dover you know doable doable
publication is known to publish
republish reprint books cheaply so they
repainted it with this cover
so yeah if you have interest in math and
you like geometry this is a good book to
to begin your math career you know you
might be you might be remembered as the
person who discovered some tiding some
new solution to a math problem that's
that's been open for a hundred years so
that's this book ya tidings and in
patterns I read most of it I read like
half of the book around 1997 so I you
know I still want to read it read it and
also when you as especially if you are a
programmer you know you read it you can
write programs about it there are a lot
of people have who have written programs
I have for example yeah let me show you
some of my programs why not so again if
you are new here just type something ask
me questions so so it's C sorry tiny
Mathematica
so I wrote this this is backing around
1997 I wrote this program that in
mathematical language that create this
graph you know draw these tiding
patterns yeah so these are you know
mathematical notebooks then they are
like 20 years old I wrote it I wrote
them 20 years ago so so for example what
does this show so you know before we
talked about tidings you know that's one
one of the many problems in mathematics
now this is this what you see here is
the example about patterns you know they
called patterns but it you know it's it
it relates to symmetry it relates to
group theory it relates to grade theory
or knots knot theory so it's all you
know it's of its of mathematics and and
actually you know the thing interesting
about this math subject is that on one
hand it's very advanced mathematics I
mean for example not theory it's used in
quantum theory so you know they study
knots and grades you know for example
you see these things going around it
looks like you know you can trace the
pattern where it goes and you can find
if there is a link you know if you know
between you know what kind of link forms
the pattern
so that's link theory you know great
great theory and and these theories are
using quantum physics you know I I don't
know about a big but but it's used in
you know there and so yeah so so back to
the topic so so I I'm saying what I'm
saying is I these subjects tie lines and
patterns on one hand they are very
advanced you know if even if you have a
PhD degree in math you can still you
know
the subject and do research in fact
there are a lot of ins on a subject but
meanwhile the tidings and patent subject
is also what's called recreational math
you know there's a category of math the
code recreational math recreational math
is such that it's it's math that any
mathematician can understand it can
appreciate it you know for example you
see these you kind of you see what's
going on you know you can you can start
to study it you know so so that's
interesting you know it's it's you know
serious mathematics mathematics
meanwhile it's approachable you know
even if you don't have like 4 years
study of math even if you don't have a
math degree so what this page shows you
know this pattern so it relates to
symmetry study of symmetry group theory
braids theory and yeah you know these
three subjects at least so you see
what's going on here you see this
pattern it's symmetric meaning that you
know if you just have this part you know
in fact you know half half of this
triangle you can generate the whole
pattern and you know there are there are
mathematical jargons for some of these
things for example this is called a
fundamental domain this this is a
fundamental domain and stuff so anyway
so I wrote this program you know you can
generate these pretty graphs also pretty
images for example this one you know it
this one it just looks like a
kaleidoscope keep the comments coming
okay type here type here guys so I can
know you know so I know where I'm going
if this is interesting topic you know if
you want talk something else and type
any questions so this image you know it
looks like a kaleidos kaleidoscope but
it actually you know this image is what
mathematicians mathematicians has
classified wallpaper groups meaning that
meaning that the symmetry of wallpapers
so the this one in particular is it has
symmetry it's called 6 3 2 there are two
notations for symmetry but one notation
in Conway's notation this one is course
is called 6 3 2 and another notation
it's just p6 now in Conway's notation 6
3 2 the number has significance it means
it has 6
I forgot exactly but it says it's about
rotational symmetry and yeah you know
things like that so so so back to the
topic so what I'm saying I was saying
that if you are programmer and you study
that book you can draw you know you can
read programs to draw these pretty
images and ok so when when you program
these things it became a there's another
subject involved that that is
computational geometry for example you
know you have this image you know this
is basically hey informatics finally
someone say it's something so
informatics says hello just start using
such drama today and it's really great
oh thank you so much thank you
so so I was talking about so this image
you know it's just octagon I mean well
you know it so it's just you know eight
point eight stars one two three four
five six yeah eight point eight stars
but now so you have a you know eight
point is start out line shape you know
you can draw that
right in JavaScript or whatever is your
favorite language now you want to cut
this shape you know you want to cut it
and separate them that is a programming
job you know you might try to write that
program you want to cut them once you
cut them into you know chunks then you
can color each one if you know with a
different color then you get this pretty
picture now when you cut them the
problem you run into is called
computational geometry so you will begin
to you know you are try to find how do
you program this thing and you'll start
to look for answers and that that is a
subject of computational geometry and
that's another you know big topic so so
you know you draw pretty pictures and
this one for example you know there are
many techniques to create create this
wallpaper symmetry wallpapers this one
in particular is recursion based so you
start with a shape then you recurse and
it it becomes fractured then you can
recur small so you get this one and this
picture is just random stars you know
you can try it actually you know try to
write a program that draws these hey
informatics so are you a programmer I
don't have people talking people come on
get out type something let me know how
am i doing
so yeah I wrote this program in
Mathematica Mathematica is great so
let's get back to yeah Tyrese and
symmetries very interesting subject and
I think we are done with our subjects
subject oh great thank you
so okay so that's Tiny's and patterns
that's you know I'd you know I wanted to
show you this math book it's a great
math book okay back to cannot talk show
so let's talk about some some other
things then let's talk about treatise
spam yeah this this guy you know okay so
let me show you let's talk about spam
for for a few minutes so I have this
page on webs web spam scam black hat SEO
collection so over the past twenty years
you know you spent spent started with
email spam you know that's the very
beginning like almost thirty years ago
but I would say you know let's say
starting around nine to nineteen ninety
eight year 2000 let's say okay that's
roughly the beginning where the email
spam the beginning with the email email
spam became popular so you know you know
they have statistics now like Google's
had statistics you know when it began
like when you know in the early ten days
you know the first ten years of Google
is a very good company and other
companies to you know they have
statistics about spam you know at some
point it's like 90 percent of all email
traffic is spam so you know you have
machine you know you have code that that
just a mass email addresses and send out
spam and of course Google these days you
have spam filter in any way so span
started like around year 2000 let's say
and so that's one of the first thing of
this spam scamming stuff then you have
you know the the spam email from Niagara
you know dear sir I am the son or
something something of king in this
Africa country and we have two billion
dollars you know they're like ten
billion dollars we need you know for
geopolitical
we cannot touch it big but we need you
know we need you you know we all if you
can you know help us get that money then
we will send you 1 million actually a
lot people fail for it in fact you can
look up Wikipedia I've read it you know
I've read the article like every you
know every few years
nyagora scam ok so apparently some even
government officials like US senators or
congressmen or something some of them
like they have failed for it and you
know they got I want to go to Wikipedia
Nigeria not Niagara Nigeria something
like that
Nigerian scan advance fee scam ok so I
guess that's a technical name for that
these days so I've read this you know
before so apparently some famous people
fail for it anyway back to spam and scam
in this kind of thing so so over the
past ten years you know I've got them of
course and I regularly you know
sometimes I write about I write it down
so whenever I got something you know I
read it down so I have a collection of
them and first of all okay let me show
you this you know today if you go to
google you know because I run a website
like you know I learned fairly popular
website since you know since since in
the 1990s late nineteen ninety so a lot
of people you know so I know about these
things and you know they did this all
sort of tactics and techniques and they
change over the years you know they
change with technology as technology the
scenery the landscape changes they
also change the techniques you know that
also changes so email spam is the first
one and then then there's domain
squatters you know for example you know
for example google.com is very popular
then you just create a new domain good
gee you know geo you calm you know
sometimes people miss type then they'll
just go to your website instead then you
have your ads eBay but I'm pretty sure
Google you know not in the case of
Google you know with three o's the
Google has probably taken care of it
let's try it Gio Gio Gio you don't come
yeah Google has you know taking that so
that thing is called domain squatters so
there are people I mean actually you can
do it you know there are people who just
buy hundreds and thousands of domains
you know when you need it they charge
you you know ten thousand dollars for it
but that that is also in the early days
like year around year 2000 you know
these days they are still a lot of them
but not as heavy and of course today the
latest one is fake news I mean when we
say fake news we usually mean the news
media you know right you know but
actually I mean they are organization I
mean there are people you know
programmers actually you know you can
take make a lot money money you know
remember this these spammers they are
not just you know they make they are
millionaires
you know they are millionaires they
didn't make huge amount of money more
than you know programmers more than good
programmers working for Google for
example so for example it has been
researched and reported you know by news
media they are fake news people you know
corporation they they what I do is they
they just they create a website that
looks similar similar like a news
organization you know but all the
articles are just fake for example they
they abuse the psychology of you know
political you know wanting to believe
you know for example if you are if you
want to believe in Trump they always
write angry things that is you know you
know saying saying is something how
Trump is get being ground you know on
the other hand if you believe the other
side the social justice named is you
know a bunch of their fake news company
anyway and today you know lots of these
mainstream organizations are also fake
news themselves because they want to
generate quick and traffic anyway let's
get back to the topic let me show you
this one so you go to google such sorry
such my name ok and click past our ok so
talk show that's correct
now click past 24 hours now you will see
tens of domains that say spikes Rd for
example this one let me magnify this is
this is this is a scam website okay now
if you're gonna do this make sure you
turn JavaScript off you know if you're
gonna check it out so you see this one
fake this one fake this one fake this
one fake they all say back sorry okay
this one fake you know so there are lots
of them so what to find these basically
you go to Google and you have to click
the past 24 hours or past hour past week
but basically after week if you click on
past month then most of these are valid
but still some of them pass through for
example this one for example this is
also a kind of a scam you know we found
sorry you know they so you so you
basically you have all these people you
know trying to make money you know we
found sorry because often you know
people are trying to search
your name for example then you do just
go to this side you know that website
then they will charge you know you know
say you know give us $10 or $50 I'll
give you information about that person
phone numbers and all that okay so all
of these are good yeah oh these are good
this one I suppose yeah yeah yeah yeah
this is good I mean by good I mean valid
not nuts then but anyway if you go to
past week you can see that let's go to
past 24 hours so you see all these stuff
you know just scam or spam websites so
you click next you know each one notice
that each one of them has a different
domain you know this it's like machine
generated domain so if you are you know
if you assume eyes website be cover of
this this began to happen around 2000 I
think it's 2016
mid 2016 they happen every day they like
change because I check it regularly tens
of them you know new domains every day
oh they all say back sorry
and I noticed the the topic you know
they have mechanic they have fun you
know they have methods like far more
machines or the black market you know
they they they know what is the latest
for example for my website you know I
know what's on my website so they and
you know for exam so they know they can
find out what's the latest that about
sorry that people are talking about what
I've been writing so I mean they have
like also the sort of techniques you
know they have koalas you know so I
noticed like when I'm doing videos these
days right so i if I'm talking about
some subject it showed up there like
tomorrow he'll show up you know Pikes
alley something about web spam you know
so that's that's one of the you know so
so back to the page so I documented you
know many of the know and then I you
know I read it down but you don't have
time to read all of them down but I did
you know some of them every you know one
year or two I wrote one of them down so
for example this one is China is peace
in AD injection so in China so if your
domain is not HTTP if it's just HTTP
then someone access you access your
website in China then there's a
middleman we are in who will remove all
your Google ads on your website and put
their own websites put their own ads
like this one you see this this guy with
the grass this is this is this is my
website sent to me by Chinese friends
you know they swing shot by Chinese
friends in China so this is my website
this the top one is Google ad okay so
that's that's my ad but this one is not
my it's just you know so the middleman
just injected that so this is one of the
you know one of the spam things from
okay so you can see the code here you
know they just injected that so this is
China ISP ad injection so I also want to
show you and some of these are done by
programmers you know just like you and
me of course almost all of them are done
by programmers because you need to you
know you are you know you need to this
are technical so this guy this guy's ass
come back ok this JavaScript teacher
let's go to J's underscore T UT let's go
to Twitter so hi guys are you guys still
with me five people watching say
something
so I'm gonna tell you about this guy
Twitter spam from this javascript
teacher so I know that guy from like
three years ago okay Twitter
this guy you know he was following me
before hey Norman great to see you so
this guy was following me like three
video ago I mean he stopped following me
because something happened you know I'm
gonna tell you that's the story suddenly
happened two months ago three months ago
but anyway he was following me you know
so I thought he was a JavaScript teacher
you know okay nothing I mean that's
great you know because I'm doing
JavaScript and so before two years ago
he doesn't have much followers you see
now he's got 30k followers 30,000 he
doesn't have much before maybe you know
hunting a few hundred you know and he's
trying to sell his book you know he
wrote simple con Emma song about how to
code react.js but you know from what
I've seen of his stuff he doesn't know
you know he doesn't really know the hard
stuff you know he might have you know he
stuff probably good for beginners that's
it so anyway so so he was following me
and I was following him because you know
I don't know who he is you know as a
friend you know ventures show usually
you you know I follow back but so you
know he didn't have much to say and I
just ignored it you know I I saw his you
know like JavaScript you know what he
says you know it's like he doesn't know
the stuff well and one time he's asking
about Crozier like haha like he didn't
didn't understand JavaScript closure so
anyway so yeah so this is this guy okay
I just I didn't pay much attention until
like about three months ago he started
to post like questions asking me like
he'd like this okay he sent to like ten
people including my name not this one
but wait yeah this one you see sorry so
he posted this and here how about you so
he so you know he post he so what is
student so he start by
seeing a JavaScript question like this
some generic question like some coders
are too logical others are something
something visual which one do you lean
towards the most so it's like a general
question
then he retreat that with a bunch of
names you know so so he want us to reply
to that and this annoys me because I can
see that that's just a pop you know
nonsense question you know that kind of
question is is kind of the dramatic
attraction to the crowd you know like
which type of person are you
what could what's your favorite color in
JavaScript you know that that kind of
question gets a lot answer so he post my
question then he attached you know we'd
he'd retreat that and with a bunch of
names then I got annoyed I then I
received that a few times you know after
a few days another one after a few days
another different question may I send a
reply you know can you stop you know can
you stop
you know CC me and it looks like he
ignored it I mean he didn't respond I
mean nothing happens then after a few
days
another question with my name there with
a bunch of other people's names so I
started you know going aggressive you
know this is the third time this guy's
banned us for his mocking his stuff I
replied two times apparently he doesn't
see it then then he started to reply he
says you know I I forgot what he says
but anyway so he you know so that's when
he's you know ceased
he stopped spamming me and he stopped
following me
but then I noticed actually he is doing
that like every every you know a few
times a second like he's actually doing
spam you know he do this he collected
this Twitter account names you know buy
buy buy whatever methods he is doing
that every few seconds every ten seconds
that is how he got 30,000 followers you
see because he used these techniques you
know he pushed to a bunch of people
unrelated to the original like not
connected because he's using retreat
then all these people I suppose most of
them are not you know
beginner programmers so they see this
question they cannot reply to that
question so it looks like you know
appear to normal person like all his
questions got Oh lots of reprise is why
God or the people love his discussion so
so from few hundred followers and then
he got thirty thousand followers that's
that's how this scumbag you know in
society they are these people you know
let's look at his treats and replies you
can see let's see let's see if he is
still doing that yeah there it is
you can see see this is 30 minutes ago
okay so wait - does he still have that
okay I don't I don't see it now maybe
he's he stopped yeah but anyway that's
just the case I want to you know I saw
these people you know and this is how
you get actually in society I mean these
days a lot of people are like that you
know there's just a lot of people are
like that okay so that's about the
JavaScript teachers spam I want to you
know put it out these scumbags and
they're all sort of other funny things
you know Wikipedia I think you know
Wikipedia the Jim the founder Jim jumbo
is also a scumbag Jimbo the guy what's
his name
let me tell you why okay Wikipedia they
asked photon donations every year they
got a lot donations and they are
nonprofit right so they don't pay taxes
and they got lots of money tons but most
of the money actually just go to that
guy you know the Jimbo whale and the
Jimbo whale guy actually he you know he
began the week when we hit me I began
it's not fees only idea there's another
guy he's a co-founder but later on he
like he tried to erase that guy's name
you can you can actually read it on
Wikipedia you know if you look for if
you go through the history of geek video
search for that you'll see it so so
anyway so there's a co-founder he but he
tried to erase the other guy's name also
before he began Wikipedia he's running
porn websites poem that's what this guy
is I mean there's nothing wrong with
that but the thing is he tried to hide
it so he rewarded you know so instead of
saying phone he says we are running a
grammar grammar website you know a
website and you know so this guy is
going around giving talks each each talk
is like a hundred thousand dollars six
six digits you know what is gone and you
know
for most people you know especially
programmers we don't know I mean you
don't know so any anytime Wikipedia as
you're asking for donation so you think
oh it's so great you know we want to DT
you want to donate so I don't think it's
a good you don't want to donate the
other thing is you know the Wikipedia is
kind of nasty I mean of course it's a
great information gathering
you know in fact you know I read
tremendous amount from Wikipedia almost
every day for the past 15 years you know
I spent an hour also every day it is
great but however you know there's so
many other things you know so many nasty
aspects you know Wikipedia the
information they get you know basically
they copy information I mean this this
is a very very tricky issue I mean you
cannot say it's bad or you know like
there's no good or bad this is hard to
say but the point I want to say is that
Wikipedia they just copy information you
know they just swipe information for
example I spent years you know our
mathematics or JavaScript you know I
have articles and many Wikipedia link to
especially 10 years ago but after you
know after a few years the link goes
away because you know people copy your
stuff you know beginning they say okay
this is based on sorry done info or some
other other websites for example but
after much edit you know everyone is
anonymous you know you added at the end
a that you improve then eventually that
original resource is like no longer
relevant
so you just remove it so that's part of
the issue I mean this technically I mean
there's nothing wrong with that but it
does you know but this is it's a issue
you know it's an issue worth thinking
about or discuss because you know for
example I spent years writing about
JavaScript you know some some some of
the programming stuff like you know you
put you you probably have the experience
you know you try to solve something it
takes you days eventually found the
answer then you blog about it it once
it's out there anyone just can copy it
and reward it and that's become their
blog I mean in fact this happens a lot
especially in the opens open source too
so I mean so what can you do I mean you
cannot say they are wrong and and I
don't want to say they are wrong but
there is something you know there's
something going on that's not good
because you know each person authors for
example especially also book authors I
know also I also know for example
JavaScript and Stack Overflow
there's a lot question about JavaScript
where does they the answer came from a
lot of it came from that the guy who
wrote the JavaScript book the let's go
to sorry sorry JavaScript book review
okay I have written JavaScript book
reviews I have written in fact I have
reviewed you know most of the JavaScript
books out there anyway in a being
beginning this is the greatest book the
JavaScript the definitive guide by this
guide is this this this really great
book but by today it's kind of old this
is probably not the book you want I mean
if you want to study JavaScript just go
to my JavaScript
okay I mean just for yourself but I
spent two years writing JavaScript in
depth you can find it by just search for
Java while it's here in my language
tutorial so javascript in depth if you
want to learn JavaScript you know you
might try that but anyway I have written
reviews so in the beginning in the most
of mm this is like the book I mean then
this I mean the the good part is also
good book by the
Roscoe Ford which is a JavaScript expert
but nothing compared to this because the
JavaScript definitive guide actually is
a comprehensive it also covers storm I
mean the good part is just kind of I
mean nothing comparable comparable to
the definite definitive guide okay but
anyways it's getting old it's today
there are better books if you actually
want to buy a tree book anyway so that
book you know so actually huge amount of
Stack Overflow answers are just from
this book you know like when you go to
stock flow like average person you know
ISO JavaScript question I can just look
at the book and answer it without giving
attribution well technically if you are
a good person you you do that but you
know in general that just doesn't happen
because a lot of people are Stack
Overflow they just they just sit there I
mean they want to amass the man the most
number of you know points you know
that's a lot of people do that they do
that because you know maybe there's
something they did it looks good on
their wrist resume you know so so this
is happening you know so you know you
know you copy other things you reward it
because because the the hacker types you
know the open-source fanatics they say
Oh info must be free you know so I mean
this is edgy you know it's a borderline
issue I mean you cannot say you know I
for example if I I spent two years
writing my JavaScript I cannot say you
know you cannot you know copy my stuff
in I mean the purpose of my book is so
you know the stuff then you became
experienced and you can you can write
your book or you know answer other
questions that's that's the goal of my
book but you know but also it's
something wrong if you just like copy
parts of a immediately we without you
learned much from it you know without
attribution that's also wrong so anyway
the nature I mean basically the whole
Wikipedia that's is
of that nature people just copy and grab
things and put it there
then the only credit is to the the the
Wikipedia guy the boss you know like no
you don't get nothing any contributors
including the editors you know you don't
get nothing yeah so anyway so that's
wiki yeah there's a lot of things about
it you know like every year there are
news controversies but people forget you
know you don't remember
what's a details so the jimbo guy yeah
the Jimbo whale is very I would say bad
person here and also the Wikipedia idea
I mean it just happened on the right
time okay so if today let's say if by
magic with Wikipedia shut down I believe
okay the information we are immediately
the entire Wikipedia information we
immediately pop up somewhere else so we
don't really need Wikipedia they will
because the information in Wikipedia
they are actually just they are kind of
you can think of it as a organized
information of the web you know it's
like all the web's information but
organizing a very good way I mean I
don't want to like so it's it's hard to
for me to say this I don't want to diss
Wikipedia you know it's really good but
there is you know issues like this you
know people you know you know we I
remember you know when I was when I had
a job back in 2000 you know in 2002 I
donated Wikipedia when beginning around
2003 or so they you know they don't have
servers you know their servers are
crashing you go to Wikipedia you know
it's busy you know so I know so they are
asking for money and I donated $2 you
can actually see Wikipedia let's say we
holy glut that was my handle on
Wikipedia
holy good user wait
user holy good now I have a poly now
that's not me my my username is P
starting with a 0 a 0 so let's try that
so yeah okay so okay so let's try that
so Wikipedia Minnesota's so ok let me
try to find it this will be quick quick
English so let's just go to any
Wikipedia page and let's click let's
click on View history English language
so some multi-language some let's click
on view history view history and let's
just click on any users so let's click
on this guy okay so now on the user URL
type my name p0 ly g aut that's me so
that's my Wikipedia page
so I actually edited Wikipedia up to up
to 2010 you know I contributed you know
I started a few pages actually for
example the karyotype page I began this
page and and quite a few others I don't
you know I'm not listing here but then
you know when you contribute to
Wikipedia you know there's lots of
editing editing fight you know they'd so
I'm tired of that so I stopped you know
editing anything since around 2010 or
2011 so that's about Wikipedia let's see
and they are mini quite let me show you
one more so maybe let me show you one
more treatise spam farm yeah and you
know the spam techniques spamming scan
they vary they change you every year you
know there are many interesting
techniques for example on Twitter one of
the technique is is a favorite spam like
everything you treat someone we were
favorited you know they favorite like
you know if it's ten thousand every
second their favorite favorite someone
street when they do that you kind of you
have a urge to follow them back or look
at their you know their account you know
so actually a lot people in the Emax
community because one day I noticed why
every time I treat JavaScript for
example one you know I noticed few years
ago then then there's this guy always
favorite much
about JavaScript almost immediately so
this has been going on so I don't know
who is that guy so I look at his account
there's nothing you know it seems just a
normal guy you know he's a CEO and
usually they you know he's a CEO of some
company you know and I'm glad you know
oh well someone appreciated my
JavaScript you know the articles so much
then but that keeps happening you know
then I get became suspicious suspicious
and I looked then then you can find out
that then you know what he favorite you
know it turns out he favorite you know
every second every five second he
favorite something and that guy is also
popular because he is also followed by
you know other Emacs users I know you
know and you know of course then I know
he's just a scam or spam you know so
there's a lots of techniques and also
yeah and you know anyway so let's read
the comments so how long have been
honking well already so did you ever
consider self-publishing ebooks for your
content well I considered it but you
know but usually ebook yes I mean so one
okay so one of the things people you
know some people want printed book so in
print 44 printed book if you want to
publish you can go to like lulu.com
I think they charge some fee so that's
printed book then for e-books
for example Amazon you can do that on
Amazon I haven't done that but basically
you can you know you know you can open
an account and do that to say oh it very
Amazon but they of course they charge
you I don't know how much I forgot I
don't I didn't I don't know how much
about maybe what percentage you know
they charge you each of your book sale I
didn't do that because
because for kind of several reasons
several cat miscellaneous reasons one is
that you know I'm just I'm sending my
Emacs book and JavaScript book for
example if you go to sorry
dot e e max sorry max practical Emacs
tutorial and you go to you go to almost
any page download where to download at
the bottom you'll find by sorry max
tutorial so I I sell this you can click
and pay power and buy it if you do great
you know do that if you like Emacs and
and I get money the whole thing you know
I $30 you know I get the whole thing and
what you get is HTML basically the
entire entire website in HTML without
any ad or tracking stuff you know that's
all being removed and the advantage is
addicts it's extremely fast you know
instantaneous when you click on
something it you know insulin is good
but but the whole thing is also free you
know on the web but you know if I go
through Amazon they are charged part of
it but also for Emacs you know Emacs is
just a narrow did you don't have much
audience I mean to to Emacs users we
think there are a lot of people but
actually with respect to the whole thing
you don't you know there's not many
people actually you know maybe you sell
one book a month and also Amazon will
take of percentage I don't know what's
the number but you know they will take a
percentage then also there's another
there's a task of converting your stuff
to eBook format which is not trivial
it's almost like writing the entire
thing because in HTML format right now
like it's like each topic you know it's
my HTML page you know but in eBook you
have to convert all this you have to
merge them and put them in you know
convert them into chapters and sections
it's not trivial so it's almost like
writing an entire book and that's going
to take you know full time for half a
year at least you know including you
know if you also you know including
Annie Mac this tutorial so Audie and
also suppose I write an eMac spoke in
print let's say let's say I publish it
via via alrighty
let's say alrighty you know the most
famous speak name published my book how
much do I get
not much you know it's like you get
$3,000 that's it you know that's suppose
you know my Emacs book published by
O'Reilly became the most popular book
for Emacs most popular you know how much
do I get maybe 4,000 5,000 that's it
because I've done research on on the
subject if you if you wrote in the most
let's say JavaScript JavaScript is 1,000
times more popular than Emacs you say it
on Amazon you know you look at you know
people you know the the authors the
JavaScript authors of the most popular
JavaScript books they have written about
it how much they make you make $10,000
that's it
not even that you know I mean we are
supposing you are the number one
JavaScript book you know the most sewed
JavaScript all righty
former ID you get $10,000 that's it and
how much time you have to spend you have
to spend four year full-time one year at
least you know that's it's that's what
that's how much you have to spend and
that applies to my Emacs anemic this
this tutorial in my JavaScript tutorial
as well so you know yeah you know
if you work as a programmer in one month
you get $10,000 and also you know I
learned that most book authors vast
majority of them like if you look at all
the alrighty books on programming vast
majority of the program of the authors
they are of the type like me like they
are they don't have a job and usually
they are learning something you know
basically almost all books authors you
know all the books even the bestsellers
the the author are learning the subject
when they write the book you know that's
all that's usually the case doesn't
matter what subject it's always written
by the person who are actually learning
the stuff that's kind of interesting
yeah and you know but act but you know
they so so I'm done intercept for
example if I'm learning a new subject I
write a book that book becomes the
bestseller and that book is actually
Authority because because in the process
of writing a book I even though I'm
learning it at the time but I became I
actually became the definitive you know
authority author you know on that
subject matter that's anyway so that's
that's an interesting aspect about book
authors most of them are like that you
know like all the programmer program
popular programming books basically
by the way how about YouTube discipline
the search filter by date what do you
mean by the way there is an interesting
thing about YouTube that I don't know
what happened you know can you like for
example if you go to a YouTube account
let's say for example let's go to this
back wheel teamwork review so you go to
any YouTube account like you click this
guy's name and you click the video so
you can see all of his videos you know
the list of all his videos and if you
click buy sewed by sautéed Otis first
that never worked for me oh it does now
as strange ok so it worked for me that
never worked for me before anyway how
about YouTube discipline the search
filter by date what do you mean so
normal says I think programming books
are usually labors of love or
advertising for consulting yeah yeah you
know a book you know they say it's a
vanity thing especially today you have
what's so-called vanity press you know
like if I want to write a book I can
self publish it you know called it's
called vanity press so that you know I'm
you know I'm the book author you know
I'm an author anyway so anything
interesting going on so I've been
talking for how I know it's that's fast
so I talked about spam today well ok
I've talked about mass tidying books
tithing subject very interesting okay so
that's math tiny stuff and the spam so I
guess that's it for today
how many how many people are watching
six people okay I think that's it for
today if you search for subject the by
date filter doesn't work oh okay
so apparently there's a bug I guess so
that's why it's not working for me so I
guess so today is Friday so where are
you guys from no info Matic and Norman
and t TI v AV we are guys located like
time zone so today is Friday right now
it's 5 o clock p.m. in California time
serbia Wow amazing that's in that's like
Eastern Europe right and no money is
from east coast of USA so let's go to
Google map let's have them let's set
have fun Google map
let's see where Serbia this is like a
lesson in geography you know I've had
that reason is like the world is so big
you know actually if you don't have a
friend in some places and you just don't
know like other countries remote other
countries so we have a globe let's go to
Serbia's are you were you following me
from for Emax stuff like how did you
find me
Serbia now where is Serbia
you know I always too like to look at
maps like whenever I have a friend you
know they tell me where they live I like
to look then I like to dive into the
street view and look at the you know
cities and the people my Emax great
Thank You ser BIA how above Greece you
know so above Greece oh yeah so I think
I have a friend who lives in yeah oh
yeah Serbia okay it's really big you
know I like to say we Americans you know
don't know about how these countries but
you know other Americans may not agree
but anyway so okay so Serbia is here you
know so what the Serbian looked like you
know like let's drop into a city let's
see what's a what's a busy
wait whoops wait dropped into the Rome
face that was a beautiful face Oh God
I have to do this again so anyway I
think that's basically it for today but
this I mean I'm just doing having some
fun you know looking at what language do
they speak there so it looks like it's
using the critic alphabet
so let's look at Serbia okay so this is
probably some kind of relic like a
tourist attraction I don't like you know
when I look at cities I don't like this
kind of thing I want you know I want to
see the actual people you know the
normal daily lives of the cities okay so
this almost looks like California this I
mean just just you know looking at this
just yeah like if you just show me this
picture I wouldn't be able to tell I
mean I might think it's just down the
street so one language serbian okay so
is english popular there i mean is it is
it taught in like high school one Oh an
info info Matic is from
okay okay anyway so anyway I think
that's that's that's it for today thank
you guys for coming
younger generations know it cool Morocco
oh yeah I remember Morocco let's look at
that next time thank you guys bye