good evening welcome to another episode
of our top show so today I'm going to
talk about JavaScript Golan and maybe
some Emacs in other stuff so let's put
the date here correctly and stuff in
stuff that's right
just stuff
select all pasted tab select all that's
good
okay let's pop this out pop out pop out
chat and let's go back to my Emacs and
that's good okay mention pay me so if
you like my show go to Sally dot info
okay so you see a patreon Amazon gift
card and PayPal and Bitcoin that is
supposed to you know advanced humanity
to be so that we are free so if you like
my stuff
put your money there thank you okay then
we're gonna talk about JavaScript Golan
and some Emacs and stuff okay I
mentioned pay me not talk show yeah
so talk show is the page you are looking
at which is that one it's on my website
and we're gonna let's see
are we here yet is people coming in yet
for watching fantastic for people say hi
um so okay we're gonna start in I'm
gonna just start to talk about
JavaScript some JavaScript stuff then
Scott a friend asked me to maybe we talk
about Golan Golan is a wonderful
language one of the latest great
language okay I'm gonna show you this
okay let me show you this this this is
Porlock okay this is the today's
prologue to saw talk show let me turn on
the volume up so you can hear it okay I
hope you can hear it now let's see
that's Russian
well I suppose it is Russian so as I
asked people you know someone to show me
what she says and she said that a little
bit earlier and the Google Translate
says I was I was advised that if I said
the pattern pattern with the letter P
Russian feed I was supposed to pronounce
like ah okay then I'm sure to be a hype
and I'm not sure what that means then
she said well we'll see armoured
personnel carrier refrigerator radio
reproducer interior interior master
interior exterior Terrier then drove hey
danielle has going so he here yes six
people watching say say say something
okay so
this this she's on tick-tock now there
is a new social website called tick-tock
that's from China that's that's quite
fascinating because you know USA while
most social networks be up like USA you
know the Silicon Valley California can
okay you know progressives you know we
they are known as progressives you know
because well anyways it suppose I mean
the philosophy is progress of course
everyone wants progress but the
progressive you know it's kind of a you
know a part of the political let's say
philosophy so the progressive meaning
it's specific they mean that they want
to push basically that like they'd like
to change
they prefer change instead of you know
you know the opposite is conservative
conservative is like you know I mean you
know yeah of course we need to you know
you know the word always need to be to
have change but you know be careful
slowly you know you know that's why they
are conservative so the progressive
philosophy is like they are more
aggressive about change you know in fact
actually you know that all that the
major changes in society in a whole
history of humanity okay and those major
changes are always brought about by
technology okay so it is actually
technology that changes society how we
how we work how we function the social
structure countries you know come and go
you know that's technology so you know
we have Industrial Revolution and
starting with engines and trains you
know and in industrial machinery and
then we got Jimi's you know huge Jim is
blowing out smoke that pollutes the air
then we got then you know that's
Industrial Revolution and today we have
digital a
age digital age in AI you know the
societies changing so fast that that
okay is anyone here hello hi guys say
something can you guys hear me because
yesterday I did a video where I talked
for 40 minutes and it's silent because I
forgot to turn on the microphone is like
turned off you know this should be no
ain't no man great to see you
so yeah so I was talking about you know
changing technology and Procrit
progressive but anyways so yeah this is
this a new social network called tick
tock that's quite interesting it's
actually from China China is like
getting amazing like every day I see
things you know I started to follow some
Twitter accounts from China some of them
some of them are like official you know
China is like centralized you know as
opposed to American okay like democracy
we need democracy everyday democracy
these in that you know but China is the
China you know China the country like
the nation the history has always been
like we you know as far as government
control so almost always central you
know centralized like one one King you
know one leader that rules the country
and they are good good times in there
are bad times you know but anyway the
democracy the concept of democracy okay
is actually Western concept so it
doesn't it's like it doesn't almost
doesn't exist in China or in in the Far
East
you know the entire Asia more or less
okay you know the Japan Korea and all
the other country I mean the center is
China because China is the oldest and
and kind of the Chinese culture and
thought and philosophy kind of spread
out so you know basically though you
could say the whole Asia is like you
know China philosophy and thoughts so
anyway does
but I mean that's just a fact okay um
but also India in India is also Asian in
India's kind of they don't call India as
Far East India is like a you know kind
of like I'm not sure what's a proper
term for the region of India's South
South Asia Asia no I don't think that
maybe South Asia anyway India is also
Asian you know the Buddhism came from
India
you know it's spread to China you know
but anyway so what I was saying yeah
China you know historically and the
philosophy always just have one ruler
you know and so yeah I was saying
democracy is is kind of the Western
philosophy but in Asia you have like
different you don't have that philosophy
you have more you have other kind of
like like in Western society you are
mostly focused on hi Jonathan
in Western society you mostly have a
okay you have like democracy you have
freedom freedom of individuals okay not
not other than freed freedom you know
like individualism you have concerns
about justice and rape like head rape
every day you know you know the concept
of a being Western societies since since
the ancient Greeks
you know the since warm and before Rome
the Greeks you know they have raped she
was you know that the the God she was he
he raped every everyone every every
every girl in nimes so anyways so these
are Western society concepts you know
just as individual freedom
I mean it's Asian it's it's it's where
the Western society sprung up you know
they are they revolve around this
concept and also very much kind of like
materialism and or code logic or physics
like you know
Oh math you know so in Western society
and Western languages I mean everything
I mean like you have concepts like
precision logic you know you know reason
you know the concept of reason is it
reasonable like all rational you know so
this these are kind of the Western
societies philosophy where the Western
society floundered I did I get the word
right of flounder you know not to be
confused with found
I think founder is when a ship sinks
flourish I forgot what's maybe I wrote
did I use a wrong word flounder but I
mean I meant to yeah I mean is incorrect
or correct let's see if ll f l ru and D
that's probably wrong and it's in into
it anyway so I was saying talking about
Western society correct
okay okay let me check quickly cuz I
wasn't I want to I mean I don't mean
sink I mean like flourish
you know the wet merriam-webster is the
worst dictionary
you know never never used my
merriam-webster I can tell you you know
because I'm an expert of dictionaries
never you know use Merriam West Webster
you know web Webster is a general name
but merriam-webster is one specific
dictionary you never want to use because
mostly because the merriam-webster you
see online and you see everywhere in
bookstores they are like actually they
are a British abridged collegiate
so-called Collegiate Dictionary and it's
one of the worst okay
I think yeah I think I used the flounder
I mean flourish okay yeah so anyway
so the Western society I was talking
about Western philosophy then then yeah
but the Asian philosophy for example for
example logic logic reason rationality
okay this concept are entirely foreign I
mean they are Western thought but it
doesn't mean like Chinese doesn't build
ships or you know technology of course
China is known for you know the leading
the leader of technology up to 1600 or
1800 you know they build astronomy you
know the the most advanced in what you
know at the time but however this this
concept you know rationality recent
logic it's like they almost doesn't
exist in Chinese in Chinese philosophy
and they and also okay so you don't have
the Western thought of freedom like
individual individualism like you
emphasize individual and and like you
know in America for example you you talk
about that every day I mean all these
concept you talk about every day you
know oh we need freedom Oh individual
freedom or journalism is you know free
speech free speech and this or that yeah
and and justice yeah and then we have
now the social justice can they talk
about their justice you know so these
are ways Western philosophy but right
China they don't have that I mean it's
just different philosophy you don't you
don't have that you don't have you know
freedom you know and you don't you don't
have individualism you rather you have
of course but I mean it doesn't mean
that oh you know Oh Chinese likes to be
controlled you know like to be slave I
mean so it doesn't mean that but you
don't the thought you know the concept
of freedom just just like it's not in a
culture so
like it doesn't exist and the same thing
with you know logic and and and and you
know reason and stuff so for example as
opposed to individualism the Chinese you
know they focus more on like family
family oriented kind of philosophy your
life okay for example you always respect
the elders okay you respect first of all
you have family you have you know elders
or you know maybe outside of your family
people oh that are you and then you have
ancestors you know your dad your
granddad your dad's that that's that
that you know they died of course you
always have a strong respect for them I
mean it's it's it's the it's it's in a
culture you know everyone do that so you
respect your your parents the foremost
then they respect you know the their
ancestors your ancestors you know
whoever you know you're you know last
generation or before and you also for
example in siblings you know your your
sisters or brothers in Chinese I mean
it's even part of the language in fact
lots of cultures and thinking you can
see it's building into the language
itself for example in Chinese sibling
you have brothers but actually so you
have the word brother but actually we
have word like elder brother and younger
brother it's always you know you don't
just say brother they it's like they
there is a general term that means
oh brother and or sisters but you don't
say that I mean average daily use you
have elder brother a word okay for elder
brother a word for younger brother a
word for older sister a word for younger
sister and the younger one always need
to like that you know it's it's part of
the culture you respect the elder
brothers or sisters
you know so anyway so that's a you know
Chinese so I mean so it's just different
so so where did we get into this topic
where did I start - I was talking about
this girl
yeah tick tock okay so tick tock is a
new social platform it's like Twitter
it's like Instagram you know this kind
of thing but but it originated from
China yes China is you got so many
things going on today yeah I was I mean
I I was I'm really amazed you know
because I grew up in USA or thought
since you know I left my country Taiwan
I was born Taiwan I left my country when
I was fourteen years old so I lived in
South America for a year Canada for
three years and I came to USA in 1989
when I was 21 years old 20 or 21 1989
okay being in California so you could
say since I'm an adult
oh my you know I I you know I live in
u.s. so but I do have Chinese roots so
you see this is interesting because if I
was if I grew up in USA you know since
maybe four years old or if I was upon us
a then even I look like Chinese but but
all my thoughts is just like American
just like you know there are a lot
Chinese people in so coach ID Chinese
Americans they were born in USA they
grew up here so but these people when
they go to China when they visit China
or Taiwan they are not like Chinese I
mean everyone can tell you know they are
just different you know they don't you
don't share they are just like white
people or you know American people with
the Chinese skin you know body so you
know it's it's different the thought of
the entire thought behavior you know
that your daily behavior your thinking
patterns is so different so anyway so I
but I grew up in Taiwan and here I was
14 they are lived in basically Canada
mostly and u.s. USA so so so I kind of
have
you know I see both coaches you know I
and and and by the way when I was
younger I don't like the Chinese culture
at all
I'm like actively organized it you know
because well because my dad and you know
it's a long history it's a complex
history but I don't like you know I'm
like a rebel what you might call rebel
you know young people always many are
like that so I didn't like any any of
the Chinese philosophy yeah like I don't
I don't like it though I think it's City
stupid I want I want the Western
philosophy okay I want individual
freedom yes I want logic you know I want
precision thinking I don't want the you
know Zen or Tao or Buddhism you know
that roundabout Taiji or everything is
you know fuzzy and this is no like
position no logic you know I like I want
the Western I like quick philosophy you
know that was when I was young but no I
don't you know I don't really I don't
think one is really better than the
other you know I appreciate the many
Chinese thoughts now anyway so back to
yeah so I was talking about social media
website so did the Chinese you know
China P Ortiz which is koto in social
media website and that but in
english-speaking countries countries
it's called tick tock you can actually
go to the website in fact there is a
tick tock in fact there's also Wikipedia
page you can read so there's a Fisher
website you know and and there's also a
GPIO here now that's a movie but anyway
there is a here yeah here so it's this
is quite amazing because tick tock you
know it's a it's originates from China
so the culture and the rules you know on
this sociopath is becoming very popular
especially in Western countries it's
populated by young people you know
a lot of them you know beautiful girls
in young people you know but they just
do things so so the the point is that
because it's from China so it doesn't
have these rules you know from the
Western American society like Google
Facebook Twitter you know YouTube you
know if you grew up if you are American
you may not know but those they have
rules like that like there's just a
certain categories that they don't allow
you never see for you know I'm not at
you know I'm not going to go into that
in detail because because these kind of
things quickly then it becomes you know
it touches politics then then then you
know get you know get on to other things
in the social justice they're gonna tie
me
but anyway so tick-tock they don't have
these rules I mean the rules are
different you know it's from China and
then the West the English version is
called tick-tock and they'd is just
becomes very popular so this Russian
girl you know she's talking about this
funny I find but you know she's very
beautiful you know and she is talking
about this not illiterate so that's so
that's interesting by the way this is
are my were the English website if you
want to go to see it Sawadee Sawadee
blog that's my that's my website about
English writing literature languages
linguistics related stuff so anyway so
that's that let's talk about JavaScript
wow this is a huge branching of talking
because I've been talking about this for
like twenty four minutes okay I think
let's go back to Joe
script good usage oh of course she's
Russian
would you call ASEAN people robotic why
I mean how how is that Daniel says
tick-tock has been downloaded 80 million
times in the United States Wow
800 million times worldwide are you you
are you a user Danielle then Daniel you
are in Los Angeles right yeah I'm you
know about the you know Daniel did a
pull request to fly keys I'm so sorry I
just never got into it because because
you know there's a lot to do you know I
have to spend literally several hours to
I mean not just read the poor request
but also I have to get back to coding
eMac B's you know I have to get back to
know the details about you make these
key binding commands you know so I kind
of just like procrastinate it but but
I'll get back to it for sure because you
know because this is my project and you
know and and actually are a lot of
people other people have issues you know
basically in the past month I since I
started to doing video I kind of you
know I haven't been reading my emails
you know all those kind of things I kind
of delayed anyway so let's get back to I
think we're gonna talk about JavaScript
a little bit then we gonna six people
watching we're gonna maybe talk about
Scott Scott are you there are you here
okay so do you guys have a any questions
if you have a questions just type it
okay you can you know type anything and
maybe then we can go into that direction
let's talk about JavaScript it's just
JavaScript blog let's go to my
JavaScript blog blog so
Danielle so you are in Los Angeles yep
okay JavaScript so I have this
JavaScript tutorial I mentioned a few
times javascript in depth and you know I
started to write a JavaScript tutorial
back in 2005 but back then I don't
really know what I'm doing so I'm Tim
I'm just starting to blog just a little
bit about like JavaScript basics like
how do how do you write a loop how do
you you know closed string you know but
until 2014 2014 I started to dive into
JavaScript in depth so I have read you
know all the JavaScript script specs you
know JavaScript 2015 spec and before
that like which is called edition 5.1
then I've also read you know some of the
JavaScript 2016 SPECT now javascript is
aspect is interesting you see the name a
comma script language specification
akuma 262 it is why it's extremely and
what's the word complicated no that's if
you know the extremely there's a word
for for being complicated complicated
but I forgot what that is anyway so let
me explain what it is okay so the
official name for JavaScript the
language the standard SPECT okay
official name for the language is
actually called a comma script now the
specification for the a comma script
language the official title is a comma
262 you know that's a standard a comma
262 is a standard
for the Akama script language and the
ACMA script language is the official
name for javascript okay that's the
basics and what's a comma a comma is the
name of the standard organization the
organization that creates standards so
that's that organization's name is a
comma so what they do they published
standards specs for variety of things so
one of the Specht is called a comma 262
and the subject of that spec is a comma
script language that's it's one factor
of luck and then so they have editions
5.1 then then they start to change your
name to instead of saying wow this they
start to use the year like a comma
script 2015 xmas script 2016 anyway so
that's aspect you know by the way
JavaScript spec is the worst suspect
I've ever read I have read the Java
language spec part of it you know a
little maybe 20% ok javascript language
I have read the scheme Lisp language
respect our forests our 4 RS or eyes are
for back in 1999 I have read about half
of it at least half of it so Java spec
JavaScript spec I have read the Python
language spec panel language spec I read
maybe 30% you know ok I didn't read you
know like all the detail but over the
years maybe 30% so I have read eMac list
spec eMac this doesn't really have
aspect but you have a eMac this manual
that's 1,000 pages read you know maybe
60% 70% over the years I have read the :
inspect : spec is the most the the best
language spec of them all and it's very
short as well the Golan's script the
writing quality the precision the
clarity the girls go-go language you
know spec is the best of them all and
JavaScript the spec is the worst the
worst you know the existence it's
very complicated and it's
incomprehensible
now javascript the language itself is
also it is extremely complicated
I would say more complicated by our
magnitude than or them all the languages
aforementioned languages but that's one
thing when you have a language that's
very complicated but the specification
needs not to be very complicated you
know you could you know describe some
complicated things with as long as you
you know your spec may not be I mean the
the complication of the language and the
complication of your SPECT they are not
like proportional Linea okay the
language can get more complicated but
the suspect can be written if you if
it's good writing it can be still very
clear okay but that's not the case for
the Java scripts Specter script spec is
verbose and and and and the word just
came to my turn but I forgot forgot
again so the ACMA scripts spec is
convoluted that's what I want to use
convoluted okay it's a like a noodle and
it's it tries to be and it's not even
it's not formal eat neither you know if
you are a programmer and if you never
studied math you might think you know
usually programmers admire math you
think you know we want to you know oh
it's formal like you know they think has
cow is but I actually ask
this is not math not math formality but
anyway so the java language spec is
pretty lousy okay it's convoluted and
verbose and let's show you example I'm
going to show you some examples okay and
now let's see okay so I was talking
about JavaScript so I wrote these
JavaScript in-depth if you don't know
JavaScript I recommend it and so let's
go to JavaScript so you see they are
like maybe 600 pages okay let's go to
JavaScript find that name HTML okay in
this directory I have 700 pages of them
some are HTML about HTML tutorial some
are about CSS tutorial but but the
JavaScript ones is about 500 or 600
pages so although all these pages now
when I write them you can see that for
example if I go to let's say if I go to
this page array form away from
JavaScript away from open showing
browser you can see that there's a
reference so basically in each paragraph
I tend to link to the reference where
that you know that's the place where
relates to what I was talking about in
my tutorial okay this you know
JavaScript spec is like one one huge
HTML like ten megabytes or something so
it takes a lot you know huge amount of
time to load it okay so this page is
talking about array dot from which is a
from is a property of the array function
object JavaScript is very complex by the
way the JavaScript is the object you
know JavaScript is also an object
oriented language however the object the
the object in JavaScript is entirely
different from Java Python Ruby tsipras
first okay in those languages you have
Opie
you know what's called class-based OPA
class-based object system where you
create classes then you create create
instances of those classes which is
called a object and so on okay but
that's class class-based
object system now in JavaScript it's
entirely different that's why that's one
of the reason that makes JavaScript kind
of hard to dive into I mean even if you
have like two years programming
experience in your company working on
JavaScript you know I can easily ask you
a question you don't know in fact much
you know a lot of your code is just
wrong you know until you know yeah so
JavaScript you know you really have to
type into JavaScript
you know actually study the language to
actually understand what's going on so
JavaScript the app the object system
javascript is actually is the name is
code the system is called prototype
based object system okay so it's a
prototype based object system we can go
into detail on how that works you know
if you guys want just remind me okay
just type it and I'll explain you know
how JavaScript object system works but
anyway anyway back to the spec so I had
all these links almost on every page one
or more links to the spec back in a
beginning I put the links because partly
when I'm writing tutorial you know it's
convenient for me to you know constantly
you know Cricut so I can read what the
spec actually says and you know I maybe
I can improve you know edit my writings
so it's correct and you know clear and
so on and also also for readers you know
so they so you have
confirmation like when you read about
these you know you might think wait are
you how can I trust you you know how do
I know you are not you know talking like
you know what you are talking about well
there is a reference right there you
know on every page almost every few
paragraphs you can read but actually you
know people don't read that I I noticed
that actually basically nobody you know
go to the spec because well partly
because the spec is just
incomprehensible like you cannot just
read the spec it's like completely
incomprehensible I don't care how many
years you have experience with
JavaScript suppose you work at Google
hey mail card hey great to see you now
cat let me get back to that I'm gonna
read the comments in a few minutes so
suppose you are a JavaScript or coder
working at Google and suppose you have
like let's say two years you know code
in JavaScript in Google a Google then
you go to this page for example you you
read the the Specht about a raid art
form you wouldn't understand it you know
that's that's what I say you know you
can you know you can you know try to
verify it yourself you know you you
wouldn't understand it I mean in fact
you have to yeah anyway so so people
don't read that and in fact it so what
I'm saying is that the links to the
reference do not provide value to the
readers actually so I'm starting to
remove them so for example a ref I'm
going to go here and delete delete show
in browser and it's gone so I'm starting
to delete them that's what I'm doing so
that's one of the things I'm doing so I
have collected all my pages that
contains reference links they are about
200 X
300 all these are already done in the
past few days so right now they are
still 200 pages so I'm just going to go
to them and deed them so that's how I
work
that's what I do you know how I spend my
time every day so for example next one
array is array so arrays array is is
arrays of property name is a property
name of the object array the object
array is a function that's how
JavaScript works so anyway so you see
the reference here so I search ref
delete delete refresh it's gone so
that's what I'm doing
so yeah that's what I want to talk about
so they I have a lot more to do but
basically that's that's what I was going
to talk about JavaScript and that's kind
of the end I mean this so of course so I
doing this time I mentioned lots of
other things about JavaScript so if you
want me to go in into that direction for
example you explain how JavaScript
object system differs from the
class-based system or give you a
overview of JavaScript object system
works I can oh I can give you a overview
of the JavaScript language so just let
me know in the comments now let me read
the comments let's see how long I've
been going 41 minutes so okay Norman
says okay so let me go to top yep
oh so then he are you beyond tick-tock
great okay so I'm going to join to I
think that would be fun you know I just
you know I like to see what the new
social network so rest rope high-res
drop miss Rob says javascript is kind of
like play Tahoe you know don't be too
sure about that you know like today's
JavaScript no they
have like a new version every year and
in fact since the 2015 version since the
2015 version as far as advanced language
feature goes you know JavaScript is more
Cape you know is equivalent or even
possibly more capable than Python Ruby
okay
Lisp I'm not kidding I mean overall I
still consider JavaScript the worst
language because all these new versions
of JavaScript they they remain
compatibility to you know the JavaScript
version one you know back in 1995 so
that means all the watts of JavaScript
you know or the ugliness they didn't fix
you know they didn't actually try to fix
because they want to remain
compatibility so instead you know
changing things they add things you know
they add things so because of at least
because of these javascript is remains a
very convoluted and the complex and hard
to understand language because there's
lots of horse and potholes you know is
it's extremely bad but however however
if you only consider the language as
like you know the features advanced
features for example generators you know
generally doesn't interface or you know
or you know you know the fanciest things
we did hacker types you know like to
talk about decorators you know foxy you
know and you know so javascript is is no
worse than actually in many you know in
some aspect is actually better than
Python or Ruby you know so it's very
advanced actually quite advanced
language JavaScript is today so for
example I have a article here JavaScript
so es2015 features where this page
summarizes the major features of
javascript introduced in in the eggman
script to 2015 which came out in 2015
now they have one new version every year
so you have 2016 2 + 2017 18 and this
year you're gonna have 2019 new version
so they are like javascript is going
incredibly fast and you know they are
adding a lot of things you know and
actually pattern matching you know the
pattern matching which is a feature you
only find in a handful of functional
languages advanced functional languages
is coming to JavaScript I'm not sure
when maybe it's in 2019 I don't know yet
but it's like it's there oh and bignum
anyway so so anyway this page summarizes
some of the new things
it's like 2015 is a complete new
language I mean yeah oh the syntax is
it's like a complete complete new
language but without actually changing
you know the old language so all the old
language you know the syntax is still
there
they still works however they are new
adding a complete you know new kind of
thing so you have let which is like lisp
sled you know it's a local let scope
constant you have arrow functions this
is great
you have function argument if default
value okay now you have you know default
values yeah I mean that's a basic
feature in you know Python Ruby and
others but so it's in JavaScript now to
you know since 2015
you have rest parameters you have
destructuring assignment which you do
not have among other many other
languages you know yet
this structuring assignment then you
have computer ability keys you have
object literal expression okay then you
have proto that's getting technical you
know some of these are getting you know
technicalities of JavaScript you have
temporary string
that which is also common in other
languages Python Ruby pearl you have
spread operator which is also fairly you
know kind of like advanced you know and
then you have set object you have map
object you have and you know so this is
you know this is overview of JavaScript
2015 so let's go back to the comments
too busy with tik-tok javascript is kind
of a dough I've only read C C++ has cow
and rust specs okay wrist Rob says he's
read cc first verse has cow in rust
specs I never read any of those okay so
yeah we are like on the different side
mostly for reference okay
no man says the Java switch spec was
retrospective not surprising it's a mess
retrospective what do you mean
retrospective you mean the language
first then they start to write spec well
a lot languages like that well anyway so
I mean yeah it's a messy
rest Rob says such a horrible language
but used everywhere in today's web apps
yeah
in fact JavaScript is like it's used on
desktop apps to you know nothing to do
with the web for example the atom editor
you know the electron framework you know
the the Microsoft vs code that's so
JavaScript you know and it's a desktop
desktop app so that's how far javascript
has like how popular it has become but
overall as i you know i really it's
really a bad language
I mean seriously bad you know I really
wish they not to maintain the
compatibility so get rid of the old you
know but they you know but they don't do
that
so milk cat hey milk at one time no see
man milk ad we should do a video chat
you and me man
you like you don't do anything so milk
ad says just spent 48 hours praying see
Lisp that's my idea of fun before I go
for sleep in studies again okay see
leaves sillies that's an implementation
of Common Lisp so restaurant says yeah
Jess uses this weird photo type system
yeah yeah it's pretty weird but but I
mean um yeah okay so so we've dog hey
web dog great to see you what do you
think about typescript it's way better
yeah I mean it's hard to say you know I
you know it depends on like what you
know what do I think of it I mean it's
great so so types temp script you know
tab script is a kind of a static typed
language that is a layer on top of
JavaScript so you know you can say it's
a superset of JavaScript so javascript
is you know type script you know you
could you know it's just but then if you
take any JavaScript code you can start
to add types let me go let's go to
because I have written Chavez I have
used typescript
in my sorrow application so let's see
function frog first I want to work on
this project but it's just like got
delayed and delayed
let's show in Safari so this is a
typescript I'm gonna show you
oh my god safaris starting up why is it
taking so long
okay so I wrote these in typescript I
mean yeah in typescript so let's go up
this is a library for plotting
mathematics curves so I'm working on
this and okay that one I want to show
you character count let me show you that
one yeah let me show you two things I
wrote about in JavaScript so if you like
it spread it okay help me out you know
that other people know so one is a
Unicode search I'm gonna show you and
the other one is keyboards let's go to
keyboard character count so if you go to
my keyboard block then you go to layout
now then you go to here cha frequency
counter now this is a interactive app
that farts this is a interactive plot
that counts the number of characters
frequency you see as I type they kind of
they start to calculate you know which
which letter is used more so try it and
if you like it tell your friends shred
you know put it on your blog link to it
you know I wrote this because I want to
study you know the letter frequency when
you design keyboard layouts you know
when you want to know you know you can
also paste like the whole thing paste
you know a bunch of things then you're
just it's in it's computing in real time
so you know as you know you you as as I
type you know let's say T et why it
doesn't read what you see I typed it
here and I want to hold it down and oh I
see on the Mac you know
anyway so you know it's interactive in
real time so that's one JavaScript app
I've written you can see the code yeah
I'm not gonna show it but you can see it
if you if you want to you can of course
see the code then the dermis then the
other thing is Unicode characters if you
just search my name sorry Unicode you'll
get to this page so let's say hot this
is also real time okay so this way
select or delete h-e a you know now it
shows all Unicode characters that
contains the word whose name contains
the word HEA so you got all these let's
see her head oh okay so you got a head
this is Chinese Chinese character for
head this is a variation and then this
you have arrow head arrow heads you have
you know okay so let's let's try
headphone there it is health headphones
so let's try H e a ha t yo K that's hot
so anyway that's my unicode character
search or these are written in
JavaScript and they work in real time of
course okay now let's go back to
typescript let's go back to yeah so I
was showing you
let's go to let's go back to the the
curves the plant so so if you for
example let's go to index so you see
that parametric plot is this page now
I'm going to open that page and that's
that page then you go to
[Music]
you can see I'm loading to JavaScript
files here now this one is the library
that does all the you know plotting
stuff
SVG this one is the actual code for this
page so if I open that that's a code so
all you have to do is you know call this
function parametric plot then you know
create an anchor to where you want to
put it you know put the plot then you
just say this is a function arrow
function X X then map to X and math sine
sine curve sine x times X sine squared
okay from 0 to 7 then 8 plots that so I
wrote this and the library let me show
you the library the library is this file
open that and this is JavaScript but
let's go to the directory you can see
it's over here so it's actually
typescript that's the JavaScript that
runs on a web but the the source code is
this one type script so you can see for
example this this is typescript you see
this you know so so no more each in
JavaScript yeah okay that we can show
you this so let's see range so so you
see these two things are the same thing
this part and this part you see both of
them define the same function f range
but notice in a typescript you have the
type of the arguments you see the
argument here is just min Max and Delta
but in typescript you have Ming is the
number number is a type max is a number
type Delta default value is 1 and the
function also returns a value and that
value has is a
of type array and each array element is
a number so what you are seeing is the
type script so they are like a layer on
top of JavaScript so is it good or bad
well I mean it's good in that it helped
because JavaScript we have no types and
JavaScript is pretty convoluted so it's
very extremely easy to create programmer
errors so typescript helps in you know
in that way because you can add type
annotations so code so called type
annotations you add you know types to
values so that the compiler will find
any type errors you know it's helpful
but however it's not really good I mean
it's helpful for sure but it isn't I
mean like you know you couldn't say it's
really good because because you see
JavaScript is a very convoluted language
you know the syntax you know it's
inconsistent and lots of potholes okay
so you begin with that typescript you
know is intended to be just a superset
so it's a hundred percent compatible
with JavaScript so you begin with this
lousy JavaScript then you add you try to
add you know syntax for types you know
to this already very lousy syntax so it
becomes more very complex you know it
really does get becomes you almost
become becoming incomprehensible if you
you can already see a little bit of that
happening you know let's see for example
this this function this function dot
products it's a function that computes
dot product of two vectors you can see
here is the argument then here is the
type declaration you know so it gets you
know the it gets complex even for a
simple function like this you know this
is just one line function
so that's that that is my opinion about
typescript
you know I'm not you know what can you
do about it there's almost nothing you
can do because javascript is used on web
they they don't want to you know
eliminate the old one they want to
remain compatible so you have like 20
years of baggage then typescript tries
to be compatible with JavaScript 100%
you know because you have this
tug-of-war situation of compatibility
and progress you know if you go the the
extreme way of progress where you
eliminate compatibility what happens is
like Python 3 nobody uses nobody want to
adopt you know after 10 years only 50%
adoption so on the other hand you
maintain comparability because of habit
you know people like that because people
don't want to change what they know you
know oh I have to relearn everything you
know they like that so but then you got
this extremely baggage you know a bag of
complex complexities like see see it and
see chaff shop you know see first first
that's what see first first is the same
way but it's popular what can you do you
know that's kind of like that
so typescript so you have this yeah the
fairly complex and you know you have
this situation you know and also
typescript they don't introduce their
own libraries that's their decision they
decided that they're gonna like play
nice you know so they create is this you
know optional type annotation on top of
hundred percent compatible with
JavaScript and you know they don't add
their own libraries like like it's not
like if you walk in typescript then you
have all these libraries part of
typescript you can use that can
automatically compile to JavaScript no
they decided you know they don't do that
instead of they
to play nice with the so called
JavaScript ecosystem so that you know
the JavaScript language doesn't is maybe
it's not too very big you don't have
many things so you rely on the hundreds
of libraries and frameworks out there
now it would be nice if if typescript
creates all the deficiencies that's you
know of JavaScript and include
everything like the Python would say you
know battery battery included it would
be nice if if you can code everything in
typescript and just press a button you
know compile to JavaScript but you know
the typescript decided you know they are
not doing that what they do is only
providing you with you know the types of
type a notation for the JavaScript
language they don't provide extra
libraries for JavaScript so you still
need to use all these variety like
millions of them the libraries out there
some not very bad some are you know you
don't know they are about their
qualities like I mentioned before even a
trim string function like five lines is
a library you know you know used by lots
of frameworks you know it's very bad so
anyway so that's one thing I wish
typescript would do you know like
provide a set of you know standard
libraries as part of typescript so I
don't have to you know use all you know
random libraries out there so I can just
call my typescript press a button it
compiles to JavaScript then you know
then that is the JavaScript you use for
the web you know so that's about
typescript that's my my opinion so such
a hard okay so lots of comments so let
me go quickly over the comments then
answer some questions and maybe they'll
be it for today so are you going to okay
so hold on a second
so are you going to do not jazz tutorial
rest drove says actually I do have one
already let me show you actually just
such sorry not Jas I have like a very
simple one-page tutorial ok
and so not J's tutorial and this is
written like five years ago and okay so
that's so you you you know this is
written I'd 2013 mostly 2013 yeah five
years ago but I think most of them are
still valid because you know they don't
change you know I mean the I mean I'm
just covering the basics so the basics
doesn't change you know it's still valid
you could try to read my tutorial I'm
pretty sure there are a lot better this
is not something I've dived very deep
but if this is your first time it might
be a good tutorial for you
but there's another one at the bottom
which is not j/s tutorial by Ryan doll
he is the guy who created not GEOSS now
this is a video and I annotated with
code you know with code from his video
so you also you could try read this one
again this one you know is even older
like his video is in 2011 so this is
kind of like the beginning of types of
notches the advantage of studying this
tutorial is that you get the vantage
point of the the beginning intentions
and the purpose and goal of not j/s okay
so i still recommend it I mean even it's
pretty old I still recommend it as a
introduction you know this video is like
one hour okay so
it's a good introduction and and this
guy Ryan okay I need to turn on
JavaScript
okay javascript song it's refresh let's
try to play so anyway this guy Ryan Tao
is very interesting guy he's a
mathematician when before he began
before he started not yes he is a like a
post doc PhD student in math in some
very advanced you know some K Theory
chaos opera or something so he's a
mathematician so you know you know so he
he spent like 10 years you know yeah
basically more or less 10 years studying
math he's a mathematician and he got
bored with that and also you know it's
funny with the math you know you math in
the math field you know there are a lot
people fast motor the smarter than you
did I mean they are turn turns of
geniuses really you know I think I'm
smart but I go into the math you know
they are really you know a huge amount
of people you know they they are you
don't hear them because they are and the
other thing about math is is such a
beautiful subject so you have all these
you know Hermits you know they study
math so deep you know they state devote
their life to math but they are poor you
know they don't make money they you know
they you don't hear them you don't see
them and but programming you know you if
you study two years programming oh you
work at Google or something you make a
lot of money you know you drive fancy
cars
so anyway anyway so Ryan is doing PhD in
math right it's a poor guy you know and
but but the subject is so advanced you
know it really takes you you know five
10 years to just understand what just to
get the idea what what is it that he is
the
you know the math so anyways so he's a
very interesting guy and also expands
out becomes extremely capable as a
programmer so he become he works at
Google now
last I heard two years ago at least he
is working on AI project at Google so
anyway so there is another video by him
not as creator Ryan Dao software
complexity and Ryan down on history of
JavaScript I would recommend you you
read them or study them because he's a
very interesting guy so yeah it sees
that that yeah so I got a few links of
his videos this one are he on the
history history of JavaScript okay so
that's Ryan Ryan da very interesting guy
and the yeah he's pretty young to me
okay so American yesterday she was great
okay I'm what do you think about
typescript okay
so normal says a comma script SPECT was
probably written by committee companies
in their worst engineers to waste their
time writing yet me okay AC 0 and
improved syntax for JavaScript like
there's a plug for HTML sass yeah there
is you know back then ten years ago
there is the CoffeeScript you know
you've probably heard of you know so you
but it's kind of died you know very few
uses okay so before javascript 2015
which is a huge you know edition you
know kind of a entire new language so
before 2015
back then even back then even 2008 there
is a coffee script now CoffeeScript is
basically is a layer on top of
JavaScript no well it's kind of a
language for itself you know but it
compares to JavaScript so the idea of
CoffeeScript is that you know it creates
a new syntax that cleans you know get
rid of all the words in JavaScript you
know JavaScript has lots of problems so
you have now a new syntax CoffeeScript
that is kind of clean and it compares to
JavaScript so that that was very popular
JavaScript was hugely popular but today
is kind of its kind of almost
disappeared because javascript 2015 came
along and typescript came along you know
so in CoffeeScript kind of like
disappeared you know kind of just died
so besides CoffeeScript they are quite a
few other other projects that actually
yeah a lot that compares with JavaScript
so depending on what you mean okay so
for example there's a hacksaw let's see
let me go to my websites cocoa sorry
language for leaf raishin
for liberation of computer languages
this is a article I wrote about all kind
of new languages then you have fact so
there was CoffeeScript they start now
dot is a language created by Google
Google intense it will replace
JavaScript but nobody wants to you know
except you know the those start creators
so it kind of is still around you know
but it's not very popular so that that
is like the syntax in so in short in a
nutshell that is like Java syntax in
Java semantics okay it compares to
JavaScript but basically it's like Java
you know I don't like it at all but you
know back then so this is 2011 this is
before 2015 you know the ACMA script
2015 came up so everyone is trying to
fix javascript because it's really bad
you know
so Google created thought as one of the
you know the that's their answer but it
didn't really go far typescript is very
popular today
it's one of the like top five languages
because when when JavaScript becomes
large when you bea start to have like
thousands of lines you need type scripts
to help you but but of course you can
also you start I mean people have some
projects do that so they are quite a lot
and this ASM Dutch is kind of
complicated to explain and Julia and elm
Amy's kind of a JavaScript alternative
then hacks is also a JavaScript
alternative and in fact many of these
elixir is also a JavaScript alternative
so actually they are quite a lot in fact
I mean even I mean
many of these languages they actually a
pure script is also another JavaScript
alternative pure script is like Haskell
okay it's like Haskell for you know
physically the idea is a Haskell but it
compares to JavaScript so they are quite
a lot you know and in fact a lot
languages such as crucial and closure
script Oh camel and so closure you know
closure the list language they also have
a version called closure script which is
like closure syntax but compares to
JavaScript you know for the web then Oh
camera language which is a function
language like like Haskell okay
Oh camo and f-sharp they also have a
project I forgot what's the name yeah
something the book script bug script
okay
which is basically oak ammo but compares
to JavaScript so so they are you know
and also coal and coal and also have a
verge have a project that you write in
gold and but it compiles to JavaScript
so all these thing which are doing that
and if I mean so is this is actually
kind of movement you know people because
people really don't want JavaScript
because it's really very crummy you know
so they so now the new movement is face
down now that now there's another
movement is called this a AMS where was
it we just saw it before helix coming
here angry thing Oh a smj dot J's so so
JavaScript is moving into a direction
where it becomes the assembler you know
it becomes the assembly language where
all the other higher-level languages
compiles to JavaScript
in fact it so JavaScript
created this what's called ASM okay so
ASM da Jia Jia's it that is a subset of
JavaScript so a tiny subset the core of
JavaScript you know a tiny subset and in
this subset it's like assembly language
so very fast so all these other
languages they are trying to I mean
that's that's the vision okay so they
all can compile to ASM then ASM you know
it's like assembly language so it then
ASM you know compares to machine code
from the browser you know by the browser
so so in theory you know the this idea
this idea idea is that you know every
language can you know they compared each
other to JavaScript you know that that
Sun so that's that
so let's see
so vbscript I'm gonna skip some comments
because you know we kind of talking for
80 minutes
vbscript was a far more superior
language but Microsoft never released it
to the community to be standardized yeah
maybe I don't know but what vbscript
oh that's a visual basic like
alternative to JavaScript it never
survived I think like nobody use it uses
it so that kind of died I think so
everyone got on the hand bandwagon you
know we should be free yo
so meow cats so I am I going to write my
language I hope so I mean that's one of
my project I know I hope I can do before
I die you know I'm giving myself five
more years to be actually be able to
code you know I'm old so five more years
you know I don't know if I can do it so
I'm learning compact I've never wrote a
compiler yet so I'm trying to learn that
and you know so I hope to you know
because I have so many criticisms about
language design so it would be great if
I can and also has a great learning
experience to come up with my own
language you know and what I think is
the best language you know on the syntax
on the semantics or whatever you know so
I hope to do that I haven't been that's
my one might go but I haven't been
working on that for the past half a year
I really should so my god what is what
our JavaScript generators
okay JavaScript generators no they are
not like least Marcos it's kind of come
come
complicated maybe we go that into that
maybe next probably next time because
that's gonna be like one topic by itself
and and it's also fairly complicated
let's take a look quickly because I
don't even remember what it does exactly
yeah it's very complicated you know it's
very technically complicated the
JavaScript generators so I mean let me
never cover it cover it for one minute
basically from a technical point of view
a generator object is a object that
conforms to both the iterator and
iterable interfaces so that is the
technical meaning of generators okay
that that is the JavaScript technical
meaning now what does that mean so in
order to understand that you have to
understand iterator and iterable and
before you understand that you have to
understand what is the technical meaning
of JavaScript interface now remember we
are talking about technical meaning not
I mean for example like in many
languages when you see the word
generator you omit immediately have some
kind of thought you know you kind of
think what it is similar similarly for
the word interface or object you know
when you see the word interface you
think oh it's you know it's something
something but in JavaScript but you can
go one step further and go technical
definition you know in the language
JavaScript so you so it's not like that
you know so so anyway so so we cannot
not gonna go into that as today so maybe
next time because it's very advanced
so a generator appears to be a function
but generators function that can stop
Midway yeah that's a good actually
that's a good way to put it Thank You
Danielle so Danielle say is a generator
of years to be a function but a
generator is a function that can stop
Midway and then continue from where it
stops yes
yeah that's actually that's a good way
to put it yeah so great point
go back hell yeah so a generator
function
oh so Ryan mail Cass says Ryan Dow made
a video in 2018 with the ten things he
regretted about nod I'm glad he's still
around because he was gone for a while
oh wow I didn't know that I'm gonna
thank you mail I'm gonna check it out oh
yeah so this is great I'm gonna check it
out because I you know I yeah I admire I
admire his walk a very capable
programmer and CoffeeScript looks screen
I see them come in script - oh wow they
have CoffeeScript - this is a guy
Christian something who wrote a list
that compiles to Arial and to solve
chemistry problems that well what is
that
so okay so anything else I think maybe
it's a good time to call it the end for
the today's talk because it's 18 minutes
kind of like like you know people need
to go to pee I need to go to pee yeah
because we covered okay we talked about
JavaScript that's a great talk I think
you know I think I that's a good talk
about JavaScript so Danielle says
message retracted by the way what does
that happen mean does I mean you typed
something and like you hit delete so I
think that's it for today guys
seven watching so JavaScript so we
didn't get to goal and that's okay so
today is just focus on javascript so
thank you for guys for coming
meow send me a email okay let me know
your because I forgot your name is hard
to search you know so I did you are hard
to catch so thank you guys for coming
and I'll see you next time bye