Good morning, good evening. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show video
check, audio check. We are going to do
some coding on um unic code. Okay, so
let's let me show you my screen. If you
are wondering about my keyboards, this
is ultimate hacking keyboard 80 UHK.
So I talked about it online on my live
stream yesterday. Okay. So, uh and I
talked about keyboards like for many
years
frequently. Okay. So, but let's start to
do today's talk show. Uh let me show you
what I want to do. So, to do not that.
So, let's go to talk show. I'm using
Emacs of course the most advanced
powerful text editor. So, we want to do
unic code. Okay. Uh so what I'm going to
do today is just update my um my unic
code uh page. Okay. So you can go there.
So you can see this is uh unic code very
interesting because unic code contains
all possible symbols of human animals
writing system every symbol. Okay. So
the most dramatic is emoji. Of course,
emoji came up in the past about 20
years, but but that's a very small part
of it because for vast majority of
Unicode characters, you know, there are
there are uh right now I think 15,000s
of the characters 15,000 thousands of
them symbols, you know, all sort of
symbols you can possibly imagine in
human history. um back to like back to
four to 5,000 years ago. Uh that's the
beginning of written history. So the
oldest would be he uh the oldest I
believe would be he helioraph
the Egyptian thing. So let's go there
have a look.
uh Ethiopic
hiro hierro glide okay hard to pronounce
okay so we are going to do unic code
basically I'm going to just update my
website so you are just going to look at
my workflow with emac kind of boring
okay so if you are watching this offline
play at 1.5 speed if you are watching
this online here say hi so mostly the
boring stuff. Okay. So, what I want to
do is I want to so unic code. So, you
can see I have a page. If you go to my
Unicode homepage, uh Unicode search. Let
me let me demonstrate this. Okay. So,
let's uh magnify. Let's see if you can
see that.
So, if I magnify all the way, what do
you guys see?
Okay, you guys see almost the um
almost the uh
so you see you guys see up to you know
here so some part of it you don't see
unless I scroll up but anyway
so okay so let's go back so unic code so
if If I can again type water w a t e r
uh it will update you'll find all unic
characters whose name contain whatever
you typed. Okay. Uh so water for
example. Then you can look at their
name. So you know each unicode got a
name and you can show their ID which is
also known as code point. Each unic code
character has a ID which is a integer.
Okay. Uh so for example you go down you
got that uh you got water closet. Water
closet that's the British means
word for toilet bathroom. In USA you
call it bathroom or restroom.
So and water polo. So anyway so you know
you can so fantastic unicode search.
Okay. So, it's on kali.info
x ah unic code search. You can find it
if you just search for that unic code
search. Okay. Click that it and http no
s. Okay. If it tells you, oh, there's a
nonsecure
that is scale tactics. As long as you
don't send, you know, you don't give you
don't you don't uh the website does not
require a credit card, it's okay. Okay.
So that's my unic code search and you
can also show so name ID and ID can be
showing hexadimal which is more common.
Okay. So you can see hexadimal
ID name and you can also show the UTF uh
16 bytes.
So those are UTF 16
bytes. That's a technical information
for those of you programmers.
Hello informaticist human animals. Oh,
you are part of the Darwin code. That is
correct. [laughter]
You hate Darwin. You hate codes. So are
Christians. In fact, Christians and also
the you know the lots of Mormons uh
Buddhism, the Islamic is Islam, the Ju
Judaism, they are all
more considered as cults. If you want to
compare atheism versus the monotheist
uh you know the one god religions
especially the one god religions
uh I've done a terminal application that
makes so looking images out of pure unic
code plus color pretty versatile stuff
now what is 6o
makes so looking images now what is 6o
is some kind of new
uh zoomer thing
uh hieroglyphs.
Okay. I don't know what you're saying.
Okay. So, anyway, so
you know code. Yeah. So, I'm I was going
I was demonstrating this. Okay. This
this is a water buffalo. Fantastic.
Because it looks like the glue. You can
use this to represent Emacs. Okay. Uh so
for example, let me show you. So you go
down unic code block.
So you can see there's a representation.
Uh let's see let's let's get rid of that
annoying.
So you see you got emacs and this is
water buffalo. Okay they they you know
so you can see they are using different
emoji. So one is from Microsoft font,
one is from uh Google's font. So
Google's font looks more like the GNU.
So we were looking at Google's font
anyway.
So that's enough demonstration. So look,
let's see. Yeah, the water buffalo that
font is from Google Notto, which is open
source. Okay. And this one you are
seeing here is from Microsoft, which is
nasty.
Okay. Well, since I talked about that
and then let me show you how nasty.
Okay. Yeah. I haven't talked about this.
Um, so you go to the miscellaneous
index. Okay. So, then you you know the
miscellaneous articles about Unico. Uh,
some are technical, some are, you know,
like Unicode smileys, some are fun.
Uh, and uh, for example, let me show you
some random fun ones. Japanese Unicode
text art. These these are were known as
ASI art because they were using
characters to create images and back
then 30 years ago before the birth of
Unicode. So in the 1980s and 1990s this
is very popular called ASI art as SI
pronounced ASI. Why is it called ASI?
because ASI was the standard for the
characters American computing something
character standard okay uh okay so we
you know so
okay so we mentioned that ASKI so why
don't we go there as well so let me let
me digress one by one we'll cover it
everything okay uh so let's go back here
so unic code for programmers Let's open
that. Okay, we we talked about ASI. So
we I need to cover ASI
uh you ASKI characters. Okay, so ASI
stand for
uh ASI. ASI
are basically the characters you see on
your keyboard. Okay. And they stand for
American
Standard Code for information
interchange
created in 1960s. So this is before Uni
code. So with ASI you only have 128
characters. You cannot have math
symbols, summation, arrow or copyright
sign or star or or you know or whatever
you know um punctuation, paragraph sign,
dagger, double dagger, bullet. You
cannot have any of these. Okay? You
cannot have you know pound sign, yen
sign, euro sign. Well, euro wasn't
invented yet the euro dollar.
So with ASI which which is early days
1960s you don't have any of those. So
ASI so for from so in 1970s 1980s people
create art out of the characters like
these okay they they are called asy art.
Now you see
asci
III art. You see I'm talking about this
because you know you guys rumors may not
know because because this was like so
well known like everyone know what it
what it is. Okay, you see asie fish
there's a collection on the news group
there are there are collections okay so
these are known as aski art but I'm
saying that you guys may not know like
you guys you know like you guys under 20
or you know you might heard of it you
might sing some of it uh but mostly you
haven't seen it because this is part of
history this most of these happened in
1970s
80s 90s Okay.
In year 2000s, you you started to not to
see them. Okay. So anyway, this so
that's when you know in the '9s that's
what when I was very active you know
when was younger you know I participate.
So you know so there's ASI art there's a
huge amount of collections uh you guys
may not see
uh or sort of okay so you see all all
these are asy art. Now, but since the
Unicode got invented, people started to
use Unicode. So there's now so there is
an interesting question. Do you call
this ASKI art or do you call them
unicode art? Because if you say as art,
it's not correct because these are not
asy characters. You see this dot? This
this dot is a bullet, you know. Uh this
star, you see that star? You see this W
thing? Those are Greek or whatever. Uh
you see this G gamma sign in Japanese
letter. Those are not ASI characters. So
it would be technically incorrect to say
these are asy.
On the other hand, when you if you call
them as art, people recognize it right
away, understand what it is because
that's what you know using text to to
create to form images. That's what ASI
art meant.
You know, the gist of ASI art is not
about the ASI character set, but it's
rather about using characters to form
images.
So when you call this asy art, it's like
fitting but technically incorrect. So
alternatively you might call them uni
code art
which is more technically correct
because you are using uni code to form
images but you know but like people
haven't heard of unic code art you know
it could be mean something else you
know. So anyway, so these are ASI art.
Okay. And these are smileys. Smileys
formed out of Unicode. Now what is a
smiley? Again you zuma's rumor
generation may not know. So let me
explain.
Smileys are the forefather of emoji.
Okay. So in the 1980s, in the 1990s,
we don't have emoji was not invented
yet. emoji was invented even uh starting
like in unic code 2008 something like
that 2008 2006 okay so there is no emoji
okay so let let me go that you know so
let's open that
so these are emoji right but there there
was no emoji back then not in 1980s not
in 1990s
so what people do is that people created
uh this kind of smileys. It began with
this.
Okay. With that uh one.
Let's see. Can you see that? It began
with that. That's that's you know. So
then you have variations like um
uh like oh this is like shocking
uh
you know things like that. Then you you
know so
smileys those are called smileys when
when they were created there's a
controversy
because in the 1990s
uh among the programmers some believe
you should not resort to this kind of
ingrammatical fancy [ __ ] You you know
these are teenage crap. You shouldn't
use it when you write communicate with
your friends or in argument like with
you guys you know you should you know
it's always possible to express emotion
in English itself you know that's a big
controversy you know that people talk
about like like like what you guys talk
about today you know so so this is in
the 90s there's a debate over whether
you should have smileys like most people
refuse
Typically that's a situation when when
whenever you have new technology the
older generation typically refuse it.
Okay. So when Smiley were created you
know you can let's let's look up
Wikipedia. Okay. So
uh let's put the font back to their
original size and uh magnify. 1 2 3 4 5
6 7 8. Okay. Now uh so what is this?
This is today's talk show and let's add
a section
uh about
Wikipedia. Let's go to Wikipedia.
Smileys. Press press
W for Wikipedia.
Okay. So, the history of smileys. Let's
see. So it says 1960s but that's
actually not I mean that may be
technically correct but it's not true. I
mean basically smiley began to became
popular
you know average people started to use
them understand what they are is in um
let's see in um
does it say somewhere okay like
Wikipedia since 1950s something
something began uh two dots is smile uh
more yellow and black design appeared in
1960 and 70s okay The smiley comp
company founded by Franklin Luadi
claimed to hold the rights to a version
of the smiley face over 100 countries.
Okay, what a whatever blob. That's not
the pop history. Okay, that's like
technical history. But let me tell you
when does it begin. Okay, anyway. So we
we need to you see these are not really
smileys, you know. I mean we are talking
about the the asy characters okay that
is the um kind of like this face this
phase began in 19607s
I think
smiley company [ __ ] smiley and object
objective god Wikipedia is like a one
mouthful of verbose [ __ ] verbosity [ __ ]
like if you ask guac or any AI like
history of Smitey, they will tell you
right away. They will point to the ASI
character because that is the real like
the real heart of the Smiley history. I
mean the Wikipedia version is like
academic mumbo jumbo you know here.
Okay. Here. So 1982. Okay. That is
basically you know smileys basically
began life on the internet. Okay. In 19
1982 kind of. Okay. So that is the real
emoticon and emoji. Okay. So so emoji
there's you know before emoji there is
smiley. Smiley is there first. Then
Smiley evolved into emoticon
which is when when some website they
started to change the smiley from text
into a little picture. Okay, that's
emoticon actually they kind of the the
mean the same. Okay, that mean depending
on who you ask people think they are of
them as the same thing. Okay. Smiley,
then emoic. Okay. Then emoji came about
like 2008 something. Okay. So that's
kind of the sequential history. Uh so
that so I mean so I was just random
talking about smiley. Uh so where did we
uh began to talk about it here? Okay.
Unicose smileys. Interesting you know.
So this is unic smileys not just asky
like a upgrade
like the matrix you know an upgrade.
Okay I talked for 20 minutes already and
we haven't started to do what I wanted
to do. So let me read the comments and
let's go back to I'm going to do what I
have to do about Unicode uh uh 2023
update.
ASI images that looks like actual images
rather than ASI art is what I meant. Oh
okay. So that's the so there are two
type of ASI art. Okay. There are two
types. One is like um one is like this.
This is called there's a name this is
called bitmapped. Okay. Uh
I think there's a specific name I mean.
So but anyway there are two main type.
One type is just um
creative. For example, this fish, you
know, you have to let's see if we can
It's It doesn't It's so small. What?
Uh let's see.
Yeah. Okay. So, one type is using
characters. Each character, which
character you choose is very important.
You create a image out of characters.
Okay. That's one type of very uh this
requires high creativity and usually a
manual process.
Now the other type of asy art which is
more silly is this kind of like bit map.
This is often done by computer. Computer
can generate it like you know you give
it a photo it can turn it into asy art.
So it based on the shade of the
character
you know. So so in general there are
there are like these two types of asy
art. Uh you know I I really I don't like
this you know this this this type is not
creative you know it's u not so good. So
anyway then there is also font. Okay. So
for example this font is also kind of
boring. Uh
okay. So so that's you know this. So
this is creative version this is not
what and this you know this one is just
um kind of bitmapped version okay as art
okay so there are two major types
so let's see uh ASI images that looks
like actual images rather than asky art
is what I meant okay so uh Iro gifs okay
I think that's
something uh terminal application oh
okay that's What you mean?
You are the coolest ever. You should be
on fish tank society. Needs more skis.
Skizo.
Now, what is fish tank society? Is that
some kind of like high IQ?
Fish Tank Society. Let's see. Fish Tank.
What's the deal with Fish Tank Live?
Fishtank Live is an interactive re
reality TVesque
live stream show similar to Big Brother
created by controversial comedian Sam
Hyde. Okay.
Well, Sam Hyde Sam Hyde is a interesting
guy but he's you know I'm out I'm you
know we are not in the same group
because he's white guy. Most of his
jokes is within the white man white
American culture.
Uh so
and you know so often times it involves
Christianity and what what you know what
whatever white men's culture which I'm
not exactly so I so often times I don't
understand it you know it takes more
time for me to like understand or so
anyway
so fish tank what is a fish tank I don't
know what it what is Okay.
So, let's see.
Use a seven co eight moon. I mean, is an
asy art just a euphemism at this point?
And hasn't that been the case forever?
Euphemism.
Why? What do you mean? Why is it? What?
I mean, what euphemism stand for? What?
They've always used unic code. Never
mind. What I said only makes sense.
Modern context. Look up fish tank. Uh,
okay. Yeah. So, but fish tank is not
turning up. Um,
so is that about So is this about about
this Sam Hyde guy?
You know, I don't really like his jokes.
I mean, okay. I mean, well, because
he's, you know, is uh because he's his
his jokes, his things is like very
particular to the white man culture,
but I'm not, you know, so I don't I
don't uh like half of the time I don't I
don't understand it. I don't get it.
So, uh fish tank fish tank also known as
fishtank.live Live is an interactive
reality game show created by Sam Hyde
and Jet Neptune.
During its run, Fish Tank is streamed
online 24/7
while allowing viewers to interact with
contestant and uh interesting. So when
when was this?
In January 2025,
second round of investment opened. Okay.
So, it looks like it's ongoing, huh? So,
is this what you guys talking about?
White and Asian are the same.
[laughter]
Not exactly. Not exactly.
Um,
they torture the contestants and they
will torture you. Okay, that was a dumb
point. I was just speaking broadly about
text. Okay. Anyway, so let's um
Okay, so I wanted to work on my unic
code. So, let me tell you guys what I
need to work on. So, if you go to my
Unicode blog, uh, go to miscellaneous
index, then there is Unicode history.
There's uh uh by the way did I mention
oh there's a Microsoft I forgot I wanted
to mention I forgot so let's mention
them there's a Microsoft nasty
you see oh this is emoji politics why
don't I talk about it more so let me
talk about all of them
uh okay so emoji politics okay so first
so you you guys probably know emoji is
very controversial And emoji became what
the white man would say weaponized thing
in American western society. Western
society basically
the heart of it is USA because the mega
rich they wanted to do something they
wanted to do war and stuff. Okay. And
they need to suppress normal people
average citizens voice. Therefore there
come this gender thing. So this is the
social justice warrior movement
beginning around 2016
SJW you know including part of it is
feminism,
gay, LGBT, trans uh you know and you
know gender thing gender fluid what
whatever you know so this is you know
so-called weaponized so so part of you
know and BLM you know BLM
And part of it is the um so the the the
and of course then suppression of white
men, suppression of average normal guy,
promoting you know uh lesbian, gay and
uh trans sex and uh
you know and and kicking Christianity
and promoting Islam for for some reason
and you know so that's a very dark
period in USA and it's like pretty bad
today. I mean that era, social justice
warrior era kind of died. But now we got
new nasty. Okay. Very bad. Um
collapse of USA, you know, new nasty
since since Trump last year. Anyway, so
this this this so so so during this
movement they have this, you know,
movement and then and and emoji became
uh part of it. Okay. So
very funny. So emoji, you know, happy,
you know, people like it usually. Oh
yeah. So this is a meme. Okay. So I'm
using emo, you know, I'm creating a meme
out of Unicode. So emoji happy. Oh yeah,
great. Then gender emoji. Oh, that's
like level up, you know.
Then emoji with skin color. So they
added they created that around Unicode
created this skin color thing around um
I don't know what year maybe 2015 around
there okay uh yeah we can we can
actually look up you know we can ask gu
when did uh emoji with skin color was
created okay so that's a image version
do we have a live version okay so you
you can see they are using different
fonts you see. So let's ask guac
when was emoji with skin color intro
used. Okay. Gawk AI will help you
resolve questions about humanity.
Am I alive? Are you guys enjoying the
show? How many people watching? Seven.
The poverty of my show. So, if you are
here, say hi. Okay.
Comments and questions. So, emoji. Let's
see. What does it say? What does it say?
Emoji with skin color options, more
precisely, skin tone modifiers, were
introduced in 2015.
I was spot on
2015.
So, you know, so gender, you got gender
emoji and then emoji with skin color. Oh
my god. Then then you got then upgrade.
You got genderless fantasy emoji. You
see these characters? You see this one
on the left is a mermaid. Okay. On the
right is genie. Very interesting
characters. Okay.
Uh God cuz I I can talk about them these
two characters for an hour. You see
mermaid,
you know, like what what do you what's
your picture of mermaid? For thousands
of years, mermaid is meant, you know,
it's it's a law. It's a mythology
in western culture. It's uh from the
Greeks 2,000 3,000 years ago. Okay.
mythology of the mermaid came from the
history of mermaid came from part of it
is northern Europe but you can it can
trace back to the um sirens of Greek
mythology 200 or 3,000 years ago okay
and typically when you picture mermaid
in western society it's as a western
society thing okay it is a beautiful
girl okay that's what mermaid is a
beautiful girl with a fish is bottom.
Okay, it's a mermaid
now. But look look at the the way they
pictured the mermaid. Okay, on on this
one, this this font is particular this
font is from Apple. Okay, we'll talk
about that. There's so much to talk
about this in this detail. Okay, so you
can see so you can see kind of different
um font by different corporation how
they try to uh use uh represent it.
Okay.
So you can see also uh here. Okay. So
this is this is Microsoft. This is
Windows. Okay.
Uh so so Mermaid it's a pretty girl.
Okay. Pretty white girl. Okay. Not
black, not whatever. It's a it's a
pretty white girl
from white man white men's mythology
Europe. And you know the uh Yeah.
And this genie genie is a mythological
creature from Middle East from like you
can uh mostly you hear it from Arabian
Knights. Okay. [snorts]
And it's a it's you know it's you know
like in America we think of it genie is
like from the Disney movie you know like
this funny blue character likable
guy. But that's not what genie is from
the Arabic or p person per persian you
know in that region middle east I don't
know much about but I read some of it
it's you know the genie character the
mythology is like it's some kind of
monster okay sometimes monster sometimes
not you know not bad okay so it's kind
of a monster okay it's it doesn't look
like
a you know nice human um may not okay
there are different type of genie but
then so but now look so the way they
render it is like um this okay so
[laughter]
so basically they are rendering it like
a trans like the the the white man's
perception of so-called trans in America
in the past in in this current 10 years
okay
so it [ __ ] it abused It abused the
Arabic Middle East culture.
The mermaid abused the white man's
culture. Both of them are not authentic.
They they they it's a lie. Okay? It's a
lie. What you know, they tell you
they're trying to represent what they
are. Okay? So this is part of the
so-called weaponization the movement of
the social justice warriors from the USA
deep state in the past 10 years. Okay.
So that's uh that's you know so then
then so okay so here what you are seeing
here that's from Apple. So these are
Apple's font. Okay.
Over here that's the that's the
Microsoft Windows font before 200
Windows 10. Okay. Windows 10. So Windows
emoji font before Windows 11 is the best
actually. So you can see they represent
you can see they represent mermaid. So
you can see it's a girl and uh you know
it just you know they they don't they
don't try to like
create a message out of it. You know
mermaid is you know a girl. It looks
like a girl and this genie is like you
know kind of look like a monster. Okay
they don't try to
put a story you know like press you know
force something down your throat. Okay.
This is Microsoft 10 Windows emoji
one was the best. Okay. Now you go on
then here. So this uh this is Twitter.
Okay. Twitter. Twitter.
This is Twitter in uh what year is this?
Uh okay. So this is um
year 2024. Okay. Twitter Twitter's emoji
also
changed over the years but because you
know
speaking of Twitter you must know what
the important thing you must know is
that there is before Ella Musk and after
Elam Musk okay before Ella Musk
is before 2023
that's run by Jack Dorsey a scum a
extreme scum Jack Dorsey Okay. After
then after 2023 it's run by Ella Musk.
Okay. Which is
I think he's mostly um he's you know
good. Okay. I would say he's mostly
good. Okay.
So anyway, so I don't know uh about
Twitter's font too much but anyway this
is a version. This is this is a font
used by Twitter in 2024 September. Okay.
Now, now observe how they represent
mermaid and genie. Okay. Now, here here
what you see here is the current
Microsoft Windows 11 font. So this
mermaid they it's like you know it's
basically a trans you know so-called the
the American version the
imagination of like trans
[laughter]
men in women's body. Okay that's what
looks like. Okay let's magnify. And this
genie you see they made this genie is
like also
kind of like a like nobody like like the
shapeless nothing. Okay. It's not it
doesn't look doesn't look like a
monster. It doesn't look like anything.
It's you know again it looks like a
trans. That's part of the queer. You
know the the proper word is queer thing.
You know they want to send the message
queer. Okay. Anyway, so that's the
emoji. That's the um that's the politics
in Unico.
Okay, that's one article. Then uh this
then the other article the um okay this
one is interesting again. So we got the
pistol history in Unicode. You see in
Unicode you got the character the
character is named pistol. Okay. Which
means a a handgun.
So,
so before so in 2023 everyone render it
as a pistol except well except you know
Google and Microsoft well Google made
Google you know Google's font make it
made it into a kind of a old pistol
and Microsoft made it into a ray gun
like a future ray gun you know science
fiction but everyone else is shows shows
it as a pistol but starting is in 2016
Apple changed their pistol emoji into a
water gun. So this is year 2016. This is
what I would say the beginning of the
social justice war year movement. Okay.
Lasted for 10 years. it I would say it
died in 20 uh 24 or 2025.
It's still kind of lingering. Okay. So
anyway, so Apple made that change. Apple
began it. Then in 2018 it followed by uh
basically everyone everyone changed it
back change it to water gun. Okay. But
in 2024,
Twitter, now known as X, under Ela
Musk's leadership, he
explicitly
put it change it back to a handgun.
Okay. He like he actually promoted so
much. I mean he he explicitly
um led this movement you know anti- the
social justice warrior scums
Hen get you know so he he made a change
2024 ele by Elam Musk okay
so so here you have the history of emoji
on the on one of the character handgun
okay then you can see here's Elamus post
nerfing of the gun emoji matches rise of
the walk work walk
virus as a courtet is equating fake home
with real harm. So he's saying, you
know, so why do they um
change the uh pistol into a water
pistol? According to these people, this
deep state promotion, they they say
that's because when you have a symbol
that that represents a gun, it promotes
violence.
So they want to,
you know, basically you call that
censorship. They want they don't want
that. They want to censor it. They want
to censor it so you don't show uh
weapons, you know. So they made it into
a water gun like nullify the the violent
image of a a gun. They say, you know,
this is important. This will help reduce
violence. Okay. Anyway, and Elmas says
no. That's like [ __ ] which is very
good. Elmas is correct. Okay.
Because because these scums, this this
you know this social justice warrior
movement also known as work
um also known as um like the democratic
party. Okay.
In the past uh 10 years. Okay. Anyway,
so the so so there's this history. This
is part of history. Okay. Now remember
the important. Okay. Well, it's it's
just emoji, right? But emoji is part of
the unic code. Unicode is part of the h
human animals writing system. Okay. So
there is this little uh history going
on. Okay. In human history.
Then there is uh there's more. So let me
I already talked for too long. So let me
just um
uh
well okay. So this one Microsoft in 2000
uh Microsoft in Windows 11 what year is
this? Let's see. Uh they made huge
changes to their emoji so that
everything looks [ __ ] much worse. Okay.
They they went all
social justice war. Okay. So what year
is this? What year did this happen? So I
um
happened in 2021. Okay. So Microsoft
made this change in 2021 to their emoji
font. Uh Microsoft emoji font is called
circle UI emoji. Okay. So that's so the
change happened in happened in version
1.33.
That's 2021 in Windows 11. Okay. So they
made that change. They they overhauled
all their emoji characters. So, so you
can compare. So, for example, why is it
bad? For example, here is Windows 10.
Here is Windows 11. So, they made the
fingers to become fat fingers, you know,
kind of like fat.
The male they made it to look like a
trans. Okay. woman, they made it into
like this trans, you know, not not man,
not woman, you know, that that's that's
what they made it to be, you know. So,
every every character is basically just
like trans. You can't tell what exactly
what they are, you know, like queer is
the word. Okay. So, and then no more
smileys. They made it into this like
this like on drugs like very kind of
offensive like you know if you can see
them. So this is Windows 10. Okay. So
this uh Windows 10 but in Windows 11 can
you see the difference?
So Windows 10 which I like them very
much. But in Windows 11, they become
this like
it's like it's like you know these
characters on drugs like and
very annoying. Okay. And also most of
the things don't look like you can't
tell what they what things they are
anymore. So for example um for example
this this this is a tumbler glass.
You know what? Like what? Can you tell
that you does does this look like a
tumbler glass to you? No. So this is
part of Windows 11, you know. Coffee uh
coffee becomes like a [ __ ] hole, you
know. So can I uh it would be good if I
can show you Windows uh tense, you know,
like coffee for example. I'm using the
font you are seeing here is uh Google.
So um so you can you can see coffee. So
let's go to coffee. Okay.
So all these font are from Google.
So you can see that's coffee. But look
at the Microsoft Windows 11 below. It
looks like [ __ ]
This is T. And look at the Microsoft
Windows 11 version below. And T part in
and in Microsoft Windows 11, they become
this red, you know, like less
recognizable.
Okay.
And the ice cube, you see Google
rendered it looks, you know, ice cube.
Then in Windows 11, it looks like this
kind of toy or whatever. It's hard to
tell what it is. Okay. So, there are
lots of these examples. In Windows 11,
they made it bad. But in Windows 10,
it's very good. Okay. So, so what so
what I'm saying is that one of the uh
judgment criteria of quality of emoji is
whether people can recognize
what it is showing. Okay. So if you if
people can tell right away what it is
that's good. If they cannot then it's
usually not good. Okay. So that's one
judgment of emoji. So so Windows they
made it uh Windows 11 like look at for
for example this one. This is a turn
turn you know the the the the the
thing in your mouth.
You know you can't you can't tell what
the [ __ ] it is anymore. So that's very
bad. Okay. I think so I I talked for
50 minutes. Okay.
Uh
I'm thinking emoji may be good for
password. Been thinking about using
them. I would not recommend it. Okay.
Because
when you do that, you might, you know,
it it's fun, you know, but and it's
cryptic. It helps you hide the password.
You know, other people wouldn't know.
But but after a while, you might forgot.
Then it become hell because emoji you
got, you know, you got the issue of
typing it. It's not normal. Uh so I
wouldn't recommend emoji. Just use
English words. You know, you can you can
have long ones. So, I wouldn't recommend
emoji or password.
What emoji design are you most fond of?
Do you mean which emoji character?
Uh, do I have like the most fond of
emoji character?
Um
uh well
let's see
let's see if I have
yeah so I I got this um
but you know so right now they are
rendered in Emacs using Microsoft emoji
font so that really offensive I don't
like them but you know you see I have
this set of emoji so Microsoft emoji
have two versions One is colored, one is
not colored. So you are looking at uh
the not colored version. Okay. So this
is the Windows 11 version.
So again to clarify,
Windows 10,
you know, there's Windows 10 uh emoji.
Uh again, two versions, colored and not
colored. Okay. Windows 11 they upgraded
you know again they are very different
from Windows 10. Okay al also colored
and not colored. [snorts] Also
if you use Google notto font also
there's a color version and uncolor
version. Same thing with Apple um
for Apple emoji. I forgot but you know
but you can look at um you know because
I have like so much blog about them. So
just search for
font
and uh
how to install font unic code uh unic
code text font art
um emac emac font so what I want to do
is we want to go to let's go to CSS font
family okay
uh you want to go to
common web font okay then you can see
standard emoji fonts, circle UI emoji,
Apple color emoji, not color emoji.
Okay. Now there is also a uncolored
version for each one of them. Okay.
Okay. So anyway, so so I used to like so
these characters I like but I now I
don't like them because it really
heavily depends on what font you um
you know what font is used for it.
Uh but I like um well anyway.
Okay. So I think uh so let's see. I'm
trying to be rude but I'm wondering
considering you are an experienced
programmer. I'm wondering why you still
use Windows. Do you just prefer it or
are you so for your constraint
constraints keeping you? Well that's a
hugely frequently asked question like
everyone ask it every every two or three
months. I answered it a thousand times,
you know, because why you use Windows
for example? And to answer your question
simply, if you are a game dev, you got
to do it on Windows because vast
majority game, you know, Windows is the
home of gaming industry.
Yeah, you could do it on Linux, you
could do it on the Mac, you could some
people play on Linux, some people on
Mac, but vast majority they play game on
Windows machine. Okay. and and and and
you the best fitting uh develop you know
is what to uh develop them on Windows
using Microsoft technology Microsoft dev
tools because you you you're going to
use the Windows technology I mean the
game technology like how they call them
you know the win well I don't I don't
develop games so I don't really know the
you know it's like the Windows uh
version of you can you can find them If
you just look at look up the you know
like the [snorts] graphics card stuff.
So let's see you know 3D mic. Yes
Microsoft 3D something they they have
you know they call it um
adjust setting with preview setting
settings. Uh it's very annoying because
because um yeah direct 3D you know so so
on Windows you have direct 3D and I
think there's newer technology but basic
but basically if you do game dev you
need to be on Windows like you need to
okay
but then your question you know true but
with advant of proton most solely window
games look excellent on Linux. That's
like idiots, okay? I mean I don't mean
you but but you you you think about this
okay like you you go to you you know you
look at let's say you are let's uh let's
say in movie industry you know I I don't
know movies I don't have movies you know
do you you are not director you are not
a producer I'm not a director I'm not a
producer I don't know anything about
movies right but it's like you go you go
to the movies industry you know you ask
them why don't you uh do this in in in
that way because it's also possible, you
know, it's just silly.
The the window in industry, you know,
the gaming industry, the billions of
dollars or the banking industry or the
chemistry industry, the material science
or the rocket industry, you know,
whatever industry, the oil industry, you
are just thinking, oh, but why don't you
work on this new new system? You I think
ideally it's better. I mean, it's
compatible, pretty good these days.
>> [laughter]
>> you you you know you're going you're
going to tell the banking industry why
don't you switch to the new system
system it's pretty good and pretty
compatible with the old way it's silly
like it's it's so like extreme out of
like idiotic.
So again back to the question
if you're going to do games if you you
know don't like don't tell me what you
know like can you can you go to go you
know go to the big game corporations
like what's what's some of the name um
you know can you like do you think it's
possible if you go tell tell them like
can you guys do dev on Windows what I
mean on Linux why why are you guys not
to dev on on on uh Linux it's pretty
good but on it's getting pretty good you
know it's like stupid thing to say
so in a in a similar way um that's you
know that's that's that's what you're
asking you know that's so why why am I
um not on Linux so besides that you know
there's many questions on Linux you know
like I didn't money, you know, on I need
a machine. I go out, I can spend two
$300. I can buy a machine and work on
right away. Not Linux,
you know. Let's say I I don't have
money. I Let's say I got $500. I I need
a computer, you know, I need to, you
know, I need a computer to work on. I go
to Walmart. $500. I get a PC. I can I
have a machine. I can work on Emacs or
whatever right away. Not on Linux.
Linux. Well, that depends. Are you gonna
do you know about Linux? Uh like do you
know about like file systems? Do you
know about formatting file systems like
hard disk partition? Do you have
experience with that? And and which
Linux do should you do? Do you know what
what is the meaning of Linux DRO
and do and which machine you buy? Maybe
if you install Linux, the graphics card
won't work. The Wi-Fi won't work. Like
does that make sense to you? Do I make
sense? $500 anyone you can go to a
store, buy a machine, and have, you
know, have a computer, you can browse
the internet. That's Windows. Or if you
have money, you can also buy a Mac. But
on Linux, well, then you first of all,
you can't, you know, you go to a shop,
they don't have like Linux installed on
it. Then you got to maybe ask your
friends, you know, you got to go which
friend where can I ask people about uh
about buying a machine with the Linux?
Can I trust them? Like how do I where do
I buy a machine with the Linux? And what
is the Linux?
[laughter] Do you know what I'm saying?
lots of problems. Okay.
So, and besides so different, you know,
so if you are a dev, there's so many uh
so many details you can look into. on
Linux. It's good if you you know if you
are a programmer usually it's good if
you work on Linux especially if you work
on open source projects like webdev
using python using uh you know uh emacs
for example or or whatever goland
but there's so many other situations you
just you just can't and also you don't
have time not like when you are younger
you have time to look at oh let's do
Linux Let's you know let's argue about
distro let's you know which window in
system you use I prefer this way you
know you you going to argue with your
friends you have time you know a lot of
other people I don't have time I got
like five years 10 year 10 more years to
go in my life I got to study math I'm
not going to spend time like which is
the latest dro what what's their drama
uh which trend started what drama with
what Richard Stman what what did they
say,
do you get it? Like you guys are young
people, right? Do you get what I'm
saying? Why why why are not why are you
not using Linux? you know so so so
idiotic a question
and I haven't get to my main point and
my main point is that it
my my experience in the past 30 years is
that the Linux Mac and uh Windows they
turns out stayed the same situation in
the past 30 years okay if you want the
best design that's a Mac okay you just
go buy a Apple stuff, but the price you
have to pay, you're going to pay twice
as expensive or three times more. Okay?
Whatever you can get for $500. If you
wanted Mac, you have to pay three times
more. Even for like the same mouse, if
it's for Apple, you have to pay three
times more. Like just everything. Okay?
But it but Apple is truly in the 1990s
in the 2000s and I would say still today
between Windows Mac
and uh Linux Mac is still the best
design the most easy to use the best
design. Okay, that's Mac. But you got
some problem. The first problem is like
you got to be you got to have money.
Okay, that's Mac. advantage and
disadvantage and many things programs is
not available on the Mac such as like
second life like anyway
Windows Windows is like the situation
it's like cheapest almost free like
every computer you buy you just got
Windows and it's usable it sucks it
sucks donkey ass in every way it's like
the most stupid why why can't you you
know when you want to set something. Oh,
but you have to go this way and you know
not very good design. Okay, but it's
just like usable. It's you know you can
you can you can just use it just like
stop complaining. You can just use it.
Okay. And it's almost like basically
it's like free Windows and every
software they will be available on
Windows first because on Windows you got
most people users. Okay. But meanwhile
also every virus every every like nasty
virus they will be on Windows too
because that's the most people they will
attack window first so you got you know
these kind of problems almost free easy
to use I mean kind of okay you can use
it you can you know and but you may have
virus problems then you got Microsoft
sneiffing looking into your pants you
know that's Microsoft okay now The Linux
the third option Linux
that's for you guys the idiot nerds
first of all you you you have to spend
like two three years to understand you
have to be a nerd if you are not a nerd
you don't know what's a bit what's a
like a [ __ ] pointer what the [ __ ] you
don't know what is a C what's the
difference of C++ and C you don't know
what the [ __ ] you don't know you can't
you use Linux okay first of all you you
need to have like two three years of the
Linux
uh the bit did
then you know you don't then you even
know know what is a Linux then you have
to spend a year two year three years
argue with your friend which dro
whatever what what is the advantage of
open source versus nonopensource
propaganda you got to fight you know
drama then you got a bit dling about the
this partition which one is the best
file system oh but there's a new one but
that guy say something that the [ __ ]
Linux [ __ ] Okay, then you got to
the guy which shell is the best shell,
you know, like the bash z shell, you
know, thousand others. So if you are
that type of people, young people and if
you're a nerd and if you happen to be in
a computer department, you know, that's
your thing, then Linux is your best
choice.
Then the Linux idiot idiots, you know,
that shoots you. You'll say it's open
source. It's freedom. It's I have the
right. Look at the source code. You
know, [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] Microsoft. They,
you know, they they they sniff. They
they they you know, they look at what
you you you do on your computer. [ __ ]
Apple. They just want money. So I have
the freedom to [ __ ] Linux. [ __ ] it. Do
you guys understand?
You know, you guys are young people,
Linux fanatics. I can see that, you
know, but you but you got to understand,
you know, what
you know, the the world is like fairly
complicated. It's not just like this,
you know, you know.
So, sorry for my ranch, you know.
My
this is my regular rant. Okay. Since you
asked a frequently asked question, I
started to spontane spontaneously rant
on this which I ran rant about almost
like every every three four month
like every time then people started to
ask me it it'll happen like by by next
month someone will ask me so how come
you are on Windows that's that's strange
why are you [laughter]
it happen again every every two months
also.
So, sorry for my rant. Uh, of course, I
don't mean I you know I don't know who
you are. I don't uh attack you at all or
whatever. And uh I don't add anyone on
Discord, okay? I'm I'm an old guy, guys.
Okay, you guys you guys got to know I'm
kind of old guy, you know? I've been
blogging for 30 years. So you guys may
know who I am. You guys watch my live
stream. I don't know who you guys are.
And especially you guys, you know, an
like everyone is is a non name like
how do I know who you are? Like I don't
know who you are.
Okay, that's it. I think that's it. Um,
so that's like 1 hour. We talked for 1
hour and I was going to so I was going
to to work on
update my page unic code. So this page
is unic code 15 in 2022
and there is a new version in 2023 and
also another in 2024 and 2025.
So there are three uh new versions of
Unicode. So I need to create a page you
know update my website. So that was what
I was going to do today. But already now
by now we talked for an hour so we don't
so I I guess I'm going to do it offline.
Um anyway so there's a lot of comments
about this Linux issue but I think
that's it for me uh for today.
So add me on this fail. Uh, okay. To use
Windows. So, you see, I was going to
Windows, you know, Windows is like
[ __ ] sucking donkey ass. It become,
you know, I was going to switch because,
you know, because Windows 10 just
expired. Actually, I talked about this
um I think a month ago. Wind Windows 10
expired. So, I need to switch to Windows
11. However, on my machine, I turned off
the uh you know, there's this um boot
security thing. I turned that off. So, I
need to turn that, you know, in in the
bio bios or whatever is a new thing. So,
I cannot install it. Won't let me
install Windows 11. So, I need to look
that into that. So, but I'm lazy. I'm,
you know, I don't have time to look into
the BIOS, whatever. [ __ ] you know, I'm
interested in like programming languages
and mathematics proof systems.
I don't have time, you know, I have like
maybe five more years in my life to do
stuff. I don't have time to, you know,
so anyway. So, but Windows 10 is
expired, you know. So, I I'm forced to
look into, you know, I started to ask
what, you know, how do I get the BIOS to
change these settings? So, I finally did
it. So now I'm now on Windows 11. So
that is why I noticed about the Windows
11 emoji because all of a sudden
the emoji on window changed because you
know because Windows 11 be you know just
last month a month ago I was window
using Windows 10. So, I'm still with
using this Windows 10 emoji font, but
now I'm suddenly suddenly seeing this
ugly [ __ ] you know, Windows 11.
So, I was, you know, so either switch to
Windows 11 or I was going to switch to
uh Linux, but that that takes a lot
time, you know, because I have to,
you know, I do backup regularly. I have
to so I have to you know first in
install Linux of course then there's the
question of which dro you got to ask
friends you know and which dro is
compatible with my hardware the GPU and
the the the Wi-Fi you know whatever
sometimes you know sometimes they are
not compatible with some Wi-Fi hardware
so you got to find make sure it works
with your you know my hardware then then
you have to install it then you have to
migrate like all your u files your
personal you know structure files into
the Linux and you have to set up Emacs
or whatever or other programs on Linux
you know it's like you spend several
days you have to do that
yeah for young people for young people
you guys you can do it you know you got
nothing to do but not everyone can do
Okay, bye guys. Bye.
Yeah, big event. Okay, bye guys. I
haven't seen what you guys saying
exactly. Okay, bye.