hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show uh we are going to do random
we can not talk about random stuff so
let's begin okay random stuff uh first
you know I'm going to talk about emac
I'm going to talk about unic code
Egyptian hero G I'm going to talk about
Unicode white space face and unical
reference Mark and uh CSS selector
syntax or these are very interesting and
uh some wam language news and uh reading
notes on bubai bubai is the Baki bubak
I'm not sure how you pronounce it is a
mathematician group uh very influ
influential and I'm going to talk about
acrobatic gy
gymnastics uh that's amazing so that's
some of the things we're going to talk
about and if you are here say hi and ask
me questions I'll answer it okay so
let's begin
um the current bit rate is lower than
the recommended bit rate this is
annoying so I need to increase the bit
rate okay next
time so keyboard okay so there's an
update on my website about best
keyboards for emac uh let's see
am I am I am I doing good yeah hello
doy uh so base keyboard for emac so I
recommend glove 80 Kinesis
360 and I no longer recommend the
Kinesis Advantage too so get the 360
okay and I recommend the wired which is
what I'm using and uh glove 80 is the is
the best okay gl80 so and also Expos
Night Ultimate hacking keyboard which
you see on my desktop
here uh and also the Apple maker I
haven't used that so I'm not sure but I
think this is good one so all these are
the best keyboard so that's update to my
best keyboards for
emx uh okay and there's a new news about
keyboard there is this um orbital
trackpad apparently it's do it yourself
someone made it so it seems very
interesting over overto
trackpad that's a keyboard news and
there is this picture I I forgot I'm not
sure where it from it's a Microsoft
keyboard with a track boo but I don't
know if this is computer generated I
think it is so anyway so that's that's
some of the keyboard news Okay so and
there's also update to the least machine
keyboards so you can see these are the
keyboard from 197 s to
1980s um and they are you know they they
are you know very much tied to emac and
lisp and artificial intelligence back
then so and by the so let me tell you a
few things interesting so you know today
you have the windows key Microsoft
invented that Windows key and that idea
is borrow borrowed from the Macintosh
the apples command key and that command
key where does that I mean where does it
came from who first created who first
had the idea you need a Windows or
command key that is from this keyboard
basically from the Lis keyboard okay and
the first one is this one sell sell
keyboard that's from Stanford AI lab
1970 okay so you can see they that's the
first one that created The Meta key you
know in emac we talked about meta key
all the time so that's the The Meta key
which is the father of the Apple's
command key which is the father of
Windows Windows key okay so that's some
of the interesting things about this
keyboard and the most uh dramatic and
and popular one you see online is this
one space cadet
keyboard very interesting name space
cadet okay so there's some
update and and you know so I update so
and so all these are list machine
keyboards and if you are a Zoomer you
know you you you love this you you want
to get one you can buy first of all you
can buy the list machine keyboard key
caps so $50 or something or maybe more
so you can you know put them on your
keyboard so this and and this this is
ultimate hacking keyboard which is what
I have someone put the list machine
space CET key caps on it so you can buy
these key caps and uh there's here is a
number
pad uh then okay then you can buy this
hyper 7 which is modeled after the list
machine keyboard so it's got
183 Keys okay actually I don't recommend
it you know some of some people when
they look at the list machine keyboards
they think oh this this is fantastic
actually it's no good it's not good it's
not good in many ways it's not ergonomic
okay for example they have the modifiers
hyper super meta control all the way to
the left and they instead of function
keys they have this you know large key
which is not good because you want the
function keys in groups of four so that
you can press them without see without
having to look at it but you know with
the this machine keyboard you cannot do
that and also besides it's not ergonomic
so if you're not you know if you are a
heavy coder or writer it's not good for
you but it's tramatic you know it's got
the thumb up key thumb down key and top
repeat you know it's it's kind of fun
keyboard so anyway you can buy the key
Caps or you can get the hyper s it cost
I forgot $200 or something hyper 7 okay
so here's some photos hyper 7 keyboard
and here's a video and here is where to
buy then if you really want to go for
the quality you get this one this is
keymax this keyboard is called keymax
it's a kind of remake of the lisp
symbolic keyboard uh remake of this
keyboard okay one of the version of the
list machine keyboard and it's very
expensive it's literally
$1,000 you know someone made it uh let's
see so you know remake of that keyboard
and it cost $11,000
roughly
so anyway so there and there's a video
review by this expert guy uh by this
expert guy yeah who who is this uh
what's his
name okay that not um there's a video
review by this
guy uh quian quios run 22 Thomas
something okay so you can you know he he
gives full detail about this keyboard
truly high quality okay that that's
about that uh list machine keyboard okay
and uh let's go back to the topics I
want to talk about uh uh I'm using
fairies sweep right now oh I remember
someone told me fairy
sweep I don't remember exactly what it
looks like but anyway uh you are on my
Discord right Kar Discord if you haven't
you can join Kar Discord you can find
the link at kali. info just search for
Kar Discord okay so that's keyboard and
uh OB overal trackpad okay and the
storman figurine this is a beautiful so
some guy I found this on El musk x uh so
this guy his wife made it for him you
know Richard Richard storman figurine
it's a it's
beautiful
handcraft okay that's that's some of the
news then let's talk about Unicode okay
Egyptian he
hog uh let me show you
here you see
Egyptian hieroglyph you know they tell
tell it as it is so you have women woman
giving child birth you know actually
actually a photo of child birth and look
at this one I'm not sure what that is so
these are Unicode characters you know
these are actually characters and you
have a king with a giant dick huge dick
and you have tit tits
here and you have this thing I'm not
sure what that is okay so and they also
have let me let me tell you here okay
they also have you see on Microsoft
Windows they censored
it they censored it but you can see on
the Mac you'll show uh but Mac has
Apple's got its own problems but anyway
so let's see let me show you the photo
of it you see they looks like that
photos of
I mean not photo characters so this
is part of
Egyptian okay that's interesting thing
about that uh and now let's talk about
Apple now Apple's unic code is very much
political you know they did a lot bad
things
so
but anyway
so so one of the thing they did is that
Apple you know Apple tries to Define
what unic code is basically so you have
these Arrow characters in Unicode you
have you know this this Arrow characters
are around since 2014 in Unicode 7
okay so by now Apple should have a font
you know including these characters but
Apple doesn't you know so if you look at
this page on on your Mac you'll see all
this shows us shows up as squares and
not and this is just some of them so let
me show you all you know the whole bunch
of unic code arrows so you can see all
these are unic code Arrow characters and
about onethird of them about 100 or 50
characters
apple on Apple computer it doesn't show
same thing on iPhone iPad so basically
Apple you know they they try to create
their their own vision of what Unicode
what characters you should be is good
you know they so they do not include
lots of these you know standard unic
code
characters so if you are on for example
here is the arrow we are talking about
so many of these doesn't show so I can I
can tell you uh which one it doesn't
show
show uh many many of these
okay for example this whole block I
think it doesn't show except maybe two
or three and this whole block apple
apple doesn't show uh and this whole
block I think this block on on the Mac
it doesn't show so a lot of so not just
arrows in this but more prominent you
know you can see this Mo most
prominently uh in Arrow characters so
why is that you know because Unicode
Unicode has some problems you know it's
it's great but it's not
perfect uh but so so apple is kind of
like trying to fix it so for example the
arrows you know Arrow the Arrow
characters are they came from many
places you know some of them are for
mathematics mostly from mathematical
books textbooks some of them from for
example some of them are from uh di bats
for example these these aror characters
they are from dbats so anyway the in
unic code many of the
characters not just Arrow but all sort
of characters they came from many places
so sometimes they are not exactly
consist
consistent uh so Apple kind of you know
on on Apple computer which is supposed
to be supposedly the elite you know the
best design so they actually they
prevent you from seeing from showing
some of these characters they they
consider kind of uh uh kind of
inconsistent or such so that is why that
you know I don't think they ever
explicitly say why but you can kind of
tell so all these you know this whole
bunch of characters is not on Apple
computer so that's that's one thing
Apple Unicode
tyrany okay so that's about that okay
another interesting thing about Unicode
is the mathematical font so on this page
for example let me show you some
interesting
some interesting things so as you type
you can get these characters and if you
go to a text edit editor open a new
paste it so you get these characters now
this is not fun this is actually a
character a character so if you say
press that key on emx it's called
describe
um describe CH then you can get the
information for example uh describe
CH on the S so you can see this this s
is named mathematical factors small s
okay so this so if you go to my page you
called math font you can you know you
can you can play with it so you can
change to bold for example these
characters are actually not not bold by
the by by the application they are
actually Bold characters by themselves
without you know italics or whatever so
there's both there's italic there's
mathematical mono space characters and
there is a math math script characters
for example very interesting and so the
update so I did so this you know so you
can see these are Unicode characters so
I did some update to tell you what some
of these are usedful mostly they are
used in mathematics so you have integers
natural numbers primes P for Prime Q for
rational R for real C for complex
numbers H for Quan and S for sadan
Sardinian and then uh a few new things I
learned in the past month also is f for
finite for finite field and B for buing
the bulling uh set of
uh buling is what
uh uh how wait how do how do they call
them set okay so bin use type Theory and
the finite and then then you have finite
field and then I learned yesterday so
you have this small case fror characters
they are used in Lee algebra okay so
that's a new things I
learned uh okay so that's that's about
that so uh so let's go back to the talk
show and uh let's
okay so showing browser so we talked
about math font and the
next wh space so in unic code you have
so many white space now so you have
about over 10 or 20 WID space characters
for example you have the you have the
character this one is called character
tabulation it's tab okay it's just tab
so you have Line Feed line tabulation
form feed carriage return space now all
these are old okay then you have next
line all these are old then all these
are part of asky characters but then you
have many new ones so you have no break
space this is also kind of old but not
in asky and you have oam space mark okay
that is some okay that oakam must be uh
language it shouldn't be here anyway
that anyway then you have e and quad e m
quad n space e m space then you have
three p three per m space four per em
Space six per em space then you have
figure space then you have punctuation
space then you have thin space then hair
space
then you have line separated you know so
you have so many new spaces in you uh
new white space in unic code you know
for example the line
separator why do they create that the
idea is that you know in in in on the
Mac on Windows on Unix the line return
you know a new line let's show wi
space uh
uh
wait okay show white space so in in in
Unix on the Mac on Unix on Windows you
see the new line the line return
characters is actually different
depending on which operating system you
are on so unit code you know so that's a
old old convention you know this
situation has been in the past 40 Years
also uh or in the past 30 years since
Windows came about
so anyway so Unico tried to have you
know this line separator as one you know
new consistent way so it kind of the
idea is that everyone just use this
character for the line
separation but I doubt I doubt you know
it'll
fly but anyway so so the so the line
ending convention in different operating
system is actually a headache it's
creating a lot of problems uh okay I'm
not going to go into it unless you want
me to so if you have a question uh say
it okay if you want to me to talk about
the problems of the lineing convention
between Mac Unix Windows there's lots of
problems I can talk about
that so anyway so unic code has all this
new space and there is this ideographic
space that's a space used in in Chinese
is because it's basically it's a big fat
space
so so that's a that's about unic code wi
space characters then another thing
interesting is that when you want to
show wi space you know there's a
question of what characters what GL you
want to represent what wi space so for
example let's uh let's input a tab uh
wait so let's input a tab so you can see
I have a tab here so it's shown as a
triangle see
uh you see so that's uh you have to pick
a character to represent you know the y
space and this is a bit tricky because
if you are in the text editor
situation you you need let's say
a a a symbol to represent line return
there are many choices for example you
can use a you know you can use a arrow
you know 90 degree turn arrow you know
any one of these you can use it or you
can use the paragraph sign so anyway one
situation is that you want to show y
space in a text editor or word processor
the other situation is on keyboard for
example the Tab Key you know the tab key
right here
so there are different situations so on
the keyboard versus on the editor you
typically want to use different
symbols it will make sense because for
example uh in wespace so how do you show
a wi space in a editor you know you can
you can show it by a DOT you know like
here or you can show a kind of under
line you know
thing but on a
keyboard now let's say if you are on
keyboard you want the symbol to show
space does a DOT make sense no because
if you have a DOT on the spacebar you
know it makes people think you are
actually if you press that key insert a
DOT you know so it doesn't make sense
there it makes sense in the editor
doesn't make sense on the keyboard label
so you know it's very interesting
interesting that which symbol to use to
represent y space depends on the context
okay that's an interesting question I
mean it's interesting issue for example
for the tab on the Microsoft keyboard or
Logitech keyboard usually the tab is
represented by two you know forward and
backward arrow with the bar at the
end uh that's on the Microsoft
Windows uh Windows keyboard or log Tech
but on the Mac typically they they use
without the on the Mac I think you know
actually I have like lots of photos to
show
this uh should I show yeah okay let's
see let's show
it so you go to keyboard let's search
um
tab
so there's a lot uh minint portable uh
let's
see let's search for symbol okay so
there it is Apple keyboard symbols so
these are all the symbols used on by
Apple Apple keyboards so you can see
actual keyboards usually they for US
keyboard versions they just use English
words but Apple keyboard for for Japan
for Russia for Europe they usually use
symbols gles okay so for example you can
see some of the examples shift key
return key and tab you see you see there
the
tab uh okay you cannot see them too well
but it's a arrow with the n Bar instead
of two arrows just one single arrow and
also over the past 10 years or 20 Apple
has changed
their use of symbols for example
the the page up and down key okay for
about five years they use this this
character arror with two bars okay up
arrow with two bars down arrow with two
bars to represent page up and page down
key but
now now they simply use a arrow okay so
you can see here so this is a Apple
magic keyboard year
2015 traditional Chinese okay this one
is used in
Taiwan so you can see and also they
Chang the home key and N key labels so
before it was diagonal Arrow but now
it's arrow with the bar you know
so so so what's this about this so this
is the interesting interesting issue
about design you know little little
details of design for example if you are
Apple if you are at Apple you are
designing this keyboard so there's a
question what symbol you're going to use
on the keyboard and why do they change
what is the reason you know you have to
you ask the designer what what is the
reason you change from one of the symbol
to the other and and the criteria it has
a lot to do with lots of things for
example on Apple's documentation
typically you want the symbol to be the
same
same as you know when you pull a menu
you know the symbol show shows there so
so there's a lot consideration and you
also have to consider cultural
convention uh things like that so that
is why Apple keyboard for USA for
English you know for American usually
they don't use these symbols they just
use
English so anyway a lot of issue to
consider so this is is one of the
thing that you know some of the details
kind of trivial almost trivial details
that You Look At You observe and you you
can think about it has to do with design
so typically these are not the things
you know the mainstream Media or Apple
Fans will talk about you know every
every year or two you this new Apple
operting system you know they big
announce this all that but usually they
don't talk about these Minor Details but
it's very interesting it has to do with
uh
design unical symbols or symbols in
general symbols design they are meaning
and uh and also has to do with writing
of documentation you know when you write
you know you read a lot programming
language documentation python parl Java
and you know some of these come up
anyway so you write a lot of
documentation so there's a design issue
what what character uh to represent what
so all these uh issues
are kind of interesting okay if you are
just you know if you if you are just
like mainstream you know if you are a
typical person or programmer you go with
mainstream you go to school you know
High School go to college whatever you
don't you don't see these things you
know they don't teach you you know you
you you are like cookie what they say
cookie stamp you know so your
brain your brain is like the same you
know they the same like everyone but if
you are kind of independent or
homeschooled then you you kind of notice
all these kind of
things okay so that's about that that
you know design documentation symbols
used in human history so so it's it's
you know it's it's not just keyboard
symbols oh it's just keyboard no it's
human history so a lot of this has to do
with you know the entire human history
or depending on how deep you want to go
has to do with
Linguistics you know this uh for example
this symbol why do they this symbol for
example this
symbol that's that's a wheel that's the
Dharma wheel that's a Indian hel Helm
symbol okay that's you that's that came
from the Indian uh
religions concept of a wheel wheel of
life
so in Indian religions or in even in
Buddhism this wheel represent Wheel of
Life meaning that you know when you die
when we die we reincarnate we become we
come back as another person or become a
pig or an animal reincarnation
cycle of reincarnation so you have the
concept of Karma if Karma means like
good if you do good you have good comma
then you come back as a another person
with better life let's say a rich person
if you do bad in this life you do evil
things you rob you steal you know then
you come back your when you reincarnate
when you die when you come back to the
world you become a pig or a bull or a
cow a beast of burden that's the that's
kind of the general idea of the Indian
or Buddhism religion okay so the Dharma
this Wheel of Life is represent that
wheel a wheel you know like it's like
the
Western uh sense of Wheel of Fortune
okay so you know so then they choose
this so this wheel symbol is actually
used to represent the control key so you
can see in this Apple keyboard Apple
laptop you know this is for use for
Canadian so you know you can see the
control key represented by that wheel in
fact that this this stipulation of using
the wheel the dhma wheel to represent
the control key is actually an ISO
standard okay if you look the deep into
that it's act you know the iso one of
the iso
standard I don't remember I have it you
know I I mentioned it somewhere but the
one of the iso standard they
specify you know what symbol to use to
represent what key such as delete back
back delete old key or option key or
command key or control key or the tab
key or the capslock key you know they
have they have kind of the standard for
that it's rarely used but anyway in this
keyboard in this Apple's keyboard uh
version for Canadian French Canadian
multilingual uh you know they you know
the MacBook Pro they actually stick with
those standard so all these symbols you
see on this keyboard is actually using
that ISO standard okay
so very interesting uh things
so let's copy
that uh and let's paste it here so that
we can have a record of what we talked
about uh okay let's paste it
here okay so a lot of things to go over
uh Unicode wi space yeah so Unicode
that's about Unicode wi space so
next hello hello
uh do you think shift key must be
pressed with both hands uh I think shift
key should be banned okay
so shift key is a pain
yes
uh ban shift Keys ban key code okay so
you go to SAR keyboard block you have a
article about bang key cords that's your
control control meta option key old key
Windows key I think they should be
banned then you'll be much more
efficient you'll be you know you'll have
less hand pen you'll be more efficient
and in fact you'll have much more
shortcuts if you don't use these key
combos key you know so lots of History
the key combination they came from
mechanical type writers okay so the key
combination they came
from
uh let's see where uh typewriters okay
let me show you a few so you see
mechanical typewriters invented about
200 years ago so where does it came from
who gave you the idea who gave us the
idea that you have to hold this key
first you know shift key then press
another key release that key then
release the shift key key must be
specifically in that order you can't you
can't just press them both at the same
time doesn't work you have to press the
shift hold it first okay same thing with
the you know for the control for the
command key for the option key for the
command key you
know so where does that came from came
from mechanical keyboard because the
shift key because the mechanical you see
all the gears you know the elaborate
gears in order to make it work you you
hold the shift so they actually shift
all the gears behind it then you press
another key then they you know that's
why they you know then you got Capital
case and stuff so that's where it came
from the shift key Shifting the gears
that's why it's called
shift okay Shifting the
gears
so so for 100 years we use that and we
get used to you know it becomes our
nature you know obviously when you press
shift you have to hold it obviously
because otherwise the gear doesn't shift
you know what you talking about that's
the before computers but the when the
computer keyboard is invented you no
longer have gears but however you don't
The Habit stuck you know by habit you
have to hold the shift first hold it
there then press on the key so the
computer adopted the typ right away
because if you don't do that nobody is
going to like your keyboard you know
they they're going to say this this
apple sucks or whatever because they
they are used to you know we are used to
the shifting thing you know so that's
how we got you know all this meta key
and you have to hold them and stuff
which is not
good so that's the history of the
shifting you know why you have to hold
that it stuff okay so let's copy that
hold on a
second uh so we talked about that and
and let me tell
you uh so that's the history of the
shift key and the the okay so so key
code okay so let's put the link here and
Bank key code okay so I think we should
uh ban key code and ban shift
key okay so key uh you know I have
articles on them you you can go read
them b key code search for s bang key
codes I'll tell you why okay so because
key key code is just key code is one of
the
most crtical critical the the one of the
most foremost reason
of repetitive strain injury you know you
hear a lot of people they you know
programmers they use keyboard a lot they
go to see a doctor their career is
ruined because they cannot type anymore
because they have pain
key code that key code is one of the
most important cause of that okay I can
tell you I have like tens of articles
about details there so anyway so you can
you can read of this read of this
article Bank key codes okay there's a
statistics uh on you know there's
statistics and lots of
information I'm not going to go over
because oh go got we already 40 minutes
we we We Are One Third Way of the things
we I want to talk about yet so anyway
key code is very bad and shift key is
you know it's part of the key code so
it's also very bad so okay so let me
think about what what are the things I
want to talk about so you are asking so
okay so first thing key code is no good
they are the four one of the most uh
foremost reason
of causing hand pain okay repetitive
strain injury now what's the other
reason the the the the number one reason
for the repetitive strain injury the
number one cause there lots of cause but
as as far as keyboard goes the number
one cause
is bad key switches
okay so the first so let me give you a
actual practical advice so first thing
you want to do is you want to go out and
buy a mechanical
keyboard important mechanical key switch
keyboard that's the first thing you want
to do okay that's the first thing the
second thing you want to do is you want
to ban any of these modifier key codes
instead you want to press them
sequentially okay that's that's related
to another article which I started to
write uh so a draft reason a draft
version I haven't finished yet so
keyboard keyboard Health guide okay so
this is a summary of my 30 years of
experience now this you know the you
know this topic is very huge and uh and
there's so many different opinions most
of them 90% of them is crap okay it's
spaceless spaceless anyway so in here I
just tell you in summary of my 30 years
experience of one you know 1,000
articles there are 1,000 articles on
keyboard on my S keyboard okay that like
literally 1,000 articles so uh for
example you can
see you know 1,000 articles so so my
summary of my experience I'll just tell
you two things okay one run go out by a
mechanical keyboard okay with mechanical
key
switch and that switch must be linear
switch and must be light so if you don't
know anything about it go get a 45 GS
activation Force such as Cherry MX red
switch okay so that's number one thing
forget about all the other advice or how
to remap you know you whether you should
remap keys where you should be cap slck
or should be control or whatever or way
ways to press the key or whether you
should touch TP you know this or whether
you you need tting you know all of all
everything my 30 years experience I'll
just tell tell you two things here
okay go out get a mechanical keyboard
with you know linear light switch that's
one thing the second thing is get rid of
key uh get rid of uh key cords okay
second importance avoid pressing control
old command key combinations so how do
you avoid it
one is turn on Stick sticky keys STI
sticky keys available on the Mac on
Linux on Windows you know you can read
this article or you can search the web
just turn it on okay that's one easy
solution
two you get a extra programmable marro
key key c key
pad like I have so for example this
timate hacking keyboard I'm using it as
a marro key uh Marco keypad for example
typically when you want to switch to
last window you press um old tab right
you press all tab that's a key code
press all hold it down press tab then
you know oh look I want to go here okay
uh where I want to go here then release
all that's idiotic that's idiotic in so
many ways I have an article on that okay
so anyway
so
so so one way to avoid key code is turn
on sticky keys or the second way is buy
a buy a Marco keypad like like the one I
have okay so you can see switch window
one single keypad press there's no code
okay switch tab previous tab previous
previous previous next tab next next
next okay close
window this key undo close this key one
single key you don't want control T
control shift T you know okay the most
important
so okay so that's it so let me go on
because we have so many other things to
talk about so your question about shift
key okay so the question about shift key
you know yeah you can ban you know it's
not easy to ban them
because if you use sticky key that will
solve a lot problems okay but it it it
has um some issues you know that's the
thing with keyboard you have always have
some minor issues because or sometimes
sticky doesn't work or this if you turn
sticky key sometimes is stuck you can't
figure out which key is stuck that's
very bad you know you have let's say you
have the windows key
stuck sometimes that happens happens on
Windows happens on on on Mac Mac has
some other issues you know happens on
Linux too so if you turn on sticky
keys uh where is the um where is my
article okay so let's go let's go to
it uh okay so let's just talk about this
issue so let me give you the whole
opinion
um keyboard Health guide okay so let's
put that link here turn off the yspace
and
the typewriters okay so yeah put a link
there okay link
it and sticky key so let me show you the
page about sticky
key copy back to
here okay so sticky
keys that's one of the solution the
other solution get a Marco keypad okay
um okay that's the two
solutions but they don't they
cannot
completely get rid of the key codes
they'll they'll solve 80% of the problem
so you don't have to you don't have hand
pain but they but they have their own
issues you have to live with okay so
yeah so let me talk about shift key so
you are talking about shift key now
shift key is one of the key the least
you know either sticky key you know
um okay well to solve the shift key
problem turn on sticky key okay
um but anyway otherwise wise otherwise
yeah so if you don't want to turn on S
key for some reason sometimes there's a
reason you so what you do you always you
know you should always use both shift
key okay use the right hand when you
want the keys is on the left hand use
the left hand when the key is on the
right hand so okay that's how you should
press the C sticky key always both hands
okay and there's some other you know
complex Technical Solutions to avoid
sticky key for example you
can you know so for example if you want
to type the add sign and if you are
using emac you can mix emac that instead
of typing shift two you can type a
sequence of three other Keys you know
for example menu space two so I did that
for half a year you know so this so
again there are so many you know
technical esoteric solutions to solve
these problems but let let me summarize
the most the first two the most
important is get a mechanical key switch
linear light switch then turn on sticky
key or buy a key markco pad okay that's
all you need to know all these details
you know I I personally tried this you
know for 10 years for for for for over
10 years try this method try that a lot
teching you know you need to write code
you know Auto H key you know I have
article I have a complete tutorial a you
know
anyway don't do that okay you know just
follow the you know this these uh
esoteric details they don't they don't
help that
much okay so that's about that so let's
move on to the next topic
um so what were we talking about so yeah
white space Apple keyboard symbols uh
copy that we copy we did that already uh
keyboard search Bank key quotes yeah
typewriters yeah mechanical
typewriters okay so let's talk about the
next topic anything anything
questions
so if you so here you know here's the
example of esoteric details you know so
Rusty says if you ban shift key then how
could uppercase letters be typed even in
the case of the sticky keys would it be
efficient to use let's say just key caps
lock for the shift or use okay I know
your question for example let's say
let's say I want to say I'm angry at key
codes I want all caps okay I am angry at
key codes okay so to answer your
question normally you hit caps lock then
you can type the whole thing it will be
all capital the my solution is you know
do this okay there there so three keys
okay
so I am angry at something okay now
watch the pinguin
okay now one key to select them all one
key to capitalize the first word of
every word another key to capitalize
them all okay so this is my solution my
answer to your caps lock
question right if you B shift key you
know or you can just
like
I uh
m e or or hold shift for for each one
hold shift hold shift space hold shift
hold shift that's another way so anyway
your question is how do you type a bunch
of capital letters this is my solution
okay so anyway again like what I said
there are so many details don't worry
about it okay don't worry about your you
know yeah but how what about this one
what about you know what happen you know
if you ban that what happen don't worry
about that
two recommendations one go out buy a
linear light switch mechanical keyboard
okay stop using your laptop it is laptop
Keys got that got me isi in 2005 I've
been touch typing heavily every day
since
1989 okay I don't have a problem in the
first 15 years until 2005 I was using a
Apple laptop I have article on that you
know search for SAR RSI history I have
like 10 articles detail each situation
each occurrence anyway so
2005 I was on a Apple laptop at all
times no actual keyboard just laptop
that got me RSI okay first time and ever
since I have RSI have other issues that
you know I have you know
so my 30 years advice about keyboard I I
I started to use vorak layout you know
in 1994 okay I touch
typing
okay RSI history okay so just search for
that you know I have like 100 articles
so
um there okay s these typing experience
and RSI okay so here is a
summary chronological summary of my
repetitive strin injury 1988 I learned
touch typing on a electric typewriter
1992 I worked as a data entry cler which
means my job is typing all
day 1994 I learned vorak layout because
I despise inefficient design I'm very
much into design of things that's why I
look into for example unic code the
symbols or programming language coding
style or documentation you know so
typing experience so 1994 I learned
about vorak layout because quality is
very bad
so you know some of you will ask should
I learn quy okay again my top two advice
go run go out run get a linear light
switch forget about all the quality or
keymap or how you should this all that
get a linearized switch okay linear and
light get used to it okay you might say
oh but but my brother says that my
friend says you know you should have
blue switch because clicky give you
Sensational T tactile feedback or this
that cra
app get you get used lightly I mean if
you have opinions that's fine okay but
if you don't know much about this my
advice is go out run get a linear light
switch get used to it linear light
switch mechanical keyboard okay that's
first thing second thing avoid key
combination how do you avoid it one turn
on sticky key okay it's got some
problems but just try to get used to it
okay or buy a Marco keypad you know $50
will get you one 20 Keys depending on
you know you can spend 100 you know or
more so MCO keypad if you are you know
Photoshop image editing CAD or whatever
video editing you know you there's a lot
shortcuts usually
30 shortcuts in every application you
know so get a MCO keypad pad okay so
like you know okay that's it that's the
two top most most things you need to be
concerned about okay the other ones are
little details vorak you know vorac
should you learn vorak or should you not
or should you learn you know uh comac
it's it's Superior than vorak you know
crap Okay this not too important not not
not too important okay for your hand
Health okay so anyway this article is a
detail of each of the
occurrence the about of my repetitive
strain injury I fully document
documented each one has a story you know
when did I you know where is the pen
where does it came from I was puzzled
you know then
2007 you know I had something I that's
when I created oo emx then
2009 Okay so
okay I switched to the Microsoft natural
keyboard you know that's okay so anyway
then then there's a problem
2010 the second time I have
RI due to this reason okay so you know
then 2012 another issue happened you
know like I was so puzzled so anyway
that's my um history of
my isi
okay
you know questions like then how do you
type caps lock you know if you I
recommend get rid of caps lock right but
anyway that there's so many that's too
much issue to talk about because there's
different solutions each one's got a
problem you know that's um kind of not
too important
so you know you can keep cap locks if
you want to you know um so anyway so
let's go back to the talk show so it's
already an
hour
uh so yeah you like tactile switches you
know if you have an opinion you know
that's fine stick with your habit or
opinion but if you don't not sure yet or
maybe you think you know you need to
change then you know you can listen to
my uh device okay we talked about a lot
keyboard okay so this more unic code so
it's already on
our
um there's quite a a lot things to talk
about unic code and
CSS and uh okay so if you like guys like
my stuff okay go to
S code s. info all the way bottom donate
okay patreon me or Amazon gift card me
use my link okay because if you are in
German or other countries you pay me via
Amazon German I don't get money I cannot
get money okay
so use the my link Amazon USA or you can
PayPal me okay if you like my stuff
donate okay let's go back to let's see
what's the next thing
um let's talk about maybe few more
things let's talk about about Unicode so
I mean all these are my my work in the
past month also lots of stuff and wolam
language okay I'm going to mention in a
bit so unic code so unic code has a
bunch of reference marks you know like I
said this is about writing about symbol
use and human languages linguist
Linguistics and human history so in
Western Society for example you have
this paragraph Mark called pureal sign
and you have section sign then you have
the traditional asterisk then you have
low Aster risk then you have double
asterisk then you have this flower
punctuation mark then you have triple
asterisk called asterism okay so very
interesting asterisk you know all these
are used for reference marks you know in
mostly in English writing history in
Western writing history so you have
dagger dagger you have uh dagger with
left guard okay so then you have triple
dagger then you have actual dagger Emoji
then you have Star Emoji and star
symbols okay so you have all these
different stars and you have all this
variety you know you have more varieties
of asterisk symbols you know they are
typically used for reference as
reference
marks one of my favorite is is the teer
drop as risk okay so anyway then you
have snowflake symbols in unical then
you have sparkles okay then you also
have flate you know like this uh very
interesting so and also in in Western
culture English writing you have these
pointing fingers okay they are also used
for reference purposes like you know C
also you know pointing finger is very
interesting then in Chinese you have for
example uh this one okay this one this
is a Chinese used in China Japan Taiwan
okay basically Asia uh reference Mark
okay we don't have you know we don't use
Aster risk I mean the traditional is
this you know for
reference but I mean in modern days you
know you know you have a lot Chinese
mixed with English for example for
chemistry symbols or mathematics so you
also see
um uh you know Western punctuations
anyway so all these are interesting as
uh reference marks
okay so it you know it's it's
interesting when you study them because
[Music]
it
is
hello am I
[Music]
back
hello am I
back the electricity went out um you
know the local power having some issue
but I guess that's it for today then bye
[Music]
guys am I
back the bye guys
back