good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show
let's see if I have okay it's good
so today so so I got a question here and
actually doesn't show now oh yeah this
is a question
Mario T commented is there a real need
to learn vim I just want to use emacs in
your fried keys
no there's no need to learn v me at all
what do you need to so exotic so let's
see let's talk about some things
first of all okay let me address some of
the things I talked about yesterday
and one of that is yeah so yesterday we
were talking about graphics programming
pain how the technology such as OpenGL
is in my opinion extremely bad ok and ok
so let's go back here OpenGL is
extremely bad and I was trying to I was
but however there is a good design but
that never came to that fail basically
so that good design you know a
replacement of OpenGL is this Farren
hate graphics API and quick-draw 3d so
if you you know you might read Wikipedia
so picture of 3d and Fahrenheit graphics
API so these are intended to replace
OpenGL now OpenGL is extremely bad
technology I mean it's very low level
it's like what I would call see you know
like you know it see extremely bad but
because it
all the irrelevant necessary things to
the programmer where the machine can
handle it you know when you design your
language or computer programming system
you know graphic system anything you
never want to expose things that can be
done by machine ok for example for
example let me give you an example the
basic example today everyone knows is
for example type inference ok so for
example if you program in goal and let's
set to go mod ok let's save this exhales
go OK and you know so I save I x equals
to 3 and trained X ok go format ok and
you run a program you see it's it's
printing out three now go is a
statically typed language so these 3 the
type of 3 is actually your integer you
can you can see it you can have a
printer type so you see the type is
actually int you know one of the gold :
type however you know you don't have to
say it's an int because you know
obviously you assigned to 3 3 int you
know so that means the machine can you
know this is something no machine can
figure out so you never when you design
your language you never want to do some
things that machine can trivially figure
out I mean this is actually an example
where the machine can trivially figure
out so you don't want to expose these
kind of things to your system to the
program so that you know what I taught
you know program go I have to always say
intense that so on the other hand sew
the opposite choice design decision is
kind of hack and sloppy and ignorant and
that I ascribe to the C and UNIX kind of
thing the UNIX philosophy C and they are
like that
you know the type inference I don't know
what's a history of type type inference
but to me these are something that's
patently obvious to any any person who
ever thought about this design okay but
type inference didn't become popular
until let's say ten thousand ten ten
years ago not ten thousand you know with
Haskell become popular Eskow is probably
the first one I heard about type
inference ok type Haskell is kind of a
special case because it's rather
elaborate functional programming
language with many elaborate functional
programming concepts but as something
like go : you know but anyway the point
is type inference you know at least for
the simple cases the machine can easily
figure you know any any person who
thought about design know that you know
but however in C C++ you know all the
languages including including Java you
know to me it's it's just like you know
so the industry adopted them of course
they are widely popular but to me they
are like patently extremely idiotic you
know because because they almost think
every everywhere you find them to
require something that that computers
the machine can easily do you know but
however they require you the programmer
to do it you know that is ok and and
also the other thing is for no reason I
mean the only reason I can subscribe to
to you know why it's that way because
it's only just because it just because
they don't care you know that that's why
I hate UNIX philosophy and C C++ these
type of people so much used when you
study them you eat the only basically
the only reason you find is that they
just don't care about these things you
know they you know you just they require
you to the programmer to
- all these things like everywhere not
just you know not just type infants like
every design of see you know almost
everywhere you know you find these kind
of problems like symptoms of like you
know the only way I can describe it is
like brainless Ness sloppy you know they
don't care they like they are lazy they
they always implement they always come
up with a design
you know actually they don't I don't
think they actually design but they the
result they of their product is
typically when you look at it back like
there's no design you know they just
sloppy they just created to make it work
you know for most cases you know you
don't care are not concerned about
extension extensibility they are not
concerned about architecture they are
not concerned about you know arrogance
or minimalism you know like those needs
they are not just concerned about so
anyway that's example but let me show
you an article then hi guys
good morning so today my computer is
good
say something say hi here so let me show
you sorry why I hate see okay so here I
think in this archive I gave some
examples you know one of the example
okay okay this article is about print
print F I don't see first first go to G
okay and most vexing pause yeah the most
vaccine pass is suppressed first I
believe let's look at the article so
magnify magnify most vexing paths the
most vexing path is a specific form of
synthetic ambiguity resolution in C++
programming language
okay anyway the term was used by Scott
Mayer seeing effective STL now Scott
Mayer's is famous for designing I think
Haskell
I think associated with Haskell
let's see Scott may spawn 1959 Oh
one year younger than me he's an
American author in software consultant
specializing in C++ oh okay I don't know
him I was confused with another guy okay
so anyway okay so let's I digressed
about a little bit but anyway so this
article is about
I hate see but this article is actually
on a separate issue about syntax and
other things well it covers some of the
issues I'm talking about about the
exposing you know implementation details
to the programmer let me for example
this one is a good example let me show
you so this is this essays concepts and
oh wait it's not this one this one this
one is about these concepts and
confusions of prefix infix postfix
invisible notations okay the this
article hack of bitmask
spooling parameters now in c programming
language as well as in python you'll
find this kind of thing basically you
know when you have a function and you
have lots of parameters you you will see
that in python you will see a syntax
like this okay it's it's called pooling
bitmask okay it's a it's called B
bitmask so your you'll see a thing like
this for example you
the function but your and the function
takes an int okay and the int integer
you know like a pipe it takes a bite and
then and you pass arguments such as red
and yellow and red and yellow each one
of them is a constant they are just the
paid constant defined by the language
then you use the OL bit or simp a Pareto
to combine them you know so it's like a
bit mask so how does that work
should I go explain that hi guys if you
are watching say something okay let me
know you are watching 2 to 2 person ok
so anyway the the in C and n in Python
you some you have the situation where a
function takes a bit mask you know
basically they are using bit mask as
function parameters ok only if I should
explain this or should I go into that so
should I go into that guys do you want
me to go into detail about this issue
because I'm gonna I'm going to talk
about some of the things about today's
topic let's see yeah the pain of doing
video some other topics the day Steve
Jobs died
ok type something guys type here type in
a comment box type here okay but anyway
let me just explain a bit mask then
let's see
let's see maybe I can show you a Python
example Python rejects functions
yeah the third argument the third of
argument is a Flags okay here
it's flags but let me show you where it
is
Python rejects reference and you want to
Python rejects flags okay so let me talk
about these ok so Python Python rejects
even go back about a second Python
rejects Fairfax okay
so Python rejects functions
okay such for example so Python has say
this is this is regular expression you
have a function that's such you know a
string so this syntax is a you know it
takes two arguments the first argument
is a regular expression pattern and the
second argument is a string yeah
so you it will return I mean basically
it checks if if the pattern is in the
stream now however if you know regular
expression you know there is Flags
regular expression in basically all
regular expressions you any language
implementation you have these flags so
what does regular expression flags -
basically they are like they are like
optional tricks on how your other
language interpreter interprets your
pattern basically you know whether you
want to ignore case whether you know
some of the patterns should match
multi-line or just or not you know and
for example a dart in regular expression
will match any character but no money
normally except newline character the
dot we are not match newline character
but however if you give this option the
dot will match your newline character
you know so things like that you know
you you know case is the simplest to
understand so you have an option for
ignore case so anyway so you see that
regular expression has all these kind of
options you can control you know whether
you want to ignore case or multi-line
and stuff so so when when a function you
know such as replace that takes a
regular expression you hi Duncan hey
Duncan
when function takes expression you
have this regular expression options
okay
now the way Python does it is that you
see you see back this function read out
such a pattern a stream then it except a
third argument which is a flag flags now
this third argument is actually just a
bite that is you know one zero one zero
or something something and so how does
this flags work so basically the way it
works is that any of these regular
expression options you are seeing here
like ignore case without motor
line dot or each one of them is
actually just a bite you know like eight
bits of one and one or zeros but suppose
you want ignore case and suppose you
want the dot to match or you know any
character so you want this option and
this option you know you want to options
but however notice that the function
only take one argument for the flags so
how does it work so it turns out you
know the way they do it is that it's
called beat mask you know so each of
this option is actually just a bite so
when you have two bites you you okay you
do a bit or to combine them it was it
and or basically you combine the bits
anyway it's it's kind of fairly complex
to explain and that that is my point
you see because because before the
simple idea of you know options for the
regular expression pattern now becomes
this complex bit mask thing where you
actually so you introduce the concept of
bit bits to programmer and then you into
a concept concept a bit combination so
this is extremely bad that's that's so
so that is this article is about hack of
beat mask as boolean parameters
now you wonder why did what I do it this
way it's because see you know as I said
see you know in my opinion series like
the granddaddy of everything that's
wrong with the computing industry so
this is so this is article this is one
my article about computer language
design and the problems I see and by the
way the best bit mask is going away I
mean these days you don't see your
language you doing this anymore it was
like that before in see languages like C
you know because they can't it's kind of
from efficiency reasons like practical
practicality and efficiency reasons
because when you have you know instead
of function taking multiple options or
named options I don't think you even
have named options in C but anyway when
you want to reduce memory size and you
want to you know reduce or that you used
that's why they thought they use the pit
mask
hate a new hate Duncan has going so I
was explaining about pit mask okay so
and you know yeah so so I guess that's
one topic that's that's that try this
curious way to define pit facts in go
okay so Duncan is showing me something
show sure
what is that so Duncan say is constant
black one equals one and flag too so try
this curious way to define bit flags and
go I don't you know I don't use
let's see how go format so you define
two constants flag one in fact two and
this this is some kind of a bit operator
shift left I think okay
Duncan says flag to gets implicit value
with okay yeah I you know I you know I
don't think pit mask is a good thing at
all and I don't like any of those any
language that has these feet operations
I mean unless the language is designed
to be you know low-level you know you
don't start with value one them one okay
but what's the point
Duncan I know what you know what you're
saying so so this is like an example of
bits in in : or who are you saying
something
Oh curious mechanism but why is it
curious because yeah because so you got
one yeah okay III see what you mean so
one is basically what one is in binary
what is one Z was one two three four
five six seven eight
so one is this right and the is that
shift left or right
Oh yota right yota is something : I
don't remember what it is so let's look
up yeah goal and yeah you know hate
these kind of things
yo tengo tengo wiki
where is it
there should be a goal and I want to go
to the goal inspect or documentation not
some random articles so goes Yatta
identifier is used in constant
declarations to simplify definitions of
incrementing numbers to simplify
definitions of incrementing numbers
because it can be using expressions it
provides a generality beyond that of the
simple enumeration okay I don't get it I
have to read in detail yeah I have to
okay that's my homework that's not gonna
be my homework so Daniel says by using
bit bit wise operation operators you are
opting into less readable code yeah
exactly
so are you guys any of you guys see
programmers because you know I I rent a
lot again in C because you know you know
again is any of the low-level languages
and design their stuff so I was running
so I mean if you guys disagree I mean
you have to say it okay I mean you have
to say it because you know then you know
you it like if you have a like when I'm
say is saying something or rant again is
some you know which I I do often you
know see stuff UNIX philosophy stuff and
if you really disagree I mean like you
don't see my point at all like you you
have some opinion you want to say you
have to say it you know type it I don't
mind you at all you know you know yeah I
don't mind at all so you have to say it
you say it so that other people can see
it you know when you know when they if
they happen to listen to this talk show
and I may or may not agree you know I
may or may not you know I you know
there's so it's you know sometimes I see
you a point you know and sometimes a Co
point and disagree still and you know
you know but feel free to you know just
counter you know my opinions
so that's about so actually I kind of
just wandered off into programming
language design okay what was the
original topic I why did I became why
did I start to toe language design okay
so yeah yeah oh yeah so I was talking
about yeah so let me backtrack oh yeah
so I you know I know what I'm saying
let me show you okay it's all good so
yeah I was talking about graphics
programming you know graphics
programming pain and I was talking about
how idiotic is the OpenGL technology
okay and I was talking about there is an
effort to create an a graphics 3d
graphics API that's actually the way I
like and which is Fahrenheit this is
back in 1990s okay wait this is backing
I think around 2000 year 2000 1997 okay
so so Fahrenheit is the one of the
project and quick-draw 3d is another
project the quick-draw 3d is from Apple
so both of these technologies are a high
level
graphics API designed you know supposed
to replace the OpenGL because OpenGL is
you know I don't like know it like
in my opinion OpenGL is this the same
kind of mode of thinking as the see you
know UNIX and see phosphors and camp
canvas okay so HTML canvas they are crap
okay deity but so of some quick draw 3d
and Fahrenheit you know they are high
level they are what I was looking for
however they both of this project for
you know business reasons or whatever
they folded they never came to be so
today we are still dealing with OpenGL
you know the worst you know this so
as I was saying you know in line with my
point of view is that the C UNIX they
are like they are scum they are viruses
you know and same thing in the same way
so I mean OpenGL is also part of it
they are viruses they spread you know
they are you know so lousy but kind of
simplistic simple in a simplistic way
not in a minimal design you know elegant
way they are like just sloppy and
simplistic and fast that's the point so
they spread like virus so they get
people used to the whole industry adopt
them then they kind of you know then she
becomes you have tsipras first Java and
you have all the languages based on its
syntax you know so they kind of grow and
spread you know like a variable say go
and spread and OpenGL and there's no way
it's like you cannot kill them and also
tear donald knuth stack and and later on
a lot lot heck you cannot rid of them
because they they are like they they
they grow they root you know into things
because you know you get rid of them
there's a whole issue of compatibility
you know there's like a whole history of
them you cannot you know the computer
will not work you know kind of like that
so it's it's and x11 the linux x11 as
well it's also part of the hidden crap
so that's you know that's my very very
strong complaint about this kind of
thing they they you know they are you
know no design simplistic you know fast
crappy and but they spread you know
because it's simple and you know they
spread so to this day you know you it's
hard to kind of replace OpenGL although
I think these days Microsoft is
Microsoft is direct 3ds
now I'm I'm not a game programmer I try
to study them I never get into it I mean
it never went anywhere so but I've heard
you know from reading other people's
articles directory is actually just much
better than OpenGL I think John kamek
kamek the famous tomb created you know
he he said that as well I mean this is
even ten years ago so yeah you know you
see so in terms of design kind of things
computer languages design you know I I
see the point that let that sometimes
you need you know to be practical you
need a speed you know so but that you
know many C programmers or C++
programmers for example these type of
programmers they don't they don't get my
point you know they know they can think
of is that you need speeds therefore it
is necessary that is not my point of
course obviously I know you need speed
obviously I know there's many
constraints especially you know thirty
years ago but still there's a difference
in design you know there is a difference
between no design thing like see okay no
design product like citrus press okay
and OpenGL okay that's one group versus
versus where where you actually have or
all the same concerns as see but but yet
the outcome is different yet you know
that you know the system the firm
language is different if you if you are
aware the separation between the
separation of issues between you know
the language you know like as an API or
and its implementation you know what is
irrelevant to the programmer so you know
that's what I mean so I was giving an
example where something machine can
figure out you know so I was you know
attack talking about the Fahrenheit and
quick-draw
you know OpenGL stuff
and I was talking about I was giving an
example of type inference in : that's
that's how we came to this topic type
inference in goal and we're you know
he's you see you example this is
patently obvious and simple type
inference but however you see you know
see first as you see or needed so so
here is an example where you know
something program you know the machine
can figure out we really don't want it
to be exposed to the programming
language that's one example so so I was
saying you know yeah about design um
let's see so let's read the comments a
little bit actually
so today so today I did good with my
computer so everything is smooth so
let's read the comments so Danielle says
by using bitwise operators you are
opting into less readable code yes
exactly
nonetheless that doesn't stop us right
what do you mean like people still want
to use it oh okay don't come says the
people who make the low-level graphics
API will say is the community's
responsibility beyond high level API on
top of it
that's rally yeah but that never happens
I mean okay so is that valid as far as I
know it never happens like Emacs is
beyond on top of C and UNIX that's not
true you can say that but that's it's
actually that doesn't that's that's kind
of you can say that to anything I mean
so so so okay Duncan so you are saying
that this low-level graphics API exists
because those people
think that high-level stuff can be built
on top of them
and you're saying one example is Emacs
you know on top of C and UNIX I don't
think these two fit together because UK
then you can say any anything built on
top of high-level period on top of C or
UNIX is is kind of yeah I don't think
that makes sense I mean how do i
illogically say you know yeah I think
you know what I mean so Daniel says the
launch strategies for Windows Vista and
Windows 7 were both accompanied by a by
an immense marketing push by Microsoft
for DirectX yeah I can't I yeah I don't
know windows take but I I think I you
know I think that's true because I've
read you know the news open geo is
nonprofit open standard yeah OpenGL well
the SGI folded so what was the name
before OpenGL you know from SGI I think
there's a something GL I forgot what's
the name you know I you know as you know
you for II you know listen to minimize
my talks I'm not you know to found of
the open source typically okay
the open source standard they become
open when the company no can no longer
make money out of something you know
like they they are about to bankrupt or
they basically it's not a command of
commercial value something is you know
something X is known no longer has
commercial value like you cannot make
money out of it then they do open source
that's a that's that's happened that's
happened to Mozilla which we got Firefox
that happens to lots of Technology Sun
so okay so there was one topic it's let
me show you something different
interesting
okay so I'll talk show okay so let me
show you so yesterday we talked about
web analytics we talked about spam and
web analytics so let me show you my
website traffic now this is a secret
okay
you guys are all privy to see my website
traffic folks are either info
I have several websites books are
leaving for his is the most busy one
most popular so if you look at my
website so this is Google's analytics
now Google Analytics is a kind of a
marketing tool it gives you statistics
about your website about you know who is
viewing your website how much you made
you know on what page you know the
people audience interest gender age age
group interest you know and things like
that they have you know they let you
know web sites such as New York Times or
any website you know need to make money
you know to be fine you know like
today's website every detail like
everywhere the ad is placed which fun to
use you know where the button is face
the whole design everything is is
catered is optimized to the tee you know
to squeeze monies because like Amazon
you know or website oh oh media website
you know and they you know the two
options because they can test you know
they you know they did so optimize to
retain users you know get more clicks so
they have all sort of JavaScript
gathering statistics like like where you
stopped
you know pause on a page and so on so
and one of the tool they use is of
course Google you know Google is doing
that because
you know the more web traffic the more
money Google makes you know so here you
know the analytics is one of the Google
store basically used by every website
you know the top top 5,000 top million
website probably but let me show you a
website Alexa ranking so there is this
website that ranks that rang ranks the
traffic of all web sites in a world now
if you have a website if you are your
website business you probably already
know but if you are not then you don't
know I know because I mean a website
business you know I'd run website for
over 20 years so Alexa is owned by
Amazon by the way so if you go here you
can see let's see resources features you
know it used to be a top link but now
they they try to make money let me show
you resources ebooks ok feature top
sites okay this is they have a ranked
ranking of all the words website so
right now you know for like 10 years a
10 years so for example you can
see here so google.com is a number one
website basically they have so anyway
then YouTube Facebook bi do bi do is
like Chinese Google search engine and
Wikipedia QQ you see QQ is a website for
micro blogging like Twitter in China
Taobao is like China's Amazon okay
amazon has a chinese version as well but
Taba is the you know the the most
popular you buy things in China
Yahoo Yahoo he's still number eight you
don't hear about Yahoo these days so
Teemo is another shop inside in China
Amazon is number 10 Twitter is number 11
Soho Soho is another search engine in
China you see I was quite amazed by how
China China has fragra stream and ously
like everywhere I look I mean I've been
observing this top 100 top 500 websites
since at least 10 years ago like you
know you can find my blog you know at
least 10 years ago I have been writing
about it computer languages website
popularity
google search ranking and there is oh
yeah so this article is written back in
2008 and I was actually ranking the
traffic's of computer language websites
you know so you see so the sand outcome
you know as we know Sun Sun is Sun
Microsystems they are dead now so you
get a glimpse of history a lot history
here MySQL dot-com / comm php.net in
ways ranking ok so site con cast legs
okay here's the yeah here's the ranking
basically Sun was the most popular then
Java then PHP by the way you see my
website back then this is this one so I
was ranking quite high more higher than
Perot is he mean this is truth by the
way this is 2008 s Kellogg jwz jwe Z's
famous jamie zawinski he's famous for
Netscape and famous for X Emacs then you
see Novick Novick is Peter Novick the
Lisp Common Lisp expert and AI expert of
previous generation so you got Emacs we
be quickie you got friends friends is a
common lisp vendor and so on jika
monkeys is a very popular common lisp
book yeah practical communism so you see
I am I was ranking the traffic of
popular websites then I was ranking you
know check check the ranking of web dev
sites and so on so this this is like
2008 so that's interesting you might
check out
but I have I came to talkin let me read
the comments
okay Duncan says Duncan says back to the
so Duncan says the analogy is that high
level languages such as lisp can be
built using the low level ones such as c
for people who don't want to use a low
level one I disagree I mean okay then he
says high level 3d API is is typically
come attached to a game engine yeah you
can say that but I don't I don't agree I
don't think I mean you can say that to
anything low level you see okay so when
you design something low level of course
you always need something low level I
mean you cannot have a world where every
language is just high level in that you
know you cannot do that you have to have
you know assembly and see like you know
low level language so low level is
obviously you know it's necessary so you
have to have low level so you are saying
you know those who create the low level
thinking that you know it serves as a
kind of a foundation then you can build
high level stuff yeah that's all of
course I mean that's true but however
what I'm saying is that I mean that's
always true because of course high level
is always being on top of low level
that's true doesn't matter what it's
always true but what I'm saying is that
this C and this this OpenGL you know
they are pair to be designed I mean even
bad design you're still going to be all
high level stuff on top of course you
know so you cannot say you cannot use it
as a reason to say that therefore they
are good you know therefore they are
good design because you know high level
can build on top of them
I mean high level is always built on top
of low level stuff you know regardless
how you know how you design so that's
what that's what I'm saying that's okay
that's that's my counter
yeah so I you know yeah anyway so uh
Danielle says OpenGL evolved from iris
Gaea okay yeah I was thinking iris Gia
you know iris you know iris iris is
there you know the SGI
you know Silicon Graphics Inc their
operating system is called iris yeah
they they they have a name like you know
they have that's their name so Duncan
says Jimmy Wales wants endless donation
because we hip here gets a trillion hits
yeah so waste do it did I have we keep
here here
what was it from was it I forgot what
what was the topic about that anyway so
let's go back to yeah maybe let's go
back to this topic so I was joining so
this website you know Alexa ranks
websites yeah and and that's you know
you can find out you can actually if you
have a website you can find out where
your website ranks for example actually
we just read we just run into it over
here see let's click that lets go there
you see so global rank is my website is
top forty four thousand and in USA is
top twenty five thousand so I've been
checking these like since ten years ago
um every every year or two and actually
I'm not doing bad you know sorry dot
info because you know you can actually
check any website let's let's see so
remember I'm 44 K okay let's see Python
let's go here and say
Python dot it was it Python calm
what does that refer to
so anyway so a Python down hook so let's
see Python Todd oh okay they are much
higher
nyow eight so Alexa they they rank only
the top one hundred thousand psyched
let's see let's see what some other side
to check but anyway you know you can you
can type any website name here and find
out how they rank so let's go back to my
let me show you the Google Analytics
three people watching less and less
so Google Analytics so so it shows me
currently I have like fifty three people
watching so I so in general I have like
66k users a week now this this is weekly
you can change it you know last seven
days so basically 10k uses a day and
this is geo time report you can see like
typically I have from thirty to fifty
sixty users every you know every moment
and you can see these are the web's
webpages they are they are looking at
typically its Unicode you know my
unicode page you saw icon top and they
you know so this is real time and Google
also shows you you know where people are
looking at yet you you know where people
are kept coming from yeah so that's one
part of it let me show you others
go back so this is Google Analytics and
you know traffic channel you know how do
you how where do you retain users you
know I really I don't like these things
because they are you know Google or
these companies they are extremely
commercialized you know this is the
backbone you see all these statistics
how you retain users you know how your
active users trending all the time you
know
are you users you know what are your top
devices are they using desktop are they
using mobile are they using tablet and
where they can come from and which date
you know which are is a busy busiest you
know and so on you know lots of
statistical information why they do that
because this is this is actually the
backbone of the of the internet because
everyone you know this info are useful
when you want to make money they track
you you know treated you know you know
the top 500 thousand let's say top 100
thousand did they track you everything
they want to know because with this
information then you can you know trick
your website you know trick the button
design color everything so your you have
only one goal to make more money you
know you do all sort of things possible
so this also helps you know clickbait
you know you you read article you know
you you phrase the title so it's
dramatic and so on then you can check
your statistics okay okay how many males
clicked how many females clicked you
know
and what age group they click so you get
that information and tomorrow you write
an article that you you know yeah all
these kind of things so that's why we
the gym you know Internet becomes
bad you know it's like you go to like
hacker news sites all the basically or
the website you don't see information
you don't see real information anymore
you just see empty content and clickbait
and copied content you know it's like
that so anyways so let me show you what
pages are most popular on my website so
let's see comments I have made so many
kind and helpful folks on keep hideous I
person
okay I got three people watching which
is very low is it because the timing
let's see what is it yeah so yeah you
know one Krong so yeah it must be the
timing and date because I know it's like
when you know it's like four crowd
controlling three o'clock in morning in
New York and you know one o'clock in the
morning in California people went to bed
but what about European users so
European is like nine o'clock right now
nyow nyow o'clock ten o'clock in the
morning but however it's Saturday
wait he's a Saturday is a Friday for
them
Google's assumption is that you don't
want to help people but instead suck up
maximum time and attention
what do you mean Google's assumption
about who so anyway so so yeah let's
show you you know this guy funny this
frankerz frankerz Renee LED radio he is
a common list expert okay he worked he
worked at the you know the air plane
ticket website that's written in common
lisp and so to google GOOG about it
remember the name anyone remember the
name you know it's it's big news so you
know you have this company that sells
that the website that tells you you know
which ticket to buy like cheapest or
something like that you know from you
know air travel and it's written in
common lisp so about 2008 something like
that or 2005 Google bought it so then he
you know so he he was working for that
company then he worked at Google I don't
know if he still works at Google but
anyway he says familiar-looking syntax
but actually hideous complex semantics
pythons easy prosperous ha attractive
nuances whose authors deserve Jaeho time
yeah
like yeah you know I totally agree with
the sentiment but however I know of
course a lot of people do not agree I
have a friend which I respect very much
his name is David Capello and he he was
my partner when we when I started work
you know when I was working on Ocoee max
project
ergo Emacs was a project that is a Emacs
distribution just like today's space max
you know you download ago you max you
got everything you know in one in one
package you you know you don't have to
you know worry about things you just are
to use it so so David Capello he was you
know he and me are working on this
project and he is a C C++
he's a C++ expert you know and he is
very he's a strong defender zippers
first so he doesn't agree with my you
know ideas you know my my hatred for CNC
first ITA software that's it thank you
Duggan yeah so ITA Software was the
software that sells a plane ticket
something like that and Google bought it
and it's written in Common Lisp okay
daniel says a graph database allegro
cash what does that refer to
I mean what's the context I forgot
a Lego cache is a object persistence in
Lisp okay friends made by friends you
know friends you know France is a common
lisp company but I think they kind of
they are becoming like one person
operation since like ten years ago I
think maybe three percent something like
that because you know the open source
you know
ideology killed everything so Allegro
they they create common list IDE and you
know the whole thing in one package IDE
and common list implementation they are
one of the most popular back then in
1990s you know you know very good
product you know but I think they kind
of just made a way because open-source
you know then you have the open source
several open source implementations then
you know there's just kills everything
but anyway they are still on Twitter
though you can kind of you can still see
them they treat now and then I don't
know who is running it now so anyway so
yeah all right I don't know what Allegro
cache is about so back to so what topics
should be interesting so I was talking
about oh yeah I was going to show you
what with my website are the most
popular so so actually basically these
are the top ten most popular pages on my
website sorry dot info and you as you
can see basically all of them Unicode
let me show you one page
my unicode project you see so so all
these so this page is about Unicode
arrows you know you can see these
hundreds of different errors available
in Unicode and I have emoji characters
I showed this Unicode page a few times
so you probably know but anyway so these
are or the Unicode Unicode pages you
know it's funny you know the Unicode
pages you know the most popular you see
that the unica arrow has got 19,000 in
seven days so that's like 3,000 a day
3,000 3,000 visitors a day then the
Egyptian hieroglyph is like 1000
visitors a day so these are the top 10
and if you go to the next top top 20 to
30 you can see that it mostly still
unicode except one javascript page now
this javascript pages has it has been
very popular for like about 10 years
about nine years yeah so this is a and
actually this is the only this is my
basically one just like one of the to
only popular page for JavaScript
nobody VD others my JavaScript in depth
so anyway so this interesting thing
going on because this javascript in
depth for example and
and many of my tutorials actually they
they you know many of my programming
tutorials technical topics they take me
far more time to create like like 10
times more time 100 year ten times more
time to create then then the Unicode
pages you know you know this like the
Unicode is there's not much to it it's
just fun único but so I have written
JavaScript in depth in you know coli and
other technical other technical topics
such as you know syntax soup you know
some of these articles they really take
sometimes days to write and these these
are like my opinions and they are rare
opinions you don't find it the Omani you
know you almost don't see it anywhere
else so what I'm saying there's an
interesting phenomenon as can be seen in
my weblog is that I noticed that you
know to get more popular I mean I mean
suppose you are a mathematician you
study 10 years you know in you know in
in a most advanced math you know then
you write a page about it nobody read it
you know what is popular is actually
those that doesn't require you know
thinking that that you know you know
like gossip you know politics common
political commentary gossips celebrity
gossips it's kind of like that so it's
kind of a sad situation for society you
know so I have you know these thousands
pages on you know some very topics on
programming or math but they don't you
know have use have you know basically
half of my website traffic is
is the is just this emojis you know it's
you know so it's kind of a sad situation
hey info Matic great to see you great
token info Matic Centennial is in like
California Duncan is in Scotland right
an informatics you wait you are you from
Morocco right so what I missing Morocco
8 o clock in the morning so actually I
think we kind of yeah we kind of like
exhausting I mean we Morocco yeah Marco
is kind of interesting let's look at
which so yeah we covered a few things
today I think that's about it
what I want to say you know it's over an
hour now yeah so maybe let's look at
Morocco Google Maps
because I don't know nothing about
Morocco so what is interesting in
Morocco tomorrow is actually in northern
Africa
so non Second Life life actually I
should fly towards the east
I don't like all antic Ocean I like the
Pacific Ocean
so Morocco let's go to Morocco okay what
language does moral core speak
oh they speak Islamic some kind of
Arabic
so which city should I look at in
formatic
so when is Morocco like
oops
ooh this is some kind of Oasis so
Morocco is lots of deserts I think
knee of okay so Morocco speaks Arabic
dialect macness near face
in the center okay let's go to let's go
back to Morocco
Oh macness okay okay I probably
pronounced it wrong
let's see in the center yeah so this
city let's magnify
I don't think I ever looked at Morocco
okay so we we start to see the city now
the street
again it's let's drop into Google Street
View
let's see what we can see okay there is
no Street View except just some
locations with photo macness okay I
pronounced it right
okay so whoo this is strange so you have
a road but you know both sides of wars
that's kind of strange why would they
cover it with wars
Oh Imperial City RC oh okay yeah this
there's no Street View so I cannot like
you know go into it so let's go back
every time
sixteenth century oh okay let's go back
to
when did it go
oh yeah well first let's let's look at
fasting
we can see like city like buildings you
know like big city maybe let's look at
that as interesting our face is the old
capital
okay and it's
Casa Blanca
hold on second before we go let's know
get some rays here
this is coffee shop cigarettes this is
inside Moroccans
let's see
let's see some other place
that's your rabbit
okay so
again lots of places let's see
so it's nice to look at
Casa Blanca ok that's near the beach
you know okay
Arabic
economic capital okay Cassandra
Casablancas is the economic capital okay
good yeah this is what I like to see
lots of array big science
cool
so anything else interesting guys so
maybe we close close sharp for the day
let's see four people are watching yeah
Oh in like 80 minutes this okay info
Matic let's pick one more spot then we
say goodbye so it was you know like like
anything interesting about Morocco not
necessarily your spot but anything
interesting actually I want to look at
the beach let's see
Oh
okay
like easier a beach with a you know very
squeals and all that
let's see
okay
ok I think that's it for today maybe God
weather okay I think I think that's it
for they set for today so thank you guys
for coming and very tasty food okay
thank you guys for coming and I'll see
you next time bye