[clears throat] Welcome to another
episode of Kas talk show. We are going
to do advent of code 2025 day three.
Uh we started yesterday but I got a I
got a call. Uh so I have to go. So we
aborted so we're going to continue
yesterday.
Advent of code day uh 2025 day three in
wam language
if you are watching this offline play
1.5 speed if you are watching this uh
here
post comment okay love to see your
comments so let's see um yeah let's
begin so let's start wam language
the most powerful programming language
And I have tutorials just search for it
wam language for programmers. You will
find complete tutorial and uh where to
download for free. Okay. So wam language
new uh notebook evaluate three to start
the kernel and magnify.
So we got a notepad going. Okay. So, w
language.
Now, my keyboard. Let me show you guys
my keyboard. Um, my keyboard. This is
ultimate hacking keyboard 80. I have
reviews on YouTube. Okay. So, video
check, audio check. Okay, this is not
good here.
So, I need to bring this up somewhere
here.
Video check. Audio check.
Okay, let's begin. So yesterday the
problem was [clears throat]
at the end of code 2025
day three. The problem was given a list
of numbers. For each number you want to
pick two digits
in the number such such that the two
digits combined forms a number that is a
maximum.
Okay. So for example 9876 something
something something in this case the
answer would be 98 9 and 8 then 98 so
that is the largest largest two digits
number you can form out of this
number uh so the algorithm would be
first pick the largest digit in the
number but not the last one
not the last digit
Okay. Then pick a large largest digit
from the digits that is after the digit
you picked. Okay. So let's code that.
Okay. So let's say uh
let's say this example. So first of all
you you need to pick a digit. So this
this is normally a string but you can so
in from language you can deal with
string or you can deal with the number
and take digits. So let's see. So let's
see all functions
that whose name contains the word digit.
Shift enter. So you got a huge number of
functions whose name contains the word
digit. Let's do it again. So it's two
columns.
Okay. So far so good comments guys.
Uh let's see
that is my Twitter. Okay. Move from
notebook here.
Here.
Okay. So from digits digit signature
digit block uh so digit characters
digit Q real digits
from digits integer digits number digits
okay so let's look at integer digits
gives a list of the decimal digits in
the integer
okay let's just try some of
So if you give that number, what does it
return?
Okay, that return integer digits. That's
what it does. Now,
now what is number digits? returns the
digit corresponding to
10 to the power n in real value number.
Okay, not sure what's the difference.
Oh, this is a new function number digit.
Let's see. This is this is a new
function in the past five years.
Does it say
new in 2021?
That is why my Wolfman programming
language mod doesn't have it syntax
colored. So let's see what it does. I
think it's the same thing. I think it's
designed for
uh floating point
with one argument. Uh so it needs two
arguments.
So let's look at the detailed
documentation.
Okay,
return the digit corresponding to
uh 10 to the nth power in the real
valued number.
So yeah, so this is designed for
floating numbers I believe. So if we can
look at some of the examples.
One, two, three, four, five,
two.
Okay. So it it picks a digit. Okay. It
picks a digit from, you know, a position
in a digit,
right? So it allows you to pick one
digit.
Okay, let's ignore that.
So integer digits you want to find the
uh maximum the first one
except the last one. Okay, so you drop
so that returns a list. You drop the
list. Let's make it one uh something
smaller. Let's say
1 2 3
8 9.
Okay, let's say that number
91238.
Uh wait, let's try a different number.
Let's say that A1239.
Okay.
Then
then you want to drop drop the last
digit. Okay. Drop.
So look at the documentation. Drop gives
the list with the first n element drops.
Dropped. Give the list with the last n
element dropped. Okay. So drop that.
Drop the last one. Okay.
312 8123. Okay.
So then you want to get the maximum.
Okay.
Uh let's see the documentation. Max.
That would be three. I mean eight. Okay.
Then you Okay. Then you um
max. Then you
Okay. You you Okay. You pick the max.
You need to know position. You need to
know where is the position of the
largest number. Then
then you need to remove everything all
the digits in front because you need to
pick the rest of it. Okay? So that would
be
position
position.
Uh
now let's make this interesting. So
let's make this number uh let's say 7
9. Okay.
Okay. So
okay then then what do you get then? Um
then maximum
is eight.
Okay. Correct. Then position you want to
know
position of the max
that would be two. The index
That's right. Okay. So, then you want to
drop
then you want to drop
[clears throat]
uh
drop the original. Um
from zero to um to that position you
picked. Okay. So what is the
give a list from element m through n
dropped. So you want to drop the first n
element.
Um
okay. So
that would be
basically two. Okay. Basically you want
two here.
Okay. Then you pick Then you pick the
max
which is nine. Okay. Then you pick the
first number.
Uh the first number you picked what is
this max eight. So the uh answer for
this number is 89. Okay. 89. So, so you
got the digit eight, you got the digit
nine, then you want to make it uh into a
number. So, you want to turn a list of
digits into a number. So, how do you do
that? Let's see.
That would be from digits.
Okay, click on that. from digits
construct integer from list of its
decimal digits. That's right.
Okay. You can look at the full
documentation here.
[snorts] 125.
Okay. So that would be
[clears throat]
from digit 89. You got 89. 89 to 89.
Okay. So that is effectively
uh how we solved it. Okay. So let's see.
So input the list of numbers argo steps.
So this these are the steps. So now we
just need to combine these steps into
one function.
So let's write a function. Okay. Uh
define
we can um define a function
extract
big
uh let's say extract max two
digits. Okay, let's name it that.
So that is a function we're going to
define here. And uh the so the function
input x is a number and what the
function does is this bunch of things.
Okay,
we're going to combine them into one
thing. Okay, so before we do that,
[cough]
[clears throat]
let's make a example.
uh
from language. So you can see syntax
color showing browser. So here is
today's code. And now let's put this um
let's put this example case into a uh
into a independent example. Okay. So
actually so
okay now syntax showing browser. So here
we have a example we want to extract
given a number extract two digits such
that they form a biggest number. Okay.
And then
then we start to code.
It starts to code. Okay. So here is the
function.
So given a number. So uh so wait. So
integer digits this is just um
x
okay so what do we want to do okay let's
say block
is a local variable so we create local
variable here So
digit list equals to
that. Okay.
Then what you want to do is you drop
Drop the digit list. Drop the last one.
Then you apply maximum.
Okay. And uh and this expression
can be written as
that. Okay.
So let's write it let's write it as so
you max drop then uh so this can be
first
make it easier to see uh my hands
type type too much is got problems
if you're here comment okay am I going
am I going well let's see uh where is my
YouTube
three people. Okay. Say hi.
So back to Wufam language. We are coding
this. Almost done. Perfect.
Okay. So extract. So first then okay see
this is a list of um
a list of constants. Okay so let's not
put value there. Let's just give a list
of constants. Okay.
So xdigit list.
Okay. then
first digits.
Okay, then you got the first digit. Then
what?
Then you want to take the position.
So this max is just the first digits.
Now let's change it to let leave it.
Okay. So position
and uh here is the xdigit list. Okay. So
that is the position of the first digit.
Then you drop
Then you drop two.
Yeah. So that that's the position. So
this would be xdigit list. you drop.
Okay, so you drop
so the first digits
that actually return a nested list.
Okay,
max
then position returns a
nested list with two braces. Okay, then
you drop. Let's look at the drop
documentation comments.
So drop. Let's see
if at least with element m through n
dropped. So first so first do that. So
what you want to do is that here you
want to say
flatten.
Okay. Flatten
then at least starting from the first
one to this position.
Okay. First digit position. Let's create
another
um another local variable so that it's
easier to read.
Okay, first digit position. So now you
flatten
starting from the first to the first
digit position. Okay. So that would be
you do that then you pick the max. Okay.
Max at that. So this would be second
digit.
Second digit equals to that. Okay. So
there's inconsistency naming but let's
don't bother. Let's move on.
Okay. So you got first digit then you
got second digit.
Then you just
then you just from digits x first digits
wait let's let's rename them. Okay let's
rename the first digit because that's
too long. Okay.
Uh let's rename then.
Okay. Then the second digit. Let's
rename them.
Okay. Save it. Close. Reopen. And now
color them.
Okay, now it's better. So digit list
digit least first digit digit first
first digit position second digit then
from digit would be just um
okay. So you got basically um
[clears throat]
yeah
that's it. I think that's it. Let's
shrink um let's purify our code. Okay,
that's the code. So if if you have this
function, you can call it. Let's see.
Let's can we can try any of these number
A1 A1. Let's try this one. So this Okay,
let's see if it works.
Hopefully. Did I make any error? So
let's um maybe indent so it's easier to
read.
Let's just run it.
89.
Fantastic. Now put a comma here so it
doesn't show the value of the function.
So run it again.
89. Fantastic. Now uh what what about
the first one?
Right again
98. That's correct. Now we can map this
function to the list of inputs. Okay. So
map this function to x input. Okay. So
remove that and uh that should be the
result.
Okay. 98 89 78 92. Let's check if we are
correct.
Okay. Then total 357. Let's total them
up. Total
minute
357.
Fantastic and beautiful. So this is our
code wam language code. One single
function. Okay.
Now I use a bunch of variables. So it
provides clarity.
Otherwise you don't need all those
variables. You can like munch them into
like one kind of cryptic pure functional
programming code. Okay. This is pure
this is this is supreme functional
programming.
Um in most other languages like
[clears throat] Python, JavaScript, you
don't have things like integer digits.
um possibly Python has a library that
added that for
uh it's a it's it's convenient for um
number theory kind of things. Okay. So
anyway,
so that is the result. Now we just need
to put uh use the custom input. Okay.
Now put it back syntax correct show in
browser. So that's today's talk show.
First
uh example, then our code. Now, let's
get our personal input.
Get your personal input. Okay. A bunch
of big numbers. Copy. No problem.
Okay. 200 numbers. Big. Okay.
Now, uh you need to save this somewhere.
So, let's save it. Let's pick a name.
Okay. Something like that. So, close.
Close. Save it.
The end of code
date.
What?
What the
Okay, let's try again. What? What did I
do?
Undo. Undo. Now open I slash advand of
code that. Okay. Now uh input copy close
close. Now let's modify this.
What?
day three.
and uh text.
Okay,
let's see.
Input. Okay, so you need to say input
day three input.
Where is my Okay, there. Okay, copy
that. Now, save it.
This name.
Yeah. Okay. Now, uh remove that. Save
it.
Copy that. Wait. Yeah. Copy file path
and
um and link it. Let's see.
Yeah. Okay. So now
paste that and in fact let's just copy
the code the input here. Okay.
So we
tree. Now here's our code. Okay. Uh
wait. So paste it and uh make it
quotation mark none separator by comma.
Yes. Okay. Then
cut
paste. Okay. And remove the last comma.
So this is our input.
Okay. 200 200 lines 200 numbers.
Okay. Now if we run this, let's just run
it.
Finished.
[clears throat]
Okay, you got a problem. This is not
what we expected. Drop.
What the is a drop sequence
specification? Uh
expected position. Okay.
What is the prophet?
Nobody's here. If you are here, say hi.
Okay. So sequence specification drop
sequence specification
expected
uh so this syntax expected at position
two in drop. So here is input
then the second part is too long. That's
incorrect.
Wait what is the second part?
Okay. So when I call drop so you can see
copy that. So here is it. Okay. So
basically when I call drop
this is the first argument. Then the
second argument
I gave is this which is incorrect. It
should be one single number or at least
one or three numbers. Okay. So this is
basically a syntax error somewhere in
our drop. So let's open that. Open that.
So where is drop use? So flatten one two
digit one position. So
oh okay. So I think I got it. So when
you say position
of the digit uh when you say okay
digit one okay so when you get the
position of digit one if the if if that
digit is unique in the sequence then you
just got one position but if the if the
digit is not unique let's say two there
are any occurrences of two then this
position result is a list of positions.
Okay. So we only want the first one the
leftmost one. So so basically what you
have to say is you have to say position
return the first one. Okay. So let's see
pattern level spec. Oh okay. Pattern
level spec N.
Okay. So level spec would be level one
and return just the first one. Okay,
I think we can run it. It'll be correct.
Run it.
66 is our answer.
Now in case you are not familiar, let me
show this again. Okay. So, position.
Okay. So, position
digit list. Let's say um
what?
Okay. So, [clears throat]
let's say that digit list then let's say
the first digit is let's say uh five.
Okay. Let's remove that. So you see five
occur twice here. So normally
if you don't give optional argument you
know it'll return
it'll return
uh basically uh let's see
one and
two three four five six one and six.
Okay. So let's try it. One and six. six
in a nested list. You see, but now if it
occur multiple times, then you get um
I mean now you say level one but just
one item, you'll just return one. Okay.
Wait, did I I did something. Okay. Oh
yeah, there's a semicolon. You want to
remove the semicolon because semicolon
whenever you have a semicolon
semicolon is a shortcut for
compound expression. So whenever you
have
a
whenever you have semicolon
or with a new line that is
that is equivalent to
this. Okay. So compound expression in
lisp is similar to lisp's
p og
uh p o uh was it p and p o g program
okay so anyway
so so in this case when you have a
semicolon this BB is omitted that became
new so the whole thing just return new
because that's the last expression so
you don't want that. So now evaluate it
again.
You got that? Okay. Fantastic and
beautiful.
Okay. That's a explanation of position.
So let's copy it. Um
actually we done. [clears throat]
Let's just post the U
Sax.
Okay. That's our personal input. the big
one. Then 177
66 is our answer. Is it correct? Close
that.
Submit.
That's the right answer. You are one
gold star closer to decorating the North
Pole. Continue to part two. Okay, that
shall be tomorrow.
Uh maybe later today but
okay. So how are you guys doing? So you
can join my Twitter.
Where is my Twitter? Okay. Twitter.
Twitter here. Kasali Twitter.
That's me. That's me juggling back in uh
almost 20 years ago. Uh so you can join
my Twitter. You can join my discord.
Kasadi discord. We have all type of
characters here.
This annoying uh so we are doing
advanced code. Some people are doing it
in
uh G scheme lisp
and uh emory board is doing it in um
common list I believe.
Okay. So that's it. Thank you guys for
watching. If you like my stuff, pay me.
Okay. So go to kasali.info.
Let me show you x a h le.info.
http no s. Okay. Then go down. Then you
go pay me. Patreon. Amazon gift card me.
PayPal me. Okay.
Bye guys. We shut down in one minute.
So let's see. Did we do everything we
wanted to do? Day three. Yes.
Correct. Simple problem. Uh we need to
uh we need to fix this a little bit. So
let's do that. Fix
position
of this list of this item.
and uh at at level one
and uh return just one of them. Okay,
put it back. Syntax correct. Refresh.
Okay,
fantastic.
Now let's beautify this code. Can we
beautify like like make it really
minimal? Okay, we can. We can. And let
me just do that. Okay.
Uh pre
language code.
Okay. We can truly minimize this
function. Okay. So let me show you how.
So you got a bunch of um
first of all, let's color them.
Let's remove redundant call. I mean
redundant um
unnecessary number of variables. Okay.
Actually this is good.
Yeah. So, so our goal here is just to do
some kind of pure functional lambda
calculus play to make this to make this
function not use any local variables at
all yet remain efficient. Okay. Okay.
Let's try let's do that.
Uh this you can do with wam language
because wra language allow this kind of
thing. You cannot
you can you kind of can do it in lisp
like scheme lisp but not common lisp not
e emac lisp in schem you can somewhat do
it but not all the way let me show you
so this is pure functional programming
remember the goal is to remove any use
of local
constants or variables including local
constants okay like no variables at all.
Uh, okay. So, let's let's do that.
Okay. How you going to do it?
Okay. So,
wait. Copy that. Okay.
Digit list digits one digit one
position.
So position
you can remove. Okay. position is used
once.
Okay. One variable gun.
Okay. Then
then this flatten
I like it to use the add sign reduce the
number of nesting. Okay. Then
then what you're going to do is you can
digit one digit two.
So from digits digit one digit two.
Okay.
Okay, easy.
So, digit one is used uh several places
here. Okay,
so from digits
there will be a function.
Okay. So, first of all, you need a
function to uh
Okay. So why why
okay
so function that net x Okay so then y
so then this is just
y. Okay. So this is just actually
Okay. Then then then
this is
digit one we don't need.
Then digit two we don't need.
Okay. So then from digits then from
digits
at
that
digit one digit two. Okay.
[sighs and gasps]
And uh this is the expression. Okay. So,
do you guys see
what I'm doing? And you don't need the
block anymore.
So, you got a pure function.
Okay. Can you guys see what I'm doing?
Let me let me maybe
syntax color. I mean
preformat a little bit.
Okay. So you got
rename it
And uh wait the digit one. Oh
Uh god.
So the digit one is still there. That
needs to be um
that digit one.
Hold on a second. Let me not rename
that.
Okay, so that digit one there needs to
be fixed.
Okay, we can do that. But then the code
becomes incomprehensible.
Oh, it's already is incomprehensible.
Okay,
let's see.
Oops.
Okay. So actually we simplify it
significantly.
So we don't even get any.
Can you guys see what I'm doing? Very
complicated code. So,
so
this block is equivalent to this block.
He he finally I got one two comments.
I'm doing AOC in my
in my own list dialect.
Okay, that's interesting.
Uh that that would be fun. Okay. So
anyway, so now let's comment it out and
let's run this. Let's see if it works.
357.
Yes, it works. Okay, so you can see um
these two.
Let me make a comment. This
uh let me give me a comment
without using any local variable or
constants.
Alternative
code
sure functional programming
supreme.
Okay. So that no local variables at all
but um but you do have like local
parameter names.
Um
anyway that okay that's it.
That's it. Bye.