so people have been asking me to to do a
Emacs - people want to see how I woke in
Emacs so I'm going to show you one today
so what I'm going to do is this is my
HTML file and starting up my browser
Firefox so this is my web block I'm
going to update my JavaScript web dev
blog you see there's this one Java
JavaScript floating floating box
following Cisco and I want to update the
code this code is before yes
2015 so I want to update it to 2015 code
you know you see these these are using
bars I'm going to change them to
constant so so this this is my Emacs and
this is the file so I'm just going to
walk through it so open the file and
this is the file first first of all I
want to see this file in Safari so you
see if I scroll down the box follows so
it's working in Firefox it's not working
because I have JavaScript turned off so
so go back to the file so first of all
update the date with a backup and let's
see so I want to okay so this this okay
there's this code section but first of
all I wanna see where is the JavaScript
file
now there it is so this is file and this
is a directory so I'm checking if it's
running typescript it's not so make a
backup and just start changing so you
see this is very old code so I'm going
to use of okay I don't even need to
function block so delete that that okay
so
sanction
okay let's let's see if that works it
may not because okay it's not because
because some of these are not constants
because I'm updating them that it's just
switch to intend it
oh you need to call it that's why so
wait
all right so move to update frequency
change back to offset from top moving
widget div so this should be let
probably there it is so okay now the
code is working copy it close it and go
back to the code here and this is pasted
here delete that and now just HTML eyes
it
okay let's see so that should be it
let's go back to Safari yes so well
usually I have to read the whole thing
through you know just to make sure you
know if there's any update I need to do
like changes in JavaScript or
documentation or whatever but for the
for this video
yeah you see here this is incorrect so
because the code has changed there's no
longer that Evo in place so anyway but
I'm going to just close this and wrap
this up so create a new section date and
copy that URL put the tag remove the
white space and that's it if you look at
you see this is the updated blog and now
I just need to because I'm using RSS
there's RSS going on so I need to update
a atom file so I just press the key and
that's it
close it save it and now I go to Nisha
you shall so now I pass Inc to my server
password
so that should be it okay now if you go
to sour
sorry info web death there it is so so
so that's it so that's how I update my
website thank you for watching
that's it for now so I'm going to do
probably am I'll do more and I'm
probably going to do a do one for
sapphire keys and all my eMac stuff okay