good morning guys welcome to another
episode of star talk show
uh today is 2020 first
march 27th almost end of the
end of march and the spring
spring is coming up i mean wow it is
march 21st is spring downstate of
spring so today the topic is gonna be
emacs and emac list
okay emacs and emac this uh i'm not sure
what to talk about actually
uh i don't have a focused topic so if
you have questions
this is the right time to ask me okay
anything
related to emacs so we're gonna focus on
emacs today
and there's a question uh already what
do i so there's a question from
uh q0 q0 he says
um what do you think about the default
undo
and redo mechanisms in emacs is it good
if no from your experience would you
recommend a better alternative
alternative so uh
emacs undo and redo that's a long story
okay
so let's search for i'll go emax undo
redo okay i have articles on that
um long story uh
okay let's look at two of the articles
it's magnify uh magnify
magnify okay actually i did a video talk
about that in 2019 december
4th uh actually we don't need to magnify
it because the
so emacs and do and we do now though if
you don't know emacs has a
very different uh undo reduced system
from
all the other modern applications in
emacs
the undo you know basically essentially
you don't have redo
okay emacs has only one concept undo
so you can but you you can actually redo
as well
but that is achieved so you so you can
think of and do as a history line so
in e-max you undo and do and do uh
in other applications in modern
applications you undo and do and do
and when you see that's a point you want
to start over then you can redo
okay i mean you can undo and do and do
and do or we do we do redo
and and once you find the the spot you
want
to basically start over then you start
to type something
then all those undo and redo are lost
you know basically you have a line of
history a linear line
no branches not not a tree a linear
linear line
so in modern applications you can just
undo or redo
until you find a point then you start
from there
then whatever you undo what we do before
it's gone
is basically uh you cannot uh
go back to them so that's a modern uh
concept of undo and redo now emacs is
different
in emacs you don't you don't really have
a
redo concept but you can achieve that so
in emacs how
the way emacs work is that again you
also have a line of history
so you can undo and do and do and do
there is no redo
okay so what what if you want to redo
like move
move up there you know uh so what you do
is you type something
emac will record that then you
undo what you typed then you undo
your previous undo okay so
oh let me let me try another way okay
you don't type something you press
escape you know basically you do
something that's not undo
then then you undo again it will undo
the undo
so in in some sense the emax weighs
in some sense uh actually simpler in
some sense
but in reality it's actually very much
very complex
because you know it's even hard to
explain
you know there's a lot of websites you
can you know search for emacs and do
you'll see you'll see them try trying to
explain it's basically like a roller
coaster
it's it's it's non-trivial it's not easy
to see at which point
is your undo history because emacs you
know so you undo undo undo
if you want to redo you you either type
something or press
escape you know ctrl g to cancel you
know you do something that's not undo
then you undo again that that is
actually
correspond to redo because you are
undoing the undo so you
if you undo again you are undoing the
undo the previous and do you are undoing
the previous and do
if you undo again you are undoing the
previous
previous previous previous undo so
that's
that's kind of the way emacs undo works
so there's no redo concept
so what so this uh this has
you know certain advantage you know
advantages
if you ask the emacs phonetics they'll
say oh this is better because
why because in this way you don't lose
you don't lose your undue history at all
you can always you know whatever you
undo don't redo you can always go back
to it
the problem is that it's very difficult
to find
you know because it's very difficult to
find
exactly at the point you want to start
over
so that is the the difference between
emacs and do
and the modern applications and do the
modern applications and do is very
simple you know you undo or redo or and
do we do
until you find a point you start from
there then whatever
you undo that we do before it's gone
okay
so for so i i started to uh
you know basically for 10 years i
so so there are a lot emacs packages
that um am i doing fine okay i'm doing
fine
there are a lot of emacs packages that
uh that tries to add the modern
redo uh concept and feature so you can
actually
undo or redo just like a modern
application
there are quite a few but however they
all they all have a problem they all
have a corruption problem okay
so i've been using this package i've
tried them all so 1997
there you know there is a package called
redo.el by this guy kyle e
jones now kyle e jones you know i kind
of know he's on
the news group gnu.emacs or
or dot emacs group.emacs.help
or com.emacs newsgroups you know
newsgroup instead so if you are young
you probably don't know what that is
is you know new scoop is the basically
uh online forum but but that's before
uh the world wide web existed before the
web pages
so anyway uh so in 1997
kyle uh he he's a very um
well-known e-max least coder
but i haven't heard from him you know
for almost 15 years now i i don't i
wonder
how he's he was doing it might be
interesting to look up kyle e jones
uh because back then he was on you know
he's one one of the big
emac this code so in 1997 he created
redo.el
that gives you redo feature in emacs so
you don't have to
so it's very easy to find uh which spot
you want to start over
then then in 2008 there's another guy
redo plus dot el which is a modification
of kyle e jones package you know
updated by this guy s irie okay
in 2008 then in 2009 this
toby cut uh created
from scratch a new undo redo package
okay again the primary purpose
is to allow emacs to have the modern
redo so you don't
have to like go around roller coaster
don't know where you are
but however so so i've been using them
i've been using each and every one of
them for several years
you know so i begin with using the kyle
johns then i
i saw oh there's uh redo plus it must be
better
after 10 years i saw i used that then in
2009 this undo tree
came up and become what you know widely
popular then i started to use that
suppose you know this toby cuts
uh toby corbett guy is a mathematician
you know he's a mathematician
a professor you can go to his website
i do have a link to his website but
somewhere or maybe i removed it because
you know over the 10 years
many websites come and go anyway he's a
mathematician
so but but the problem one one big
problem is that they always
or any one each one of them all have
a fundamental problem that is sometimes
you are doing you know undo and redo and
over certain emacs says no more undo
but you know this and do you know but
you might just tell you there's no more
undo
in other words the undo history got
corrupted
each one of them have this problem okay
each every one of them
like i i don't know until all of a
sudden after
you know a year it doesn't happen often
but after a year
if you know you do something serious
coding you you you are
you know you feel free to do a lot of
and do and redo
thinking that you know you just you can
get it back but all of a sudden emacs
this
is says there's no undo you know it
[ __ ] up
your you know then you lost you know
this
10 minutes of coding so that each one of
them all have this problem if you go
to reddit you'll see people talk about
that
problem but this problem is hard to
debug because
first of all it's very hard to reproduce
it doesn't happen very often
but once it happens you are [ __ ] you
know
usually you don't want you know because
you rely
you know you rely on knowing this and do
you know for example
deleted the whole package and i changed
a whole paragraph and i changed
something
and oh i thought you know let's try it
the way it was before then i can just
undo
you know so they all have these problems
so that's
that's a big problem you know and uh
that's a big problem
why does this problem happens because
undo
is a very fundamental emax feature you
know it's deeply
uh you know it's a part of c code i
suppose
if you um let's say uh let's see
uh wait where is the
okay so let's go to a simple dot el
so here is the undo code
uh wow uh hold on a second and let's see
so hold on a second let me magnify okay
let's magnify
so so let's see undo code
narrow to region so it's got hundred
lines
uh fairly complex anyway
so so why why this why you know these
are
uh great emacs list coders they are emac
these
experts you know many of them been
coding emacs for over 10 years
almost probably every one of them so why
does this happen this corruption
i don't know so nobody knows uh so i i
presume is because
the undo feature you know it's it's
i i never actually looked at the undo
code
but i suppose it you know it's fairly
complex it's called it's the core of
emacs
so whenever these external packages
tries to modify it
it's hard you know it's prone to uh bugs
i don't know exactly so nobody knows so
far so i haven't so far i haven't seen a
guy who actually
created a reproducible way to you know
have uh undo
corruption it happens to each one of
these because it happens to me
it happened to me for each one of these
undo package
you know it's all of a sudden i can't
undo anymore i lost
work so
so that's a that's one problem the other
problem there is a
e-max phoneticism because in e-max
community almost every year
people will complain you know emacs and
do because it's
it's unnatural you know but the emacs
phonetics
will insist you know they're they're
insane oh you are just the window idiots
you know
yeah that's their mentality maybe they
they are not as rude as i am but
basically their mentality is like go
[ __ ] yourself you go
go use your window go to use your
windows you know this
this emacs coat [ __ ]
so so there's this very strong emacs
code you know they
they they they tell everyone to you know
emacs and do is the best because you
don't know
you know you don't lose your you know
your undo history
so uh so this happened
uh and and uh you know so i have an
article on that emacs and do an emax
code
problem goddamn [ __ ] emacs undo
oops now my youtube is gonna be censored
for good you know i i i
actually i shouldn't be too much of a
rant today
uh and so i'm going so if your questions
you know type my name and i'm going to
read the
questions so anyway emacs and do a
problem
and it's also a code problem because the
e-max
phonetics they refuse to change you know
but meanwhile but the fact is every
almost every year
you'll see on reddit or whatever is the
current forum people will complain
you know emacs and do how does it work
you know what how do i get the you know
uh how do i get redo you know that
people want the modern
undo redo system you know it
happens every year and otherwise why
would people you know or
three guys you know every five year 10
years another guy writes a redo package
why does that happen because people do
want it
meanwhile in the emacs community
everyone is saying no
no emacs andrew is a you know the
perfect one
so it's a problem so so so and then
then you know then there's a corruption
you know this deep problematic
corruption issue so
it's a mess okay so it's a mess it's not
a good situation
uh so what can we do you know i would
recommend
you know i personally i would recommend
that
you have to get the emacs people the gnu
developers
not you know not writing another
package external package that fixes
emacs and do
because that's not going to work you
want this you want the emac
list developers to change
the [ __ ] emacs call so that it so
that either
it adopts the modern undo redo system or
provide the system so that you can have
a choice you know either the old
you know emacs undue system or the
modern way
you know the one one of the code problem
with emacs is that because emacs is very
old you know 30 years old
emacs has undo before any other
application
so in a sense you can say emacs invented
undo
okay yeah that's true but you know
things change you know it
so which is better so so now let me
jump to another question which which
using you know this has to do with user
interface or user experience
which which one is better and one you
know i actually think the modern way is
better
because the modern way you know you can
undo
all we do and do and do all we do to the
point you recognize
then you can start over from that okay
but whatever happened that
you know you can throw away basically
nobody very few people really care
you know it does happen sometimes you
made a mistake
but on the other hand the emacs and do
system
it's very hard to find you know to to
locate the point
after you have some undo and redo
because it's actually
if there's no redo you just undo undo
and do undo and do
and do the undos so so you don't know
you
after a while you don't you you can it's
very hard to find where you are
but it has an advantage of you never
lost your undo because you can just
but you cannot find it that's a problem
so between these two
systems if i have to make a choice you
know it's
let's suppose i'm the i'm richard
stowman i i'm telling people what to do
i would say use the modern system so you
know
you know throw away the emacs you know
the this
way okay use i i would say the the
modern undo is a better
uh user experience system
okay that's the situation uh so
currently i'm not using any of this
package once you know once i discovered
you know the the the you know the
corruption problem so i
i stopped i stopped using any of these
redo things
uh around 2015
yeah around that 2015 i stopped using
any of any of these
uh redo packages i just use
emacs undo so if i want to redo i just
you know press ctrl g then undo again to
undo the undo
uh you know and you know sometimes
if you want to do a lot redo and do it
gets very confusing
at that point once you have a few undues
above the undues
you basically become lost you know so
so you just be careful you don't you
don't you know you just
careful don't over undo okay or don't
over undo the undues once you find it
you know stop
you know do you know that's so today
with stuff like keys i don't use any of
this package i just use
um emacs and do plain emacs and do so
that's the situation about the the undo
okay
so let me ask uh let me see the
questions okay can you write in chat
what you are saying please don't have a
headphone
what can you write in chat what you are
saying please don't have a headphone
at a moment what are you talking about
uh so ernest
says what happens if you undo your
undoing of undo
uh you if you undo your undo you have
redo okay
it's even hard to demonstrate because
you know
yeah it's hard to demonstrate you have
to you know
there are articles you can go read about
it hey good morning break the loop
uh break the loop says i have a question
about the purpose of mathematica as a
programming language
uh it's mathematica's applicability
closer to excel vba in that
is visualization and numbers crunching
tool
okay big loop did you watch my last
video
my uh the video yesterday because i
i think i explained that for 10 minutes
uh no it's not like excel or
visual basic you know that's
that's uh isn't it it's
and um
so what so what is the purpose of
mathematica it's
as a programming language okay so it's
um
you know so uh please watch my
yesterday's video
yesterday's video i spent you know one
hour explaining
uh you know the primary thing i
explained is that
why mathematica is a artificial
intelligence
language okay uh and it's not like
an application like a lot of people who
never use mathematica
they see it as a application like for
people who don't know how to program
you can get results it's not you know in
some way it is but it's
it's a programming language okay it's a
it's a lisp
and apl based programming language
and i would say the expressibility is
far more powerful than
than this or haskell or airline or
whatever
so anyway watch my yesterday's video
so it's nothing like excel vba visual
basic what the heck
you know visual basic is uh one of the
language
uh vba right visual basic uh
what does the a stand for you know
visual basic
is one of the language programmers
despise because
you know it's like easy you know it's
it's
it's it's for people who don't know how
to program and it's
you know it does it does things very
inefficient
slow but you know it's mathematical it's
not like any
excel is like
uh so it's not like that okay i so i
would say it's a
artificial intelligence language far
more better than lisp
and haskell or any other and
it has uh industry most the industries
mostly scientists and
engineers biochemistry chemistry physics
mathematicians
uh and also these days machine learning
crypt
analysis right you you post it right
break the loop are you trying to ask
questions to help me to
uh talk about it yeah you posted a a
big loop posted a blog where this guy
deciphered one of the uh interesting
cypher
a murder case where the murderer uses
a crypto analysis you know secret
messages sent into
taunt to taught taunt the cops
and the guy who recently uh
finally after you know after several
decades
used mathematica to decrypt this
decipher
the encryption so if fbi is right now
looking into it still
so that's a great article so let's see
if i can find it
anyway i want to talk about uh emac
lists today so mathematica
mathematica san francisco murder
decryption
yeah so so here is the blog okay
so it would be interesting to read for
you guys so there's a
very famous uh murder called zodiac
killer you can find it there's a
wikipedia article on that
so this is unsolved you know murder in
san francisco back
back in 1950s i think
uh 1970 1960s okay
serial killer i think so very
interesting and
then you know just recently this month
or something you know
they the guy one guy used mathematica to
to find out what what he's saying so
here is his message
so anyway so you know this is nothing
like uh
visual basic or excel so anyway so uh
are you wearing two glasses yes one is
for
nearsightedness one is for old age you
know the
reading glasses because i'm getting old
dmt says doesn't undo three some of the
problems you are talking about since it
retains the history of changes well
yes but i also i was saying
it has corruption problem okay
uh yeah uh richard stowman you know it's
uh
controversial lots of controversy visual
basic for applications okay
if there was a way to talk sally would
be to
compare mathematica to visual basic
that's right ernest says i see you
are your perspective of what a language
should be
is to be able to analyze things uh
thanks make sense
uh when taken term language literally
okay
so is there anything about emacs um
so that's about undoing and we do it's a
problem
e max you know e-max
users is rendering and rendering
so a week ago about a week ago i did a
video on doom e-max
and that video became popular um
that video became popular um
1 000 views you know for me it's uh you
know
popular so so i'm thinking
you know i in the past few videos i
didn't read the comment too much but if
i did at that time
it would say it would save me a lot of
time
so you know i went through the trouble
of installing doom emacs on windows
but eventually i did it but
then i wasn't able to use it because
you know when doing a video like you are
kind of multitasking because
you know on one hand you have to figure
out what you are doing
with emacs meanwhile you have to figure
out you have to do it fast because you
cannot spend you know
store for two minutes to read something
so so you know the win the thing with
doom
i realized is that the first thing
to study doom to be able to use doom is
that you have to get
acquainted with the evil mod so yeah so
basically you have to learn
evil mod because that's uh doom's
default um
you know if you want to learn evil mod
then the first thing you have to
know is a little bit vim or vi okay
so actually i have a tutorial on vi
uh so go
go all the way down emergency
vie
uh yeah so that's basically you you have
to know the basics of vi then you can
use
evil mod then you have to learn the
the complexities or intricacies of
vi in e-max because you know it's not
exactly like vim because you you are
kind of
emulating vi vim in emacs so
so that's what i have to learn in order
to use doom smoothly
so anyway what what else okay
uh how long have i been talking for um
28 minutes anything else
doing imax has a lot of buzz around it
yeah it's and it's fairly popular i was
kind of surprised
and the guy henrik
uh lis listener
says that he actually have you know
there's a lot stars on the github
he actually says half of his income came
from donations
so that's fantastic
you know that's achievement uh
i'm wondering how how is fly
i mean space max
compared to you know the popularity
okay let's go to uh actually let's go to
oh yeah so this window ah stupid
nvidia let's go to space
max let's see uh
doom emacs
okay let's compare their popularity
let's see you know one way is just to
look at their github stars so doom e-max
doing e-max has got
10 000 stars
and 1.8 forks 1.8
um thousand like 2 000
folks so let's go to space
max go to github
starts 21 000 okay so space max
is actually uh twice as popular
yeah swiss space max
so they are both very popular um
you know i'm thinking one one of these
days actually i need to do a space max
you know i try space max as well and
also
you know a lot of people has been asking
for soft light keys to be
you know they to be integrated in space
max and also in doom emacs
and uh right now they are not
and there's no clear you know
instructions on how to do so
i can understand it because you know
basically each each person they focus on
their
you know their their opinion their the
way they like
so they don't you know why should they
you know why should i spend extra time
to
integrate doom emacs into stuff like
keys you know
see in a similar way people are thinking
that
so i have to so if i really want
to help people to run stuff like keys in
doing me max or space
emacs i have to do it myself i have to
um you know yeah so i have to spend time
you know it takes
actually a few days to actually do that
you know so these you know many of them
use
some emax technology that's new to me so
you have to study it because
for example do me max created its own
kind of package structure and and also
using the straight dot er which is a new
kind of function of declarative package
management system for emacs list
and space max also has its own system
space max i like have
layers i i'm not sure how exactly
it works you know that so that that's
something
i would be interested to know you know
to to know
not necessarily you know the space mac
or using it or do me max but i want to
know
i would be interested to know how what
they do
i mean the mechanism how they what kind
of system they
they implement so yeah but it is a lot
of time to
i have to spend a lot of time to do to
dive into that several days
days or a week probably a week
uh but but usually there's not much
financial reward you know
and i'm getting old so i need to i need
to you know i need to do mathematica
and i need to get on some other things
golan
you know i don't have time to uh do this
uh did you check this remax project yeah
re max project
is the uh emax
implemented in rust again you know for
my
what i hear they are making progress but
nothing to
show you know you know
so emax implemented in rust the idea is
that you know rust
is a language uh basically a modern you
can say it's a modern c
okay because it has you know you know c
is
very old 30 years old so russ is kind of
a
sea replacement in a sense it's a modern
sea
uh in the same category
uh in the same use case
you know purpose of c because it's very
uh close to the cpu it lets you control
the memory you know exactly so it's
supposed to be very fast
so the idea of implementing emacs in
rust is that it will be much faster
i suppose you know in general that's the
idea
and meanwhile it also updates
the tremendous you know
piles of [ __ ] accumulated in emacs that
is true
you know if you look at history the
other day the one of the guy
jeff true he is the
founder of the emacs meet up san
francisco
you know you you can go to search for
emacs lis
emacs meet up san francisco you'll find
the page
you know he runs the emac meetup we used
to i used to go
you know in san francisco in san
francisco bay area and we
meet up in real life but since the quran
corona virus we
you know that stopped so we do he does
he organized some kind of online meeting
so last last week he he did one
where he demo taco you know tekko is the
father of evacs
so you can see that lots of emacs
terminology
emacs philosophy emacs thinking is
actually from techo
you know so why is a buffer called
buffer because back then
you you you cannot display the whole
file you only display part of it
and that's why it's a buffer so
so this is one of the emacs problems you
know on one hand
it's very old and on the other hand so
so there's a habit you know
and the and emax is kind of you know
dramatic people refuse to change the
e-max phonetics
uh you know they always fight they
always fight the new ideas
you know it's a bit complex you know new
ideas are not necessarily good you know
for example like the undo the modern
undo
is not necessarily it's not absolutely
better okay but meanwhile the emacs undo
if you you know it's not it's not
necessarily better than the modern one
as you know two
so lots of emacs is basically a pile of
you know um how do you say the
pile of um
baggage you know you especially in code
you have huge amount of baggage because
emacs is
basically it's
you know the emacs ui the use you know
the code is trying to emulate
a terminal emulator which in turn is
trying to emulate the taco
text editor which in turn is trying to
emulate
teller type you know i don't even know
exactly what tera type technology was
30 years ago so it's a huge amount of
baggage in e-max so this
uh rust e-max project the e-max
you know it's a good thing it's a great
thing but right now it it's like
i'm not sure they are anywhere you know
where at the point you want to use you
know with you know you
with the tech you know the hacker types
you know they
they they have a tendency to create a
project that
for hackers it's great you know for
example if i want to use
uh the emacs what do i have to do
i have to re i have to spend a few hours
you know
reading oh maybe i need to download a
gnu compiler
maybe i need to uh does it run you know
maybe i need to run it linux
what doesn't work you know maybe i have
to adjust
memory cache or whatever you know it's
very technical
so that's no good so for
for tech geeker for hacker yeah it's
great you know after i spend a few days
then oh my god i can run you know
this new remax and everything works
great
it's faster but but you want to get to a
point where
people just download click download you
know
then they can run it that's what you
want that's every application
you know for example browsers you know
the
the google chrome browser firefox
browser
uh uh windows edge browser
that's you know that's what you that's
your aim that's what you want to do
but with the hacker types they always
they
they kind of they have an inherent
inherent
uh mentality to refuse it because if you
do that they think
it's for you know stupid people they
don't want that they
it's a problem so until one day
you know the rust emacs i can just click
download
and just everything just runs i'm i'm
more than happy to use it
i'll switch right away but that's not
you know they don't have that situation
yet
you know i don't know when you know and
another problem you know
also with a scheme you know kyle based
emac emacs that's also another fantastic
fantastic thing but you cannot just
download it you have to study it for
for a week or two then you can actually
compile a
a e max with a gaia scheme
lisp as you know replacing images
you know as an engine for emac this
you know that that project has been
going on for 20 years
and it's still like dead in the water
and in a glue
dev uh community there's always flame
wars you know because they don't have
structure everyone is just mouthing
opinions
oh we don't want that you know and then
there's the
old war between common lisp
camp and the skim this camp so the
typically the common these people they
they don't want they don't want the guy
or emacs because they
they don't like the scheme they want the
commonly thing
uh you know and so and you know the
generation so
now we have new generations um many of
these old flame wars are forgotten but
it's still there because
a lot of the gnu emacs death they are
still the
you know uh they are pretty old they are
like my age or older than me
some of them uh okay did you check the
okay so i think i tried some doom things
but the latency of commands became
high yeah that's another issue
okay if i may say so you know i'm i'm
peddling my own
system stuff like keys okay you install
scuffs stuff
stuff like this with plain glue emacs
and
and you then you have a system
that's faster than any of these i
that i can guarantee you okay
of course i i wrote stuff like keys
myself so that's
you know i'm selling my own things you
know i'm giving
good opinions of my own stuff you know
but but you can compare
so so i would say why
stuff like keys so i would say i would
claim it's more efficient and it's
faster because
the space max and and and uh
and do me max they are primarily you
know they they
they are based on the evil mod
and for emo evil mod they have you know
tens of packages
to so that evil mod works very well with
other mods
for example you you then you know i
think i think both of them use
helm or iv something so that when you do
uh something you know uh for example
open file
you have very fancy colored you know
syntax highlighting
you know but so that's great you know
many of
the feature is great but i think if you
prefer the simpler way simpler system
with
and also lots of you know good um
let's see if i can magnify the font
uh you know it you don't necessarily
need
you know helm or you know the wait uh
the fancy
uh other and it's faster because
yeah because you know all these
interfaces they adds up
um
time you know like like a few
microseconds but you can
i you can notice it because last last
time i was using
i was trying to do me max
i noticed you know a few microseconds to
pop
up you know uh opening files or stuff
uh what are the advantage of gail emac
list
okay uh use my name okay paste you know
add
tag me add saudi so i can easily see
your question
so what are the advantage of gail elise
okay
so emac this is very old okay
i talked about this uh a few times in my
old videos you
if you search it you might find it so
emac this
is um you know 30 years old 30
yeah 30 or 40 okay
it's almost let's say
yeah 40 40 years old at least
uh and there's not really much change to
emac at least
meanwhile in javascript in in
in php in python they
in perl you know they have a new
compiler
written from the ground up every five or
ten years
but evo emacs at least it's the same
compiler it is not much change there's a
little change
you know now and then but emac is pretty
old
and so so people want to
people have been been wanting to change
it since at least 2000 year 2k
okay like big controversy that you know
people argue you know in common this
camp versus
skim this camp they want to you know on
one
you know uh part of the people they want
they want common lisp to replace emac
list
on the other hand another camp they want
to scheme this
to replace imagbeast you know there are
advanced
advantages because emac this is really
kind of puny
you know although it works for you know
as a integrated
package for you know integrated language
to
change emacs but it's not very powerful
you have a lot of problems it's nowhere
comparable to
any other python perl javascript not
nowhere okay emac this is very bad
let me mention again but the imac
community you don't hear that because
all you hear is that
oh emac this is graded but i i did a
video on that
so you might be sucks really really bad
you know you really need to modernize it
but since year 2000 there's a lot
talk and effort trying to do so but they
never went anywhere
and one of the you know some people
wanted
there are several efforts you can search
for it now like in fact i have article
that i'm not going to show because uh
then it's gonna it's gonna going to take
much
too long just just search for sardi
uh common disks in emacs or search for
it okay
com and list emacs okay so anyway
there's a lot of controversy
since um it's not this
okay this is one of the uh earlier
later articles okay here okay here's the
you know there's a huge controversy i
mean today
i don't even mention this much because
the new generation forgot about this and
don't care it's like history okay so
this
article is emacs switching to kyle's
scheme this
return in 2010 because at that time you
know
in june there's a big revival you know
then
people are thinking oh oh fantastic it's
coming
it's not no it's aft no it's 10 years
10 years later nothing basically yeah
nothing
nothing came out of it then here's even
older article okay
thoughts on common lisp or scheme this
based emacs this is written in 2008
okay i give you a summary of a lot of
arguments
you know uh you know things arguments
among the people you know back then it's
common this was a scheme
you know each camp is very adamant
adamant
about their opinions you know so and
there are several projects for example
hemlock is a emac emacs based on common
lisp
okay it's not really good all these are
not very good that's why they
you don't hear them then climax is a
another common this
e-max okay then edwin is a scheme this
emacs okay the the url is dead long ago
but you i
you can still find it i i think if you
can still find it if you want to try it
then lice i don't remember what it's
like slices
uh liz is a lisp computing
interface sabets okay i know that guy
this guy
okay dead you know yeah that's what you
get when when you you know you we feel
okay submits if i remember correctly
he's a guy who created
rad poison you know the the linux
styling windows manager red poison
then later on a commonly spaced one
called
i forgot what's the name but anyway he's
a big fan of common lisp
okay uh so so you know so
so i'm showing you some of the projects
that tries to make
common lisp you know the or scheme this
the basis for emacs then there's a e
okay e is the editor okay it's it's it's
dead
e editor wikipedia does not have an
article
you know it the article has got removed
e editor is a when haskell became
popular very popular like around 2008
people are trying to make emacs like
editor with written in haskell that's
what
e editor is so i guess it went nowhere
and the wikipedia article got removed
so there's and there's even older okay
so if you
actually pay uh friends inc
you know if you pay to buy to buy the
allegro common list
it comes with a editor that's um
that's written in common list but i
think i forgot but anyway
uh so anyway so this these are you know
this is written in 2008.
then then 2010
guys game list so what do what are the
advantages you know there's a lot
because
once you know you update the com you
know
there are quite a lot of advantages of
replacing
emac this with either common disk or
scheme disk
one is that you actually get a real
programming language general purpose
programming language
because as emac this is you know you
cannot
use it to program any other thing
except you know mostly text editing you
cannot
do much although people try to you know
people imax phonetics will say these
idiots they'll say oh you can you know
this emacs to view video to
to to to read emails to there's a
browser written emac list yeah there
they are but they
but the code is like a mumbo jumbo you
know
people put a lot of effort to do it
you know you don't have even you don't
even have a name space what the [ __ ]
you know you're talking about emac these
don't even have a namespace
what the [ __ ] is that a language without
the namespace
and you are saying it's good you know
you know
i did a video on e magnesium okay it's a
it's a one of the circus language
it needs it desperately needs
modernization so
one advantage of replacing emac list
is that with the modern this is that you
get a real language
then the second advantage is that it
usually will be much more faster
because this scheme this there are so
many scheme these
implementations and commonly is used in
industry
so there's a lot effort to make them
fast you know so
so that's the advantages you know
make the make the you know using a real
programming language general purpose
programming language that's one
then the other one is make it much
faster
of course they never happen to this day
you know and we don't know what will
happen
uh it's pretty sad so
okay i think maybe that's it for today
so i i've been talking for 52 minutes
any more questions
uh space max and doom is a good start if
you can make a system that is great for
you yeah
i've been tempted to jump into doom
emacs bandwagon many times but i'm too
invested in my own config and the whole
model
editing thing is not my cup of tea okay
then says that okay dmt says i really
like moto editing i really want model
editing for emacs keybinding okay
so vinnie seuss
says i like the idea of vi move
keys i mapped my uh mechanical keyboard
to use
uh those on layer okay uh elise
feels powerful to me though especially
macros
no i mean well yeah okay but you haven't
tried any
any other lisp that's that's the thing
how can you make a judgment about emac
this without even trying
other lisps at all because the point is
about
replacing emac these with other lists
commonly when speak skimming this
okay uh you know so commonly
is you know emac this is just a
scripting language it's like a
application you know it's like visual
basic for applications
essentially it's not a real
general purpose programming language um
stump stump window manager that's the
guy the
sabbat you know this guy
he you know the lies
the lies editor this let's see read me
the lisp computing
interface is a port of gnu emacs c core
to common list
and accompanying imac business code so
when is the last uh update let's see if
we can see
2007 yeah it's dead it's dead since
yeah it's dead for 13 years but this guy
submits he also wrote
rat poison and uh stump
stump window manager he's a communist
fan
and he's also a juggler and he's on
twitter okay you can sometimes see
him juggling i think he's uh in western
canada
last time i heard like 10 years ago
uh so
so next uh any common questions
post it okay i think we're gonna close
in five minutes
i heard mitchell uh mr stoneman doesn't
like communist yeah he
so richard stoneman is rather he doesn't
like comedy
he's on the scheme this side
yeah it's a big flame war you know it's
a big flame wall
uh snowman doesn't like anything i can't
imagine spending afternoon with a guy
he's quite insufferable yeah his
list is useful really on some niche
areas
that's why never got consolidated in one
dialect actually it may even be better
this way
uh i don't know how old are you i have
to ask because
you know when you when you talk about at
least
you have to know the history of or
you have to be there okay so this was
the
industrial language for artificial
intelligence throughout
1980s so but around 1990 it kind of died
because the artificial intelligence
became a bubble basically a bubble
so all the military and industrial
financial support went away basically
but it was you know it was
supported by you know military u.s
military and uh
big industry you know and so on so it
kind of died
so that's when this machine died that's
when a.i
know so called with ai winter you can
search wikipedia this article
ai winter so beginning in 1990s
1990 so this kind of you know is no
longer using industry
but then it's a it's a big history okay
so i
i read i i wasn't around in a computing
scene
in 1980s but i tried to read quite a lot
of them
uh so from what i know you know commonly
schemed this
is actually earlier than comedies
okay let me let me tell you my what i
know about commonly
okay commonly before common lisp
there's actually quite a lot of other
lisps and it's a big
war a very ugly war war just like
you know python versus pearl or gold
line versus rust
you know kind of more severe than today
because today you don't really hear
much about language war as a as a
religious war
that much okay as compared to 1990s why
because today
there are so many you know there's like
exponential growth of languages
and it's common that when if you work a
company
you have to know several like javascript
you have to know both
javascript golan or python javascript
and you know you you have to
code in three or more languages it's
very common
so you don't hear you don't even hear
much about language war that much
today the concept
you know kind of went away but back then
it's more severe okay
and so i'm saying in the 1980s which i
wasn't there but i read a lot
when you study emacs history or lisp
history
or artificial intelligence history you
saw artificial intelligence is very much
tied with lisp okay back then
uh so when you read a lot history i
i realized i see that you know back then
there's uh
quite a few lisps mag at least you know
quite a few i don't you know i can't
remember the names
uh off my head so they and it's a big
ugly wall
you know they don't like the you know i
don't like your lisp you don't like my
list
you know it's created by different
companies
so commonly you know and it's a problem
because all you have all these lisps
these and they they cannot interoperate
you know they are not compatible that's
a problem just like today
windows mac linux is not compatible you
know wouldn't be great
if they are all compatible you know you
can play you can have
we you know all the video games and
nvidia drivers
supporting windows but you can run on
linux fantastic
and you can have all the unix commands
all the older mac
mac fantastic easy to use
graphical user interface but it's not
you know so on
on windows you have one set of key
bindings on mac you have to change your
you know command and windows
they swap they do it this way that way
and linux is
different so same thing with the
list back then you know different lists
that are not compatible you cannot
use one software written in one list in
another
this environment so so there's a also a
need
to you know make them
compatible that's that's the idea
of common lisp okay
yeah again uh linux distro two you know
there's a big war
among linux distros you know red hat uh
uh debian uh and you know and and
gentle you know and arc linux this
big ugly bloody war you know nobody like
each and and we know managers
like [ __ ] you know that's a situation
okay
that's because people people they want
that's a human nature okay you you just
want to promote your stuff
and just like companies companies they
sell google
why is apple world garden because apple
wants to just make money
they know you know they don't make money
and give it to google google
does the same thing microsoft they do
the same thing they are considered evil
by the hacker types the hacker idiots
meanwhile these linux idiots
you know they they say oh we we we love
humanity we are open source everything
we share but actually look at the
distros
look at the window manager they they
fight you know without money they fight
for fame
they fight you know this is my you know
system that's yours
you know they fight so linux distro you
know they have different
uh package managers but why don't they
you know if you are really good for
humanity
like merge them so that all
linux packages can be used in any links
in linux
why doesn't that happen it hasn't
happened for 20 years and in fact you
have more
diverse you know you know package
managers you know
that's the nature of things okay but the
the tech
geekers these open source phonetics they
don't really they don't see it
they just all they see is that of the
the greater good for humanity like
richard stowman
that and richard snowman then richard
snowman fights with the open source like
you are my enemy
open source you are a scum you stole my
idea that's
that's the opinion of richard stroman
you know and richard stowman and and
meanwhile the
the open source camp you know saying you
know uh richard stroman you are just a
nut job you are too extreme
we need we need an open source idea so
that corporations can also benefit
you know that's the that's the esr guy
you know he pushed for that view
so it's a fight you know it's fighting
all over
so commonly is trying to
uh kind of create a lisp that's you know
a standard list everyone can use but
however it has so happens that the
result is a disaster okay because
you know nobody you know they they try
to have a
a community you know a committee to
decide
you know this standardized lisp but
meanwhile every these
corporations they they they don't give
up their
that you know their system they say oh
you need to have this feature because
our list you know really want this
feature and so
so companies became this ugly giant
mess you know it has uh you know
features
of all different disps so it's very ugly
and complex
so that's why the commonly specification
is like 10 000 pages
and some some these
uh experts back then say they you know
their opinion is that
common lisp killed this okay you can see
you know i have i have uh tens of
articles on this
i'm not going to show it but just search
for sadly these
you will find them okay some some of the
histories of the
and some of the famous disperse what
they said about all this history or
about emacs
and a lot that of that
so commonly this is a effort to
kind of unite to create one standardized
lisp okay so once common lisp is spawned
it's and the result is uglier you know
not many people like it
but but then when commonly is born all
the
other lisps kind of died they died along
with the ai winter
common lisp remains okay but but still
is
actually it's also dead too but anyway
at the time so you have now you have two
lisps comedy and scheme this they also
disagree very much you know because skim
this
is actually earlier than they have a
different philosophy you know
uh so anyway people you know they they
cannot
agree and uh so so this communist versus
scheme this
became the flame war
uh very very bad flame war lasting for
like about 20 years
throughout 1990s and 2000s
by 2010 you could say
this is dead nobody you know now you
have new
new generation the millennial generation
then the social justice you know
generation then you have programmers
you know programmers you know so things
kind of changed
the hacker types generation is also dead
so and this is also kind of dead you
know
yeah nobody finds the common these
versus giving this
anymore why because not because they
unite
they they they you know they become one
rather because both of you know this
is dead so that's a history okay so
that's
um okay that's it for today i guess
um yeah and scheme list
if you know i don't know if you know if
you are young you don't know so skim
this
then around 2008 the they became racket
you know one of the skim this you know
the rice university they
created you know they renamed they
skimmed this
as a um racket okay
and consider it as a new language so
so now you have two kinds of scheme this
one is the classic
scheme this following the r4r
s or rs or r6is
the scheme standard you know then the
other can be
racket oh yeah then then you have
closure yeah right
okay i think that's it for today uh
anything else
um so i've been talking for one hour
uh so if if you like my stuff buy my
emacs tutorial okay buy my emacs
tutorial and um
uh stuff
or donate or patreon me or paypal or
amazon
gift me
so we close down in one minute so i
guess
closure is the new companies okay so on
it says
it seems like each list feature the
different this
offer can be implemented in any list so
it's why i personally don't understand
no it's not trivial to implement one
lisp in another
it's actually it's actually quite
then trivial uh you know this is an
interesting question
in fact i would claim that
to implement a lisp it's actually easier
to use a language that's not lisp
okay that's i'm not sure exactly but
that's my that's how i feel okay i
um anyway so
we are looking at you know re max the
rust based emacs
and some of these people i recognize
this guy
miles badger he's also i guess you can
say he's the old
disper he lives in japan now
he has written for example the pdf
viewer
package in emacs that allows you to view
pdf
is written by him okay and you know we
we've talked
you know um the last time we talked is
like
almost five years ago or ten five five
so i okay avenues this guy is another
this guy is a he's a very serious
discorder and he's not
you know among the emac beast people
some of them are very popular and maybe
dramatic
like me okay like you know people know
about me he's a dramatic guy
meanwhile there are a lot very deep
serious coders
that he's the you know top expert of
lisp
and c but however that you know they
don't write blogs and they don't post
online you know so they
you don't know him this is one of the
guy
i recognize uh our venus i don't know
how do you pronounce in his name
so he you know looks like he doesn't
even have
what is this he doesn't even have a
github
but but he wrote if i'm not mistaken i'm
pretty sure yeah uh
venus he has made
core uh what what did he
he he wrote the found c
engine the display engine found engine
in e max 2000 in e-max
um 25 or 24 a unicode engine okay
you know he's he's a yeah if i'm not i'm
pretty sure
uh he's also a serious
contributor to the x11 i think you know
he's a linux hacker he knows c and this
very well but by whatever i mean he
wrote
tons of code in in the core emacs engine
you cannot see it okay it's like you
know so
that's what i uh you know
last this guy is another very
he's well known uh lisp coder
you know he has written many many very
well known
things uh gw and he is a very well known
in portal or gateway to
the new school interface it was popular
for like over 10
20 years you don't hear it much today
because news group is dead
you know he has written that not just
that he's also the author
of gnus you know the news news reader in
emacs
he's also the author of the
uh you browser in emacs
that began like five years ago five
seven seven years ago or so
you browser in emacs so
it's a browser written entirely in
emaclis
okay that guy you know he doesn't he
he has he also has a blog okay yeah he
has a blog
and he he writes very interesting things
and he's a collector of comics you know
he collect you know
pretty old you know so so these people
you know glues
yeah so anyway so that this guy very
interesting he is
his vlog last
inga brunstein uh in a
something like that and he's uh
he lives he he's a northern europe
guy i forgot which country exactly uh
no way or something you know
one of the scandinavia guy
uh you know so i'm giving you my
um the laws of the
emac lisp people
joking verona i think i i've sold
i i've i've seen him on imac this
dev quite a lot like even 10 years ago i
think but i don't
know i don't know what he does
paul edgard is another
you know core contributor to emac lisp
to gnu emacs okay like he
you know he's one of the main guy in gnu
imax
lisp dev you know like if you ask people
all of you emacs users even if you are
emacs fanatics
like if you i ask you guys okay who
you know in the past 10 years who
contributed
who are writing the code for emac at
least you know we have
i mean emacs you know we have emacs 24
since 10 years 10 years ago
the emacs 25 emax 26 and emacs 27 which
which is what i'm using so who who wrote
this code not richard solman he haven't
been coding for
10 or 20 years and your answer is
typically uh you don't know
[Laughter]
that's a problem you know that's the
problem of the gnu emacs
community you have to know who you know
they wrote them they they should have
credit
not richard snowman the [ __ ] okay you
know you know so
so most people you guys you know even
even even if you are
even if you are a emax fanatic if you
ask you you know you'll just say
oh doing me you're doing emacs the space
emacs guy the those guys you recognize
all the you know the the few the top 10
very popular packages on melba
but they they but but they are not
typically they are not the emac beast
i mean the gnu emacs contributors the
mothership
so who who contribute to the mothership
it's you know
it's this um bunch of
people you know i happen to tell you
okay and
you know so i was talking about paul
edgard okay so he's one of the you know
like
some of these guys they are serious
c and emac these coders they they
they they code you know they they make
the emac the the gnu emacs
float and moneo this is stefan manilow
also
you know he's again a fundamental
contributor you know he
he was the e max grew imax maintainer
for like five years okay around 2010
he's a professor of functional
programming
okay then this guy ellie zareski
zareski he's he's a very controversial
guy
he's also a very old emac this
and c coder okay very old he is
you know probably the main contributor
in emacs in grenoble emacs okay he's
this guy however he has a reputation
he's very annoying this guy is very
[ __ ] annoying
you know because of him
in fact i could say you know i i had a
across
home homes with this guy too a few times
but it's been so long you know we talk
you know we know we don't you know we
have frictions but you know he knows me
i know
you know all these guys know me i know
them okay all these guys
many of you know most of them i've
chatted i've talked i've exchanged
flames or
otherwise nice uh emails or on
news groups so ellie
he he's he has a very abrasive
personality in what he says and not just
with me
because he's known for that he's he's
he's got problems with almost
almost other uh no emacs developers
and and now and then he'll threaten you
know if you decide you're gonna have
this feature i'm going to quit
this eddie guy so that's that's uh
you know glenn morris again he's also a
very old whisper
now i don't know exactly what he does i
mean
of course he does you know he he he uh
write code for imac
group emacs but i'm not sure exactly
what package
but he's also you know so all these guys
are very
other men emacs new emacs
developers you know the you know the
this guy
it is this guy you have to thank for
okay this you know these people so they
are now helping
the you know the re max oh wait
i made a mistake the reason you know
they are not necessarily helping the
emacs the reason there
this guy shows up is because the emacs
is you know they they in the beginning
they
they they began with the gnu emax repo
so that's
why that's why these people's names show
up they are not necessarily
helping to write uh rust emacs
okay that's it um one last question i
guess
uh
uh we need the accidental okay so pretty
much uh yeah
okay funny i hate this
uh trading generator uh but the question
is do these people also eat the skin
from their feet
that's that's the that's a
that's a unique unique show of richard
stowman
yeah richard so much you know he's to
such a degree
doing that in public is really sad
okay yeah i know he's a nerd right i'm
i'm too
yeah but you don't do that in public
and you can say you know oh i'm too much
of a nerd i don't i forgot you know you
don't say you know you
don't do that you know he he he does
that it's because he's so
he he's like he's become one of these
you know indian guru
leaders he's like on one hand the
idea of open of free software
you know it's a past you know it's a
good idea that
but you shouldn't take it too extreme
to the degree that no other idea should
exist
the only good idea for humanity is free
software that's what he thinks
you know extreme in a way he's a
communist
you know he becomes this dictator hitler
in a way in a sense so in his idea if
you don't have food
if you work for free software and refuse
to work for
uh commercial software then you're gonna
your children is gonna die
and richard solman says yes do that you
should do that that's what you should do
that's what he you know he actually
literally said that
during interviews so that's not good
that's not
you know to that degree it's not good
you are not a good person
anymore so he become this
you know like this guru leader you know
very bad
then anyway
okay that's it for today thank you buy
my stuff okay donate
make me float bye
i