good morning everyone welcome to another
episode ofar talk show today we are
going to do wolam language coding
Mathematica okay if you are here say hi
love to see your comments comments and
you can ask me wam language questions or
Mathematica
questions and if you are watching
offline skip around and play at 1.5
speed because I ramble all over okay so
we're going to do wam language coding
today
so let's take it
easy and have a drink of red
wine my
keyboards glove 0 fantastic ultimate
hacking keyboard
fantastic nulia track B
fantastic and uh this this you know this
this pen device
fantastic uh what is the name it's one
of those China chipo hang H hang
okay yeah anyway so and then there is
this fantastic device s
board okay uh swab board I have video
reviews for all of them
okay uh check it out and I'll be using
SW board uh not yet sorry about that
okay shall we go back shall we start to
code you know nobody's here so I'm just
going to do my thing my work tremendous
work uh video check audio check okay
let's do my stuff okay so let's go to so
showing browser I'm using emac of course
uh this is the video close back to emac
showing browser okay and uh let's go to
to plane curves so I'm going to work on
this project if you are not familiar
with wolam language or
Mathematica uh search my YouTube because
I've done by now hundreds wam language
tutorials okay you know you get
introduction where to download for free
and things like that so we're going to
work on something like Parabola okay
last time about a week ago we were doing
this but we didn't get to code but I did
offline so we got some code here so you
can see this is wam language code so
let's run it you know let's just show
you a
demo we already started wufan language
oh okay so you don't want that uh
control shift enter
okay
wait you need to I have sticky key on so
okay shift
enter there it is okay so that is
hyperbola this is these are hyper a
bunch of
hyperbolas that shares a
Vertex okay so actually so there's a
mistake I don't want the semicolon here
because when you have a
semicolon it's supresses the output so
let me
magnify okay so you can see
better so if you put the semicolon there
shift enter it suppresses the output
okay so semicolon so now you do it again
now it shows okay now open that so copy
that close paste the link back to
browser copy the link back here paste it
linky both make a list showing browser
fantastic there is a hyperbola okay now
let's go to the hyperbola page now on
the pink window you can see all my
command course command name on the right
and keystroke on the left okay sh
browser uh so yeah so let's search for
pre
uh you know you want to get rid of the
uh the semicolon where is
it pre yeah there okay remove it back to
browser is right
here refresh
okay okay what we're going to do so you
know so these PL C projects there are uh
let's
magnify there are hundreds of special
plane Cur curves mathematics this is BAS
basic geometry uh this is kind of if you
are learning calculus in college this is
for you uh some of these are you know
these are calculs or pre-calculus okay
uh fascinating okay this these are
fascinating
Sciences you need to know know that you
need to know all of this in order to do
to be a rocket scientist you know today
they are talking about AI artificial
intelligence chat GPT and so on you need
to know these things okay for example
chat GPT neural networks you need to
know um logarithm functions calculus you
need to know linear algebra you need to
know matrices that's that is the heart
of neural networks so and log functions
logarithmic functions you know those are
functions
that computes score in each layer
something like that okay so neural
networks
chat connection successful reconnection
f is my am am I
healthy okay uh I think I
am hello
doy some of them are amazing thank you
okay so um we going to do so you know we
I did this starting in
1999 actually in
1994 uh where I then in 1995 I got a
internship at Wolfram for half a year
then I I continued to work on this and
uh that's when I learned worldwide web
the internet so 1995 I learned about the
internet so I contined to work on this
project so now by you know basically
back then from 1994 to about 1997 seven
I created this so there are a lot wfam
language uh notebooks I need to update
okay so for example this is a wfam
language notebook this is a source code
you can see this is a file open it you
see a bunch of text opening wam language
notebook okay I need to so these are
very old notebooks okay so this one is
for
example something around 1997 okay so I
need to update
them okay so that is my job because I
mean that's what I have to do update
this uh so that you know many of these
are uh generated like 30 years
ago uh okay so what so what I want to do
is
yeah I want to for example hyperbola you
see there's a notebook link you click on
that that will download it but the
notebook is very old so for example this
is my package this is my package this is
my package they already they
are you know these are back then uh on
the website at wfam research called math
source so you get the you got the item
number which is the ID then you can get
it you know it's like a source callede
repository back in 1990s so wufan
research is one of the earliest but now
the math source is like obsolete so all
these packages I have Rewritten
them few months ago on my website just
search it you know you know you'll find
them so but however this notebook is is
old so and for example this package
implicit part that is obsolet
now it's building okay building with a
different name now it's called contol
plot so my point here is that all these
notebooks they are old okay
so so for example
um okay I go to
Powershell
magnify okay let's see Power shell so so
you want to list directories file
recursive and
filter and uh
star
MB okay so that will show you uh let's
do it again okay there show so you you
got like uh how many of them uh pass to
measure so
so there are 82
notebooks uh my job is to update them
okay so let's go back clean close that
so this is one of them so okay
so uh I want to pick something you
know let's see uh
cheers you know I'm just going to do
something fun so you can you know maybe
get something interesting out of it
let's see what I want to do so all these
are new images I did few days ago
offline and uh what I want to do here is
all these are uh very interesting
properties about hyperbola okay so
actually so this one is
about stretching H stretching
rectangular
hyperbola okay
so so you can see
the
graphics can magnify the
graphics okay but that's not um so which
one should I I want to
um okay let's just do okay let's do this
one yeah so these are old images you can
see these are old
images so let's do a new one
okay so let's go here
okay select all delete I want to
do
um light rays okay let's see old four to
make a
title
okay uh then this is another thing this
is
pedo old four to make a title
okay
so so now I can one click to copy the
entire section you know once you have
the title and sub subsection this is
like o mod okay so you can collapse this
entire thing you know you can expand it
or collapse expand so let's give a title
so this is called catac costic costic so
costic
means basically means the study of light
rays so hyperbola and Parabola and the
ellipses they
have uh Optical properties so for
example in the case of
hyperbola you will have if you shine a
light from a focus then they will they
will um deflect to the other Focus so
that's one of the property Optical
Optical property of hyperbola okay so we
got a lot to do so we need to you know
update this image and add wam language
code here uh you can see some other
costic properties so for example this is
a parabola which is used for
a head lamp of your car you know they
direct the light into one straight
direction and you you can have some
other beautiful images we when you do a
you know when you shine a light on
different curves so this is what like
this is what you get from if you shine
the light from the
top um you you know onto a sign curve
you got you got that so you know it's
like pretty effects and this is um this
is a physical effect when you have a cup
you'll see this often uh and that shape
you can see that kind of hard shaped
thing that's called that's called uh
cardioid okay another fascinating curve
okay wait I don't want
that fascinating curve so this curve and
can be generated by Rolling a circle on
another circle like that so again you
see this image uh generated like 30
years ago so I need to do redo all these
um all these things okay so back to so
we digressed so you know we talking
about costic which is about Optical
properties costic okay so go back here
hyperbola so we got this section on
costic so we
can in wfam Notebook it's just like or
mod so you can have sections and
subsections so now copy it go to the new
notebook paste it okay so we going to
work on
here and meanwhile save this close
it
okay
cheers okay we got a bunch of code now
actually copy copy
a new
one paste it just for backup so I don't
have to open the other one so
now
um so here is the code
let's copy
them copy back to
here and uh now this is
HTML and uh we want to go to cosics okay
cosics
okay there is the image close that
there's the other image close that uh
Optical property okay I want to make it
you see these are H3
headers so again this is a Asian project
this is this is from 199 you know 4 to
1997 so there's a lot formatting issues
I need to
change uh
yeah okay so let me just do it so
instead of like talking it's easier so
change your H3 to H2 um wait okay H3 H2
I already got a function uh don't don't
don't okay change change change change
okay uh
inversion Okay so
so what is this inversion so inversion
is one property what I want is to make
each of these property to have a section
by itself to have a box okay so so what
you can do is
here select select make a box okay then
select select select make a box delete
the Todo and date select select select
make make a box so make a box means add
a section tag so now if you show in
browser you can see now you got like
each section is enclosed in a
box uh okay they you got more to do
so so select select select
select select this
is uh pointwise construction D that d
property showing
browser description formulas
okay uh yeah okay so and also delete the
section so you don't get
nested okay now we're going to work on
the optical property okay so wait
okay so this is something wrong
here check yeah that's good that's
better so we're going to work on the
optical
property okay
so let's make a section uh let's make a
section wam language pre okay pop it out
and go back to the here copy copy it
paste
it okay so you don't want the
graphics clear clear clear okay copy it
select or paste
okay okay let's start to
code clear hyperbola so this is uh
backup
so again you need to remove the
semicolon it was there because in the
old
version that does not suppress the
output okay now done
now okay so let me just code it if you
have questions for me
ask Nicola says hi it's my first time in
live thank you cheers from Colombia oh
hi Colombia
you know I noticed that
Colombia is it Colombia or
Colombia they have a lot hot
chicks so um so let let me just work on
this okay so actually you need this
okay
so let's show
that
paste evaluate okay
mistake uh range specification so you
need to fix
that range uh I know why is that because
it used to be I'm using my own
customized function so in my own custom
customiz function for the parametric
plot the
range can be you know can can have
several several uh values so basically
this means you want to plot it okay so
you want to plot you know Co parametric
plot remove the first okay you want to
make this plot and then with this
formula
now now that h P came from a package so
I need to find it so let me do
so uh get that's one of my plank cve
formulas
package okay planker formulas there
there okay so you see this is on GitHub
so if you like it you can go and grab it
basically it just Define a bunch of
names for for a formula okay parametric
equation so let's see where is The
Notebook here okay so you need hyperbola
okay search for
hyperbola okay there it
is so you got the
usage okay
so copy it and then you got the
okay then here is the
equation okay copy
it
back okay paste it here so here is the
hyperbola so once you define it you need
to kind of clear
it so delete
delete paste it here so clear
this and then this is the documentation
this is the inline documentation okay
and uh so here is the formula okay let's
rewrite this into a way that's more
understandable so I'm going to reite
rewrite this
to
function and
uh okay equal close to that you don't
need this one okay so so these two lines
are exactly
equivalent it just the first one uses a
shortcut syntax you see that
ment symbol that's that's just a
shortcut so this first line is exactly
equivalent to this line so this line it
means whenever you see
hyperbola
something it's equivalent defined to be
a function of this thing so it's a list
of two things secant this and square
something tangent okay and uh you see
that pound sign that means the argument
so that's like
X okay so this two are equivalent so I
don't need that one so now you got the
hyperbola so
um so actually I want to rename it um
so rename hyperbola to be lower
case formula okay change change change
change change change change change
change okay rename it to hyperbola
formula okay so we got the formula
defined then here now we call it um then
evaluate then we need to so the second
argument is a range so T goes
from uh 2 pi okay so T goes
from 2 pi minus
001 why do you want to minus
0.001
because that avoids the asymptot because
when you plot a curve sometimes you have
a point that will go to
infinity or a point that's undefined
like the limit is undefined so when you
whenever you have that you'll get a SYM
toote or a vertical line something like
that so usually you don't you don't you
want to avoid that so that's why I say 2
pi minus you know something because when
it's at 2 pi it'll become like
infinite so this is 30 years ago but
today I I think they fixed you know they
they made it better so they it will
detect that so again the point pi and
three and you know three over 2 pi are
special points that makes the curve go
to infinite go to Infinity okay so but
now remove
them okay so here is the uh let's see so
let's make it one line copy
it paste
it eval oh okay not working well that's
because we haven't defined the formula
yet okay
so okay so you need to copy copy that
select or paste
Evol
beautiful okay so this this plots the
hyperbola and we also assign it to a
name okay so you see what we want to do
is to actually generate these
Reflections Optical to illustrate the
optical property you see like that but
however there's no boding function to do
this because this is kind of specialized
Optical
property so we need we are so
effectively we are doing Graphics
programming you know wolam language
provides graph graic
facilities you need to program it so it
shows the light rays and things like
that
okay uh so we got it here okay this is
complicated we can't you know so the
code is here this
code you know this that code will show
you show this
Graphics but however this code
is using a package I wrote okay so let's
go to that
package um yeah okay let's go to it you
know you you can you can well anyway
let's go to it okay so
get get
then what you want
is plank cve plot Okay so open it so
there it is so here's the code PL code
plot it was known as par
plot 30 years ago it was known as power
plot okay but now I updated as you see
1994 to 2024
okay so uh God so I need to load this
package you know we have two choice to
do this one is to Cod this from
scratch uh you know I can do that
live like I can do that live right now
but it will take one hour because in
order
to program this
Graphics you need to draw lines you know
you need to draw each one of these line
and you need you need to know from where
to squ and in order to do that you need
to know the mathematics you know you
need to find given a line from this
point to that
point and when it hits a curve you you
need to know where it intersect the
curve for example right here then you
need to find the equation or the the
point for the the other line that
deflects the line so you got a line you
need to draw a bunch of lines passing
passing the Focus
right then for each line you need to
find where it where where it touches the
curve on the other you know on the other
Branch then at that point you need to
find you basically need to find the
tangent of the hyperbola at that point
once you know the tangent then you can
easily compute Where's the Line heading
to so in other words you need to know
the the point another point on the line
okay then once you know that point then
you can draw this deflection okay uh
what is a proper word it's not called
deflection it's called Uh refraction or
something okay you can read the details
let's see yeah refraction it's called
reflection re refraction okay so to do
this manually you need to
like do
this you know you need to draw all these
lines and get into into mathematics so
but I wrote a package for this so you
don't have to do all that or you have to
do is you just say where is the orine of
the line uh for example uh let's see uh
let's copy that here somewhere
here okay
uh you
see where is orine there it is you see
this line costic orine so you just say
where is the light source then you say
how long is the length of the light rate
you want to draw CTIC light
length then then you can say a style
like what what kind of color you want
then it just does it just do it for you
it will figure out where intersect where
it goes you know so I wrote a package
okay so we have a choice to do to code
this manually right now or use the
package let's use the package okay
because you know you know coding this
manually it takes you know
like um an hour or two if I'm going to
explain it okay so let's load the
package okay so load the package the
package
is loading the package the package is
right here okay the package is on GitHub
okay so you can see where is the website
uh oh I
didn't what uh okay so let's show The
Notebook so here is a bu of examples
from that
package so does it tell you where is the
link
no you see all these uh results you know
it can plot cost sticks but it can also
plot
uh you know it can also plot tangents
for example this is a sine wave with
lots of tangent uh and this one is
tangent you know of a sign like curve
and these are tangents this is also
tangent of a of a deltoid curve and this
is tangent you know illustration of the
meaning of tangent so you can plot
tangent you can plot
um normals okay so normals nor so this
is a party normals normal to a
curve
means on any tangent point you have a
line that's perpendicular to the tangent
that line is called the normal at that
point okay so if you plot all the
normals of a parabola you get that
okay and here's other example of normals
so you know and you can see normals of a
spiral normals of a e uh
elisp normals of a
deltoid and the normals of a um this is
hypot troid I believe you know anyway
you get pretty pictures so you can get
you know this this is a normal of a
curve that looks like a cactus okay then
you can also plot SEC SEC and you know
SEC and so on so this is AA on GitHub
okay now let's go to the cosics there
they are so you can plot the cosics of a
of a uh
Parabola okay I didn't so you know then
there is the refraction of hyperbola
actually this is what we want actually
we didn't you know we just can copy this
code refraction of a hyperbola showing
the optical properties okay okay so let
me show you where the code is um
so maath you just search for Kar
math uh or search
forar wol frame
language okay then wolam Language
tutorial that's my website go
there okay then uh about the author then
uh packages there wam language packages
okay then you know these are my packages
then you
want planker plot package this one okay
so there it is download click on
download you go to GitHub then you can
download it MIT license sponsored by
wolf
research okay
fantastic so now
so that you know so that's where I mean
so now I just going to use my local
uh go to talk show go to it and uh paste
link okay showing browser actually
actually I don't want that link copy
paste okay showing browser there it is
so uh planker plot package
so we need to load this okay so let's go
so where is the where's our
code
what uh
what oh yeah so
wait close that close
that okay go here yeah so here's our Co
we need to load that
package now
um now I need to check my own website to
see so go to wolam language
index so you need to know how do you
load a
package I know of course but I mean
there's a little bit complication okay
loading a
package read WR f load a package there
load file okay get okay let's use get
cheers okay out I'm out of why let me go
get some
y recently three days ago I have some
back pain so I'm
hurting for
am I doing good are you guys doing
good Che
okay let's copy let's get on to work
close that uh actually don't close that
get back
here okay you need to load a package
uh yeah that's exactly
um you see we got into issues because
you know this will load a package for
sure
but but that's not the way to publish it
because if you publish it you know this
is a local file path people won't you
know they won't have it you that's why
um but you know this will work for me so
let me just show you
okay so let's cop let's copy the uh here
copy
that so for
example okay so for example copy that go
here paste
it now shift control D to split this
into two cells okay now go to the first
one and uh
wait go to the first one here shift
enter
you see that loads it then go to here
shift
enter
beautiful you know you don't have to
like before you don't you know you don't
we have to write a lot code or formula
in that but now it's like
beautiful
so so what to do now so um
yeah so and and this by the
way contrl L to duplicate the cell above
then shift control n to make it typ set
you see
beautiful you see type set and automat
automatic line wrap even with types set
mathematical equations you see for for
example look at that fraction or look at
this square
root type setting and auto format on the
Fly okay this is far more advanced than
any Goan rust or hascar or python
uh and this exist 30 years ago in
1996 wolam language version three okay
so that's why wfam language is a
magnitude more advanced than all these
other languages Goan rust C Shar python
Ruby uh hascal
F A magnitude not just better better
than them but a magnitude beyond their
capabilities wolam
language okay now we got this
actually I don't want a typ set
because you know because typ set looks
nice but you cannot paste it to
the uh you cannot paste it to
um to website you know you need you know
you you you can but you know let me show
you let me let me explain for example if
you copy this typ set
formula copy back to emac or any
editor am I doing am I am I doing good
check okay so you open
paste oh it doesn't uh wait let let me
try again
copy oh okay never mind okay so here's a
code so what you want to do so yeah okay
so hold on a
second so you need to copy these two
okay copy
paste yeah that's what I want
close Okay
um put this
back and uh make a
new
uh W language paste the code here and uh
delete that move up here paste okay and
now
copy the
graphics let's do a
screenshot okay
beautiful okay now it's copied to the my
pictures folder now I have a emac
command
to press uh
wait press press press then the photo
the image is moved in to the current
directory see go to the directory you
see this is image okay screenshot close
okay now I want to rename this file path
okay uh shift enter uh tap e r okay now
let's say
hyperbola costic
okay there it
is the file has been renamed close close
close okay now change the name here
press a
key now it's
good showing
browser go
down there it
is okay light rays coming from one focus
of a hyperbola will ref frct to the
other Focus
perfect okay so do I need to do I need
these two no so so these two are 30
years old um let's say
1995 yeah 30 years so delete them okay
so but you need
to syntax color this part this part
refresh fantastic now it's syntax
colored and uh this part I need to
change because this is my local file you
need to say you know um that's that's a
bit more complex I you know I if you
have a question ask me
okay comments no no comments okay so
these two pictures needs to be removed D
because they are 30 years old so one is
that uh the other one is that so before
I delete them I need to make sure my
website of 10,000 pages does not link to
them in other places so what I do is
copy the file name
copy
search that file name enter search in
disar info directory
search. HTML files yes then wait a few
seconds it'll tell me all locations
containing that
link
cheers so if you are a programmer if you
are
nerd you know do programming mathematics
engineering that's a great thing because
the world needs it and you will be good
you will have a
career um of course if you are not a
nerd type you can go into other
professions
um you know but but engineering is a
hardcore
good
thing okay it takes a while because
whenever you do some kind of search it
takes some a while to load you know the
10,000 files it actually have to go
through 10,000 files usually usually
takes 30
minutes for the first time because but
once you do it once then the next time
you do it is instantaneous because they
are all the files has been being loaded
to uh
memory I'm actually using a uh my hard
drive is a flash drive so it should be
fast but still take some there it is
okay so there's only one occurrence
Okay jump to it there is only one
occurrence okay should I D
it yes good okay what about this one
okay let's search again search P let's
search that search that in. infoinfo
or HTML
files now it should be instantaneous you
see only one occurrence okay open should
I delete it
yes okay and remove that remove remove
Okay so
so this remove that common
okay
now showing
browser uh
where is my head okay so what is
this I want to make sure that you can
see okay so anyway go
down go down go down go down go down go
down go down down down there it is
Optical property
okay so we did this
fantastic and uh this part is the old
code yeah we should R delete it okay I
you know I'm going to delete it offline
so anyway so here we use the package so
this should be changed let me show you
what is the proper
way
um so here here's a code so instead of
that line you should just
say you just say
needs okay so you just say needs needs
is a mechanism of loading a package so
here instead of a file path you you just
say the package name
okay uh so the package name will be that
okay then remove that okay now
now let's kind of clean up the code a
little
bit
um okay so it's like that put it
back syntax color it go to browser
refresh okay so now you see that's much
better so for other people now I'm going
to you know upload this to my website
update so other people can copy the code
then you know they have to install it
the plan code plot and put it in a
special directory just like emac you
know wam language is exactly a lisp so
it's just like emx you have a init
directory so you need to put this
package in the in directory then then
you say
needs which will load the package which
in emac it's like um require okay so the
emac lisp analogous to the wam language
needs is required you know so so so for
example I can show you
um so for example HTML mods so you got
this bunch of require require require
that
means you know that means Lo this
package if it's not already loaded yet
okay and this you know for this new
common browser URL Ur
U and so on those are in emac this they
are called feature names okay now
similarly almost exactly the same almost
exactly the same
instead of require you say needs okay
and the planker plot is a is a symbol is
a uh package name so in iMac LP they
call feature name but in wolfen language
it's called package name so you know but
basically these two are like
identical so you load the package if
it's not loaded already then you know
that will generate that okay uh close
close close so this part actually needs
to be placed it here so back to browser
refresh
okay okay I think that's it any
questions we talked for almost an hour
now uh so that
shows my workflow it shows you my
workflow how I work on my website how I
update my website it showed use some
wolam language
code uh Tech you know wolam language
technology you know I should
um so the alternative to doing this is
not to load a
package uh yeah but then the code gets
you
know if you load the package the code is
only one line or five five lines okay
but if you downlo the package you need
to draw these lines you'll take you know
50 lines or
something yeah so I think you know I I
have to think about this which uh Choice
should I make I think I'll load the
package
yeah yeah okay any questions any any
questions for me and that's it for today
thank you guys for
watching have have a good
night so we shutting down in a minute
okay we shut down in a minute
fantastic beautiful you know this all
these beautiful mathematics and geometry
they are beautiful in two ways
one way is just the sheer visual Beauty
you know you you can see is kind of
beautiful visual Beauty okay the other
way is the mathematical Beauty this is
more abstract you know as spon Russo you
know one of the greatest philosopher and
mathematician in the past 100 years
beron Russell who happens to be my idol
as well beron Russell
influenced me a lot okay so if I have to
name one single guy that influen my life
the most that would be butron Russo okay
he's he's a logician he's a
mathematician mostly known for his work
in uh math foundation so logician okay
and he's a philosopher he's uh one of
the greatest philosopher you know
foundational in in Western
Society because he is the philosophy of
the school called analytic
philosophy uh and also a sub branch of
that is called logical positivism okay
look at beron Russell you know he's a
BRI British man so he's a logician one
of the greatest you know the most
influential in the past 100 years beron
Russell veral in his work in that in
that field is mostly in the foundation
of mathematics he's a logist he believes
you know
logic
logicism okay anyway so great great one
of the great mathematician and he's one
of the great philosopher okay in the
past 100 years Western
philosopher uh but he's also one of the
greatest uh
pacificist you know so meaning that he
fight for the arment of
nuclear weapons and uh for that he has
been put to jail by United States of
America uh by the
Christians he's beron Russo is also one
of the guy who is
against the in
institutionalized religion okay so he
has criticized Christianity a lot for
example one of his most famous essay is
why I am not a Christian okay that's one
of the great article by
him uh so butron Roso is personally my
idol one one of you know one of the top
my idol so anyway so mathematics you
know so you have visual Beauty you know
just anyone looking at it without
knowing mathematics you can see it's
beautiful and if you learn something
about it you'll know oh these are you
know these are Optical properties you
know a light Ray from one point deflect
to refract to the other Focus actually
did okay so actually I didn't I doesn't
show here yeah okay so
this so This I need to add more another
picture to show the to show the not just
reflection but the defraction to the
other
Focus actually that can be done easily
here uh by saying negative okay there it
is okay so I I should have used this
picture so so in this picture you can
see the reflection but also the
defraction
wait uh yeah yeah you see it
there so there's a visual Beauty but
then then but then then there's a
mathematical Beauty which is you know
you look at you know like you have this
formula you know you have this abstract
you know like
uh where is a Formula you know you have
this you have this abstract formula
secant square root and tangent you
know then they have this focal focal
properties and a bunch of other
properties so it's like just
tremendously amazing