good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 2020 may 22nd friday
3 o'clock in the afternoon san francisco
time
and am i alive
the livelihood must be checked
so let's start this code and let's show
my
emacs screen
my emacs screen for those of you emacs
users
so this pink window will show all my
emacs commands
so today's topic uh i don't know
i don't so if you have a question put it
to me okay
and let's see what we're gonna talk
about and yesterday i had a epic
fail 100 epic fail i was talking
non-stop i was doing a great show for
one hour
then after one hour i realized
i i was not streaming
and uh there is this guy jay team90
who gave me 100 who asked questions
about
machine learning and artificial
intelligence so i talked about that for
like 20 minutes or 30 minutes then he
also asked about constructive
mathematics
i also talked about that for like 10
minutes i also answered quite a bunch of
questions
alan's question about the artwork and
arie ryan's question about nudity in
society
so that's one hour talking to myself
what a epic failure spectacular
okay so what we are going to talk about
first of all i'm going to
tell you the great artwork of yesterday
now so let's see star talk show today
and uh so if you have questions put it
to me okay
now let me show you sentient trash can
now this is sentient trash can out
vile jelly donuts
now this is by a friend a online
acquaintance i know
his name is florian
lengo lengio or however you pronounce it
you can go to his instagram uh just
search for
sentient trash can you probably seeing
my website cazar arts
uh the url is on top there you can see
and
then you go to his instagram he's got
lots of a few more
uh several other artworks so his artwork
is
um fantastic they are uh how do you
describe it philosophy
i was trying to find the word to
describe his kind of artwork it's
it's not you know this word is not a
particularly about the style of the
artwork
but rather about the content of the
artwork um
something like philosophical but it's
that's not the right word
i i don't remember what's the right word
but it it gives you
kind of a a strange sense
um oh yeah i remembered um
nonsensical not nonsensical the
the universe mysterious universe
which is you know there's a genre of
science science fiction
where you use this term to describe that
genre
cosmic some sort of cosmic hero
uh uh i forgot what's the phrase does
anyone know
basically it means that it means the
content i mean the
content address describes the
the randomness the nonsensical the
um the way of you know the questions we
don't know so anyway so he's got
so let's see uh where are we
wait a minute
chrome just crashed what the
oh did i quit it by mistake i think
chrome just crashed
okay let's get back let's see
lovecraftian yes that's yes that's a
word but
actually but love crafty and that's uh
using
one one of the science fiction author
love lovecraft
to describe the situation but there is a
word that describes the situation
directly
aesthetical brutalist not that
i'm starting the show right you can see
it right so so let me go back to the
artwork okay so
sentient trash can so here is his
artwork and here
uh it's got this cat
anyway sentient trash can okay so you go
to his instagram
uh he's a online acquaintance
i met on google plus about seven years
ago so this is him
uh
and he um so anyway check his artwork up
very interesting sentient trash can and
he's got this cat by the way
there is an artist who draw who draw
crazy
um cats let me show you okay so
uh psychodelay cats let me show you
psy psycho delic
cats
there it is and his name is
now let me find the proper name
this is so slow jesus let's show it
luis when i believe the name is luis
wayne
it's very interesting so
psychedelic cat
yeah luis wayne so let's let me show it
[Music]
l-o-u-i-s-w-a-i-n
there it is so you have a wikipedia
article
so he is a guy he's an artist you know
he begin drawing cats
for children for example this is one of
his artwork for children
uh let me show you okay then over the
over a decade his cat becomes crazy
crazy more crazy and crazier in the
beginning it's uh cats for children like
that
like that then later on his cats becomes
becomes like that
so this guy luis wayne so you can look
it up
and so my friend my acquaintance this
guy
i suppose this artwork is inspired by
that luis wayne's cat
okay that's about the artwork let's go
to the next topic
let me copy the url so
copy url and put to today's
talk so what are we going to talk about
today
anything anything otherwise i'm just
going to start to go random
uh let's see so if you have a question
for me
put it put my name to it okay at saudi
have you been have you seen inland
empire no
i haven't seen that i don't know what
movie is that also i know you have
watched 2001
a space oddity uh yeah it's that's a
great film
but it's somewhat boring in the end
because that
kind of draw draw draw on you know but
space quality that's a great film so let
me
talk about that okay sorry
space other t now there there are quite
there are two things
uh let me show you about that david
bowie this is a fantastic
song by david bowie space oddity
uh and the space odyssey okay so the
other one is space odyssey
space other c
i spelled it wrong uh land of
land of lisp let's see
o d e s y right
uh o d y
s s e y yeah other c you know that's
that's
that's like the greek drama
space o d d y s a c
y something like that
there it is uh but i want to
find space odyssey
my article about okay so i know where it
is
sound music
okay search space
other tea and space dementia that's
another great song
by midnight poison
uh and there it is stacey bell in 2001
a space odyssey so here is my article
let me show you okay
here so here's my article and uh
so you if you haven't already you should
check it out
so this this this movie it's got an
interesting i mean
this is a great movie uh it's you know
got a classic
it shows human animals and
you know it it's kind of philosophical
and describe the human
uh human the meaning sort of
bit meaning of human human animals with
respect to
uh the cosmo let me find the other word
lovecraftian
uh yeah love crafty and harold that's
the uh but i'm trying to find a word
that describes cosmosism cosmosism
uh but that's not the word i was
thinking
cosmetic cara perhaps
cosmeticism is the literary philosophy
developed
and used by the american writer
lovecraft
in his weird fiction in his weird
fiction
lovecraft was a writer of
philosophically intense horror stories
that
involves a cult phenomenon like astral
possession and alien
uh missing mis miscenter nation
and themes of his fiction over time
contributed to the development of his
philosophy
cosmic colorado i think that's what i'm
looking for cosmic cargo
uh okay so so let's go back to so
you know this is a great movie uh 2001 a
space odyssey odyssey is the
homeless you know the uh great greek
classic novel odyssey
i haven't read that uh and in space
odyssey there's
this interest interesting thing
that is the computers since a song
let me show you part of it
can you hear it
i gotta stop that because
so how uh ho 9000
is a artificial intelligence computer
program
and it's supposed to be here in 2001
but it's not we are in 2020 it's not
here yet
so space odyssey this movie is made in
1960s
1958 or 1960 something like that
so they predicted this is how the future
going to be
in 2001 but we are we don't have that at
all
so there is this computer uh artificial
intelligence
sentient computer whole 9 9000
that since the song daisy bail and
interestingly
around 2001 someone wrote a
pearl program that uses artificial
synthesizer
on the mac so you run this program and
you're actually seeing the song
so that's fantastic uh
but i cannot run it now because it's
missing a library
but i believe it's possible to get it to
run but i didn't have time to get it to
work
so this is 2005
a pearl program that seems a song using
on the mac so if you
you know i would be interested if you
try to you know if you get it to work
let me know
okay so that's about space oddity uh
odyssey the movie now there
is uh let me show you another one okay
the land of lisp
that's a book okay that's kind of boring
so let me show you
so david bowie has a song space other t
that's another fantastic song
so let me copy the copy the url and put
to kaza's talk today
okay i'm a bit now or
messed up space other t okay
now space odyssey space odyssey
copy it show in browser okay close
close space dementia is another great
song
now this song now this song
there's a lyrics it goes a twist
of love gives us hate a
poison of midnight dementia in space
actually that that poem is written by me
okay
but the the song has a lyrics
oh
i gotta stop that so so this song
is used in a perfume advertisement you
know the
dears uh you know women's perfumes
you know it's interesting if you look at
women's perfumes their bottle
their artwork um and
their naming of things for example this
one is called midnight poison
you know you might think who would want
to put poison you know
to to use something to use the name
poison but that is the fact that that is
what perfumes are usually named after
usually it's you know
it's essentially um seduction
and erotics and you know lots of
you know they
they some of the perfume bottles they
are shaped like um
or tits or you know female
you know that that's the thing it's very
interesting
so there's this ad featuring this girl
she's a famous actress
famous actress eva green in one of the
james bond girl and uh
this is a great ad by the way it's
beautiful
and uh and it features the song
by muse you know which is uh how do you
classify what's the name of these uh
class of song
it's kind of the
i don't know hot heavy metal part um
something something
i cannot think right now for some reason
space dementia
and this song there's these uh lyrics
so so it says
h8 is the one for me it
gives me all i need and helps me coexist
with the chio uh it's it's pretty good
uh lyrics and and notice they use
the letters h8 to stand for
hate
it's very interesting
so that's about that song okay so let's
go back
let's see what what else i want to talk
about
uh i can't talk right now so
let's see do you like dogs too are cats
your spirit animals dogs and cats
yes i love them but i like cats better
did you know what the writer of 2000
writer of 2001 a space odyssey author
c clock went to a science fair and
saw a robot singing daisy bail that was
how he
got the idea okay i didn't know that but
well i know he talked about it but
you know the the first one for the first
there's actually a computer the ibm
mainframe that is the first computer who
sent the song
and
and here is a recording of it ibm 1794
singing uh since daisy bail that's the
first
song sent by computer in 1961
okay so
okay you you cannot hear the music okay
there must be something you have to do
with other channel or something
uh yeah that's the issue i've
um look for so anything else
how long have i been talking
right now i'm some somehow not in a
groove
so i'm not
like i forgot how to talk now
so how long have i been talking 27
minutes
okay
anything else let's see
okay let me let me um
relax and see what we're gonna talk
about we are going to do a typing demo
maybe
that yeah that's easy to do
check
okay i've been talking for 20 minutes
let's do a typing demo type eraser okay
so
there is a question so let me talk let
me tell you about these
keyboard things so we are starting to
talk about keyboard actually now
since i mentioned about keyboard i
actually have quite a lot of things to
show
you guys new things now logitech g herb
is the worst software okay don't
i mean the logic tech g herb starting
about half a year ago
logitech came out with a new software
for their gaming devices gaming keywords
and gaming mice
before before the g herb it's called
logitech
gaming software and that software is one
of the greatest
software it's the it's very extremely
easy to use
and powerful you can set your mouse or
keys
to whatever um you know uh you know you
can program the buttons and you're
working any operating system without
needing to install the software again
but about half a year ago logitech came
out with a new
uh software g-hub that is that is
replacing the
the old one logitech gaming software so
g-hub
but g hub is the worst
possible to the degree that
i do not i no longer recommend logitech
uh mouses because when you buy a
logitech mouse for example
for example i was trying to program this
uh
these mouse i have using you know i
downloaded their latest version g-hub
you know they they named it g-herb and
it actually bricked
my mouse because all the programs you
know the the the keys i programmed
i want to change one of them but after
using g-hub it's screwed up you know
it's very it's extremely hard to find
out how to do things and
you know and some you know even it's
impossible maybe
so it essentially breaks my uh the mouse
i had
so i had so eventually i found out that
their old version the logitech gaming
software is still available online
so i downloaded that then i change it
back you know then i did what i wanted
but now if you buy a new logitech mouse
for example let's say
you know so i've been thinking i want to
buy a new mouse for example this one
this one is new if you buy this mouse
you cannot program it with the old
software the logitech
gaming software you cannot program it
with that
you have to use the g-hub so
but with a g-hub i collected many
comments on amazon and also my personal
experience
you you know here's many uh comments on
amazon
the g-hub is just impossible to use so
so you know if you buy a new logitech
mouse it
essentially becomes um a break
did you get a tech text shinobi what's
the text shinobi
uh okay so so logitech g hub is no good
okay
i got several other things to tell you
okay now here is a mouse with a
mechanical key switches
modification i think that's a great idea
because
one of the hand pen caused by mouse a
lot of people have
you know hand pain repetitive strain
injury with the mouse
one of the problem i think i'm pretty
sure is the
mouse button because the mouse button
they are you know
they are pretty stiff you know you have
to exert pressure
and you know pretty stiff so i think it
would be much better if
someone created a mouse with a
mechanical keyboard keys
preferably low profile
uh blue clicky switches i think that's a
great
great idea so some people have tried to
do that you know someone drew this
schematic
and some people actually did that so i
think that's uh that's a great idea
so if you you know we wait for someone
to market that
now another news is that there's two new
pieces
of trackball from elecom
now these both of them are for
pretty small they are for mobile
purposes so one is
index finger based trackball each one of
them got five buttons
pretty basic so this one is finger
index finger based and this one is
thumb based and
either of them they have a bluetooth
version and the wireless version
like they for some reason the japanese
makers they separated them
so you either buy the bluetooth version
or you buy the
usb wireless version with a dongle
transceiver
and also let me show you okay let me
show you so i have a collection
of all the trackball sizes so here they
are
so you can see all the
sizes of the balls so this one is
actually
25 millimeter uh ball
which is 2.5 centimeter actually i
didn't
i forgot to write it so let me do it
right now so
open the page and uh and go here
let me magnify show the keyboard so you
can see my
emacs operation so paste it here
modify 25 there it is show in browser
so you can see now it says 25 millimeter
so you have 32 millimeters 34
millimeters
uh 34 millimeter balls are very popular
so all these
these these these these these these
are all compatible you can switch the
balls
then you have bigger balls so that's
about that and also you can buy the
replacement balls
these days you know today you can easily
buy the replacement
balls they come you know it's on amazon
they specifically designed for
the trackballs but let's say five years
ago it's usually difficult
for example if you have a logitech
trackball you want to replace the ball
you you buy them it costs like twenty
dollars it's almost like buying a new
trackball
so mark barrowzov gave me five dollars
five pounds which is like six dollars
thank you
i challenge everyone here to do a super
chat
thank you okay so let's i'm going to do
a type demo okay so
yeah let me so so let me uh okay
hold on a second let me show about let's
put the topic here
talk show and show the keyboard magnify
open it magnify and
midnight david bowie midnight trackball
and both sides so we talked about that
and electron trackballs we talked about
that
and go here so now let me talk
about keyboard
the speed differences of different
keyboards
so let me go going to show you my
keywords
okay and this is answer this is the
answer to
one of the guys super super are you here
you know
there it is super super get on
super are you in the chat like say
something in the youtube chat
so let me get the keyboard let's do a
typing comparison on different keyboards
so there it is my kinesis advantage to
keyboard and plug it in
so let me tell you what's going on so
when you are doing a speed typing for
example
uh in in typing competitions keyboard
matters
okay some keyboard are slower some are
faster
and typically you know the laptop
keyboard you know they got
thing profiles so you don't have to push
so much to activate
it laptop keyboards are fast okay so if
you are doing
a typing competition you want to use
laptop keyboards
but if you want to um
but but however you know you know
usually
keyboard nuts we are into mechanical
keyboards
you know with mechanical keys so let me
show you
um
you know for example right now i'm using
my um
this is stupid let me connect it let's
see if i can
okay so i'm using the um
the le which side is left which side is
right what the
yeah okay okay let me pull my camera
okay
and let me show you my desk
so let's go over here
and let's show you my desk okay so right
now i'm using this
this uh ultimate hacking keyboard
okay and now here is kinesis keyboard
now both both of them are mechanical
keys because you can see
the keys uh there's some depth to it
and this is this that my micronesis is
using
uh cherry mx brown keys which is tactile
and here on the happy hacking on the
ultimate hacking it's uh
it's linear red switches so
linear switches is faster than the
cherry mx brown but also because of the
shape of the
kinesis it's actually much uh kind of
fairly uh significantly notice
noticeably slower if you want to uh
do a speed typing so let's go to type
razor and let's do some
comparison so in summary
if you are doing speed typing like such
as in competition
different keyboards matters okay laptop
kind of you know low profile that's the
fastest
kinesis is the slowest now
but however remember that kinesis you
know
speed has little to do with comfort so
kinesis is the most comfortable
so if you are typing for example four
hours a day for a year
and you use the laptop keyboard that's
going to ruin your hands
the next year you cannot type anymore
yeah you type fast but
but next year you cannot type anymore so
you actually do want a comfortable
keyboard
so you see the these are some of the
intricacies and complexities about
keyboarding
uh you cannot have everything you know
you
you actually theoretically it's possible
to have a
very fast keyboard that's and also most
comfortable
yeah for example this uh my ultimate
hacking keyboard it's
you know it's very fast so let me show
you let's see the difference
okay so i'm going to go to type racers
okay so let's see
uh let's quit this code okay
and enter typing race okay so i'm going
to start to type
on these i guess
get ready to race oh and
three two one
say my trailer is legally defined as a
ah
it
oh they they require everything to be
correct
okay now i know because one of the
technique
is is to skip when you got a mistake
just skip it just keep going
you don't want to fix the errors because
that slows you down
but on this particular side they require
i said i think they require uh it to be
correct
actually i won for this one wait did i
i did some other people don't know how
to
type okay so what's uh
54 world per minutes okay that's
usually i can like if i didn't practice
it would be
70 words per minute if i practice
for you know for for 30 minutes i'll be
80 watt per minutes i can go up to
90 usually so let's do another one okay
um i got a warm up
how can you guys join i i think for you
guys to join
i have to register a account something
like that
so if you found out how you know post a
link i'll go there
otherwise let's do another one so let's
see race again
okay
ah
68 world per minute better let's do
again
yes sign me up no i don't want to sign
sign up no thanks
actually i need to get prepared there
you know
and me
you
69 world per minute okay
well that's about 70 word penance the
the most error are
you know the correcting arrow that costs
you that's a problem
okay that's with my um ultimate hacking
keyboard let's let's try the kinesis
keyboard but
before i do that i
um
so before i do
the type pin test i need to
warm up on my kinesis
keyboard first okay let's let's do it
now i'm using kinesis actually i should
point the camera to my keyboard so you
can see
i didn't mean to
do that please
now that's a quote from pulp fiction
you can see actually i'm slower
partly also because
because
what does
what country
what
english do you speak it
then you know what i
i am i'm
saying
so that's significantly slower 52 per
minutes
partly because
i haven't been been typing on my kinesis
for the past for today
so you have to actually use it to get
warmed up
but you know it's a bit it's a bit
slower than
my ultimate hacking keyboard
okay i think that's about that let's see
youtube comments
i think my type racer you can still
press ctrl backspace to delete the whole
world oh you can
okay that's a trick you know
with these websites you have to know can
be faster for correcting mistake yeah
note uh 2d the whole world either then
make a bunch of small corrections
yeah ctrl a select all and delete
backspace
okay pulp fiction
okay so that's about that anything else
okay i'm let's see what else i want to
talk about so yesterday we talked about
uh i'm i answer i try to answer the
question why is web
why is web technology so complex so
up
and i end up uh you know talking about
that for
30 minutes something like that
now let's do another one maybe
you see um
you see the control backspace
uh to delete a word that's great
but however for me that does not
necessarily work
because i have you know for example in
my emacs
for me to delete the word backward let
me show you okay
so let's see i want to delete this word
experiences so to delete that i just
press
this key a dot you know a single dot on
the borac so
undo let me show you again you see a
single dot on both rack
so i'm used to this is stuff like keys
on emacs
so i'm used to this way of working i
never actually press ctrl backspace
in fact i've reprogrammed my keyboard
such that control backspace is usually
not easy to do for example on my kinesis
to press control backs backspace
i have to use both of my thumb you know
one finger on control and one finger on
backspace so it's
because i don't have control key on the
right hand
so i think maybe that's it for today
coffee no more coffee
what do i think about text editors
versus ide
well what to say about that basically
you know text editors is sufficient for
text editing
well ide is typically designed
to in general okay the the general idea
that
you know the id integrated integrated
developer
development environment
okay that's what it stands for
integrated development
environment you know by definition
ide is better purely by definition
because
it has far more features and this
integrated you need you know this id
is designed by design
from the ground up it is designed for
you for programmers to compile
uh code and you know you have debuggers
you have all
sort of tools and features designed for
particular
for programming developers purposes
especially
for particular languages such as c
c plus plus java you know in
in in these languages you typically use
ide
but anyway in general it doesn't matter
what language you program
the very concept the definition of the
ide
itself means it's better okay
it's simply better than a text editor
you know simply
just editing text now however
however in the real world the ide
typically became
such that it relies on buttons you know
it relies on graphical user interface
so for nodes you know for
efficiency nodes you know relying on gui
is
typically not efficient so typically
for in particular microsoft windows you
have to use mouse okay so let me
summarize id
the very definition of id means it's
better
it is just better than text process
text editors period however
in real world typically ide
because of social reasons they
the way ids ides are typically very
inefficient and
bloated uh
for social reasons okay not for
technical reasons for social reasons
therefore meanwhile therefore many
many of many of us prefer text editors
you know such as emacs and vi
so that's uh that's my opinion about
that i
myself almost have never used ides
because i don't program in those
languages i don't
i don't really have experience in
compiled languages
such as c c plus first
um java well i know java and i know go
lan okay
but i never worked with them
in a company
so that's about that that's my answer
for that
let me put my kinesis keyboard away
um
an exception any any so um
so hello says any text editor can become
an id
just make more add-ons not
not necessarily so you know so hello is
saying any text editors can become an
ide
not really he you know hello says you
all you have to do is just add on
extensions
that's false for these kind of things
you have to
design from the beginning you cannot
simply make an
uh text editor to become an ide
you can you know many text editors they
don't have extension
possibility you know they don't have the
architecture for example notepad
are you going to make notepad to become
an ide
no or the simplest text editor on the
mac
text edit so right now i'm on textedit
so this is a text editor you know the
simplest one can you make it
to become an ide no so
for emacs for example v emax and vim
you could okay you could do you know
you could add features so it becomes
more like ide but
not not really not exactly
okay i think uh maybe that's it for
today let's see how long i've been
talking
40 50 minutes okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
bye and also uh uh j
team so if you are watching i don't know
you know
you last time you answered yesterday you
asked the question about
machine learning and artificial
intelligence
too bad you know i didn't i made a
mistake so i wasn't online
uh so i don't know if i should
you know do a video talk about that
you know maybe not because you probably
have seen
you know my talk about those things but
anyway so i think
the best thing is that if you are online
you know you are yeah you ask me live
you know then i'll talk about that
that's better
okay bye guys