Hello guys, good morning. Welcome to
another episode of Kasantop Show. We are
going to code advent of code. Ad event
of code 2025
day one problem two in wufam language.
Video check, audio check. Okay, so I'm
using ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80.
That's this one. Fantastic. I got a
review on YouTube. You can watch.
Okay. So today's talk show uh continue
from yesterday. We did day one
yesterday.
So it's fantastic video check. So if you
are watching this offline play at 1.5
speed. If you are watching here live say
hi. Hello Danv. Hello everyone. So Danv
are you a wam language coder? Are you
already know language or or are you
Emacs Emac list Emacs user or Python
coder or something? So let's begin.
Okay. So we we did uh yesterday Wufam
language uh this is yesterday. So the
problem we drew a diagram interesting
diagram
at the end of a code usually you have to
do diagrams. Okay. So uh and today uh
two part two uh problem two. Okay. Now
if you don't know Wufam language it's
the most advanced high level language by
a magnitude
uh more than Haskell Julia Lisp closure
any this uh any fancy language okay and
you can download it here follow this
link search for Wuam download Wuam
engine on kali.info info wam language
for programmers. Okay, you can download
it for free beginning about 5 years ago
and uh go back go back uh download and
wam language for programmers and the
kasaw wufam mode which I'm using allows
me to code wam language in emacs. Okay,
let's begin. Okay. And kafly keys that's
my key binding system is the most
efficient than even more efficient than
vim or neoim if you count keystrokes for
emacs. Okay. So I I've done like
hundreds videos about all those topics.
So today let's focus on the day day one
part two. Okay. So go to the problem. Go
to it. Switch to it. That's the right
answer. You are one gold star closer to
decorating the North Pole. Continue to
part two. The problem part two. Let's
read it aloud like reading a poetry
day. I still have code. It's annoying. I
still have code. Okay, this this you see
this advent of code idiotic website
design. They they have hardcoded layout.
So you cannot uh you know have narrower
window. very idiotic. Okay, let's just
continue. Okay, so comments if you have
comments or questions. Hello. Hello.
Light something. Hello, Dan. A little
bit of wolf wolf. Not so much lisp, but
interested. Fantastic. Okay, so I'm
starting to grow audience of wam
language. Before it was keyboards and
eagp and stuff. So, part two. Okay. So,
let me have a sip. I'm still having a
code.
Um, okay. So, you are sure that's the
right password, but the door won't open.
Okay. So, you still need to increase
this.
You are sure that's a password, but the
door won't open. You knock, but nobody
answers. You build a snowman while you
think. As you are rolling the snowballs
for your snowman, you find another
security document that must have fallen
into the snow. Due to newer security
protocols, please use password method
0x434
C 4943 4B until further notice.
Okay. So, it's got the document. Okay.
That with that magic number. Okay. You
remember from the training seminar that
method this now check is that the same
number? Yes, it is. Okay. Now, method
this 0x something means you are actually
supposed to count the number of times
any click causes the dial to point at
zero.
Okay. Regardless of whether it happens
during a rotation or at the end of one.
Oh, you idiotic I think I already
know what's the problem.
So, previously you want to count
after each rotation left or right if the
pointer is at zero.
Okay. But now I suppose you want to
count every time if it passes zero.
Okay, that's I suppose that's what the
question is.
Okay, so method that that means you
actually supposed to count the number of
times any clicks any click causes the
dial to point at zero regardless whether
it happened during a rotation or at end
of one. Okay. So if you just count when
it stops at zero then that method is is
given a name this zero x something
following the same rotation as in the
above example. The dial points at zero a
few extra times during this during its
rotation. What does that mean?
Uh the dial start at pointing at 50. The
dial is rotated L68
to point at 82. So 50 L means minus 50
minus 68
uh is -8.
Then because there are 100 numbers you
plus 100. So 18 -8 + 100 is 82. Okay.
Check.
So point at 82 during this rotation it
points at zero once.
Okay. Now you need to go back to the
diagram. Okay. Let's see.
So when when when you have a diagram
like this one. So it basically certain
rotations the zero the pointer will pass
zero or zero will fly by it.
Okay. So what are you saying during this
rotation it points points at zero once
you see a bit ambiguity because now you
don't consider rotation as one shot. I
mean so each click it stops. Click click
click click click click stop. So during
this rotation it it points at zero once.
Okay. The dial is rotated L30 to point
at 52. So 82
L30 minus 30 is 52. Okay. The dial is
rotated then R48 2.80. So r 48 uh + 52
that's 100 plus 100 divided by 100 is 1
minus one is zero. Okay. The dial is
rotated L5 then you got 95. The dial is
rotated R60 to point at 55. During this
rotation it point at zero once.
Okay. And blah blah and blah blah and
blah blah. Okay. and blah blah rotated L
82 to point at 32. During this rotation,
it point at zero once. Okay,
in this example, the dial points at zero
three times at the end of a rotation
plus three more times doing a rotation.
Okay.
So in this example, the new password
would be six.
Okay. Be careful. If the dial will point
at 50, a single rotation like R 1,000
would cause the dial to point at zero 10
times before returning back to 50. Okay?
So it's becoming tricky. It's going to
tell you to over overturn,
you know, R1,000.
So using password method this what is
the password to open the door? So wait a
minute. So this path password method.
Okay. This password. So this method uh
basically tells you to count anytime
when zero is passed. Okay.
Okay. So now I know the problem and uh I
can um so we need to start to code
starting to become boring or interesting
depending on your point of view.
Nobody's here. No comments. Okay. Did I
read the problem correctly? Okay. Let's
let's begin to code it. Okay. So what
what so what is the uh Okay. start the
code
from language and uh we pop it out and
we probably so let's look at yesterday's
code.
So yesterday
we just have we basically modeled the
lock the rotational lock just a list of
numbers.
So let's we need to think about this.
Okay. So you uh so you when you rotate
um
God I still got cold I got cough.
So you need to rotate. Um
so before yesterday so yesterday we we
thought about modular arithmetics which
can compute what is the ending number.
Okay. And but now you want to compute
the past zero.
So
very easy. So now first of all if it
gives a number huge number that's over
1,000.
So any number more than 100 you can just
modular arithmetic it.
then you get a number is cycles. So for
example 1,00 divided by 100 is 10. That
means this cycle will pass zero 10
times.
Okay.
So you see so any number when it's
greater than 100 you can just do a mod
and uh with and the resulting number
just add to it. Okay. But then other
other than that let's see so if you
let's say you have something like that
you want to so how how does do you
determine when zero passes okay so let's
say the current number is five
and you rotate right by one you get six
you don't pass zero Okay. Now, if you
rotate right by two, you get seven. You
don't pass zero.
Okay. Now, but if you rotate left by
one, you get four. No passing zero. So,
when you rotate, let's see, one, two,
three, four, five. If you rotate left
five times, you stop at zero. Okay? If
you rotate left six times, you pass
zero.
Okay. Now, is there a distinction
between stopping at zero and passing
zero?
So, in other words, does stopping at
zero count? Tricky question. This trying
to this elves trying to trick me.
So when you stop at zero, does that
count as like one? Oh yes it does
because you know it like
stopping at zero in this example the
dial point is zero three times at the
end of the rotation plus three more
times during a rotation.
Okay. So you also so you count when it
stop at zero. You also count when it
pass zero. So both of them count.
Okay.
So now when you stop at zero. So when
you pass zero. So how do you know when
it pass zero? When the number of
rotation is let's see okay this is about
greater than or less than problem. So if
you are rotating left,
if you are rotating left
and the rotation number.
Oh god, what a tedious problem. Okay, so
I need to
I need to suppress my cough.
So you need to count the total number
of zero including passing zero.
Okay, let me just think about this.
Okay, so
have you guys done the problem? No
comments. Okay. So
when you rotate left first of all the
number are arranged in counterclockwise.
Remember that.
Now when you rotate left
and uh
when the number of rotation
is
greater than the current number. So the
current number is five.
So if you rotate five to the left.
Oh, okay. So there's a left left and
right issue. So if you rotate rotate to
the left
five times,
five is equal to the current index.
That means it ends at zero because five
rotate left minus five means minus five
you get zero. Okay. But if you rotate
left six times
that's 5 minus 6
uh which gets you 99. Okay. So you pass
zero. So how do you um so if the
rotation number
is
greater than
the current number.
Okay. Then you get then you get um
okay we can do we can simplify this by
modular arithmetics.
Let's write it out because I'm doing a
live stream. So let me just you know
keep myself busy so you can see what we
doing.
If
the current lock number
is
the current number let's call it current
index
wide speed asparagus. What does that
mean?
wide speed asparagus.
The the the
current number, let's call it current
index,
the rotation number.
his number of clicks
to rotate.
God. Oh my god. Cough.
For example, R of five. [clears throat]
It's five. Okay.
So you got the current number, you got
the rotation number.
Let's call it um
let's call it [laughter]
C.
Let's name it
uh okay let's make it
let's not use uh n
is five okay
so you know we start to name variables
If
C
uh
go.
Oh god.
Uh
okay. Let's copy it. Let's do it in Wam
language. Okay.
If C if N is greater than C
zizo is one old think.
Oh god I'm I got this C.
So if n is greater than um so you got
rotate left and rotate right. you got
the left and right issue. So if
so first of all
mod
and
100 okay then uh
let's say
let's Say total
number of times passing zero
or
including stopping at zero. Okay.
So total equals to uh first of all
okay so it is uh it's starting to make
sense.
C equals to something. Okay. C equals to
current number. Let's say five.
Okay. Then the rotation number
uh
the rotation number let's say given r5
n equals to
five six okay let's say Six.
Okay. Now it's all simplified. You see
now
given given let's say uh let's say 600
first of all total equals to
modular arithmetic 1,00 over 100. Do it.
Let's see what happens.
running wam language.
Oh, wait a minute. You want that's a
remainder. So, you can't do mod. You got
do you got to use the rem the the
dividant.
Let's see. dividant divisor
quotient you want to get a quotient okay
not the remainder so
let's see if there's a function named
quotient there it is
so what is the syntax I don't know let's
just try an error
that's correct looks like so let's look
up the documentation. Quotient. Whoops.
Oh, 1,00. No. Quotient.
Quotient. MN gives the integer quotient
of M and N.
Fantastic. Okay. Now, Wuan language got
fancy stuff.
Question table something something.
Okay. Question is what we want. So uh so
first so
so first of all total equals to
quotient
n. Okay.
So first of all you do that.
Now you you need to
take care of which way it turns. So
because the result is different. Okay.
So,
so if current number is five, let's go
back to our diagram so it's easy to
understand.
So, current number is five. If we if we
rotate to the left, okay, let's change
this to left for for now. Okay, rotate
by six.
Okay,
rotate by six.
So,
so we will end up at 99.
So, let's just first of all document it
first. Okay. New
new C
equals to um mod
I'm pretty sure.
So current. So uh C
and uh
N.
Okay.
So we run it.
Okay. So this gives you five.
Wait.
That's
what
Oh, yeah. So mod wait. So
that's right. So C + N
mod 100. Okay.
The result is should be 99. Okay. And uh
actually minus one. We need to minus
one. Okay, let's try it.
10. Wait, not plus. Okay, this is minus.
Remember L is for minus. Run it again.
Fantastic. But not quite correct. That's
off by one issue. Let's double check. So
if we want to rotate left six times. So
1 2 3 4 5 6. So six times it should
result in 99.
So you don't want uh wait,
you don't want minus
one.
Yeah.
But uh but if you don't minus one,
there's a problem. Okay, I think
wait so we
do we want the modular to be 100 or 99?
If it's 100, the remainder is always
between zero or 99. That's right.
So if the modular number is let's say
three
like something divided by three, the
remainder will always be zero or one or
two. That's right. So always one number
less. So if the modular
number is 100,
the remainder is always between zero or
99. That's right. Okay. So the current
index
five minus the rotation L6.
Um
oh this actually let let's code the
minus sign into it. So this this should
this is cleaner. Okay.
So it all means minus. Okay.
Yeah
then. Okay. Let's run it.
Okay. Neg uh five. What
what are we doing here?
-6 run it
and uh what about this part? This part
this is the quotient.
So if it's negative, we don't care. Only
if it's we want to do this only when
oh god when n is greater than 100. So
ignore this part for now. Okay. But now
is this part right? So okay. So let's
remove that. Let's move it down. Okay.
So I hope you are feeling better. Okay.
I'm doing better. Okay. So now,
so now um so let's just model this one
single rotation. Did we get it right?
the current index
plus rotation
and the
modular arithmetic 100. Okay, so hold on
a second.
So you want to get the remainder and
modular arithmetic. The co the the you
want to get the quotient and the
remainder at the same time. One shot.
Let's see. Let's see if there's a
function does that.
So mod gets you the remainder modular
operation. Okay.
Now, is there a function that combines
both mod and remainder?
[clears throat]
Let's see
quotient remainder. There it is. Let's
open a new tab.
Give a list of the quotient and
remainder.
Fantastic.
Okay.
Okay. Let's test uh let's say 10
20 divided by three.
Okay. Divided by 3.
You got 18. 3 * 6 is 18. remainder is
two. That's correct. Okay. Now, let's
modify.
Okay. That's uh let's modify this this
line. Okay. So, we don't want mold. So,
okay. So, we let's put there
and
something like that. Okay.
And this we don't need. Let's run it.
Okay. So, so the result is this is 99.
That's a current index.
And uh this is the new
um what what does this get get you? So,
let's see.
Okay. So the result is that
and what does that signify?
That means
C + N.
Oh, it's negative. It's a negative
number. Okay. Now you need to deal with
negative number. You see so 5 - 6 what?
So basically we are doing this uh thing.
That's right.
Okay. So this number on the left this
quotient
integer quotient the absolute value of
that means the number of times it has
passed zero I tell you guys okay so we
already got this figured out now let's
say if the number is five rotate from
the left five let's see what we get okay
uh so let's remove that. Okay. Run it.
Z 0. Okay. So,
okay. So, the left number,
the left hand side, the left number
means the number of times it has passed
zero.
Now, the right hand side, the the second
number is the the new index. And if it's
zero,
you know, we have to add it. Okay. So
now it's so simple.
Now let's just experiment. What if we
are rotating right?
So
excuse me.
God this
uh
so negative right let's look at the
diagram
so if we rotate from the right so let's
say rotate
five
on the right.
What you get? Uh, you got rotate, right?
So,
five, six,
e, uh, sun.
So, you got 10 rotate to the right and
you pass zero zero times. Correct? Yes.
So basically this formula is correct.
Okay, we can kind of write let's write a
function. Okay, let's just uh dud
uh because I keep coding you know keep
type keep busy that's the key to live
stream.
So
uh function
current
number. Okay. Then rotate.
Okay.
Let's say uh rotate n. Okay. Current
number we are writing a function
equals to
equals to basically just copy the whole
thing here. So
uh
so you can just do a block block is like
a local variable okay
expressions here and we don't need local
variables.
So the current number is the C C is a
current number. Okay. So C is the
current number.
Uh, and the rotate end is the end.
[clears throat]
Okay.
And uh what what is this new?
Yeah, remove that.
Why do you need Oh, yeah. So we don't
need that. That's a second. That's
already here.
Delete that.
So delete that. So one single line. So
it actually just one single line.
So
and in fact it's one single line. You
don't even need that. So that's our
function. Okay. This function will
wait. This this is not the we have to
say
uh
x operation. Okay, this is our rotation.
This is our function name.
Okay, so here
this is our function.
This function takes two numbers. The
current index then rotate n. Rotate n is
a positive or negative number. Okay. And
it returns we can start to document it.
Let's let's let's go elaborate. Okay.
This is how you document how you do
inline documentation for wam language
like this. Okay. So you just say
uh
returns a
list
A
is
let's say uh
C D okay C is
the number of times it passed zero.
D is
the new number
the new index number let's say. Okay. So
that so it's all clear.
So
okay so this all clear now let's try our
operation let's let's run it operation
uh what you want to say so you want to
say five
five run it
okay so let's put a semicolon
here to suppress test output to make it
return no. So when it returns no,
there's no output. So run it again.
So you can see
it now returns this 010. It's repeated
because because we got the examples
here. So in fact we don't Yeah. So
anyway, it returns 010.
Okay. Now,
okay. So, hold on a second. Let's clean
up. So, let's
cut let's move this out. Okay. So, from
language, this is our model. And now we
got the function. Okay. So, and what
about this
this part?
Okay,
clean.
Now run it.
So here is the output. Now
five
negative five means rotate left.
Okay.
Okay. Now if you save five negative
six
uh I'm going too slow. I'm going too
super slow. So anyway, so this
yeah you do you rotate left six times
you will go over zero one time
from from from this side from the left
rotation side. So it actually tells you
which side you you uh went over zero. So
but if you do this let's say 60 times
you need to go over 600. Okay. So let's
see.
You will end up in 99 but
passing it 11 times. I think
uh wait actually no
that's right. So you pass zero six times
and ends up in five.
Uh,
wait. He said, "So what if you do 100
times?
Can we like put a print statement
somewhere here?"
Uh, let's let's do a print statement.
Okay. Print. Uh, what do you want to
print? Do you want to say
because this is um
beginner beginners Emacs tutorial
tutorial. There's one I did about two or
three years ago on YouTube. It's got a
few thousand views,
but
you know, so do you know about that?
But maybe I should do a new one though
because it was a few years ago.
So anyway, so let's focus on this. Okay,
we almost like almost done. We just need
to like um
redoing. So
So the current number is five. You
rotate left. So let's It's just Come on.
Come on. Let's get this to work, man.
So
Yeah, you rotate 100. You rotate left
100, you go you go back to five, but you
got that once there.
So if you rotate left 600, you get back
to five, but you got six times. Okay.
Now, what does the right uh if you
rotate right? Let's see what happens.
Okay. minute.
Okay. So, I think I know the answer now.
Okay. So,
the final answer
is you need to um so you got this
function operation. So,
so you are given a uh okay so let's put
it back syntax correct show in browser
regroup. So we got a
beginning model then we wrote a function
about it and we test it seems to check
out
and uh now uh so the problem is that we
going to given be given a bunch of these
right
so we do as before
uh can we do as before let's see we do
Yeah. So before we are using actual
model of the you know we got a list of
50 to 0 to 99. We shift the list rotate
left and rotate right. So we actually
model the lock almost physically.
But now what we are doing is modular
arithmetics. So we don't need to keep
the huge list.
So in the beginning state it's going to
be
yeah. So let's copy the code. Okay.
Let's copy the co
let's start to code today's
thing.
[laughter]
Excuse
me.
Almost done. Almost.
We are applying the technique of oneshot
coding
where you think for one hour and you
press a button and it's all done. One
shot. Correct. Okay. So,
so this is the input. The beginning
input is going to be zero and 50 because
the current index number is 50. Okay.
This is init state.
Okay. Then the input is this bunch of
thing. Okay. Uh let's
clean it up.
Then the result same like before.
Let's see uh in this state let's color
it.
So
then the input let's color it okay pink.
Then we need our function.
Function copy this operation. We define
the function here.
operation. Okay.
Okay. So there is our function. Let's
make it one line. And this test we don't
need. Test test test test.
Okay. Now our operation. So so now you
can see
we do a fold list. If you don't guys
don't know what's a fold list. fold
that's same as reduce
and here is a illustration what it does
okay just like reduce in Python and
JavaScript okay
so you do a fold
uh in fact
fold or fold at least let's see
anyway so you got a you got a fold takes
three things. One is the function which
is here. The second argument is initial
state. The third argument is a list of
input. This l R l. Okay. Now we need to
change what function we feed it. Now the
function will take two arguments. Okay.
So this Z list, let's call it state.
Okay.
Now uh and the
x operation. Okay. And did we Okay. We
don't want to confuse the names. So this
uh
so let's rename.
So this x operation let's name it do
operation. Okay,
let's uh let's just say compute.
Let's get an elaborate long name.
Compute rotate. Let's say compute
rotate. Okay. Uh let's say let's just
say do rotate.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, so the function takes two
argument a state and the do rotate.
And now before we do something else,
let's do a little trick. Let's remove
let's change this
L to negative and R2
positive. So we don't have to do the
string processing. the string start in
you know the annoying
you know like cheat because
at the end of code they don't care you
know they don't care how you get the
answer so let's not have some artificial
restriction you know like supposing the
input is such such let's just um so um
so what you do
call sore lines no
uh sad replace brackets
replace quotation mark by none. Okay.
Now to find replace again
replace capital L by negative.
Okay. Then replace capital R by
positive.
Actually just remove it.
Okay. So our
uh so
our new input is just that. Okay. Save
it. Close it. Uh wait.
Save it. Close it. Reopen it. So we get
rid of the syntax highlight.
Okay. So it's just that.
Okay. So now the you don't have to do
the state
if something if
so this if statement in fact
because we are not doing any of that we
are not doing the rotation. So
okay
so fold wait what what is okay now it
becomes this simple
now
we the function
two arguments
state and to rotate.
So what so it will happen. Yeah that's
right. So it will give you a list. So in
fact in fact this whole function is
simply
to rotate.
Okay. You don't need even to define a
personal function. So the whole thing is
just that
to rotate is a function that takes two
arguments.
Then we got initial state, we got input,
then this count. Let's not do it yet.
Let's compute this and see what we get.
Okay, copy all
now. Oh, now start wolf frame language
the most advanced
superior
supreme language.
Start it.
New notebook
three. Shift enter to start the kernel.
Okay. And make it 150 huge.
Okay. Now,
now pray to God this will work in one
shot.
The result should be
we have to do one more step. Okay. But
the final answer should be six. Paste.
Okay. So you can see
Right, right, right, right. So, shift
enter.
Fantastic.
Okay, so here is a result. Let's expand.
Let's expand.
Show all. Okay, so here is the result.
Um, let's see. each time. What does it
um
you see the answer is pretty long, but
uh maybe I don't need fist. I just need
to fold.
Let's just see.
Shift enter.
Okay, I think something is not right.
Found it. Thanks. But still looking
forward to your new video. Thank you. So
yeah, maybe I should do a new one.
Uh the old one is still good. you know,
it's like YouTubers um like every few
years, you know, you want to do a fresh
one,
but it's the same. I mean, the content
eag.
But if I do a new one, I probably would
improve it because now I have more
experience doing live YouTube. Anyway,
this this problem is like I'm I have a
headache.
I'm not solving this, which is no good.
It's already 1 hour
and I need to cough so badly.
Okay, you need to think. Okay, I I do
you guys understand what we doing? It's
it's not super clear. So this function
every time it returns two
list of two numbers.
Okay, that's wrong.
So what do you want to do? You you want
to make this number this function takes
a number like that. Okay. So let let me
show you. Okay. You want you want it to
because that represent the state. Yeah.
So
pass zero count.
Okay. You want this function to take a
number like that.
So that is the current state
pass zero count the previous state you
know then the current index number then
rotate. Okay.
So
you can either change this function or
you add this little bit over here. So
you create a new function.
Uh let's create a new function. Okay.
Okay. Let's just do whatever comes to
mind for now. Okay. Function.
So this function
takes two arguments.
Okay.
State and uh
new ops.
Then in the function you will need to
call to rotate.
Okay. So,
[cough]
so in fact the state uh
god
anyone is watching because right now I
feel like aborting
Six people.
Six people is not too bad cuz I got
cough
and and I need a break. My back hurts.
Do I look good?
Not too bad. Not too bad for my age.
Uh, okay.
So
what are we doing? We want to yeah so so
the function right now this line takes a
current number and the number of
rotation then it returns a um a pair of
numbers. Okay.
Then you want to
return some pairs of numbers.
You know it's kind of embarrassing
because otherwise be if you do in Python
or other people you finish it in 10
minutes.
Uh god.
So anyway, so so the function right now
returns this pairs a list of two things
and uh then
if you make it
you want to know the total number of
times it passes zero or ends at zero. So
compute compute compute. So yeah. So
let's why don't we make the function
take an argument like that it'll be
easier.
Yeah. So it will return
previous pass zero count. So you need to
modify this
uh because you need to add the previous
zero count.
So
you can either do it in this function or
or not do it in the function or if you
just do it like that.
Okay. So question questions decisions
Jesus
you know if you accumulate in the
function then you don't need fold list
you just use fold but if you don't
accumulate then you need fold list then
you need to at the end count all the
zeros and the number of times passing
zero. So but you have to think so. So
let's see each time.
So this is very simple current number
initial state input.
So why don't we just make it
uh No, you have to
right. So
number of times passing is passing zero.
Is this interesting?
Uh [groaning]
okay we can do this. We need to finish
this number of times.
So this function can number Hey,
So if we were to write it this way
then what will it return? It will
return.
Let me just like start to code it.
>> [sighs]
>> Okay.
So that
so that then
you
so the problem is when it stops at zero
Oh
god.
So this negative one [cough]
must be absolute. You need to make it
absolute value.
Okay, let me just code it quickly. Okay.
So,
so it's going to
return a pair of numbers
and this is going to be
absolute value
of that
plus
that
Plus
if the remainder is zero.
If remainder equals to
zero then one
else zero
and the second number is the ren this is
the remainder. Okay something like that.
Okay, if we do that then we need to
modify the
new usage. Oh god.
Yeah, but but I just want
Okay. So,
we need to modify this. Do do you guys
see what I'm doing? Do you guys
understand?
Maybe not. Let's forget about the
documentation for now. Okay, let's just
run it. See if I can get it to work.
>> [clears throat]
>> something like that. Okay. Then you
don't need um
then you don't need
so turn six.
If if it does then that does then that
means we are done without thinking too
much.
No it returns nine.
Uh
932.
Okay.
Not right.
What's our initial state? What what is
the initial state
any state?
050.
Okay. So
see 050 then one one three four five six
seven eight nine. So every time it's
adds one.
Oh wait. Yeah, we got this wrong. So
this remainder if is uh
what
If remainder equals to zero then that
means it stops at zero. Okay.
So let's see
the advent of code. It says
something something something
50 82 52
50 82 52. We got the numbers right.
Then 955
then 0 955
then 099
099 01432.
So we got the rotation right but it just
the counting is off.
How is the counting off? Well, because
cautioned and remand. Am I doing good?
Are you guys like still watching? Does
it make sense?
Uh,
need to finish this. Yes.
So, current. So, so we got the the
counting of the passing zero incorrect.
So, let's see.
0 0 some trivial error.
So absolute quotient.
So now let's double check.
So if this operation
That seems right though.
I don't know. So let's go back to
previous.
So operation
it should be zero on the first part.
That's right. Zero.
So if it's 99
then it's um let's rotate right then
it's it's it's one that's right. So this
seems correct.
Okay. So but what what is not correct
though?
So the C
it's quotient remainder pass that's the
previous pass zero count what is the
initial state initial state is 0 50
okay initial state is 050 okay
and uh question remainder And uh
Yeah, I don't know. We need to debug
this.
So,
so 82 then it's one. That's correct.
Then when it's 52
rotate L30
then you got 52.
So the quotient is still one. I mean the
the number of times it pass zero is
still one. So so far so good. Then
then R 48 you got zero again. Okay.
Then you got zero again. And all of a
sudden you got three here. So this step
is incorrect.
[sighs and gasps]
So then over then you got three again.
So we how we got three because we got
one. So it added two
other say
52. So when we get 52
then uh 48
uh 48
zero. So,
so that's one,
that's two.
Shouldn't be three.
Three, four, five, six, six.
Uh, logic is incorrect. Somewhere in
this very simple line [clears throat]
here. Okay. This this line somewhere.
So this past zero count is should be
named previous.
Okay.
So,
so that makes it easier to see.
So quotient
plus previous
now if you don't add this remainder what
happens maybe they'll get it right.
Okay, you know
there's some do it
probably right. [laughter]
So you got 632.
Now you now the
we happen to because we are brainless.
So we do trial and error and we are
correct.
But um but now the step is to to figure
out logically why is it so?
Uh I don't I don't know. I mean it's
like you just have to think about it a
little bit.
Okay. So let's put this back and let's
try it on the real problem. Okay. So
uh let's just try the real personal
input because I got pretty tired of it.
So the previous personal input is this
one. big big number.
Copy. Okay.
So, paste it.
Make a copy. Paste it. Now,
replace all
quote symbol by none.
Do it.
And uh replace capital R by none.
Do it. And replace capital L by
negative. Do it.
Okay. We got a big number. Now make it
make them multiple lines. Okay. Instead
of one big line because Emac has
problem. Okay. Now cut.
Close.
Uh actually reopen. Uh new.
Okay. Copy. Close. Uh close.
Now go back here. Now this is new input.
Okay. Now make sure
delete that. Delete that. Wait. Delete
that. Okay. That's a new input.
No,
now let's solve the problem. Now we are
done. Okay.
Copy.
Go to W notebook.
Select or paste.
Do it.
6583.
Am I correct? Let's just submit
paste. Submit.
That's not the right answer.
Go. yourself.
[laughter]
It's not the right answer.
Uh what?
Okay. So what what is not the right
answer?
What what are all these numbers? Okay.
These numbers are big input. Now did we
let's see input.
Okay.
Now we don't know
suppress the input.
Okay. So this this is this usage is
outdated. Okay. And uh
and wait why are we doubling it?
Idiotic. Okay.
So but
uh
but why is it not correct?
This usage is incorrect. But
uh but okay but it just return a number
right at the end. Wait, what is this
fold to state init state? Did we get
init state right? I think so.
Initate 050.
Right.
So let's just do it again. Okay. Select
or paste. Shift enter.
not the right answer. Your answer is too
high. If you are stuck, make sure you
are using the full input data.
Stupid input data. Did we actually get
the input? Wait, did we get the left and
right correct?
Like did we right is positive, left is
negative. So
let's look at our
so begin right 10 right 10 left 11
wait begin right 20 right 10 left 11. So
20 2011 that seems right. Okay, check
the last part.
22 34 36 neg negative positive.
Okay. 22 34 36. Okay. Negative negative
positive.
Okay. Is the data incorrect? The data
seems to be correct.
And
So all these rotation. No. Is there a
rotation of zero? You tricky
No, you know, we haven't checked the
rotation of zero. It should also work
though.
Uh
so every time it passes zero, it counts,
right?
So why why is it um
[clears throat]
I don't okay I don't know so if we do
fold list let's see it's show or
intermediate result
okay so you got this huge show
so Beginning 0 0 0 doesn't stand one
started to have
more accumulated 3 4 5 14.
Okay. Then 1,00.
Okay. Uh one problem with this state
output is that it doesn't show what's
the input because if you can also see
what is the input such as this 569 big
number that must pass at least five
times.
So then it's easier to debug.
But now
you got this output. So it just
increases. That's right. Because it
always increases.
Um
is there any
anomaly?
I don't know. So if you look at the
right side, that's a current index. So
for example, here 4117
It should have been added but it's not.
Okay. So I think you see previously we
it magically worked. That's incorrect
and we just happened to work for that.
We should have not just removed um the
reminder. Do you guys know what I mean?
like if we put it back and you see
previously
we got this um I already removed it.
Okay, but you should have
I mean the issue is what happens when it
stops on zero. Okay,
so
Uh the question is what [cough]
what happens when it stops on zero?
Okay.
Yeah, we need
Let's see. Where are we?
So we need to check what happens.
You see here is the problem.
>> [snorts]
>> So previous let's try to rewrite this
previous first
plus absolute quotient
previous zero
So if it pass So if it stops on zero
like like like what we had is that
if the remainder
wait is a remainder
Yeah, if the remainder equals to zero
then you need to add one otherwise uh
zero
something like that.
Okay.
So I don't know what why is this logic
incorrect.
Um
you see you need to if you do this then
okay so let's look at our code.
So we got that that we okay then we got
that. So let's let's modify the
documentation so it's better. Okay.
Yeah, it's repeated. Yeah. So let's
let's make a good job. Let's do a good
job.
Documentation the previous
implementation is that remove that. But
now we got
we got that that. Okay. So this this is
a new uh documentation previous zero
count current number rotate end.
Okay.
Okay. And the returns what does it
return? It returns
returns a new
where
the new
includes if
if currency The current index
number is zero. Okay, something like
that.
Okay, this is the correct documentation
for this code.
Now, but the the issue is this little
part
that
So if stops at zero.
So let's say five. Let's go back to you
know we had we need to sit down. We
can't rush you know even we spend an
hour
other people finish this in one minute.
There's a lot people you [snorts] know
these speed coders they finish the
problem in one minute actually few
seconds.
Uh but
but we need to solve this. So we need to
sit down and think about this. Uh where
where are we? So we need to go to let's
look at the diagram again
from yesterday. So this diagram.
So if the current number is five and it
rotate left five. So one, two, three,
four, five. Then it ends up at zero.
Then that zero should be added because
it stop at zero. Okay.
So
right so that's why if the remainder is
zero, you add one to the count.
No. But but does that create
consequences? accumulated consequence.
So if it's at zero, you guys comments.
Okay.
So if it's at zero.
Oh, wait. It's either or.
Wait. Okay. So the absolute quotient,
it's either So the quotient
Okay.
Okay, you got another question.
The quotient is the number of times it
passes zero. Okay,
so
the question is can the both the
quotient and what's the relationship
between the quotient and
the remainder. Okay,
it could be both zero. If you rotate
zero, so if if if it begin at zero,
you rotate zero clicks,
then you end up
with a number as zero
and uh you didn't pass zero, but you end
up at zero. So that also count one. So
in that case quotient is zero
remainder is zero
then you add one which is one that's
correct.
Now is it possible now is it possible
for uh okay so if the current number is
zero and you rotate 100 100 rotation
clicks
right or right or left. Okay. So in that
case you got a
100 divide by 100 you got one. So you
got
oh that's that's when the problem occur.
This cannot okay this.
Okay. So I think I know what's going on.
So yeah. So you see
let me show you guys. Okay. So instead
of this expression,
so basically the quotient uh so you see
the quotient and remember remainder
cannot both occur something like that.
Okay. So because one example is if the
current number is zero.
Okay. And you rotate it 100 clicks.
So the new number is also zero.
And did it pass zero? No.
Okay. So the the the the the answer
should be
one in this case because it ends on
zero. Now let's suppose you rotate 200
times.
So, so if you rotate 200 times, then you
um you pass zero one time.
Oh god, this is not
Uh we have we you know now I am out of
drink.
Why don't we I think I take a break.
Okay. I want to so we need this to
remain fun. So I need to take a break.
So let's be back in five minutes.
Something. Okay. something.
Almost done. Now, this this we don't
need. And uh let's just cut that. Okay.
10 minutes.
Hello guys, I'm back.
Turn on the video.
Check.
Okay.
What the hell is this language? This is
woo fam language, my friend.
This is Wufam language. Search for Wuam
language for programmers on sali.info.
Okay.
Wuang language tutorial.
Okay. You got their official tutorial
and you got my tutorial there. WA
language tutorial
and uh
there it is. Okay. So,
and you can download it.
Okay. It's a most advanced programming
language. Okay. We I'm back. Now, the
problem is
I kind of know the problem. The problem
is with the number zero.
So if the current number is not zero
then everything oh it doesn't stop at
zero everything works fine you just
compute the quotient
okay the quotient
but if the current zero the current
number the remainder
is zero
then you got an issue.
If the remainder is zero then so if it's
not zero then the result is the previous
zero count
plus um
plus the quotient. Okay, if the
remainder is not zero,
but if the remainder is zero, that means
the current uh number is zero, then you
need to
then you need to um
add one because the current number is
zero. But also you cannot
let's see the quotient. Okay. So let's
see
the quotient.
So quotient. So 100 divided by 100 is
one.
Okay. So if the current number is five,
you turn 100 clicks.
You pass zero. Now if the current number
is zero
you turn 100
um clicks
you do not pass zero. Okay. So there are
many ways there are several ways to
compute this. One way is to check if the
previous number is zero
or alternatively you just check the
current number is zero. So the if the
current number is zero then you want the
quotient to be minus one
absolute quotient then minus one. Okay.
So basically what you want is is this
this okay
quotient minus one then plus one then it
doesn't make sense. It does wait
-1 + one they cancel out
then the whole thing is zero that that
that doesn't make sense.
So wait, so if the current number is
zero and you if you turn 100 clicks,
so how does that how what is supposed to
be?
The current number is zero. Um if you do
100 clicks then
what is like the supposed
uh
answer?
Well the suppose answer is that you you
count it if it pass zero. So from zero
to zero you do not pass zero.
Oh god.
What? What if the previous zero is not
zero and the current number is zero? So
if the current number is zero,
there's two conditions,
two situations for previous number. The
previous number can be zero or not zero.
Okay. So if it is not zero, let's say,
oh god.
Uh
Let me think. I'll just have to think
about this. Okay.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> So when you do the clicks whenever it's
it counts
except
when the current number is zero.
So yes. Okay. So the special case is
when the current number is zero then
yeah the special case is when the
current number is zero that's really
just a problem. The current number is
zero then
Okay. So you need to this will depend on
the current number. So
you see the current number and the new
current number the remainder is related.
You look close.
I saw that in a similar way. Fantastic
user. What language did you use?
So yeah, I'm pretty close. This
something with the you know either
current number or previous number or the
I mean the zero. Okay. So I just need to
do clear thinking about this. Um,
so if the current number is zero,
rack it. Nice.
Okay. If the current number is zero, um,
Okay.
Yeah, this should always um
Can I be just logical? Come on.
So if the remainder is zero, you return
you add one, right?
But if the remainders is zero
the quotient is needs to minus one
not necessarily
because
okay the special case is when current
number is zero and the remainder is
zero.
So you got multiple conditions
when the current number is zero
and
the remainder is zero
then
it should be quotient minus one. Okay,
let me write this up.
Something like let's write it up here.
Okay.
uh minus one.
No, you can't even minus one. Only you
want to minus only if the quotient is
greater than one.
What a complicated
So when the current when the current
number is zero and then the new current
number is also zero. So what you do you
you take the the number of quotient.
Okay the quotient. So you could So
um
min - 10 max
something like that complicated
That's right.
So this if expression is getting
up.
So it's getting um
so let's do if the remainder
so if
then another if statement. Okay.
If the current number is zero,
then
okay. So I can I think I I think I know
what to do.
Something like that. Okay,
previous zero count plus if remainder is
zero. That's special case you need to
watch out. If remainder is not zero,
then you simply
add the quotients.
That's that would be the number of times
it passes zero. Okay. But now if the
previous number the current number is
also zero then you need to
minus one the quotient if it's positive.
So you could say
so if the quotient is one it should be
zero. If the quotient is two it should
be one.
If the quotient is zero then it's still
zero. Okay. So you take the max quotient
negative one uh or zero. Okay.
Okay. Something like that. And let's
let's just test
max1
and zero returns zero. That's right.
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay. So if the current number is zero
then you do that otherwise just one.
Okay. Otherwise
so if the previous number that you know
the the current number is is not zero
but the current remainder is zero then
you just say add one.
Okay. Does that No. Does that
Does that
Does this make sense? This should be it.
Okay.
Now, Wen language is hard to read here.
Okay. So
this section is the heart.
Double check one last time. If the
remainder is zero
then do this. If it is not then just add
a quotient uh absolute value. Very
simple. But if the remainder is zero
then you check the current number is
zero.
If it is then you
uh take the max of the absolute value of
the quotient
minus one. Okay. But if the current
number is not zero then you simply add
one because the remainder is zero. Okay.
I think that's it. It's just
trial and error our way through blast
our way by trial and error.
Okay.
So, so initial state input numbers clear
the definition of the function define
the inline documentation of the function
because we are perfect. We document
everything.
Something like that. Where? Where?
Where? So this should be new zero count.
Okay.
Okay. Then uh
Okay. Documentation. Perfect. Then here
is the actual definition of this
function rotate to rotate it returns it
returns this new zero count and current
number. Okay. Uh and this this this
logic that is the logic and this is our
uh code we can just remove and just fold
and be back in five minutes. Done.
Now go to Wuam language.
Am I correct?
He's struggling. You use user ly. Am I
correct? Spoiler alert.
[laughter]
Pasted the code. There it is. There it
is. Now shift enter. Shift enter.
Please. My god. Please. Eight.
Incorrect.
>> [laughter]
>> Eight is incorrect. Oh Jesus. Jesus.
I'm struggling. Did you solve the
problem? Did you solve the problem?
What? What is What is wrong here? Jesus,
what what is wrong?
Why can't you just solve the problem?
Where did it go wrong? Rotate in state
input. No, but you
No, but you also close.
So, you did not solve the problem.
Okay. So, yeah, very close for sure. But
this is becoming idiotic. It's easy to
solve brute force it, but your more
elegant way is a lot harder. It took me
hours to solve it. Oh, really? This is
like day one number two. It should be
easy problem. It should be you know you
know annoying uh you know the annoying
advent of code problem actually like
usually each problem takes few hours.
Um but they are like speed coders. They
finish it in few seconds in 10 seconds.
Hello Fay. I don't know who you are.
Long time no see. Okay. I don't know
what uh so what so what so let's you
know something wrong here let's just
think about again
if the current number is zero if
remainder is zero if the current number
is zero then
then
I don't know why. Why? What's wrong with
it? What the is going on?
What the
You know. So,
so now the next step is to you just need
to think about this. Okay, I need to
think about this like calm down and
think about this. That's one way.
The other way is simply start to add
debugging code. So in this function, we
print each step what are the inputs.
Then we can visually see each step, you
know, where did things go wrong.
Um,
you know that GPS, I don't know why it's
showing us a name now. Okay, that's a
bad coding. I'm doing good.
G Oh, GPS. Oh, okay. GPS. Well, I don't
even remember GPS. Not exactly.
So anyway, so this code is wrong.
It's supposed to be six.
And uh why are we, you know, so
590?
Uh did we miss some special case?
If the current number is equals to zero.
Oh, so I think this is not just minus
one. This should be absolutely zero.
That's right.
Wait.
If the current zero,
if the current number is zero and if you
do 200 ticks,
how many would that count? Two, right?
Okay. I think this zero. I think that's
it. Okay. I think that's it. Select all.
Paste. Oh, five. Now it's one less
max absolute value. So,
so if you have 200
clicks
and current zero is one. So you so you
pass
you Yeah. So you passed it.
You passed it one time
but also it ends on zero. So what what
is the situation? You you pass it one
time but also ends on zero. Return to
day one.
Uh
zero.
You see none none of these give a
situation when the turn is exactly
multiple of 100.
So you got several cases where it ends
at zero. The current number is zero. But
but there's no instance where you rotate
100 or 200 or 300 clicks.
So but suppose the current number is is
at zero.
Okay, you count it from you know you
count that as
as a occurrence.
Now you do rotate 200 clicks
to the right. Let's suppose
so 200 clicks
you will end up on zero again. Okay. But
meanwhile, did you pass zero?
Yes, you pass it once.
However, the quotient of 200 is two.
That's why
now is this minus one correct?
So if you the click is 300.
[sighs]
So you end up on zero but you also pass
zero one time. So what but so what is
the uh what are you supposed to do with
that situation? The number of times the
dial is left pointing at zero.
Wait, that's problem one. Uh the problem
one, the password method 0x something.
Remember from the training seminar means
you are actually supposed to count the
number of times
any click causes the dial to point at
zero.
Okay,
regardless of whether it happens during
a rotation or at end of one.
So if you start at zero and you if you
do 200 clicks
now the proper answer should be
two.
That's right.
So I think you know our model of the
problem could be made use a different
model that fits this better. Right now
we are doing but it's still modular
arithmetics
but there's something wrong here. Okay.
So again,
if the beginning number is zero, you
turn 200 clicks,
it ends up as zero again. But meanwhile,
it passed zero once.
So in this rotation then you would add
two counts, two occurrence. Okay?
So did we catch that situation? So this
quotient
is two 2 minus one
that's correct.
200 by divided by 100 the quotient is
two. 2 minus one
is one. Okay. That's not that's not
correct.
There's a caution we always add.
I think our model is like is it
completely wrong this absolute quotient?
Oh, our model is completely wrong.
it.
Because it's not
absolute quotient. It's Our model is
incorrect because this is quotient
because for example
for example this simple example current
number is five. You turn left
one two three four five six times
and you will get one.
Oh, we missing uh we wait did we? Yeah,
we missing something here. Question
remember current number plus rotate n
plus 100.
Okay, something like that. But hold on a
second.
You see if you have five then you rotate
one, two, three, four, five, six, six
times left.
minus 6 you get 99.
However, you do you did pass zero. So
result is 199.
Okay. And uh according to our uh
previous test did we did we test that
case? We did
open it.
[sighs]
You see five and you rotate left six
times, you get one
um passing zero.
And how did that
So this is 5 / -6.
So the negative passed onto the
rotation.
That is incorrect
because if you do this this way,
anytime you have a negative, you're
going to you're going to incur.
So let's test that. Okay. Our model is
just wrong. Okay. No,
your model is completely wrong. You
idiot.
Okay. So, for example,
if you five and uh turn left four times.
Okay. So, you have five
So, you got five. Let's open this.
Yeah.
So, you got five. Then you turn it to
the left four times. One, two, three,
four. You arrive at one. Did you pass
zero? No.
So this if you run it
uh what
run it.
Oh undefined. Well okay you need to run
the whole thing.
So you run it. You got that which is
correct actually.
So our model is here is correct.
No, it's not correct because
God.
[cough and clears throat]
Okay.
Current number.
Current number and rotate end.
So rotate right plus rotate left. So
when does it pass zero? So
This is not right.
50.
So if it's 50
now there is a problem.
50 50.
Yeah, this is not good.
Wait.
So if you are at 50,
you rotate right 50.
Pretty [cough and clears throat]
And [clears throat]
yeah, so
this
may not be right.
[snorts]
So current number
it's passing zero. So
zero
goes to increase to the left.
So rotate right means
plus rotate left means negative.
Okay. So whenever you have a number
can the number be negative? Not really.
So whenever you have a number
[clears throat]
to 99
rotate Right. Means uh
rotate right
means
what
the number increases to the right.
Rotate rise means minus
Did we get minus and plus sign wrong?
Rotate.
We got minus and first sign wrong from
the input.
Oh god.
The input
minus plus sign is incorrect. Okay. So
let's what what are we dealing with? You
know the right left is got wrong.
That's why. Okay.
Let's just do it one more time. Okay. So
show in browser.
So this let's so what is this one? Day
one problem two. That's today.
Voice check, video check. Okay, so we
got the input may be incorrect.
Search for initial state.
Okay, so
wait. So let's see this one.
Okay, don't deal. Don't ruin that one.
and this one.
Okay, that's the model.
Then next. So this one
the input we got the sign reversed maybe
let's check L L R
now L actually means positive
okay so we got we got it the sign
incorrect
what the
so L is actually positive.
Now let's check yesterday's code.
Yesterday's code uh did we do it
correctly?
L Oh, yesterday we just do rotate left.
Okay, it's simple. But now we doing
modular arithmetics. So the we got the
input wrong. How can it possibly be?
So um so let's get the input again.
Is that the input?
Yesterday
we have
yesterday here is the input. Okay. So
so the input okay let's do it here. So
the input L is actually positive. First
of all, remove the quote.
Okay. Now L is positive. So capital L
remove by nothing. Now R become
negative.
Okay. So that is bad input. Now that is
correct input.
Now if we
is our logic still correct?
Not sure. So let's copy it.
Let's just run it.
So wra language here. Select paste.
Shift enter.
Uh you got a uh syntax error quotient.
Okay. You got the syntax
here. Okay.
Copy your select or paste. Shift enter.
Four.
Okay. Something is wrong
now. Uh,
how incredible. We got the input
incorrect sign reversed.
Very painful. Okay,
let's let's make sure
rotate left.
Wait, rotate left actually means
rate wait rotate left means decrease.
Oh god,
what what am I thinking?
L rotate left.
Rotate left means decrease. That is
correct.
What am I thinking?
I subtract it on the right. Okay. I
subtract on left, add it on right. Yeah.
So
you are correct. But I I think right now
I just
uh I'm totally
screwed here. It's like
[laughter]
um
so left is negative
left. So what why is our code incorrect?
So
Oh, this is not this should be
cautioned. idiot.
That's right.
Why is this not um
This is not six.
Mhm.
There. Okay. Found it.
No, this should be one.
Yeah, stupid.
Okay. Copy all
paste.
No, it's eight.
What the heck?
Zero
zero
zero.
99.
You know the logic is wrong somewhere
somewhere. So
wait.
So five then the current number is zero.
So the current number is zero. Then
then it adds
996.
So between these two why it did become
Mhm.
Okay.
previous zero count plus if remainder is
zero.
So if the remainder is zero
stupid. [clears throat]
Shouldn't
you have one here?
I think so.
Okay, maybe this this time face God
please
[laughter] no
I become 12
it has to move 100
that's why I got eight you probably
counting zero because starting at zero
>> [laughter]
>> Mhm. Mhm.
This is annoying name. Let's change it.
Okay.
Good thing.
Okay. [clears throat]
Mhm.
Trial and error. Copy or paste it.
Evaluated
six. Correct answer. You see correct.
Correct. Now let's try our um custom
code.
Okay.
Now this long list of code.
Now we just need to get our code.
Okay. This long list of code. Let's see.
Coffee.
Okay. here.
Here and uh here is our new code.
Okay, it's delete the old code. Delete.
Okay, the new code the init state
input delete init state move to the top
same
init state custom input. Now custom
input is 20. 20 is right. R20 R10. Okay,
let's check. R 20, R10. That's right.
Right is positive, left is negative.
Okay, so that and uh new code.
Copy.
Go here. Select all. Paste it.
Okay.
6580.
That's the same number I used before and
it says it's incorrect.
Let's try again. Face 6580. Submit.
That's not the right answer.
Okay.
So, uh,
now we need to exam our existence.
I don't know. I think maybe I'll stop.
Let's
just say
we failed today
uh and we're going to do tomorrow.
And uh this is not good because
this simple problem
shouldn't take that long.
Uh I am very annoyed.
this simple problem
very annoyed. So we really need to think
about
this rotation business.
I think
our model here is even incorrect.
Um
this
part
may not be right
because over here we are kind of relying
on negative numbers to get the
quotients.
I think it might be incorrect.
I don't know.
But over here
R 20. Did we
Did we get the R and L correct? The
input must be
okay.
So, here's what we do. Okay.
We're going to continue this maybe until
it's done. Okay. Okay.
It's like code or die. I'm going to
complete this.
Okay. and be back in 10 minutes.
I'm back, guys.
Problem. Now, let's have some
recola.
Can you see this is candy recolola?
Can you see recolan? This is a throat
candy so I don't cough so much.
Uk keyboard. Fantastic.
You made me a great programmer.
Back to code.
Now this you know we just have to
carefully go through this. Okay.
So um
is interesting you're still watching.
Wow.
Said um
said said
said,
"Who is the guy who asked me what
language I'm using? Is that you?
[clears throat]
Who is it asked me what programming
language I'm using?
Did he delete the comments?
Oh, what the hell is the language Jose
or says?
Okay.
So the problem
so let's go back to our uh
drawing board.
Okay.
Um
so this operation let's check this part.
What?
Okay.
Does this always work correctly?
Change left
way.
So,
rotate
left -4.
Oh god, we got the sign wrong again.
What the is with the sign?
So if negative means rotate left
wait right left okay
four one two three four that result is
one so okay
so if you rotate Right.
Five.
One, two,
one, two, three, four, five. Is 10. It's
correct.
Rotate left negative.
Rotate left five. One, two, three, four,
five.
Means zero.
Okay, let's deal with negative first.
So, let's move the positive down.
Okay. One, two,
four, five, six.
What if you have rotate left 99?
Okay. 0 0
0 0
199.
Then
this is
-1
6.
So
obtain depth.
So five rotate left four.
You got one.
Rotate left five. You got zero.
Rotate left six. You got 99.
Now rotate left 100, you got five again.
Now, but rotate left 99.
You got six. That's correct.
So the rotate left and uh
so rotate rotate left 99
you pass zero. Okay. One time. So once
you go beyond five
you got you pass zero.
So you got one there, one there
should be correct.
Now rotate left
101 66 should be right. Okay,
this operation this function should be
correct.
Is it correct?
Make sure one more time
because this is fundamental.
Okay.
Uh, I'm probably doing So, I don't
know if you guys want to continue to
watch.
So, now right now I'm not in my best
mind.
So, anyway,
so this function is it correct?
Operation X operation
current number rotate n returns a list
DC.
So we can improve the documentation.
Um yeah let's let's not
okay
D is a new index number. Okay.
Is this operation correct? Can we be
certain?
Looks like
now what if you say rotate zero?
Will it do anything wrong?
Oh, you need to evaluate the whole
thing.
Okay,
rotate zero means it didn't pass zero
zero times.
And uh the result is C5. So that's also
correct. Is this operation reliable? Are
you sure? Yes.
Current number plus rotate end.
Yes.
And current number is always a positive
number.
Is that right? Yes.
So
this number
this algorithm this function
let's say it is 100% correct we can
trust trust it okay this operation
now
but now we back to our problem why is
our problem
why can't we solve this
L68
L30
6830.
Then
um
L
is negative, right?
L is negative. Okay.
R is positive.
That's right. Because the number is goes
counterclockwise.
Okay.
Wait. Are you sure?
Because uh it shows some examples uh
previously.
Where is it?
Yeah, you kind of show the example.
Okay.
So,
so we can remove this input.
L is negative.
L is negative. R is positive. Okay.
Right. Now,
so now we come now we back to this uh
this this
problem.
Why is our code incorrect? Okay, first
of all, the number of times it pass zero
is given
in this question.
Wait, hold on.
Wait. The number of times it pass zero.
Did we cover that before?
So, oh we didn't wait hold on a second.
So, hold on. Before we do this, let's
revisit this previous.
What if you begin with zero? That is the
problem. And you rotate let's say five
times. Run it.
Okay. That means you
you arrive at the number five and no
pass.
Okay. But now you begin at zero and you
rotate 100 times.
100 clicks. Do it.
[cough]
There lies the problem. It tell it says
you pass it one time.
So
when the current number is zero,
there's a special case.
Wait, the current number is zero, you
rotate 100 times. God,
let's try negative. Would it also give
something? It'll just be negative one.
Yeah.
Okay. And uh let's say if it's 101. What
if it's 101?
it.
What?
[cough]
05 1 0 and one one. That's right. That's
the result.
Okay.
The but the problem is here. So if it's
zero, it begin with at zero. You rotate
it one 100 clicks.
It returns one. However,
you did not pass zero.
You merely stop at zero.
So, this is a bit tricky. Okay.
Okay. So, yeah. So when it's 100,
when it's zero and you do 100 clicks
Z 0 will work for sure. We'll just
return zero.
You see
because you are just doing the
remainder.
Okay. The tricky the tricky part is
this. Okay. Because this
indicates the documentation is
incorrect. Because if you begin at zero
and you do 100 clicks rotation,
did it pass zero?
Not really. But it begin at zero and
stop at zero. But however, it returned,
you know, one.
So, so the tricky part is is the meaning
of passing zero and stopping Z at zero.
Is there a way to reconciliate them so
that the algorithm becomes a simple very
simple?
If you look at this example
starting at zero and 100 clicks
that means start at zero and after 100
clicks it ends at zero. So even though
it doesn't pass zero but however it ends
at zero. So by the requirement of the
problem the result is still one because
either pass or ends at.
So you might say
this operation is simplified nothing
special but however it doesn't work when
um
when you have this case for example
starting at at five and move to the left
five clicks.
So in this example
you didn't pass zero and you end at zero
but however it should the result should
be one because you ended at zero.
So there is two uh cases in uh kind of
in different uh in you know
[cough]
uh and both of them are basically
related to either beginning as zero
and end at zero. So uh or um
this end at zero. So another in another
way we could say this is simply wrong
because it didn't it didn't pass zero it
just ends at zero. Okay.
So we can add a special case here when
if the current number is
zero and end at zero.
We must minus one
when when the current number is zero
and end at zero.
Then
we must minus one to mean the number of
time it pass zero. But at the end we
have to add one again because it ends at
zero. Okay.
So this function is actually technically
incorrect.
The number C returned is not the number
of times when it passed zero.
It is wrong in a case when you begin at
zero and uh also end at zero. But if you
begin at zero and uh but you don't end
at zero then it's still correct. So
let's see you begin at zero and not end
at zero. Is there any case like that?
Yeah. So anyway so this this function is
technically incorrect. It is incorrect
when
you begin at zero
and when you end also at zero.
In that case you need to
subtract one from the first element.
Okay, that's the current analysis.
So this is technically wrong. Let's
write it out. Okay, for the since since
we already spent like 2 hours, 3 hours
on this, this function is incorrect
when
current number is zero
and
the result
is uh the result second part and let's
say the result index number is also
zero.
In this case,
the returned
value
first part
should
minus one something like that. Okay.
Something like that. Okay. Now put it
back.
I'll go to the next.
Okay. Now next
now
so we are computing D.
It's all correct. Like normally you
would say
normally
the result would be
previous count
plus
uh
previous count plus if the remainder is
equals to zero add one.
else
zero. Okay, that is if this it stops at
zero add one else don't add.
Okay,
normally that should be the result. But
we do know uh this this operation is
incorrect when it begin at zero end end
at zero. So,
so what we have so we have the we have
logic to counter that.
So when the remainder is equals to zero.
Okay. If the remainder is not equals to
zero then just um
wait what are we doing? Wait. Previous
count plus
absolute. Okay. plus wait
plus absolute quotient plus. So this is
the normal.
This is the normal result.
previous zero count plus first plus the
absolute of the quotient first the
remainder is is if it's zero add one
okay this is the number of zero count or
ended at zero
and then rem remainder
the current number okay now but because
this quotient operation is incorrect
when the number is at zero and also end
at zero. So we need to like
do a correction.
So if the remainder is zero
if it's not
then whatever the absolute quotient if
the remainder is is zero and also the
previous number is zero then the
absolute value quotient needs to minus
One.
Did we get the max wrongs?
Absolute quotient
minus one.
absolute value of the quotient.
Did we get this part right? The the more
logical way to say this is if
if that absolute value of quotient is
greater than zero
then
greater than zero then
at minus one.
Okay. Otherwise
otherwise just zero. So
otherwise just absolute value of the
quotient. Okay.
Because it's not greater than zero. So
it's either equal to absolute always is
it's zero or greater than zero
when you have absolute value right so
it's so do you know do you guys know
what I'm saying
guess not
so absolute quotient if it's greater
than zero then then minus one
okay but I think it this should be
equivalent to that
maximum of between that minus one. So,
so let's say if the quotient is one, one
is greater than zero, true,
then quotient minus one, it becomes
zero.
Okay. So one one zero one with one it's
zero. If it's two it should be one. If
it's three it should be two. So it
should be whatever it's you know it
should be uh zero or the minus one
that's correct. So I don't I think
that's correct.
further wise absolute value quotients.
So the only situation you want to minus
one is both the remainder and previous
number are zero.
Now what if the remainder and previous
number are the same? Oh, that's another
situation.
Bin. Yes.
Let's say
did we
let's say this case
the new number is five. The previous
number is five.
Okay. If you turn it multiple times,
600.
One.
So, one
2 3 4
6 that should be correct.
Now I don't understand why is my
algorithm incorrect though.
Fold initial state input.
Okay.
should press one though.
What?
What am I doing?
What should I doing?
[laughter]
special case only happens is is zero.
Okay.
Special case only happens when it's um
zero. I thought we documented.
Refresh.
What?
No, we didn't. What?
Let's put it back.
This function is incorrect when number
is current number is zero and the result
index is also zero. Okay,
it's only incorrect when
current number is zero and result is
also zero. So,
so now if we go here
one
That looks correct.
Okay.
[clears throat]
See,
this looks correct, but um
I'm going crazy.
And see, I'm going crazy over here.
Can it be this? No.
Let's try uh equal
Yeah. No.
Uh
just incorrect. Okay. Something is
incorrect.
So 6.
Say 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 11
rotational operations.
One 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10.
Right? So 10 operations beginning with
the initial condition. Okay. So you can
kind of see
one, two, three, four. So one, two,
three on the third operation. Can we can
edit it? One, two, three. Third
operation 48.
So 1 2 3
on the third operation 48 + 48 you got
zero.
So on the third operation
initial 50
one two three third operation of R48 you
got you arrive at zero.
That's right.
uh by then
but by then you already rotate it how
many times let's see the dial okay so
the initial condition
so there's one this first operation
first operation one are
L68 arrive at 82
L6 arrive 82 one rotation passing zero.
Correct.
Then second operation L30 arrive at 52.
Okay. Still one time occurrence.
Then the third operation dial is rotated
R 48 and arriving at point Z.
So the third operation of 48 this one
here
arriving at zero and all of a sudden we
got three.
So that's up.
L30 are 48.
So 52 + 48.
So hold on a second. So we got 52
and 48.
So what is going on? So,
so can we still call our function? Yes.
Let's open a new one.
Okay.
And start to massive. So, so we we have
uh
previously 52
then 48. Okay.
Um
52 then + 48.
Okay. So at 52 then you rotate right 48
you arrive at zero again.
And did you pass zero?
Yes. But somehow you got three here. So
there is something uh something in our
logic here is incorrect.
So something in our logic here.
So if [snorts] the remainder is zero
previous come has come. Come.
Okay. So let's just not add that.
New paste. Run it. Now this one is
correct. Okay.
Let's copy that. Paste the intermediate
result and let's magnify.
Okay. So now
now this answer is correct
for the toy example input.
Okay. So that's initial 050
then
then after three operations
it's uh
after the 48 you get zero. So,
so you get a zero and at that point you
have two times
either passing zero or end at zero. Is
that right? So one time
two time that's right.
So L5
95.
So that's
uh
alpha 2. 95.
So this is incorrect.
Five.
95. Why is it increase to three?
So our algorithm is like
what?
Which one are we looking at?
Close this one. Okay.
it's not three.
So from this two zero it becomes three.
So 0
0 - 5
0 - 5 which is
minus
>> [snorts]
>> minus 5 is rotate left.
Rotate left. So you got
95.
Okay.
Zero. Rotate.
Rotate
left five. You got 95.
So, but why do you get three here?
The remainder is not zero.
in the caution the previous count. So
why do you get that? Did we
go
need need to print something? Okay,
this is print debug. Starting to print
debug.
Just print the out of it.
Let's
print one bunch of
numbers
so that we may better debug it. You know
there's no way because computer don't
make mistake unless my CPU is doing some
magic trick of bits
otherwise something I did wrong.
Okay. So now it's like better you just
you just need to okay
copy
and let's do the full list. So we are
starting to do heavy debugging this this
I don't know what the is going on
previous count is zero previous number
uh previous zero count zero 50 so
between
so the the the the problem occurs when
My god, every time this runs, this got
the long things.
Can we actually make this long line
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah.
The problem is this.
this increase. Okay. So the problem is
here.
This is initial step.
First step, second step, third
operation.
Then the fourth operation that first
number is incorrect. We want to know
why.
Okay. So we have the steps here.
Previous occur is zero number. Previous
number is 50. 050. Okay. Then 182.
Then 182. Uh wait the quotient. Okay.
Uh 50. Then the result is 182. Okay.
Then 152
here. Okay. Then two zero. Okay.
Previous zero count is two. Previous
number is zero. Okay. Now be careful.
Now how did it become three?
Now previous quotient x quotient is -1.
So x remainder
is 95.
So two 0
and two 0 and 395.
Wait,
what?
L295.
Yeah, it Where does the 395 come from?
Where does a three come from? So before
the count is two
and previous number is zero.
Then
then you do the step
two. Okay. Two zero. So the fourth step
is
L5.
So 0 L5 minus 5 is
95.
[sighs]
Okay.
There's a problem. There is a problem.
starting at zero, you don't end with
zero, but you still have a problem
because when it's zero, so we found a
bug finally when it's zero initial
condition
and you move -5.
Okay. So that's why I think our um our
thing here is incorrect
thing where
this operation this operation got two
problems.
Okay. So next stop is to fix this
operation. Okay.
So next stop is to fix this operation.
We kind of found the problem.
Kind of very annoying.
Okay, hold on a second. So, let's clean
up this um thing.
I think I got to go pretty soon.
It's not
Hello guys, I'm back.
This is not going well. This is like 3
hours or was it 4 hours already? So, let
me turn on my camera. I got to go.
My wife coming back soon.
Um, well, a long stream. Just got back
from gym and had dinner. Fantastic.
A Vindra.
So, long session we got we got stuck in
a bug and uh
I have found the bug.
I think I got to go.
Yeah, my wife is back. Hold on a second.
I think I'm going to go.
Terrible,
terrible session. So I got to go and we
found a bug. The bug [clears throat] is
presumptuous
presumptuousness.
Uh because we found a bug is this
operation is incorrect on two accounts.
An hour ago, we identified one of the
problem. But now we know another
problem.
So this this is just too fast coding,
you know, kind of too fast coding.
That's why we didn't think through the
uh that's why there's a bug. Um and
and I can continue, but
yeah, but it's probably not good. So,
um, let me just do another video then
continue this next time. Okay, bye guys.
Thank you guys for hanging around.
Yeah, I I'll get it soon. I hope for
certain.
Bye, guys.