foreign
I'm going to show you
the most efficient way to input
math symbols or emoji such as for
example let's look at this keyboard okay
you see this is the least machine
keyboard you see all those symbols there
those mathematics fantastic you see all
these those symbols and you have Greeks
and today you know I'm gonna show you
how do you make your keyboard to insert
those and not just math symbols you see
these are actually APL symbols you see
the inverted a infinity symbol the
Reversed e
the you know differential partial
differential operator
and the Double Arrow red arrow so those
are APL programming language symbols and
you see the approximately equal to and
you have thumb up and thumb down this
keyboard is actually dated 1980 1983 or
something okay so it's amazing
uh and let me show you another keyboard
okay so uh so now you have emoji
keyboard now this is mod you know today
the Zoomers in the millennial generation
they need to have emojis look at that
emojis you know so this one is no longer
on sale this one 2015 this one but this
one is uh apparently you can you know
you know you have some keys to insert
Emoji okay so I'm gonna today I'm gonna
talk all about it about the keyboard
about Unicode cmoji or maths symbols and
the several methods to insert them for
example there's that key
so let me show you so for example there
is that key let me just open it okay
math symbols a brief by Lee smart and
old graph for example let's just open
them all okay
so you can see there is so these are
Unicode so you know if you want to
insert emoji and all the food uh Emoji
characters okay
and here is mathematics amazing
fantastic mathematics you see oh you
have all these symbols
uh
math okay
and then you have
this is a keyboard from 1980s some
Microsystems this one some Microsystems
type 6 keyboard you can see there's old
graph key a physical hold graph key and
you have the compose key
you know what are they they allow you to
insert characters access accented
characters such as you know acute e or
the copyright symbol things like that
then you have the Mac which is modern
let me show you uh but anyway so the
point is you have old graph key and you
have compose key this is a tech vt2000
terminal okay so let me show you this
this is 1970s let's see
uh 1983 so you have this keyboard
1883 you know those screens are 40
characters 80 characters by 40
characters that's how small they are
today's tiny
so anyway so on this keyboard you have
the compose key okay so go back so you
can see compose characters so that allow
that's a different way to let you insert
acute e or Copyright symbol you know
different ways so you have old graph you
have compose uh then you have the that
key now that key is a another uh
interesting thing so the difference is
that is that the way you you press them
is different so for example the old
graph what you do is the old graph is
just like modifier like Ctrl alt so you
hold it down first then you press
another another key you know you hold
old graph down then you press e then you
release them both then you get the acute
e so that's the old graph you know it's
a modifier a combination a keyboard key
code
on the other hand the compose key the
way you operate it is that you press con
compose then release it
then you press the tick you know the
apostrophe then you press e then you get
the acute e
so this compose key it's a key sequence
instead of key code okay and then then
you have the that key which appears if
you go to friends you know if you buy a
ticket go you know fly to friends and
buy a keyboard there then you have the
dead key and some other countries
Iceland and you know Europe
so that key that key is just like
compose okay so it's a key sequence it's
just like compose you press press a key
release it and press several key in turn
okay but however it only uh focus on
certain uh characters for example you
cannot use it to insert copyright sign
but it's only for you know the umlot or
the Hat you know certain uh Keys like
that that there
so anyway so these are three different
ways you know uh historically three
different ways to let you insert but
anyway I'm going to show you today from
the ground up
they are more than these ways okay from
the ground up how do you insert these
characters now let's see the next one
okay so here is Martin again hello guys
good morning immortality
so here is a modern Mac on the Macbook
so you have the option key now so what
option key is essentially it's
equivalent to the old graph key it's a
key combination so you have to hold
press and hold option then you got this
then you can press several different
keys to insert symbols then you can also
uh press this to add a cute you know
accents to letters to letters okay so
that's Mac that's modern
okay and let's see next one and then so
here you are looking at the APL keyboard
layout okay so you see these symbols so
let me show you okay let's go to APL
symbols and let's go to
um some more keyboard let's let's just
show some more keyboard okay so this is
uh APL is a programming language it's a
mathemat for mathematics for computing
matrices just like Wolfram language and
Julia these are different languages in
these languages index array index start
with one that's what mathematicians do
for programmers already index start with
Israel at zero that's idiotic okay
so anyway so
so this page tells you the different
ways how you can create a diff uh your
own keyboard layout if you need these
symbols uh often and you can make them
Emoji you know for example so that's why
it's useful API is kind of dead not very
popular APR stands for a programming
language from 1960s or 1970s okay APL
programming language now let's look at
so here is the Unicode for all the APL
symbols and this keyboard you are
looking at is the Grand Daddy of APL
keyboard IBM 2741 APL keyboard
okay and uh oh I don't have a link I
should have a link to the actual machine
but anyway so this is the APL and let's
look at next and this one is from Russia
I think wait
uh MCM model 70 micro computer
1972 so you can see it's also got APL
symbols uh
from Canada okay not from Russia but
there's a
Russian also have something similar I
think I forgot but anyway so these are
you know different keyboards and
interesting things about them
so now you can see here is a code so I'm
gonna start to show you okay so let's go
back let's let's let's see so any
questions comments posts in a chat okay
so let's start to demo okay so I showed
a bunch of keyboard let's start to demo
so let's see
ammo I just type ammo it's magnify and
Bam you see I got all these emojis so if
I want the emoji for let's do a new one
okay
yeah let's do a new one let's see I want
a Emoji for pizza my favorite food
you know I don't have it set up so let's
do it let's start emacs from scratch
first of all turn on Powershell now
emacs is a special editor Okay so
if you know it you know what I'm talking
about if you don't know uh well you can
do it in Word Microsoft Word I'm gonna
show you later okay so Powershell
and what we're gonna do and the e-max so
let's see where is emacs
so wait I need to magnify so you can see
uh let's let's magnify okay so emags so
yeah so let's start emacs e-max
here Max Dash q that means no you need
file so this is playing glue emacs
okay so you can see I need to magnify
okay now I'm going to
this is playing emacs so there's no
setup so I cannot I don't have the Emoji
set up I'm gonna show you how to do it
okay right now so first of all let's go
to load stuff like keys because I need
um my key binding okay
so
get
XA
fly
Keys enter
so let's just load okay so magnify
outload it yes
okay now I have it uh wait
yeah oh yeah I need to specify uh
okay open it
yeah too small
okay this is not good this is taking too
much time but hold on a second let me uh
get to it
so because I need full rack oh God how
do I type for rack
old space
control space
what
so I want to yeah so right now I want to
create an emacs create a keystroke and
also a brief system to insert the Pisa
okay that's what we are doing but right
now I'm stuck with this
um
so I'm using okay let's let's go to
quote hidden
all right
what what layout am I in U.S quality
okay
no that's not courty yeah
let's go to Warwick yeah
that's not good okay so net oh God
Microsoft okay let's close that
do I want to save no let's start over
okay
It's Not Over
now go to
control oh yeah so I need to switch to
war rack wait wait okay yeah this
keyboard This is exposed keyboard it's
already
um
War rank so yeah that's why I made a
mistake before so now I open my file
in it
uh Dot emags
okay go there and
open the unit file
magnify
yeah let's let's set the
set default fonts okay let's make them
large
okay for now
so now uh wait
control that
okay so now
that is undo yeah so now let's open this
file
and
uh so let's see what I do what should I
do so
this is not good this taking too long
too much time to do this okay so let's
open the
so this is a French Emax nothing has
been set up uh and what am I doing so I
want to open some fly Keys okay let's
let's do this okay
so go to git
sa fly
okay go open that and uh
and
open it
okay and search for
set
okay that's the part I want then change
this to wall rack
okay now about the buffer
about above a Ctrl x e
no not Ctrl x e uh let's
meta X
okay let's copy copy this line
Ctrl W is for copy wait Ctrl W is cut
but now let's go to diode
oh my god without software Keys
everything is so painful let's
let's eval buffer okay so alt X
eval
buffer okay now this file is loaded now
I just go here and the Ctrl x e
and it's
it's missing cannot load file no search
file directory what
oh yeah because it's not set up
um
dad
so get out of that
so what I want to do now so
yeah okay okay I think I no no let's
switch to
it's War rack so I cannot do this
yeah I cannot
I cannot change the keys properly
all right
kill buffer
yes do I want to kill modified do I want
to kill anyway yes okay
I remember a time when the only found
images were called dingbats now they are
mostly forgotten that's true but team
bats remain in Unicode then bats rename
for example they become
you know they
you know they are part of the Unicode
they become being in many places for
example some of these characters are
originally dimpad and also
uh some of these keyboard characters and
also some of the shapes characters and
so on okay so now I I want to do this
so I want to make emacs to be able to
set up
but the problem is right now I don't
have
I want to show you how to start from
scratch in emacs to set up keys to
insert emoji and right now I'm failing
that because
I'm unable to
[Music]
set up stuff like keys so
well because the reason is because
this keyboard is physical vorac you know
there's a lot confusing confusion the
reason is basically because I'm unable
to set the mod to work for software keys
so if we so failing that what we can do
is
just go with plain emacs okay so let's
create emacs
okay go with plain emacs but that would
be fairly painful
uh
okay so how do you do it how do you do
it okay so let me show you okay so
actually
uh so go to
go to
uh so go to today's talk show
in browser and you go to
this page a free mod by emac Visa code
so let me show you so you just copy this
thing
copy it so this page is a remarked by
emac this code you can search and find
it so now we go back to emacs now let's
open a new file
name doesn't matter and now paste it
Ctrl Y is paste there it is and now
increase the font so you can
I also have sticky keysong so it's
fairly confusing so now here is the emac
this code now you want to set this file
save this okay so save this Ctrl x s
save as let's say XXX dot e l okay
do it okay
this magnifier again so now you want to
load the file so load the file so what
you can do is you
Ctrl X Meta altx Meta X and you say eval
buffer
okay done now let's open a new file
uh something something okay new file
magnify now let's see our pre works okay
e m o enter
no okay you have to turn on every mod I
think
so old X
a brief mark
agreement disabled
uh
old X
agree mod a Brie mod enabled
so yeah it's not there because it's not
part it's not there so you have ARG okay
so let's try a r g there it is ARG
become argument
BTW by the way okay now I do I have some
Unicode here yeah so we have cat face
there so
cat face space it becomes a cat face uh
but the font is not set up
lots of problems
so the point so let's try Hearts okay
so the font is not set up so let why
don't we uh set up font
uh so let's see
options
set default font
uh not Korea you want
console us okay console us 16. do it
okay
now uh it's why is it not still
okay so anyway let's try hearts
there it is now the fund is really bad
the fund is not
working because
uh because I don't have the Unicode
setup but okay I I guess you get the
point
this video is so up so anyway
that's how you set up so we wanted to
set up Pisa you know so we we want it
originally
to be able to type
the pizza okay so let's copy Pizza copy
and uh
paste it and the pizza doesn't
show well that's because the font is not
set up
and so in order to do that
let me see if I can do something quickly
okay
[Music]
paste it so that's the Unicode
paste it here
so let's eval this Ctrl x e
and that's
save these save this Ctrl X Ctrl s
save this XX temp
Dot
txt okay
now close this Ctrl x k
yes okay now we open it
Ctrl X control F
x x temp
okay the font is not
set still so
uh
what so what is the font currently using
so you do Ctrl X
no you do
meta X
yeah mid High axis oats
old X so you do describe cha
okay so now you can see
you can see it says display no font
available
now what but what
I thought we just set up font so
purpose options
multi-lingual environment okay
God the utf-8 okay
so let's try again
multilingual environment set default
font why is that
console usually should work but I have
no I don't know
why it's not working
okay this is pretty bad huh
so right now you see the problem is that
we are trying to do this in a plank no
Emax
but it's not working you know I can show
you I can
he didn't even let me show you how how
it works the uh in my setup okay
uh a brief so you want a brief so all we
have to do is copy that copy that and
make it this piece of wood okay do we
have pizza yeah there it is okay let's
say pizza okay magnify so there it is
show the current line there it is pizza
evaluate the buffer a new page and the
magnify and type p i z z a space no it
become Pizza okay that's one way to do
it now the other way to do it is uh let
me show you another way okay
uh okay so
go through today's talk show uh go to
emacs so
so go to here showing browser this is
so this is the way to set up a key
keystroke to insert characters for
example let's see let's say that okay so
go back to go back go back here paste
this code
and show them in emac beast mode so you
can see that's what you do so if you
want pizza copy that pizza
here and uh
yeah so and uh and then
you want to decide what key you want
let's say
um let's see what is Ctrl t
PX when so let's instead of X F9 let's
say Ctrl T okay
so let's remove those okay so there it
is so now you want to evaluate this line
and do it okay that's done
uh you call
Eva last six okay now you can type Ctrl
t p that will insert pizza so let's try
Ctrl t uh wait
Ctrl t
what
eval
uh yeah I know why it's not working yeah
because I'm using stuff like keys so
lots of problems okay let's try a
different key because
of like he's it's overriding whatever I
Define here so
so let's see do I have some unused key
F5 okay so let's make it F5
F5 okay now shrink the font a little bit
so now f5p should insert Pizza evaluate
that line
there it is now let's type f5p so
okay
F5 P there it is okay so we basically
showed two ways to
to configure emacs to insert any Unicode
or Emoji one is by abbreviation you type
pizza or any kind of word and you become
Pizza the other way is by keystrokes so
in this case f5p okay
but
you know this is my emac setup so
everything is nice now we were trying to
do this in the default emacs playing
glue emacs without any configuration and
first problem is the font
you know the font is not set up
so you have to set up font let's see
what you can you do can we do that yes
we can but that's another topic
uh
uh this is pretty bad video today 30
hours already 30 minutes so okay so
let's
let's try to set up this emacs okay
let's insist on that solving the problem
am I doing good
okay so let's uh
fix this this new Emax problem
okay let's insist
we must fix it so first first of all you
need to set set up the fund why is it
now play so
okay so now because I have sticky keys
on so now we go to setup font yeah so
emacs init and the font setup there it
is
so
so let's copy that
let's paste it here there it is now
let's evaluate this code
Ctrl X control e
okay that should be evaluated already
but um
so consolas should be our font so let's
call
meta X
described char
it still says no fun available why is
that
so let's try
let's turn this into emac Beast mod okay
old X
Emax this mod
okay now you have some minimal syntax
coloring
and now let's evaluate this
parentheses let's see if the so this
part means whether it will tell you if
the font cancel us
is found in a system okay so let's
evaluate Ctrl x e
so it is there
um but why is it not
hey California greetings Arnold
frame fund console as T and T
God
but why why are these
let's save it
it's okay Ctrl X save it
close it
kill buffer
open it again
and they are not still
fun problem
I don't understand why why why is the
default emacs don't have
um
let's go to the Emoji page
the default emacs should have all these
let's just copy them
copy back here
expand the panel
paste
okay emojis basically
Jesus
okay so now we need to go back to set up
the font so that is not enough it should
be though but
um so now
these available fonts check if a fund
exists set fund for Unicode symbols okay
maybe that is what we have to do
copy it emacs should have it set up
already but for some reason it is not
so paste it here now
Ctrl X control e evaluated
yeah but but
why is this all this not showing
save it
kill buffer
yes close it stupid
open it again
okay so let's
made our eggs let's go to emac this mod
and let's evaluate this line to see if
the Circle UI symbol which is the
default font on Windows for emoji to see
if that is available
okay Ctrl X control e
there it is it's available
uh then let's set it
that's yeah so it should have worked now
let's describe character
meta X
describe character
you see it still says font not available
[Music]
Okay so
you see
so we can go to the next step of setting
up fun for emoji but this should not be
necessary because
you know by default emacs should I
should have what what version of emacs
am I using let's see
mid High X
version
28 yeah 28 should be good
okay I have no idea why this happens but
let's just try out an arrow
Ctrl X1 to expand now
paste this code so this code setup Emoji
okay set up specific fonts for certain
characters
so Ctrl X control e
so now they show okay so finally now
they show this idiotic emacs right why
didn't they set up uh
why did why didn't they set up this
before you know this took us
30 minutes
okay now we have the Emoji now can we do
we have pizza let's try again
p-i-z-z-a
no but
oh yeah because yeah well okay so now
you need to switch buffer control X
uh what what is the key for switch
buffer control X U no
Ctrl XB okay switch to the
long time no use emacs
xxxel okay so switch here now all we
have to do is Define the pizza okay
I'm gonna be persistent at what what did
that do
so now let's just
enter
okay
Pisa okay p
p i z z a and here should be a Pisa
symbol okay
we're gonna be persistent and push
through this
we insist that we must get this playing
new emacs to work
okay there it is now evaluate the buffer
okay
meta X
okay wait save it first Ctrl X control s
now meta X
eval buffer
what Oh wrong type okay you you you
you've got the extra period okay to
remove that now Ctrl X save it now
meta X eval buffer do it okay fantastic
now let's go back to the other buffer
switch buffer
temp okay now
p-i-z-z-a
enter
fantastic finally got this done now
let's try the other one so we got
abbreviation work to work in the playing
gnu emacs and how do you do that
that is done by
you know this uh this page okay you go
there and you you have it you just copy
this code put in your init and you have
it you can have any of these a brief so
it's you know just type PSI and you'll
get it so now the other way
the other way I want to show you is the
um
creating a key to insert it okay
yeah which we did did we uh
no that's setting up font then okay so
yeah create a key so now let's copy this
part
and go to your init file
okay go to your unique file and paste it
so you can see it's too big
okay so you can see this section
uh
set keys to yeah so this C you see this
is a fee symbol okay so we can call
describe chart yeah old X
describe char
and you can see this symbol is quick
small letter v
now let's turn on highlight current line
So Meta X
High Line uh that you know it makes a
huge difference when you
when the emac setup makes a huge
difference now I'm trying to find what
is the command name to highlight the
current line
all right
I don't know so let's go back to my
emacs so let's see
do it do it and okay Global Highline mod
okay so now back to the gnu emacs now
meta X and type global
height
Global high watt global
H
lying my idiotic
enter okay now finally okay
the emac setup now switch
pen okay now you can see so that
character is
is the quick small letter V okay now go
back here now let's evaluate this code
so this line Ctrl X control e done okay
now all I have to do is press F9 P okay
F9
oh well F9 I have it system wide to
switch windows so
to switch to last Windows the season 8
the key so you want to change this you
know so I can actually disable that
system white key
uh well that key is actually
a macro from the keyboard firmware
so if I want to disable that I have to
start
the wire software
okay this one
you see so the F9 key is actually doing
M3 which is one of my macro okay so you
can see which is
control tab you know that's uh well M3
here old tab you see it's doing all tabs
so when I press h f 9 it's actually
doing old tab
okay and this is part of the keyboard
firmware
so a lot complexities so I can disable
that actually I can disable that but I
don't want to
because then I you know it's too much
trouble I I can change the key to
uh
I can just do it okay okay yeah there it
is okay so now F9
there it is finally okay so we
demonstrated
two things one is
Thai pizza and space this is inserting
Unicode or math symbols by a brief the
other way is to create a keystroke to do
it and let's see
and we can change this to Pisa but God
so but
okay so you need to
what
so you need to copy the pizza it's
easier to copy it here
so copy Pizza back here and
[Music]
we insist we're gonna do this correctly
Okay so
P okay now that configuration will
insert the pizza okay now Ctrl x e okay
now
F9 P fantastic p-i-z-z-a
space fantastic
F9
wait what did I do
God
I was trying to undo but by default the
undo key will hide emacs
stupid
key okay so f n i p f n i p there it is
F9 P there it is okay
so I think you know I was you know I was
so that's that's the demonstration the
kind of frustrating so
um
okay so that is that is that okay now
let me show you
there's some more ways okay so let me
show you actually there's more ways so
close that now um
let me show you quite there's quite a
lot of things uh 51 so let's
let me do it quickly okay so so
now so suppose I want to insert some
other another way okay so I want to
insert so let's say you have five more
frequent most frequently used
um Unicode so one of the way is for
example let me just show you okay so
you see I press the key it calls the
command and then it gives me a list of
what things I want so for example I can
type 5
I can type 5 and it inserts that music
symbol and this symbol is described key
it's multiple musical notes okay so
let's do it again
okay so I have a pop-up of choices so
let's say I want uh I want a diamond so
four there it is a black diamond okay so
you can see this character is
um Black Diamond okay so how do you set
that up well that is the function now
let's see describe key press it and this
function is called insert Unicode okay
let's do it okay so actually let's try
to do this in playing new Emax so this
is just to show the power again is the
playing new Emax
okay here is the code that's all you
need okay so here is the code copy it
let's go back here uh and let's expand
the window let's paste the code here
paste it so you can see so this code is
two parts one is you define a list of
what Unicode you want so each element
you know this is technically called
associative list it's basically key key
and value pairs so the key is Unicode
symbols and the value is whatever name
or shortcut you want to remind yourself
to type that okay so this is a variable
Unicode list then here is a function
because I Define unicode
and we got what a parenthesis mismatch
uh where does that come from well I
don't know that's probably because we
have some
what
that matched
uh
and did this match let's shrink
so this prayer match in this parade
match and why is this
it seems to match but I don't know why
does the emac this mod makes this part
all red
I don't know so let's evaluate it okay
so first of all evaluate this part so
what you do is you
select buffer okay let's make selection
control space
let's evaluate both okay so there and
the old X and now eval region
do it fantastic now it's done
okay now I just meta X
then call the command X insert unicode
do it
okay so
another problem it you see it's supposed
to pop up at least but it doesn't why
because you haven't configured emacs to
pop up a list so right now you have to
press tab if you want to see this and
and they are formatted in this bad way
so anyway so let's say I want
uh thumb up okay type thumb and press
tab
wait what no match
what uh God
okay so it's it's actually not working
so actually it requires you type to type
the Unicode first this is
this is not good because
well because of the configuration
because you haven't
okay let's let's make it work okay let's
go all the way so let's turn on Fido mod
feeder vertical so metax
Fido
vertical
okay do it now let's try the this
command again
meta X
sign insert Unicode enter now it's
fantastic
now you can use the arrow key okay so
let's try the to insert the Black
Diamond four
there it is beautiful fantastic let's do
it again
metax
signs of unicode
and this time let's type 5 to insert
that musical notes there it is there it
is fantastic so if you want pizza you
just add pizza here let's do it let's
just
today is one
up
because the Pink new emacs haven't
been set up
so now we want pizza so now let's copy
the pizza okay
Ctrl X
move here and copy is
Ctrl W and control W is cut actually
yeah God
okay so anyway let's go back here
let's put this
pizza here
oh actually Pizza should be here
Pizza should be here and here you just
say
p-i-z-z-a okay now you want to evaluate
this code again so you can do that by
um
eval defend okay
meta X
Eva different okay done now
meta X star insert unit code
p i z you see a completion
there it is finally
so we showed three ways to insert
Unicode one is by
a brief p-i-z-z-a okay
agree now a brief is the most useful if
you have thousands of
you know Emoji all math symbols if you
use all of them
for example you have you use them often
so if you if that is the case then you
want a brief because if you give them a
key like control something meta
something or hyper super then the
problem is sometimes you forgot
you know what's the you know what is the
key for a particular Emoji or symbol
but
so that's a brief so the other way is
let's say Ctrl 5 p uh wait
was it control five
uh we did
all right if I have to save
what key did we use
well the other way is
via a keystroke a key sequence okay
uh that allows you to
uh key sequence where is it this is a
brief so yeah key sequence that lets you
insert a Emoji or math symbol and then
another way is a pop-up menu
which is this Unicode list
okay and actually there are more ways uh
for example let's say I want Alpha okay
so I type A then now I press
shift enter wait what
shift space okay now it becomes Alpha so
I type B shift space it becomes better
type c shift space it becomes
uh
this is chi okay so let's see
yeah small letter Greek small letter G
okay so this way now the command is
called
PSI input math okay so that is actually
one of my package you can buy if you
want to
but you know so this package
supports
you know over a thousand symbols math
symbols it's all set up for you so for
example let's have a look so this is a
math input mod so the way you activate
the way you the method you insert these
symbols is that
you type a short a brief first then you
press the key to turn it into a Emoji or
math symbol so that's another way so if
you want this you can buy it pay me go
to my website you can see uh and pay me
by PayPal and
did I mention it somewhere
yeah PayPal
or you can do like we talked about all
the tutorials in five minutes you can
use a brief or key to insert Emoji okay
so this is uh today is a bad video
because we wasted 40 minutes on setting
up setting up playing gun emacs but
eventually we did it everything we
finished
okay that's it for today I think that's
it
it's one hour okay so I was planning
actually this uh there's a lot
interesting things to talk about but I
think that's it because
I'm getting tired
um
so we showed many uh the fancy keyboard
we showed emoji keyboard
we
it showed Unicode so you have all kind
of unicode
and we showed
math symbols fantastic math symbols all
these you can set up a key to type them
then
this is how you
in emacs set up a key sequence or a
single key if you want to F9 F10 you
know f11 if you want to to insert any of
the Unicode characters
then we also talked about
some math input mod which which is
already set up you can buy
and we also talked about
emacs a brief system this is actually
the most efficient so you can set up
hundreds of a brief for all emojis for
each and every Emoji you want you just
type a short word and press the key it
becomes basically press space or enter
and it becomes a unicode easy very easy
to set up
and we also talked about old graph key
compose key and that key what are what
are the differences
and we showed some the APL keyboard and
uh
oh and if you are using a Mac you can
create your customized layout with the
option key to insert different Emoji if
you want for example I have a code here
I show you how basically all you have to
do
hold on a second let me see
let me see if I can
what
uh
let's see if you can see yeah you can
see it okay so this page
create custom keyboard layout this is
for the Mac you can you can set up your
own customize option uh key to insert
Emoji or math symbols basically all you
have to do is to create this file and
save it uh save it in this directory
and you'll have it
okay so that's for the Mac
and then so that one more thing okay one
more thing so
you know we should we talked about
several ways to
several input methods to insert certain
special characters
what which one is the most efficient so
that's what this page is about which one
is most efficient so you can
you can use a if you have 1000 Keys you
can just press a key directly set up
your keyboard to do that actually
keyboard cannot do that that's another
issue because the keyboard firmware they
don't send out characters to your
computer directly what they send is just
a number okay
there are 150 a limit limited number
they are only about 150 of them that's
in the USP protocol
so you so the keyboard you know they
only send what's called key code you
know a number to your computer and this
150 numbers becomes
you know ABC or punctuation so you don't
so it's not possible to make your
keyboard firmware to actually send a
Unicode or Emoji or math symbols
directly to your computer so that is a
major
frequently Asked question from any
keyboard you know do it yourself and so
on because the USB interface do not you
know they are not sending characters
they are just sending one of the 150 or
so numbers so
you can make them
send emoji but you don't have enough
Keys you know out of 150. so anyway so
what usually
you do is once the computer the
operating system gets the key code from
your keyboard then it can
you know uh via layout or whatever
translate them into whatever character
so anyway the different input methods so
one is by pressing
key code or key sequence to insert the
Emoji or you can type something and
press a key to change them into Emoji
such as the emacs a brief system then
you can have
you know so and also compose key old
graph and that key there are also
different methods but the question is
which one is the most efficient
so I have this that's what this page is
about essentially
that depends on
how many
here's the answer okay it depends on how
many
characters you need and
how frequently you use them for example
if you use if you need a acute e which
is very frequent you know acute e in
French for example
um
not here acute e is where is it
yeah so here so if you
need a character for acute e
you need to enter it every few minutes
you know every minute is also then
what you need is a
key sequence or key code okay a breed
doesn't work well because for a brief
you have to type you know for example
e then apostrophe then press the key
actually it can work as well but anyway
if you only have a handful of most
frequently
needed symbols then the most frequent
the most efficient way is a
key code or key sequence okay but if you
have hundreds of briefs such as all the
math symbols you you know not everyone
of them you use very frequently but you
do need them sometimes
so you have if you have hundreds of them
then a brief is the uh probably best
system
okay so that's it thank you guys for
watching
bye guys come on ad what is common ad
bye