okay hello everyone welcome to another
episode of SAR talk show today we are
going to talk about random subject I'm
going to give you an update of what I
have been doing in the past one week or
two okay so introduce first of all my
keyboards glove 0
fantastic ultimate hacking keyboard
version two fantastic I have a review
both of both just search YouTube and
this I want to give a shout out again a
shout out again this is s board data
hand just search for s data hand you'll
see my previous video about three videos
three videos ago now I don't have news
for this thing yet but I just I just
want to show it again okay here is a
Mouse you know I mean the pointer
fantastic okay I'm going to I'm going to
have a lot to do with this okay Val
board s v a l b o a r d data hand search
forar data hand you'll find it okay so
that's about my keyboard uh and this is
Logitech uh whatever this is called I
also have a review fantastic okay let me
go over now if you have a questions post
it now okay uh I will check and answer
every question uh and now let me go over
to the main topic you know what I have
been doing in the past uh week or
two so live stream you know I have been
coding a lot emac LP and also updating
my emac lisp tutorial just search for S
emac lisp tutorial so and a lot of wolam
language coding okay so showing browser
I'm using S HTM ma mod okay so
tremendous coding for example let me
show you cfly keys I'm using cfly keys
uh you should try it if you have not
already it's the most efficient key
binding system in emac more efficient
than Vim or EVO mod okay uh 4,000 lines
of code so here is all my mods and by
the way I also have started to learn FSH
FSH is fantastic the best industry
language now in my opinion is FOP before
that it was go land go okay I have a
tutorial so I'm going to talk random
okay if you are here say hi and ask your
questions sko Language tutorial am I am
I on yes video check audio check
fantastic chick Ching $2
Euro oh God $2 favorite English word
thoughts on two in or CN method okay so
you are talking about Chinese input
method oh you are Chinese I didn't know
uh I have a a lot quite a few article on
that okay uh so thoughts on zooing or
alterate Chinese method okay that's kind
of that topic only Chinese would be
interested because otherwise for typical
American or european they wouldn't know
what that is let me talk about that in a
bit okay but first of all let me talk
about the main things so goand was my
favorite tutorial this is my goand
tutorial it's the most
concise it's the most efficient tutorial
if you want to know goland you know
there are a lot of tutorials these days
you search then most of it is pit you
know like idiotic that like they they
pretend they think you are a children
they you know like you don't know what
is a function you know they anyway you
if you want if you are a programmer you
already know a language you want the go
land you want a most efficient
and correct and precise and kind of
indepth
tutorial you go TOA tutorial skoland
okay I have one for goand and uh I have
you know quite a few tuto tutorials on
programming languages I talked about
this many times but let me quickly go
over emx is a great okay great tutorial
emac list is a great if you are emac
user
try to get into emac list okay I have
the best tutorial wolam language is the
best thing it's the best programming
language it's the most highest level but
it's not a industrial programming
language okay meaning that it's not you
know for example if you are going to
write a
compiler you know that would you you
wouldn't use score language but I mean
wolam language but wolf and language is
like just everything else everything
else by a magnitude better than hascal
FSH rust you know the rust idiot rust R
rust Fanatics you know rust people are
kind of idiots the rust type of people
who talk about rust all all day they are
the type of people they they are like
the subset of the C and
C++ type of people they are into
compilers they are into kernal they are
into operating system they are into like
lowlevel memory you know like typically
they are idiots okay they don't know
nothing about mathematics they don't
know nothing about group Theory uh you
know or functional programming theories
type Theory logic you know uh you know
the the whole branch of entire or
artificial intelligence they tends to
know nothing about they they they just
care about memory memory compiling
that's a rust type of people okay but
anyway M wam I got more new news I going
to talk about W language so that's my
favorite so but FSH is a great the most
now is my favorite industrial language
okay so I got HTML tutorial CSS you know
it's necessary to know these days and
JavaScript in depth this this one
JavaScript in depth is the
most the tutorial that I spent the most
effort about two years to write it and
still uh maintain it so JavaScript in
depth okay and SVG tutorial the most
concise and precise and uh non nonsense
okay in all my tutorials my style is
that I tell you exactly what it is you
type this and that's what it means this
is output okay I don't talk about the
story like some people especially
non-technical type of people they like
storytelling oh once about upon a time
there's a spring you you know the AUM
leaves are falling and I feel great I
went into this place and there's a this
thing there's language oh but I'm famili
with see and you know but I'm surprised
in in the language oh then and then I
realize that's what the function
mean it's idiotic storytelling style
well it's I mean depending on your taste
some people a lot of people like
especially non technical people they
prefer that because that's kind of human
the guy guy you like you read a like
read a novel but usually people who like
that they don't get far because they
don't you know they are not habituated
with the mindset of technical
engineering type if you are the
mathematician type engineer type
chemistry or into physics you you like
the you are the kind of the engineer or
scientist mindset you don't usually you
don't want that because you your passion
you know you have a about technology or
sciences that that's what drives you
okay but most uh a lot people most
people they they heard oh programing can
make a lot money that's those type of
people but they have have no interest in
learning I mean they they they find it
boring like like what you to do what
what to do with this you know programing
language oh but I can make money with it
oh okay so I try to learn what is a
common that's vast majority of people
well not you know a lot major you know
half of the programmers kind of like
that they go to school they go to
college because their parents told them
to you know you need to go to college to
get a degree so but if you are the
programmer scientist type you know if
you are really a nerd then you'll find
my tutorial
uh helpful I I hope and uh you know it's
not story storytelling type okay so
there's a Goan I'm proud of my t
tutorial about goand and pow shell okay
pow shell is when you are on Windows if
you are a window user then power shell
is necessary okay look look forward 10
years not like the most YouTuber today
you know teach you a programming
language like you what's the best
programming language you know they they
their goal is actually just to be
popular to get you to watch their you
know Learn Python in 1 hour learn
JavaScript no you know the this thing
you never know about JavaScript you know
there's lots of most most of them on
YouTube programming tutorial are like
that you know they they want you get
what they want they want is not about
you they want to be popular you know
they make money that's what they
want I want I I want your
money but but what but foremost I'm
obsessed about these things okay so
that's why you might find my stuff
interesting okay so my Ruby program my
Ruby tutorial is not so good my Python
tutorial is very fairly good okay uh so
and pearl okay and so that's my
programming language tutorials okay
that's a sid track because I I haven't
started to uh we need to talk about the
things we talked about okay swab board I
I talked about okay uh you should look
check check out my videos okay so next
thing so let me get on and answer you
guys questions okay so wolam language
there's update so I have worked a lot on
wolfen language my favorite language so
let me show you so now right now these
three packages are on GitHub so it's
free thanks to wolam uh research okay I
work there you know 1995 as a summer
intern for a while so and then but I
since then I have somewhat a
relationship with
them so wolam language so let me so the
what's new is this package I talked
about in my past two or three videos I
talked about it often so it's all about
geometry okay now look at all this this
I need to show it okay so this is uh
this is called transformation of the
plane okay let me quickly demo it for a
few minutes
okay uh wfam language I need to
transformation of the plan okay so so if
you are if you are hardcore coder you
are interested if you are rust coder or
C coder you are a hardcore you you are
hard shot you know look at the language
okay so this one is 300 lines okay so
here's a source code by the way if you
are from the industrial programming C
python Java JavaScript you never seen
code like this okay you see this code
that's one single
line you never seen it in your life this
is wam language why do you do a single
in single line W oh my God you don't
understand okay I you know if you watch
my past tutorials I have you know I have
like a set of programming tutorials for
Wam language you can understand it and
about the syntax okay so let me show you
so anyway yeah so I wanted to demo so
actually I want to demo wolam plot uh
gallery and documentation okay so let's
open up wolam language it's on GitHub
okay
so uh let me show you some of the
Transformations okay so these are called
um transformation of the plane okay for
example you start with the grid like
that just a grid rectangular grid then
you apply a
function to any point on the grid so the
function will so the function takes a a
vector or a point and returns another
Point usually in a different place so so
when you apply the function to the grid
it it transforms the grid to some other
shape in this
case oh my phone alarm in this case it
just it flipped it around the diagonal
line so you it flips
okay so this package is now on GitHub
free okay just search for it so in this
case you rotate you app you apply a
rotation Matrix okay let me show you
guys what is this because it's
interesting so rotation Matrix that's a
function in Wolf language you can see
very simple actually so if you study
linear
algebra so you know this is a heart of
linear algebra rotational Matrix okay
then you'll know what it is so here you
apply a sheer transformation here you
apply a log kind of so this is this you
will not see much this you'll see often
rotation you'll see often the reflection
you know the you'll see often uh and
this one is simply identity okay in
functional programming you often have
the concept of a identity function which
you sometimes
need so and then we start to get in
interesting this is a square function in
a complex plane so complex function so
and this is a inverse function one /x
okay beautiful this this is one of the
most beautiful
uh functions uh functions um graph okay
I I would consider this one to be the
most beautiful graph of a function in
mathematics this 1 /x 1 /x over the you
know where X is a complex number okay
and here is a a cosine uh very
interesting okay so that's some of the
basics then you started to get fancy you
can begin you know previously we start
with a rectangular grid and then you see
the image the result of the function but
now we start with a triangular grid what
happens okay and and or you can start
with a uh polar grid okay so or you can
start with a re rectangular patches okay
so you can see again some basic function
basic functions here's a
sign here here is a sheer Shear function
applied to the S curve so originally
sign curve is like normal but now you
apply sheer so it becomes like you know
slightly Twisted am I good yeah I'm good
okay so am I am I good say hi okay so
anyway here are the basic and here is a
one/ X again a inversion geometric
inversion
beautiful okay let let me run the code
so you can see actually run the code so
let me load the
package uh where is the okay so let me
load the
package okay so it's loaded so we can go
to any of these so for example that one
deleted this is a code shift enter to
run it is see there it is and uh now
let's show some fancy ones okay I'm
digressing a lot because actually we
have a lot other things to talk about
keyboard today one of the main topic is
about keyboard and layout I want to talk
about okay so for example this one run
it
what oh okay so you forgot to Define
here yeah run this
then click run it now there it is is
okay so and this one this one is very
interesting if you are studying linear
algebra this one shows the angon
vectors Ang vectors is a vector where
when you apply a transformation function
to a
plane ion Vector is a line such that any
point on the line remain on the line
they don't they don't go anywhere they
remain on the line so that's I iron
Vector uh iron Vector okay so this one
shows
it and then you actually you have the
threedimensional okay so let me show you
threedimensional version I mean this my
package provide this function
stereographic
projection okay for example delete that
and run it run it okay then you can see
the graphics and let's
magnify then you can rotate it
you see isn't that
beautiful
that's projection from a plane to a
sphere and this sphere is called Raymond
sphere okay Raymond sphere you can look
up look it up on
Wikipedia so I'm G giving you very
interesting account of mathematics if
you are in college you might have heard
of you know when you are studying
calculus you you might have heard of
complex analysis complex plan or Ron
sphere Ron what what exactly are those
so you you you actually see uh you know
the interesting part so kind of like a
introduction okay so then you can also
use grid then here is a square function
you know like Square function oh no wait
this is a cosine function
okay uh where is it yeah this is a sign
function okay sign
function you see previously we have seen
cosign let me quickly go through because
I want to talk about keyboards so here
is a plot of cosine cosine and sign look
similar for example let's do sign
okay uh wait so shift enter so that's
cosine now let's change this to
sign okay sign uh
wait shift enter okay s cosine they look
uh exactly the same you know so this is
a graph of a
sign okay so actually we need to change
we should change this to 0 to 2 pi so
actually 0 to uh they overlap some
somewhat but anyway let's forget it so I
want to show you the 3D version so what
I mean is that so once you get this you
know you you start with the grid
rectangular grid then you apply the sign
function to the grid then you get that
okay or cosine you know you get that
that okay then you so this is a graph on
a plane then you imagine there's a
sphere sitting on on the on the floor
then you project this this picture to
the to the North Pole of the sphere then
what you get is
this the then you get this okay you
see fantastically beautiful you've never
seen mathematics this beautiful this is
mathematics okay speaking of mathematics
let's go to s. info
okay so you can see my website and uh a
week ago April 1 I added this JavaScript
reing you know reing mathematical
symbols so that's kind of fun and if you
are into JavaScript you can see how this
works okay so you go to JavaScript
tutorial uh there JavaScript in depth
click you go to
Dom then you go to um for example fade a
element fade and fade
fade uh this are some user interface
things and this one is how to create a
tool tip you see and then you one of
them is raining effect so there is a
code you can study how it works
okay now that's about wolam language now
let me show you so actually so there's a
lot interesting things for example all
these are transformations of the plane
um you know
so so it's great for if you are studying
complex analysis or if you are studying
Vector functions you know when you get
into calculus of multivariable calculus
you'll find this package very useful
because it helps you visualize what the
function do you know and also comp in
complex plan complex analysis that is
imaginary numbers so-called so you see
and then also if you are artist you can
use this package to create beautiful uh
artworks so you see very interesting
then let me show you some of them for
example this you have seen often in
science fiction in illustration of black
hole or in wave you know so this is a
wave uh so you can see this function is
right
here there that's a function okay so and
then you can see the same function but
now appli to a triangular grid you you
see how interesting that is then uh then
then there's this is like a Windows logo
you know you apply a transform
function in this function you know you
have to be creative to to to find this
function okay so control shift n to make
it um type set so you see this is a
function s * s s sin x * sin y s sin x *
s y then times that by the unit vector
XY normalize means create the unit
Vector then transform it by plus XY
translate I mean if you study linear
algebra you will know what I mean but if
you not you know you can study linear
algebra so you know and this this you
might have seen as well usually in
camera if you are a camera camera you
know photography Fanboy you you might
have in this effect you know this is
like a burn kind of like a burning
burning hole and that function is this
one so one over one over the uh length
of a vector plus two then plus four then
multiply by the unit Vector then then
you also translate plus the the vector
okay so anyway so and this one you have
must have seen too this is a fish lens
effect fish lens
okay okay and and this one is
interesting I call this one
tits okay okay that that's about the
that okay so because I we have a lot to
talk
about so I want to show you the GitHub
for this package uh download
there GitHub okay okay it's
free uh and some of the other
interesting Graphics I you know so
anyway so that is about that so let's
see what's the next thing uh we want to
talk about how long have I been it's
already half an hour oh my
God okay so let's talk about keyboard so
maybe I cannot finish today okay I can
finish the let's quickly talk about
keyboard okay so go to search for S
keyboard block let me tell you some news
or the things I worked on okay uh I'm
I'm just going to talk about some
interesting things so there's a update
on my ergonomic keyboard layout so you
can see so these are the collection of
ergonomic keyboard layouts so you have
the quality so this you are seeing the
heat map of corac workman asset Norman
you know it's JavaScript so you have quy
so I arranged them by date quy
1870 vorak
1936 then moton layout now this is a RAR
mention moton layout it began in uh
where is the date morron layout do I
have a date here or I need to add a date
here moton layout began
in 1970 197 77 okay then you have
programming programmers vac
1999 which is a variation of vorac okay
then you have the
Areno 2001 that's a beginning you know
2001 people started nerds like us
started to
um to do this uh you know keyboard layer
then you have caps Cape whale one of the
early one cap whale then Cod MAAC that
one blow it up that one is the beginning
of the keyboard layout C coac 2005 this
guy Shai Coleman you know he created a
website in the Forum so a lot of people
you know start to talk about it you know
and adopted comac and he Market his
layout very much you know the idea is
that he says he tells people hey vorak
is not the only one okay after you know
100 years actually today we can create a
lot layout more efficient than vak
that's him so he created V coac that's
the that's the first wave
of of keyboard layout um Ching thank you
Crystal okay so then you have asset 2006
then you have wman 2010 you know the
Workman guy he tried vorak he don't like
it he Tri Comax supposed to be
Improvement uh he got problems too so he
created Workman okay let me tell you a
story about all this workout you know
nerds you know these nerds are crazy
like they today they are still creating
layout which is kind of
idiotic there typically their story is
that you know today you have like tens
of layout right so there are stories
like that oh I tried
vorak I didn't like it I tried coac I
didn't like it I tried the coac DH you
know which is a variation I didn't like
it's got a problem too I tried this I
tried all of them but they all got
problems so I started to design my own
you know letter layout these are focus
on letter layout only that's important
because letter layout is actually not
that important but but these nerds you
know they they don't see anything else
you know they because they are just like
they saw this they they think they must
be a best way so they just focus on that
they don't they ignore anything else
like they don't they don't
know so basically all the of all of
their stories like that you know I tried
all these others they all seems to have
a problem so I create this one you know
this one should be the best you know
then there's a qfm lwy layout
2011 supposed to be the most efficient
suppos that's the thing uh then mini
MAAC you know he's got new ideas oh all
the others but they got problems mini
MAAC is most easy to learn you know if
you Mini Mac because it it it only has a
minimal key changes so if you already
type on quy you know mini MAAC is
easiest to learn then there's Norman
layout Norman is the first one of the
first guy who says oh yeah I tried
Norman I I mean I
tried vorak I tried kak I tried wman I
think they all got problems now let me
introduce Norman
layout okay that's the first kind of the
first after all these 10
others Norman but one one thing they all
got they they all you know they are not
their approach usually all these
creators of later layouts later layouts
they their approach is not scientific
and it's not not encompassing it's not
systematic okay typically they are just
like a nerd okay like I am you know I
happen to you know know about keyboard
layout then I just focus on that you
know what's better so but they they
don't their view like is very narrow
they don't see they don't see other
things for example all of them almost
all of them so far they think
that X the key X and c and V of the
quality layout should be remain where
they are because if you change them then
all the shortcut got changed then that's
a problem so all these people so far
kman you know kman Norman
minimac uh
Workman wait does that include Workman
uh not so much Workman but anyway a lot
of them they
insist that the XC V cut copy paste Keys
should say the same you know which is
actually false the xcv keys causes
repetitive strain injury a lot because
that that's a shortcut most people if
you are a programmer most of the time
you don't type okay most of the time you
are moving the cruiser you are doing
copy paste opening file close file
switch buffer switch file switch tab
you know and delete this word delete
this paragraph insert you know that most
of the key is shortcut keys or if you
are Photoshop image editor Video Creator
you know today there's a lot jobs for
video editing video image editing right
you don't type okay type is not the M
main thing all this letter the all this
all this um keyboard letter layout you
know that's not the main thing the main
thing you do on the computer is
shortcuts control X control something
okay so you don't want the xcv keys for
cut copy paste that that induces
repetitive string injury
okay but but all these people they think
you know those keys shouldn't change so
so that's defeats the purpose of
creating a efficient layout the the you
see the purpose is to reduce to be more
efficient and reduce repe repetitive
strength injury right so they you know I
don't think they in my opinion okay let
me just say this is my kind of you know
I have some scientific basis for example
I have G give a lot statistics about
this
anyway then there's qwp
2013 then there is comac D
2014 then there's holac this is
beginning to be new holac this HC so
what's hak hak says oh uh we are based
on AI today the the power of AI so
therefore horac you know based on
artificial intelligence algorithms but
actually the the very earliest
the the cape well is based on AI okay
2005 uh it's called evolution
evolutionary Pro programming or genetic
programming okay that's part of
AI technique to
program so anyway so there's a homac who
claims you know it's AI it's it's based
on this AI system okay then there's
engram engram claims to be the best okay
actually I do think engram is good okay
but anyway there's a lot of details you
know you you can't really say which one
is the best but I think um I have good
um I think engram is good a good uh New
Creation so
anyway uh so 2021
engram okay and then there's more okay
now now there's a this one bco now let
me talk about so all these
layouts some of them a few handful of
them are actual
innovations that is they created certain
concept about layout that never existed
before or people don't you know haven't
they they brought it out so they brought
out new ideas
so uh which one are they let me let me
let me tell you
okay vorak is a first one about 100
years ago the idea is that alternating
hands and don't move hands so much the
shorter distance okay that's the first
one is the second
one 50 years ago 30 years ago something
40 years ago okay the first one to put a
letter key on the thumb so if you guys
don't know um about motron let me show
you okay so keep lay this let me let me
just
uh so moton is the first layout that has
a letter key e a b c d e FG e the most
used letter in English on a thumb key
okay so it's kind of a special layout
because you cannot do that on a normal
PC keyboard so they come in you know so
and here is the the computer language or
English or whatever uh character
frequency for example I can copy my
entire buffer and for example
deleted some you can see it this chart
updates in real time as you type okay so
I can select or paste my whole emac
buffer then you can see the frequency A
and E so e is by far the most frequent
frequently used by far you know more
than much more so you can so that is the
morron layout who who started to um do
that
okay so let me open
them uh motron layout so that's a
Innovation okay then then you then the
next one is comac you know I don't I
don't like comac so much because it you
know comac tried to disrupt comak is the
first one that disrupt the idea of vorak
you know by saying that there is better
so in a sense it's bad because it you
know before everyone can just use vorak
then eventually we
can we can dismiss Cy I mean I mean so I
mean so the whole industry every
keyboard will be vak right but comac
tried try to dis disrupt that he's
saying that comat is actually better
slightly maybe you know so anyway so
then then you have then you started to
have so
many so the end result is that quy
people still stuck stick with quy the
the most worthless you know most
inefficient
so comac so but however comac does have
a great idea comac is the first one that
tells you that vak is actually not you
know the only one it's it's you know
like before comac everyone is think
thinks that com you know vak is
basically it but comac says actually no
you know actually you know of all
layouts there's some will be possibly
better than voak okay that's the that's
a contribution of KAC and I would say
comac is also the first one introduce
the r concept which is you move your
your your you type in the order of the
pinky
to to the ring finger to index so it's
kind of this inward rolling motion which
is very comfortable okay so comac
introduced
that then the next one I will say is PCO
now PCO is one of the so bco let me show
you bco layout okay bco
layout bco layout is one of the kind of
odd it's like a niche or Niche you know
you try to look for like typically all
the other layout typically they have a
website uh let me show you again so let
me just
show uh keyboard layout design
okay connect frequency plot B code
keyboard layout yeah so so typically all
this layout usually they have a homepage
or GitHub or whatever so they tell you
okay this is my layout you know this is
here's the reasons I think it's better
here's where you can download it you
know that's
typical but B layout it's like among the
nerd niches there's no website you can't
find it there's no website that says
this is the B homepage this is layout
why it's there why is this way it like
none instead it's just bunch of nerds
they like talking among themselves you
know that's a situation okay B layout
so and and related to bco is another one
called Mt Gap Mt Gap like you can you
can never find the information about it
it's like you you you find like people
talking about it but you don't know
exactly what what it looks like okay
because these are nerds you know some
some layout in particular for example
KAC they are created by a guy who
heavily tries to Market it you know like
the coac people they try to you know
they put it in Apple computer now it's
on Apple computer you have it so where
is it let me show you comac okay so let
me go to their
website you know one giant website and
forums and you know you know one giant
website you know very clean welld
designed heavy marketing you know home
download FAQ try out Advocate donations
learn you know like they they really
want to push it it's like marketing
heavy marketing and he he su succeeded
in making apple having the cor Mac by
default and also linuxes you know but
not in Microsoft not in micros not in
Microsoft Windows but heavy marketing
okay because he want he want his
creation to be know know you
know but not not the beo guy like you
you can you can find where where is it
like what the like who created you can't
find an empty Gap okay this so it's a
different type of
nerds like you know different you know
so you can find information about it
however I have people you know among my
followers nerds who M I live say hi guys
okay how many people are watching
give me some actions give me some
reactions say say oh 16 people
okay where where is Tiffany do put it in
the
chat then I'll be banned by
Google so
B is the niche Nish like you
know by by this e on doglas uh no wait
by byan Douglas I've kind of talked to
you know uh with communicate a bit but
by
this say or say Voom like you don't know
who you know like he don't have website
no GitHub nothing you don't know where
it's came
from but but luckily there is this
website death desk authority. net Wiki
they documented you know they documented
the bco layout So eventually I I find
good info
and another one is mty Gap you know that
one you can't find you know like you
don't know where you know where they are
so B you know like they have like 15
versions like you know anyway so but I
think bco is has a great Innovation p is
the first one who pushed idea that don't
use your pinkies at all e even on the
home row okay almost all others all the
other keyboard layout they you know they
focus you can see the heat map they
focus on the home row they want you know
the home row to be emphasized so almost
all of them you can see the home row is
like all straight
lines so you can
see except quy quy is the most idiotic
then you see vorak it's all on line
comac comac DH well comac DH has the
idea that you don't want the inward
motion of your index
finger then Workman okay Workman also
have some that idea asset you know then
it's a line Norman okay also
that and you know this supposedly qf ml
Wy the most efficient is also a lie and
mini MAAC so anyway
so for the bco is the first one who who
specifically emphasize that no you don't
want to use your pinkies at all so so in
contracts you see all the others got
heavy Keys heavy use of the Pink Key
except PCO okay so in that regard I
think bco is a
Innovation this this bco layout it's a
you know it's a Innovation real
innovation in in in keyboard letter
layout design okay so that's a that's
about it I think I talked already uh 50
minutes so actually I have more topics
but so maybe today is more about just
layout so let me see anything else
there's uh anything else I want to say
so so keyboard blog go talk show block
go back
close uh okay so which go to talk
show yeah so the Innovations in summary
vorak motron
comac boo that I think these are the
these are the layouts actually added
Innovation to
humanity the rest are just nerds you
know it's just the rest are just nerds
trying to do their nerd
things kind of
okay so that's that's that about that I
you
know the opinion May differ there are
others uh you know some people who have
designed other keyboard for example
there are few for example let's see you
know hands down layout he's got
elaborate site website and he's got 507
507 layouts on his homepage hands down
and among the NS
you know some people just like mention
it all the time but I don't really see
much points about hands
down uh okay
so so anyway opinions differ okay so you
know it's great they created their
layout you can try them you know you can
think about which one is good okay so
maybe that's it for today so let's
see so I talked about bco uh so some
other things Okay computer characters
frequency let me talk about this one a
little
bit so I created you know go to the
website just search for computer
languages characters frequency
so so this is this gives a chart about
which character is most used punctuation
characters in by different comp
programming
languages so for example here is
Javascript you can see equal sign in
JavaScript equal sign and parenthesis is
most used and Dot and here's another
JavaScript from different
project and then in Java the dot is by
far the most used character Java
okay so you can see Java then this goand
also Dot and parent then
C++ that's a underscore or low line
because every I identifier every
function name every variable name you
have lots of underscore C++ and C by far
you can see the underscore is going you
know by far that's the most used
character why you need this that's when
you study keyboard layouts you see you
you need to know which character is most
frequently used so then there's PHP
Dolla Sign of course then python also
underscore and Dot then Ruby okay so
anyway what I added recently is wolam
language comma okay in wolam language
comma is most frequently used uh
actually can you see the graph yeah
actually you can
see right you can see the graph right
right
right so w language comma and the
brackets and eisp is a hyphen and
parenthesis you know in Lis you might
think it's just parenthesis right so
let's go to a you let's go to a list
source
code so you think it's all parenthesis
but actually it's the hyphen because
every identifier has several of them so
emac this hyphen is most used in this
hascal uh
okay so that's about this you know uh so
you can you can plot it of course you
can plot your own just go
to character frequency plot and you know
copy and paste your source code and you
can see uh which character is most
frequently
used okay that's that so let's see
what's the next thing uh let me talk
about the Chinese input
system so there are few more updates uh
Aon keyboard okay so this is a gaming
keyboard a new photo thanks to
Matt
uh for gaming but however this is not
comparable to the SM data hand okay not
comparable
because because the switches now this
data hand is magnetic so it's super
light I don't you know as I don't think
that's comparable at
all so let's see let me double check
uh let's
see I'm about done that's it that's
about it for today okay so just
some okay so this keyboard This is a
rare happy hacking fans would love so
this is a rare keyboard using the um
topper switch topper switch is there's a
coat of topper switch from Happy happing
happy hacking keyboard of Japan a lot of
people love this so and this is a rare
one uh Emily thanks to Emily who who
showed me who gave me the photos so
here's Emily's workstation with the
Epson you know they don't they don't
make this anymore so but this is one of
the keyboard
that many topus
which fans would
love okay so and also Emily you know
Emily has a lot of interesting things
which she showed me you know like uh
even in 2019 you know beginning so she's
got lots of interesting things if you
want to read it search for Happy hacking
Emily lisp
server
okay so uh so let me show you talk show
so what uh so we talk about so I'm just
going
to okay so let me talk about Chinese
pinging input
system TOA switch I don't like TOA
switch myself okay I think it's
too too heavy and it's you got a heat
btom problem okay just my opinion
so your question about P input so what
do you think
about uh Su in an old Chinese input
method okay so Chinese input
method so I have a few articles on that
so let me show you so you just search
for
Chinese input okay then
uh
actually
uh so you have Chinese input methods you
have Japanese input methods and uh so
let me talk about that so for Chinese
you know if you need to type Chinese and
or Japanese it's not like English or
French or Italian or you know there's no
Direct Key corresponding to the
character you have to use the input
system so for example I can show
you uh let's type some Chinese
okay so window space
so that's a pronunciation so I want
to okay that means type Chinese okay so
so first of all there are many there are
about 10 or even 20 different input
methods or systems for typing
Chinese so it's not like English you
know for English maybe you have the quy
you have vorak okay you have different
layout but for Chinese you it's not just
about it's not about layout it's you
have different ways to type them so in
general there are two categories there's
phonetic based based on sound meaning
that you type how it sounds using
English then uh maybe not you know you
can use English or there's zoing and
other but anyway the main thing is that
you type the sound how does the sound of
the character for example Z zong means
the first Char first you know means
middle so then it pops up all these
choices you can select different
characters having that sound then after
you select one you know then that's a
character so you type the sound first
then you select the character so that's
pronunciation based okay that's the main
category now among this category there's
10 different ones okay because there are
different ways to indicate the
pronunciation of Chinese characters the
different systems
okay now the other way the other method
main category of Chinese input is the
character shape based so for example if
you want to type the Zone character you
don't you don't you don't you don't type
the sound you you you type Based On A
system that describe the shape now that
system requires learning and actually I
don't know how to I don't know any uh
but for example you can do by writing
okay let me try
Z one so I can write it you see I can
write it
too okay
so you know so so the in this category
of input system for Chinese you you
describe how the character shape and
there are many ways to do it very very
complex so you have to spend time to
learn it but usually the end result is
that typically is faster
okay so Chinese input method you know if
you want to read it you can see uh so I
have a Linux Chinese input setup so this
article Chinese input methods that
describes
how Chinese are typed for example here's
the Apple keyboard from Taiwan okay so
you can see very complex uh you know
labels on the keys actually they
actually you are seeing three different
systems to input Chinese here like some
people prefer this system some people so
it's like quite diverse so anyway here
this article describes how uh so you can
see and Google if you use Google Gmail
and Google stuff Google also provides
their own you can see there are like you
know 1 two 3 4 five six seven
eight 9 10 11 12 13 13 just on
this you have 13 different ways to input
Chinese you know 13 Chinese input
systems you can pick from Google Google
Gmail so your question is about zooing
versus alternate okay so zooing is a
particular uh Chinese input system
that's based on sound and that's how I
grew up I learned two in when I was in
Taiwan that's
the system I grew up but I actually I
just used PIN so your question is about
which one is more efficient or what do I
think so actually I don't know much
about it except you know I
studied you know I studied and know
about how how many you know all these
different systems but actually I don't
type Chinese that much so I just use the
most basic pingin
system and if you are Chinese in China
or Taiwan or Hong Kong there are like I
believe there are some competitions or
you know like testing or studying which
layout is more efficient but uh again
usually it's very Niche you won't find
most people most vast majority like 90%
of Chinese they just use pinging okay
and if they are in Taiwan they usually
just just use is zing so p and Zing they
are both phonetic okay so you type how
the words the character sounds then it
give you a many choices but how do they
differ well p is the China system based
on English alphabet so for example let
me type um so it uses English
alphabet so where's my notepad so let me
try again for for example I want to type
zong so that's z h o n there it is
okay okay now zong means middle zongo
means China okay like the Middle Kingdom
Middle Country so but if I if I want use
two in which is also sound based but you
don't but you don't use English
characters you now I don't know do in
two Wells I mean I know twoing well but
I don't know
the do I have it I don't even have it on
so I have to add the input
system so two in is the you can see it's
the upper right corner of each key label
here uh I have arle on that for example
I have study on pin letter
frequency then I also have uh P versus
string versus IP and IPA compar
so here this column the First Column is
two in okay that's
a okay the second column is Ping which
is English alphabet okay I think that's
it does that answer your question yeah I
don't know the details about the Chinese
input
systems um
so okay so I'm kind of tired I talked
for 1 hour I think that's it do I still
use vak yes of course yes of course I do
now you don't see vac here
because I'm using a you see this glove 0
is vac is vorac so I'm using a physical
VOR okay I think that's
it okay bye guys thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff donate
okay
so you can uh yeah donate to me just go
to S okay so let's switch back to
English s.
info
fantastic and uh you go to the bottom
then you'll see my uh patreon and Amazon
gift card and PayPal okay thank you guys
for watching I think that's it
bye
guys we need sof fly Chinese input
system yeah I don't think I'm going to
you know that's
a Chinese input system is very complex
because you have to design a system that
lets you
type 3,000 minimum typically 4,000
characters uh so it's
um did I miss any questions okay I think
that's it I'm hungry I'm going to eat my
wife's cooking spring
rose
bye