good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
so today we are going to do emac this
coding
and plus tutorial i'm gonna show you
uh
emac beast coding so what i'm gonna do
so let's begin uh today's 2022
march 20th
so if you have questions for me post it
okay if you are new here say hi okay i'd
love to see your comments so let's begin
emac this coding so what are we going to
do today so
this is the problem okay uh here's
today's talk show so on the pink window
is all my command codes and keystrokes
uh wait where is my
uh
global highlight
mod
hey somehow it's not on so anyway so so
uh here's what uh what we are going to
do so i'm you know i write a lot html
tutorials and a lot about keyboards
you can see uh
my keyboard blog and let me show you one
page okay so you go to software software
how to and there is all you want to know
about windows keyboard shortcuts how do
you create them you know how do you
create a key to launch app
uh and so on so here is all about
windows keyboards uh tutorial different
software you can use which one are they
so for example here is a list of all
windows keys
keyboard shortcuts microsoft windows
that involves the windows key so here's
at least all of them
and here's a
list of most useful keyboard shortcuts
on windows and here's power
microsoft power tool is very useful tool
over windows and auto hard keys is
extremely useful tool for windows
uh let's set the magnifi
magnification to
uh
in a browser so i don't have to do it
for each page
uh let's see home
zoom
okay
so
now
yeah so
so i have so i i write a lot
uh
html tutorials for keyboard shortcuts so
you if you go back then there's also one
for linux linux is far more complex lots
of keyboard shortcuts
and you can see i have to write a lot of
these notations for example on this page
control s
let's open that file and search for swap
ping
so you can see
there it is the
control s
you know that's marked up this way you
know kbd and
so
i have to write a lot of that so how do
i do so i for example control s i type
this okay cs
okay and i press a key
you can see it become control s and i
press it again it becomes
that but however the s part needs a um
kbd
markup so let's do that
so you see
uh okay that's wrong so uh so that's why
so this is what we are going to do i
need to fix this
yeah so i need to fix this
what i want is this
okay so i i already have i already have
the command for example let me show you
the command
um
describe key press the key and here is a
command xlr html keyboard shortcut
markup and jump to the source code you
can see
this code began like 15 years ago
and
but it was never satisfactory to me but
however it's 98
good
uh but in the past few years i screwed
it up i made some changes and uh
you know and uh
right now it doesn't so
it doesn't work so well so that is why
today we are going to write this command
from scratch to turn
a simple key strokes into a
into a html markup for keyboard so it
shows nice here
so you can so here's my linux keyboard
keybinding tutorials and there's also
one for mac you know all the things you
need to know so check them out go read
them search for xrd keyboard blog and in
the software how to section you can see
so there's windows linux mac and emacs
e-max is the most expensive keyboard
keybinding uh emax key overview
uh how do you classify you know which
which command use control key which
command uses the meta key the old which
one uses you know
control c control h what's the
difference and when do you use control
and oh together so that's about emacs
lots of
articles about
20 or 30
and also all you need to know about
defining keys in index so it's all
discussed here
and such as what is meta key what is
super key what is
hyper key
so anyway so that's my tutorial about um
keyboard shortcuts so today we are going
to write a
fantastic cortez
thank you
don't change my days
what does that mean change my the unix
change mod
so okay so today we're gonna write the
emaclist coding live plus tutorial on
how to write a command to to uh to
automatically do the markup
okay so so let's go back
keyboard block close that go back here
close that show this in browser
fantastic back to emacs close it reopen
it show in browser
okay
so
so first of all you need a syntax you
know i decided i'm going to adopt the
emacs key binding syntax
as the most as the shortcut you know for
example when you want shift
c hold down shift and press c you can
just say s dash c instead of s-h-i-f-t
you know typing the whole thing plus you
know so
so this syntax is the input syntax and
this is basically based on e-max syntax
so you know if you don't know emacs let
me show you a
um
okay so let's show you um let's go to
okay so you can see here is my personal
uh key binding
uh and and you can see
there is uh do we see them here you
don't see much control oh here
uh but you but anyway you see this one
c
r that means hold down control and press
r and so this is emacs
this
syntax
okay so
my command is going to be based on emac
this syntax but so let me explain so s
capital s is shift capital c is control
capital a is old
old old key
but however emacs
syntax doesn't have windows key so i'm
just going to create my own so capital w
will
stand for
windows key
capital o will be option key on the mac
and
and capital m is part of emacs that's
meta key
so when you have capital c dash c that
means control c okay so that's the input
syntax i'm going to based on and here is
a bunch of text
test code i'm you know once we have the
command we're going to test on this
input
so i just put my cursor here somewhere
here and press the key it becomes nicely
marked up
okay so let's begin the coding okay
so
so coding so so okay so so yeah so let's
begin coding
let's begin
uh let's go down here let's start a emac
list code and pop it out so we have a
leave my list code
so but before we do that let's look at
my existing code so
describe
key
let me jump to it
yeah
describe key
then i press the key to call
the site html keyboard shortcut markup
then
jump to the source code so here is my
existing code for doing this
so we probably
you know we can use lots of these okay
let's just copy it
let's um
base it on
based on this okay
so here is
html emax to windows keyboard notation
that's not the one we want we want the
name to be this okay
so let's
this is going to be our code uh hold on
a second
so html keyboard shortcut mockup so
that's a command and optional arguments
begin and end that's the beginning and
end position and here's the
documentation change emacs key notation
to windows notation on selection or
current line
that's right
okay for example
yeah okay so i already got it documented
okay here wait here is not correct
so
this should be
okay let's let's fix it let's get the
documentation
correct okay
so let's get the documentation correct
uh
let me just quickly fix it fix it
okay and i need a keyboard
okay so copy that
that's correct
that's a
so
c dash h
f means control
plus h
um wait
ctrl first edge
show the pink window so you know what
i'm doing so ctrl plus edge
then
not plus f
so
uh
yeah
okay so
that is correct that is correct
that becomes that
so wa will become windows plus a that's
correct okay so here is the correct
documentation it's just
it
delete that we don't need it so here is
a proper documentation
double check one more time alt a
so f9 f8 means press f9
then press f8 okay and the special w for
windows and we have also other special
key
such as
capital o for option
key and the
capital
command we need the command key so let's
say yeah let's forget about the
documentation that let's let this be
how it is for now okay
this command will do most emacs syntax
correctly but not 100 correct especially
on notations like that
okay that's you know that
it's you know that's uh some details
let's uh don't worry about that for now
when coding
this code begin in our region beginning
and end positions okay uh yeah sure shut
up
so let's put today's state
okay
so here is the code
now the first thing to do okay
now i guess
you guys are maybe confused
thiago good morning disney's good
morning do you prefer c like syntax or
this syntax
so okay so now
what is our plan well
uh
let me let me tell you what's going on
okay so
you see
yeah let me begin this simply so you can
for those of you new to emac this coding
so you can understand so you see here is
our function so far we just have the
documentation you know here's the in
inline string documentation on what this
function does
this command and we start with
interactive okay that means this is a
command
when you have this interactive that
means you can press
meta x
or alt x
then
type the command name
e max will
call that function
so interactive so then let's declare a
variable
local variable okay so let local
uh
so the first thing we need to do is
to get the beginning position and end
position of the region we want the
command to act on
for example if if your uh
you know for example you can select that
and
then the command will act on that
uh text so you need the beginning
position and end position in the buffer
so how do you do that so here we have
let me show you this one by one okay so
you can see okay
let's type it okay so because
uh actually here's a code you know
here's the code but let's let's type it
out so
so you can understand better
so we declare a variable p1 that's
position one
uh and uh okay so it's pretty fine
p1 position
position one and the value will be
yeah
the value will be p1 is the variable and
the value will be if
okay if there is
begin
so begin is a parameter we declared here
so if this function is called by some
other lisp function you usually
you know you
may or may not
give a argument because it's optional
you see so if beginning is already
defined
then just return begin
okay otherwise
otherwise you want to say
otherwise otherwise if
if there is a region
region active p
then
you want to say region beginning
position
okay
if there's no region you want to say
beginning of line okay beginning of line
okay now pretty far you see you see what
are we doing
let me clear the code
you see we are
declaring a variable local variable p1
that is supposed to be the beginning
position
where you want the function to act on
now if there is a parameter it's already
defined you know if this function for
some reason you know
is calling emac this and
this argument
then
that position is whatever that argument
begin okay but however if beginning is
not defined
then we want to check if region is
active like selection meaning there's a
selection or not for example i can make
a selection
or i can make a selection you know
meaning if there's selection or not so
if there is a selection
then
the beginning position will be region
beginning which means the position of
the
beginning of the selection if there's no
selection
then
we want the command to act on the
beginning of the line okay
so that's how we get the first argument
p1
now for p2 it's basically the same thing
so actually so like i said before the
code is already here i'm just retyping
them and explaining them so you know
okay so for now let's just actually just
copy the whole thing
paste it here it's the same code okay
okay yeah so
okay let's let's make
them let's uh
let's make them let's add line breaks so
that the code is easier to understand
okay
okay so p1 and p2 two variables that's a
beginning and end position where this
function will act on
okay now we have that
now you just say
okay what's the next uh thing i want to
do
so basically now you got a string okay
so let's see
okay i don't want to use that so you see
this is my old code
uh and it's using uh kind of find and
replace algorithm so my old code what it
does you can see the old code here okay
so
this this code what it does is that
first of all you know you determine the
beginning and end position then
it does a find and replace string so
excel replace pairs region so whenever
you
found this string prior replace it by
page up
and so on and then
you know whenever you see this string
right
you replace it by a right arrow
and then this part is interesting this
you know this part is calling sub
replace regular expression pairs region
uh and whenever you find you know c dash
something one character replace it by
c
dash um oh yeah
well
it's a little bit
complex to explain anyway so this is my
old algorithm basically find and replace
so you just take the input string and do
some find replace
so let me show you okay so for example
this this um
this command let's let me show you okay
copy it so for example
s uh s
dash c right
s sheet
s dash c
so now i'm gonna call the command meta x
xr html emax to windows keyboard
notation wait
oh yeah
uh
emacs to windows keyboard notation
what
emacs windows keyboard notation ah
that's right so
let's try it here so i'm gonna call the
command
xsa html emax to windows keyboard
notation okay
do it
you see
that s becomes shift
okay that's what the command do
okay so but we don't want that algorithm
so let's do something else let's remove
that so
now here's our code again
so now we got the beginning and end
position
what to do next okay
now remember this is what it should be
you know
this thing on the left will become the
thing on the right
okay
so now we got the input stream
input stream so
so first of all
you want to split the string by space
so space is kind of
you know separate
yeah you split the string by spy space
then
then you split the string by
hyphen
that's right then you go through you
once you split the string
then you go through each item you know
once you split the string each element
it becomes a list
so
you go through each element for each
element
you
make the
find and replace so you replace your
capital c
single letter capital c by
by this
you know by by this marker
that's right okay so first of all let's
focus on a simpler problem you know
this input for example let's make this
um let's make this
easier so you can
clearly see the input
okay
and
actually i don't want the angle brackets
[Music]
okay so actually
okay so
yeah so let's add that let's work on
something simple first
cases like this
uh
let's just make uh work on this single
example actually this should be meta
okay
and there should be a a
and this should be alt
okay let's let's work on this
these three simple examples first okay
let our code just work on these simple
examples so we're gonna split the string
so so now
now let's declare another variable
let's say input text
what
input
okay
now the value of the input is
sub
string
substring no properties okay
then
from
position p1
to position p2
okay
that will return a string
of the region of the p1 and p2 and let's
put a asterisk here
meaning that so let
star
means
the variable declared before
their value will be available
for the next variable so here
we are declaring a input variable and
the value of this input variable depends
on the
the value p1 and p2 we declared before
so in that case you need use you you
need to use let star okay
okay so that's the
that's the local variable part now here
is the body of the the the main body of
the code
so now we just need to work on input
stream so
split string
we want to split the input string
and we want to split by a
separator that will be dash okay
and emit noise
meaning that
uh okay so if you split by dash yeah
that's
uh amino so
what happens when you have like c dash
dash you know that's
that's an interesting thing the issue we
are dealing with here so what happens
when you have c dash dash you see
normally that will become
you know something like control plus
dash where dash is just a key
but however if we are going to
use split string
here
then
in this case our code will be incorrect
so immediately we are running into
issues
you know if you use split string
here
and split on dash then
then the code will be incorrect so
so the proper solution
is
yeah this is painful
let's just ignore the special case okay
ignore this edge case
let it be incorrect okay
let's comment this out so we can see
okay so yeah let's ignore the
special case
so amid noise let's
say
uh
true you know we
you know we are assuming that dash dash
never happens you know there's no
consecutive it's consecutive dash okay
let's just assume that okay now we split
the string
now we need to declare another variable
for these
uh result
temp list okay something like temp list
okay
so set
temp list
to
be the result of split string
okay
so now what you got is
for example
a list
like that okay
then
then what you do is you want to go
through each
one of them
you won't go through each one of them
and do a replay stream okay
so you want to go through you want to
loop through at least enumerate at least
you want to go through each element
so
and each element is a string for example
this capital c
you want to go through them
and then you want to replace
that string
by
by by by something like this okay
for example let's
okay so this will become that okay
so
let
let me write this
so you can easier to understand
okay and other examples other examples
for example
m should be
meta oh actually this should be control
c t r l
m should be meta uh
o should be option
okay and so on
well and there are also special cases so
then if you have
ssc shift okay
but if you have for example
end
then the result should be end and and
then home and so on and the page up
pgup
should be
page up
okay
so that's the kind of replacement we
want to go through we want to do
so remember for each string each element
in the string
we want to do these replacements
so how do you do that okay first of all
let's
do the loop through the list okay
map c
so this is how you do a loop
through a list
okay in emac list
okay so you want to map this function
lambda something
on this sequence and what is this
sequence the sequence gonna be temp list
okay
so you want to so for each element x
here's what you want to do body
okay
so for each element you want to uh
here's a body okay so but what's what's
the body going to be it's
okay the body is going to be
[Music]
finding replace okay
so you want to
find that replaced by that
okay so um
uh
find and replace am i doing okay
okay so i have to think
so for each string you want
for given a string
you want this kind of replacement to
happen okay and there's a lot more
there's a lot more you can see for
example here
uh
so you want them to happen and you
[Music]
you cannot simply do a find replace by a
string because
because for example
and so how do you do this you want to so
given this so given a string
the string may be arbitrary you know
many characters a sequence of characters
given a string
you want this particular replacement to
happen
okay
so
so uh you want this particular
replacement to happen
and you cannot do them sequentially
why because
oh my god this is getting more and more
complex
for example and let's say let's see we
also have a for alt right
so a will become old so what happens is
that
so
so if you cannot do these replacement
sequentially
because
uh
you know what what what what do i mean
c-t-r-l let's see
you cannot do them sequentially why not
well because
because if you have
let me find an example where
let me try to explain this
why you cannot do the find and replace
sequentially
well basically because once you replace
some string by some other string
and if you are doing them sequentially
you know if you are just going through
you know your list where you want to
find replays
but you already replace that
by that okay
so
so the new string
you know they have lots of new things
and when you
go through them sequentially
the new string may contain things you
want to replace
but that's not in the original
string
so i'm trying to come up with an example
so i can i can show explain this easily
so but so far
there's no example here
so let me see okay let me check
uh
insert down menu
okay let's see that you know this this
is a good example
so
one of the things we want to do is
whenever you see menu
replace it by
that okay so
let me show you this okay
so
if you have a string that contains the
word menu
then it will become
this right
with a capital m menu
now if you do the next replacement and
when you come when it comes down to here
you see that capital m
so capital m becomes meta
so that means
that means
uh
hold on a second that means
that means
this new stream will become
and
will become let me write it okay so
it'll become like that
you see it will become
like that so it's incorrect
so you cannot do them sequentially
[Music]
so what you have to do is actually
you know you can just do a find and
replace string
so what you
really should do what i should do
is to check if the string is equal to
this string
and if it is
do the replacement and that's it stop
there you know no replacement anymore
yeah that's that makes sense once you
find a match
once you find the match replace it and
stop stop the whole loop
that makes sense
okay so once you find
you know this this stream is becoming
boring i'm pretty sure
uh
comments and questions posted okay make
it more interesting
so once you find
a match okay once you find the match you
want to exit
you know you want to stop
is that correct
so you know we are doing live coding
thinking about algorithm
once you've found the match
what i mean
first of all
first of all you cannot even do just you
know you should not do find and replace
at all you should simply for example why
can why can't you just do find and
replace for example
for example these two lines
now if you are trying to do find and
replace okay if you are using a
technique of find and replace string
and if the input string is this thing
menu
then
suppose you are doing this replacement
first so it finds the m there
then becomes meta
so
so this will become kind of
let me explain here okay so
so if you have a string
menu
then
if our first
replacement is that
then it becomes
yeah it becomes that
it becomes that
which is incorrect
you know because m becomes meta and then
you have e and u so that becomes
incorrect
so you cannot just do a find and replace
for each element so instead
you want to check if the string matches
the hole
if the string is equal
to that exactly
then
replace it and once you you did the
replacement stop it
okay so that's that's the
that seems to be the correct algorithm
okay
uh let me just let me just code it then
um
comments and questions
say something okay so otherwise i'm just
gonna start to
do this for myself so i you know i need
to think
um
so let's look at my old code let's see
what my old code are doing
maybe i can get some inspiration so my
old code
there are two of them one is the
emax to windows keyboard notation
and the other one
[Music]
is html keyboard shortcut marker
so
so the first one this function
what it does is that it turns
the emax syntax to a
to a windows notation windows notation
such as you know
that
kind yeah
so you can see
it turns the emac syntax to the standard
windows kind of notation kind of
standard
uh notation for
for keyword shortcuts for windows
and you can see that
uh i have article on that let me yeah
let me just show you my articles then
so you see there is no universal syntax
or notation for keyboard shortcuts
how do i know because i have studied it
you know since 10 years ago
and i have
quite a few articles on that so let me
show you
so we are looking for so we are right
now we are talking about keyboard
notation is there a standard one
you might think they are but actually
not really
we have certain conventions and they are
each one of them are illogical i mean
there's inconsistencies
inconsistencies so let me show you okay
so you go to my keyboard blog then you
go to uh
keys and lay out key binding design
there it is this article
so it's all about keybinding design
and there one of the article is about
exam shorthand system let's see
uh keybinding design okay maybe it's not
here
how many keyboard shortcuts are there
why oh tab is no good okay desire v mod
activation key
so it's not here i don't think let's go
to key let's go to key so design let's
go to keys okay
so here is all the articles about
computer keyboard keys you know their
history
what they are used for
and
i want to go to the page where it says
notation there it is
so you have three articles here
okay
let me show you each one of them
so this one is basically all the unicode
characters
for keyboard symbols i talked about this
before many times okay
you can see many funky symbols okay
you know it's a survey so you study all
the keyboard out there mac keyboards
windows keyboard laptop keyboards
you know then you know you make a
summary so that's what this article is
about keyboard symbols
and this article is
what we want okay keyboard shortcut
notations
and what's this article this article is
uh
you know the keyboard symbol or the
label used for the enter key
so you can see a variety of variations
so this is pretty standard with a
longish
arrow a return arrow kind of
and you have
you know this is a variation
and
then you have this
outline
online
uh
left turn
arrow
then you have this you know
different keyboard uses different
enter key symbols enter key logo graph
okay so that's what this article is
about
but the article we want is this one
keyboard shortcut notations you know we
are trying to find if there's a standard
notation
or syntax notation usually means for
human consumption syntax usually means
it's
designed for computer consumption so we
have talked about emax
you know keyboard notations we have seen
some of that
uh syntax you know emac syntax for keys
so anyway this article is a survey it's
i'm trying to find the standard
notations for keyboard
and you can see you know i'm using
microsoft windows platform and see how
they indicate shortcuts
okay typically
you know using the plus sign to indicate
key combination
and then there are many details for
example escape you know usually it's esc
but it should be should it be
capitalized
the first letter or should the whole
thing be capitalized or is just uh you
know whole thing is lowercase you know
the many variations
and you can already see an inconsistency
here
you see normally look at the control
0 you know control 0 is for
zoom to the standard uh you know no no
magnification no shrink you know
standard zoom
you know like i can do it here
control plus
or control minus shrink right
is magnified actually control equal sign
you see or i can press ctrl 0
to go to the neutral
you know no no magnification you see
normally the
notation is you have the control key
then plus sign
indicate indicating combination then
then a key
zero okay
but now if you look at zoom in and zoom
out
shortcuts you see
there is a
it's it's it's
it's using a different notation because
you no longer see the plus sign in the
middle even though there are key
combinations you see
so
so this is my survey
survey of the windows notation you know
this is the most common notation because
windows is the most popular operating
system
and you can see there's this consistency
inconsistency and there's also for
example the
con the zoom in
key
you know it's funky because you see it
says control space plus
but it actually means
holding down control then
pressing the equal sign you don't even
press the plus sign you press the equal
sign
why because
so it's fairly complex why because
how do you explain this one because
y is a shortcut for zoom in control
equal
but not control plus
you see
it was control plus
why do they use control plus because
control plus
because the plus and minus minus sign
they function as a contrast contrast you
know increase and decrease you know plus
minus increase and decrease therefore
the keyboard shortcuts for zooming and
zoom out they use the plus and minus key
okay
but however
the plus key
you cannot press a key directly to
represent plus usually it's a control
control
equal
then you get a plus
so that makes the key
cumbersome
you see
ideally
you want control minus and control plus
for zoom out and zoom in
but because of
convenience purposes
you actually
can just press ctrl equal
for the zoom in you don't have to
press ctrl
shift equal to get a plus you just press
ctrl equal
so that's one thing but then when it
comes to shortcuts
you know they
they
create a inconsistency they don't use
the plus sign for to indicate
combination anymore you know they
directly just say a plus
and even that is incorrect you should
use an equal sign so this so in this
particular example
for the zoom in
shortcut key notation
there are
kind of three different inconsistencies
open together you know for various
reasons for convenience for for notation
ambiguity reasons for you know for
several reasons you know it's fairly
complex
so
so that's a
example of you know the complexities the
issue about shortcuts notation okay and
that's one of the example this is from
this is the windows convention which is
the most popular convention
okay and there's another issue other
issues for example typically you if you
look at the keyboard shortcuts let me
show you one okay
so
for example i'm on firefox let's show
the menu
you see
you see that ctrl shift edge uh let me
show you some some
some something okay for example manage
bookmarks
ctrl shift o
uh let's let's use not this one let's
see this one ctrl d for bookmark
current tab
okay ctrl d that's universal that works
on firefox
works on google chrome
works on basically all browsers on
windows
ctrl d
to bookmark the current
tab okay
now you notice that d there it's capital
d
it's not lowercase d it's capital d
but however
the keyboard shortcut
is not actually using the capital d key
it's actually just the lowercase d key
so there's another complexity and
inconsistency here because
if you are a martian i mean if you are a
logic machine if you are a machine you
see that control plus d capital d
you would think that means
you hold down control then you press the
capital d key
now on keyboard you there's no direct
capital d key you have to press shift d
so the total full keyboard shortcut for
for for this current tab
bookmark current tab is
ctrl shift d
but however it is not it's just ctrl d
you see so why do they use capital d
you know why do they do do this in
consistency
they use capital d instead of just
lowercase d and this happens all across
any other shortcuts notation you see on
windows for example you see control c
they use a capital c
instead of lowercase c you know some of
them you can it's more obvious control a
is capital a not lowercase a why they
use capital letters it creates you know
it's not intuitive because capital a
involves the shift key but actually it
is not
well the reason is that
so it drags so this whole thing drags
back to the keyboard history keyboard
notation you know drag back track drag
us back to
100 years ago or even a thousand years
ago
yeah depending on how deep you want to
dive into
so it drags you back to the
history
the original history
of capital letters why are capital
letters invented in the first place how
did they became to be
and it also
drags you back to if you really want to
research this this issue
about why is it named capital and that's
kind of strange you know uppercase
uppercase versus lowercase first of all
you have different names you know for
the uppercase you have you can call it
capital letters or you can call it
uppercase
letters or sometimes it's
uh big case you know
so anyway
so
let me
tell you why it's capital case
okay for the
shortcut notation on windows at least
it's capital because
because in general capital letters
is more unambiguous than lowercase
letters
you know and capital letters is more
easily recognizable for each letter
now if you have a sentence then
lowercase is much easier to read
but for a
for a particular specific one single
letter
capital case is easier to read
and easier to recognize and less
ambiguous
why because for example the letter l
you know
when it's lower case
it looks like one or it looks like you
know it may be one or l you don't you
don't know which one
unless you have particular found you
know it's hard to tell so but when it's
capital case
you don't have this problem usually
because i because l is you know
it's
so it's less ambiguous that is why that
is the reason
the keyboard shortcut notation
on windows they they we use capital
letters okay
so you can see we have gone through many
of the complexities
and inconsistencies of the keyboard
shortcut notation at least on windows
you know so we talked about the zoom in
and zoom out shortcut key notation on
windows of giant inconsistency
involving several things involving the
plus sign involving the shift sign
involving the
you know avoiding the standard notation
where plus means a combination
and we also talked about
the
you know the capital letter versus
lowercase letter and the shift
complexity
you know this is quite a detailed issue
because
you know you might say okay
okay so now
you know for example let's let's show
that again
for example you know
select or
you know okay we use capital letters
because it's
less ambiguous okay no big deal no big
deal why why are you making a big deal
out of it well
the the problem is you see
then you got other issues then when you
started to have a shortcut
that involves some symbol
you know such as the add sign
or a number you know let's say um
well the sign for example or the order
exclamation
or you know many
uh dollar sign for example
then you have the problem
you know in that case
you have to say shift
um you know in that case it introduces
more ambiguities
because
because in these cases usually you have
to use the shift key
well not necessary you know you see
okay let me explain this okay
when you have a shortcut that involves
involves the
add
sign
how do you write the shortcut notation
what you know how do you
what is the notation for that shortcut
you know control add sign
there are two ways okay
one is
you just say
you just say control add okay that's how
you say control at
how do you type the add sign
well depending on your layout but
usually in american layout usually it's
a shift two okay shift number two
but if you are using
some other layout
you know then it's not shift two okay
it's not it's not shift two it may be
it's shift three or something and and
moreover on some particular keyboard you
have the add sign directory so you so
there's no shift key involved
so
the problem here is is
if you have a shortcut
of control holding down control then
plus the add sign
which shortcut you know what what is the
notation for that that shortcut
it's a problem because
then you might say shift 2 or you might
just say add sign or you might say shift
add sign you see why do you say shift
assign because that makes it convenient
that in the you know this is most
intuitive
kind of you know that tells people
it's an ad sign but you have to press
shift for it because that usually that's
the case for american you know keywords
so this so these are the you know
complexities of the
capital letter you know whether it
should be capital case or lowercase
and that's not all so that's
one of the complexity then
then they're small okay
yeah so the the issue becomes
becomes
gets us into
what do you want the keyboard notation
to be
you know what like what's the original
purpose like
do you want to consider keyboard
notation keyboard shortcut as a
as something you type or some buttons
you press
you know depending on which philosophy
which kind of thinking you go then you
have different choices whether you
should use the shift key as part of the
notation or not okay
well vincent has a
you know
vincent disagree but you know look into
the
issue detail more you will see
then also then we have apple's key
notation you see on apple they
they don't use the plus sign at all
so they simply put keys adjacent to the
modifier key to indicate that you are
holding the modifier key okay and they
also
also they are found of using symbols for
example you see this space
you see this paste
they don't say
you know they don't say
command plus v
they simply draw that
symbol then v you know to indicate
holding down command key and press v so
apple has a
kind of their own notation
okay you might think okay this is
actually more intuitive not really
because then
you have a problem
then you started to have a problem
when
when you have a
key code sequence
that does not involve holding down a key
for example on windows you know
on windows i can press the old key down
you see i just press the old key
then
space
not here
okay let me yeah let me show you okay
yeah well okay
you know i press alt and left
and left my um don't i don't have to
hold it okay i press and release alt
then i press and release f
you see then i got this
panel then i can press
t
for tab okay
t you see let me try it again
alt
f t each one is separate press okay
alt f t
that gives me a new tab you see close
alt f t you see
so
so if you have this key sequence you
know let's call it key key sequence
instead of key chord you know if you
have this key sequence
on the mac
now if you are on on the mac and you
want to indicate a key sequence of that
how you gonna do it
you have a problem
because normally
if you just put these three keys names
together
that doesn't work because by the mac
notation convention that means you hold
you are holding down those modifiers
okay
so you see
the keyboard notation is kind of a
science by itself
uh so which one is better you know so
and
you know
okay that's about keyboard notation okay
and then then we have about
then then we have about syntax keyboard
syntax okay
where i showed several examples of
different
programming language or different
systems there are different keyboard
syntax
uh let's open some let's let me show you
okay very extremely
complex there's no standard
you know
um
let me open a few of them so let me show
you
so e max as you know here is if you are
looking at emacs you know here is the
emax key
keyboard syntax okay
for example if you want to say the
return key
it's represented by ret you know
kind of this is also
another syntax for return that involves
anyway
so you are looking at the emacs keyboard
syntax okay
then let's see
then here you are looking at
mac os 10
key syntax okay
so for example they use these symbols to
ever represent
the modifier key
so for example a dollar sign represents
a shift key
you know a tier dot sign represents the
option key
and the add sign represents the command
key okay so this is the keyboard syntax
used by mac os 10
at this part of their system you know
you
mac allows you to define your own key
bindings you know you can read this
article and you
can you can learn how to okay so that's
a
mac os tense keybinding key syntax okay
now let's look at linux linux
x11
keyboard syntax okay they have a
different way
uh for example uh
you know the linux way involves the scan
code then key code and key sim okay
scan code is a code
that your keyboard hardware sends to the
operating system
so scan code the concept of scan code
came from the keyboard okay and it's you
it's kind of universal kind of
so scan code exists on the mac on
windows on linux
everywhere that's uh you know that that
that's the code the keyboard sends to
the operating system so that's scan code
so on linux then you also have key code
and key sim
key code is basically
the unix x11's own system okay
then key sim is key code is a code it's
a number okay
they created their own system
uh for a number to represent a
particular key
then they also have what's called key
sim
which basically is a name or string to
represent a particular key so you can
see some of the x11 code here
so you got you know key code then you
got key sim here on the right side
so that's
that's another different syntax to
represent key keys okay so that's x11
linux and unix
then you have
auto hard key okay auto hard key is a
key
is a
key binding tool for windows
they have their own
you know syntax for example auth is the
exclamation sign
shift is the first sign and so on
you know so you are looking at their
code
and then you have
emacs key syntax okay we went through
this before but here's another article
explaining all the very complex details
emacs key syntax is not
consistent neither
and
actually emacs key syntax there's a lot
of variations
because of 40 years or 50 years of e-max
history so you have quite a few
variations
okay
so
then you have
okay let's okay
let's forget about this one so anyway
so you have
you know so let's go back to what we
were talking about we were talking about
keyboard shortcut notations very simple
idea you know keyboard shortcut
notations and keyboard syntax
key syntax very simple idea
but
you know there is no universal standard
notation for it and there is no
universal standard syntax for it neither
so what's the difference between
notation and syntax well notation is
usually typically something you write
down for humans to read
and when you talk about syntax it's
usually something you write down you
code for programs to read
in either case
in either case there is no universal
notation for them
that's a problem and actually and for
each example each syntax or notation
each platform each operating system or
each application
their system actually often are
inconsistent for example we have talked
about many inconsistencies in windows
key
notation and we i have mentioned many
inconsistencies in the e max
notation
okay so so
yeah so the for the simple problem we
don't have a universal notational system
okay so let's
so now we are back to
coding
uh problem you know i probably already
talked for one hour
maybe that's it for today how many here
are actually
you know want me to continue to finish
coding
coding our function
uh
yeah i kind of i digressed over because
i'm i'm stuck in the middle of coding
this then i started to digress into the
notation and syntax issue
i hope that's uh
kind of useful you know interesting
information
you know the thing i want to tell the
story
i want to tell about this
like like if you read hacker news if you
are a typical programmer you read hacker
news you read reddit or you read
whatever was there before you know
slashdot for the past 20 or 30 years
uh you will not see people talk about
these
much you know because for example some
of you are in the key
you know do it yourself
uh
do it yourself keyboard communities or
some of you are in the emacs communities
or some of you are in the vim community
you know if you are emacs you know as
you know
or maybe in the x11 you know windows
tidy managers you know community the
linux community
you know and you will see
the key binding issue turn up over you
in fact you'll talk about it day and
night oh this key binding is best that
is you know you should cap caps locks
should be controlled or whatever
all these people all these people emacs
veeam unix
window managers linux
and do-it-yourself keyboard communities
there's hundreds of articles they have
written about
but that's the thing about
my peculiarities okay my idiosyncrasy
there are thousands you know in the past
20 30 years articles written about these
phonetics
you know veeam emacs each one they're
gonna tell you what about key binding
you will not find one you will not find
one article that discuss that discuss
that takes a deep dive into
the issue
where we talked about for the past hour
that is there is no universal
keyboard notation
and there is no universal key key
binding syntax
and and of
of the existing ones they always they
all have lots of inconsistencies
okay that's that's uh one of the point i
want to make
thank you coffee on me that was a
beautiful rent
fantastic oh god i got one confirmation
thank you fantastic
yeah so okay so that's kind of you know
that's why you know i'm a bit you know
that's i'm explaining
my you know a lot of people say you know
sauce got weird articles
what's this guy you know about you write
about emacs it's weird you know you
don't see other places talking about it
there so
so i'm trying to give my perspective you
know it it's it's kind of one of my
common thing i do
you know a a look into a
look into the design
of a
keyboard shortcut notation or keybinding
syntax so far i have not you know
there's it doesn't exist
so if you are interested in this thing
you could you know you could start to
design one yourself you know it's gonna
take it's gonna take a while
so but
um yeah so
yeah anyway anyway so
i think maybe that's it for today or
should i continue to call it magnificent
uh yes
i think something went wrong with the
payment actually gotta go to bed oh no
okay
okay no problem
uh bye thank you thank you
okay so that's it i think that's it for
me
uh
let's see how long have i
been talking
let's see
4 30 yeah so we talked for
90 minutes already so
start a committee no i'm not gonna start
a committee you know committee is the
worst way
committee is the worst way to get things
done you know so you know so so we have
an issue of designing a universal
keyboard shortcut notation or a
universal key binding syntax for example
these are actually separate problems
now let me okay let me random talk about
this a little bit more
ideally
you you know as a nerd you you might
imagine you as an engineer you might
imagine
it's it might be possible to create a
syntax a keybinding syntax
you know a universal keybinding syntax
that can be used
by any application such that
it's also
human readable
intuitive so therefore you don't need
two different things you you don't need
a syntax and
then a separate thing or notation
you don't need it you can actually just
a have one single syntax
you know that way you don't need a extra
separate notation system
ideally
you know i i'm not sure
i'm thinking maybe it's possible
actually i think it's possible but
that's another issue you see that's
another that's another
issue to to think about
yeah you know i don't think it's
actually
doable you see
another issue is why why are there so
many because actually they have
different purposes why are there so many
syntax for example x11
you know we are looking at x11 you know
the unix x11s
syntax for keys
and we have looked into auto hotkeys
syntax you know and then we have emacs
syntax for keys
and we have apple syntax for keys let's
close this okay let's close irrelevant
articles
then we have apples you know
apple's
keyboard syntax why can't they use the
same thing well
historical reasons and you know
you know when x11 are around apple is
not around and auto hotkey is not around
so
and that's so that's one reason the
other reason is you know
for each one they have a different
purpose for example for apple they
choose this single symbol single symbol
to represent
modifiers
now first of all this is not going to be
intuitive
you know
if you ask mom and pop you know to read
to think that dollar sign means shift
key
she's going to be confused
you know and
and similarly for auto hard key
you know they also choose a single
symbol so that's that can be a
universal
it can be a notation first of all it can
be you know you can't replace the
keyboard shortcut notation
but as a syntax by itself
you know then
why don't apple for example apple and
autohotkey agree
you know
well because there are different
corporations you know that's why that's
why you have windows and mac and linux
you know why can't we just have one
operating system
you know so
and
different history different purposes
so this universal syntax idea is kind of
artificial okay
yeah so you know
i mentioned before me as a nerd as an
engineer of course i think about you
know you might think about why don't we
create a universal
key syntax and and or keyboard notation
well that's a good idea that's that idea
is similar to creating a universal
language you know universal
artificial language such as
esperanto and lojban okay
so from an engineer's point of view or
if you are a borg you think that's the
most efficient
but from a humanity point of view human
history human behavior human mindset
that's artificial you know that's
in other words that's inhuman
and it will not happen
and if you created it if you create it
not many people will use it because it
does not come out
it does not come up naturally because
you are artificially trying to think of
you know envision like today's google
and
animal engine you know you envision a
nortopia where we should you know let's
have a note notopia where peace we're
gonna have peace on earth and everyone
is gonna be using google you know
so
so in the same way
when we think about creating a universal
syntax for keyboard notation or
you know or key mining syntax
that's kind of artificial because
there is no need i mean the the
it's not like we need it usually
human creations
came out of need
you know for example
mac os you know why do they create
this notation well because they need it
apple wants to sell
their computers they want to make money
and they want their product to be better
than others so they want to have a
customizable
feature
for mac os
therefore they have to create this
this application this syntax this
programming language kind of to let
people do it
and
they choose the symbols how do they how
do they design the syntax well they
choose whatever that's best fit at the
moment so for apple you know
like apple users you know they are not
going to think about wait a minute this
is not universal you know they don't
care all they care is that they can
now create
their shortcuts in you know shortcut
their personal shortcuts
on the apple on the mac
and these symbols are short and easy to
type you know
and similarly similarly for you know x11
back then like 30 years ago 40 years ago
the x11 has their own system
similarly for all hockey
and similarly for emacs
uh where's my emacs emacs here let's
look at this page okay so here's a emacs
syntax example
so
each person you know each
company or organization created their
own
naturally because they need it for a
purpose you know emacs for example
richard storman he he has a vision he
wants to have a universe he he wants to
have an emacs for everyone so
you know
richard storman is not going to think oh
let's create let's use a universal
keybinding syntax so that apple and
microsoft can also
share and use this
yeah he's not thinking of that okay
that that completes my kind of
extra beta digression into this issue
um
okay i think that's it for today
you need key do you use programming
socks no i don't use programming socks
and i'm not a trans
and i'm not a gay
if you are gay or if you are trans or if
you like programming socks that's
fantastic for you but i'm not okay so no
need to hit on me
keyboard dystopia okay
so i think that's it for today uh
and as far as this program goes i need
to work offline and i use a lot to code
you know every every time you code
something
seemingly trivial but it's lots of
issues come up
okay great to see you guys in
fantastic i got money today uh
bye guys
i'm gonna shut down
shut down in five minutes
okay so yeah so rambo we begin with emac
this coding and we rambled okay so
no problem so let's ramble some more so
let's
copy the things we talked about and
paste
on my talk show page okay
copy switch back paste switch back
close copy back to emacs paste
back to browser
close
copy back to emax paste back close
copy back
paste back close
fantastic articles close
okay that's today's talk show and
let's make a link
okay
show in browser
that's the code okay that's the links
that's the themes articles we talked
about
let's move them up
so okay so let's just put here for now
okay
bye bye
luis bro hello luis
okay
close that
linux keyboard so for your guide okay
let's create key version consistency
okay
yeah that's it