good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of the pixar talk show
today we are going to do coding
javascript and wufang language
so uh how are you guys the dearly
beloved people from all over the world
good morning luis and uh
seth uh from
who is from brazil okay
so we are going to do javascript uh
let's begin let's begin fast okay video
check audio check and you are looking at
my keyboard this is kinesis advantage
two
red switches this is ultimate hacking
and this is uh
my mouse this logitech with a spin wheel
fantastic okay i talked about in the
past two or three videos
so uh let's begin quickly so uh you know
we gonna not waste time and start to
call javascript so let me tell you what
is it i'm going to do
so if you just go to so let's start a
browser let's uh
hold on a second let me turn this off
let's begin the browser
okay
sorry
uh you search for unicode arrow okay
search for unicode arrows and you can
see that one is mine no that's [ __ ]
some somebody
okay you want to click my link okay oh
[ __ ] these people copied my website
okay so this one unicode arrows sari
okay so you can see
here we have unicode arrows you move the
cursor there and we'll it will have a
popup showing the
character name and the code point the id
in decimal and the code point in
hexadecimal
so this is fantastic
and
and let's go to emoji
the millennial generations thing
emoji and i just added a feature
recently that allows you to uh
click on the show character info so
let's close this panel
there's a you know there's a new feature
so that when you move so you can your uh
if your mouse moves away from the panel
it won't disappear so you can actually
copy you know select and copy the
information or click close
so but i also added a feature such that
if you click show character info
then you can see all the
unicode name
for the character
and the
hexadecimal code point for the character
for all characters you can see
so this is um page down
let's
close that
page down you know so you can see all
the unicode character names this is
sometimes useful because sometimes you
want to search for
let's say
heart
you know so you know there is one
occurrence this is you know there's uh
multiple occurrences this is
a smiling face with heart shaped eyes
and then you have this smiling face with
smiling eyes and three hearts
and
then you have the smiling cat face with
heart shape
so you get so that's a useful feature so
this is hide character info show
character info hi character info or just
move your mouse to a emoji and it will
show
now another feature let me mention so at
the bottom of each of this page
you have
for uh unicode search so you can type
h e a
it will show as you type h-e-a-r
so
these are the unicode characters
whose name or contains the word
h-e-a-r-t
you know you can add a t so that removes
one
so these are the unicode characters
showing the heart you know has the word
hot in their name
okay so that is unicode uh and very
interesting and uh
then okay let me
since we are on this subject let's tell
you keep the comments coming okay i'm
going to um
answer every question if you have a
question specifically specifically for
me uh tag my name like add sardi
so let me mention some other features of
my unicode collection okay so this is uh
useful if you are working on unicode or
emoji or you if you want to if you are a
programmer then you want to go to the
bottom
unicode for programmers so you can have
a complete understanding all you need to
know essentially what is unicode so
unicode basics character set encoding
utf encode point what exactly are they
what is a character set what is a
encoding
encoding essentially is a
id a number okay for a character and
what is uh
character set what is the coding
encoding system you know what is utf-8
what is utf-16 and and all that
so
yeah so you can click on that so let's
copy that let's go back to talk show
showing browser back to emacs and and we
are in emacs and in the pink window you
can see all my command cores and uh
and the keystroke i'm using stuff like
keys and i'm using um
soft like keys and
emacs package and i'm using vora
keyboard okay for a keyboard layout so
let's also
go back unicode for programmers go back
then we have unicode stars click on
unicode emoji copy it back here
paste it
yeah this is something
showing browser so back to emacs
connect
connect the list showing browser so you
can see what we have talked about okay
so
yeah so let me demonstrate some of other
features okay uh
now you have seen the
unicode introduction for programmers a
tutorial
uh but let me also show you okay click
on back to unicode so this is now this
page is upside down so
you it's magnify
you can type anything here
and the upside down version
will show as
you type
okay that's a very interesting website
upside down so you can copy it and paste
it you know on twitter or whatever
upside down text
then there's a few more upside down
so click so copy the url let's pick
let's paste it here
um
okay this is annoying what is the result
is
okay let me okay
digression let me modify
the my emacs this code let me let me
explain what's going on okay so you see
so undo so you can magnify
uh global highlight line one okay so now
you can see this line this is a url i
want to make it into a list okay so i
press one key now watch the pink window
you can see the command name and the
keystroke so i press
two keys okay now it becomes
a link uh you know not just link bit but
also becomes a list so undo let's do it
again
press two keys then it becomes a
list with the link in it so if you show
in browser you can see
that is this one unicode uh
invert text
okay but there's a problem
so let's undo let's undo let me tell you
what is the problem uh where is it undo
undo undo
undo okay so here
so when we
when i make this into a list you'll
notice it jumps the whole frame to the
top you see let me try it again do it
you see it moves the whole thing to the
top i don't want that okay so
why does that happen because my code i
added a
print
that's
it's a quark of emac these so let's just
fix the code quickly so um so let me do
it okay so the command is this one
html lines to list and jump to the
source code so here is the function
not too many lines so what happened is
that so let's narrow to region okay
narrow to function so message
um
okay so
this happens in this function actually
excite tml any to link so
show the description of the inline
documentation of this function html any
two link and jump to the source code of
this function
and it is in this
function called that
there is some code that screw up that
made it jump so let's narrow to region
so we show the entire
function definition in
you know uh
in this buffer so now let's search for
search for message okay
okay it's actually some other function
because
you know that jump happened because
because i'm doing a message
okay so let me actually i want let's
just quickly fix it
yeah okay i'm not going to explain
because um
it's getting a bit complex so
copy that
go to
my agree file
and here is all my personal emacs
stuff
search
for html any to link pre-hook
okay search for all
emac these files okay now there's one
result this is uh from the package casa
find okay and this functions are fine
text so jump to it okay open it so here
is the hook
so
i added a hook of this function
site html link to transform
site html link transform so
describe function to show the inline doc
for that function
jump to the source code here is the
source code and you see here is a
message there is a tool message
link remove them okay that those are
causing a problem wherever
you have okay here's a technical detail
for you emac these coders whenever you
have an arrow to region in your emac
list code
and
during that code execution whenever you
have you print something like message
something
then it will cause the buffer to move
that's a problem so let's comment this
out
eval the function
close it save it save it close it close
it close it close it
close it
okay close it
now let's try again do it you see
fantastic undo you see here's the url i
want to linkify it and i also want to
make it a html list okay url
do it now it becomes a beast but
but the buffer you know doesn't
it doesn't shift
okay that's fixed showing browser
fantastic it's right here okay fantastic
okay that's the digression
to emac this let's go back okay go to
talk show yeah open it
uh actually net renamed you see there is
a underscore that's a arrow yeah so
digression to emac this again
you see
this link start talk show
if i press enter
it will open the file
and now show in browser that is today's
talk show page go back to emacs close
this buffer now we are back to this link
talk show link now you notice there's an
underscore there we don't want that so
we what we need to do is to rename the
file without the underscore
so normally what you do is you open the
file you go to direct
hide the unix information so this is the
file you can see there's an underscore
there and what what you can do
you can you can call
you can call this function uh
toggle read only mod then you can start
to change name change name okay
for example dd that or whatever
then press ctrl c ctrl c
that name is changed
open it
showing browser
you can see the url field that file name
has been changed okay that's the typical
way you change a file name in emacs
very useful okay now close that now we
are back in this link
now this link will no longer work
because we already changed the file name
you see if i press enter it says file
not not exist okay if i show in browser
that's this link click it
you know it doesn't work because we just
changed the name
okay now
let me let me do this quickly and change
the name back okay so
uh toggle read only
and delete that
okay do it you see that's done close it
now back in browser click on that it's
work it worked again so what we have
done
we have just done
the changing file names in emacs very
supremely efficient
okay with this a lot of digressions here
so
why two keyboards okay i'm gonna answer
answer that well if you watch my
past three videos you'll see
uh well the two key
okay so this keyboard is used as a macro
keypad marker so everything you know
switch browser i explained that many
times in my past videos so switch tab
switch tab switch to last window
open a new
uh
open a new tab for example uh wait this
one okay open a new tab
close it you know things like that
that's what so that's the ultimate
hacking keyboard i use it a as a
keyboard macro and
go to keyboard blog just search for xrd
keyboard bug and click on ergo keyboards
you can see my review of the kinesis
advantage 2
lots of photos
details detailed review and video review
that's kinesis advantage too
so back and the ultimate hacking
keyboard is this one fantastic okay so
go buy them for my amazon link
support me and if you you know like my
stuff donate okay
donate paypal patreon uh uh amazon gift
card and i have all links on the you
know yeah watch this video watch this
one or this this one keyboard guide you
can see
i go over the keyboards but not today
okay so the open last opened so let's ah
[ __ ] like you see that that one is uh
this marker is old f4 which close the
window so i want to reload relaunch the
bavardi browser this button okay
uh where can i see it
yeah you can see so this button okay you
can barely see it
let's see if i can adjust it okay press
it
my body is back okay now hide this uh
obs
okay so what i want to uh yeah so we
digress a little bit so let me get back
so we have just done the changing file
names in emacs so what is this page
keyboard page okay
back to emacs copy the file path close
it open saudi talk show
paste it here
linkify and make a list show in browser
there it is that's the things we talked
about if actually
i want to link to
this one so
so people can actually see it okay
i mean the the video okay so close that
back to switch close that
emoji okay let's
go back to emoji so
digression about how to change file
names in emacs but we haven't done yet
okay so i mean there's more so close
this so back to this thing okay let me
talk about this
uh
so before
we
open the file go to diet hide the unix
part then we change the file name by
calling toggle um the command is let me
show you the name
the command is styled toggle read only
once you call that you can you can just
edit find replace whatever and press a
button all file names will be changed
fantastic but now there's another more
efficient way more efficient
html mod so if you are in html mod
if you are a blogger
and if you are using emacs and if you
are using html mod which is a package
excel on my website just search it
search for it there's a more quick way
to change the file name
in in a link
you know without going to diet so for
example right now
on this file i can open it close it now
i want to rename it without underscore
so what i do i just press three keys
okay
so you can see at the bottom
it says
you know new name okay so i just edit it
here
do it
done okay now you can see underscore is
gone
press enter to open it
showing browser fantastic
close it
now this
now this is the previous you know with
underscore if you reload that no longer
exists correct close it
okay
so that's digression so uh so okay so
let's put it uh put we
so
combine the list combine the list
let's put what we talked about here okay
so
so the command name is
okay and this one in fact there is a url
so if you want the code you can actually
grab it here or you can just get
html mod okay
this is my mod let's turn on javascript
okay so this is a kind of demo of size
html mod you can buy it it's open source
but you have to pay me okay
so copy that back to emacs
close that
and actually reopen that okay so anyway
so
we are we paste the link
and
describe function
that
and this
and go to the website copy the url back
to emacs
close this window
expand unsplit
then
enter paste the url then linkify link
them
okay they jumped again but anyway so
link it
remove the you know remove the extra url
there do it
combine the lines
combine the lines show in browser
okay that's the size html mod
and
rename file source html rename source
file path okay we
we went over several different things
now let's get back to unicode
good morning andrew
uh and okay so and good good morning
alan i'll get back to the comments in a
bit so let me continue
talking about
unicode okay
uh unicode and javascript so this you
know
we demonstrated copy it did we have the
yeah we have an invert text so go back
let me show you some others so this one
is gothic okay this is called
uh math font okay
so
again you can just type
anything here okay you'll convert them
to this
uh unicode gothic font and you can
change them to
double stroke font magnify
or math bold
math italic
math script
math mono
math bono is not interesting now this is
the unicode characters they are mono
spaced but however it's not
it's actually not changing font it's
just a
unicode characters so you can copy this
copy it
and
go to twitter
the drama stuff and paste it there you
can see
that's how you do that
without you know changing font and stuff
okay close that do i want to save
stupid twitter close that
okay so that's math font
demonstration okay so
click that copy the url
back to emacs let's let's paste them
here so
so we have a record of what we talked
about
go back now let me show you now this is
spectacular this is roon
this is spec
s-p-c
t-a-c-u-l-a-r
this is unicode roon okay now this is uh
white people's obsession they love these
room characters so you have you there
are several versions of you roon is the
kind of the ancestor of the english
writing system okay
so you get you have elder roon or
germanic okay you know something like
that
so um
so you have several versions in history
elder
june
anglo-saxon
tolkien you know lord of the rings of
it's a fantasy the obsession of many
nerds tokyo
you know that that load of the rings i
didn't like it that much rather i like
the
you know the modern one game of the
thrones i like that
that uh tv series series very much but
the tokens
you know the lord of the rings the
movies i didn't like it
so you have several versions of room
medieval okay so that's unicode room
copy the url back to emacs
paste it here back to unicode
back to previous page and now you have
the
cricut unicode braille okay
select all
unicode braille
so this is a
poor man
cryptograph
okay
so and you can also copy that
copy that go back here select go paste
it and
and convert it back to english so you
can use this as a cryptograph
among friends
okay unicode braille copy the url back
to emacs paste it here linkify and make
them into a list and delete the
redundant ul
and compact the lines shown in browser
so that is what we have talked about
today so far fantastic now
to the kind of the main topic what i
wanted to do
is to
let's say let's go to food
okay let's go to let's go to something
interesting food in
vehicles okay food
now i want to so you can see
okay let me explain what's going on
first okay show character info high
character info let me explain
what is it
that we uh
okay here is a great example unicode
cultural and religious symbols okay so
you have the christians cross of
diverse varieties now these are all
greek cross which is used as a logo of
the red cross
you know the the kind of uh
medical emergency you know red cross
then you have various you know uh greek
cross you have uh
black cross on shield you know
your you know varieties you know many of
these uh cross symbols are ancient you
know two thousand two thousand years ago
so then then you have the latin cross
which is very classic okay then you have
other you know this um
permanent you know this this is a
christian's symbol you know orthodox
typical symbol for
lower rank feast okay
i'm not familiar with it but alan
probably you know
about these symbols you study
um orthodox
christian symbols and you know so there
are many diverse oh and this one the
dramatic the american the white people's
obsession this cross okay and there's
there is this
this cross variety okay
let's not talk about that okay and uh
some of them are not shown because you
know the
you know the people you know they they
haven't developed the
font yet even though it's already two
years old but they just
kind of you know this is kind of
implicit implicit refusal to create the
funds for these characters now this deep
history of these characters this this
character let me tell you
when did it origin you know to the
typical american or you know you might
say oh that's a 1940s
you know a certain country in europe
wrong
this is chinese character asian
africa the origin is actually indian
okay two more than two thousand years
old okay
uh so i like these symbols okay that's
not whatever you think it is you [ __ ]
[ __ ]
you you know the the the telling people
what to do okay this is
buddhist symbol
in india and china okay and in fact this
this particular you can see the unicode
name for this character is
cjk idiograph okay it's not whatever you
know the name you know i don't even want
to
uh say the name because today's society
you know the social justice scan
in america especially in particular are
so [ __ ] up like you know they're gonna
censor you
if you talk about these things okay so
that's another digression but let's go
back so christian cross there are many
varieties and this one this is not
exactly a cross this is anch okay it's a
origin is egyptian okay it's egyptian
symbol
uh
you know you can look up wikipedia it
has uh some details okay
so they you know so many of these are
like cultural and religious symbols
okay now that's a bit digression and
also another digression is you see
this this
series of characters you know look
prosperity they are not sure because
they are not sure because there is no
fund why
racism
racism by the social justice factors
these are chinese characters but why why
didn't they just just like these okay
just like these
you have the characters you know you
have the characters in microsoft font
right now in my microsoft platform right
microsoft windows you have all these
but these why are they
how come you don't have fun
well i would i would say
it's kind of an implicit resistance okay
uh so they don't you know they don't
create fun for it and by the way related
let me show you another interesting
interesting
thing
censorship okay so we have many ancient
uh you know human writing systems
then one of the oldest
three thousand or four thousand years
old is egyptian okay let me show you
so egyptian
heliograph where is it
so you have tamil you have tibetan
tibetan is by the way spectacular it's
also
it's also very political the on these
topics for
many reasons okay so let me show you the
egyptian
so asian okay so this
helio glyph cuneiform kuniform is the
first
not the first okay good well
kuniform is even before hideo graph okay
so let me just show you show you okay
this spectacular spectacular unicorn
stuff ancient human writing systems
humanity history of human animals okay
this is cuneiform
uh then we have
linear b
again no font okay
then we have phoenician phonician is
kind of we
say it is the grand daddy the grand
grand grand you know the the first the
the we say that it's the root of the
english alphabet so you have phoenician
then you have the greek then you have
you know latin you know then you have
you know uh others but they all
originated from
they are orange
this phonation
is actually originated from the egyptian
heliograph
heliograph okay
uh and okay so asian characters so then
you have ruin is not that old ruin is
like uh
year one thousand year eight hundred
something somewhere around there but the
oldest that are the heliogram helioglyph
cuneiform linear b okay these three
linear b and no font by the way on the
mac you have the font okay
now google is telling me uh install
google translate no you cannot translate
it
linear b and linear a
okay so that's how they look i have a
image
so but what about the censorship okay so
let me show you so let's go back to the
egyptian helioglyph so this is uh
fantastic okay egyptian heliograph
so let's look
look okay let me just show you some
random
pages okay heliograph
you know they have cows their bulls in
different different postures
you know kneading and cut you know car
with a young
sucking
circling circling you know that's called
circling you marine gen idiots
which is sucking on tits okay
uh egyptian you know cow sucking uh you
know and deer and whatever meow horse
okay so
uh these are egyptian and what is this
one
so in monkey baboon so you have baboon
and you have um you know uh lions or um
you know big cats
panther
uh and you know lots of things
asian and
what is this i don't know
then you have paper clips
the microsoft clipper
hieroglyph okay right that's how you
pronounce it hieroglyph yeah not not he
you know not
hero hieroglyph okay so then then you
have you know birds you have uh you know
owls you have um
uh word vulture vulture eagle
uh you know
and you have queens
fascinating fascinating okay then you
have you know
uh whatever
sparrows or whatever duck you know geese
goose
uh
what is this
so eat you know snake eat and cobra you
know and frog pepe the frog there it is
in turtle
turtle and crocodile okay
very in and fly it you know flies in the
wasp
and beast and centipede
and whatever that that's a beetle must
be you know that's something like that
okay so very interesting then okay
there's a lot like you know there's uh
a thousand or two i i forgot
then you have you see
you have [ __ ] you have penis there
that's part of the egyptian helio glyph
okay so you have lots of thumbs those
are tardis like one one thumb two thumbs
three thumbs four thumbs
then five six seven you know then you
have this you know
what is that
a penis with a tower over it
so
so but look look okay so let's search
for let's let's see where are they so
that's the image okay
but microsoft windows they censored it
you know microsoft windows so you have
fonts all these things but
but those penises are censored they
don't have a they don't have a character
in the font
where is it let me let me show you okay
stop showing that
so go up go up we want to look for the
fingers part okay where is the fingers
lots of fingers
there
okay
where's the [ __ ]
there you see that square square square
that's
censorship
they censor
human animals you know uh history that's
what going on that's what is happening
censorship big story in america
by the christians by the christians
before and now by the social justice
warriors you know we are witnessing the
change you know the ebb and flow of
history you know what
you know what
you know they censor these things but
meanwhile the pornography is all over
town all over over you have cam girls
you know
only fans you know it's over but they
have to they they need to censor this
these these asian symbols
and also including google
let me tell you my sad story that you
know i'm trying to make a few
cents few dollars via google ads and
google keeps spamming me because
that's a digression but shall we talk
should i talk about it maybe a little
bit okay so
search for sally architectural beauties
okay now you see these are photos from
my website so just click on that link
you can see
so you can see
this one
now you you can see if you know what it
is you know this is ancient okay so this
is uh 1 000 years ago
indian
you know this is very
by the way this is very famous very
popular because it's shocking it's a
it's shocking to the white people you
know the white people
so this 1000 years ago in india you know
kind of buddhist stuff you know would
you know related to buddhism they have
these asian sculptures and they have you
know they have all these things
sculpture
um
[Music]
you know
as a temple
so i i have this this page and then
google says
your page is illegal you know we cannot
allow you to have these with google ads
they're gonna ban the entire website
well i was
dying of hunger
you know so this is one of the incident
there's more okay there's more but i'm
not going to um
you know but you get you you get the
idea you know what happened
to me so i have actually a page if you
i have actually
you know i'm a observer of humanity
of human animals so i write down i tried
to or the incident that occurred
occurred
as a record of history
at least you know some of my personal
history so you can see
if you search for
saudi google ban
okay there it is the article google
adsense span on asian asian goddesses
okay click on that
so you can see this is my documentation
of what happened google you know i have
this page and it looks like that
and google sends sends me an email
saying
uh hello this email is to alert you that
one of your website is not currently in
compliance
compliance with our adsense program
policies
and as a result ad serving has been
disabled on your website
that is me
trying to back
a quarter or two to survive
and
google the all benevolent empire banned
me for it
and you cannot you know there's nothing
you can do they don't they don't give a
[ __ ] you know
so that's uh
that's more digression okay today i
don't think we are going we are going to
talk about wufang language so because we
already
talked for 50 40 minutes yeah
and so we let's just talk about unicode
and uh
and uh related stuff
okay so so that is that we copy the url
and that is that back to emacs paste it
here show the pink window please
and close this one
back to the browser just move the mouse
no click no all tab crap
if you watch my past three videos you'll
see
i
discussed that efficiency of operating
the keyboard the computer in detail
so this tempo
back to
architectural beauties so i have a
website that because i
what i love architectures you know many
cathedrals these are huge
monuments of humanity you know doesn't
matter you are religious or not it's a
fact they are you know
huge part of human history and even
today and you know of course
lots of wars
millions of people dead
has been because of it religion okay and
even today iraq war for example
so uh so let me just post uh you know uh
post of some of the uh yeah so so this
arch you know so why do i you know i
like
why do i like architecture
well mostly because architecture is a
manifestation of geometry
you can see and i love geometry geometry
is part of mathematics i love
mathematics
so um
so you can see architecture and you know
these are all
giant cathedrals and they are the best
known for the most beautiful grand
architectures built in you know
thousands of years ago it
take few hundred years to build them
a
huge part you know the cathedral
itself is a huge part of western's
history okay like giant you know you you
could you could even say the western
history is mostly cathedrals okay in
short it's you know christianity
so and my opinion is that doesn't matter
you believe in uh christianity or not
it's part of the history okay if you are
american especially
you know i'm a chinese-american but for
many of you guys are white american
that's part of your history okay you
cannot deny it
uh and you know so then we are seeing
other architectures we have modern ones
so this is a mod this one for example
it's a modern church
lotus temple okay it's a temple it's
well so so it's you know different
religion they have different names for
their buildings of worship so when it's
when if it's buddhism you call it temple
so for example we have cathedral we have
church we have you know
you know uh
well i i don't know much about
christianity so
many of you
know but anyway cathedral temple uh
church you know
mosque that's islam mosque
this is many varieties actually
different names and actually that ties
us back to unicode so let me show you a
few
so but wait wait a second
did we already have the heliograph now
so
so let me show you a few for example
in emoji which is millennial generations
thing so if we go to places
you can see
they
added
you know so this one is is church
church
then you have
shinto shrine no that's japanese that's
japanese version of buddhism
originated from india then it migrated
to china and become the main religion
china i think
infused with chinese philosophy
so today when we speak of buddhism it's
mostly china
you know indian
or although buddhism originated from
india but however india india they have
their own really you know other
religions which is more predominant in
india so
so as far from my perspective as far as
i know as a chinese i grew up in taiwan
so buddhism is mostly
china you know
you know
religion
indian you know indian they have the
they you know they are multi you know
they their religion have multi gods you
know for example you are familiar with
the elephant
uh god you know
that's that's mostly the indian
uh main religions
you know the guy with the elephant
head
so shinto you know shinto and
zen
you know the word zen that those are the
variety of buddhism in japan which came
from china okay
then you so you have most mosque okay i
don't know much about
mosque and synagogue okay mosque is
islam's
building for worship
you call it
mosque then synagogue i be so it's
jewish it's a judaism i guess
okay then there's kaba you know so i
don't know exactly what's the difference
between mosque and kaaba
if you know type it
so kaaba is also islam some you know uh
variation yeah i don't really know
then you have hindu temple exactly so
hindu has their unique style of their uh
religious worship buildings you know
for example the most famous is that
majaat taj mahal or something okay so
it looks like that
then you have a generic symbol so you
know this uh emoji you know the
emoji the history of emoji the very
first one oh this doesn't exist okay
okay i can tell you
the only one that emoji originated from
emoticon pictures in japan japan's cell
phone so in the beginning there's
nothing none of these you know
multi-cultural [ __ ]
you know japanese they are very
you know according to the social justice
[ __ ] they are they are racist okay
japan
china or just about every country
by the social justice ideas they are all
racists
but anyway so japan begin emoji okay so
there's only this one shinto shrine why
because it's practical that's what
people want you know japanese people
they need they want they need you know
they are not going to be oh we but but
but
but we need to be multicultural so they
we we how come how dare you you missed
you you know the you missed the
the
the other religions you know so this
also you know so that's
you know japan okay japan china asia in
general they they don't know what the
[ __ ] is you know
the american social justice
things are different culture so if you
really want to be inclusive
of you know of different cultures you
need to take you need to respect
chinese
me
my culture japanese culture which
don't give a [ __ ] about the
western white concept of multicultural
you know [ __ ]
so that is my culture okay if you want
my respect my culture it's you know we
don't have these notions that's your
notion about this you know many of the
western notions
that's your notion okay
stop infringing our culture
you know i get
angry on these things because it's
pretty big you know so um
and then and then the millennial
generation they don't know nothing you
know there's the social justice people
then there's the chan people the
the right
wing the right wing
all this all this is china's fault
china censorship
we need democracy
okay so these are the you know symbols
okay emoji okay copy that back to emacs
so we
we went into politics which
i didn't really want to because
uh you know lots of uh
blood blow boiling you know that's what
when it comes to this kind of thing okay
so wait
so there's an error somewhere
showing browser there it is we have a
record of what we talked about today
all the links so we
digressed to emoji we came we talked we
were talking about censorship of the
penis you know this video is probably
gonna gonna be banned by google saying
oh you cannot monetize it because it's
not suitable
so then we have architecture do we have
a link
okay we we do uh
let's let's put it here okay
so we i talked for one hour we are about
to shut down but we haven't got to the
main topic of javascript coding yet
we'll get into it just in a moment so
architecture i love it because geometry
they they are a manifestation of
geometry in real world you know that's
geometry for example this we are seeing
another church
so what is this one cathedral of
cathedral of vassar okay basilar is a um
brazil i think it's brazilian sitting in
brazil
by the way i have
i used to have links to wikipedia and to
google maps and all the mainstream
website now today it's organ we you know
removed them
so if you want to look at google maps
you copy the link so here is
here is the cathedral of basilia what is
this
expert
esplanata
those
ministerials
you know that's spanish okay so brazil
indeed shrink shrink so
shrink
shrink shrink
shrink shrink brazil now how do you
actually act did i even pronounce the
city correctly brasilia
okay so in brazil in portuguese it's
brasilia
that's a city or
yeah
okay that's a
cathedral okay i believe cathedral is
the name for
for catholics right the the name the
the the building of worship for
catholics in particular you don't call
it
um
what's the
uh or the name anyway so there it is
you know modern modern
you know um these temples you know
temples and temples and you know
buildings of worship they are
particularly artful they are particular
they exhibit
you know they are particularly
uh glorious beautiful okay uh just you
know
so this is uh
you know a modern cathedral of brazil
uh
of the catholics i suppose
and and this one in particular it's
modeled you know the shape of the
building is modeled on polyhedra okay do
i have a link here no okay but
but but
okay copy the link let's let's copy the
link and post it here
so we want to
okay then we
let me show you
sally
hyperboloid
so you can see those buildings okay i
don't want wikipedia i want xrd
page okay this is my page okay go back
here and
make a record of it
okay that's
that cathedral this one is modeled on
this mathematical surface called
hyperboloid of one sheet and this
surface is very interesting has very
interesting mathematical properties
because this surface is made of just
lines straight lines okay so you can see
okay so actually let's shrink
so you can see it's made of string
straight lines depending on how slanted
are the lines you have different shapes
so
very interesting i talked about this
before and we did actually we used the
wufang language which i was going to
planning to do today to you know we did
this video i used language this code
yeah let's show it let's copy it
so we talk all over the place so wufang
language paste it here okay that's kind
of big
okay so
shrink
shrink shrink okay so this code
so this code evaluate there you see
there you see the um
then you can rotate it let's magnify
okay
so you can see
uh different versions of these
hyperboloid of one sheet
okay so
so now let's go back to
yeah so that's
that is the model
of this cathedral
and there there's quite a few there's a
lot of buildings modeled with these um
these things so let me play this video
very and somewhat counter intuitive how
is it possible for a surface that's made
of single line to be curved you see this
surface if you look at this picture you
see obviously it's very curved but
however
every point on the surface
i mean the entire surface is made of
straight lines that's a that's an
interesting property of this surface
this surface is made of straight lines
however it's not
you know it's not straight it's curved
you know so that's you know so this this
video shows the
counter-intuitive part of it
okay and there's lots of buildings or
towers
made out of this uh idea
okay so that's about that
okay so now close that back to so i was
talking about why am i interested in
architecture you know so there's so many
interesting and beautiful ones for
example this one in particular
this
is called arc
art deco style
this style is a very you know very
beautiful and grand i love it however
it's not
based on geometry like many of the
cathedrals
or
you know like many of the cathedrals are
the the beauty of
cathedrals is primarily
of a geometric nature
okay actually i failed to show you some
of the islamic
uh
uh their mosque you know
they have their own style and also
geometry okay so the beauty of
cathedrals and the mosque
primarily
is due to the geometry elements
but here
the arc
art deco style is not just it's not
geometry but rather it's about kind of
the
it's less of a geometry for example here
is another art deco okay this one is in
usa you know you have this kind of uh
angel hero character this is in syracuse
new york
beautiful okay arc deco and this another
one beautiful fantastic this is a also
in usa ohio
cleveland ohio
fantastic beautiful art art deco
also includes the u.s entire state
building okay which is one of the first
or was it the first
skyscraper okay architecture that's why
i love it geometry
okay so i showed some of these um
so let's
i want to copy
uh yeah actually i want
let me let me just talk random okay so
let's now copy that paste it
copy that
paste it
okay that already copied so okay some of
these architectures
um and uh there are so so much so many
more okay so many more action pictures
so this this one
you know this this one is now abandoned
okay this in uh eastern europe is it uh
burgers bulgaria okay
then there is um
there is you know it's
a mixture of modern you know the alien
xenomorph you know that's what they call
ada and this alien movie
uh with asian cathedral goggle concept
so they made a goggle out of this
thing
uh
okay so that's that's some of the
interesting things okay the architecture
now let's go back to
unicode okay
so unicode we're gonna finish in five
minutes so okay we already talked for
one hour any questions
that's it for me okay i think that's it
for today uh
i'm i was i was going to
actually code some javascript
uh
about
i want to change font okay the reason i
mentioned okay let's go back
let's see if i can still do it and we
have time
it should be easy though but let's go
back to
yeah culture
uh
so is it cross shapes box keyboard
common punctuation
culture okay this page
copy it back to emacs
and do we have it
let's see
no we don't so make a link
and
and put it
back here somewhere so
okay
so
now i want to talk about you see some of
these characters are rendered as emoji
while others
are not why is that
well that happened because the unix the
unicode idiocy the unicode consortium
made a mistake about
and 2009-2000 also
so that when you have a character
sometimes it uh it appears as an emoji
but sometimes not okay
so the the reason for that is this
article here
uh
where unicode for emoji versus emoticon
symbol becomes emoji this article okay
so for example if you are writing about
mathematics you know
you you have this character you know
so here's the example you see
so you let me magnify okay
so you can see
this character
you know it's a plane
you know a symbol but over but however
here is shown it's a show it's showing
like an emoji
so if you are a mathematician you know
when unicode became it was you know is
invented and became popular you know you
think it's that's fantastic now you can
write you know you can write mathematics
with unicode for example let's go to
arrows
uh
let me go to errors or close that
shrink shrink
so when you if you are a mathematician
you know you have all these symbols you
know infinity so it's fantastic and you
can also have all these arrows you know
double headed arrow or whatever uh which
is very often used in math for example
this arrow and
and let me show you some of the arrows
commonly used in mathematics for this
for example this one left right triangle
headed arrow you know so they point both
ways
uh
so you are writing math you know you are
a mathematician you write
then all of a sudden you know after two
years it becomes this [ __ ]
it becomes an emoji like
in your mathematical formulas it becomes
this idiotic thing and same thing
happens when you write for example when
you i you know i write about keyboard
keyboard symbols on keyboard so you know
the multimedia keys you know stop play
pause next
mute you know volume up then
you know you write a documentation about
which key to press then
after two years it becomes this
this us this speak speaker um
image to [ __ ] [ __ ] up your document
so why how so why is that that's because
unicode unicode one day decided they
they are going to have merged emoji with
symbols so that's what happens it's a
problem it's a mistake okay even the
unicode consortium
you know the people who created unicode
they admit
you know it's it's a consensus it's a
mistake okay
that's what happens that so that is why
okay so that is this page is this is the
reason why
hold on a second let me add this here so
this is the reason why
this is the reason why some of these
symbols
are shown as emoji while others not it's
become incongruent you know it's become
inconsistent [ __ ]
that's what that's why that's what
happens so what is the solution i mean
when so if you have this for example
this latin cross symbol
but you don't want it to be shown as
emoji you you want it to be just like
you know a
plane lateral symbol what do you have to
do you have to actually use you know
change the font you want to use the
symbol font
but if you want this character to be
shown as an emoji then you have to use
the emoji font so
i was so that's the issue you know and
it's complex because then
a character ceases to become a character
for example if you type
english letters you know you
you don't say you know oh but i want
this c to be emoji like some of these
characters become emoji [ __ ] up your
writing [ __ ] up the human animals
writing system
you know
[ __ ] it up the [ __ ] unicorns
consortium idiocy you know and the
millennial generation [ __ ] they
they did this okay the
millennial generation they don't know
what they what what they're doing
so we have this situation and today it's
worse because on
on twitter on discord everywhere if you
haven't joined this code yet join saudi
discord
they you know they instead of emoji they
actually show them as a pictures so it
ceases to be characters
it [ __ ] up the foundation the original
purpose of unicode
the purpose of unicode is that they have
you know they provide a way
for any human animals to
write any character in human history any
language okay in a consistent way
but now
when emoji is introduced
why they include emoji in unicode
because
japanese you know japanese you know
teenagers they use their phone you know
so they have you know they want to you
know it's fun you know it's part of
human what we do you know we want to you
know girls especially among girls they
want the heart you know they
they want you know sometimes the kids
are hot and you know they like that or
smiley right
it's common need okay so japan japanese
their phone they also it's a commercial
competition so they created emoji
evolved from emoticon which also happens
in usa as well for example back in
around year 2000 you have the yahoo
instant messenger you have microsoft
instant messenger you know
so emote you know emoji came from emoji
cons okay so let me show you another
article
so you know
here i explain what is emoticon so
emoticon is you know smiley frown wink
again big history and controversy
because when emoticon was created in
1980s 1970s you know some many of the
nuts resist
it you know they in their opinion these
nerds or today's you know python priests
you know the unix philosophy many of
these people you know this
these programmers they think they say no
no you cannot do that you need to write
proper english
a lot of people back then that's the
case just like today among you many
nerds oh you need to use linux oh you
need to open source the [ __ ] idiots
okay come and go you know there's
uh
thy guys you know that's what they say
you know the the thinking comes in go so
back then when emoticon was first
introduced many people among the
programming community in particular the
hacker types the elite hacker types you
know typically those are you know back
then it's a c or these programmers you
know that hardcore compiler right you
know these type unix and unix users bash
you know this type of people they will
say no no no you you know stop using
emoticons you don't know you need to
learn proper english
that's a mentality very common
even throughout 1990s okay throughout
1990s
so that's emoticon okay that's origin
you know of emoji gun look up wikipedia
okay just search for emoticon you'll
find a full detailed history which i
think is pretty good
because i read them you know i read
wikipedia
you know
since 2002 and encyclopedia before that
every day every day fit several hours
and in fact one of my video talk show
uh
in two months or three months ago
there's an entire talk show about
encyclopedia okay
so i've read them you know emojicon you
know the you know you know
and so emoticon you can look up history
of emoticon then
it gradually became
emoji why
because
because emojicon is kind of a hack you
know right back then you don't have
unicode you know you have you know you
so you
you hack you know you you you know you
type a colon in that red parenthesis if
you look at this way it looks like
smiling you know that's why they are
called smiley
so it's a hack
you know hack means you don't have a
proper solution but you make do you know
you
you know
you make do by the way there's also each
you know here is a a japanese style or
engineered from japan
you know they have their own uh emoticon
okay they don't use the western ones
this these are the white white people
yeah
western okay western
emoticon then in asia japan mostly
primarily you have a whole set of it and
also i also have a holocaust on that
okay so this you know
actually i don't yeah actually i do yeah
so these are some of actually this is a
mixture of unicode uh
a asia japanese style
unicode emoji kong okay but these are
using unicode
back then in 1990s there's no unicode
unicode began in 1990
1988 something like that but unico was
not popular until after year 2000.
so anyway so
so i'm kind of going over so i wanted to
say i'm telling you about the history of
emoticon and emoji okay so in the
beginning in the west you have emoji
kong and
and in japan i think the west start
first emoticon japan created their own
version of emoticon okay it's all based
on ascii characters no unicode then
unicode became popular then emoticon
emoji began
to appear why because emoticon is a hack
you know so
as technology progresses you know people
say when you're wait why don't we type a
actual
smiling face
image instead of this hack
so you know instead you know for example
the classic one
you can still see today you see this one
that is the first ever
emoticon
it came from emoji
okay so emoji is there first
so this one
so
people are thinking you know the
programmers you know who create websites
and stuff
chat rooms you know uh yeah it begin in
the
instant message
uh
applications such as yahoo
instant message aol instant message you
know microsoft instant message then
skype those are dead today
except skype but the skype is dead too
going good you know dying
today's you know you got discord uh and
others anyway so emoticon
then it became emoji because people
thought you know why not just
replace those hack with a picture then
unicode became popular the unicode
people are thinking why don't we create
a standardized
character that represent
emoticon
why not so now we have you know instead
of each
application create their own icon for
the smiley why don't we standardize it
so you know so we actually have a
character for these different smileys
that's a good idea this began
around 2006
okay
so the idea is to unify them to have a
standard way to have these characters
then
then the millennial generation happened
they [ __ ] up everything okay i haven't
begin even talking about the story yet
the millennial generation
why because
then then we then we got into then we
start to get into the skin color issue
okay uh happened around year 2010 2012
okay then then the skin colors then
then all the characters the people are
no longer looking like human animals
anymore because
very sad story all the people they don't
look like people anymore they look like
this fake doll
you know uh you know because and it
actually become part of the unicode
consortium's policy they say one of
their policy if you go
go research okay go research what i say
one of their policies not you know
because of the social justice movement
in usa
they say when you have a picture you
know when you have an emoji that is
that is representation of a human animal
they say you cannot have it to be
realistic you know it may it must it
must be very generic it doesn't actually
represent any actual person you know so
that's why
that's why today's version of uh emote
emoji doesn't matter on microsoft
windows or on apple
you see these
faces as cartoon face they don't
represent you know like
actual you know
uh human face
you know artificial and they also have a
rule that says you can have the color
of the of these
faces to be real you you need to use a
fake color that doesn't actually
actually look like a human animal why
because if you actually use a actual you
know skin color then then oh my god it's
racist racist because you forgot the
black people or the other the other
or the red skinned people or the yellow
skinned people oh my god it is racist so
so you need you must make them all fake
that's what happened to emoji so we have
all these
many uh made many of them become creepy
okay very creepy
so you know look at the santa claus you
know father of christmas santa claus
you know and and and very creepy you
know for even fantasy creatures you know
this
mage or wizard okay
this fairy do when you you know
cartoon so they they they make it into
like cartoon like
then you have elf okay does this
actually you know make you
you know f elf doesn't look like elf
mermaid doesn't look like you know the
traditional what people actually want to
have a mermaid character this doesn't
look you know mermaid is a
representation of the
attractiveness
of human female you know a fantasy
creature back in ancient two thousand
years ago greek mythology okay back in
greek um well it's a mixture of several
mythologies greek and
and northern europe okay it's a mixture
of several things but even back in the
greek mythology they have
uh
what's the origin of mermaid you know
anyway it's a mixture of things okay so
you so
and this genie genie is from
the origin of genie the fantasy creature
is of the origin
middle east okay that's the origin of
the genie you know i you know
because i know because i
saudi word english okay let's see
saudi.org okay you can let me tell you
where to find how do i know okay so you
click on wordy english which is
the view of
the duo of vocabulary the depth of
literature the question of style the
logic of linguistics the ears of english
and the cure by writing so all these
sections
a thousand articles about
about linguistics writing grammar
literature vocabulary those kind of
things
so we go here
literature classics and this one arabian
nights okay this is not not what you
think what it is as you know as you've
learned from disney okay
arabian night is not not what you think
it is okay this is the real arabian
nights okay let me show you a few photos
so you can see what is the actual
arabian nights
arabian nights is was written it's a
stories from middle east you know around
iran
persia okay uh from
from
year
800 or something okay year 800 okay this
is the true nature of arabian nights and
you can read them
in my blog in my you know
org
so arabian nights you know i have the
full article and annotated you know
annotated with javascript you see
you know so this version when you read
arabian nights you want to read the
version
by this guy
sir richard burton okay he's a great
scholar okay and alan or alan here about
part of the book
uh so you want to be this is a real
arabian night all these old by this guy
who's hussein had a way this is a modern
genuine authentic translation not the
disney you know disney
you know when you watch disney arabian
nights that's not that's not arabian
nights that's american
american story okay with a dog and with
a
girl that's an american story that's not
the arabian night but the real arabian
nights is what you see here
let me show you some of the
pictures so you can you you know that's
the real arabian nights
uh okay so then um and there is also
monsters you know huge monsters and
fantastic okay huge monsters and uh
you know um
and uh okay so
we were talking about this because genie
okay here is the genie okay there it is
here is a picture of the
kind of the you know
real genie you as you know you might say
not not not the
certainty not the emoji [ __ ] okay
we we are we were talking about arabian
nights because you know from emoji you
know so here is genie
genie came from middle east countries
that's their culture that's their
uh mythology okay uh and uh
you know
okay
then vampire is western thing mostly i
mean
in particular this one this now this is
this is a disrespect of chinese culture
because chinese culture we also have
vampire okay but not like this okay
nothing like this more like these but
however this one is zombie uh this you
know again western you know all these
are like western you know
western culture meanwhile they pretend
what they are doing these millennial
generations social justice people they
pretend they are doing justice
to
multiculturalism
uh
uh you know
so that's a story okay so that's why we
talking about arabian nights okay
i think that's it for today so back to
let's
um
you know i love this story so this is
here is another genie
so you know
illustration so this this is the first
story of arabian nights okay
and here is a genie okay
yeah
uh and there here's another rendition
you know of the imagination the
mythology the genie
okay uh and uh then then um we were why
are we talking about so let's go back
to history of emoji
uh
yeah there's more i want to say but
let's
call it a day that's it
so we shut down in
five minutes no more for sure so let me
read what you guys are saying
so bye guys if you like my stuff donate
donate okay that's what i'm here for
donate
to my patreon paypal and you know i have
links on my website
you can find it easily
and uh
you know the typical youtube crap you
know subscribe please subscribe [ __ ] and
please thumb up if you please thumb up
if you like it please thumbs down if you
otherwise so please do comment let me
know what you think oh please do please
let me know what you think i just talked
about this pregnant woman
the [ __ ] millennial generation in the
google empire you know this because they
what why are they doing that because
the youtubers do that because that's the
way to get you more viewers
and ultimately that's a way to get you
more money donation you know
donational ads you know
but why
but why can't they just ask for donation
why do they have to please subscribe
please hit on the bell you see that in
every youtube you know please this you
know please say
why because google google is behind all
this youtube and google is the money
machine google love love you youtubers
google says you know we are here to make
your life you know to make humanity to
help humanities to spread information so
that all of you can now can do youtube
you know can do live stream free
and we also we are we help you know you
as a creator we will help you so you can
run ads you know with our system
of course they take they take 50
of the money
and
so money that is the thing that that is
what's all this is happening money is
talking
so
and google have algorithms you know then
the thumbs up a thumb down then the
comments why
why they want you to comment because the
more common
drama you know the more comment on
youtube
every video
people see you know people usually like
to see what other people are saying
about a particular video
so
uh you know so
drama is the thing okay anyway that's it
that's it for today so
you know well if you like my stuff
donate and you know about the thumb of
you know yeah of course i like it too
but this because there's nothing i can
do if your youtube if you if
you are doing live stream on on twitch
or youtube anywhere if you don't get
much thumb up
you know you don't get you know your
video doesn't spread so what you know
there's nothing i can do i don't like i
despise these these google [ __ ]
like they're doing these things
nothing i can do
uh okay so that's it that's my that's my
stance about this youtube thing so
bye guys
um
i'm not sure what you mean why isn't
your website linked
in the description or do you do that
after live stream
oh yeah it's usually
you know so the question is for example
let's go to saudi youtube
okay so you can see this is my youtube
yeah go to it
okay stop
and
so this is my youtube you go to
click on that
so
lots of videos
uh you know you know i yeah watch my
videos okay talk i talk about wolfen
language coding in the past few and
other things
and keyboard and stuff by now i've been
doing youtube for like uh two two years
two or three
and they get better and better just like
everyone else and so the question is for
example for example let's click on
let's click on the one before
today we i did this two days ago
so
why don't i have a link in the
description to my website
i used to okay but now i started to not
to do that because
why do i do that
you know what so what's the purpose so
the purpose is
for one reason
so that people who watch my view to it's
convenient you know it's part of the
service you know i'm doing star talk
show so those people are interested in
star talk show they
you know they probably want also to see
my website because my website the
corresponding page has links to all
these relevant information i've written
right so you want a link so that's part
what
that's part of the purpose of the
youtube description
and also describe what what you talked
about you know what's this video about
us so
part of the purpose is a service to
you know what i'm doing what each
youtuber is doing now there's another
part the on the other big reason very
big reason for the youtube description
as they are used
is
money okay money is the answer like
amazon affiliate links you know i like
this keyboard why don't i put a amazon
feed affiliate
where you can you know people can click
and buy it and i get money why not why
not in amazon get money
amazon get a lot you know i got i i will
get a few dollars
so amazon affiliate links or patreon you
know if you like this video please you
know click on the patreon right there so
convenient for you
as a service to my youtubers so
convenient i just put a link to my
amazon paypal so you can just click it
so simple so simple
so that's the other
part of the reason of the youtube
description okay
commercial purposes
now
so um i started to not doing i don't you
know i started i'm not that
you know
well so what's the reason you know
there are several reasons i stopped
doing you know link to my website on
youtube
one
let me just ramble about some of the
reasons
one is that today
you know youtube google empire they
track everything so
so of course you put a link they don't
know
they already know they know already i
mean yeah
but i mean you put a link so they they
they you know they they can see that
it's connected to this page or that page
i don't want that i don't want that i
don't want to give google
some explicit you know education i mean
what's the point if you like my video
if you are really interested in what i'm
talking about you will go look for it
you don't need you don't need a
convenient link right there okay if you
are the type of person who is gonna
donate to me you already did it
you don't need a convenient link to my
amazon page or whatever patreon you
don't need you don't need it okay
you know it's possible maybe i have a
link then it induces some people to
click that not really okay that's a bad
thing okay i want people you know
it's a generally good thing
let people
do what they do okay so i don't need to
say please subscribe please oh please
you know donate those people you know
they see things think for themselves you
see it you truly like it or something
you will do it you don't need
the marketing okay that's that's the
thing marketing has become very bad
marketing especially in america you know
which is a very capital district
and also
i think that's a great idea you know
capitalism but however in usa there's a
lot of corruption so today you have all
these ads full of marketing and
packaging you know like unboxing like if
i don't if i'm going to review a
keyboard
i don't just review the keyboard i need
to do the unboxing of it
because the box becomes important you
know what they say
malenchen idiots
so marketing so i so i tried you know
that's that's not my style so
so for this kind of several reasons i
do not
you know take the time also it takes a
lot of time you know it you know takes
time to
put my links
add my links into the youtube
description
then if my some of my link changed or
something it sometimes
rarely it does happen
then
then it's
very painful to modify all your links in
the past because if you look at other
people's youtube you look at them 10
years ago all the links are broken you
know
anyway that's some of the reasons okay
that's it that's it bye guys bye bye bye
thank you guys for watching bye
is my
google okay so google
oh yeah so i need to
hit the end stream 11 concurrent viewers
fantastic thank you guys