good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our talk show there is so
much pain pain in my life
pain is Pena's how I survive
so today is May 15th 2019 how times pass
so fast and this talk show is partly a
record of humanity
it functions partly as my blog a record
of myself somewhere when one day I'm
gone from this world there is a you know
a record a live video Olivia a video of
the of it but what what is the purpose
of the video anyway I mean why do you
want to what do you want to I mean white
does anyone I mean what's the value me
for okay for individual persons it may
not matter that much but however but for
for Humanity on a whole there is certain
value because its history you know
that's the essence that's essentially
what it is that's because then you can
see what your grandparents or parents of
parents your ancestors you know like
what have they been doing you know what
has happened before before your time so
that is the purpose of the record and
for me I guess that's that's part of the
reason you know you know history is not
history is not like when you think of
history good morning Andrew and Julie
were you from are you from China or
Taiwan or USA you know when we think of
history we think of the you know like
the history we taught in school you know
the history of the world I mean like
history of United States history history
history of China Japan or you know
Europe or you know
Middle East or things like that that is
the grand picture of history but history
I mean that's the academic sense of
history and that's what we think of
history I mean you see but but what we
speaking you know history is just
anything that happened in the past
including your own history you know what
you did yesterday oh you know what did
your mom did yesterday that's history
but the reason when we think of history
we only you know we think of you know us
history you know the you know certain
big events you know World War two the
reason we have that conception of
history is just because oh oh
archaeology dinosaurs you know dinosaurs
or Egyptians pyramids you know the
reason we have no history is those
things it's because it's really because
you know you cannot really possibly
understand history because imagine there
are billions of people you know and
every day happens to these billions of
people and you your lifetime you already
have one lifetime you know you you
cannot possibly know you know you can
see that you cannot possibly know even
one single person's history you know not
to mention you have 2,000 you know 3,000
4,000 or actually you know millions of
years of human history so therefore when
you try to and also you know a lot of
history you know it like what what your
mom's did every day every hour in her
life you know
a lot of it is not interesting so we
when we study history you know we only
want to essentially end because of time
limitations we only want we will only
get the big elements you know big parts
but however also know that it's very
misleading and confusing the history we
know it even if you are historian I mean
you accept unless unless you are history
historian and you focus on specific part
of history like specific aspect of
history for example there are history of
sort you know sort so the sword sort has
sought that's how American pronounce it
sawdust in you know I'm eating bread
this is my okay so can I show it good
Moni Andrew so you are in Chinese
spawning Australia oh that's amazing
what I didn't know I have no idea how
many percentage of Chinese are bowing on
Australia is that something comparable
to us yeah actually I have no idea
what's a figure what's the statistics
leaving living in Australia what city is
it Perth because I know three people now
two or three people from Perth Australia
that that are watching my videos so so
I'm eating bread you know this is my
breakfast in oh well I guess right now
it's breakfast and I'm drinking milk
milk with honey in it honey is the
luxury honey is very expensive oh so you
are in Perth so it turns out Perth Perth
seems to be one of the big city in
Australia because it seems to be even
bigger than Sydney I mean in terms of
population is that true because so far
you know I've you know over the past few
years have known you know few people
from Australia you know my mostly my you
know
my blog readers or followers and they
are all from Perth yeah most oh yeah I
think all of them are from Perth I know
this girl she is extremely beautiful and
she's I think she is half Chinese she
one day she contacted me I hope she is
watching you know I miss her so I think
Perth is smaller than Sydney and mobile
those two are the bigger ones oh I see
so you know Australia they have lots of
weird spiders like like insects and it's
a true I'm American I don't know nothing
and so anyway so I'm eating my bread and
I was talking about history you know
like my talk show is kind of going down
I mean going down in the sense like like
I think less people watching something
like that
I have 837 actually I should pop breath
my teeth because this says I need to
breath my teeth every time I finish
eating because because I'm a TV or game
getting so bad you know I lost my upper
molar and I haven't seen a doctor you
know dentist for 15 years you know like
I'm going away anytime
okay so the idea that Australia has lots
of dangerous animals is true but not a
problem unless you live in the brook in
a bush
the ocean is where more dangerous Oh
ocean like the man-of-war of something
like that you know the jellyfish so what
we gonna talk about it talk about so I
don't know like you know I watched my
channel you know because they are less I
think there are less people watching but
I kind of know why the reason that
happens is because me you know because
you know I've been you know I like I big
I have been not focused and when I talk
I was kind of dragging on and on about
you know being repetitive and basically
it just becomes boring like nobody wants
to watch you know let's say you have
tweaks let's say you want to express an
idea then you talk about it for maybe
five minutes ten minutes but I was like
talking talking about it for like 40
minutes in our in 90 minutes and often
repetitive then and also often kind of
aimless and goalless so in general
general the quality is going down I mean
like people get tired of watching you
you know all the time so that's
happening that's that is what happening
to my channel
you know like today so but but the
situation the situation is what you
cannot do like most people most people
when they have a youtube channel okay
there they have a call you know their
goal is often typically to make money
you know they a lot of them today you
know me you know they are gamers you
know their goal is to you know play
games they have a goal you know their
subject is scam or review of games some
people review keyboards of course and
some people a lot of them today are
doing politics you know especially the
anti social justice you know a lot of
them doing politics so they talk about
things and you get viewers you know some
of them they review news you know what's
happening today so and in almost all of
them they they are interest in did I
mean they have the goal making money you
know they want to so it's a performance
it's actually work it's a it's like a
show you know it's dedicated so you know
I hi you know hi welcome to Startalk
show and today I'm going to talk about
something interesting of interest to
your audience you know so they are very
they have a call usually and in a lot
girls like they are you know I was
studying YouTube there are tons of teen
girls they they are gossip you know the
teen girls they are just they just
gossip all day day at night like this
you know like I look at them they are
like there are many billions of videos
about this girl gossip you know they
follow celebrities you know who is
married to whom who's got you know who's
who's dating with what boyfriend and
their and what what's the latest bikini
you know ladies shoes or the makeup over
the oh my god the makeup industry is
like 40 billions I was looking up few
times more than pong okay
the makeup industry the girls and it's
like okay fine if you need to do makeup
to make up but then they have like I
mean they just the the girls the idiots
idiots okay they you know suppose I mean
to make up okay just you know you buy
things make up things and that would be
it you know you just okay maybe it's an
art but that's not too much of a not you
but the girls they they have they have
all they
new brands of makeup stuff like you know
if they have to review it
yeah just like nerds but it's different
okay it's different from what the Nerds
you know the guy nerds things the girls
they they spend all this money so it's
it's you know it's a huge billion you
know forty something like forty billion
dollar market and they they they sell to
this thing women and they the almost
like a scam okay
really it's but that's what they want
you know be you want to believe what you
want you know it's like so I learned you
know the girls we gossip about sex who's
you know which superstar is pregnant you
know so it's incredible you know it's
like you can actually see it if you just
go to a supermarket you pick up
Cosmopolitan magazine you're the
cosmopolitan by the way Andrew do you
speak Chinese
you know you go to a website like
cosmopolitan and you see this you know
there are things that's what girl talks
about everyday you know right so I have
seen this magazine since 1990s it's a
say same every issue you know for
example this issue
why does dress size defines how we feel
okay
why does dress size define how we feel
okay 2015 hair big word hair okay
cops cops whops pops and sharks
you know also there's this interesting
thing about you know if you have
interesting linguistics like me you know
you observe you know so we know it's you
know we nerds have a jargon you know in
computer in programming we have jargon
you know we have you know
object-oriented programming we have
patterns you know like pattern factory
patterns we have kiss you know keep it
simple stupid you know we have UNIX
philosophy we have a clock you have well
quirk and you have grab well great grip
is you know actually the name of the
tool but you know you have it like lots
of these jargons among programmers I
mean they are not jargons for example I
mean the slaves and you know kiss dry
okay do dries
do not repeat yourself you know dry you
know that's one of the fashionable
jargon in the past few years
okay so that you have jargons among
programmers basically among any
community you they kind of have the
jargons for example in the chemist
community you have you have lots of
jargons for example I was in second life
the second life virtual world for like
living in it for four years from 1919
from 2007 to 2011 something like that
okay
I lived in second Eiffel every day five
or eight hours ten hours a day every day
so I learned you know I was mixed in
with these gamer types usually very
young young you know and I was
40-something back then so I was 45 or so
but they are they are like teens or 20
or 20 is something and they are older
people as well but you know in second
life so there's the there's griefers
this law you know law is one of the most
popular you know jargon from gamers and
a lot of you know when you are in a
community you use those struggles every
day and people understand you it's kind
of like okay anyway in linguistics for
those if you study linguistics there is
basically you know there's a study
specialized in how jargons or lingos or
AG not a good you know used like you
know gangsters gangsters has their own
jargon but anyway back to the ghost of
dingos so they have joggers for example
these 2015 hair then he says chops
whops pops and checks I don't know what
they mean Benigno you know for the
fashionable girls you know what it means
oh you know I don't know if those
joggers are popular but you know some of
them are not very popular okay so back
to the looking at the cosmopolitan so
you say so
are you having copy and paste sex are
you having copy and paste sex oh my god
what a question say bye-bye to that
bedroom what bedroom what oh that's what
then claw talk talks just King Bieber
Crowe talks Justin Bieber sex and doing
the dishes
then says when the other woman when the
other woman is his mum okay girl things
and mom then it says how do you fit a
whoops okay now it's bigger good how do
you fit a giraffe in a fridge
beware the tricky new job interview
questions okay that seems a good good
one oh then the lingerie lingerie edit
357 pies to make you feel fab know that
look at that word fat that's
abbreviation for fabulous but they so
girl these so this you know writings are
Girl Talk you know I haven't just
fascinated by it you know because you
know every time why go to a supermarket
when I check out and you have these
bunch of gossip magazines you know on a
checkout so you wait in line and I
suppose women you know look at it and
they'll buy it so I just you know every
time I was you know yeah so I check out
I I spare I got just throws and stare at
these these things and you look at and
you see the girls magazines they are all
girls I mean this is their pong
basically so cosmopolitan it's go back
to for cosmopolitan so you have you know
issue every month or something and it's
like that for you know as far as I know
for 20 years
you know since 1990s 30 years I guess so
every every issue is like sex and you
know and that can actually it's and this
is not just Cosmopolitan this this is
true for essentially vast majority of
women's magazines okay
I mean the other ones like Vogue or
women I think there's something in any
way style or whatever they they are not
as savvy
okay as cosmopolitan Cosmopolitan
magazine is like they are very focused
on sex everything is about sex and all
these magazines by the way they are
written they are written by women you
know essentially the reason they are
like that you know these you know sex
hair and stuff it's like that it's
because that's what women want that's
what sells you know that's what women
want okay it's not like you know today
it's funny you know today's social
justice you know they say oh patriarchy
oh because men it's because men created
different beauty standards men you know
they they want to cut off glorify
obesity you know super fat but then you
look at these women's magazines that's
it's it's not me that's and you know you
can you can look at the things so from
so many aspects you you look at the
celebrities you know in Hollywood their
performance is singing dancing they are
practically half naked you know and the
main you know you they want to blame
them you know you you can begin by not
wearing makeup you know you you know
it's like he's nobody is supposing you
you know you can begin by not making
makeup and stop dressing sexy but
because that's not what they want you
know this happened this what is the
reason
okay the reason all this happens is
because it's because there's a
fundamental sexual drive that's a nature
you know because we want to have sex men
you know because you know men wants to
have sex because the more sex you have
the more baby you know the higher
chances of number of children you will
have so you just go out and just [ __ ]
any girl you have you know you have a
greater chance of have you know a lot
babies the
and for those guys who do not like to
you know just have sex you know they die
out basically you have less baby
eventually you have no baby if you don't
like sex you die out that's you know
that's basically the nature of life you
know if you are the type of guy if you
are a monk or nun that your belief you
know is that you you know a person
should never have sex you extinct you
know that's that's that's just what
happens so dope but on the other hand
those people who [ __ ] around the guys
who [ __ ] around all the time you have
more babies and in turn your babies
those who ever [ __ ] around all the time
who have more with more babies and
therefore you know therefore men you
know always like to [ __ ] but for women
it's a little bit different okay because
women they can only have one children
every like 12 months you know because
they get pregnant so they it does them
no good to you know just [ __ ] like they
they can sleep sleep with 10 guys for a
year you know I mean they can sleep with
hundred guys they can sleep with a guy
every day a different guy every day but
after a year they only get one baby so
so for women that doesn't work that way
you know you so they don't want you know
they don't have they know after
generations they don't get to have the
desire to have you know just [ __ ] around
all the time because they you know it
doesn't pass on it doesn't increase
their chances of having more of their
children and what it does help is that
they want to find a guy who is worthy
you know for this one year they want to
you know pick up the you know the right
guy the strong guy the rich guy who can
provide them you know we can help them
because they have a baby in their tummy
and when the baby is born that you know
they have to feed the baby you know buy
milk of course so you have to
so if you have some resources that can
help you usually it's a dad you know
so that would be so that way you you the
chance of your baby growing up to become
a adult and have his or her own children
increases so for women you tend up to
they tend to become too you know they
want to pick the right guy
yeah but anyway so back to cosmopolitan
you know so that's so what is you know
so so that is the difference kind of the
difference that creates the sexual the
difference between sexual you know
preferences between men and women so
that's why they are different on the
other hand no no but now you go back to
look at the women's magazine the other
question is why are they like what way
are they talking about these hair and
you know things gossip all day it's
really because it's really because the
oh yeah that yeah that that's like a
poem for men for guys it's poem you know
you you look at women you know naked
girls you have you got this urge this
incredible urge you know when I was a
teen I masturbate every day I still
actually do okay that's actually true
for most guys okay if you don't you know
I don't know about you guys and it's not
something everyone wants to talk about
but that's you know you can tell you
know from your friends you can you know
it's just true you know every guys
masturbate every day yes especially if
you are a teen you do that multiple
times a day so often sometimes because
there's this urge you know this is this
incredible urge you need to you know it
you know it's like it's biological its
building but and and similarly for women
there is also
you know to mate you know mating I'll
have sex is kind of like it's really
truly just so fundamental because if you
don't have sex you you're raised going
extinct you know you wait you race you
know just don't see it's just cease to
exist anymore so for women they also
there is also a urge for sex but they
this urge does not take in a shape or
form of males like you know you just
want to have sex because women you know
first of all they can only have one baby
per year you know more sex than that
doesn't help you know doesn't do you
anything you have one guy you know what
you know what one one baby a year you
know you you pick that you know you
sleep a few times when baby just it max
so but but still you there's a very
strong urge to mate because also because
of biology you know women you have you
become pregnant you have baby in your
tummy and also God you know that's just
amazing okay that's a guy I don't you
know I don't of course I cannot have it
you know so I don't feel you know the
way women feel but by the way what I've
said before if you take a course in
biology okay you're learning it I don't
know about today today because of the
social justice the political things they
may you know they try to censor or
remove any such teachings of course you
know they they try to do that but
actually why I was in 1990s I think
1990s I actually took a biology and I
learned many of these things actually
they they did teach that you know so I
mean the you know if you study biology
and on the sex thing on a sex issue you
know you study different organisms how
they reproduce you know how they
duplicate and you know you learn you
know
you kind of learn many of the things
about sex anyway so for women it's also
critical to have sex because if you
don't you die out and but also for women
if they must do it when they are young
you know this is why women beautiful
women becomes so you know young girls
beautiful girls they are ubiquitous they
are like the number one concern of
humanity you know you see it everywhere
you ads in news like you go out today ok
take yourself on you go out you record
every image posters image TV you see you
know you take a photo then you then
compare of each photo that contains a
human face ok compare how many of them
what percentage are girls so beautiful
girls you will see that they its
majority hold every day you know you can
do this yourself
just to check that true to see if that's
true
so we may have you know so the other
thing about women is that they they get
pregnant you know and to have a baby in
your body is not it's not an easy thing
you know and you know it's and you know
it's it costs a lot to yourself you know
you're there you have a kind of a
struggle you know it either your life or
your baby's life I mean so for example
in a past when when medicine you know
it's not so advanced many women you know
they died when they give birth so it's
not it's not a easy thing and when you
are 40 you know women go through
menopause you know you basically you
cannot have babies anymore which is
different for for guys guys you can
still have you know your sperm count
decreases but still you can have you can
have a baby at age 60 you know even 70
almost with no you know
I mean you're spent you know maybe you
have a hard time getting up or your
sperm count decreases but in general the
baby see will be will be healthy but for
women you have a short kind of window
you know before so anyway that's a
that's that's what I'm saying so anyway
so I'm saying that in so women has this
urgent sexual drive and women also
mature earlier you know like 13 you know
they they become mature actually becomes
like their ways of thinking they mature
meanwhile boys boys so thin guys are
typically very stupid you know these
guys don't mature until maybe you know
you and maybe onto your third when you
are 30s like that applies to me as well
like you don't know what you want so
anyway so this cosmopolitan things so
that's so on YouTube you have these you
have these millions millions like girls
they you know they are meeting they are
so many of them they have video blogs
about you know this makeup stuff anyway
so let's see the comments so they can
see how many people are watching fine
okay you'll be good if you were to plan
your topics yes yeah I mean think about
that and put them in to title otherwise
people won't know what you talk about
when they quick yeah that is true so I
mean the thing about my youtube channel
is that I wasn't sure you know what is
my goal you know even though I don't
want you know I kind of don't want to go
because good morning although because
you know
that's kind of my you know go endless
and goal is my situation you know and I
don't want it to be so I don't know it's
so I should have you know I've been
thinking and it could happen any time
you know just say this week what time
I'm going to have a talk show and what
topics I'm going to do I might try that
but my life is falling apart I'm not
sure what to do so anyway so let's see
next a little bit can't read or write
though because I've always lived in
Australia okay so you speak a bit
Chinese but you cannot read and write
yeah Chinese is very difficult to learn
I mean the reading and writing part the
listening and speaking is not too
difficult so these magazines use this
jargon to exploit the thing insecurity
that they Manuel fact that they
manufactured with the same magazines no
I don't think they I don't think that is
true you know in my opinion these
magazines have these jargons these
Chagas doesn't came from the magazines
they came from the girls themselves
because you know because it just
naturally forms in a community for
example in programmers community we have
these patterns or you know lots of
joggers kiss or you know dry you know
these struggles did it's not because
well you could say part of the part of
them came from corporations they want to
sell you things like agile stuff but I
don't think that's the primary source of
these joggers rather it formed naturally
between programmers because so this has
to do with psychology you know with you
know psychologists who study social you
know
formation culture formation and you know
group formation or you know when you
have a community or group or even you
know a religion or code depending on you
know how you're sizing do you find them
funny but anyway when you have a group
okay it tends to develop its own kind of
ways because oh man of so jargons you
know because there is the because it's
for bounding you know it creates a
pounding for the community members and
and why the bounding what's the bounding
for pounding is so that your community
forms a group and can can therefore
survive you know maybe you have one
shared idea so shared interest or or
shared blood lie like clan that's what
you know what crowd you know like a
family related
oh you share your vision you know like
oh you know cooperation or you share
your country basically the very same
race or same ethnic group there are
similar ideas okay but anyway so when
you have a community you tend to develop
jargons okay that that is kind of that
that is roughly why the job is developed
for girls the girls jargons let's see
what let's see what what they have here
kinky boobs kinky boots okay the edge
filthy which player horsetail you know
so player is another jargon player means
like player refers to guys who are kind
of very smooth you know with girls they
can pick up girls just like that they
can you know and have sex with them
but they don't they are not low yo I
mean yeah that's what you know players
me that's a jargon among the team
communities you know so some girls are
girls girls they develop these jargons I
think is just just their own thing you
know because girls they then you see
these chuggins this is related to
competition you know when it comes to
mate mating ok I'm gonna answer the
question about doing Emacs
actually I haven't I have not tried it
so actually I don't know nothing about
it maybe I'll talk about that in a
second but anyway so the community so
six you know main teen sex it has a lot
to do with competition you know when it
comes to sex there is competition
because you know as you know for guys
you have sometimes you have you know one
girl you have to fight what a girl you
know you see this in animal kingdoms you
know alliance they have to fight you
know you you win the fight you becomes a
king you know the king of the pack and
you have lots of wives you know the
female lions and if you don't win
basically most of the male's you just
don't get to mate you are going to have
sex yeah that that is you know that is
what you might think is a cool fact of
nature that happens in a lot animal
kingdoms in lot of you know animals you
fight you see males fight to their death
you see antelopes you know some
antelopes or deers they have horns you
know usually males male has it you know
if they fight and you know they get
injured the winner gets a girl you see
that allotting a lot insect so you know
the
the animals and it actually happens in
human animals as well in us because you
see you know in high school where you
know like you have you used you used to
have duels like you know with sword you
know two guys fight a duel well it's
that the duo is not always is you know
it's not necessary about girls but you
know any high school you have fight you
know over a girl you know and in
corporations and even you know in nation
you know it's in our mythology you know
the foundation of Western society part
of it is quick mythology and in Greek
mythology you have this Trojan War you
know as you might know Trojan War is
square it's you know it's a mythology
and it began because basically it's a
fight over a girl you know it has very
immense interesting history well okay
let me let me just cover it briefly
because okay one day you know I am NOT
able to tell you the story in detail or
in any manner of smoothness but the
basic guide the basic outline is that so
there's a party among gods okay and then
you know that the god gathered together
and there is another god or goddess
okay the eros I think her name is Ares
she's known as the god of goddess of
discord discord meaning like chaos or
disagreement you know discord you know
someone who makes trouble she's known as
the goddess of discord
so Ares um it's mr. snooker
Aries yeah that's a girl
so that's the goddess of discord and she
and here's you have a Disney's version
this Disney's version is crap they you
know they try to mix areas quick
mythology into the Arabia
you know mythology like really just
mixed things you know and everything is
still American all the actual cultural
stuff is removed from it so anyway you
have this area's goddess you know who
was not invited so she got angry and she
throw a golden apple into the party and
on a golden apple it says for the most
fair you know for this is for the
fairest you know basically it means the
for the most beautiful so she threw a
coda not Apple into the party then there
are three goddesses they are saw it and
they fight for the Apple because they
think you know they each one think she
herself is the most beautiful and you
know that Apple is for her so the three
goddesses saw one of them is Aphrodite
you know basically the goddess of sex
after that physical sex you know sex and
the other one is I don't remember the
names you know well actually I can't
remember the names you know do you so
you guys deal with me am I going down
the right path
am I not talking like like you see
stopping interesting so anyway you have
these three goddesses fighting for the
Apple you know they want then Zeus Zeus
is the god of all of them or you know
and he led a boy who's what's the boy's
name
Paris the boy's name is Paris anyway are
you guys still here
so I'm kiss I don't know I cannot you
know I don't know what you guys are like
Oh what are you here I mean maybe some
of you are listening to me via you know
not watching video on the phone or when
you are doing something you know working
on something or washing dishes or
whatever anyway so he so she the god is
through the Apple and the other guy
speak you know the goddess is fight for
it and then and then
the god Zuzu Zeus toda boy - to choose
you know let the boy
Paras pdop the church you know say which
one is actually the most beautiful then
each of the goddess tribes the boy you
know the Alfred I says I'm going to give
you if you say I'm the most beautiful
I'm going to give you the most beautiful
women as your wife the most beautiful
woman as your wife then the other
goddess is also each one gave bribes the
guy you know one of them half rope tied
Athena's okay another goddess Venus and
the other one is hell Hera
I think Hera yeah so anyone anyway so in
the end the Paris you know the boy
chooses Aphrodite because you know he
wants the most beautiful woman as his
wife so he gave the Apple to Aphrodite
so after that you know fulfills her
promise by choosing Helen heaven is
supposed to be the most beautiful woman
in a world to be the wife of Paris but
however Helen is already married
or something like that you know and you
know by anyway she she the goddess gave
Helen to Paris so that began the Trojan
War because because Helen is already
married to this king in this country and
Paris is in the Greeks you know you know
but helen perris took Helen and that
began the Trojan War
so that so the the mythology of Trojan
War is about a war over a woman and by
the way in Chinese history that happened
I think quite a few times as well you
basically a war but
and as you know that happens in you know
so fighting to mate you know happens a
lot in you know other animals in human
animals so yeah back to what I was
saying about competition so that's what
happens you know that's what men do
because if you you have to fight to get
the make you have to you know because
girls you know they choose what they who
they want to mate with and you want to
be the winner you know that then you
have a pack of wives you know basically
you can see that in human in our history
you know most Kings Kings you know in
China or in Europe you have a lot of
wives you know you have ten wives so you
know sometimes sometimes hundreds like
literally literally hundreds not you
know the the actual title may not be
wife but they may be concubine so they
may be you know like in Islam they have
harem you know you know just women for
you to have baby with so you know so
that's that's what happens in animal
kingdom you know one guy met have sex
with you know you have a lot of wives
and that also happens if you look into
the cattle industry or cow you know
carioca basically usually you keep one
male you know cow or whatever not may
oka the bow you know you know you pick
the one best poor horse to mate with you
know all the cows females wrist you know
the rest male booze you know you get
castrated castrated and used for other
purposes
you know and so anyway so so for males
you can see there's heavy competition
but for females there's also you know
for females it's interesting that did
it's almost like every female you don't
have to you always get to mate okay you
don't have to like for males most of you
will never have sex in your life okay
and today in today's society we have
this in cell you know whatever that in
cell goofy you know you who says that
they are you know they cannot get a
girlfriend things like that yeah and and
that's actually you know that's actually
natural situation because most girls
they want to you know they want a guy to
be the most powerful because that give
them you know so-called security you
know it's like even a guy may not like
her may not actually love her but she is
assured that she's going to have baby
and and have money to you know for her
life she doesn't have to worry about
things so anyway so women they have
almost you know any any women they don't
really have to fight to have sex they
can you know they can have sex you know
they can just have sex and have baby
they will in fact you know most of them
unless they choose not to you know a few
anyways so a but however there are still
competition among them the exact reason
I don't know yeah I don't remember you
know I have to like have to be prepared
to actually to talk about that yeah yeah
anyway I don't know what but anyway so
what I'm saying is that the competition
among women is different from the
competition of men to have sex but
however there is also very strong
competition and that is why ok that is a
reason where these jargons developed
among among
girls hunting girls by the way if you
are interested in this kind of subject
there are books on them
Amazon okay there's one i read for
example let's see sorry
intimacy okay so guys so I guess I don't
have read five people watching so put
put the comments okay let me know what
do you think so this guy who is a so
this article reading notes on intimate
behavior this is written by it's a book
the title is intimate behavior it's
written by Desmond Desmond Morris
he is a zoologist or anthropologist so
he study animals including human animals
and he has written so I have read this
book this book is about they look at
human intimate behavior among human
animals okay but they look he looks at
them in a cold very cold way as if as if
you are studying sexual behaviors of
reliance on monkeys okay you know so
this is a book it's very good you know
he's actually very well known he's very
old town I'm not sure actually he's very
old I don't know it may be I hope he did
not pass away but he is very old now
desmond morris old and in fact he has
written several books on this topic
so there's intimate behavior there is
the naked woman and the naked man you
know so I recommend this book so that's
one book there are lots of others that
studies okay let me show you another
book
about women why about the competition
among women you know there is okay let's
go - yeah let's go - so these states
there's a naked yoga there you know in
San Francisco places like that it's kind
of very creepy stuff not well not anyway
anyway it's so there is a book I want to
find okay let me try to find it
menstruation
I don't well I maybe I'll put the link
up when when the video is then put in
the descriptions but there's today it's
written today written by women you know
women psychologists or something like
that they study you know women the
competition between women why women
dress you know why do women like like
it's one of the interesting thing like
when you look at the women's magazines
it's like all the pages I mean it's
different from guys magazine guys
magazines you want to look at women but
in women's magazines they they they like
every pages or women and they are you
know sexual you know look at this look
at this they are very you know sexual
state so women look at women the reason
they look at women is that they this is
how they want to be you know it's you
know it's all about sex this is because
you know they need to attract men that
they need to attract the men they want
not just any men
they can get you know any men but they
want to get the men they want so this
you have these sexualized things you
know in women's magazines is like it's
almost better than porn you know you
look at them page by page all these you
know these women so yeah so there are
books you know they talk about why women
do that in fact women do that they you
know actually women dress up so
according to the book I think you know
through theories they often the dress
between women you know they they dress
up is not for men it's not really for me
it's for women because there's a
competition they say listen there is
kind of a communication between women to
signify
what is going on or you know kind of
fighting fighting among themselves okay
I think that's it for today so the
clothes that Cosette
Tomy mags
son are you still there okay I think hey
you know usually I ramble too much and
all the people is our gun so we have six
people so xuong xuong asked what do you
think about doing it to me Maddox I
haven't used it so highly card Oh what's
up so the card oh do you have a question
how do you how did you find me
I haven't seen you here before your
programmer
I think maybe that's it for today you
know I've been talking talking for one
hour
Leo kado
not a programmer so how did you find me
how did you find me
do you know me before I always oh you
just bumped into it like it's today is
the first first time or something
Oh keyboard fan great so we get that's
fantastic so we are talking about
keyboard yeah yep
Kibo is one of my love yeah so yeah I
used to collect so do you have a happy
hacking keyboard that's that's the worst
keyboard possible and so do you have a
happy hacking keyboard and oh are you
happy with your current keyboard or are
you looking to buy a keyboard you know
so I'm about to close for today's talk
so if you have any keyboard questions
you know ask me about a keyboard and
I'll talk about that and maybe for nine
minutes you know five five minutes and
that'll be it for today so you use poker
poker three okay that's another very
well known keyboard one of the elite
high quality keyboard that's the poker
keyboard so let's look at the poker
keyboard so this all these happy hacking
and Poker keyboard they are all in my
opinion they are all the same okay I
don't care much for them what I really
care what I think is superior is far
more superior these Batman keyboards I
call these batman keyboards they are
fancy ergonomic keyboards and they they
cost a lot more like three hundred
dollars two hundred fifty anyway so but
but between the PC keyboards you know
you have all these you know basically
they're all the same
they differ by you know maybe the
keyboard key switches the quality of the
key caps you know and lighting you know
GB you know rainbow color lighting some
of them programmability you know things
like that
but as far as economic is concerned you
know as far as function inefficiency oh
these are pretty much the same so I
don't really care for them but also
especially if you divide if you take the
Koala your feature feature quality you
know of the keyboard divided by the
price you know the cost how much it is
that gives you a score of maybe the
worth how you know the worst score of
the keyboard if you saw if you look at
the that then happy kept hacking is very
low is [ __ ] expensive two hundred
fifty fifty dollars so pokers three is
this one it came a few years ago
it's absolutely better than happy
hacking why because because because the
poker keyboard it has it's programmable
and not just that it's driverless
programmable you know meaning that if
you want to program the keys you just
press keys on the keyboard so yeah so
that's that's what I think about polka
keyboard so so do Caudill says he's
looking for redox yea redox is one of
the do-it-yourself keyboard yeah you
know the so redox I think it's pretty
good but I don't like those ones that
has less keys you know there's a fashion
among you know there's kind of a trend
where keyboards you know they become
less and less keys like 60 keys so how
many cases we had red dark 70 keys yes
you know 70 keys you don't have function
keys
you know f1 f2 f3 you don't have that
but however function keys is Inc is
critical it's critical convenience when
you want to save keystrokes so you know
so it used to be that when I look at
this
you know keyboard that has 70 or less
key 70 is kind of bad barely minimum a
lot of them are like less than 70 like
60 you know it's like what the [ __ ]
iris keyboard 54 keys you know so 70 is
kind of you know okay and if you look at
Canisius
let's see kind of kanessa so is what I
use you know I've I've been showing this
almost thing every what every minute
video so it's very back so that it's go
back look at Canisius wait am i show you
my window color yeah so let's look at
Canisius advantage it has 68 keys yeah
so even other connect Kinesis I don't
find there's enough keys so anyway I
used to you know really you know I don't
recommend any keyboard that has less
than 70 keys even 70 is not you know
it's not enough you know 70 is to like I
have a problem you know but however
something happened so you know if a year
ago I realized that you know you don't
necessarily need a keyboard with 100
keys but rather you pick a keyboard
that's your favorite you know let's say
whatever let's see let's say the red
dogs okay so it has 70 keys so you buy
this keyboard for example you know
whatever you you buy your keyboard okay
then you buy you you buy a programmable
keypad to go along with it so instead of
thinking one whole keyboard
you just think of it as keyboard with
components so you have you know one
component for your left hand one for
right hand then you have a keep keypad
program or programmable keep keypad so
all these are programmable and some of
them has lots of keys like this one you
know these two has they actually have a
screen on it one two three four five
fifty so this one is 15 keys you know 15
keys and this one is like one two five
six 24 keys
this one is got like 60 keys or
something so you know you you get the
programmable keypad with it so this way
it just became supreme then you have
like a supreme system you know you have
your favorite you know keys they are for
typing then you have a dedicated
programmable keypad in fact that's what
I'm doing right now you see you see the
number pad in the middle this one that
actually knows I it's a number pad but I
programmed it you know so all the keys
are like function keys they do things so
yeah that's so so yeah that's about that
so let's see it
break on this cable with the minutes
escape our weird hobbies okay happy
cocky he doesn't have control on the
right side yeah yep
yeah I really love you you know I really
love also linear layout like you know a
grid where the keys are laid out your
grid you know there's one disappoint
I had disappointment I have with with
this to keyboard because they are not
o'the Alinea so I have this one you know
automate hacking they are truly the most
wonderful and they and happy hacking I
mean the ultimate hacking keyboard is
also the most programmable I mean when
you talk about programmability there are
actually differences in capabilities in
what exactly how you can program the key
like what kind of mark well you know
what kind of things you can do remapping
you can go into detail and and in fact
there's a huge difference between
programmable keyboards in what what the
actual things they can program and this
this happy this ultimate hacking is one
of the most powerful I've seen and you
can just buy it but but this I have a
disappointment with it is that you know
the staggered this layout of the keys is
like normal keyboard and it's usually
called staggered and that's a pain
because between staggered and between
the ortho Linea you have to take take
some use to you know take some practice
to switch one from the other so if you
if you are used to the auto linear like
right now I am then I start to use the
Ottoman hacking you know you make a lot
of mistakes you have to like you know so
then when you switch back then you make
a lot you know you make a lot of
mistakes too so that's a issue and also
this key this keyboard can assist
freestyle is also excellent it it this
this one features driverless driverless
for
Ramy the ultimate hacking does not
feature driverless programming not now
anyway but again it's also staggered so
that's a problem the FN key
[Music]
the FN keys you mean the uh nope Ottoman
hacking yes on the Ottoman hacking
keyboard the FN key can be programmed to
anything you want to any key you want so
that is why I say it is actually the
most the the feature you know the one
one of the most programmable keyboard
you can program the FN key you can you
can change any key to any other key ok
this like No Limit
there's no restraint you can change any
key to any key including these two mouse
click keys you know here so you know and
such for a mobility you we are not find
for example in gaming keyboards in
gaming keyboards there's a lot of
limitations of what keys you can change
what keys it can be changed to so Linux
supports hyper super hyper
because no I never heard of Biko Biko
balanced effortless advanced keyboard
layout balanced effortless is a radical
evolving theory and observations that
strives to find the optimal efficient
economic layout he's a red radical
evolving theory okay so the result is a
series of progressively improved layouts
as new discoveries and models updated
into the theory latest recommended Bicol
a of now you know it's great you know I
haven't heard of these before thank you
for it
are you actually using it but the thing
about layout is that they are not
practical you know you know suppose you
you pick one okay so as far as layout
goes you know you go go check out my
article so I will not talk about that
so you know if you go to my keyboard
you know just such solid keyboard blog
you'll find it so I have a section on
keyboard layout that talks about all
kind of things about lay but about
layout and also key binding design the
thing about layout decide you know so
today you have lots of them for a
quality you know Co Mac Mini Mac Cooper
you know like normal and the Walkman you
have tons of then each one claims they
are more efficient or they are more you
know comfortable but basically once you
you you can pick any one of them and it
doesn't matter anymore
you know these differences between them
it's not it's like if you pick pick any
two of them okay let's say other than
quality let's say for a Coco Mac you are
you pick any two of them you know their
difference is such that you have to type
your whole life to see the difference
ya know it's like basically the you know
as far as efficiency goes you know you
have to tie type the entire you know
Shakespeare's you know writings to
actually have a difference have a
discernible difference you know in you
know whatever so and then there are
other issues like it's inconvenient you
know and especially like this picot okay
so they are saying they are a evolving
theory I mean it is true that we
actually do not know there is no
scientific formula right now today that
that can absolutely tell us which one is
the best and actually you know I've been
doing a lot of research on these kind of
things layout and key binding you know
so you know can we go read my website
you know tell people about you know link
link to it I would appreciate it so
anyway so you know I have studied
lots of these also input systems in
general so including the piano input you
know as you know I have been obsessed
with this for 430 years actually because
in 1990 you know that in 1994 I created
a variety out on the Mac you know there
was no Iraq on the Mac I created myself
so I've been studying this for you know
30 years especially especially in the
past 10 years you know I spent all our
everyday keyboard are also the veins
keyboard electronic electronic slayer
keycaps physical layouts and key binding
systems VI systems in mac systems you
know efficiency then ok ok then the you
know repetitive strain injury how they
relate you know what makes difference
what doesn't make a difference so on so
so I'm going to that I tell you right
now that as far as layout goes we
actually do not I mean it's not it's
it's like there is no best ok and among
the best today among the top one they
make no difference but however each time
you learn new what there's a significant
cost to you because it's extremely hard
to learn change muscle memory and and
this speaker is evolving you know I mean
so my impression right now is like I
mean it's good ok if you are into these
kind of things yeah it's good
I mean I'd rather spend the time to
study programming or something or
literature you know study study
something actually useful mathematics
and this keyboard can offense innate
they go nowhere okay so so what I'm
saying okay so this peak peak oh okay
that it's good that they are doing this
kind of research
you know for so for those of you
including myself you know who are into
layout research you know it's very
useful but however however it really has
little practical value
you know and busy and basically we'll
never have any impact to society because
it's never likely that society will
adopt anything like this I mean Borak
you know even Barack has not being
adopted
so anyway anyway that's the so that's my
point so I'm gonna read about this
website a little bit having offline you
know just to see just to just to see
what's the latest stuff okay so let's
read few more comments and now be it
if Finding Nemo were accurate Marlin
would have swapped genders and mated
with his I haven't watched Finding Nemo
actually
okay so that's it for today today oh oh
wait is so this speaker site is I
created by her or whatever this guy is
you know it's it tend to use female
profile photos so I've been running into
this site for quite a while ago
you know for like 10 years and I've seen
their stuff you know it's pretty weird
it's like kind of out there and one guy
I know here that I don't know
you know because I don't actually know
they use pseudonyms because you know so
I don't know actually he or she has
talked we have talked but there's
another guy I know who also post on this
forum and we've discussed things you
know we've this guy young Doug
he is also creating his own way out yeah
this young Doug but I don't know who is
this 10 I mean you know him then sohyeon
Doug he's also creating his own layout
you know Yeon Doug is from I think he's
from South Africa yeah I was surprised
by it you know he's from South Africa oh
no not this one anyway Yann Doug has his
own he has his own blog I don't know
where but it's easy to find you know
he's home blog he talked about he he
also created his own keyboard design
physical keyboard you know when it comes
to keyboard like for example this page
like many of their opinions like like I
have my own opinion like I feel like I
can just go tell them no this is wrong
that is wrong okay this
it's really you know because anyway so I
think that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for watching good - nice
to see you
Leo carto hi Diego
and well hope to see you next time okay
let's show that arrow and try again okay
let's see that
oh yeah this is young dogs page see
he undoes anyway bye guys