hello guys welcome to another episode of
satoshop Star Talk Show so we are going
to do emac Beast coding today emac lisp
so uh video check audio check okay we
are good to go so emac please let me
show you what we are going to do okay so
we are just going to code emac list live
and as I do it I'm going to explain
maybe some tutorial and maybe a little
bit randomish because today's topic is
kind of esoteric okay so it's just
mostly for me I need to code some emac
this so I just made it a live stream so
it's it's a little bit more advanced
emac bits so if you don't know emac this
you know you you never had
beginners tutorial you might check out
my emac this tutorial so I have a video
before so you go to emac this Basics
just search for it and you'll find I did
a introduction emac this for beginners
so you watch that one but today it's
gonna be more complicated okay so let's
begin
so we are going to and I love to see
your comments okay comments and
questions posted there hey or flamio
so okay so emac these so we gonna do so
what we're going to do is that I'm going
to work write a command write a e-lisp
Elis command
uh function actually
function uh function
that
given
let's let's let's start to write the
documentation okay so meanwhile so we
can write the documentation and
uh so let's begin emac this coding so
different Define a function let me tell
you what we are writing so this command
will be called HTML uh let's say fix
links okay let's just call it that in
the dark stream so here is what we're
gonna do
well here is what the command is going
to do
given a text block so we need some three
variables
text okay
the first variable is text which is just
a block of text a string and
current path okay then current path is a
current file path where this
block of text came from okay
then
Target
path
okay this target path is where you're
gonna move this block of text to so
there's a
from N2
um source and destination okay so you're
gonna copy a text block from one file
basically to another file and when you
do that all your local links may not
work anymore so
so in this command
given text block change or
links or local links
uh
fix our local links so that they
are correct
in the Target path okay
that is what this command is going to do
now let me show you a demonstration of
how why do we need that okay so let's go
to my programming blog
so I broke I you know I walked Non-Stop
on my programming blogs you know update
uh
check them check them out check them out
okay so there's CSS tutorial I keep
working on them lots of things so
there's also
three columns layout
um there's a let me show you these three
columns layout CSS it's actually a new
feature so this is like a newspaper
column layout so this feature became
available a few years ago okay
uh so you know I keep updating my
website then there is Javascript how to
iterate Loop a HTML elements you know
when you get them from get elements
so this is Storm get Elements by ID by
name by tag Name by class attribute and
so on so once you get a bunch of them
how do you look through them uh fairly
complex because changes over the past 10
years
because there is not list and there is
not live object or non-live object then
there is not list versus HTML collection
you know so if you are a JavaScript
coder if you are a web dev
check out my JavaScript tutorial in
depth okay so as I was saying I was you
know working on my blog all the time uh
technical topics you know Unix so you
have some ecosystem Solaris this is
Asian this is around the year 2000 I
wrote this so right now so in the past
days I just um
we work them rework them you know move
some parts into a new page so it's
easier to search uh so you have some
ecosystem Solaris or sun OS then you
have HP ux then came around Linux you
know around year 2000 becomes becomes
popular it began 1993 also
so in the beginning you have Debian the
most popular is uh Debian yellow yellow
dog Linux Debian red hat and suse or
Susie however you pronounce that you
know these are the most popular
20 years ago then of course you have
free BSD
very interesting history so you can see
a TNT there and you can see dos there
and then you have next computer it's
which is the Revenge of Steve Jobs you
know he got kicked out
from the company Apple he started
so he started next and the next failed
you know then there's POS which Apple
you know
sabotaged them essentially POS you know
all the corporate corporate backstabbing
and so on and what you know the Unix
Linux idiots they don't know it
they just think open source is great
anyway so this apple
so um so I did a lot so let me get back
to the emac this so what am I doing let
me tell you okay what am I doing
why are we on and there's kids you know
recently I updated a lot uh git tutorial
so you know check them out
uh and why python sucks and geometric
inversion that's my favorite thing uh
geometry
and uh okay so let me let me show you
what what what is it I need I need to
code this okay Crazy Frog hello I think
long time no see
thoughts on the new three-seater
integration for passing what is that I
don't know what is that is that the Emax
thing explain okay
explain I don't know what that is
so we're gonna code emac this first then
we're gonna um so anyway let me wait any
anyway let me show you what what is it
we're gonna we need to do okay so for
example I have a lot you know so so you
are looking at my sorry dot info and go
up one directory you can see
sally.infolded and there is huge amount
of you know about seven thousand files
among my
among my domains okay because art you
know those domains are all good now it's
just slightly info and study org I moved
everything else into Sally info and
Sally org
so Sally info is mostly uh programming
and math okay technical topics and Sally
org dot org is other things random lots
of other things arts and literature and
writing and politics and so on
and also music it's all moved into
xavi.org
[Music]
okay let me show you
so here is sally.org
and then you have studied that info then
you have several other sections English
and art and music songs Human animals
and their songs an analysis look at the
human history or culture via what
they've seen you know you look at what
you know there's lots of tons of songs
on love on all kinds of things and you
re you know you check out their music
and lyrics and you look at you do
analysis on what are they saying
different culture they say different
things different type of songs rock and
roll heavy metal you know country music
love songs and love songs Lots you know
you have love songs among all these
almost all of them except maybe heavy
metal
you know so you can see certain topics
goes with certain songs then you have
Chinese songs which is entirely
different culture
and you have wrap of course rap is
mostly you know
and hatred you know anti-cops you know
this uh kind of thing
uh against uh you know against the rap
rap and and so on
so anyway so
so that's Sally and you have odds of
course uh that's
saudi.org okay and there is also second
life which is exploration of the virtual
reality The Meta Universe you know today
it's called meta you know but 20 15
years ago it's
this is a emerging technology virtual
Life Second Life okay I spend about four
years every day in it
exploring the technology you know the
future reason you know what are we going
to be in the future what what is society
going to be like you know so
you know so so I I write a lot of things
and there's also a section on politics
which I do not link here so I don't want
I want to avoid the drivers you know the
drama oh you know this political parties
doing what all these hateful and so on
so I don't think here
so that's sally.org so
we digressed a lot so anyway let's go
back to Sally dot info
so here is technical stuff
computer programming
in mathematics so there's wufam language
and Mathematics and there's keyboard and
you know efficiency and programming
languages python Pro Ruby Haskell Java
crochet you know JavaScript you know I
tell you all about it
so that's the introduction to my website
so you know so but what are we doing so
what what is it that I need to do today
so let's go back so let me show you okay
so you can see here is my directory
structure you know there are so many
things 7 000 HTML files basically and uh
and now
but now
common questions okay post it there but
now I have a problem the problem is okay
so let's go to
sally.info.com okay so that is
that is my programming blog you know I
have
if you go back to
saudi.infox.code you have
I have several blocks you know some talk
show
which is what we are doing today in
keyboard blog you know lots of tons you
know
1000 Pages there
then you have programming blog
uh then you have math blog you know math
blog I haven't been so active because
math is uh you know difficult
and recently I learned periodic numbers
you know it's very Advanced fantastic
periodic numbers Advanced number Theory
um and you know so there it is my math
blog and a lot of it
focus on the
decorative things in mathematics you
know
uh you know algorithmic mathematical art
I need to do a full video on this one
day I did one before but not so good I
need to do a full video one day on what
on defining what is mathematical
algorithmic mathematical art so it needs
to be mathematical but it also needs to
be algorithmic
and there are certain requirements
in the definition you know it's not just
you know for example a lot of you
Zoomers in Malaysian idiots
you know you would be interested in
general genetic art generic uh no what's
it called let's okay let's digress a
little bit let's search
generative art okay
that's the worst that's the most
worthless [ __ ] this generated generative
art okay this is the most worthless was
less [ __ ] what this is generative art is
just doodling you know what is doodling
let me show you what he's doodling
okay so let's go to
uh
okay so let's open that one we need to
open it in snip and sketch okay so you
know sometimes
sometimes we just doodle you know when
we talk on the phone and we you know we
just
um
like without concentration we just draw
something
you know doodle you know this is
doodling you know
[Laughter]
this is manual doodling you know
that is what genetic art uh generative
art is okay that's doodling with
computer the most idiotic [ __ ]
so you know if you are a programmer a
lot of you are and you you know emacs
list emacs users you know and you might
be interested in creating you know
algorithmic uh joint you know don't
don't do don't
you know have some brain don't don't
fall into this you know generated
generative art crap okay there are
several languages dedicated to
generative art those are crap and this
generative art is usually sponsored you
know it rose up with the Malayan Jin and
Zuma crowd they don't know they don't
know things okay so you don't want
generative ad
and you don't want Ray tracing Ray
tracing is a classic hacker you know
programmer especially of the C C plus
plus or the rust type of people when
they hear a ray tracing they get excited
already chasing they're gonna you know
they think that's math no that's not
math okay this generative art is [ __ ]
it's not math and no is it art not math
and not art
generative art not math and not art
Ray tracing let me show you Ray tracing
okay actually I have an article you know
recently
so let's open my blog let me show you
this article okay
uh
why Ray tracing is not math okay this is
a
rent turned into a essay from Sally
Discord you know if you haven't already
joined the sorry it is Discord
interesting people and we have arguments
you know cloudy Discord uh also the
topics so
so math so you know Ray tracing let me
show you first of all Ray tracing you
know look at look at that you know
programmers get excited about this
oh oh mathematics oh linear linear
algebra oh God Matrix this is so
difficult I need to Master Ray tracing
the most idiotic [ __ ] programmers this
is not math okay
what is math
what is math oriented art or math
mathematical art that is a piece of
drawing or visualization or artwork that
embodies mathematics okay so Azure it's
Asia's math work artwork would would cut
you know sketches you know or your pen
or whatever
they they are not even done by computer
okay they are done manually by artists
okay but those those are mathematical
art okay
you know this for example this is Asia's
artwork woodcut okay wood engraving you
know it's actually using you know uh
some sort of carving wood okay to create
this artwork and here is more than one
done in Second Life you know we talked
about second life virtual reality so uh
a friend who is a guy know it you know
he created a emulation of the Asia's
artwork in Second Life so this is 3D you
can walk around you know you can as a
human you can like this is a 3D object
you can
stand on this thing
you know so it's a three-dimensional so
and he she also created I don't know if
it's he or she but he's but she's a a
Malaysian so you can see
this amazing thing you see you standing
in this
I forgot what it what what structure it
is E8 or something the higher
dimensional polytops
Okay so
so those so what is mathematical art so
what is mathematical art
mathematical art is an artwork that
captures mathematics
that embodies mathematics that the
essence of this artwork is mathematics
okay
that is the definition of mathematical
artwork
okay
now as opposed to
as opposed to uh
as opposed to this crap oh glasses oh
wine glasses do you think that you know
when you look at this picture is there a
mathematics in it no
but why is it Ray tracing why why do
programmers think Ray tracing is math
because they think you know the the the
methodology to create this that's math
of course
but a car is also mathematics do you
when you see a car you do you say oh oh
my God I'm seeing mathematics no but if
you build a car engine combustion engine
that's all math
my microphone YouTube stream that's all
mathematics okay
so Ray tracing is not math
so as a programmer let me give you some
something positive okay for you
programmers or uh 10 technical computer
users or whatever you do Gamers or you
know image editing video creation audio
expert or whatever
many of you are so
so let's say you know when if you are
young many of you are you want to you
might be thinking mathematics as a
career or programming
uh remember they are different nature
okay they are not the same thing they
are different nature okay let's let's go
back to emac this because I want to code
so okay let me show you what what I need
to do okay let's start actually focus on
the emac basic coding now
so we already spent like 20 minutes on
this
chatting random which is good we haven't
done that for a long time
so what are you try uh guys saying so
do we have emacs users serious emacs
users you know I get usually I get
excited when I see comments that's
relevant and people are you know more
serious about whatever I'm talking about
yeah you cannot paste links in chat
that's YouTube
coffee
so of flamio says I want to listen to
you Bash
mbti that's Maya's brick thing I have an
article on that okay I have a I have an
article on that
you I think you can just search it sadly
Myers
minus brick you know this personal so
there it is okay that's on sally.org
this personality test you know Myers
break the personality test in that
calmed the world that's true that's the
history that's what it is Kong
you know cheating it's a kind of a scam
it's a okay if I'm gonna talk this about
this it's gonna be full one hour okay so
because it relates to psychology you
know there's a lot about it in
psychology
you know so let me just quickly let me
talk about this in for three minutes
okay so in so my ass break you know you
are probably familiar you know it
there's a lot of Internet websites that
test that gives you the test of your
personality it summarizes four letter
you know code you know I I
um for example I am
I am i n t p okay
so yeah there it is I and you know
there's infp four letters okay ESTJ
I more or less int P I think or a little
bit e and t p okay INTP so so anyway
it's a psychology that's a personality
test okay
Maya speaks there are several variations
actually over the past 20 years there's
there's
you know anyway that's a psychology
personality test okay it gives you a
code that that signify what kind of
person you are and then
maybe some theories about what type of
person works with other type of person
or flamio I you know says I'm intj okay
J is judgmental yeah you know so I'm I'm
actually between J and P
you know so anyway it's it's a rough
test okay it so
so this test became hugely popular in
1990s even okay now many of you Zoomers
think you know you just saw this you
think it's new uh in fact in the night
in year 2000s this is the first one
that's on internet all over the place
actually psychology tests personality
test is one of the things that becomes
popular all the time all the time so
depending on depending on what year you
know this particular test that becomes
crazy you know today's you call it
become a meme become a you know anyway
it's super popular so anyway in back in
1990s 1997 or I even went to the library
and I
I read the book I borrowed several books
related to this so I read about it
because when you are younger when I was
younger you know we are
thought about you know we have problems
you know I have problems depression what
what exactly is my problem you know you
read a lot of books so I read uh tons of
them anyway
let me just
stop talking about this in two more
minutes then let's go back to emac this
okay so it's a personality test
and uh
you know all these personality tests the
psychology itself you know psychology is
a academic topic psychology is an
academic topic and it's partially
science it's not a hard science you know
you would classify it
it as social science okay so in social
science social science is not hot
science it's not like math physics
engineering if you get something
incorrect people die okay
now
um but on psychology and others other
social sciences political science you
know social Communications journalism
those are you know those are not science
okay those are just
trying to be science so psychology is
you know you might call a soft science
you know you it's not completely
art you know you might say oh it's just
you know it's not arbitrary but it's you
know they use scientific methods to try
to find
um the nature the quality the
characteristics of human animals whether
you can classify them for example
personality is a thing and there's also
mental illness you know many of us are
afflicted with
you know in Malaysian Zuma idiots jargon
we would say otist autistic
you are watching me because I'm autistic
idiots these humans so psychology is a
soft science that means it's not too you
know it's not 100 correct and and as a
soft science in particular psychology is
filled with
scams you know and this my aspect is one
search scan
you know so
so it gives you you know it gives you it
tests your personality it gives you you
know a score of your personality so you
might say so so the ultimate question is
how correct it is
you know it classify Human animals
personality into these 16 categories
right so you might ask is it correct is
it is it good is it is it is is does it
work does it work to classify human
personalities into these 16 categories
you know there are different type of
personality tests which classify using
other schemes for example there's one
called Big Five which Jordan Peterson is
very fond of you know Big Five that that
tests your uh your uh explorativeness
you know they they use their own jargons
um
but anyway so
so the question you want to ask is is
this test correct does it work
you know is it test for ex and you need
to do this comparatively is this test
you know how how they classify human
personality into this 16 category is
this
does it has predictive value does it
work you know in other words like
like what what is the effect you know
once you know okay okay fine so you you
can classify all human animals into
these categories what what does it do
you know what does what does it do what
what good does it do does it suddenly it
can tell you oh you are a bad guy you
are a good guy or this guy is good for
programming that guy is good for being a
lawyer what does it do the power you
know the power of the test
uh and you have to do this comparatively
you have to compare two other you know
other uh psychology tests but ultimately
like I said psychology is a soft science
so in fact it's it's pretty hard to
assess
just how good it is okay there are many
psychology personality tests it's hard
to actually say this test is better than
that one okay
somewhat similar to IQ tests there's all
sort of tests there's uh you know
but but okay but
that's one thing okay first of all we we
can be sure we cannot say for sure this
is a good test or not
that's one thing
the other thing I want to say why this
is bad is that it turns you know many of
these popular personality tests they
originated from essentially a scan okay
and lots of psychology
or psychology
popularity something about some for
example fluid Freud one of the
Main
uh School of
psychoanalysis you know psychoanalysis
from Sigma fluid you know how how you
pronounce it he is one of the main
school of thought in psychology you know
psychology they also have different
theories so
uh how do you pronounce it
uh
Freud okay something uh
let's let's get the pronunciation fruit
okay I don't know how do you pronounce
it but anyway he's the one of the
mainstream okay Freud Sigmund Freud okay
he's a one of the mainstream
main school of thought in psychology
there's also behaviorism you know his
school is called psychoanalysis you know
so it's typified by how you see a photo
of a client lying on a big chair or
comfortable sofa and then a psychologist
asks questions and take notes you know
that's
you know and his theory is saying it
ties everything to
uh sexuality and mother okay lots of
that
then there's also anyway so we're
getting into psychology so let's go back
to this test okay
so I was saying first of all this test
you cannot be sure there's no sure way
there's no sure way to assess whether
this personality test is good or not or
whether it is better than another okay
there are quite a few
so we don't know we don't really know
it's you know all basically all
psychology tests they come out seems
reasonable because first of all you know
I if I'm going to tell you oh you are
you are the type of guy who are
interested in computers what does it do
you know of course yeah of course you
are because otherwise you wouldn't watch
this video then some people you know but
it's kind of fussy okay for example let
me give you an example color test you
know one of the most simple psychology
tests is which color do you like okay so
you have a test you know red blue cut
you know which color do you what what's
your favorite color
foreign
that is the most simplest personality
test
okay then given that test we can ask
what good does it do does it actually
work well it does work in some way for
example if you like red if you like the
color red that probably means you are
more flashy you are more uh you know
maybe extrovert you you know you are you
you want to you know
somewhat okay if you like the color
black then maybe it means you are more
kind of a secretive person or maybe you
perceive you know you are afraid you
don't you know you are maybe anti-social
maybe you are like the Batman character
you know the Batman
you know you you you know you you are
kind of
dark you know because colors associate
with uh
history and you know associate with
culture and if you like white and maybe
you are a purist you are a pure you like
everything clean maybe maybe you like
things clean cut you you like things uh
you don't you don't you know you like
things
innocent for example which is opposite
to Black which is often you know has the
connotation of Darkness
so color color test you know
so it does
at least a little bit shows your
personality okay so you could say yeah
oh yeah oh that's a fantastic that's a
valid color test you know
yeah but it's fussy that's the thing
so first of all
nobody nobody can really say it's valid
test or not that's one thing
now the second thing is that a lot of
these psychology tests they stem from
a scam basically somebody someone wanted
to become rich okay then they promote
their Theory now Maya's break is one
such example and this girl these women
who wrote This Book
her name is Merv Emma
Emery something like that move Emery So
she wrote this book and she apparently
she dug into the she's on Twitter by the
way she dug into the history of the
myers-brigg you know saying you can you
started to see
it's a little bit of a code you know the
history basically created by two women
two sisters or mother and daughter I
forgot
then they made the test you know they
are not psychologists you know they are
not psychologists they just made a test
and became popular because it it it
um
just like today you know today you have
memes you have social justice you have
genders that's current thinking the
current thinking you know 20 years every
every 10 years every 20 years you have
certain current thinking you know other
people especially young people believes
it
so
and especially things like psychology
personality you know you don't you don't
need to know mathematics to understand
it you don't need several years of
training in programming and Engineering
to appreciate it when when things are
about psychology everyone is like have
opinion about you know
so that's why they became popular so
they they started a company or something
they become bigger and bigger money they
make money that is a point okay they
promote their tests because they make a
lot of money so they become bigger and
bigger and bigger and they you know
there's a cooperation it's in copyright
and of course
so anyway that is my criticism of the
myers-brigg okay
and you know when I begin you know when
I first learned that I did my test you
know INTP I was also very enthusiastic I
I was thinking this is correct you know
I'm the architecture type you know
according to the analysis of the types
INTP
or a little bit entp or intj you know
for each letter you have a degree you
know they give you a number something
like that
so when I first did this in the 19 late
1990s I thought this is you know then
then I would put in my blog just like
today you'll see people on Twitter
is not fantastic okay so so you will see
a lot of people put on Twitter you know
I am especially INTP types like you and
me or flame you and many many of us on
on the saw Discord because like-minded
people we are many half of us are
programmers right
so we are you know excited about this
you know correctness you know about this
finding about ourselves
you know one one of the thing about
psychology is that
most human animals almost all of us we
just focus on us okay I just care about
me
so
and so so you know so when I learned
that oh yeah I'm INTP and and because
you know therefore you know because that
means I'm the I'm best I'm I'm good at
engineering I'm good mathematician you
know and and then you look at some other
opposite you know he is something
something oh yeah those are lawyers
those are the Social Butterflies those
are idiots something like that
okay that's about the Maya Spriggs test
okay are we still going to do emac this
yeah I want to
uh
Tyler my maze says saw an interview with
a former CI CIA agent on Lex Friedman he
explained that mbti is a useful tool for
quickly categorizing people while
working undercover to try to get a
predictive line on them
it so happens we on the onsar Discord we
discussed
that video I watched that video the
whole video we discussed that about two
months ago with George
so in fact I have a Blog on that on that
guy on that CIA operative I think that
guy is super smart Okay meanwhile Lex
Friedman is the most idiotic [ __ ]
possible
uh should I show my blog because there's
a lot of politics you know I rather not
show it
video you know those of you who are
really interested you can find my stuff
you know just search for Sally
Lex Friedman okay Lex Friedman is Lex
Friedman is one of the lowest IQ he
don't he doesn't know nothing in fact I
doubt his capabilities you know he is
supposedly to be this assistant
professor doing AI artificial
intelligence but I find him you know I
watch quite a few you know not not too
many
I watched about by now maybe at least
five of his video interviews he he does
things he does a lot of them tons of it
you know interview famous people see
Creator you know other language creators
famous Pro programmers and language
creators and scientists Stefan woofam to
you know and AI big shots
he he interviewed a lot of people okay
but Lex Friedman is like Joe Rogan
okay next treatment is like Joe Rogan
the Babbling monkey he doesn't know
nothing he's the most idiotic offensive
[ __ ] because every time because he
interviewed a lot of people you know and
I'm interested in those topics how the
visual intelligence in programming so
and also I'm interested in particular in
those people he interviewed okay so so
for example recently he interviewed this
guy
because well cuz well very famous I
think he's sort of crackpot but I'm not
sure yet I always have an impression
because well he's some kind of crackpot
by now he's pretty old like like 80
around 80 or something so so anyway so
I watched so many of the people in
interview I'm very interested whenever
that guy talk about the universe or
programming something very interesting
The Lex Friedman always [ __ ] it up you
know he just Babble something idiotic
you know he think he's making comedy or
he's thinking you know smooth interview
you know whenever that's someone he
interviews he's making very interesting
statement or opinion about something big
in in big science or whatever the less
treatment idiot
often just something to destroy it then
it becomes you know it becomes something
else misleading the conversation becomes
something else
[ __ ] Lex Friedman idiot and I don't
think
you know so my opinion of he he's him is
very low okay
and in particular in that video where he
interviews this CIA xcia agent this CIA
I forgot the name but you know he's on
my blog this CIA agent is very
intelligent okay I highly value what he
says okay this CIA agent however
he indeed mentioned that mbti is very
useful he you know in the interview he
says you know the in the myers-brick is
one of the best psychology tests
okay so that's uh that's a good point
you know that's a good opinion you know
you listen to other people you know it's
you know follow smart people okay that's
one of the thing you want to do
associate with high IQ people
okay you listen to what they they say
um so
I very much in my opinion in my judgment
I very much I in my opinion that guy is
very smart Okay so
but then he has an opinion that the
myers-brick test is a good one so okay
that's interesting so you know
you know it's not like oh yeah then you
know he if he says that he's you know
then he's stupid no but you know you as
absorb different people you know there's
all diverse different kind of people so
if he says that okay you know that
registers in my mind okay that opinion
but again like I said you know
like I said you know you you in general
you want to look at things broadly okay
everything you do I try you know at
least that's my mentality everything I
do maybe programming or social things
whatever thing I try to put it in the
context of humanity okay the history of
human animals so you look at so for
example
you know for example if we are talking
about psychology tests for example if we
are talking about the Maya speak first
of all you want okay so what is it okay
it's a personality test okay what is
personality test okay it's part of the
part of psychology okay what is
psychology okay psychology is part of
the broad
academic study you know you want to look
at the context you want to put things
into the context of human animals
history you know three thousand years of
recorded history or or a million or more
years of you know you so you want to
look at what what's the importance of
this thing in terms of human history
same thing I value in the same way when
you look at programming languages emac
this or python you want to I try to at
least that's my mindset I try to
put them into some kind of broad
relevance
in the context of
the entire human Endeavors okay then I
make I make whatever judgment you know
whatever thing may be it may be coding
style for example if you are a
programmer you your debate about coding
style or or memory management management
of the rust you know the rust language
was or
so that's that's how I tried to um
judge things okay so this so so this
this you know this video are we still
trying to uh are we still going to do
emac this then maybe not
uh it's you know we haven't had a long
you know random chat for a long time you
know because in the past in the past
half a year I've been trying to more be
more focused on
uh you know focused video on programming
tutorials and
and wolfam language and you know
um so we haven't done this kind of
random chat which is which is very fun
though
uh so let's
so hmm
um Okay so
so I'm thinking yeah maybe we should
stop because then the video is gonna be
more than one hour
uh so
yeah so if we stop now
then today's topic is you know this
video is just going to be something
about psychology you know
okay so let's see what what are the do I
have viewers how many
four oh God
the positive my viewers
foreign
for interviewing smart people and well I
don't I don't know you know so today the
two biggest is Joe Rogan of course Joe
Rogan and Lex Friedman
but both of them are idiots you know
uh and that kind of makes sense because
only those type of people
who try you know
interviewing
famous people is one of the sure way to
get yourself to to to make you to make
yourself super popular
because the all the famous people you
know famous people
famous people celebrities especially in
technology
uh or in politics you know that's by
them for me that by definition famous
people
but definition most people know them so
they want to you know listen to what
they say so if you are doing a YouTube
Just interview these famous people
that's one of the sure way to become
very popular
that's basically that's essentially the
story of Joe Rogan Joe Rogan is one of
the most idiot idiot one most you know
idiotic
guy
so um
but if you are um
you know that's what they do you know
it's you know
so there's a question have you read
systems Thinking by Donald by Donella
Meadows no
let's look at what that is
okay
yeah this is German
now let's go to English
systems thinking is a way of making
sense of the complexity of the World by
looking at it in terms of horse and
relationships rather than by splitting
it down into its parts okay
it has been used as a way of exploring
and developing effective action in
complex context
systems thinking draws on and
contributes to systems theory and system
Sciences okay
uh no I have not heard of it but this
kind of description the first sentence
is okay you know looking looking at the
things from the whole but then it
started to talk about
systems theory and system Sciences I
think those are starting to get into
you know a crackpot and uh stuff you
know these cybernetics
Systems Science you know those are kind
of wishy-washy crack Parts interdiscent
interdisciplinary yeah usually those are
so System Theory is the inter-dism inter
this plenary interdisciplinary
[Music]
study of systems that is cohesive groups
of interrelated interdependent
components that can be natural or human
made
uh
uh every system has casual causal
boundaries is influenced by its context
defined by function
you know this kind of crap okay I would
say just crap
you know this system
boundaries homeostasis adaptation
feedback group reciprocode transactions
Microsystems to crap okay
System Theory is it's crackpot
system science ah crap
so
um
yeah so maybe I'm thinking in terms of
the whole but I wouldn't I wouldn't you
know
go with systems thinking whatever that
is that that that itself is is a fad
it's kind of you know that's how they
you know then there is critical system
thinking that we're getting into
critical theory now
crap
yeah Stephen Wolfram interviews people
but Stephen wolfram's you know so I
highly recommend Stefan wolfam's stuff
uh although he tends to be repetitive
you know because Stefan Wolfram
you know he's using Wolfram language you
know I've been talking about wolfam
language all the time my favorite
language by far I've been coding it for
since 1990s so and I met you know I work
at wolfam research and you know I know
Stefan will fam a little bit we we met
in 1995. so uh and uh
I highly I like that guy his view of
things I highly respect him both you
know he's one of the rare who is uh you
know one of the top programmers he wrote
Mathematica he created the mathematical
language but he's also so he's a top
programmer he is also one of the top
physicists you know he's and he's also a
genius certified genius because when he
was 17 or so 17 or so he was an author
Awards with a million dollar
uh funding you know something like that
so anyway so he's a
top programmer
type physicist he'd been publishing his
he was a team you know in publishing in
physics physics journals and he then he
and then he and he uh you know left
Academia he to create Wolfram research
which became a successful and private
owned company you know that's so he's
also a one of the top entrepreneur
top businessmen top innovate you know I
hate the word entrepreneur how to
pronounce
a mouthful you know I rather would say
Innovative businessman okay Innovative
businessman so anyway Stefan Wolfram is
multi-talented you know accomplished
that's the way to put it you know
because you look at what he has done
successfully so he has been
the best successful programmer by his
product you know actual you know so
you know I demonstrated woven language
in lots of my videos so with my language
top programmer top businessman and top
uh physicist okay but that's not all and
he went you know I mean I mean
I mean he also started to create his
kind of philosophy about
um
computational Universe you know cellular
automata is his thing so he he so in
other words you know say we will talk
you know his theory about computation is
a bit controversial you know it's not
used it's not Universal universally
accepted you know but however he
but the topic of cellular cellular
automata is hot science okay it's hard
science part of
you know he's a founder of the cellular
automatic the science of uh Cellular
automata in which he would call
you know the
computer Universal computational
equivalence Theory okay that's his
theory let's let me show you okay
let's see uh computational equivalence
okay that's one of the his principles
principle of computational equivalence
okay there is a so so he's got tons of
articles but there's a wolf there is a
Wikipedia so let's go
let's go to Wikipedia
theory of computation
um
uh not here uh
and yeah there is a uh article on
Wikipedia of that
foreign
not general relativity there is a
Wikipedia article but uh
but you have to find it
uh there wait
equivalence principle no
okay so that's his book
I have
on my on my website I have you know I
wrote a annotated version of this book
uh so we want to search for
equivalence okay principles of
computational equivalence
I remember there used to be a
independent article about it
but anyway anyway so Stephen Wolfram is
accomplished
men super talent in several fields in
programming in physics in
business you know in in business but he
also he created this field of automata
cellular automata okay and he believed
in a theory of
computational equivalence
which is which is his theory not not uh
universally accepted Okay so
so I very much like his ideas and I very
much like his views so you can go you
know he also does videos every every
week several videos YouTube on YouTube
so you can watch him but he also wrote
blogs you know each one of his blog is
several thousands words takes several
hours to finish so I read a lot of them
almost half of them so in in fact Stefan
Wolfram is one of the person I follow
personally because since 1990s you know
let's say up to 2005 I have read
everything
basically everything written by Stefan
Wolfram you know back then there's not
you know internet is not like today so
you also read books and you know so I I
almost read everything
that's available online by Stefan woofer
so I studied this guy very much and I I
like his views a lot
uh do you stand him what do you mean
so
so um so I highly recommend you know you
you can read his blog or watch his
videos but he tends to be repetitive
because he you know in the past 10 years
he often just focused on his
idea the new kind of science cellular
automata you're gonna talk about it
Non-Stop
like you you would hear if you watch a
lot of tons of his things you then
you'll hear the same thing uh often but
anyway he also have great you know yeah
so I would say I highly recommend him
because I I still read him uh you know I
still read him
today
lots of uh you know and um lots of
things
so yeah I recommend it
uh and but yeah but he so back to the
thing we were talking about so he he
sometimes does interview of other you
know Fame you know accomplished
mathematicians or physicists usually old
you know like 70 years old or 80 years
old
so but but his interview is not very
it's usually very dry and boring so
uh because Stefan wolfam is not
you know he's he you know if you watch
let me give you my view of his
character okay online so when you watch
him you know video you watch him talk
you know you you see this nerd you know
he's kind of nerd kind of guy he
you know it's it's not like some it's
it's not someone with uh High Charisma I
would say you know he's more like a nerd
he he
so you you you you may not find it um
on a Surface very attractive anyway
that's it that's it for today I think
okay bye guys now now like my if you
like my video
post it okay post it to your Twitter
you know get the tank you know if you
are watching this offline
you know get you know some parts you
find interesting
get a URL with a timestamp post it
comments or post to your Twitter to your
blog or tell your friends okay do that
do that for me
or you can donate of course you know you
go to my website there's you can see
donation button
thank you guys for that
that's it bye
shutdown in in one minute
yeah so we didn't do emac list today
that's okay because I did tons of you
know emac business code in turns
um in the past
and uh so I'm just going to do it
offline you know like
I have a lot to code you know every day
I have so many tons of things to code
and oftentimes I think of you know doing
a live stream of it but I've done so
many so many you know
like for emac basic coding I've done
more than 50 in the past year or two
um
yeah more than 30 at least so
so if you want to actual actually watch
emac this
you know just go through Sally emac this
okay
sorry
dot info then scroll down
emac lisp
then you have a introduction
and then you have more than that then
you have practical iMac this there's a
video of that then you go to emac Beast
writing a major mod this video on that
as well
so those are
fundamental you should watch those okay
okay bye guys