Hello guys. Good morning. Welcome to
another episode of Sound Talk Show.
We are going to code Wolfram Language
today. Wolfram Language.
In the past week, we did so many Wolfram
Language coding. So, today is another
one.
Um
So, I'm just going to code and work on
my website uh
kind of randomish. So, um this is about
mathematics, geometry. I'm going to work
on my this project, Visual Dictionary of
Special Plane Curves.
Coding Wolfram Language, okay?
So, if you are here, say hi. If you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed. If you are here,
comment.
Um
Okay, so
So, if you search the web, Visual
Dictionary of Special Plane Curves,
you'll find my website. And uh a few
days ago, we've been working on this
asteroid this asteroid animation.
Fantastic.
Um And we're going to continue work on
some of that, okay? It's kind of
randomish. You know, this is like my
office hours. So, you watch and uh
if you have comments,
post it, okay? You can ask me questions.
So, let's go to Sound Talk Show.
Uh and also, my website is still
not being updated since like
20 days ago.
Uh because
uh I got some technical issues. Uh but
it should be fixed soon, okay? But
anyway, the website, it hasn't been
updated
for like 3 weeks.
So, anyway, so let's go to today's talk
show. So,
so Wolfram Language, so yeah, let's go
there. So, today's talk show and let's
remove this live stream notification.
Delete that. We don't need it anymore.
So, Wolfram Language, if you don't know
already, you can download it. Just
search for Xahlee Wolfram
uh
download Wolfram engine, okay? Search
for Xahlee Wolfram Language for
programmers.
X
A
Language. Search for it.
You will find my website. That's my
website. You go there. So, you can see
Wolfram script download version dates
com- uh programming language tutorial.
So, I got lots of
So, you got download links there, okay?
So, you can download it. Okay, um
yeah, and the complete tutorial for
those of you programmers. If you program
in Python, JavaScript,
Go lang, uh Rust, F sharp, or whatever
programming language, you can learn
Wolfram Language from the ground up.
Okay.
So, that's the introduction. I've done
hundreds of videos on Wolfram Language
on YouTube.
So, what we going to do today, okay?
Again, say hi, okay? Like you you you
can like
uh ask me any questions and we'll talk
about that.
Uh Wolfram Language related or
programming language related related.
Okay, so this asteroid curve, there's a
lot to do though. So, let's see what you
know, there's huge amount of things to
do. Let's see.
So, that is my Twitter. So,
you know, we we code this
few days ago. You know, we did several
talk show about this. Uh we did this one
rolling a circle around another circle
generates an asteroid. We also did we
wrote this code fantastic. So that you
can allow us you to generate, you know,
any rolling circle of another circle,
okay?
We also did few days ago or last week
about this trammel of asteroid
fantastic.
So you see I have updated my website,
this website, you know, this visual
dictionary of plane curves.
I have updated locally, but it's but if
you go to my website, you won't see the
update. You will see the old page of the
asteroid.
So you don't have you don't get the new
code. So that's a problem. So I need to
fix that update my website, okay? So
that's the issue.
But meanwhile,
let me just work on things locally
because
pretty soon I'm going to update, you
know, so by the time if you are watching
this video,
you know, probably next month whoever is
watching this
my website will be updated.
So anyway, so so what what we want to do
today, okay?
So let me just talk random.
Cheers. Have coffee.
There are several options.
One of them is just to open these
notebooks.
Let's start with Wolfram Language.
>> [sighs]
>> For example, this image is generated 30
years 30 years ago. It's about parallel
curves.
So you see parallel curves looks like
that. All these images are small by
today's standards, so they all needs to
be updated.
Uh so, that's parallel curve. And uh you
know, if we go back, parallel curve
parallel curve like they just basically
means
a curve that's parallel
to a given curve. You generate this is
how you generate it by this picture, you
see?
You you draw the line, you know, you
know you know there's a tangent line.
Given given a curve, there's a
any point on the curve, there's a line
passing that point
and tangent to the curve, meaning that
it approximate the curve at that
location, tangent. Okay, we talked about
this few days ago.
Uh
so, this is basic calculus, you know,
you need to know some basic geometry
analytic geometry.
Okay, so you got tangent line, then if
you draw a line perpendicular to the
tangent line, that line is called
normal. So, you can see this picture
this image.
You see you I don't know if you can see
it, those yellow lines, those are
normal.
Uh
the normals called normal.
The normals of the curve at many points,
okay?
Now, if you fix a this you know, if your
normal line is fixed length like that,
then the end points generates what's
what's called the parallel curve, okay?
So, you see you see all these four
images are kind of similar.
So, you can look at this one normals
each normal line is fixed length. So,
you at the end of the normal line, you
see this kind of pattern. And those
pattern are those, you know, that and
that. So, those these two curves is the
normal curve of this red curve. The red
one is sine curve.
Okay, so
and so but normal can vary by length.
So, you can have, you know, if you
change the length of the normal line,
then the
the parallel curve is going to look
different, okay? So, you you can see.
So,
so again, given a given curve, you have
a family of parallel curves. So, you
have quite a few curves that's parallel
to that.
And here is a formula how you can
create, you know, create a parallel
curve given a normal um
parametric equation, you can derive the
formula for
for parallel curves.
And here are some examples, you see
you see all these rainbow-colored
curves, they are
different parallel curves of the sine
curve.
Okay.
And this picture is the um
is kind of
how
uh what is it called? Evolute, okay,
fascinating. That's evolute, okay,
that's another thing.
All these are interrelated, so very
fascinating, okay?
Evolute is a uh basically the center of
the
curvature circles, okay? So, these red
dots are the is uh is the evolute of
this ellipse.
So, this red curve you see here, that's
the evolute of this
blue curve.
And evolute is generated by all the
centers of the circle of
uh
tangent circle.
Also known as osculating circle.
Okay. Is that interesting? Any comments?
Okay, we we digressed into we, you know,
we kind of started to talk a lot about
mathematics. So,
here is parallel curve again. So, all
this needs to be updated, you know, this
we we can write a animation for that.
And this this shows, you see, the
astroid curve looks like that, kind of
like a star, you know, like ninja dot.
Okay. And then
you all see you see this this are the
parallel curves of the astroid. You see,
so it's fascinating. It's beautiful.
So,
so so this picture this image also needs
to be updated because you see it's
small. It's generated 30 years ago.
And you go down there's quite a lot we
need to do. And you know, the thing is
like which one
shall we do?
Uh that's also
needs to be updated. Uh this we did
update. This is
channels of Archimedes.
Fantastic. And here's a code. And here
we also updated because you can see it's
a big picture. It's a like
all these are ellipses
lying on the same axis such that they
are
uh
their minor the length of their minor
axis and the length of their major axis
the sum
is the same for all for each and every
of these ellipses. You see? So, when you
draw all these ellipses you see these
are ellipses. Ellipses are these
this is uh property of ellipses.
It's the locus of the
points
that's the same distance from two points
two fixed points. Okay, that's how you
generate ellipse. You can draw a ellipse
this way by
you know,
take two nails
uh or pin
stick it on a board, then take a string
then you you you you you put a pin a
string of a fixed length. Okay, then you
put a pin, you make it tight, then you
can draw a ellipse like that. That's a
definition of the ellipse. One of
ellipse can be defined in many ways,
okay? So, ellipse is a family of curves,
you know, in school usually they teach
you this way, you know, it's like a
family.
Uh
in fact, you can go to Wikipedia today,
there's lots of rich information.
Originally 30 years ago, Wikipedia just
copied my website, you know, they just
copy it
and rewrite rewrote it like beginning 30
years ago.
So, anyway, so so ellipse
Okay, so ellipse so you can generate
ellipse by many other ways, okay? Many
different definitions. Another way by
the trammel is you can also see
uh let me just show you, okay? As we you
know, we started to talk about
mathematics nonstop.
Hello, yes, sir. Uh uh
What's up? I go.
Okay, so here is a ellipse, so you can
see this is trammel of Archimedes. Now,
how do I
Let's see.
Can you see this?
Can you magnify?
Okay, it doesn't magnify the picture.
Uh
wait.
Yeah, it does, okay, but
So, let me show you this, okay? So
Yeah, there.
So, you see, you have a wait.
You got a horizontal line fixed and then
you got a vertical bar fixed, okay?
Then you have a bar that's
a bar of fixed length
but it slides on the horizontal and
vertical axis. So, let me show you.
So, you see this bar
is fixed. You see, look at the
horizontal axis.
You see, one end of the bar is always
fixed on it.
And look at the vertical axis, the other
end of the bar is slides on the vertical
axis. So, this bar, you see this bar
you know, just slides around.
And this mechanism is called trammel,
trammel of Archimedes, okay? This is a
mechanism. I think you can see them
like in the past, I don't know what they
We can search the web, you know, let's
see what was it used. You see, you know,
today you can actually build this, 3D
print this a lot of
You know, you there's a lot videos you
can watch, people generated.
Oh, and they call it what? Ellipsograph.
Okay, so I wasn't aware of the name
ellipsograph.
Okay, so they uh
So, but you see, so
Okay, so Wikipedia is pretty rich today.
You can see.
So, what
but I wasn't aware of this page before.
I know there's a trammel of Archimedes.
Perhaps they
I think they renamed the trammel of
Archimedes to
to ellipsograph. I think that's what
they did.
Sometimes, maybe.
Because there used to be a let's say
Wiki.
There used to be a trammel of Archimedes
page. Oh, there is.
Okay, yeah. So, they redirected from
trammel of Archimedes. So, apparently
ellipsograph is more
well-known
than the trammel of Archimedes. Oh,
that's something new. I didn't know
about that.
So, anyway, I wanted to know what was it
used before, like
I mean, I don't think this is just a
toy. I think it was used um
historically for
something's
uh
Okay, the history of such ellipsographs
is not certain.
But they are believed to date back to
Proclus and perhaps even to the time of
Archimedes.
Okay, ellipsograph is a trammel of
Archimedes intended to draw, cut, or
machine
ellipses in wood or other sheet
material. Okay.
Wait, but I mean
what is the actual um
use? I believe there was.
So, I don't know.
So, it didn't it didn't say, but you
know, let's try to ask Google
AI, okay? So, let's see what, you know,
Google will say.
What was
trammel of Archimedes used.
for?
I don't think it's just a toy. I doubt I
doubt it's just drawing ellipses.
Uh
okay.
Okay, the trammel of Archimedes also
called an elliptic trammel or
ellipsograph is a mechanical device that
traces out an ellipse, a stretched
circle or oval oval oval shape. When
moved in a specific way, it its primary
practical use historically and in
professional settings was drawing
ellipses accurately. Oh.
That's it?
It especially in technical engineering,
architectural, surveying drawing. That's
it?
Professional versions, blah blah blah.
Okay, so actually it's just like
for drawing. That's interesting. So,
there is no uh
Wasn't there any mechanical
usage such as
in
windmill or such?
Let's ask it.
No. The trammel of Archimedes
was not used in windmills or similar
large-scale power transmission machinery
like mills, engines, or historical
wind-water-powered
devices.
Its core motion converting two
perpendicular straight line
sliding movements into elliptical path
or vice versa is elegant and
mathematically perfect, but it has very
limited practical mechanical
applications
beyond generation generating or
following ellipses.
Wow.
That's interesting. So, that Okay, so
uh do I trust AI? Yeah, pretty much on
this
from my experience. So, there's no
actual uh
mechanical use. I thought there was.
Okay.
That's about trammel of Archimedes.
Okay, yeah. Well, look look today you
have all uh Okay, those are like
uh more
uh elaborate mechanisms. Lots of YouTube
you can watch.
Very pretty pretty these uh things,
these toys.
And you can build. So, there's like you
you can have like more than one uh you
know, more than two lines. You can have
several lines and they
do interesting stuff.
Anyway, so
back to Yeah, so this um
GeoGebra I was trying to show you. So,
if you um can we clear
Can we clear the uh dots? So, anyway, if
you have a fixed point on on this bar,
then it will trace out an ellipse. So,
you can see. Let's regenerate uh for
example.
Yeah.
So, you can trace out all kind of
ellipses. So, that's one of them.
But, if you change the distance of the
fixed bar,
you see they trace out a different
ellipse. Anyway, so that's
So, that's GeoGebra, which is uh plain
geometry software. It was open source.
But then, about 15 years ago, they they
changed it to a closed source, very
nasty.
Because, well, you know,
because, you know, I've been using this
plane curve um
application since like 1990 1990s.
And uh okay, there's a lot questions.
So, I'm going to answer it in a bit,
okay? So, I've been using them like
there's lots of but
but each one one by one they went away.
I want something public, you know, so
everyone can use it
without having to pay, right? So, I
build a lot applications, but then after
few years this application went away,
you have to pay or something. So, you
but then I found it, you know, 15 years
ago around like 2008,
there is GeoGebra,
which is one of the open source because
there's quite a lot, okay? There's quite
a lot.
So, GeoGebra is becoming, you know, very
popular. So,
so I use it.
But then, after a few years, they they
they closed source. So, I have like 50
or something
uh GeoGebra GeoGebra files on my website
that you cannot use.
In order to use them online, you can see
uh let's say let's go to the top.
GeoGebra, where is it?
Uh
info about this site all these are very
old, okay? So, but you know, like what's
new? Like this is what's new 15 years
ago.
Um
plane geometry software, so GeoGebra.
So, I have, you know, lots of GeoGebra
files I build.
But
it's all kind of wasted because then one
day they became private.
So, you cannot use them.
You have to In order to use them, you
have to go through their um
their website. So, this is hosted on
their website. So, you have to upload
like if you look at the source code for
this page,
you see, you actually go through their
website.
You see that.
You cannot run it locally. So, this very
nasty open-source scumbags. You see,
open source is such Basically, the
situation is that
when you are student, when you want to,
you know,
when you are student, you don't have
money, you use them, and you create
things, you say it's open source,
everyone can use it,
trying to make yourself, you know,
popular.
But once
your software become valuable, it has a
value, like like
can make you a living,
then people close source it. Happens all
over, you know, or they get sold to
Microsoft, you know, they they get sold,
you know, once you once your software
has value, you forgot about your
ideology about oh, you know, this needs
to be
open source for the good of people. You
forget about it once you can get money
out of it. So, these open-source
scumbags
that happened to GeoGebra.
So,
I wasted my time, you know, there's
nothing I can do, you know, I don't want
this so you have to run this on their
website.
Because, you know, why do they do that?
Because at that time Java is it they
were written in Java.
But
around 2008, Steve Jobs killed Flash and
then Java also went away. So, they they
have to port it to JavaScript. You see,
2008 is a time when
JavaScript becoming popular. So, they
they killed the Flash from, you know,
Adobe and was from
Macromedia. They also killed Java.
You know, Java is like
very
tedious.
So, GeoGebra was written in Java. It was
a big open source thing.
But then
they have they have to rewrite it. They
have to pull it to JavaScript. That's
when they started to close source.
You know, so so then all my like all my
50, you know, hundreds uh GeoGebra files
become basically dead.
So, I have to
So, basically then I took me like
several months to
to to to recreate them and then link
them
uh link them to the to their website.
You see, this is their website. You can
actually go to it. So, for example,
close that. So, let's go to the website.
geogebra.org
and you need to turn on JavaScript.
Very nasty. Very nasty the open source
[ __ ]
You see, this is my this is my, you
know, file. I have to
I have to put it on their website.
That's the only way to run it.
Kind of the only way. The other way is
you download Java then you you know,
which is like 1 GB or something. Then
then like you have to be a programmer.
You have to download Java. You have to
download a Java applet. Then you have to
install it, you know,
that's the other way to run it.
So, so this was very big disappointment
and problem for me because now
you know, I have all these files, but
I'm forced to like use their website.
Anyway, that's a problem. That's one of
the story like lots of stories about the
nasty open-source
ideology, okay?
So, uh
five
five uh point conics is also very
interesting. Five points defines a conic
section, okay? That's a very interesting
thing
of projective geometry, okay? Very
interesting.
Anyway, that's just algebra, so
So, okay. I was going to, you know,
[ __ ] You know, I was going to code
Wolfram language, but now
we talked about so many other things
now. Uh let's go back to ellipses, okay?
Uh so, we were talking about Yeah, so
let's go back. We were talking about
Okay, we we we like we digressed one
into the other. So, we were talking
about
trammels of Archimedes. So, you can see
we were talking about this.
Then, it can also generate ellipse. You
see, this thing can generate astroid,
but also ellipse.
And
we were trying to find out what's the
application of trammel of
uh Archimedes. Apparently, not much
except just drawing it.
Then, there we were talking about Yeah,
we were talking about these ellipses.
The you know,
uh astroid is the envelope that this
shape of these all these ellipse
ellipses.
Okay, that's why that's when we started
to talk about ellipses, their definition
and and also as a trammel here.
Okay.
So,
anyway, so yeah, I need to redo all
these new animation. Then, um then
there's a lots of the other things. And
also this spectacular optical
properties, okay?
Anyway, so let me just um
you know,
the the talk is not good because what I
really want to do is code.
So, let me see the comments, okay? So,
guess
Does the world obey the rules of
mathematics or is mathematics just a
tool that explains the world? Well,
that's a philosophical question, okay?
That's a philosophical question.
Uh
and according to some school of
philosophy, it's just meaningless.
That's sort of question, okay? It's like
not very useful.
Okay, so grinding rice, apparently, no,
they didn't use that to grind anything,
the trammel.
So, Beatons says, "I think a woodworker
would always use two pins and a string
to lay out an ellipses." Oh, okay,
that's
I guess woodworkers, they are familiar
with that.
Uh
then user says, uh
a chicken egg situation. Yeah, that
mathematics kind of
By the way, chicken and egg, that
paradox, the uh
egg came first.
Please do coding, okay? Yeah, so let's
Okay, so let's do coding. So,
Well, what I want to do is Okay, let's
go let's do some coding, okay? So, let's
see how long we've been talking.
Uh we can No, no worry. So, we talked
for 31 minutes. We can we there's we you
know,
let's go to my GitHub. So,
my Git directory, then generate, then we
can see lots of plain curve uh
stuff.
Code that I need to improve.
Then the other day we did this uh
then let's see um
Okay, so
So this code, by the way, this code of
course is available on my website. Just
search for
you know, just go to this page, search
for
uh
Xao Wufan
language packages by Xao Li. You'll find
all these
packages for doing plain curves, like
all of them on GitHub.
Allows you to draw all of these.
So
So the the ones that we are trying to
rewrite recently are these uh is this
one.
Plain curve generator packages. They
They create animations for plain curves,
okay?
And that's the one you are looking at
here.
Okay, so
What
um
Please I'm coding. So
Diego, are you like um
Are you a student?
Have you been coding Wolfram language
before?
According to some people, drawing
circles in your spare time is a waste of
time, but here you are.
You mean the uh the philosophical
questions? Well
not really.
No, that's different, okay? You see, let
me
>> [laughter]
>> You see, I'm very much into philosophy.
So,
in other words, I'm a thinker.
But, your analogy is not making sense,
you see.
You know, first of all, the question,
does the world obey the rules of
mathematics or is mathematics just a
tool that explains the world?
That's a kind of the classic
type of things of philosophy. That's a
classic
uh
philosophical kind of type of question,
okay?
Now,
but I'm saying
So, I made a comment. I'm saying that
this specific question is useless. It's
rather very useless. It's extremely
useless, okay?
Uh but but you are kind of saying, well,
yeah, but drawing circle is also
useless, but we are drawing circles,
right? You know, we are writing code to
do this. No, not really.
Drawing circles is extremely useful. You
know, it's not just useful. It's like
without drawing the without the ability
to draw circles or even ellipses,
you wouldn't have sciences. You would
not have engineering. You would not have
cars. You you would not go to the moon.
You don't have computers. You don't have
um
you basically go back to
like you cannot even build pyramids.
Okay? So, pyramids was built 4,000 years
ago. Actually, 4,000 or was it like 800
8,000?
So, you would not even have pyramids.
You would not be able
when when when you are unable to draw a
circle.
Okay? To draw a circle you need to
understand the principles of circle.
There are several aspects. You need to
know the theory of a circle. Like what
is the definition?
Why is it defined that way? Circle.
Circle is defined as a uh
uh the locus of points that's
equidistant to a single point, fixed
point. Okay. So, that's a definition,
you know, that ties to what we are doing
today. Circle, the definition of a
circle is locus of points
such that it's equidistant to a single
fixed point. That define a circle.
And a circle is also a
uh
A circle is a special case of ellipses.
Okay, so actually we were talking about
curves, so let's
uh do some more talking about curves,
okay?
A circle is um
you know, so we were talking about
ellipses, so let's go there. So, a
circle is a
special case of ellipse.
Okay.
Now, so the ability to to draw a circle,
you know, this theoretical part and it
becomes very deep. Okay, because a
circle is a two-dimensional sphere.
You you can go higher dimension. In in
3D you got a sphere, a ball. In 4D you
got a four-dimensional sphere. You can
go to 5D. So, you you go to uh it became
very
advanced esoteric mathematics. Or is
basically just a circle, the most
primitive concept of mathematics. Like
this is the circle is the most
primitive.
Circle and line, okay? Circle and line
is the most primitive curve
in human history in mathematics. In in
any engineering, you need to know circle
and line, okay? The most fundamental.
And circle is just if you talk about the
theory of circle is tremendous. It's
like um
it's like you can cover almost the in
well, the the the big chunk of
modern mathematics just by talking about
circle. For example, in circle, you need
pi, which is the ratio of the diameter
and the circumference of a circle.
Pi.
When you talk about pi, you you get into
lots of things like real number, normal
number, normalcy of the number. You get
into uh
then you also get into philosophy like
why
why is there a number that just never
repeats and you know,
what you know, is it possible like pi in
some gazillion digits suddenly you will
you will just see all ones. You know,
it's
you know, like the the the number will
spare our God. You know, if you go on,
you know, or if you can, you know, if I
recite 100 digits from my mouth
and it so happens to be the
billions of billions of billions of
power of the power of the power of the
power of pi
if I just utter those, you know, let's
say 100 digits, then suddenly the earth
will collapse. I will go into the new
dimension. Is that possible? How do you
know?
That's philosophy. How do you know? You
don't know. Because we never did we we
we never did it and nobody can prove it
won't happen.
You know, that so we talking about pi is
a lots of things. Then the theory of uh
random numbers that's like very deep.
The definition of random numbers, okay.
Randomness. So
so that's also that you know, that came
from a circle. Pi.
Then um
so so back to back to um back to what we
were talking about. So, the ability So,
that's a theory part of the circle. The
practical part of the circle is ability
to
draw a circle. Because without
be able to draw
at least somewhat accurate circle to
your needs, you cannot build a wheel.
You cannot build lots of things. You
cannot build, you know, you cannot build
pyramids.
So,
you
you know, and and also understanding the
circle that like it has to do with
uh rotation of the Earth and the
astronomy. Because without basic
astronomy, we all die. Because we don't
know when it's going to get cold, when
it's going to get hot, like the seasons.
Then you can
you can't plant crops,
you know,
or you you don't know where to move, you
know, you can't hunt even hunt and
>> [laughter]
>> you know, because animal animals
migrate. You know, the birds can tell
the seasons. They kind of So, so do
humans, but you need to know
like the circle, okay?
You need to figure out things. So, a
circle is extremely practical, okay?
Extremely.
Now,
the typical classic philoso-
philosophical problems. Why am I talking
about these like for for the past 10 10
10 minutes like these these like useless
things? Because I'm a philosopher, okay?
So, I'm addressing this thinking
thinking issue about the uselessness of
philosophy.
So, so I'm pointing out that your
analogy is very
It's It's It's just It's incorrect. It's
It's In other words, it's bad
philosophy, okay?
Uh so so because the circle to draw a
circle is extremely practical.
Meanwhile,
questions such as like this this
specific question of philosophy about
whether math come first or the world
come first, that's um
that's kind of like
the most useless
question in philosophy, okay?
I would say that's like I would say
that's the most of all philosophical
questions, this type of question is kind
of the most useless.
It so happens to be, you know, it so
happens that you were asking the
question. So, this is
this is like my analysis. And well, you
know,
you don't have to believe me, but but
but because this this type of question
is like
this this type of philosophical question
that is like that's part of meta
metaphysics, okay? Which is
akin to
like does God exist?
Um
you know, is is is kind of like
in in that type of philosophical
question.
And ultimately, it's I mean I mean even
the the question about whether God
exists is more important, more useful
than about
whether math come first or the world
come first because
if you ask about whether God exist,
there is a fundamental
need for human to ask that question.
You know, we we want we want to know, we
need to know where we came from. What's
our purpose? That that's why we ask
whether God exist.
We've been asking that question for
thousands of years.
And in fact, in all religions, not just
the Christianity or Islam or Judaism,
the Abrahamic religions, but also in
Buddhism, in other
religions, basically God means like a
creator.
So, we get into the creation
fable. Like
how do you think where where we came
from?
So, that's like the question about the
whether God exist. That's a fundamental
need of human animals need to know.
And why do we need to know? Like we
don't know either. Like Like what what's
the meaning of like the soul or the
brain or consciousness. Like what We are
AI becoming intelligent. It's kind of
kind of like that. We don't know.
>> [snorts]
>> So, but we do know. But we just need to
know. Like
where where where we came from? Does God
exist?
So, that is why that question is even
more like fundamental. That's uh
we've been asking that question.
Even though that question is part of
metaphysics and
turns out is kind of like one of the uh
most useless part of philosophy.
Because
in this
field of philosophy of metaphysics,
basically you go roundabout. You never
arrive and at anything like useful. The
whole
like the whole endeavor about the field
of
uh metaphysics
part of philosophy is is just about is
almost like just like thinking
masturbation, you know? You just sit
there, you know? You just think about,
you know? You feel good about thinking
about things. You're pondering, okay? It
doesn't actually do anything.
That's kind of summarize metaphysics.
The the the type of philosophy of
meta-physics, okay.
Anyway, so this
we ventured into um
philosophy, okay.
So,
So, [laughter] I don't know if we are
still coding.
Okay, so um
So, does that
do I make sense? I mean on the on that
question. I just like to talk about
things and especially because I'm a
thinker.
So,
that's why I'm talking about this
subject.
Using Wolfram as credible data sources
currently, but I need to dive deeper
into creating Wolfram packages. Why are
you rewriting plane curve generator?
Um
Well, I'm rewriting it because this is
written in like 1995.
Okay, so after 30 years, there's quite a
things a lot things that has changed.
So,
I updated this package about a year or
two ago. So, it
it runs in you know, in today's Wolfram
after 30 years.
Actually, that that it
it works before it too, but anyway.
So, basically you want to update it
after a long time because you can
there's a lot of things there's a lot
new functions that make will make your
code run faster. For example, there's a
list animate, there's a manipulate in
Wolfram language. You can interactively
manipulate like they create um
you know, like um so, for example, this
for example, we just did this. Just copy
the code
and go to the Wolfram language and just
paste it.
Shift enter to run it and uh make it
font large and move it here.
And uh
Okay, so you can see this manipulate.
That's new. That's this this thing is
new like about
10 or 15 years ago.
This interactive thing.
It wasn't there. So, you can You see,
you can You can drag and
drag and move and uh
stop that. And you can make it go faster
or
you know, or or slower.
It wasn't there. So,
so you add a lot features, you make a
lot changes to that. You can also
improve a a lot code. And also, the the
other big reason. So, anyway, the
package I already updated, so it's out
there.
But
I need to change it now more because I
want I don't want it to be a package
anymore. So, I want people to
for example, when they see this
animation,
they can grab the code right here. Just
copy it
and go to your Wolfram code and paste it
and it'll run.
You don't have to Oh, by the way, I need
to install a package. Where do I
download it? Where do I find the
package?
Which one is it? You know, you don't
have to do that. Well, because, you
know,
in the past 15 years, we have the cell
phone. Like on cell phone, you don't go
install packages.
You know, it's like You know, the world
technology changed. So,
it's better today you just have the
code, you know, right there people can
grab instead of like
here, you know, like what you know, a
collection of um
packages, you know.
So.
Check.
Okay. So, I talked for long. Maybe I
should shut down. So, we didn't get to
code actually. So, no problem.
Because I'll be continuing doing this
like for
probably years until I, you know,
So, this tomorrow we going to do
continue to do this
um
lots of fascinating
uh these
things.
Um
that's psi. That's the most fundamental
function in mathematics. The most fun
the most important function, psi.
Trigonometry is quite interesting
because you you, you know, who would
think trigonometry is just about
triangles? Triangles the the ratio of
the angles and, you know, the length and
angles.
That's trigonometry. Trigonometry is
also the first fundamental science along
with line and circle.
Trigonometry, triangles. Okay, you need
to know the ratio.
Given what angle, then you have certain
ratios, you know.
And it turns it turns out it's it's so
critical. Trigonometry is like the
fundamental like
together with
line and circle.
It's most fundamental branch of
mathematics, you know, without you
cannot have astronomy. You You need it
you know, Pythagorean Pythagorean
theorem. You need it because
without you there's nothing you can do.
You cannot, you know, you don't know you
die, you know, all humanity die. You
know, because you don't know you don't
know the seasons. You see? Mathematics
developed because
we need to know the seasons. That's the
like the the the first ever application.
You need to know the seasons. Like And
how do you know the seasons? You look at
the moon.
You know, the the moon, the sun, their
position, the stars.
So, from 10,000 years ago, you look at
the you know, that's how
you can know the seasons. When when is
going to be summer?
Like when when is the your flower is
going to bloom? When is some certain
animals you will see?
You know, so so that's astronomy. And
you know, and so when you look at moon
so you need to know a distances and it
turns out so the most fundamental
math math is trigonometry.
You know, just triangles because you
know this length, you know that length,
then you can figure out the other length
and and angles, you know.
And so then
trigonometry,
it you know, you you thought it's basic
geometry, right? You thought it's just
you know, just triangles. But no no,
trigonometry is is what sine cosine is
about. With the they are smooth
functions, okay? They they are circular
functions.
They are the functions that just waves
that smoothly repeats.
And that lies in like the most That's
the most important function in physics.
Sine sine cosine.
How
You know, they are they
because you need you you need basically
this periodic thing, this wave thing.
Wave. Sea wave, you know,
you know, wave radio wave magnetic
you know, wave, you know, this wave
thing.
This wave thing is sine cosine, which,
you know, sine cosine tangent they are
all just sine, basically. They are all
just sine, and and and it just came from
the ratio of the triangle, okay? So,
from a ratio of a triangle, you got this
uh
sine cosine thing, okay? So, let me show
you this animation.
So, that animation actually we also need
to update. So,
sine cosine is somewhere here. So, you
know, I need to like there's a a lot
things I need to
uh improve on this. So, where is uh sine
cosine era of analytic geometry, okay?
Uh
sine curve, okay? Sine curve the
spectacular
uh
artwork, visual artwork based on sine
cosine mathematics.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay.
So, you can see this this okay, so we we
Okay, we need to generate this Okay, we
can Can we generate it? Yeah, we can,
you know, so but because, you know, this
is too small, so I need to update it.
So, you see
sine cosine. So,
and
So, here's GeoGebra, and you see so you
can see
uh how do I
that.
Uh let A be a point on A, and let D be
the drag C2 trace the curve drag CO,
okay? So, oh, yeah, here. So, you see
you see as you rotate you you, you know,
the as the time goes on
and as you as this this point E rotate
around the circle
with the time. So, this distance, this
on the on the circle is the same
distance as that.
And the the the Y axis, the this sine
curve is just the
the height, okay? The height of this
point E. So, that's how that's how the
sine curve came from.
Basically, triangles, you know, this
just this
triangle.
So, it's amazing, okay? So, anyway,
that's kind of random digression. So,
sine sine cosine trigonometry began.
They they are the like the
the most fundamental
of mathematics.
So, I think that's it for today, okay?
Like random chat.
Hiksa, so
did I answer your question, Diego?
Hiksa, how do you learn new stuff
nowadays, especially on IT field? Do you
watch video lessons, read books?
I almost never watch videos.
You know, I find it very interesting the
Zoomer generation or starting late
millennial, like starting around
let's say 2015.
The you know, actually before that, like
the the younger people, they don't they
don't read.
You know, when they learn new
programming language, they don't read
books or
or online or documentation. They like to
watch videos.
Back in like 2012, I learned that.
I find it amazing because when you watch
a video, like usually it's 1 hour,
right? They they teach you they don't
like but you can't get the detail like
the books or online, you know, tutorial,
you can
scan and skip. You can quickly know
what's going on.
You know, you can have a idea. But, with
video you have to watch second by
second. It's very slow and
you don't know who's the guy, you know,
like you have to
needs to be a good teacher, right?
Professor.
Uh but, it's kind of slow, you know, it
takes 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, you
know. But, with books or online, you can
quickly jump around and you can learn
you know, you can understand in depth.
But, that's but, turns out
the late millennial zoomers, they
you know, I I I usually I say they they
they are brainwashed. They became
incap- incapacitated in some way.
They became unable.
Because
for certain, okay, so, you know,
sometimes I wonder, you know,
am I saying
what am I saying? Is it really true?
But, I think it's for certain.
Reading books
reading about especially when you are
learning programming language, reading
is actually
far more efficient method.
Uh
at least twice as efficient. Like, if
you learn a new programming language by
video, you spend 1 hour in the same
amount of time, 1 hour, if you read, you
you you would benefit you would learn
like twice as much, minimum. Okay. So,
in my opinion, reading is like far more
efficient
than watching a video
for programming language. But, the thing
is, you see, you need to have the
prerequisite of learning the ability to
to read information.
And especially like for programming
languages, you need to already know a
programming language. So, unless you are
the first time, you know, you don't know
anything about programming languages,
then it's good to have a video or
uh
another person teach you like professor,
you know. But once you know
a programming language, I think it you
know, it's far more efficient for you to
learn by reading
you know, text.
Okay, but
I I learned a lot. Most young people,
they don't they they don't know this.
They just need videos to to tell them
what to do.
So, that's amazing. So, I would
recommend read, okay?
I almost never watch video. I watch
video rarely
and
only
rarely and only only usually so oh
usually I know the guy is a professor,
okay? He's professor for sure or or
someone I admire like Stephen Wolfram,
you know, well-known
uh computer scientist.
Or well-known programmers in some case,
very well-known. So, I know for sure the
guy
is not just good but but above, you
know, it is is accomplished.
So, those people
and
uh
I think that's it. Even those people, I
don't watch them too often like once
once in a while one or two videos
because watching videos is like you you
waste well, it's not a waste of time,
but you
but you have to sit there and you know,
wait for them to say this and that, you
know, it's like
too procedural, too slow.
Um yeah, so I usually I usually I don't
watch videos at all. Um
but so what how do I learn today? Today
let me tell [snorts] let me tell you a
short story. Today well, the the the
shortest answer is that today I just use
AI a lot, tremendously. Like did did
didn't we just ask AI
uh for something? Yes.
So, I just asked AI uh yeah. So, for
example, we asked about trammel of
Archimedes, okay? So, I asked a lot AI
questions. It used to be web search, but
AI beats web search.
I talked about this before. So, like
before, we like usually my questions are
esoteric, maybe math mostly esoteric
questions. Questions like nobody ask,
you know, some like technical details
about programming languages design.
You know, so I used to search the web,
then it takes a few hours, then usually
you can't find it. You got lots of
links, you have to, you know, read them,
see who are they, then then you have to
also check who who is the guy who wrote
it, you know, like
their writing style differs, then you
have to make sure they are correct, you
know.
So, before AI, you you you spend few
hours, and sometimes you don't get the
question. I don't get the answer to my
question. But with AI today,
I've been using a lot, you know, I've
been you know, we've been all we know
all know it. So, I ask AI every day. So,
it's amazing. Like in 5 minutes, I
usually get I can get like the answer to
my question, my esoteric
question that you cannot easily find on
the web. Some questions you cannot
easily You cannot even phrase it. Like
there's no It It's hard to like
like often it's a It often it's a case
some questions you can't phrase it. Like
because you don't know what's going on.
So, you have to kind of probe it, you
know.
But with AI,
it can help you significantly. Like it
it can help you
to know what what's the question you are
asking.
Of course, you don't blindly just trust
AI. That's That would be idiots like
Zoomers today, you know? You don't You
don't trust the AI. You must have
already have like experience like me.
Me for for example, I've already
I'm obsessive about reading encyclopedia
since 1990s before this Wikipedia. I go
to I go to the library every day like
basically every day. I sit there for
several hours a day in libraries, in
public libraries, in Mountain View here,
in university libraries, in Foothill
College, De Anza College libraries. I I
know all the libraries. I go I just go
there. That's what I do, okay? I go to
library, sit there, and read
encyclopedia, you know? This 1990s,
there's no Wikipedia.
And other books, of course. Then you
have to search research for books, you
know? But But then
after year 2000, then, you know,
Wikipedia, you know,
it became so convenient. So,
it beats libraries, okay? Wikipedia, no
question about it.
Wikipedia, like in 5 minutes I find what
I can find on, you know, what
my question answer to my question on
Wikipedia in 10 minutes.
But before Wikipedia, it's like several
days. You got to go to the library. You
got to do research. You got to, you
know, pick up books, heavy encyclopedia,
or maybe it's not in library, or the
book is borrowed out. You have to wait.
Then you go to you you Then you got a
stack of books.
You know, you then you have to check
which page answer your question. Not
here, you know,
something like that, okay? That's
research.
You know,
in
So,
so since Wikipedia 20 years ago, it's
just amazing.
You know, Wikipedia began in 2003 or so.
Okay, so I would say it became
pretty mature by year 2010.
Okay. And it's better and better, but
but but then it got corrupted by deep
state, okay. Anyway,
I talked about Wikipedia detail in my
past videos.
So, anyway, in general, especially for
mathematical questions, physics,
engineering, you know, this kind of
questions we and programming languages,
Wikipedia is just tremendous.
5 minutes of Wikipedia yeah, beats, you
know, few days,
you know, in the 1990s.
Okay.
Then, but today so but in the past 3
years this AI, you know, like AI just
beat Wikipedia like by by by another
magnitude AI. So, it's amazing.
Like Wikipedia some some questions like
especially for example,
research questions about programming
languages
like for example, you know, the design
of programming language strings.
Many questions you can you know, there's
no
article about it, you know, there's no
article. You have to
you know, it it it's not like an article
about that topic.
So, anyway,
so that's you know, if so, to answer
your question, how do I learn today?
It's almost like
AI, okay.
And I don't watch videos.
And by the way, I don't I don't read
books neither. I stopped reading any
books since about 2000
5.
So, about 20 years ago
I
basically stopped reading any books. I
don't read books at all because
like video book is kind of very slow.
You know, like for example even
mathematics, you know, like especially
mathematics, you know, books academic,
you know, books textbooks
undergraduate textbooks or graduate
mathematics, you know, mathematics
textbooks on
on geometry on differential geometry
sometimes they are big you know,
you know, anyway so the the book
it's very slow because when you read
book especially mathematics you have to
the author is like usually
kind of like formality obsessed you
know, typically very formal and verbose
professor type. So they don't
they don't like they don't teach you
like right away like things they they go
over like preface then why why do I
why is why why I wrote this book who is
this book for then you know, what am I
going to cover why don't I cover other
topics, you know,
then pedagogical you know, things like
that then they start to talk about first
chapter prerequisite, you know, this is
very slow.
So I I stopped
you know, basically reading any books
but I prefer encyclopedia. I always just
prefer encyclopedia. So even for
mathematics, you know, I want to know
certain you know, topics in math I dive
into right away then if something I
don't understand I try to you know,
learn them. So
I don't read books
much.
>> Okay, I think that's it. I need to stop
watching videos. Yeah, read more. AI is
really good. AI is really good, but
sometimes they get completely wrong.
That's true, too. So, when we are we got
to be careful. We don't know what's
going on.
Um
you know, so few
We we did a live stream, you know, a
week or a few weeks ago about
watching AI. So, we don't know what will
happen, you know.
The potential for
complete misleading lie of AI is very
big. Like, you know, it could be like
that in a few years all, you know, we we
just going to be lied by AI. And we
don't even know it.
And in fact, AI is such such powerful,
such that
just like the Zoomers got brainwashed to
watch video, they lost the ability to
read. They lost the ability to like
understand things by observing and read
and do.
You know, they kind of lost it.
But in a few years, we might lost the
ability of anything, you know, we just
need AI to tell us what to do.
That's very possible, you know, so.
But we don't know what's what will
actually happen, you know, because then
there's also a lot people who's like
just
idiots. Like they are the drama, the
[ __ ] you know, they they they are
streamers or they are, you know, they
are popular. They have 1 million
followers. They're going to tell you
what's about AI. Oh, AGI is going to be
this way, so you need to do that way.
You need to use this, you know, whatever
the current cloud or whatever AI
machine.
And and this or that those are
bullshits, okay? That those are scums.
Despise see
Late Malaysian and Zuma scums. Why are
they doing it? Because money.
You know, especially those, you know,
with a few big followers, medium
followers on YouTube. They're telling
you what to do.
Scums. Not all of them, but most of them
are.
They are doing it. They are just
[ __ ] [ __ ] for money.
Unlike me, you know, creating like very
boring videos.
Okay, that's it. Um
Yeah, go Wikipedia. Bye, guys.