good morning everyone good morning
everyone
welcome to another episode of discuss of
Gaston talk-show today's is 2019
December 7th Saturday 12 o'clock
San Francisco time good morning guys
Papa moon and Nabi and named eleven so
today's topic is half of it is gonna be
Emacs and live coding some Emacs stuff
and yes
Emacs coding and let's see talk-show
it's in a description okay so today's
topic is in Addis in the description so
we can see I'm gonna talk something
about something ok so start command log
mod so you can see all my Emacs commands
on the left window ok there so let me
adjust the window and we are good to go
so any questions you guys any anything
interesting type in the chat ok then we
are going to begin but first of all let
me show you this ok so I'm working on
this page this is Windows shortcut
frequently asked questions you know some
how to disable the sleep key how to
disable caps lock how to disable windows
logo key and things like that how to set
a key a shortcut to launch an an app so
this is returned in 2009 beginning 2009
so I every few years I try to update it
and you know writing a blog is not easy
I mean there's lots of tedious tasks
anyway today I found for example you see
it says here it says here no built-in
way to do that with Windows Vista or
Windows 7 so disable caps lock or
windows logo key you cannot do that do
that with Windows by default you know
using Windows GUI at least not in
Windows Vista Windows 7 so this article
is videoed but anyway I noticed the word
building and I don't like it because I'm
particular about about this kind of
things you see the the word peel in
there I'm using here it has a - the the
word building using a - is actually
standard so let me look up so let me
show you okay so you call a command to
look up the web search so you can see
merriam-webster dictionary that by the
way that's a what's dictionary okay
don't use that use the this one or free
dictionary calm so anyway you can see
the building word it's either building
without - or with - but but I don't like
that so I what I want is for example let
me let me do this okay so what I want is
building without - and but before I make
a change I want to be sure that this is
also Papa because you know I'm
meticulous things English writing Styles
even though I do make grammar mistakes
but almost the way you see my writings
almost the every way down to how things
are spelled is in control you know I I
am in tight control of it so you they
are there are a lot ignorant programmers
you know a Native American you know
English speakers white people they see
my writings they say oh sorry it was
writing no you don't know how to write
okay because well I'm not going to give
into a history about a whole whole thing
or my qualifications because I've done
that in previous videos so anyway the
the I want to the building word to be I
want to without be without - but usually
before I do that I have to make sure
that is accepted for example so I let's
search
and and so far the merriam-webster I
have not found it to say that the
building without - is also standard I
mean it's a variation so I haven't
sensing that but however you see it in
wiki Wiktionary this grassroots version
of not here Wiktionary okay so for
example here see also all pages
beginning with Pio in that with a hyphen
or Pio in without - or filled in with a
space so actually that does not that
does not mean it is you know so actually
right now I'm not sure I'm not sure I
want to change so far actually it needs
more research oh there it is I found it
here yeah I saw it before so you see the
word you see the on Wiktionary they have
built in without without - or space or
and they say you know they say also see
building with a - in space anyway so
here is an instance of confirmation you
know meaning that at least this is
somewhat popular usage orthography by
the way this kind of thing is called
orthography you know because you know if
you want to go technical about this this
is not about spelling because it's it's
about involving - in space or without so
this is called orthography you know
technically speaking in linguistics and
also also you might ask the more general
question about in English writing you
know we have terms of words with -
sometimes you know the similar cases
like this building like sometimes you
have have for example email email begin
with you know it's central electronic
mail and it begins with a - e - mail
then then then it just today it's just
email you know one
without - or space and in fact today you
might often see people just say mail
mail it to me
meaning email sometimes okay so you can
study on these kind of issues you can
study the history of the changes you
know the evolution of words with
hyphenated words or not so that is the
so that is my exploration on you know
when I'm doing writings and you know it
went into attention into lots of lookup
and research so actually I was going to
change all my website building with -
without without a - but I'm not sure
right now I don't want to do it now so
anyway so I'm talking about that topic
so okay so let's close that close that
let's go to today's talk show and let's
go to today's talk show page so Nabi
says Google Ngram viewer shows if it's
popular okay you want to do it good
morning Alan so now we do the research
for me you know Google Ngram Google
Ngram you yeah you can use that it's one
of the tool okay so Google Ingram so so
before we talk about so first of all we
talked about peel in built-in
hyphenation or built in okay or built in
you know so we have three V Asians three
variations and the question is about the
orthography and the evolution of
hyphenated words so that's a topic of
study and meanwhile since we are talking
about that let's go to class were the
English
from the haughty emotions of lexicons
the listing concerns decipherment of
grammar and idioms linguistic allottee
literature and logic allottee this is my
my word wordy english.com website so
let's go to the home page then he says
the lure of vocabulary the depth of
literature the question of style the
logic of linguistics the ills of English
and the pure by writing that's what I do
okay so those of you there are a lot of
people you know they flame me for
everything you know cuz I hate us
because I'm anyway let's you know I I
don't want you know they did anyway so
let's go to the I want to talk about
yeah I want to mention so I collect
vocabularies okay this is another big
topic I did a video about this several
months ago one or two anyway so I have I
have obsession about collecting words
vocabulary so the in fact that's how I
learned English so anyway I just want to
show you I have a collection of
hyphenated words so you can see but by
the way this list is like 20 years old
20 30 years old so for example these are
collection of hyphenated words okay so I
don't have JavaScript there so let's go
to a page where I have JavaScript on
okay so new page why don't we create a
new page okay sorry
- ated words let's see if we can find
that there it is Sawadee English
hyphenated words so we have this is a
collection of heaven and it was okay
that that's a mistake that shouldn't be
like that well okay let's fix it let's
fix it right now let's go back to Emacs
open the page search for h2 wait what is
this actually page - wait where does the
page to come from
oh it such for each one okay so that's a
mistake somewhere that there shouldn't
be there
delete it okay anyway go back here so
you have you can let's do random run so
you have words like hand up at the babe
I forgot what at Billy's oh yeah so
let's read it you know example of the
usage at lip what does it mean so he
says when he was when he was showing how
a next location could be used to query a
database that ran on another company's
server the next machine crashed jabbed
at Beebe Kim D that's how you know it
was life okay so this is from a book on
Steve Jobs so this I read this book in
1998 or something something like that so
the book is Steve Jobs and the net Steve
Jobs and then the next big thing 1993 by
Randle East Rose he is a historian okay
you know he's writing so Steve Jobs he's
a guy who created next machine
do you guys know I have lots of photos
collecting our next machines keyboards
and stuff I wonder if I should go into
that so we have already a laptop a lot
of topics so anyway so you're on this
page you can see all the hyphenated
words so what does ad lib mean so he
says did I give a definition here no
usually I do not give definition do you
know why because it turns out when you
are learning something you learn it if
it's more difficult to learn you
remember it better so I do not give
definitions so if you want to understand
you have to you have to like look up
yourself then you remember so for
example let's search ad lib there it is
intransitive to improvise and deliver
extempore
vanie ously meaning without preparation
so so Steve Jobs is demonstrating is
doing a demo on his next machine very
expensive and the Civic does something
wrong you know the server crashed and he
says that's how you know it was live ok
so you know he's recounting a story of
Steve Jobs so anyway this this this page
is a collection of words with
hyphenation face off remember there's a
movie named face off starring good
morning
the new language do you guys remember
what's who starts in the movies face off
what's his name
he also he's a star and he also starred
in leaving Las Vegas what's his name how
do you so guys do you know so the new
landlord says wait what's the definition
the definition is to improvise and
deliver a extemporaneously ad-lib okay
so that that is ad-lib you know you just
say something on the spot without
preparation
John Travolta and someone else or face
off oh oh yeah right but I was thinking
the someone else guy Nic Cage yes
Nicholas Cage that's tsukai face off
so you know so well we'd I used to do it
I don't do it now I stopped doing these
things like 15 years ago since 2005
since 2010 because you get old and it
becomes anyway you know so it's my habit
and in fact it's my obsession that
whenever I read some some what I don't
understand or not quite sure the exact
meaning I look up and usually I also
write it down so I have a collection of
hyphenated words here so larger for
example larger in life larger than life
about face so we have face off then we
have about face
now about face is like it's like that
you know the is like sharp turn auto
reverse kind of us then you have turnkey
you know turnkey solutions is which some
companies use that name as a company
names turnkey solution double cross good
goody-two-shoes not as a idiom
goody-two-shoes call a sack so anyway so
these are heavy native words now so you
know when you know if you are interested
in linguistics literature writings you
you would be interested in these kind of
things and you want that for example we
can ask can this what we are this what
could a sack ever at some point you know
becomes without the hyphen
you know just see you l de si si si in
this case no it's not likely so we have
avant garde we have cloak-and-dagger in
anyway so we have many of these things
things so that's about hyphenated word
words
okay so let's it's just so let's put
into my sock show page so we have a
record of it of the topics we talked
about okay that's two thing I'm going to
be the comments okay and what a
what what the what the what
what do you mean name 11 and then 11
where does you where do you came from
I also seen resources Tanabe yeah so so
yesterday I was doing so yesterday we
did they talk on on Emacs Stev okay so
let's go to Santa show index page so
yesterday we did let's magnify so we did
this Linux firewall IP table and
networking and how to contribute to
Emacs we we I gave a kind of who is who
in the Emacs staff you know people for
in for the past 20 years
kind of and and the day before yesterday
it's also a big brand it's also a Emacs
topic I did a big rant on Emacs and do
we do so of you Emacs people if you
haven't read it already check it out you
know it's a one hour long video so I
have done a lot videos you know one day
so you know go reco go watch them okay
so you know you guys if you got nothing
to do because many of the topics I'd
repeated but anyway I was going to say
so yes
you know I because of my character I
sometimes I swear a lot and yesterday I
felt bad a little bit because sometimes
you I noticed you know when you
sometimes you like online in online
arguments I I become I swear a lot and
somewhat mean to people you know not to
people but you know I I begin to sway a
lot that's sometimes that's because I'm
not feeling well you know I'm you know
I'm feeling pressure or something you
know there's pain
so anyway yesterday I felt that like I
did some of that unnecessarily
especially I was not I was not you know
I was kind of being mean to but okay but
you know his spot but are you here so if
you are watching about sorry about that
because you know he mentioned he was
talking about unix/linux fire war tool
then I started I started to flame it for
10 minutes saying it's a worst
possible yeah so sorry about that but
okay so that's about that let's let's go
through the next topic so we got a lot
of things to talk about so let's see
so eMac lists so the next two things I'm
thinking of going into email base are
you guys interested like I'm going to do
a live coding of eMac B's I want to do
that and then okay before we do that
let's talk about sponsorship okay you
guys people sponsorship it's time to pay
so you go to my keyboard blog okay and I
have some interesting things I want to
show you okay Sully keyboard
sorry keyboard there it is let's go to
it there's this many interesting things
here okay so let's wait for this video
to turn up it's loading why is it not
showing what the okay go to Casati
keyboard it's trying in Firefox okay so
the video format is wrong anyway that's
a very interesting home a trackball okay
so anyway the thing I want to mention
okay get by a by a fanny pack okay so
this is good for notes this is what I
use actually place my so they actually
let me show you let me demonstrate mine
okay
this is my fanny pack so that's that's
the utility belt of a nerd so this year
so I don't use wallets a lot guys you
know you have wallets I've never
actually I've never used wallet in my
life so this is what I use and so you
guys you guys can go buy it you know I
make some some books and there are some
other interesting things people bought
for my Amazon links I don't know who
they are
so it's anonymous I I just know you know
the things people buy so you can see let
me show you some of them okay so you
guys if you you know you guys go buy it
there is the link and let's look at some
of these things you wait wait for Amazon
to load
so we have here a a water flosser that's
that's an interesting idea you have a
floss for your teeth but now they have a
water flosser I've never seen that
before then you have okay this is a
amplifier for you guys nuts so this is a
2 - this is digital to analog converter
for headphones headphone amplifier okay
74 dollars so for you guys walking
accompany you you go buy it you got
money and for this in order to to use
these of course you need to have a
expensive headphone because otherwise it
doesn't make sense you need to have one
of these fancy headphones hundred twenty
seven dollars okay so let's look at the
next thing and this one is a pressure
cooker and this this one is good for
rice so if you want to test taste the
rice the AC on rice this is what you
want you you buy this okay rice so among
the hackers and gamers or the Mimas
there is the there is a slang rice
something rice something you know I
forgot what it means exactly so what
does it means anyone you know the jargon
among gamers rice something like I
forgot what it means and and it happens
in keyboard community a lot too so this
one is a humidifier okay so it's a four
places that's to dry such as California
you need a humidifier and let's look at
the what's the next one now this one is
for those of you who has who have cats
Nabby so a mess you're doing good
comments
okay guys so this is some kind of cat
cat litter I guess
platinum and platinum platinum slide
easy king of grunting cat litter okay
cat litter stuff and this one a lot of
you will be interested you program
innards this one I need to buy one I
need to buy one for backup so this is
SanDisk one terabyte portable SSD
external drive okay that's that's good
close them close close close okay that's
about that and keyboard stuff
adlib okay addley so good morning sound
toxin so close that and some toxin says
rice as a verb started out referring to
modifying crappy cause with things like
extra lights I think oh but in the tech
world
it's like customizing how your desktop
looks okay yeah okay battle station so
so keyboard block close that back to so
I'm going to start to code email list so
what do you guys think
because eMac beast is kind of you know
technical you know only if you call
d-max
you Cody Mavis view be interested so let
me know ok I wait for one minute you
know if you like him ass stuff say it or
else or else we're gonna see 27 minutes
or else we're gonna talk about Unicode
or stuff so I think I'll just start to
code eMac be spin yeah unless you guys
have something else to say okay okay so
one of the first thing is write a
command to increase font because for
example I close this buffer close reopen
reopen that that is my default font but
when I do a video I prefer the found to
be a bit larger like that so but I want
so I do have a command that changed the
font just by pressing your key you see I
can magnify magnify magnify pressing a
single key but it does not change on all
the other buffers for example I I have a
copy this new page basic here I only
might magnify the current buffer I
wanted to happen to globally for every
window in buffer frame so I want to
write that command and that command will
be easy to write in five minutes so
let's do that
okay so lit before we do that let's see
what Nabi analysis so Nabi says I want
to know how to get paddle style paddle
style linking in Emacs PI Docs style
linking in Emacs what do you mean by dog
style so PI dock so I guess my dog is a
tool for Python and I suppose it's some
kind of linking tool
and you know you run the program on a
Python source code it will possibly
reformat the you know the the formatting
style of the source code and possibly
also give you some warnings so that's PI
doc linking but what do you mean hi doc
styled in t in emacs so I don't
understand okay Nobby say it say it you
know let me know what you what what what
do you mean exactly so Allen says do you
ever use different input methods in
Emacs to type diet diet ryx no I don't
in fact I have a system and I want to
tell you what's the easiest way to do
that okay so let's talk about that okay
how to type dialectics in Emacs I mean
is that what you're the focus of a
question or something else let me know
because are you talking about just one
or two accents in a letter such as
access accented e for example this is
what I do all your talking about for
example I can do these two whoops not
that what is that I forgot okay so for
example you can I can also do that but I
want the oh yeah so I want that okay so
you have the oh these kind of characters
that's how I type it yeah I'm using
right now I'm using the package saw math
input to do it and it's actually one of
the most efficient way to do it
yeah actually so I already started
started to talk about it so it's a if
all you want if you if what you want is
to type math symbols or some of these
characters then the best thing is our
input mod is one of the best things so
let me show you the fact the the
name okay so here is the command name
that's the command name and it's in this
package and you open it go to the top
here is the source code here's a URL you
open the URL showing browser so you can
see that's the URL so you can eat some
ALPA you can download it and use it
it has over 500 math symbols and it's
also you can add your own easily
trivially just by one line you can add
your own so as far as inputting unicode
they are quite a lot ways but one thing
I can tell you is that do not use
whatever the way that is building in
Emacs those are very inefficient okay so
let's go to for example let's search for
Kesari Unicode actually such such folks
sorry Unicode Emacs okay so then you
will find Unicode tutorial here this
page this page talks about all the
things you need to know about inputting
Unicode or related issues such as how do
you find the character's name how do you
find its code point and things like that
so let's copy the page let's put it here
let's put it here then let's also copy
this page and put it here so we can okay
then let's copy that put that there
okay close this buffer save it reopen
magnify show that go to a browser
refresh okay we got the topics layer so
let me go back to read Alan's question
oh yeah so for entering emoji okay
yeah so one of the best way I would
recommend is you just download and use
my package saw math input mod you can
add your own you can add your own emoji
in fact the other way if you do not need
you know the whole set of math symbols
then you can just do it a brief for
example let's say I want to emit emoji
let's say you know actually there are so
many ways to do it okay so example I can
type this hot and I can press the key
using the saw math input mod so you got
a hot and suppose I want let's go to
Unicode okay so let's open my Unicode
website let's see let's say I want a
male emoji Apple okay let's say that
let's say I want cucumber cucumber is a
nice fruit yeah we want that okay so oh
god that doesn't look good
stevia max it's let's go back to Apple
so let's say I have app it looks ugly so
anyway so there's a long story you know
you Emacs the GUI max reaches home and
told people to remove code so that so
that an emoji looks ugly
just like Linux on the Mac because they
don't want the fuchsia snowman don't
want Emacs to be superior then the Emacs
on Linux anyway so suppose I want this
Apple okay so as suppose I want to type
this Apple often so how do I do copy it
go through my a brief way not this go to
my a brief file and just paste it here
okay so let me magnify this so you can
see I pasted that pace here then let's
say APR okay well
say Apple then copy that paste it here
okay so I have this line this is my
Aubry file so evaluate it open a new
buffer now I just type Apple and if you
can't suppose so
some thing and today I ate ate an apple
then become sample so that's how easy it
is so now you can just have all your
emojis here so in fact I have quite a
few of my own emojis for example thumb
up I'm not sure that's the no so good
good tea yeah good tea okay so I you
know that's the thumb Bob and oh my god
you see oh my god that becomes that so I
have some of my own emojis hot ok hot
doesn't walk hot hot tea no so so so
that's anyway so that's how for example
I have quite a few others okay that's
right arrow left arrow you know you can
create yourself
I actually I have a live stream video
about how to set up a brief and
demonstration of all these several
months ago just go to youtube and search
for it so I don't want that evaluate
close okay then shrink and what are we
talking about a brief okay so Emacs a
brief saw e-max breathe okay sorry you
max a review search for it and you'll
find the page ok the page is already
here so o this what I have talked about
it so on this page so guys for for you
guys Emacs users you know just go to my
go to read my Emacs tutorial there's
tons of goodies you know so instead of
everyday people asking me repeatedly how
do you do this or that it's all there
it's all there all you have to do is
just go to take half an hour to read it
okay so that's about Unicode I mean the
said answer I mean the question okay
cool
input method yeah so you know use a
brief a brief is the best if you just
have a few your own emoji you want or
math symbols but if you want a system
like all the math symbols you could use
the Saudi math in put mod that's a
package now again they are quite other
with quite a few other ways to do it but
these two should be enough for you for I
mean for anyone okay so so that's about
that so let's go back here close that
and close close tabs to save memory
Unicode emoji okay let's copy that close
it back to Emacs let's paste it so we
have all these topics where I will put
in a youtube description so later on
people can know what are the topics we
talked about okay how to so how to type
dialect same thing for diuretics you
know for this exit exit accented letters
same thing you know you just create an
emoji
I mean create a brief or or use the some
ass input more so okay so that's that's
about that let's see what's the next
next one let's see yeah we already have
that yeah so let's copy that here
actually so copy that here okay so let's
see the comments like typing JPEG with
the right accent or whatever oh yeah so
that one you can do too
let's get this just to demo that okay so
let's stim on that coffee that qu e PE C
right and then you have a lot of that
there okay so make that that and let's
say QB you know that's a QB for Quebec
and capitalized okay
okay evaluated new buffer magnify QB o
QB q p there we have it so it's super
nice super nice
okay just wanna how you approach these
okay so mo trudeau motored says do you
think it's worth investing time to
closure I find it quite interesting
coming from Opie okay yeah closure is
nice I talked about closure for one hour
in my past video so look for that in
fact I talked about more than once and
these two videos on closure so you know
you might check check on that basically
I like closure the language but I don't
like the way it is intertwined with Java
yeah so I did more than one hour of it
you know check check check the old
videos up that's so that's that's what
I'm saying because I got questions
asking me frequently asked questions you
know just go to my croc show page then
you have an index here or you go to
youtube you you know just search for
sorry closure you'll find it so anyway
so back to heaven edit words close that
lets back go back to start off show I
don't want to Quebec anymore close it
close it reopen magnify and put it here
- native words actually we already have
it okay so actually remove that
okay showing browser so what is so Nabi
says Navi says I see some packages for
Emacs but they can't they come with
their own linters I want to be able to
choose my own
they well they don't come with their own
linters usually they have a command that
cause the external linter program
typically okay yes as far as yeah most
of them do not you know it's not the
case where the interests are written in
Americus itself you can it can be done
of course
yeah but Nobby I don't know what's your
question exactly like show you show a
concrete example like I have a pad like
like you know for example I'm you okay
so I'm using so I just I started to
explore Emacs I'm using this Python dot
Satya
you know a name of the package and in
that package I saw this this command but
it doesn't do something I want you know
if you ask that question you get answers
you know because I it's like I don't
know you know your question is like if
kind of to general I don't know what
what is the you know question so so do
you have Lenny and shrug no I don't know
what is Lenny ku input method
oh that those kind of things I have it
of course I have
so today we let's talk about Unicode
yeah so let's just talk random on
Unicode and I think in fact we can shut
down soon Unicode Unicode tutorial so
let's go to Unicode and we want you know
there's some interesting things like
wait not not this okay so oh I need to
go to my unicode page wait fruit where
is my unicode page yeah you bear fruit
emoji okay so food emoji then you go
down you go down down down then you
you go to actually I want to let's just
go to Saudi Unicode there it is
and go all the way down on the left you
can see some of the interesting
japanese-style
ASCII art you know ASCII art you guys
know ASCII art these are kind of like
ASCII art except they are no longer I
mean you don't you don't call them ASCII
art anymore no you know it becomes
because today you are using Unicode I
mean these are what's known as ASCII art
but the Japanese people are using
Unicode to do it so here is some
interesting examples I've collected and
but also look at the first one okay this
is or text they have very creative you
know they spent hours to create this
text and to you use use text to unicode
characters to create an animation that
is actually 3d that's what they've done
so it's very interesting but then you
also have this Unicode Smiley's a bunch
of Japanese style único Smiley's you
know I have like collected them so that
one is called Lenny I don't know about
that one so anyway you know this this
for fun but in general I don't like this
okay you know why because I'm I'm a when
it comes to text I am kind I want a
formal language okay I do not want any
possible occurrence where the brackets
are mismatched
so in the hole in the entire basically
almost in the entire six thousand
articles of my websites there is no one
place where you only have mismatched
bracket like for example when you are
using a bracket for a smiley for example
let me show you magnify okay so for
example this this is a common smiley you
know but I don't use that okay because
this screws up the the the matching so
you have a matched bracket now so I have
a session about these I don't want that
so the proper way for this to work not
that okay so the proper way for example
I'm gonna call my saw math input so I
wonder smiley act I I press the key and
it becomes that you know the it becomes
an emoji that is the proper way okay so
if you want the smiley these you know I
don't like Smiley's in the first place
not just because the mismatched bracket
but that came later but the the reason
you know in the beginning I didn't like
Smiley's because they you know why
because they are a hack
I don't like hack of any kind I don't
like the UNIX the UNIX the entire Unix
Linux because they are all hacks they
tends to be often hack you know just
make it fast you know and i and i don't
like the word hacker whenever I see
something that's named hack hacking
hacker you know the hacker types they
love it the UNIX philosophy type of
people or Linux people they love it they
enjoyed the power people but when I see
something that's hack I I hate a despise
I despise the word the the concept hack
hacking hacker okay
including the happy hacking keyboard
happy hacking he were the worst keyboard
possible okay so anything else maybe
that's it for today so let's see hey
pollo
Leonie Leonie Paulo and Leonie how do
you copy your key by now do you copy a
key by like if I want to copy mx2 MQ oh
yeah you want to you want translate
right that's what do you mean you want
translation is that what you mean
so you you you you you want what you
wanted to be such that whenever you type
meta X it becomes meter Q is that what
you mean say yes if you know you let me
know I think that's what you sing right
right so if you want to do that let's go
to Emacs Brock okay so you know so this
stays you know the for you guys Emacs
people you know all the people who are
watching my videos just read my
tutorials because I spent 15 years you
know cuz you have the best the most
condensed the the the the amount if you
spend the time on my Emacs tutorial the
ratio of the time spend versus what you
learn what'd you learn divided by the
time span is the maximum of all Emacs
resources out there okay and you are
going to learn the most logically
correct style of concept okay the the
I'm telling you the well you know I'm
saying I'm the best okay but anyway I'm
telling you the you you're gonna get the
best concept that the best how do you
how shall I say it okay so it's almost
it's like a mathematical approach okay
so you so I'll tell you what it is not
okay by by way of communication I can
tell you what it is not then you all
know what I mean by
it is mathematical mathematically the
best or something like that so it is not
for example my Emacs tutorial and also
my other programming language tutorials
what they are not they are not they are
not in a style of storytelling you know
in many many programming language
tutorials they they they they like to
being a stocking a fashion of a
storytelling for example hi guys for
example of for example introduction to
eMac beasts you know they will say oh I
program in this language C++ and Pascal
and one day I did I discover the Magnus
means and oh my god you know they tell a
story like tell or sometimes they they
want to ingest humor like they want the
reading did they want the tutorial to be
funny they like they want to have humors
like a little snippet or some like also
it happens off often then you have a
snippet of quote nonsensical idiotic
quote at the top for example if you read
clue donald donald knuth book the art of
programming in each chapter or section
it will begin with a quote the
idiots
you know if the quote is supposed to be
like somewhat humorous somewhat capture
the spirit of this chapter somewhat cap
you know dislike that okay
and this this is somewhat fashionable
and for example there is a book i think
some of you are reading i don't remember
who the eloquent javascript okay alright
it's a good book okay it's eloquent
javascript it's a good book for
beginners like you never coded anything
before there's a book eloquent
javascript very popular that book is the
epitome of a storytelling style like you
read it you know in one 1000 words only
only 200 words are the actual content
the rest 800 words are about like
setting a mood setting up setting a mood
something like he you know he's telling
your story about peacocks about animals
about whatever so that's it you know a
token JavaScript so I that's the worst
book in the I would not know what it's a
great book but it's a worst writing
style it's English style writing style I
despise the most okay eloquent and but
he is a JavaScript expert he knows I
would say he has more experience in code
in JavaScript than me I would say that
but because he has written JavaScript
compilers in JavaScript but anyway the
the book you know the writing style of
this book that's what I'm talking about
that's it's seeing a style I despise I
mean I don't like okay it this this his
book is a you know it's ap to me a great
example of the storytelling example a
style of writing so in in my programming
language or email is for Emacs tutorials
you see none of it unknown but none of
it every sentence is is to the call you
know it's it's it's essential it's
necessary every sentence okay so that's
so I'm talking about one of the writing
style okay so for I mean is lanista
that's a big topic I can go on about
that for one hour or more so let's see
where am i so let's look at that
programming style okay so we are talking
about writing style of programming
language talk and tutorial and that is
truly a big topic because I'm I'm I am
going to talk about that for 10 hours
because I have a collection I have a
collection of articles on it too dark
for Delta means
in fact I we haven't talked about this
topic for a long time for several months
now
it would be good to talk about it maybe
next day
so what Denis anyway I've just what I've
done is giving you one example for I
mean tutorial reading style or
documentation ran in style
in Python documentation is also the
worst Python Python doc doc for dummies
that the worst one of the worst okay for
example you go to the Python
documentation they have you know that
they have keep these under your pillow
Pete oh my ass okay excuse me I
don't want to I don't want to get into
that to become like angry rant that's
that's that's not needed but anyway you
know you you you do have you know Python
documentation if you have read it wait
wait let me go to where am I
close that refresh close that what is
this page emoji close that Annie
Maggie's basics close side okay eloquent
JavaScript okay close that close that
close doc yeah so Python documentation
you know they they have a would you know
keep this under your pillow that is very
to me you know to my personality is very
you see here right here you see keep
this under your pillow what the idiocy
Python talk you know not you know it's
not just little things like okay this is
fine by the way I'm not this is not
nothing wrong with it it just so happens
that style this little jokes little
humor is not my style
okay that's all I'm saying there is
nothing wrong with that style okay
however the Python documentation is
okay the the the the the the the writing
style of the writing quality the
organization the search ability is pure
so in
that topic is a big topic we are not
going cannot go into so anyway I I
talked about one of the writing style
but the other thing I want to mention
let me mention quickly is that some of
the programming writing styles the for
example Python Python is Python talk is
a great example of the worst
documentation okay so we talked about
the humor or storytelling style of
writing of documentation okay that's one
thing I don't like with nothing wrong
with it
but it's just a style I don't like you
will not see it in my tutorials so
that's one thing now the other thing is
some of the style read programming tacos
or tutorial writing style they they are
taking a some kind of a computer science
approach okay they are taking a computer
science approach now Python doc is a
good example of that in Python dog is
also a good example of a storytelling
it's a possible for example let
me show you this Holika okay so this is
from Python doc and it's it's still
there I'm pretty sure in Python 3.3 you
know this guy he started to say where is
it let's see anyway that's another topic
so I I just want to mention that in some
of the documentation one of the style
that happens frequently over you know
over the programming industry is that
they will take some kind of a computer
science approach you know they like when
you are trying to explain something you
you have a tendency to try to chalk it
up you know you speak fancy jargons like
linked list or memory you start to talk
about memory pointers references you
unnecessarily so you started to talk
like like if you are a computer science
scientists even if you are not I mean
most vast majority of this documentation
they are written by basically idiots
okay basically by students vast majority
of them
unikz man pages Python documentation
everywhere almost everywhere of hacci
documentation you know almost everywhere
they are written not by computer
scientist scientist ed at all they did
they did they don't know they only
heard you know they heard some jargons
from computer science they rotate they
took you know they took some courses in
university so they know some of the you
know the joggers they tend to so these
people they they try to make their
writing field with these words you know
they try to think it's also but it's but
in fact the the so that's a that's
approach ok that's one of the style I'm
talking about one of the writing style
you you see that over Python
documentation is a good example and and
ok so what I'm saying is that this style
I don't like neither ok you will not
find this style in my tutorial at all
you will not see you will not see any
jargon unnecessarily so if it's
necessary you will see it if it's not
necessary you will not see it for
example is it isn't that instance say
said or was it the Einstein says
something I forgot with who exactly they
said you know if you cannot explain
something to a child on the street in
telling in three minutes then you don't
understand it if you guys do you guys
remember that quote that you know clip
from a sauna or hang you know faint
phenomena or something you know if you
cannot explain something to a child on
the street in three minutes then you
don't understand it that is so that's
that in my in my point of view that's
very valid okay so when I read a
tutorial you will not see none of these
jargons because I don't like a style but
by the way that style from you know take
writing things from a computer science
point of view it's not necessarily bad
ok
is actually valid style so what is a
good example of that style Java Java
documentation is good
okay Java documentation is professional
professionally written and it is in a
style that is kind of formal okay formal
so when it has a lot jargons for example
in Java documentation you will see
linked list you will see data structure
array
you know they is formal okay and it's
well that it's done it's written by
people who know that what they are
talking about
unlike the Python and perl
python perl you know lots of
documentation by these people they don't
know they don't know what they're
talking about
okay so that's about that so back to you
know I so this is a you know again III
should do this topic again in next video
but let's go and also actually I've done
a video on Python before so you can
watch that just such folks sorry
on YouTube sorry Python so anyway the
other thing the reason I'm mentioning
this is let me summarize okay I
mentioned two styles tell tell tell a
telltale style of humor you know tell
story style and also the computer
science point of view style these two
style are not my cells okay so you will
not seen of it in my tutorial okay that
that's that's that's why I'm mentioning
it so you know so you can you guys can
read my tutorials if you like that okay
so download news right that's how do you
pronounce his name news is it north of
news is here okay let's see
okay navi download good news I tend to
phone ask the G because maybe I'm
influenced by the new you know a thing
well yeah so it's knuth donald knuth
yeah there so there is okay you know a
oda bouquet there so yeah so so now you
care at least if i don't program me and
computer it by myself okay okay so I
think that's it for today
didn't get my stream notification where
yeah like what
come oh gee oh okay come oh gee
so how do you copy oh yeah so you have a
question oh yeah so okay so polo one
more question so that's it for today so
you go to my Emacs Emacs web page then
you go to you go to my Emacs web page
then you go to oh yeah keep keybinding
so you have this section this section is
all about keys there's a video I have a
JavaScript off so you don't see it you
you go to my website you'll see it so
this is index of or articles ready to
Emacs keybinding and one of them is
talking about key remapping okay so
there it is
so this one so if you want to be map
keys this is what you do so let me see
okay let me check because there are
subtleties I remember so let me check if
I it will does what you want
Oh again by the way here is another way
to insert Unicode and if you are still
here so another way to insert Unicode is
you can define keys to do it for example
ff8 can press a key so and by the way
Paulo there is subtleties so hold on a
second because I remember
you cannot you this you cannot use this
to translate you know meta X to
something because when it involves two
keys it may have problems so let me see
what okay so wait so let's see so anyway
let's just just try it okay so let's
just try it and we'll see let's magnify
so not too big so let's remove sorry max
this mod magnify
okay so remove that so translate map you
want MX meta X 2 meter Q let's say let's
say that okay so let's say T G okay so
evaluate that oh error oh yeah so it
says you cannot do it because
you cannot do it yeah so what is arrow I
don't remember let's see so I don't know
if if that meta X is your particular
specific question or just in general any
key so anyway so if you want to do the
meta something then you may not this may
not work and I I have to look you know I
have to read in detail and because I
wrote this I forgot you know this
written in 2011 Inca code I will check
it so what's Inca code so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching bye
guys
Oh in general okay so in general yeah so
in gently I it's it gets complicated I
don't think I don't think there is a
general wait for you to type any
sequence of characters to be you know
any to be something else because how do
you define you know how do you define
when the key stops that's one thing well
for for meta X so so I don't have the
answer right now because I don't know
because I have to look so for example if
this page doesn't answer you have to go
to eMac based reference then you can
read the details you know so anyway so
that so thank you guys bye guys
now if you like my stuff PayPal and
patreon okay I have links on my website