Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of South Talk Show.
Today is 2020, May 23rd, Saturday,
9:00 in the evening, San Francisco time.
And what are we going to talk about? I
don't know.
So, if you have a question for me, type
with my name on it. So, stalker quo,
stalker
quo ask
asks, "Is Racket worth learning?" That
depends on what you
you know, that depends on you, your your
personality, your situation in life. For
example,
uh a better question would be, "Is it
Does it have market value?" I mean, can
you find a job with that language? And
for that question, the answer is no.
Now, if you are using If you want to
learn a programming language for
studying programming languages per se,
you know, programming languages by
itself by itself,
you know, Racket is
So, if you are academic, you are
experien- experimenting with programming
language features, then Racket
uh the full name would be
The full name would be Racket Scheme
Lisp. Okay, that is the proper name.
Because
because
Lisp, a branch of Lisp is Scheme. Then a
branch of Scheme is Racket. So, Racket
is the Racket Scheme Lisp. You know, you
must do not forget your
um
your parents, your roots. So, Racket
Scheme Lisp. So, if you are interested
in programming language research, uh
Racket is known for that. You know, it's
a pretty good um
you know, you can do that. But still,
uh you know, that is
it's not um
For example, there are
issues that the Racket Scheme language
will not do. For example, the syntax,
the nested parenthesis syntax.
Now, for this language, you can never
change nested parenthesis syntax. You
know, that is why
the people, the PLT Scheme people who
created Racket,
they ditched Racket. Instead, they
invented Pyret.
JTeam90 gave me $200. Oh my god.
$200. So, I'm going to answer JTeam's
question. So, let me finish about the
Racket. So, I have a few articles on
that. So, let's see inside Racket Lisp,
okay?
I don't have a um I don't have a
tutorial for Racket language, but I have
some some, you know, minor stuff. Let's
see.
So,
inside Racket Lisp.
Let me show you. So, let me talk about
Lisp for a little bit. Actually, I
talked about Lisp quite often in my talk
show. Uh, so
some of them are,
you know, good. So, you can go to
YouTube and watch some of my Just go to
search YouTube Sadi. I have quite a few.
I would say at least three of them is
worth watching, including Emacs Lisp.
So, I have a tutorial on Emacs Lisp. I
also have a huge rant about why Emacs
Lisp sucks donkey ass. It's a It's one
of the worst language in modern society.
Uh, especially addressing the Emacs
phonetics. You know, they This, you
know, in programming community, the
hacker types phonetics, typically they
know nothing. They know nothing except a
very extremely narrow view of a uh
specific language technicalities, such
as the Linux people and and the BSD
people. The BSD people, we have an
expert here that is El Cook Luis in our
discussion Saudi this code group. So you
guys, if you have not already joined
this code, okay?
Fantastic people, variegated opinions,
diversity, the real diversity.
So racket So racket list, let's see if I
can find some of my articles. So racket
using Emacs racket mode, okay?
Uh so I have quite
um
quite a lot languages on Lisp.
Uh okay, there is there is one of my
YouTube videos.
Um
and many of them, they become history,
you know, because you know, the in the
programming community, just like society
in general, you have fads and fashions.
They come and go. For example, in
programming, you have patterns, you
know,
uh during 2000s, pattern is all over is
raging all over. Patterns. Every
programmer will mouth about patterns.
Oh, you need to do this factory pattern.
You need to do that this that pattern,
anti-pattern, pattern and and then later
on you have anti-pattern. This [ __ ]
idiots.
But But today, you don't hear about
patterns much anymore. But you must
remember, you know,
many of you are younger generations. You
don't hear about that, so you don't
know. You know, instead, you focus on
what is current fad, such such as such
as JavaScript, React, or Angular, or
React, or this or that library, or
Google Google Google machine learning
library. [ __ ]
But back in 2000s, throughout 2000,
pattern is a thing. Every programmer,
you'll hear it every day. It is a
pattern this or that. Then you have Of
course, you have
uh Agile, you know.
Extreme programming Agile, the the dad
the daddy of Agile is extreme
programming.
Then it becomes Agile and part of the
and they invented unit testing, the EDSL
I talked about that before.
Unit testing and
pair programming, you know, all these
then then
these days we have the social justice
guy.
It's beginning with so we have hacker
types programmer nerds, then you have
bro coders.
You know, bro coders.
They are not nerds, they are social
people but they started to do
programming.
Then today you have the social justice
guy with their code of conduct.
Uh
I've talked about that a code of
conduct. If you see a project open
source, you know, if you see there's a
code of conduct, never ever contribute
nothing to it. Never ever. In fact,
never ever contribute to anything open
source.
Okay, I do not recommend it.
Some of you do, you know, such as Luis.
Yeah, that's fine. But my point is that
remember
remember when you are contributing to
code
to the open source, you know, the open
source code
what you might be thinking is that, you
know, you are contributing to society.
That is part of your thinking and mostly
the other part is that
so it it you know, you you have selfish
reasons. For example, you want to
contribute so much so that
you can put that on your resume, you
know, put down your resume looking for a
job. Look, look I'm a contributor of
React. Look, you know, on GitHub.
Anyway, my point is, you know, when you
see a
uh
uh open source project, never ever
contribute in except
I mean even for putting on your resume,
that's not worth it. Okay, there are
much more better things you can spend
with your time that is more efficient
for your personal benefit such as create
a program by yourself, something some
something useful such as like Facebook.
Okay, like Facebook and Twitter do it
for yourself. Never ever
fall into the trap of the open source
you know contribution. In particular, if
the project is big such as whatever
Google or Facebook's project, don't ever
contribute. Okay, that's my
recommendation recommendation or Linux
never ever contribute contribute.
And remember when you are contribute,
remember the word contribution. You are
spending your time, energy
which is equate to money in many senses.
You you know, you are devoting your time
to someone else's work. That is what
you're doing and typically you will not
get a get a credit. Okay, never country
especially for example, Emacs Emacs
community is the worst. Okay, I have
um
I have contributed in a sense big or
small, you know, for in the past 15
years.
Yeah, I indeed Ergo Emacs mod Ergo Emacs
mod. I worked on that for 10 years in
with help from David Capello and uh
and and now there's another another guy
who is leading the project.
I'm so Matt, okay, Matt.
So
So I did that so eventually the Ergo
Emacs project is now part of GNU. I have
to sign a paper GNU Emacs, you know, you
can go you can find it on the GNU alpha
repository. That is Ergo Emacs project.
So I worked for the on that for 10 years
and many bugs reports, you know, doesn't
taste good in your mouth.
Uh but I did, you know, when I had
problem about 7 years ago, uh many
Emacs people and actually this is sad to
say, you know, I I I write my blogs in
English.
Hold on a second. Let me get to Let me
Let me finish my train of thought, okay?
So, I've been writing my blog. It's all
English, no Chinese, for, you know,
starting in 1996,
okay? And I started to write Emacs blog,
yeah, starting in 2006.
I And that is also the year I started to
learn Emacs Lisp. So,
So, basically I've contributed in one
way or another to the Emacs Lisp or
Emacs community for 10 years. But one
day I had a
I had a problem. I'm I'm about to
uh die, you know, going homeless, and I
asked people for donation. This is
around 2011 or 2012. You probably have
seen it, you know,
it's on Hacker News and Reddit. It's
It's the first thing you will see when
you search my name.
So, I asked for donation and people, you
know, many of you people donated. So, in
in the end I got like $7,000
or $8,000.
Not much, but that's, you know, that's
country you know, that's donation from
people. And one of the interesting thing
is that I write my blogs in English, no
Chinese, basically no Chinese
whatsoever. But most of these
contributors are from China.
You know, this is very interesting. Most
of these 7,000, you know, half of them
at least, are from China, who I never
met. I don't, you know, I
I don't know Chinese programmers at that
time.
Now I know some because I I started to
dive into the Chinese programming. Most
of the So,
they are from China. So, here we see a
ratio issue, you know, that today in
America, the white people society, you
have, you know, social justice [ __ ]
heads with their diversity and equality
and that.
But, in my case in my case, you know, I
I write in English, I live in America,
I'm American, I, you know, for 10 10
plus years. When I ask for, you know,
when I'm about to die, I ask for
donation, half of them came from
Chinese people in China who I've never
met, I never talked, I, you know, I
don't know them.
Why is that? Because race, okay?
So, that that is, uh, you know, race is
a natural
thing and it's also a healthy thing.
This today's social justice gang, these
[ __ ] heads, they are creating,
uh,
sophistry, you know, they are they are
basically doing things for their,
uh, political power and benefits.
You know, uh, meanwhile chanting about
racism, oh, we need to really eliminate
racism. The the social justice people,
you know, especially the leaders, they
are the most racist the [ __ ] scum in
society.
So, okay, so that's a digression to the,
uh,
we going to get back to to to code. So,
from Lisp
to open source project GitHub to
code of conduct to
racism
the donation situation to, you know,
Chinese programmers we we digressed.
Now, let's get back to some of the Lisp.
Then we'll get to the question about,
um,
you know, I'll see what you guys are
saying.
So, Racket Racket is The question is is
it worth learning? I That depends on,
uh, you, okay? You know,
is language X worth learning? That is
the most common
uh, question asked asked by programmers
for the past 20 years and that is also
kind of the most silly question. I mean,
it's not exactly stupid because it's
very common. It's you know, it's natural
question. Everyone when you are young
Yeah, as you know
is really because you are young. You
know, you started to learn programming.
You You know, there are so many
languages. You want to know which one is
worth learning worth learning or which
one is best to learn.
You know, you want to spend time on
languages that's
that's worthwhile. You don't want You
don't want to spend, you know, 2 years
on a language that has no future or not
interesting things like that. So, that's
it's not you know, it's a good question
It's a It's a common question.
But partly because it's so common, the
question really don't have any depth.
So, what do you really want to know? You
know, you want to look at the question
more deeper. Like
what do you mean by worth learning? It
depends on the person, depending on your
background, on your preferences. Like do
you want a programming language for for
for having a good future,
security, you know, finding a job with a
language? In that In that case, you want
to go with C, C++, Java,
Python. Okay, these are the language you
want to go. And if you are the type if
you have money already, you are learning
programming just for your personal
interest, then then you have many other
choices. Haskell,
Prolog, Haskell, Prolog, Erlang, Lisp,
you know,
and Scala, Julia,
many interesting
programming languages, you know? And
also depends on your preference. Like do
you
have a affinity for, you know, the
elegance thing? Like Like many of my
type of people, many of you guys,
you know, we are interested in
languages. Typically, these people are
really interested in good languages like
elegant languages. For example, we would
would not we wouldn't like Java, okay?
Java, JavaScript,
uh Pearl, Pearl, okay?
Uh C++, you know, typically
we do not like. So, we want some sort of
elegance in some sense. So, there are
many aspects to what language is worth
learning. And uh
Uh so so there is that about Racket,
okay?
So, Racket, so I have quite a few
interesting articles about Racket. So,
Racket, too,
they are starting to you know, this is
actually I did a video talk about this
in uh
2019 September.
They are actually thinking of um
throwing away the Lisp parenthesis. You
know, let me show you another article.
Let me show you some
uh some some of the articles on Lisp,
okay? Lisp infix syntax survey. Now,
this is one of the most popular thing
among Lispers. When you begin to then
learn Lisp or when you are in Lisp
community, everyone everybody is talking
about Lisp parenthesis, whether it's
good or bad.
Uh
And here's a survey of all
um people who are who tried to create a
uh infix syntax for Lisp. And these
people are you know, many Lisp fanatics,
these idiots called Lispers, they they
they think that if you don't like
parenthesis, then you are a beginner.
Like they think you don't get this. You
don't you don't you don't get it. You
you are not you don't you are not fit to
learn Lisp. Go back to your C land. To
go back to your Java land. That that's
these these fanatics
think. Every time you mention about uh
the parenthesis, you know,
um
they will say that.
But again, these people are idiots
because
over the past 30 years
all these projects that tried to create
a Lisp with a infix syntax,
these people are Lisp pioneers, okay?
They are almost always the Lisp experts.
So, I've collected many projects. For
example, let me show you, okay? So,
uh M By And by the way, the very first
Lisp by John McCarthy
in his mind, okay? Parenthesis, it so
happens it's just a side effect, okay?
In In his original design, he wanted M
expression.
Not the parenthesis. The parenthesis,
the nested parenthesis is called
S expression. S stands for symbolic. It
just happens to be that way.
You know, with their reasons, okay?
Anyway, and let me just So, So, the
original Lisp creator, he wanted M
expression.
But however, that never happened because
that takes time to implement. So, it
just never happened, and so
the S expression is just like the raw
thing, you know? You start with the X
expression.
You are supposed to have a wrapper, you
know, a syntax wrapper with the M
expression that translate to S
expression. It just didn't happen. So,
that's John McCarthy, you know, the
modern Lisp um
the modern Lisp fans, they idiots. They
Because they are phonetics, not really
because idiotic, because they are
they uh are phonetics, so they don't see
things.
So, then then you have 1973,
you have seagull, okay,
um
created by this guy
Vaughan and Ronan Pratt, uh
you know, computer scientist. You see
this screen.
You know, he's known for the
Knuth-Morris-Pratt algorithm. You can
This screen uh links to Wikipedia, so
you can read about their biography. So,
this guy 1973, he created created a Lisp
version my Emacs Lisp with the infix
syntax. Then you have Mathematica,
Stephen Wolfram.
Uh very famous today, 1988.
Uh by the way, we have a person in our
group
who is the typical, I can tell, the
typical Unix philosophy, the tech gigas.
Excuse me for my opinions, okay? That is
what Kasparov is about. Now, so he he
has flamed Mathematica several times.
He has flamed flamed Mathematica several
times saying that Mathematica is
uh you know, it's
it's like um
it's not that great, you know, you
should use open source, you know, the
say Sigma Sage SageMath is good enough
and Maxima. Oh, Mathematica is just this
or that actually it's not that great.
You should, you know, SageMath today is
actually in every way it's comparable.
No, that's the most idiotic crap, okay?
That is like, you know, um
you know, the distance is so great that
that you make such a comment is
extremely extremely idiotic. Uh igno-
ignorant. You know, I have read I have
studied Stephen Wolfram since uh 19,
let's say, 1992.
So, from 1992, let's say to 2005,
I have read every single article about
Stephen Stephen Wolfram and every
article
that Stephen Wolfram has written that's
online. I have read every one of them.
And back then, you know, you don't have
internet as much. You have Scientific
American, you know, the magazine.
That he's got articles in Scientific
American
by Stephen Wolfram which about
computational mathematics. You know,
if you are in math community, there
there's another there's a big issue
about whether uh computers will be the
future of mathematics. It's a big topic.
You know, so anyway, so I've read quite
a lot about Stephen Wolfram and you
know, of course, I worked for Wolfram
Research.
Uh
for for half a year in 1995.
So, anyway, so Mathematica is uh
Mathematica is a Lisp, okay? It's
actually the syntax is more pure than
Lisps.
Parentheses nested parentheses the
[ __ ] the the [ __ ] Lispers, you
know, I so despise them.
Okay, I think I started to talk
about Lisps almost non-stop because I
have so many topics. Am I doing good
with the Lisp topics or should I
stop?
Uh
Okay.
So, J team says, "By the way, I also
think Mathematica is [ __ ] They give me
2 weeks trial, but the [ __ ] thing
takes 2 days to download."
You you Actually, I think you are in the
positions to simply just buy it, you
know, just buy it. Actually, it depends
on what you need, right? Anyway, so um
oh, Alan,
thank you, Alan,
for the money. So,
let me quickly go over my this articles
and and and I'll talk about I'll see
what to talk about today.
So, anyway, this article is about Lisp
uh, you know, a project that creates
alternate alternative
non-nested parenthesis syntax. So, then
then you have Dylan, 1992. Now, Dylan is
created by Apple. The Dylan language is
supposed Basically, it's a Lisp, okay?
It's supposed to be the modern
industrial Lisp created by Apple, 1992.
And in the beginning, they used Lisp
syntax, the nested parenthesis, but
after a year or two, they decided to
change it to the to kind of the C or
Pascal syntax.
Why? Because they they realized that if
you use parenthesis, then nobody will
learn it.
That's a, you know, that's
that's a valid reason.
You know, nested parenthesis, in some
way it's good, but in some practical
sense, it it it really sucks because
because human human animals are not
designed to see something uniform, like
everything For example, keyboard keys,
you know, you you have a massive grid.
Everything looks the same. That's not
good. You know, in nature, you will
never see a giant array, like squares,
the perfect squares aligned aligned
vertically and horizontally. You'll
never see it in nature. You see trees,
you see rivers, they are irregular. And
when when when things are irregular, you
can recognize it very fast. You have a
visual recognition.
But when things are extremely nested,
for example, look at this Mathematica
pure nested syntax. Look at it.
You see, this is the pure form of Lisp.
Nested parent, instead Mathematica uses
the the square bracket.
You see
it's hard to see, you know, it's hard to
see which one is nested in where. Then
then you need indentation.
It helps somewhat, okay? So, this does
have problems especially in especially
when you need to do
a lot of math, you know.
So, there are good reasons. So, so Dylan
in 1992 from Apple, they created, you
know, Dylan which eventually died
because
for many reasons, historical reasons.
When Steve Job Jobs came back, they he I
don't know if it's him or someone else
killed it.
Uh you know, it's a big history Dylan.
Then we have Scheme, you know, Scheme
SRFI 49 which is a module that allows
you to
um have
uh infix expression, I I expression,
they call it. Then you have Readable
Lisp S-expression project 2006. And you
know, you have quite a lot. Every almost
every year you have people, Lisp
experts, who wanted who who want to
create a alternative alternative syntax.
Okay? Then you have Arc Lisp from Paul
Graham.
Arc Lisp
Paul Graham Paul Graham wanted a
language for hackers, you know, he in
his belief,
you know, the best language is a is a
language designed for hackers, whatever
that means. Paul Graham created Arc
Lisp.
Which was When I look at it, I think
it's idiotic.
Then you have Okay, then you have Racket
Lisp. Now, Racket Lisp itself has it's
not purely nested parentheses because
you you you can also use square brackets
or curly quotes, curly brackets,
interchangeably with the parentheses.
That is Racket Lisp, okay? But even this
change is not good enough.
Because then Racket racket list they
created Pyrex. Let me show you, okay?
Um
Sorry for liberation
of
programming languages.
Uh actually I can just go to their
website.
So anyway, when you when I I did several
videos about this. When it comes to this
uh you know, I'm going to talk nonstop.
So there you see the racket list
which is scheme list, you know, the PLT
scheme
which became the racket list. This is
their logo.
Then this is the logo of Dylan, Apple's
Dylan.
Um
but I want to show you Pyrex which is
from the same people
who got tired, you know, who got who
find problems with the parenthesis. So
they create they created Pyrex.
Show it. So many you know, so many
languages. There it is, Pyrex. Okay. So
what is Pyrex? Pyret, not Pyrex. Pyret.
From the same people who created scheme
list, racket people. So they created
Pyret Pyret. As far as I know, it's
basically just scheme in Python syntax.
Scheme list in Python syntax. These
people have a gun.
Gun nutty.
But why do are they do that? Because
I I haven't I haven't studied the issue
in detail, but I kind of realized I I
think that's because, you know, the list
parenthesis
you
you you know,
in many ways it's good, but in real
world you have lots of problems with
nested with pure nested parenthesis. And
the thing about this is that, you know,
this piece has um
a reader, you know, a synthetic
synthetic macros and and you know,
these idiots. You know, they
many of people including these
professors, okay, I have a list
professor who is following me on Google.
He he is you know
professor in academia in in France. We
argued, you know, he many of these these
fanatics they think, you know, they
think that the list macro
the reader, you know,
it's more complex technical complex. In
these languages you have a reader, you
have something called a reader. Then you
have, you know, they redefine the sense,
the meaning of syntax. Anyways,
I am I'm not going to talk about that.
Uh I did
some other day I think I did before.
Anyway, so to these these fanatics they
believe
that
in a list language such as such as
common list
you could use the reader, you know, the
part of the list facility to create a
syntax that is not nested parenthesis,
okay? Many of them believe that. They
will argue with you to the end.
To to the death. They are wrong. They
are simply they this because they are
fanatics they don't they stop seeing
things, you know, they define they like
when you argue with them
when you talk about syntax, you see, in
their head
they are the meaning of syntax is
different from yours. Is different from
the entire computer science because
these list [ __ ] heads they in list they
they they think something else is the
syntax. You know, they argue with you in
this. But anyway, in the end
it is impossible to use the list macro
read readers, you know, the the the
uh symbols
what's the proper name? Symbol macros or
the the reader macros reader macros
that's a proper name.
It is It is impossible to use the this
reader macro to create a infix syntax,
okay? So, that is um I believe that is
why the
the the Racket people created Pirate,
you know, which is in Python syntax,
which is as far as I my own opinions,
the Python syntax is the most idiotic
thing.
Um and I have like 10,000 articles on
that. Just search for Xali
Python syntax, you might find it.
So, anyway, some of the, you know, uh
and uh let me just wrap up wrap up about
this. So, so
So, this article nested syntax design,
XML versus Lisp, you know, back then
around, let's say, 2000 to 2008, XML is
ruling the town, you know, XML every
everyone wants to do X- XML. XML is the
future. Every programmer is small thing
about X- XML every day. This hacker, you
know, like today, you know, you you you
may not hear it because you are younger.
And, you know, these fads just pass by
pass by you, and they become buried, so
you don't see it anymore. And today you
are concerned concerned with your own
fad or whatever you are talking about.
So, back then 2000 to 2005, let's let's
say. XML is all over town. Everyone is
doing X- you know, saying is saying XML
is the future. You got XML database. You
got language whose syntax is pure XML.
You know, you got XML
and this, you know, we can see
a a consequence of this because today in
in in Apple or in Microsoft, many
configuration files, they become XML.
That those, you know, before it's like
Unix style configuration. You just have
have simple lines. But during 2000 to
2005, when the XML is everywhere, they
started to change all configurations
for, you know,
thousands of programs into the XML
format. To this day, you can see
you know, you can see a piece of history
because on Apple Mac OS, many of the,
you know, their apps, their technology,
you know, you go to the library
Uh maybe I can show you. You go to the
library, okay? Let me see. Do I want to
show it?
Uh you go to the library directory,
okay? Um let's see. Library, yeah, there
it is, okay? So, you see this is, let me
magnify, okay? So, this is the Apple's
you know, home directory, then you have
a directory of library. And this
directory is mostly configurations by
different
applications or by system. You see, you
have assistant, audio caches, calendars,
core services, core color pickers, and
you also have a keyboard configuration
here.
Many of them are all XML, okay?
This happened during 2000 to 2005
because before it was not, they started
to change everything to XML. You can
also, I think Microsoft Office, I don't
know today, I think I think it is true.
Microsoft Office also changed their
format into XMLs. So, now the Microsoft
Office is also XML.
And also Microsoft, um
their keyboard, you know, come with a
software called um IntelliSense.
And the format of the keyboard
configuration is XML file. So, XML was
huge back then. You know, people they
are XML, they are they are saying they
are they are they are databases
uh in XML format.
Just like then, today you have OOP
databases, the [ __ ] idiots, these
[ __ ] [ __ ]
But anyway, they then
XML got killed by HTML5,
this group I talked about
before, the what the [ __ ] group from
Google and Opera. Uh mostly in the
beginning from Apple and Opera. They
killed XML.
So that's the end of XML or and also
JSON JSON. So JSON
is there first. JSON then HTML5 together
they killed XML.
Um so but but when XML is all that all
over town then Lisp people got angry.
You know, they they they are going to
say, "Oh, the the XML is idiotic. XML is
Lisp syntax done wrong."
You see that everywhere in the Lisp
communities, you know, they that's they
you know, so I argue with them then they
ban me.
I'm banned everywhere in lots of places.
So now
now we can look back, you can see so I
have article here, "Lisp Syntax Design
XML versus Lisp." Why am I writing that?
If I don't write that, it's forgotten
history. Now this is a piece of history.
I'm telling you, you can see what's
going on back then, what are these these
people are saying. And I have a bunch of
articles I believe I didn't, you know,
some of them linked to Google Groups.
Um
yeah.
So anyway
so lots of Lisp
um articles and here there's an article
about how using Emacs Racket mode. So
why why do I know Racket? Because I
actually I coded Racket for about 3
months doing a homework for someone. You
know,
you want you want to do your homework,
pay me. I'll do it for you.
Then
So, this is around 2015.
I did home I did homework writing a
racket some kind of murder game
for someone. And for doing that, I read
the entirety the [ __ ] entirety of the
racket
manual and tutorial.
Um I believe it hasn't changed. So, you
go to the racket website, they have a
manual, you know, and they have a they
have you know, they have one
tutorial and one manual.
I read the entirety of them. That's what
I do. I read computer documentations.
This is so So, I you know, I was coding
it. So, I also installed racket mode.
You very good, okay. Racket mode very
good. So, I have a short intro.
Uh then you have you know, you install
the racket. So, this is my
uh kind of intro or my own notes. I tell
you how to install it.
I haven't haven't I haven't been
updating them. I haven't been doing
racket since 2015.
But racket, I would say is a better
Lisp, okay. Now, here this article is
critical.
You know, it says can this macro change
this syntax? The answer is no.
And I have a detailed account telling
you why. I have excerpt from various
Lisp documentations. So, for example,
this this excerpt is from racket.
So, according to racket documentation,
they tell you the answer is no. You
[ __ ] Lisp phonetics, [ __ ]
Then this document is from closure,
okay. They tell you no.
Then this document is for Common Lisp.
They tell you no.
This Lisp [ __ ] fanatics.
Uh and you know and
and uh there's and from the book, the
most famous book, Practical Common Lisp,
very popular around 2005.
You know, they they have a chapter,
Macros, the which is idiotic by the
Peter Seibel
guy. Wait.
No, I don't think is it written by No,
there's no link back to the
uh stupid.
You know,
when you have a website there's that
provides no link back to the top of the
page, you know, go back to the index,
that's really idiotic.
Okay.
Um
So anyway, so actually I probably talked
to random too much.
Okay, so I guess let's go back to what
we Let's go back to the questions. Okay,
so
So hello, good morning.
Good morning, Shikashiko.
Shikash uh uh uh
You mentioned Shikashiko.
You know, this guy you guys stop using
these [ __ ] nicknames. Just use your
[ __ ] real name.
You know, you got one name on YouTube,
you got one name on Discord, you got one
name on Twitter. You This you know,
nerds. They want all you know, they want
to be anonymous. Just use your [ __ ]
real name.
Except you are persecuted by government,
which in in in in in
I mean, that's not actually happening,
okay?
Uh so Jim
J Team 90 says, "I don't worry about
last stream mishap. I donated because
you did something or said something, and
not because I want to you to answer
question." Uh, act. Question is just in
case if you run out of topics. Okay.
Ever Ever hear of Sonic Pi?
Your thought on music in general. Okay.
So, Sonic Pi.
No, I don't
recall what that is. I don't remember.
Let's see. Sonic Pi.
So, now I'm drinking tea.
Oh, Sonic Pi is a coding environment.
Let's see.
And we have Sonic Pi tutorial and a
Sonic Pi Raspberry. Okay, let's go to
Wikipedia.
Magnify.
Magnify. Okay, that's too big. So, Sonic
Pi is a live coding environment based on
Ruby.
Okay. Originally designed to support
both computing and music lessons in
schools.
Uh, developed by Sam Aaron in the
University of Cambridge Computer
Laboratory in collaboration with
Raspberry Pi Foundation.
Thanks to its use of the SuperCollider
synthesis engine and the accurate timing
model, it is also used for live coding
and other forms of algorithmic music
performances and production, including
at
AlgoRaves.
Its research and development has been
supported by Nesta via Sonic Pi. Okay.
So, Sonic Pi is the live coding
environment based on Ruby. Now, what the
[ __ ] is live coding?
Okay, live coding sometimes okay, so I
see live coding sometimes referred to as
on the fly programming, just-in-time
programming, and con- conversational
programming. Makes programming an
integral part of the running program.
What the [ __ ] does that mean?
Okay, am I still good? Doing good?
How long have I been talking? Hold on a
second. Let's take a break. Let's um
intermission.
I've been talking for 53 minutes, I
guess.
Okay.
So, let's go back to live coding. What
is it?
So,
it is the It is most prominent prominent
as a performing arts form and a
creativity technique centered upon the
writing of source code and the use of
interactive programming in a improvised
way.
Live coding is often used to create
sound and image based on digital media.
Okay, I don't know what the [ __ ] is
this.
Uh some sort of millennial thing and in
my eyes, as far as I can see, it's uh no
good.
Research A number of research projects
and research groups have been created to
explore live coding, often taking
interdisciplinary
[ __ ] approaches bridging the humanities
and sci- [ __ ] Is this Okay, so this
As
far as I As far as I know, I From what I
can see, this is merging into the social
justice [ __ ] thinking. Okay, live
coding.
Now, coding
Okay, so coding, you know, coding is
programming. You have to think to solve
problems. And now they have, you know,
live coding. First you have pair
programming, then you have live coding.
Uh what are you supposed to do? Okay, I
suppose you, you know, creating music
live and creativity,
uh improvise.
audio visual The figure of live coding
is to perform the act of live coding.
Usually artists who want to learn to
code and coders want to express
themselves or in terms of Wang and Cook,
the programming performance composer.
Live coding is also an increasingly
popular technique in programming-related
lectures and conference presentations.
You know, so when you're doing your
programming,
programming is an activity, um kind of
like doing math, a bit like doing math.
And uh you have to be You have to be
creative and you have to be
knowledgeable. You have to know You have
to analyze the problem. You have to
think. You have to think a lot.
Study a lot, solve a problem, writing
code. You have to understand the
programming language.
Uh and all these are not really
compatible with like live coding, like
improvisation.
Like
you know,
you write a code, you you you don't, you
know, if you make a mistake, things go
wrong. It doesn't compile or
um
you could try Yeah, you could do live
coding you know just [ __ ] around you
know like especially when you are
learning you know experiment.
That's learning okay like you know this
article says it's usually for beginners
you know that's learning that's not
coding.
You know usually artists who want to
learn to code and coders who want to
express themselves the [ __ ]
So coding is not active is not an
activity to like
to do a show you know you could you you
could I could do a live coding but it's
not usually the result is not so good
unless you are competitive you know you
and
coding is you sit down you study for
you know for hours months or years then
you write a code that solves problem
without bugs it's not really something
suitable for live coding. You could
force that into doing it you know you
could force it you could force anything
but it's um
this you know this is what the
millennials you know this
current you know today's hippies they
are trying to do they are trying to make
it into some sort of
art. So Sonic Pi is a live coding
environment based on Ruby originally
designed to support both computing and
music lessons in schools you know
lessons for beginners.
Okay let's see what let's look at the
screenshot.
Uh
what live loop haunted to sample the
yeah.
Okay that's not something I'm into
you know.
Uh you could have great programmers into
this and doing great things I don't
think that's for me. That's my opinion
about live coding.
Jagan, thank you for uh your money. So,
Jagan, also I have a question.
Uh
Jagan's question is more or less racket
land don't need to have sex syntax. You
can hook Lex/Yacc directly into reader,
for example, or you can
I see. I didn't know. I'm not, you know,
I don't know racket that well. I just
I only uh did it for
2 months.
So, let me read the comments, okay? Some
more comments, and maybe that that'll be
it today for today. We have been talking
for 1 hour now, I think.
Yeah, about 1 hour.
So, any more questions, put it into the
chat, and I'll see it, and I'll get to
it.
So,
and let me drink tea.
You know, you go to China, they're
drinking tea every day. Everyone is
drinking tea. And you you watch Chinese
movies, you know, the kung fu movies,
everyone is drinking tea.
You know, I I learned few years ago that
tea actually there's a
uh element in tea, you know, the chemist
chemist study. There's element in tea
that makes you calm.
What is that ingredient? So, so there's
caffeine caffeine in tea, which at the
end of we know what they it does, you
know, it makes you alert. But, there's
also an ingredient that makes you calm.
So, Alan says the proper term is
programmer. Yes, indeed. And Alan
self-proclaimed
that he is a programmer.
You know, Alan is pro
pro programmer, millennial programmer.
Flexible. Flexible, you know, not not
not socially awkward nerd who cannot do
nothing except in you know, just hunched
over in front of a computer. Alan is a
programmer, you know, he can code, you
know,
relax and code do some code and
then next day you go out
you know, going out with his girlfriend
or do social gathering and then talk to,
you know,
Alan.
And and also draw artwork.
So, is software is key is open source?
Yes, of course.
Al Cook, my goal is not to improve
society, nor help it, but rather to
improve the experience I have with the
operating system I proactively use.
That's a good reason. So, Al Cook is a
expert of BSD.
Oh,
what? NetBSD or is OpenBSD?
So, Al Cook has been contributing code
to BSD kernel, I think, right? Uh many
times and also been credited for it.
Hey, good morning, Aaron.
Aaron Hall, as I have talked So, Aaron
Hall is a Python expert. He is the, you
know, on Stack Overflow of all the Pyth-
Python questions, he's got the highest
decoration stars. He answered the most
questions.
Uh I'm doing okay.
So, Al Cook says, "I also don't see any
issue in having vested interest in uh
in when contributing, okay?"
Uh ethnocentric preference.
Yes, Emacs is great. Thank you Jim, J
Team, J Team 90.
By the way, J Team 90, so yesterday we
were doing type racing.
And I saw your name on the type racing
account, you know, typing. Is that you?
Uh
Uh you should be uh you also you should
also blog in Chinese.
Yeah, it takes a lot of time, you know.
Um
and actually I I have been interested in
getting into
Chinese China you know, actually a lot
of people on Twitter are from China, you
know, they are programmers in China and
they you know, they go over the firewall
to follow me. So I actually I have quite
quite a lot
fans
uh in China. Like every time I tweet in
Chinese
I got responses. Meanwhile, most of the
time I'm I'm doing English. You
You know, there's there's there's a race
issue. There is you know
There's
you know, race issue.
Wait, what why do Chinese follow me?
Because I'm Chinese, okay? That's the
that's the reason. No other reason. In
the same way, white people, you know,
you many of you guys white people you
get white people supporting you, not
supporting Chinese.
And but but many American, you know,
they will say, "Oh, that's race racism."
You know, race is a fundamental it's a
basic natural thing. And it is with us
and it is not a bad thing, okay? It is
it is not the a bad thing. It it must be
it because it's it's it's part of
humanity. If you want to get rid of
racism, you are getting rid of humanity.
Everyone becomes a machine, robotic, you
know, like robotic.
Cold and not doing, you know, and you we
and we cannot even achieve that. Race
race race, okay, the race perception is
part of your brain, okay? You cannot get
rid of it.
This today the social dis- justice gang,
they are, you know, crying about racism.
They are just They are simply
trying to get more power.
So, I so
okay, back to, you know, so
so China, you know, as they say,
everyone, you know, in business knows
China you have huge population, like 1
billion. You know, on on Earth we have
about 7 billion people, right? And 1
billion
1.something
uh is Chinese. So, 1/5 of people
in on Earth is Chinese in China.
So, they say, you know, the we hear on
the news all the time China has a huge
market. You know, if you are Google, you
want to get Chinese you you want to get
into the Chinese market because you then
you will the people who buy your things
will increase 10 times, 100 times.
That's the, you know, that's reality.
So, I've been wanting to talk to Chinese
people since I also speak Chinese.
Mm, but you know, it actually takes
quite a lot effort
uh because then
you know, I have to Yeah, it does take a
effort.
Uh okay, so we're looking at nice math
graphics ads on sub sites. What my
uh um
I think that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Let's see what else. Let me just read a
few.
Okay, let's just read my names, okay?
Uh Alan says, "Which Lisp variety do you
think has been the best marketed?
Favorite logo among the Lisps?"
Uh which Lisp has been the best
marketed? Okay, that would be Clojure.
If you really like Lisp, you know, and
you want to get a job with Lisp,
go with Clojure. Nothing else. Not
Racket, not Scheme. Okay, not Scheme
Lisp, not Racket Lisp, not Common Lisp,
not Emacs Lisp, obviously. You want to
go with Clojure. You know, get you know,
get really good study Clojure, get
really good. You'll find a job in San
Francisco over here. There's a lot um
uh
you know, jobs.
Good uh some some jobs for Clojure
people. They are hiring
in San Francisco Bay Area. You know, the
Silicon Graphics here. And, you know,
industry. So, Clojure Lisp is industrial
language.
Common Lisp was, you know, Lisp was back
in 1980s. It kind it died out.
For today, Common Lisp, you know, it
Common Lisp has no future, basically.
Common Lisp, no future.
And Scheme Lisp also kind of no future.
Racket, you know, in academia, yeah, you
do language research, but no
future.
Uh
Okay, so that answer which Lisp variety
do you think has been the best marketed?
That would be
Clojure.
Uh and uh the you know, Scheme is known
from 1980s to 1990s to early 2000s.
Scheme is known as the most elegant
language. Uh but actually that's not
true. So you could say it's actually uh
good marketing.
Why Why is Scheme known as the most
elegant language? You know, back not
like today. Today you have so many
languages beginning uh
uh since let's say 2006,
you started to have one new language
every year, you know.
But before 2006, from 1980s to you know,
you don't have that many. Scheme is
known as the one of the the most elegant
language.
Uh why is that? Because in part due to
the book SICP uh SICP SICP.
SICP which stand for uh Structure and
Interpretation of Computer Programs,
which is a great book. I've read that in
1998.
I talked about in my videos. I have
article on that.
Uh
So yeah, Scheme is known for the most
elegant language. Um but
now I know quite I know at least Do I
think Scheme is the most elegant? No.
Not even
No, not not
You You You got quite some way to go
before you say Scheme is the most
elegant language. Uh
you know, in my opinion.
And uh Alan also asked about favorite
logo among Lisp. You know, the One of
the problem is like Lisp, you know,
Lispers
they are like a cult, like Emacs people.
They are nerds. They are the hacker
type, which is dying out. Uh you know,
today you have millennial gen
programmers.
But anyways, so so Lisp
um people, you know, they are hacker
types and they
you know, they they they don't know uh
marketing. So they they they don't do
well with marketing. So for example, I
have a article on Lisp logo. I tell
them, you know, in my opinion, you need
a logo, but they are saying, "Oh, you
don't need a logo."
Uh I you know
So I have an article on that. Let me
show you.
Lam lambda logo tool. I have quite a few
articles. Lisp needs a logo, okay?
Let me tell you a bit history about So
this is around 2006.
I'm arguing, you know, I'm like [ __ ]
with these Lisp Lispers Lisp fanatics in
comp.lang.lisp
newsgroup every day.
You They call me a troll.
I'm not exactly a troll, okay? I I
I you know, I'm not there just so that
oh yeah, you know, say something stupid
so and and make a mess. That's not I
want That's not
what I do. That's not what I like. I
don't That's not my thing, okay?
I look at things. I have my opinions. I
think you are wrong. I go there and say
it in in in in a flame
flamboyant way. I think I say I tell you
you are a [ __ ] idiot. That's what you
are. I So that I I tell them, you know,
when I disagree with their opinions. And
they they they say I'm I'm a troll, you
know, I I've been banned here and there.
I have a record a documentation of
those, you know, just search for Xahlee
ban ban Xahlee. You'll see quite a few
articles. Documentation the history
historical record of what happened.
So anyway, so Lisp logo So this article
back in 2006, I was arguing, you know, I
And some not always antagonistically,
you know, I'm talking with them, you
know, in our community, you know, Lisp
is a community community I'm in just
like on Discord. You guys have seen when
crazy
flaming people
in in in Exceed Discord
group.
So, you know, I'm I'm I'm telling you my
opinions as it is. No hard feelings,
okay? You can have your uh opinions,
whatever your opinions.
Um but there's one you know, don't hurt
people, okay? If
if you are hurting people, don't do
that.
But as far as opinion goes, you know,
you like that, I don't I think you are
wrong, I just say it.
Uh so anyway, so Lisp needs a logo. So
back then I was telling them, you know,
we need a logo because
and they don't they you know, these
nerds, they all say small problem, you
know, they say, "Oh, oh, we
These these nerds, [ __ ] idiots, they
all say, "We don't need a We don't need
a logo. Wait, who who needs a logo?
Logos are for idiots. No, we don't want
to become stupid, uh you know, inviting
people who don't know nothing. You you
you you look at pretty pictures. We
don't need that. We are Lisp. We you
know, we are solid." That's
These [ __ ]
idiots. But anyway, but they have
actually tried to have some logos. For
example, this one, this logo that's very
old. Okay, this this one is used on the
lisp.org website back in 2001.
You know, history. So today lisp.org I I
guess it's already gone. You know, you
can check whether it it's it's dead. I
don't know what's going on with that
domain. So then you have people who made
these uh badges, you know, to promote
Lisp, you know, the alien technology and
you have these, you know, they become
popular for a year or two, then they
they die out 2005, you know.
You know, they want to you know, Lisp
fans, they want to promote. I tell you
know, every time you talk to these
nerds, they'll say, "Oh, you don't need
a logo. That's stupid." You know, they
they seriously, these nerds, you know,
these these hacker types, they seriously
believe
uh you are wrong, you know, they think
are they think you know, you don't
actually you know, that they'll go is
the most silly thing, you know, we
shouldn't have it. That's that's because
they don't know society. They don't know
how things works. They only know
technicality, you know, in a narrow very
narrow way.
Uh
So, you know, back then also I argued
with the Python [ __ ] you know,
back in 2005. You might find my articles
in the Python mailing list, which is
connected to the Python mailing uh
Python newsgroup comp.lang.python.
They are connected. So, when you post to
mailing list, it also get posted to the
newsgroup. If you post to the newsgroup,
it also gets to the mailing list. So,
they
I think they banned me. I don't
Yeah, they don't you know, they call me
a troll, okay.
So, I was back then Python do not have a
logo. They don't have a official logo.
However, you know, today we know this is
right. This is the Python logo. But,
back in 2005, they don't have a logo,
okay. But, they have unofficial logos
like like this one and some people use,
you know, you you have a variety of
them. You know, they are trying to
promote Python phonetics. They are
trying to promote Python. And I'm saying
so, in in in the Python newsgroup when
when the subject come up, I tell them,
you know, actually we need a logo. And
every one of them is like, "No, no, we
that logo are for idiots." These [ __ ]
nerds.
Then eventually, okay, now then then in
what year? In 2005.
Yeah, so before 2005, they don't have a
official logo. In 2005,
Python become bigger and bigger. They
started to have a logo. Now, you know,
once you get big, okay, when you are
small, this niche Lisp group or you
know, you don't know what the [ __ ] you
are talking about. You don't know. You
just have a bunch of these nerds, you
know, think, you know, patting each
other's back, you know, the
technicalities, Linux kernel and stuff.
Then, but when your group gets big, you
start to have other people. You have
marketing department, you have human
resource department, like Google, okay?
You have equity department, the
department department of diversity and
equity, [ __ ] These scums of the
society. So, but my point is when you
when your organization or group becomes
bigger,
then you actually start to have things
that becomes like what you see in
society.
Then you have people realizing we you do
need a logo to, you know, logo.
Two nerds, you know, logo is like
clothing, oh, you don't need every nerd
is like in a t-shirt, you know, right?
But
but clothing is important, you know,
often, especially in modern society, to
represent yourself in different
situations. You want to put on different
clothing, right?
In logo is the same way. Logo is a
pictorial representation of an identity,
your name. For example, my name is Kzar.
You know, and Python is a name for the
programming language.
A logo for Python is a pictorial
representation of the name, okay? It's
In other words, it's a name, a picture
version of the name.
And it's useful.
You know, it's useful in you know, you
you know, you could think of it as a
marketing thing, which is true, but it's
not just that. You For example, in
Chinese, signature, signature is also
identity, you know, a representation of
you, signature.
Meanwhile, in Asian cultures culture, in
China, Japan, you know, Taiwan,
you have seal. Instead of signature, you
have a seal, which is,
you know, kind of a picture that
represents your identity. That's what
logos in
in many ways that's what they logos are.
So, logos are not just oh, it's just
marketing for stupid people. We don't
need that. They're [ __ ] nuts.
Okay, I think that's it for today.
Um let's see.
That's for let's talk to for Jagan.
Okay, one more question. Jagan says
small list wait
what?
Jagan says small list racket land don't
need to have okay, so
any more questions? Green deck
uh Green deck, good morning.
So, what's the best computer algebra
system besides Mathematica? Mathematica
is the best by far. Just use
Mathematica.
Uh
Well, that sounds very interesting.
Trading for S is like a conversation, so
practicing this with computer maybe
improves your skill in real life.
What is that about?
Uh
okay, I think that's it because I've
been talking for too long. But, I joined
20 seconds late. Oh, [ __ ] you all.
Type racer haha. Okay, so J team 90
he types like 110 words per minutes.
So,
J team 90, are you on Discord? Join
Discord so we can chat, you know.
So, Jagan says we are about to close.
Jagan says designer of racket was asked
why didn't you write racket for the JVM?
It would be popular like closure is now.
He says, "I don't want to be popular. I
want to be right."
That's what those nuts think, you know,
they that's the that's a classic answer
from those nuts. Now, who who said that?
Who exactly said that?
Uh you know, because yeah, I'm familiar
with some of these people.
Um
You know, so yeah, those those are
nerds, you know.
I don't I don't want to be popular. I
want to be right, you know, like Emacs
people also say that often. Like every
time you [ __ ] debate about changing
of Emacs user interface, some of the
Emacs fanatics nerds they will say, "Oh,
we don't want we don't want to be
popular. We don't want to be popular at
all."
But actually
But actually, you know, you don't want
to die, okay? When you are unpopular to
a degree, you die. Death becomes of you.
Oh, Matthias
uh
of Felleisen.
Yeah, they they are great computer
scientists. Um
I I think I I think I I would respect
their views.
Anyway, okay, I think that's it for
today. Let's see. Um I talked for
80 minutes, I think. Let's check.
Yeah.
That's it for today. Thank you guys for
watching. Today is fun.
And uh
And uh thank you, Tim, for the money.
Bye, guys.
Oh, actually, we only talked for
70 minutes.
So, I'm going to close down in in 2
minutes.
You know, let let me tell you about the
thing about Scheme. You know, I really
really
Hold on a second.
You know, Scheme I really really, really
wish Scheme or Lisp is popular, you
know. I've been, you know, we've been,
you know, I've been on the this
community since year 2000, uh
since 1999. And I love Lisp.
Although I have a lot of complaints with
fighting with the Lispers, but in
general, all things considered, among
languages, I love Lisp, okay, because
not necessarily because of the
parenthesis. I like it, okay. But
because it's functional programming and
I think it's far better than Java, C,
C++, [ __ ]
Far better than Perl, [ __ ] And Python,
[ __ ] Okay, I prefer Lisp over them,
over Python, Perl, C, C, C, C++, [ __ ]
Okay. I really love Lisp, but the
problem with the [ __ ] Lisp nerds is
that they go nowhere.
Now, 20 years has passed.
Now, it's 2020. Where is Scheme? The
[ __ ] tiny community Scheme.
This nowhere. That's the the the [ __ ]
That's the problem. That's why I despise
these nerds, [ __ ] [ __ ] you
know, they they go no they they they
they
You know, you want you want to be You
join their community
you know, you want to be like them, you
go nowhere. You you you fall apart, like
me. Okay, okay, like me. You beg for
money on the street.
That would That's what happens. I, you
know, wouldn't be great. I so much wish
for
Let's say Scheme. Google is hiring, you
know, Scheme is the Google's language of
choice. Go- Google is doing Scheme, you
know, uh
uh artificial intelligence, machine
learning language libraries, Scheme.
Facebook is hiring Scheme coders.
Wouldn't Microsoft, you know, that's
That's what we want, right? But then you
But then you talk to these Unix
philosophy [ __ ] these these
phonetics [ __ ] these Emacs
[ __ ] They are saying, "Oh, we
don't want to be popular. We want to be
right." [ __ ] them.
Bye, guys.