good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh hello Emily hello
Nabby so today we are going to talk
about Emacs then since you guys are
using Emacs and okay let's set up this
okay I'm good to go I think so Emacs we
gonna talk about Emacs the Emacs in
Emacs Lisp coding and okay so let's see
today's topic so today's topic is Emacs
and we are going to do let's see I have
a topic here topic spring and we are
going to keep it under 1 hour today
maybe 15 minutes or maybe 40 minutes so
let's see topics range so Emacs ma
defects are tired show metadata so it
prints to its own buffer okay that's one
of the things we're going to do you know
on the Left window you can see that's
all my list of all the Emacs commands I
call so here is the topic sprint cut
that okay so cut cut cut cut close save
and today is over here open paste and
show in browser so Emacs mother facts
are tired show metadata good morning
Bart so let's do that and Emacs satire
show so there is this fantastic command
you can use I can use everyone can use
okay so let's go to keyboard block there
is a lot things going on in the keyboard
Department
many wondrous things this we have a
thumb
eater keyboard you know this keyboard
from Japan there is a Tokyo keyboard
meetup going on so we see a lot great
varieties of keyboard and this is
happening in Tokyo right now I think
it's maybe closing down but so you see a
great amount of fantastic keyboards and
look at this one this this this one is a
thousand ski monster and to operate this
keyboard you you kind of splay your
hands like normally they they make it
like that but this one is different this
one you know this is weird people you
know so different things going on you
don't know what is he thinking why would
he want the keyboard like that maybe he
walk around a round desk like you have
take circular desk so you have to this
is a power station so anyway so we going
to keyboard because I'm going to
demonstrate to you a command that gets
the metadata of images the secret data
hidden in images so let me show you so
let's go to the Atlas keyboards okay
this is a thumb ETA you put in you stick
your thumb in there Nabby and let's see
what happens they have they actually
have four keys in this thumb hole so you
can press your thumb up down or left
right I have no idea how what what it
does but you know someone is you know
some Japanese people Japan people are
experimenting with this so we look at
let's look at the images okay so we have
here image open it the
it is image now go too tired now here is
image now let let me delete the files we
don't need the backup files so delete
them yes okay so here is the image go to
tired so here is image now I want to
look at the metadata let's see so we I
call this command there it is so this
command is called satire show metadata
so you can see it's over there it's that
one however there is a problem because
it displays the output in the message
buffer now message buffer you can go to
you know just switch the to the buffer
named messages or use the keyboard
shortcut control H E okay so let me
expand the window so you can see this is
my Emacs message buffer you know I just
started Emacs so if we go to the top you
can see I just restart the Emacs so you
can see it's loading my unit file sense
and so on so all the messages go to in
this buffer in Emacs and then you can
see over here okay over here starting
this over here that's the meta data
output starting from there to there and
you know meet meta data is such that
when you have an image you can also have
text file name with hate and whether you
want to rotate it and what camera is
taken what camera is used to take this
photo
what exposure camera settings means
things like that and also it may also
include your geolocation your location
your coordinates so some of those
information are sensitive and you can
also include copyright or any comments
you want so that's what meta meta data
is about it's part of the JPEG or many
other image formats it's part of the
standard
but nobody you don't see these okay so
you don't see these when you see the
image you don't see it unless you you
know actively try to look at it so here
we have the metadata for this image
apparently there's this is the minimum
metadata the but if you just take a
photo with your phone normally you will
have a lot more metadata like lots of
other things do I have an example I
don't know but anyway so let me show
this command again so let's let's look
at this one okay so this photo let's
let's try to the metadata so I press the
key that's thought I'd show metadata so
we here we see the metadata for this
file now you can see this files got much
more metadata now if it's are there any
personal information let's see
primary platform okay they don't yeah
they don't have personal information
which is good I got those photos from
you know I'm ago or Twitter I think but
I'm not sure when you upload the image
it may automatically delete the metadata
I'm not sure not you know you can't you
don't you don't want to rely on that
hung on social networks to to hide your
metadata to remove you know so anyway so
you can we can see the actually there is
a personal information here you see per
file date time so apparently this guy we
can assume he had the camera since at
least 2016 possibly wait maybe not okay
so the proper but anyway those are extra
metadata so let's do it again so okay so
it is this file from Japan today so we
look at the metadata again then there we
are
but now okay now remember there is
Google profile creator Google and there
is let's see what else have I google
yeah so Google device manufacturer
Google you know that's kind of private
information so you want so this command
cuz I look at me no data is very
convenient and and now let's do okay so
there are a few things we want to do
okay so let me go to the talk show and
write it down so today's talk show we
are going to modify this command there
is something I want to do I'm going to
show you so we are going to do a email
list session but before that we
demonstrate this command what does it do
so explain meta data okay metadata is
info embedded in imagery files okay and
some of the info may be private such as
the location and time you took the photo
okay so that's made-up metadata and the
next thing we want to do is we want to
delete them okay let me show you so
again it's this file now I'm going to
call command to delete the metadata so
press press I forgot what's a key let's
try this okay okay that's that's show me
that data so let's do it again
first press press now he asked me sure
to remove all metadata yes okay I say
yes so it removed the metadata for this
image now let's try to show it again
show it now you can see
okay so now let's go to message buffer
to show it so now you can see it's much
shorter all the metadata the private is
the private parts are removed so that is
metadata and that that is the Emax
commands cuz custom commands you can use
to remove or show metadata so the the
one to remove is there so tired remove
all metadata okay so now I'm going to
show you the code so the code is online
and you can use it so let's go here let
me get to the command okay so here is
the documentation for the command saw
tired show metadata and let me pop this
out good morning Daniel and Louis
any comments questions posted okay keep
the flood the chat okay flood the chat
Channel so so that's my terminal control
error to clean it and let's see what am
i doing okay so back to Emacs so this is
a command satire show me the data okay
so let's see yeah so let's go to the
source code so here is the source code
it's not too long so this is show
metadata and and this is remove metadata
it is why you asked us all so many
photos it is why you asked us Oh
for so many photos you think so how do
you get that nice screen background mine
is white well that's that's that's very
easy okay that's that's Emacs settings
okay let me show you that okay so so
okay let me remember where are we so we
go to I'm going to show you that okay
hold on a second so go to the top back
ground
okay so here is how you how I got my
background color okay so so you just
call this command okay Nabby so you you
you you call set background set back
ground okay I don't have a brief for it
set back ground color okay that that is
an Emacs command you call and you can
say pink or whatever okay but okay
that's let's do it
so there you have it now if you want it
in your eMac in it you just put that
there in fact let me show you let's turn
this back to honey do you okay that's
that's the way I have it so Nabi just go
to this fantastic
Emacs tutorial you go to this fantastic
Emacs tutorial and then you there
practical Emacs okay and and at bottom
you'll have a theme so maybe if you are
learning Emacs this is a great place to
be
let's search for Oh actually you go to
the in it set up in it set up and
somewhere here there is color thing okay
and this article has all the details you
can set up a theme or you can see the
background like I just did before here's
a code and so on okay so that is about
setting back up color honey true yeah
okay so yeah if you just wanted the
color so let's go back to talk show and
let's add that there
save it okay save it now go back to the
what we were talking about which is
metadata delete metadata and show
metadata okay so now we have died remove
all data data metadata okay now if you
want to use this command you go to this
URL and these commands are here the code
is here you just copy them and put it
into your Emacs init file okay you can
wait where is it oh okay yeah so I got a
bunch whole bunch of Emacs commands that
deal with images scale images auto crop
come out to JPEG convert to PNG and
remove metadata that's the one and show
metadata those here so that's the code
so let's copy the URL close it go back
to Emacs and paste it here so close that
close that open that so there is a code
for metadata but now we are going to we
are going to modify the command we are
going to modify the command to do
metadata you know there is something I
want to do plan fit okay so let's so
what do we so let's see what are we
doing so we want to modify that minner
data so yeah so this image so so yeah
remember we had some problems with with
a command because okay let's go - lets
go - tired because every time we call it
show metadata it shows it displays the
output in the messages buffer which
which means the
when you move kusa or when you do
something it goes away so if you want to
look at it it again you have to switch
to the message buffer then you have to
expand the window so that's kind of
tedious okay what I want is that I want
this output to be in a buffer by itself
so it's kind of more permanent you know
for this session so let's do that and
okay let this so let's do that so let's
see what people are saying good morning
urban fun matrix manipulation JavaScript
L is small okay so I'm I think maybe we
don't do that today because we try to
keep it short maybe possibly we we're
gonna finish Emacs it and let's see
where we go okay so eMac beasts so yeah
so let's start modifying the command yep
so okay so let's call the command okay
let's go to where the command is there
it is okay so the here we have show
metadata we want to modify this code and
okay so what we do is we copy it we copy
it a new buffer paste it here copy the
file name save it as a new name okay
dottie yeah so we just modify this code
and so far so good
so
so so we want to yet so so so right now
it's printing to the message buffer why
is it printing to the message tougher
because of the shell command the shell
command so here is a shell command by
the way this this command can also do
more than one file so for example let's
go to you know what why am I doing this
command because because yesterday I was
working on all these keyboard photos you
know all these are new keyboard photos
Emily so you know I was working all
these keyboard for us yesterday and I
noticed there is a problem because all
these skeebo photos I you know I want to
remove the metadata's and and but
there's a problem because every time I
call the command it just show up there
then I do something it disappears that's
why I want to fix it and I was you know
I you know when you write a blog so I
was working on my you know I was working
on my keyboard blog and they are a lot
to do because they are a lot to do
because every time you for example I get
a photo
you know these photos are from Twitter
or image or from discord okay
so let's show okay let's go to this code
so they basically if you are a blogger
you have so many sources online email
girl discord reddit used you sometimes
grab the photo if it you you know if
there's no problem with copyright then
you have to credit the photo like for
example when I write this keyboard block
I have to credit the photo I have to get
the keyboard name in this case the kibo
name is Alice Atlas 56 is right there
that's not so obvious for many cases for
example this one you you have to find it
you know
maybe it's some sometimes it's on
Twitter there's the information some
that you have to read you have to dig
through and so you've you have to
provide information author when is it
created what circumstances what what is
it for things like that interesting
information you know that's that's what
you write a blog for for people to you
know get to find it interesting and the
be old be old info things like that in
this one for example this one I need
more work to do because this one I only
have one photo I need I would like to
have more photo to showcase this this
keyboard and also I don't right now I
don't know who is the author for this
keyboard so you know you just take time
to go through Twitter and sometimes you
ask them ask the people so so I was
working on this Tokyo keyboard meetup
yesterday and I need to deal with this
information so so so you know I this is
not done yet because they are they are
quite a lot more photos I have
impressive process for example this
photo this this keyboard is beautiful
it's because you know and I don't know
who is the author of this keyboard so I
don't have information yet and also this
one is very interesting because you have
a curved surface and I don't know who is
the author of this keyboard yet you know
it just take time because they are hot
literally hundreds of photos you do you
have to do them one by one and and so I
was doing this there's a lot to do I
haven't done yet and here's a bunch of
Tron keyboards I already have like 10
photos of Tron keyboards on my website
so I see the trunk keyboard I need to
merge them I need to for example let's
go to Toronto
keyboards okay so over keyboards then
you go to the bottom open ami keyboard
history and here we have the trunk
keyboard and there it is a video of it
the granddaddy of ergonomic keyboards
Morris okay Chong is 1987 okay so it's
fantastic
I already gathered many great clear
pictures so but today you know I got a
whole bunch of new trunk ebook pictures
so I need to merge them like which one I
want to use which one I don't want to
use what are some maybe some if new
information I need so things like that
so you have a lot to do so yesterday why
I run into a problem why I want I need
to get metadata you know I'm not mean
yeah I don't really care for them
but then yeah well the I was looking you
know the reason is because they are ok
let me explain the tediousness of
writing a blog ok writing a keyboard
blog so you you got all these photos
sometimes these photos are duplicated
from different social websites so if yes
that yesterday for example one is from M
ago you know the someone posted a
collection of Tokyo photos in on
keyboards
you know in McGirt so it's a photo
sequence you know there's tens of photos
on the page some there you know you go
there there's a bunch of photos but the
photo of the the the almost almost exact
photo shows up also on Twitter because
this is there's a lot people on Twitter
using a Japanese people using Twitter so
they also post this photo and apparently
it seems to me I don't know for sure you
know because the same photo
exactly same photo appears in different
places so I downloaded them when I was
working on them I don't know they are
duplicate until you know
I put on my website then you see a
duplicate but but you see when you see
two pictures that are two images that
that are visually identical but they are
not necessarily the exact same file
because someone may have cropped to it
or shrink to it you don't know so that
is when you want to compare so yesterday
i have two photos that's the same
basically the same size and same visual
content but however their file size is
different you know one of the way to
church if two images are exactly the
same is by is by file size that's but
but that's not hundred percent correct
way to do but most likely if two image
files have different file size then then
that means they are probably different
but anyway I have these two photos and
they looks exactly the same and same
size looks the same however they're in
their file size differ by like hundred
100 bytes that is when that is when by
the by the power of my knowledge I I
looked at the meta information because I
want to see wait I just okay I just I
just made a copy of the jpg file okay so
so you look at so you want you you you
look at metadata because I want collect
photos I always I'm kind of obsessive I
want to choose the better quality ones
you know especially with JPEG images you
could have two photos photos that looks
the same but they are one is much more
compressed the other one is not so much
compressed you know JPEG is lossy image
format meaning that it's compressed you
know the loose is info
so I always wanted the higher quality
version but that information is not
necessarily easy to determine usually
sometimes I think sometimes it's
impossible for example if you look at
the metadata of this file you can see it
says encoding process wait you can see
there is you know that's a problem I
want to fix today you can see this
encoding okay so let's go to the you
know sometimes they say what kind of
encoding process anyway my point is that
they you cannot it's it's not necess
to find out which two photo is the
original that that's my point
typically I want our engine or so so I
so yesterday I did the metadata for two
almost identical files then I see the
metadata differ by a little bit
I forgot exactly what but anyway finally
I realized one okay basically they are
the same image images so I just deleted
one of them and you know all this
because I really want you know it's kind
of obsession you know as a nerd you know
I want I want a version with higher
quality even even that may mean that
visually it's impossible to see the
difference but you know so that that is
why I got into the metadata business
yesterday and and the and I was going to
you know typically I was just going to
fix the code right away at the time but
however because now I'm doing video and
often it's a case that I can't remember
the topic you know like I have so many
topics but at the moment you want to
choose one that that's usually hard so I
started to
you know I I was thinking oh this is a
great thing to show people you know the
how do you modify this code and then you
can explain the whole process like like
what I'm doing now I just explain to you
what happened for the process of doing a
keyboard block all the details you know
the details the troubles in the Emacs
commands how they really relate in
things like that so it's a great
opportunity that's that's why I'm doing
the metadata by the way these commands
they has they have been around for a few
years wait I started to play this video
by mistake you see this this keyboard is
fantastic what is strong keyboard
greetings to Russia well good
hello Matt to Germany just look at my
website okay just search for stop it
just search for Saudi trunk you will
find it so anyway this command has been
there for a while so where is it anyway
so let's show it okay so here is a
command
so it's it says 2019 because I modified
you know remembered I'm I added these
two lines because I started to modify it
then I thought let's do it in a video so
this command has been since 2016 yeah at
least you know it could be audio but
anyway let's start to fix the code okay
shall we so let's fix the code so I want
so right now it's printing to the
messages buffer and I don't want it to
print to the messages buffer so why is
it printing to the messages buffer
because of the shell command so let's
look at the describe
function shall command let's see the
documentation maybe you'll tell you what
buffer to output so let's see none
Interactive colas in specify codeine
streams shall command default arrow
buffer so where is it
so shall command is something something
something it's found to something
something so this is the syntax shell
command command something something
there it is output buffer
okay so output buffer in era Berthe
execute something-something
interactivity so where does it say okay
here so the optional second argument up
above even Anil if nanio says to output
output in some other bhava yeah what a
redundant sentence redundant explanation
so if output buffer is in is a buffer or
buffer name erased at buffer and
ba-ba-ba-ba-ba okay let's just do this
okay output buffer so now we know how to
do it so the second argument so here is
the first argument we need a we need a
second argument so a second argument
let's just give it a name and let's say
X our meta data output okay now by Emacs
convention buffers that are generated by
Emacs should begin with the name of
asterisk and end with a asterisk so
that's why we named it that way so let's
try if this works okay eval buffer now
it's loaded okay now let's try an image
file again so go to go to keyboard go to
the hellos again open that go to tired
and let's go to command don't Dunton
know that steel looks like it's yeah
that that looks that's still image
buffer so I mean the message buffer so
that's not okay so I don't know what
what is going on now real-life coding
now this is this is a demonstration of
real-life coding so where is the page
where is a code
here is a code did I just diet show
metadata and oh okay you see this
command has the power of let's see what
what does uber fun hello uber fun by the
way you used you could use face fash
algorithm to compare photos for usual
similarity okay every says asterisks are
used as in this view put them around
global variables by convention and
purpose are just like Robo streets okay
fantastic
it's great to know okay so tired show me
the data okay so that's what are we
doing we are trying to we are trying to
write we are trying to get it to print
in in our own buffer now there is a
issue you see how do I explain this you
see okay first first of all let me show
you a feature of this command okay let's
now let's look at this photo
okay here is another photo and let's
show metadata okay there it is metadata
and now now there's a you
you entired you can select multiple
photos and call them again okay call the
command then it will show metadata for
all these images so it's very convenient
so for example let's go to messages
buffer okay now we're gonna kill the
message buffer so nice killed the
message buffer they regenerate so you
don't have to you know you can cure it
no problem
cure it kill killing the message buffer
is basically one way to clear everything
then every time you have a message you
know you'll be there again the message
is buffer so now we have selected
several image files okay now we call the
command okay
hold on let me show you the window okay
let me show you the command log window
so now we call satire show metadata so
it is actually showing all this oh
actually now it seems to work it's it's
trying to show I mean it's going to show
all metadata for all these images now
let's see right but but however right
now you only see one of them you are not
seeing you know you only see the method
metadata for one of the images why
because it may explain why because our
command is calling a map ok so hello
beautiful people I'll command first of
all i'll command let me explain how the
command works it is trying to first of
all is trying to determine condition
okay condition if string equals two
major multi mode so it's trying to
determine if you are entire tired is
which is this directory listing so if
you are in tired then you ask Emacs to
get marked files so you you will get a
list of file paths
okay that is if you are in tired or if
you are not in tired but if string equal
major mod image mod if you are in the
image mod such as you are looking at one
of the image then then you just create a
list of that single file path you know
before file name returns the path of
that file so so the bottom line of this
is so what wait
so yeah so so basically this file this
command will try to operate on a bunch
of files and those files are this file
list okay that's a parameter name so you
see we have file list here and we are
trying to map you know we met this
function lambda something something to
this list okay so for each file path we
call a shell command of this command
exit tool so you exit to is a Linux
command line tool that's doing that's
getting the metadata so you need that
command for this to work so you can
download it you you know you find it on
Linux or Mac it's also available on
Windows in fact let me show you let me
show you exactly exit xz4 - okay I have
a article about that if it's a technical
topic topic I have an article about it
okay so there it is Linux command to
view delete metadata image file so that
is a tutorial okay so if you are not
familiar with these two this is a
command line tool so you can use it on
the command line if you want so let's go
to talk show today's talk show and show
it here okay so
in fact let's go here to the terminal
and which exif - oh which you spelled it
wrong there it is so I have I installed
it myself because you can see use a
local pin by default I don't think it's
on the Mac so there there is that
command ok so for those of you new to
Linux go learn it today
keep the doctors away ok so so there it
is so we are you see you see what we are
doing so we are going calling map of
lambda function for each file we call a
shell command and the shell command is
is this
EXIF tool then the file name the the
file path ok actually we use related
file name so so you see then we say you
know when we call shell command we give
it a second argument you know solve
metadata output so what happened is that
it will do that for the first file then
output in in this some metadata buffer
ok then it will do the next file then it
will output to the examiner data output
buffer the same buffer again meanwhile
erasing what's there previously that is
why that is why we got this problem the
problem so wait wait so let's go back to
the image file so this myth's well let's
go to diet so you see clearly we have
more than one file selected but when we
call the command and it's a problem ok
ok so ok so we actually we talked too
much we talk too much and not much code
we need to fix this let's let's fix this
it's for that day so how do you want to
shell command so let's look at the shell
command again okay the shell describe
function shall command to see the
documentation so wait so in this
paragraph it says the optional second
argument output buffer but if output
buffer is a buffer up of a name erase
that buffer you see it says here erase
that buffer and insert output there okay
then
Annie or value of shell command don't
erase buffer previous okay so that is
the that is the key that is the solution
so you all you have to do is set that
variable so let's do that
okay this let's let's get this going
this you know live coding and tutorial
is very time consuming so we want we
want to set this to true true okay so
what we do is we go here how do I know
because I have experience
I've been coding this for ten years
plus so you just put that there
hold on a second within this block of
code so now we have to do is to move the
whole map to here okay then purify
everything lest the Elise cards are
angry okay now we avowed above a good we
should be ready to go
so now close the messages buffer now
let's go to let's switch over to some
output okay this is our previous summit
our data output kill it now we don't
have that bother anymore it's so we are
doing things fresh now let's select
three image files okay
and that's called a command good
actually it's working now okay actually
it's working now but why is it confusing
it shows two paints why is that because
the one in the middle is the kilometer
data output the one at the bottom that's
from the messages buffer it'll just go
away when you move kusa so you see
so actually we need to fix that if we
want to but now in this buffer you can
see you can see oh actually this is the
metadata for all three files they don't
have line breaks that's why it's
confusing so you see we add the line
break ourselves add the line break loops
add a line break ourselves there it is
so we have three three you know
information about three different image
files so now let's do it again close
that go back to the code we want to add
a we want to add a print you know we
want to add a new line okay
print print C okay print C a new line
okay actually we can say turn three okay
so I never mind let's just say print a
new line so Eve our buffer we can do it
again so do it again switch down
it's it's not working it's not working
because when you say print it actually
prints through the message buffer so
it's a more problem it's more more
complex than you expected
well that's always the case in real life
coding but okay so let's look at the
shell command documentation again
describe function and go down and let's
keep reading here so if I pop up is a
buffer debase I buffer then insert
output and if the shell command don't
erase buffer is true then prevent the
buffer from being race now if output
buffer if output buffer is not a buffer
and not near inside output in the
current buffer okay so anyway we got I
cannot say this is complete you know I
can't leave it just like that because
although we succeeded in putting all the
output in one buffer but however there's
no new line separating them so even as a
sloppy solution this is not acceptable
so now I have two choices do this myself
offline or continue with this continue
to solve this problem how shall we do it
Emily what do you think should we
continue to solve this problem or just
skip to skip it hello team Morris
so let's see how long have I been
talking 15 minutes that's pretty long so
so should we what what should we do guys
should we continue to solve this problem
or continue ok League of noobs hello
good morning yeah ok let's continue so
how do we solve this problem it's ok so
you know it could get complicated you
know that's the thing with coding so
Emily says if you know what I needed to
do then carry on but if you need to look
up stuff maybe not I think I need to
look up stuff well I kind of know but
you know I kind of know but it's it's
it's it's not it's not a it's not going
to be clean and simple because then I
have to explain well I could you know
I'm getting better with the with like
lecture extempore without preparation
I'm getting better so ok so the problem
we need to solve this problem houston we
got a problem the problem is we want to
print we want to print the output for
all the images in one single buffer but
we want a separation blank blank line
between the outputs and the way we are
doing it right now is we are calling a
shell command and call this exit tool
and it will you know the shell command
takes the second argument that says
which are put to printed to however it
just combines the previous output
without a newline
so the to solve that I think we cannot
use Shou command anymore you see that's
a problem because shell command is so
convenient simple you know it's very
simple you call the shell command eMac
beasts function then you just give it a
shell command then you'll handle the
output and everything but without that
then you have to call a you know
background process yourself then you
have to control the output and stuff so
what I'm trying to think of what to do
now so
yeah Emacs output it's kind of annoying
so okay so okay let's go to sorry my
Emacs init file I have so many lines of
code here some some what some of them
must already saw have solved this
problem actually maybe not let's remove
the files remove the annoying backup
files
yeah with current buffer that's that can
that is useful but but if we do with
current buffer then you know the and
then you have to switch buffer of us you
have to switch to a buffer you have to
there is a command code with output to
buffer that ok let's let's try to
explain them if we cannot do it today
you know this we explain something maybe
you know we explored something so anyway
so let me go to the settings first okay
go to my unit file and let's find share
command to stream oh that's that would
be a good solution that yes I think
that's good solution to try that would
be simple but before we do that let me
try to okay let's try shell command to
stream first of all let's look at the
documentation shell command to stream
okay so shell command
I don't know I don't know what I'm doing
to string okay I have I think actually I
never used this command who's wrong
wrong key so describe function yeah I
never used this command return the
output the screen as to string okay
again we can use that so let's look at
the source code without put to string
okay so it says it's trying to share
file name shall command to a string
shall commence which also here is a
command and it's trying to use process
file okay and process file is this one
okay let's let's use shell command to
string great let's let's try to solve
this problem I've never used this
command before Thank You Emily
great suggestion so okay so we need to
put it here it's just magnify so shall
command to string
so it returns a string okay so it
returns a string then you have to
contact and concatenate well that can
walk too but that can work but okay now
I have another dilemma whether to push
through this which would not be optimal
solution or try something else
you see if we do shell command to a
string then we need to we need to grab
the strings such as for example set you
know set X set X to that string result
we need to grab it then we need to
accumulate we need to then because we
are inside a map right we are doing this
multiple times then each time we need to
append you know we need to kind of
concoct something like this okay
something like contact okay contact X
okay yeah actually we can actually we
pushing through you know almost we just
almost finished contact a new line then
yeah this is the it's almost dead so
each time we call it it gets a stream we
contact to the original value of x and
here we need a temp variable X here temp
output out stream okay string
yeah so and this needs to be empty
string okay
the default value will be empty string
so each time we call the command we
contact - yeah we connect to the that
I'm wondering if my roommate is back or
something so yeah so she'll come and -
yeah so okay we almost done
almost now let's format them so it's
makes them pretty
so this block of code instead of this
block of code so so that's I think maybe
we can try that that should be it so
let's double check one last time before
we run our stuff so map right
we map this function to a list and the
function is what the function does is it
will set this value and well it calls
this shell command then the output will
be appended to that stream okay so when
the command finished you need to
actually print that output so let's do
that okay
there is a command I need okay so
actually there is a command so now we
got the temp out strings up for stream
we are wrong key
so with current buffer with output to
string without put to buffer okay that's
the command we need so with output with
output to buffer with tempo for know
without put to there that's what we need
that's the one with output to temp of a
buffer name of a name will be that okay
but for name will be that and the string
will be print okay train
please make this work
please that should be it let's give out
the buffer okay then go here
Emacs in it we don't need it close it
close it settings we don't need it close
now select three image files call the
command there it is beautiful great
great conclusion you are beautiful
so I think that's it actually so we got
this yeah this is what we want exactly
so now I'm not I don't think I'm going
to change this it just works so now okay
so let's try it again
now we're gonna kill this buffer kill
and we're gonna select all of them okay
select all of them oh I want to see all
the metadata in a world
okay now call it oh you have to wait for
a while okay now it's out yeah so so
magnify so now we cuz is the metadata
the metadata then another metadata
copyright Apple then another metadata
another metadata so that is the power of
metadata and the denture of metadata so
you don't want you know there are some
incident when compiles it works yes you
know there are some incidents about
metadata that you know some you upload
the file maybe to newspapers because you
have some photo or something then it so
happens it contains your information
like your location especially the most
critical one is geolocation
you know especially if you are a spy or
something but most people are not spies
but anyway they ask you know situations
where you are journalists or something
you you you you don't want to show that
you know there are many circumstances
you don't want to show that so but
metadata is such a thing that you don't
see it nobody you know you don't see it
normally for example I got a bunch of
metadata
now this out for public photos right so
let's shall we
you know usually other people's photos I
mean the photos I downloaded I don't
look at metadata so it's a problem not
great look at you know it takes time to
look at them but now we can call command
to remove them all the metadata you know
also you don't want to just remove
metadata because sometimes it contained
copyright information you know people
want that make that information to be
there so you shouldn't actually delete
it so I actually as I am NOT going to
delete them and you know these are just
keyboard photos anyway so so you know if
you know every day there are millions of
photos uploaded to immigrant who Twitter
to Facebook who is looking at the
metadata Google Facebook they are doing
it and you don't even know it you know
we are programmers so we know a bit
about this but the Google Facebook they
are they look at every image files
metadata for sure and they tabulate they
if they found a location they are put it
in database you know I can bet I can
tell you for sure
so they have accumulated vast amount of
information for most people you know
they don't even know what is the data
meta data you know average people they
don't even know a photo you have you
know information inside it so that's you
know so that's today's topic metadata
and emag beast and
one hour in six minutes good time to
stop so thank you guys for watching if
you like my stuff support me okay paypal
patreon it's all over my website and you
know and you know since we are doing
Emacs today I have Emacs tutorial for
sale it's still alive okay it's very
alive it's not dead you know some people
think oh you haven't updated I you know
is like you walk I walk on this for over
10 years every day 15 years okay you
update it every day but typically when
you go to a website when you see a
website you are not sure you know you
want to like you want to contact you you
want to bug the author like it's your
it's your Emacs you're still on sale
even though you can see clearly it is
but the thing is many information on the
web sometimes they are ten ten years old
and no longer updated for many years so
that's that is why people want to check
are you see oh you know they want to
know you know they they want to kind of
get information to know if you are still
active doing it but anyway in my case
yes absolutely so it's all up to date
fairly okay well I would say you know
it's good it's just good okay buy it
thank you guys for watching and see you
next time