good morning
good morning everyone this is San talk
show episode 1001 good smoke good
morning everyone so I am Alive as indeed
today's topic is going to be random now
first of all we need to check this time
stamp topic will be first in order
philosophy Python Kaido yeah Kaido the
guy so I'm going to work on my okay soft
hug show first of all it's make the
title correct so you know here select Oh
taste or one button operation you see
I'm just pressing one button
good morning hey Jack great to see you
so let's see how what time is it in
China wait don't tell me
wait wait don't tell me I know so it's 1
o'clock
well o'clock afternoon
what was that Jack Nihao what some sort
someone that this is chin that had me
off so it's someone no hi YouTube that
woman and song sohee say Shannon Reno PD
PD does his soil someone wrong yet how
does she uh Tadashi arnica 11 a.m. okay
so someone wanted or she r- ahamed
somehow hunter yet today watch anime or
don't wanna say it's a champagne good so
if i know you hold so in song like a pvp
d so yeah I was talking Chinese -
Chinese friend in China and basically
I'm thinking of doing a video for for my
Chinese friends in China in Taiwan and
elsewhere and that but the problem is
that you know in China well even in USA
you know lots of websites now they
required a phone number you know to hook
up so they can track you they can you
know and I don't have a phone hi guys hi
everyone so how many people watching
three people great number three is the
second prime number okay so today I'm
going to do let me know what topics you
guys want to talk about so so the format
is ask me anything ask me anything okay
today I was thinking you know I was
going to maybe talk about YouTube but
you know there this there is this
fantastic Chinese statue in Seoul here
I'm gonna I'm like this is my website
let me show you so this is my music blog
some music blog and there is this
fantastic statue let me turn the music
on so you can hear it now you you might
want to lower your volume let's see if
you
can hear it
[Music]
what a beautiful thing
you know this thing is like hundred
meters tall and it's in China it's a
it's in China it's a basically she is a
goddess some kind of love goddess I mean
her stories of a love song a love story
and she's a goddess
she's a legend you know kind of in the
Chinese male ethnicity I didn't know
anything about it but I was you know
looking up because on Twitter you know
people posted and from this website this
this this website is becoming hugely
popular tick tock
in the English version is called tick
tock but in Chinese is snowing and you
know they live like also the funny thing
is every we're doing is no well in China
in no well I haven't used it but I have
seen a lot tick tock
sing a lot take that stuff you know
usually yeah so let me so anyway so what
am I gonna see yeah can you did you hear
the music were you able to hear the
music when I pray and pray that it's a
turn turn down
so that's you know that song and I was
doing you know I was writing about it
you know to see what it is and that song
is beautiful I found it then I found it
on YouTube okay check so do you do you
have a question like about Emacs or
programming or anything you want to ask
me
you know you need your give it know me
or when t go change eager so that that's
my music blog so that's my that's my
body blog okay this is this is this is
New York New York in Las Vegas this is
New York's skyline so I went to Las
Vegas like in 2004 and and I wrote a
travelogue so they have this face you
know this is a city of gambling and sex
and and they have this facade you know
this this thing is a facade they create
that to mimic the New York skyline so
you know and then there's a Statue of
Liberty there and that's when I started
to study yet you know I started to dig
into and you know knows about it so
there's that
a goddess goddess of freedom yes it's a
girl lovely and then she has you know he
or she is he or she is he says this is a
miniature so she is wearing this kind of
sandal I suppose of the that is the what
Roman or Greek or engine something like
that and there is a poem at the bottom
oh yeah so there is that here we have
the freedom goddess then we have the
gambling goddess
I suppose this is Fortuna she decides
your fate so here's my LasVegas
travelogue you can set you can find it
if you just search my name
Casali Las Vegas and stuff you know
there's mega hotels in jjigae hotels and
stuff and oh my god this Monte Carlo
disease of the Italian how you eruption
or engine and they got things well and
these sculptures you know they are
miniature you know they are copied you
know version of the real thing and many
of them are extremely beautiful you can
you can see that they depict the
voluptuousness of girls in every detail
of course you know in America the u.s.
culture they don't you know they feel
nervous about this thing but not in
Europe but however things have changed
you know as you know in in the past few
years anyway look at this one this guy
you know he's carrying the girl and just
flying around you can see her
expressions and you can see you see you
can see it's a animation it's animated
you can see how it is even they don't
move is in far liking and you know
running so anyway so I was like you know
actually when you know I was very and so
I took all these photos you know running
around just by myself and took photos
and for each of them I was trying to
find you know what's the saddest name
for this one for example I haven't found
it you know it took a long time and this
is back in 2004 there is no hippie dia
where it just began so I mean even today
so yeah I suppose if I try to do
research I find a name but does anyone
know what are these statues I mean the
name of this night
but anyway so Las Vegas report there are
tons of stuff you know this then there's
this mg and an MGM Grand which which is
a was modeled after the Queen City The
Wizard of Oz well only the color though
but not everything else everything else
the theme is basically slavery you know
what a great concept you go you know
when you are rich and powerful
you have slaves serving you look at
these guys this masculine you know well
beautiful even though I'm not gay but
this this you know masculine guys
holding stuff for you that I suppose
that represents I think it's there's a
Greek god Atlantis or something I could
get the name room but OC also this is in
your art deco-style
but there anyway there is a God that
holds the earth for you something like
that yeah this look you see it's it's
but however you know it's done cheaply
you know you look at this it's not well
done it's not that like I guess I
suppose everything art deco-style then
it's okay but I somehow find it you know
somewhat cheap looking the guy but you
know Joe notches the guys then of course
you have girls necessarily so you know
in places like this of course then you
have these then you have that you know
so I take it I took photos then you have
this lion habitat lion habitat what is
what what is the light lion habitat it's
so that when you are gambling and
sipping drinks in this place and you can
watch lions basically it's an indoor
elaborate cage of lions
so that is Las Vegas in 2004 and I
suppose it's pretty much the same thing
today and there is this Studio 54 you
know so when I was writing this page it
takes days you know a week just few
weeks you know weeks to write this
travelogue I mean I mean the tradition
of writing travelogues and then you have
this so Studio 54 that was that that is
a famous bar or something and look at
this chick standing on table tabletops
how a looing and that's just MGM grand
and so you know each each of these Omega
bigger g-got hotels and there's Caesars
Palace of course the Caesars the Roman
Empire you know it's a theme after the
Roman Empire Caesars Palace and this is
the most famous statue and this one as
well
you know I have discovered you know I
have right you know you can beat you
know what they are and this one is a
victory at Samothrace same old same old
face Cemil face something like that
victory Samothrace it's a sculpture
discovered in 2000 that was 2,000 or
3,000 years old victory at summer
samatha smother race or cemeteries
Samothrace god is a victory sculptor
unknown about 300 BC okay but however it
is in Paris she has moved you know she
called a taxi and she wanted to move to
Paris apparently because Paris is the
richer country so anyway in this statue
I haven't found what's the name
and you know this woman
guy oh and this okay spectacular this
one this one is called is called the
rape of say binds when I was there in
2004 you know I was you know arguing
around in Las Vegas by myself you know
this nerdy guy you know the Kings
running around taking photos and I saw
this I was shocked what you know this is
plated you know that says you know the
name rape of save mice
well even in Las Vegas you don't grow
glorify this thing how can they I mean
it's this is still USA right so I was
you know of this shocked you know the
what what what what is is the rape of
you know say mines then oh my god how
ignorant am i this is a this is a one of
the most the almost the defining thing
of Western society this is the art you
know the greatest thing story about rape
of sabors it's a Roman it's a legend of
the the founding of Rome you know but
anyway look at this sculpture it's
supremely beautiful
you know it's delineates the whole
situation so this is a soldier I mean
this grab the same semi women and that's
her dad so anyway so that's my visit to
Las Vegas yeah there are so many other
God gods and goddesses in Caesars Palace
you got the whole bunch of gods and
goddesses Roman god you know legends
they are all back borrowed from Greek I
don't care about the Romans actually and
well I like the Greeks much better quick
quick the Greek mythology is my religion
if you ask me what is my religion my
religion is quick mythology the gods and
goddesses of the Greek and in fact many
sure
you asked to become stupid babe sorry
the love of the me theology of the
Greeks what a mouthful hey good morning
good evenin great break the loop and
good even good evenin nomen so let me
look at the so if you if you guys have a
question type it I'll talk about that so
I just wandered the my topic wandered
into Greek mythology so where is my
article okay there is another article
the cut Apocalypse Now ride of the
Valkyries that's another that's the
Scandinavian mythology this movie
Apocalypse Now it's a great movie I can
never forget the helicopter scene you
know death from above
whoops stupid YouTube you know YouTube
has these problems anyway so the volcker
II you know that she is a goddess war
goddess of war anyway is a it's the
Scandinavian kind of Norse yeah what
knows I don't know much about not know
its mythology but you know it so you
know the comics you know the superhero
though that's from no no no where is no
say DIY I guess my I suppose it's in
Scandinavia in that region right but is
no see say is a is a Haitian country or
is it ethnicity something so okay anyway
let me check the comments you know
before i going astray too far
into some remote universe okay send
someone whoo
yeah I need a phone for sure I need the
phone you know I'm like a modern hermit
I don't have a phone doing okay
motocross operation multi cause multi
cursor operation in emacs
I actually don't use that I don't use
multi cause I think so what do you think
about software bloat compared to the old
days of complete IDs in less than one
megabyte yeah what can you say about
that I mean well yeah there's a lot of
software bloat for sure and but on the
other hand you know all the memories and
hard disk size and CPU speed they are
growing growing exponentially I mean
literally exponentially if you measure
them you know each year you know the
standard hard disk size and the memory
size so I mean it's impractical to write
software so that you know like the like
20 years ago because it's because you
know I thought about this one time it's
like saving pennies you know like when
you when you were young or at least when
I was young in China you know you in
Chinese culture you save pennies like
each day you have a cake you put pennies
pennies inside and you know the the
point is you know what well this one but
the point is you know they accumulate so
after year you got some money you know
but actually I mean today I mean also a
doubt they don't you know they don't
accumulate like if you save a dollar you
know
yeah it's saving every day you know
you're putting a dollar after year you
got $300 what you're gonna do with it
you know it $300 you cannot you can
survive you know you cannot survive for
a week well you can yeah I mean you know
so you know you know so so and come you
know
converted to programming so you know so
this relates to programming because
because in programming communities for
example C or C++ I've seen you know
people people try to save microseconds
you know they argue for days about you
know which to use for example let me
give you example for example you have
this I equals 2
I press 1 ok you have that statement but
you can also write it as I plus I yeah
you can also write it as that and in C+
first for example you can simply do that
now I don't know about today but in the
past these are different statements
meaning that the compile conduct
compiler will create assembly you know
machine code that that are different
this one is the fastest so if you are
coding C let's say 20 years ago you when
you want to you know do assignment like
that you want to use this one what I
press for us you know it's like tsipras
first you want to do that why because
that tells the compiler you know you
just want to increment it on the other
hand if you do it this way back then it
is back then the compiler is not smart
enough you know they cannot figure out
so they have to go the general way in
the generate code that's less efficient
than these but of today in these cases
this this specific case probably doesn't
matter anymore because the compilers has
been smart enough they were just you
know they will see that these are the
same thing ok that comes to another
point about language design I'll talk
about that someone remind me ok but
anyway back to the back to about the
saving pennies you know ok this this is
one example that properly doesn't matter
but there are some other examples that
still matter but my point is you know
some of these different way to code at
you
at the language I'm not sure how you
call it
syntax level or kind of EDM level okay
suppose you have two different code that
does exactly the same thing
mathematically algorithmically
however they the compiler because they
are different code different idioms
different styles they create different
machine code they generate different
machine code you know children so they
are they are different in the sense that
they their speed the speed is different
usually usually by not much by
microseconds
so the point is just you know why should
you so people argue programmer argue
about it or often well maybe not today
but often it's saying mm you know the
programmers you know they argue about it
you know they say okay you should do it
this way or you know that you need
hacker types you should do this way
because you know the compiler create
faster code and so on but if you think
about it you know that's okay saving
microseconds does that make sense okay
so if you a whole program you pay
attention to these things you did you
know these things are not easy to come
by I mean the knowledge about this you
know it takes stays you know it takes a
habit to study read about all these
details to actually know about these
things so you spend huge amount of Tanna
as a programmer on these kind of things
but the you're whole' software if you
pay attention to these things home how
much do they save how much time do they
save actually imperceptible by the
average programmer so you are average I
mean imperceptible by the average user
of your software yeah really
imperceptible so so so this case you
know I was thinking it's like saving
pennies you know you you save with ten
pennies a day you know it amounts to
nothing you know really it's like
doesn't matter
in fact technique be scientifically
speaking technically speaking if you
measure all the time you spend and so on
it's actually a waste of your time it's
a
waste of the resources in a ward all
things considered you know you because
you are a programmer you can your time
spend you can do more valuable things
for the world
you know then spending time about
worrying about which way you know is
it's a few microsecond faster or which
style of indentation and so on
yeah indentation that's another topic
coding style and formatting there's like
tons of pages about in each language
they tell you how you should format it
the proper way is really just like Golan
you have a program you press a button it
formats for you for everyone the same
way you know that's the way but stupid
programmers especially the hacker types
like despise they day every day they
tell you how you should format your code
well let me give you example okay
there's this Emacs this Emacs I don't
like okay he might watch my video that's
hi guy hi guy you know so sometimes I
ran about people and criticize and he's
you know if you are if I'm criticizing
you then you probably don't you know
like it too much you know but I
criticize all the time but anyway
there's this let's see so that's such
for Emacs project I he he's a great
Emacs coder of course Emacs decoder and
he has written many Emacs
packages that are very popular so the
guy is this guy be passive you know he
he so he wrote projectile which is very
popular
it's a package for if you work on
project
it's a package for you to manage your
project like read sort of open certain
files such within your project and
things like that I don't use it I'm well
because I don't use much of packages
yeah so that's this guy
bozer da paths off okay
now he is in Sofia Bulgaria
okay somewhere in like Europe like
eastern side or middle of Europe and he
has written you know he is into
programming styles [ __ ] foreign stars
he has written the crows Crozier style
guide and let me show you
repositories to magnify so his written
style guide is such for style
kosha style guide Emacs style guy go
[ __ ] yourself okay
Emacs this past guides my territory he
has also by the way I can't find it here
it's or next he has also written Ruby
style guide let's see yeah but anyway
you get a point he has also written Ruby
style guide but I mean the point is that
he likes you know he liked the style
guide you know he's the he's a hacker
type the unique hacker type I despised
okay nothing wrong with a person I know
he's he's probably a greater got great
guy and he has written more you know
more valuable coding eMac B's than me
okay he he probably knows more
immigrants than me okay
nothing wrong with a guy but but the the
but his ideas he's thinking you know I
despise he's one of the elite hacker
type you know I despise so so back to
the style guide so here's written you
know closure style guide you know the e
Magnus style guy so what they do I mean
they are like they are like rule stick
you know they the guide you know they
want to tell you how you should format
your code and how you should name your
variables you know it's like and usually
they say you know to make it more
popular he opened this this type of
often people often say this is community
based you know like
oh this is just not my opinion this is
like the community based consensus about
how you should you know the name your
variables are where you should put the
indent to [ __ ] yourself these people
these people are idiots I hate this
video it is it is these people you know
these elite hacker types that spread all
the garbage wasting programmers time and
and dude and kind of you know you know
do things to the industry now let me
tell you why first of all Slough Qaeda
covers many things but many there are
two parts okay you can generally
separates our guys into two parts one is
the one is mostly about formatting
issues for example formatting you know
where how many intents you should be you
know where you should put your bracket
you know you know where you should put
your bracket now that part okay so
there's this indent a formatting part
now this the other part which is more
valid okay I agree which is about the
naming well okay maybe the naming of
variables because in different languages
you know some allow cap case some some
you know allow underscore and then you
have classes you have function names you
have you know global variables so naming
conventions usually helps helps in some
way in your project but anyway it's a
mess but I mean it's it's a mess among
different languages and even within
language one language let's say Python
you have different styles of naming you
know because google says one thing but
you know another microsoft says another
thing they kind of you know they don't
really it's not really that great thing
I mean it's not really I mean even if
you have a style guide on these kind of
issues
okay so naming is one of the things
there are other things like idioms like
when you write a loop to do something
usually depending on language you know
usually you want to avoid certain way
because that way
it's slow you know it bounced down your
program so there are some some good tips
about idioms you know
so anyway style guy arch it in general
there are two issues why is mostly about
formatting the otherwise about idioms
and variable names and stuff okay in
general
okay the formatting part is the most
worst worst less you know that any
anyone espouses the formatting about
style guide they should be I don't want
to say the word he because Google gonna
pair me they should well what I mean is
that you you kick them in the ass okay
you kick them in yes what should be done
is that you should any any language you
should come with the language at or like
colon colon is such a great idea you
know go that they you know so for
example in colon go language you have a
go format fmt that's a tool go format
okay let's show you a let me show you
example so a new buffer switch to go mod
okay so go mod okay then I'm going to
insert my template go okay so you can
see I have my stuff let's say so I run
it or I can say that I have to save it I
run it and okay it's study three it
prints 33 okay now I call the command go
format hey formats the entire file you
know by what by one kind of standardized
format so you never have to worry about
any formatting for example let's put the
whole thing into one line okay now I
call go format no it doesn't do this
part okay why is that
let's see
let me magnify so hey can you guys hear
me I know that am i doing good so let's
see two plus three okay so let's see
print two purse three and put it in one
line and let's call go format okay so it
doesn't actually separate the lines but
that's a flaw that's a problem they
should solve that anyway but if you co
go format you will format your entire
source code into one you know a
standardized way this is the approach
you should do and in fact Mathematica
has this like since you know since year
2000 since 19 since Mathematica three
come out so this is what you should do
you know you should have a program I
come with the the compiler you know that
just people call and when you have this
program it's also automatically building
you can have a automatically building
into the editor for example I used to
you know when I run a when I run a go
program it it also automatically Costco
format for me you know I took that hook
off because I want to do it manually
because sometimes I'm not ready yet you
know so anyway so the point is you
should have a program that automatically
format your code and this program should
be part of the compiler you know part of
the you know your language software so
that once you have this there will be no
discussion no writing you know wasting
people's time about formatting the other
thing is about formatting is that people
anyway that's another whole topic I can
go on one hour about it so anyway so the
formatting you don't you know you you
want the automatic okay and also for
especially insulting to me this is the
Lisp language now the formatting issue
depends on the language because because
in some languages you cannot have
fencing all in one life for example if
you have all in one line because the
newline the
new line character has six semantic
significance so you know and okay that's
another huge topic oh my god I'm going
like into a river and river lots of
topics
sorry why space let's see that you know
in programming language they say okay
what does it mean
well programming language crimes
whitespace is in second ear this this is
a huge amount daughter goes okay that's
a lot of topics to talk about so what
does it mean when a programming language
claims whitespace is insignificant you
know a lot language like to claim that
but there's out and then idiotic
programmers like they discuss about this
but they they have no idea what they are
talking about anyway so this is this
article you can read a talk about Perl
Ruby emag this in JavaScript anyway did
about the formatting that I have a huge
amount of things to talk about and okay
here is JavaScript what space what is
this this page shows what's considered
whitespace from JavaScript SPECT okay
okay well that's another page you can
read if you want and this is a page that
shows you how to do how to show white
space in Emacs and whites and this is
another trend okay like this in Emacs
you have this package building code
white space mod that's part of Emacs
maybe six years ago ten years ago and by
default it shows things like that
extremely idiot you know idiotic well
anyway on this page I show you I show
you how to configure it and so it
display things like this anyways back to
the topic so is it these formatting
issues it relates to syntax of the
language it relates to several other
things
I'm going to okay so that topic so I can
take I can talk up for a few hours but
let's go back to the formatting style so
formatting you know you you want to have
the it automated it should be okay now
on the EDM part side you know some of it
is valid let's go back to this guy's you
know X style guide okay this email style
guide should be banned you know this is
this is he he he is spreading this
[ __ ] you know because he spread this
[ __ ] and and a lot of people you
know especially on reddit you know this
hacker types ok this code type of
programmers like they think they are
elite you know like him he's he's
exactly one of that such person and he
think of you you know sometimes you
watch his videos you know he think he's
like you know he's above above it you
know he he knows better than you he's
gonna tell you what to do so he created
this you know well of course he's mine
you know he was like thinking he's
helpful you know he's being a leader you
know he helped the Emax immunity you
know help everyone created you know
style guide what a [ __ ] you know so
anyway so the sustar this should be
banned especially with the Lisp language
because the least lambic language has
such a uniform syntax you and it's
trivial it's trivial to write a program
that are actually format for you but to
this day we don't have it for 30 years
you know I talked to this programmers
they don't they don't know their brain
is like tofu made of tofu you know in
Mathematica which is a far more
accomplished OH you a little bit of
Mathematica since we are talking about
this topic so let's go go to sorry dot
info okay so now my blood pressure is
going up I haven't read the comments yet
I'll do so you know in a minute how long
have I been talking now okay go back to
hacker code go to the top of my page
and there is this Mathematica language
okay let me just show you a couple of
things okay this is mathematical coding
in in in its you know what's called a
notebook I mean a default editor for
Mathematica you see this thing you see
these expressions this method this
method expressions mathematical code
when you type you know it's such a way
when you type it formats this
complicated expression for you
automatically as you type this is a
[ __ ] whispers okay
and Mathematica is life is a language
that's basically a list family okay so
you know it form as benders these
two-dimensional things as you type
starting with Mathematica version three
in released in 1998 okay around 1998 and
you know and and today we still have
programmers like oh you should you know
eat the basically today each programmer
they form at line by line like in Emacs
you know you eat when you type you press
ENTER it tries to format one line and
and then you have to intend and all the
people you still to this day you're
talking about oh how do you intend liked
it this way how to do it you know this
is this [ __ ] idiocy buddies you did
hacker [ __ ] okay so so you don't you
know you you want a program I just
eliminate this programming style things
you know you this topic is so you know
it's it's one of the epitome of the
elite hacker stupidity okay because in
every programming this elite kind of
programming language in Perl in Python
in Common Lisp being email is you know
you have a bunch of style guides like
they tell you how to format what what
style should it be and everyone talk
about it at a every day day and night
like on reddit you know every time this
maybe this style guide shows up on
reddit and everyone is like you know
some some bit of you know okay that's
one time that's that
the topic about the formatting I'm okay
that's that that crows is one topic now
I was going to talk about I was why I
was talking about the the love of the
mythology of the Greek mythology okay
maybe I'll talk about that but maybe
something else where's my [ __ ]
I want to show my page okay so anyway it
syncs all odds okay let's just go to
Chris arts sods this will be quick okay
sorry okay there here is my domain so
I'll start
org and by the way this this one is a
polish artist it's one of the greatest
artists his name is Stanley Stanislaw
Zaleski something like that polish
artist is amazing art he create amazing
on okay and and he turned out he kind of
lived in in in poor you know poorly and
he is also a very he's kind of a nut job
you know he has now here's a drawing of
Bertrand Russell one of my favorite
author of all times is somehow he
doesn't like Bertrand Russell so he he
chose you know he portrays war so as
this kind of you know guy and he's
drawing on Japanese women anyway so case
arts star visual arts then you are see
anyway I have a page about quick
mythology where I discuss you know many
of the great
Greek mythology they hear a love of
mythology of the Greeks
now she this girl this this this this
sculpture is actually a sculpture in
Caesar's Palace in Las Vegas a gambling
hotel you know her name is Artemis she
you know in today's terms she is the
greatest [ __ ] you know of all times in
history you know what what does she do
she's the goddess she's you know the the
highest God is she's she's she has
perpetual virginity she asked her dad
Zeus to get to grant her perpetual
virginity and she kills people she he
killed other you know what this 12 she
and her brother Apollo or polis Apollo's
you know shoot like hunting game you
know killed the 12 children of women
because the women boasted that you know
she has 12 children more than her mom
you know her mom her mom only has her in
her brother a polis so she shot him
killed him you know the greatest
beautiful you know of course she's the
most beautiful you know girl and she
killed you know hunters you know she and
her maids know she had bunch of mates
following her and you know he's walking
around in a forest and a hunter you know
a huntsman saw her and she just she
killed him the hunter saw her taking a
bath
and she she made the hunters dogs or
wolves you know rent the guy you know so
that's what she does and then there's
other Greek mythologies and you know
it's not mom you know he's so so here's
the nymphs and Medusa or the gogans
Medusa
my god Medusa you know the girl with the
snake head because you know why she was
the most beautiful girl in a world okay
but one day she's [ __ ] she's lucky
she was a suppose you know they say
she's waived by the the goddess of the
sea Poseidon in the temple in the tempo
of the another goddess Athena yeah in
the temple of Athena Athena angry you
know so you know so Athena made her you
know she made her to be the ugliest
women possible to such a degree if you
look at her and if you love her you know
if you lock eyes with her you become a
stone you know you don't want to look at
ugly girls because you don't know what
to do
you don't to look at them that's what
happened to her that's how big she
became what she is Medusa you know so
the Greek mythology they have stories in
days thus their stories reflect reality
reflect the human animals nature the
jealousy the you know the pride the lost
you know the temptations and stuff and
this this this this the story of the dad
dyad Dallas in the her son Icarus Icarus
how you have however you say it
this stupid young person you know so
this stylist dyad alice is he's an
engineer he's the one of the greatest
engineer okay there's so many stories
involving you know the miner tour you
know the poor with half human the pool
monster but anyway he's a great engineer
you know so many stories but he so he
may need wings you know and he and his
son flew and he told us sir not to fly
too high and the Sun ignored it you know
I can I can fly you know he's in fly too
high in the Sun
melted his wings and he fell to his
death so here that there there is the
lesson for you young people okay and so
on a Greek mythology and oh my god this
one this one is the death of the the
death of Hector of Troy great hero but
anyway so there's a lot you know have
that squeak mythologies but let me go
back to read the comments I probably
went astray by far fifteen minutes okay
I've been talking for 15 minutes
okay so let's sweet let me read the
comments so what do you think about
software bloat okay so I haven't
finished talking about that topic but
basically so saving microseconds is no
good okay but also but in also today's
software you know the CPU and so on the
hardware or become exponentially more
resource you know more powerful but
software bloat I mean the actual concept
blow still exists because a lot of
people you know you know as there are
more and more programmers you know
programmers they just write using higher
and higher languages but that's not only
good meaning program has become less
knowledgeable about programming so they
write garbage essentially they create
garbage like a lot of today's JavaScript
you know seeing so they create a huge
amount of garbage so so the software
becomes so they actually slow I mean you
can see you know some software you
shouldn't be so at all like you know
something you know people it becomes you
know like it takes one second to to load
for example mini-pig webpages are like
that it shouldn't be because they are
loading 100 libraries frameworks this
Java scripts idiot frameworks because
they don't know how to write you know
five lines of code two
trimmed string you know dream the head
and tail of a stream they exist like a
library that trim stream that's just
five lines of JavaScript library and
that use that's used by you know
thousand thousand frameworks and a few
years back that was that became a big
issue because something happened but
anyway yeah so you know the JavaScript
world so so yeah that create prose so
that's a situation you know but okay my
my thinking okay my point of view my
advice on this is always you know any
subject you want to look at things
scientifically you know you don't want
to fall into you know the typical elite
hackers you know whatever they say or or
you know for example
oh yeah it's bloat you know everything
that people don't know how to write
programs is broad and meanwhile the
hacker types are you know doing micro
codes you know saving microseconds it
they spent one hour to argue about which
way saves 10 microseconds you know so so
bloody exists you know as a programmer
you want to be you know you try not to
really have you know you should know
what you are doing now of course
javascript is that way because then this
this NPM
you know which is a commercial you know
greedy enterprises the NPM leader is is
is a scum okay I don't I don't actually
know that person that much but from the
few incidents
you know happenings in the past few
years the people from the few I've read
I observed the guy I think he's a
scumbag you know I don't mean just
technique of technique like usually I
attack the hacker types because I have a
different point of view on technical
issues you know but but there are some
programmers I think they are actually
bad person and I think the leader of the
MPM the JavaScript and the NPM guy is a
bad person I think okay I'm not too sure
about that by the way for disclaimer
you know this is just totally opinion
you know I don't actually know the guy
okay yeah in case he gonna sue me
okay so so yeah that's a bad bloat yeah
so let's see
okay quite a few comments let me go
through and and maybe that'll be it for
today so I like Michelangelo's pietà
okay I don't know what's that one what
is your opinion on Las Vegas I know last
would you ever live there no I wouldn't
well I mean it's a it's a place where
you go there you can bow and there's you
know girls and there's an interesting
thing okay Las Vegas listen we're known
for prostitute right but actually the
Las Vegas city actually it's illegal to
prostitution prostitution is illegal in
the Las Vegas city but of course people
still do it you know but but technically
it's illegal there but however if you
want to go you know it's it's outside of
Las Vegas it's legal you know but but
you know fewer of course people people
go there you know still do it so in Las
Vegas you know in Nevada it's very dry
it's actually a desert you know there is
so the you can you know you go there
actually your nose you know your notice
that it's you you get sandy you know
it's it's very dry but I notice you know
a lot other people I mean I think other
people live there as a retirement
so yeah let's let's Las Vegas I save the
microsecond hi Daniel Wrangler is hey
Danielle I haven't I'm sorry I haven't
looked at your pool requests on
Sophocles yet I haven't got to it yet
you know yeah so I so okay it depends on
the context I'm programming for hft I'm
saving the microsecond but otherwise I
think you are right what is hft okay
still sassing
oh so Norman says hi Norman still it's
sad seeing electron apps taking 8g
gabbai to make a text chat client yeah
so electron is a framework that uses
JavaScript to you know so you can build
apps from it using javascript and the
heart of electron is basically Google
Chrome browser right yeah I always
wanted to look into electrons but I just
never had but I think Adam is created
you know the atom editor is that's our
engine of electron the framework is
split out from the atom editor Adam is
the editor created by github company
that create you know that few years ago
by now it's already like six years ago I
think so electron and also Microsoft
also be out there new editor Microsoft
code out of electron oh yeah you know I
really I like to look into but I got so
many things and I don't have money you
know it's you know I'm doing the video
but so by the way okay so let me just
say this so if you like my things go to
my web site of course
put your money there you know donate you
can you know it's you go to any of my
blog you know put money there so let's
go back to the comments so in isn't
there something to be said for
consistent course tiles for a project
that multiple people can contribute to
yeah so this refers to coding style yeah
I mean I'm not saying that coding style
is you know totally bad the format the
formatting issues is bad okay you should
you know if you are you know company or
whatever oh yeah I mean even if you
create a language or exist existing
languages you should use a you know
software that just format your code so
you don't don't don't don't ever do it
manually
they should be part of the editors you
know you just press a button it formats
your whole code oh it should be you know
every time you know yeah you should have
that on the other hand for variable and
EDM issues of course the company you
know it's up to the company you know you
you know you might have a standard but
the thing is you know it's just you know
different languages you know here okay
here's what I say you know you should
you know when you create a new language
or programmers should know okay much of
the idioms issue depends on the language
you know the the very very much depends
on the design that I mean the specific
language so you want to create a rank
when you create a language you know you
want to make it so that so that it well
I'm not sure what's the term to describe
this but basically it should has the
property it should have the property
that that basically eliminate eliminates
the idea of idioms and you know
different ways of variable you know
naming issues you can do that you create
a language that eliminates that issue
for example for example I mean this is a
silly example but just to illustrate for
example your language you allow only
lowercase for variable names period I
mean there's no cabs okay only lowercase
and in and let's say let's say you allow
the underscore so if you have a language
like that then obviously there's not
going to be issues about you know cap
case or camel case your snake is because
you know if you have that won't compile
you know so so that's one thing of
course
then you're gonna ask okay but if you
have all our case then but you need
something else
I mean I'm give me I just illustrate the
issue okay but it's absolutely doable
enforce it in your language you know do
that that way so that that eliminates
the issue about you know the variable
case naming issue first first of all
now let me give you another example
about the idiom such as such as you know
I press press versus I you know equal
plus equal plus 1 versus you know for
example equals 2 I plus 1 then there's
many sleepless press the most idiotic
language you also have I equals 2
I press equals to 1 you know the you
have these kind of things so in your
language you don't want these things rid
of them there they are they are stupid
created by the C and C++ programmers why
they create that because they are
compilers are stupid so they create this
and they they tell programmers you know
to do that what should happen is you
just have this syntax period okay
because you know yeah but if you are a
compiler writer or if you are familiar
with you know low-level programming I
despise the low-level programmers
typically it's them create all these
these things okay so you won't only have
this form okay but then you then there's
a valid question
yeah but the compiler are not smart
enough you know you know so you know if
you have this form it's actually faster
that's a valid point but but here this
is this perspective that's your problem
that's compared to a writer's problem
that's not programmers problem okay
iOS on programmer oh I want to do is you
know I want to assign a variable and I
want increments and this is a universal
syntax you know I don't want to worry
about these details about compiler
details that's your problem that's not
my problem
don't put your problems on to me okay so
it's a c scumbag so kc programmers cants
about a C++ as I say you know C and UNIX
they are the father of everything that's
wrong in in programming industry they
created this kind of thing then they
spread you know they because C so lousy
then
see prosperous then you have pearl you
have seashell then you have Java it's
all based on sin agree and then you have
JavaScript of course also based on C
syntax you know it's a virus you know
each time improves a little bit okay so
that's the issue so you at the language
level you want good design in Python to
you especially Python stupid Kaido
he likes to create this so in kaido's
syntax you have lots of these things
because he you know he thinks you know
this is more efficient but he don't
realize that you know as a programmer
you know as a compiler writer that's
your problem you know you you create
whatever you can do you know if you
cannot optimize your code you know you
know that's your problem
you know you as a compiler I don't want
to you know for each whatever I do I
have you know ten choices you know which
is faster in this situation or which we
is that not faster you know I just want
specify algorithm that's my that's what
I want to do as a programmer my job is
to specify algorithms not worrying about
optimization at whatever see whatever
CPU or CPU you know whatever machine you
know so that's that is my take now as a
programmer you know you should
understand that you should understand
this this perspective okay about
optimizing compiler that's one problem
programmers job you know that's another
problem you you've you as a programmer
any programmer must know that these are
two distinct tasks different concepts
then as a language designer you know
what when you create a language you know
then it's up to you to you know maybe
you know yeah you idea you know your
mathematical oriented idea is good but
however we still need to be practical
so you know maybe in some cases we want
to have different syntax so that you
know one syntax is really fast you know
because you know compilers there's no
way to you know it I'll take technology
there's no way to you know make it fast
that's totally understandable you know
but the point is you have to understand
this there are different things which is
not happening in most of these hacker
types this Elise
he beat you know as you know III was you
know many of my programming opinion
anyway that's another topic so that's
about okay so I think I talk to a lot
quite a lot and how long have I been
talking one hour and six minutes okay
let's keep the comments it's keep
reading the comments : okay so so still
okay so next comment isn't there
something to be said for consistent code
yeah and next comment
you see same thing other domains such as
newspapers yeah so you know we hear your
sides good break the loop great to see
you know man anomalous a scholar has
great Turing's around the language yeah
that's great
Daniel says I've always been found over
the power way when it comes to
formatting source code apply the
official for my formatting options for
the source code doing checking they have
that I didn't know they must have yeah
it's so long it's been a long time I
coded for literally like 18 years ago
night no yeah almost 20 years ago so Bo
Johnson says hype oh you have a point
when you mentioned Godot format go
format but I'd rather be able to choose
how to style my own code okay that's a
good point
automatic formatting tools around the
more yeah that's a good point so some
people prefer you know for whatever
reasons they prefer certain styles of
formatting and that can be rolled into
as an option of the formatting tool like
go format I'm not sure go format does
that
but anyway first of all you should have
a software that format your code you
know entire like whole directory of you
know 10 min your eyes you know that and
that shouldn't be difficult to write
again it depends on language okay you
should you first of all you want to
create a language that that the syntax
has a property that it makes it very
easy to format entire you know thousand
lines of code even if they are all in
one line you know that's so that's
another topic you know there's a issue
about the newline syntax anyway that's
another topic but anyway so you should
have a true to that to do that then then
it's another question about whether the
tool should provide options so that
different programmers can you know can
you know can kind of have their their
own preferred way of formatting but
anyway nice you know what one format is
still good you know I mean that's just
my opinion but I mean yeah it's it's
good to have options you know if I mean
it depends on the creator of the
language right you know he might think
you know you know you know you maybe if
he's dictatorship in kind and you just
want to create just one format you know
you just stick with with this format if
you want different format create your
own tool you know co-create you want to
and if if some other people you know
they maybe they are more you know yeah
you know I want people to have choice
you know so well if that's the case then
different companies will have different
format you know in general that's not
good idea
so if you allow options for different
formatting you should have still one
option that is you know the standard so
you know the code in anywhere in a word
should appear the same that's a good
idea
so H F key is a Wall Street
high-frequency trading
oh okay so you have so
[Music]
let me can i microfiber Indo on a second
it's a few of a program in speed is
paramount oh yeah I should add a link to
my donations you know about the donation
every time I ask for it I don't feel you
know is it's it's not something I feel
like you know maybe you know like you
know doing yeah but I should do that you
know because I mean I mean logically
it's it's I say I can see I have I have
of course I have valid reasons because
I'm creating things so I create things
if people like you know you put money to
me but there's also the other hand you
know I just I guess it's my personality
and it's probably not so good because it
has to do with a schizoid personality
you know one of the trade of the
schizoid personality I talked about that
a few times in my past videos like two
of the videos you can see the schizoid
personality one of the things is that
they are we we kind of aloof okay well a
disappears to others we don't we don't
ask for anything like I don't want to
ask anything you know I'm just here by
myself I don't want to ask anything yeah
like yeah yeah that's the schizoid
personality so well I use this identify
a case to distinguish between variable
and Adam yeah that's a good example you
know different anguishes has that and
yeah Adams okay a great green deck a
great green deck so Daniel says Adams in
Orlando prologue or symbols in this for
Ruby they have no underlying
representation to worry about they are
invisible in indivisible atoms or
symbols
I think I I know what you're saying but
I forgot what's a context they look like
strings for perform almost like integers
you know yeah I sometimes I forgot the
context like I should be able you know
yes like the tap you know what I was
talking about something and I you know
then later I look at the comment I
forgot a context and okay I guess that's
almost it for today I mean unless you
guys are how many people are watching
let's see 10 people but I've been
talking for yes 70 minutes I think
that's it for today and let's go if
there is something I missed
you know I want to talk about I don't
think so so a style guide crochet style
guide yeah you know it's especially
insulting to me because style guide
should never happen on these languages
because this these languages you know
it's all nested parentheses
it has a inherent property that it is
trivial you know you want to write a
software to write a program that you
press a button is reformat the whole
thing so I have written about this issue
like you know 5 or 10 articles you can
see if you want to look at that you know
it's it's in syntax roof on least you
know anyway you see I have like you know
quite a few articles about that it's one
of my big issue about this formatting
you know people anyway that's a yeah I
should talk make another talk about that
another day so yeah good point
so thank you guys for coming I think
that's it for today I'll see you guys
next time bye