Morning, good evening, good afternoon.
Welcome to another episode of K Talk
Show. If you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed because I ramble. Uh,
today we're going to code wam language.
So, I'm going to show you how to define
functions via the function keyword which
is kind of like lambda in other
languages and or how to define function
using pattern matching. Okay. So, Wuam
language tutorial. Search for it on
si.info. You'll find it. And uh here is
where to download it for free. Okay. So,
let's begin. So, um yeah, wam language
um um function definition. Okay. So, uh
then I need to code. So, I need to code
this uh modify this code. Okay. So
negative pedal. So let me just show you
first. Uh so today's talk show and go
here and uh then let's open a wam
language. Uh and uh yeah there paste it
there. Pop it out. So wam language I
already started wam language 14. Paste
it and uh run it. Okay. So, let's make
the window
large.
So, 150%. Uh, that's too large. 125%.
Okay. Okay. So, here is a code. Control
shift D to separate into two blocks and
evaluate the first part. So control
shift D. So actually evaluate it.
Controll enter. Evaluate it. Then
control enter. Then we got that. Then we
can change the
uh change the function function. So
negative plot. I did two live streams
about this thing uh about introduction
to wraim language graphics. So you can
watch it about a month ago.
on my YouTube. So I want to show
uh what is this part? This must be
the negative the pedo point. Where is
the pedo point now? Here. So 0 0. So
let's say 0 0. Then you got that. Then
if you change it to
one
one then you got a different shape. So
let's try to change it to 44. See what
happens. Four four. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Beautiful. So we going to So
how do you write a function? So okay. So
let me let me show
you language. Pop it out. So the the
most simple way to define a
function, most easy way to define a
function. The most simple way to define
a function is via this function keyword.
So for example, x + one and that's a
function. Then you can evaluate it.
Let's say evaluate at three and run it.
So you got four. So for
example, and if you and you can of
course assign it to a uh name. So my
fun.
Okay. So if you say that then let's add
a
clear my phone. Okay. So my phone is a
function. Now you just say my phone and
let's say three and you will get four.
Okay. Now what about uh what about
multiple parameters? Uh very easy. So
you just add so this function you just
add this x. So for example add another
uh parameter xy. So let's say x + y.
Okay. So now let's say call it
34. Okay. And uh why do you need that
part?
Oh yeah, you don't need that part.
Forget. Okay, so let's try this again.
Run
it. Oh, it returns. Yeah. Okay, that's a
return value. So let's put a semicolon
at the end. That will suppress suppress
this
constant. So now evaluate
again. You see you got four. Okay. Now
here now we now we have two uh
parameters add a semicolon to suppress
output and uh delete that run it
function 3 4 so the result is seven so
this is how to define a function very
simple uh and this function keyword is
just like lambda in lisp in or like
function in javascript uh it's kind and
lambda in python so it's lambda in other
programming
languages. Now, uh there's a limitation
if you use this if you use this function
keyword to define a function. Um
basically there's a limitation on the
parameter. So it allows you to have
um using function
uh wait uh
okay function
to define a function has a
limitation on
the function
parameters. Okay,
namely you can only have ordered
param rest
param. Okay. But but you cannot
have default
values. Okay. So when we define a
functions usually we want to say if for
example if y is not given then just
equals to three that's a default value
or when x is not given things like that.
So but but that does not uh this
function keyword does not allow you to
do that.
Okay. So this function keyword is the
most fundamental like lambda just like
lambda in lambda calculus. It's
basically reflect mathematical function.
Okay. So in mathematical function you I
mean you don't really have like default
value for a parameter you know you just
give out all parameters. But in practice
when you want to define a function in a
programming language usually you want
some kind of default parameters. You
also want uh kind of structure matching
you
know so that you can um so you want
default parameters you want optional
parameters. So again this function
keyword do not allow you to have option
parameters.
Okay. Okay. You can you can have ordered
parameters, rest parameters but you
cannot default values option optional
param or named param. So named
parameters, optional parameters and
default values. These are kind of uh
computer engineering programming
language issues. They are not
mathematical issues. So this function
keyword is just for mathematical
functions.
So in in order to have
default values, optional params or named
params you need to define function by
using pattern
matching okay so how do you do that for
example so let's say let's say I want to
define the you know just same like that
okay so let's say I want to uh define a
function you know that returns + one of
the argument. So what you do is my fun
equals to now this you use colon
equal. Okay. So then then you say um uh
actually you uh yeah so you do this way.
So you want one argument and that okay
let me just show you how to write it
first then I
explain. Okay that's how you write it.
Now let's add a
clear. So this is how you define a
function. My fun of one argument and uh
the body of the function is just
argument plus one. How does this work?
This is pattern matching. Okay. So this
the full syntax for this is actually let
me show that because that will become
make it very clear. Hello
Palash. Are you the uh Palash? Are you
the uh panache guy? The Indian guy. Uh
so so to define we so we want so this is
pattern matching. Okay. So what does it
mean? So this means uh let me show you
set
delayed. Okay. Set delayed two
parameters. You want to set my function
and uh
um then you want to
um yeah hold on a second. So two
argument the first one is what you what
pattern you want to
set. So uh uh so okay hold on a second.
So um let me show you first.
plus. Okay. So set set delay basically
what it does is actually it define it
sets a value. Okay. The left hand side
set set the right hand side to the left
hand side. Now the for for the whole
sess session. Okay. So that means
whenever wam language sees whatever
pattern here it will replace it by that.
Okay. Sets a
pattern
whenever left hand
side match replace it by right hand
side. Okay, that's how set delay work.
Okay, so the right hand side is just
plus x1. Okay, the left hand side is
needs to be a pattern. Okay. So in in
our case to be in our case we need it to
be okay we need to be a pattern and uh
the pattern name will be X okay and uh I
believe that's a sing uh okay let me
just finish it first the the pattern
name will be X then the pattern is
blank okay so what so what this pattern
means this pattern is a named pattern.
Okay, so the pattern is blank means that
it matches anything any value any
expression you'll just match. Okay, so
whenever you match you assign it to a
name X. Okay, so that is a pattern. Then
you set delay of this pattern. So that
means
whenever wuan language sees this pattern
which is basically anything
uh then it will replace it by plus xy
where x is what whatever that pattern
is. Actually we need something else
here. So we need a named pattern. So the
named pattern will be uh
my it will be that. Okay. So this is the
actual so this is actually syn the the
full form syntax syntactically
equivalent to this line. Okay. Uh but
let let's double check. So let's double
check. Okay. So when you say full form
hold that will show the full syntax for
that. So let's paste it here. Run it. So
you see this is the result. So let me
show it here. So let's compare to see if
we got it right. Okay. So
paste and uh okay. So set
delayed my function check pattern
fantastic blank fantastic and plus
fantastic exactly exactly as I have
written. So that means I I'm pretty
familiar with this. Okay. So what am I
showing here is
that I'm showing that this syntax to
define a function via pattern matching
is in fact identical
to to this expression identical because
whenever wam language evaluates we it
will convert any of these short hand to
this fully nested form. Okay. So these
two things are completely
identical
100%. Okay. So so this set delayed. So
but now how does it work? So the reason
we are using this is actually to define
a function. That's our intention. That's
programmer's intention. You know we want
to define a function and and in wam
language this is you know we are
actually doing pattern matching. So what
we are doing is that we are creating a
permanent replacement rule for the
current session. So this rule is called
set delayed. Why delay? That means the
right hand
side evaluation is not evaluate right
away. only
until the left hand side when it's
evaluate when the left hand side finds a
match then the right hand side evaluates
so that means whenever x actually
matched something then the right hand
side evaluate and that x will become
something okay that's why it's set
delayed so set is just like you know set
x equals to three you know so it's like
set delayed okay Then the set delay
takes two arguments. The left hand side
is a pattern and this pattern is
just just a symbol my followed by a
bracket then by a pattern and it's named
X. Okay, the pattern is blank means
anything. So that means so whenever you
see this pattern whenever you evaluate
something in wam language after you
define after you run this. So whenever
wam language sees this my fun something
something and the pattern match it will
replace it by this plus x1. Okay. So
this is basically the how the entire
woof language works by this pattern
matching. Okay. So so uh so let me um
let me clean up a a little bit. So this
is
how to show the full form
syntax of some
expression. Okay. By using full form.
Okay. So that's a separate topic. So
this is this is defining a function
pattern matching. Okay. So and the full
form is this.
Okay. So now we can run this and we can
for example we can uh call it let's say
three. Okay. Now evaluate
it. You see it returns four. Okay. So
this is pattern
matching. This shorthand syntax is
equivalent to that. Okay. So let me just
uh where should I put
it? There. Okay. That these two is
exactly the
same. So
now so this is how you define a function
via pattern matching. Okay. So far so
good. Am I doing good? Palash says yes.
So PL congratulations you have written a
package in uh the next version of Emac
30 something about switching frames that
is
fantastic. So so that's about defining a
function. Okay. So now let's see where
we want to go next. So we explained
defining a function and we explained the
pattern matching. Oh yeah. So let's show
some more example about pattern matching
about
okay
so so in order to have a default values
optional param or name param you need to
define function via pattern match and
this is example
and and how it works is because you know
we explained by the set delayed and
pattern and so on. So but now let's get
more practical. So
now let's get practical.
Okay. Uh pra uh let's see
practical
example
of defining a function via
pattern matching. Okay. So let's give
some practical
example. Okay. Copy that. Uh so let's
say two parameters. So how do you define
two parameters X and Y uh that okay now
we don't you know let's forget about
this full form. This full form is like
understanding fully how warm language
works but once you understand it like
you don't need it like in practice you
know nobody writes that you can just you
know this is how you normally define a
function. Okay. So now let's say 3 4
evaluate three and
four. Run
it. Fantastic. Seven. Okay. Now let's um
now let's uh create a more example.
Let's say now let's say I'm getting
fancy. I want to I want this function
where the second part is a uh let's say
a vector. Okay. So the second part is a
vector
ve and uh um okay let me show you some
other uh yeah let me show you okay
so yeah like before remember we said
that this way allows you to define um
default values and optional um default
par default parameter values and
optional parameters and named
parameters.
Okay. So the named parameters we already
showed it basically you give it a
name and wait named parameters usually
uh you can means place you know you you
should be able to place it anywhere. So
that's not it. So okay so let me let me
let's show okay. So so
here let's example of default value.
Okay. So, so X and Y and let's say
YD424. Okay. That's how you do it. So,
now run
it. Fantastic. You got seven even though
Y is not given. So, but you see default
values. Okay. Now, now let's uh let's
cover the other example. What? So we
cover default values. Then we covered um
uh default value is kind of similar to
optional param. So this default values
optional param and name param they are
kind of tied together. Okay this kind of
relation because default values to a
parameter basically means that parameter
is is optional. Okay. So for example
just like like like
um like here you know this y is optional
and also it's got a default value but
then another sense of optional value is
that is that um you see right now in
this example although four is optional
so let's make x optional okay so let's
make x optional too let's say three okay
so now if you don't give
anything it returns seven. Okay. But now
if you say if you say uh let's say y is
uh let's say I want y to
be let's say I want y to be five. I want
to I want x to be optional. You cannot
do that. You see in order you know when
you do default values they are still
ordered.
So y becomes optional or both of them
are optional but you cannot have x
optional you know you
cannot want to have a value for y and
let the x be optional like this you run
this that won't work.
Okay. So what I mean so what this means
is that the meaning of default values is
not completely identical to the meaning
of optional parameters. You see when you
have ordered argument okay that's why we
are talking about this because we are
talking about the the default values and
optional param their relation you see.
So when you have a default value for for
older parameter that means only counting
from the last parameters they are
optional you know you can have two
optional parameters near the right hand
side or three or more but you cannot
have the beginning. So so then then
another concept is named param. So let's
define named param.
Okay. So let's uh clean up a little bit.
Let me clean up. So, so here's a default
example of default values and here is
example
of two default values
and how only the
ones and and
how how you cannot have the first
param as optional.
Now
this
showcase how default
values does
not is
not
completely
complete
completely equival
But lent
two optional
param. How
param with default values is not
completely equivalent to optional param.
Okay.
If we want y to be five and and use
default value for
x, this
cannot won't work. Okay, that's an
example. This is error if you run it.
Okay, so that's a relationship about
uh default values for parameter.
parameter with default value versus
optional. So let me so now let me um so
now let's show an example of name named
parameters.
Okay. So now example
of named param par parameters.
Okay. Okay. Example of named params.
So
x y and uh let's so uh
okay so so there's another issue about
named parameters the relationship of
named parameters and uh optional
parameters again so there's a
relationship of that for example in
JavaScript in Python you have or in
powers shell or in bash you have this
dash you know name then value you know
that's a parameter so those are
typically called named parameters and
usually those are orderless so when you
have named parameters they needs not to
be specific order they can be anywhere
and they can they cannot exist and by
default they will have a value but so
let me just show you okay so the The way
you define named parameters is by
uh well let me look up so I forgot at
the moment I I I I remember but let's
look up my
um wolf language tutorial. So Wuam
language in depth. So all the things I
talked about is in fact already written.
So check it out. Wuam language inepth
onali.info. info table of contents. So
basics comments string number boolean
list and expression atom head variable
conditional loop iteration function.
Okay, that's what you want. The function
section defining function define
function with optional parameters.
That's what we want. Okay, so let me
just copy um so save save us type
typing.
So okay. So yeah. So let's just do it.
So there is the example clear. Now let's
change F to uh my phone just to be
consistent with the way we were doing
it. Okay. So so clear my phone the
symbol. Then here is a um this is a
option. This is a default value. Okay.
Uh okay. So not actually not this part.
So optional positional parameters,
right? That's not what we
want. You know, this is interesting
because the full name, the more precise
name for that what we showed before is
optional positional
parameters or you can say uh a parameter
with ordered parameter with default
value. Okay, that's a full name. We
showed that before. But what we want
now, what we going to demo now is
optional named parameters. Okay. So, um,
let me just copy it. Let me do it. Okay.
So, yeah. So, here's a instruction to to
write optional named params. So, let's
just do
it. Okay. So, we want my function just
same as like before optional named
param.
uh example of optional named parameters.
Okay, my function and uh the name the
symbol is uh my function. Okay. My
function uh wait uh op yeah options uh
uh wait my function then opt one that's
the option
name opt whatever it is you know my
option uh let's say my op one okay uh
let's capital okay my opt one my opt two
and let's say default value is three
default value is four. Okay, remove that
act. Okay, so this is how
you create a optional named parameters
to a function. So the function is my
fun. Okay,
then okay then then you define a
function. Okay, just like before. So let
me do that.
So let's say yeah so let's say
um yeah so let's remove that
[Music]
entirely let's just say that and uh yeah
that okay then optional param
um then
uh yeah so then here you want to say now
you want to say a module. Okay. So what
does module do? It's like let in lisp or
in f in okamel or inascal module that
lets you create local variables. Okay.
So it takes two arguments. The first
part is
params at least. The second part is the
body. Okay. That's um okay. So the
params let's say let's leave it empty.
Okay. Now the body what what the body
will be? Okay. So that would
be okay option value uh my
op
one
plus my up two.
Okay that's how you do it. Uh actually
so we don't even need the module part.
Just like that. Okay. So now we have a
function with a optional param. My opt
one my opt two and uh and this is the
definition of the function. Okay. So now
we can call
it empty. So let's clean up uh uh wait
let's clean up make them together. Okay.
Run it. Hope hopefully it works.
Warning comma encount encountered with
no adjacent expression. Where is the
comma? Oh yeah, here. So in uam
language, you cannot have trailing
commas. Okay, so remove that. Oh, it
evaluated anyway. So seven. You see? So
let's do it
again. Seven. Oh, by the way, that's a
nice new feature. You see, it
doesn't stop. it it doesn't error out.
It creates a warning but it still runs.
So the training trailing comma is kind
of kind of a syntax design issue. You
know by now we understand like trailing
comma just ignore it. You know it's very
convenient when you when you can just
ignore the trailing comma in a list in a
array or or you know things like that.
But however when whenever you have
trailing comma if you allow that then
that means your the logical soundness of
your syntax is is not too logical
because logically you don't want the
trailing comma when you have a list of
things you
know you know like a list typically the
comma is meant to be the se you know
separator. So anyway that's
a syntax design issue. Okay. So anyway,
this is how you write um optional param.
But this looks complex. So let's let's
make it uh let's try to make
it okay. So this this kind of simpler
but it's still complex but okay. So but
the point here is
that okay let's evaluate this. Okay.
Evaluate
it seven. Okay. Now so the point of this
optional named param is that you can
have like hundreds of them you know it's
not just my opt one so this is for
example plot point you know number
uh let's say number of plot points
uh you know you can say kind of like
that you know you can have lots much
options. Color, you know, color
something like by default red. Uh number
of plot points, uh let's say 30 by
default. Uh
uh uh
launch missile, uh for
example,
true or false. Okay, so the point is
that you can have like hundreds of them.
you don't need to specify all of them
and you don't need necessarily need all
of them in the in the body part of the
computation for for your function. So
that's a that's a thing. So for example
in a typical wam language plot function
uh let's say
plot 3D let's say let's try something
fun okay uh
wait
s
x
cosine
y. Uh, it's it's actually easier for me
to type this in uh emacs. I'm using
wuam. I'm using kasar
emacs. Kasawa wam mod emacs. Okay. So,
wait, do I Yeah, here. So you can
download it. So it allows you to code
wam language in Emacs. Uh it's on
GitHub. Okay. Wu mod. So it allows me to
type faster. So for example here we want
x. So 0 to uh 2 pi. Okay. 2 pi. And we
want y to be 0 to 2 pi. Okay. So plot.
So this plot function right now is
taking one
arguments, two arguments and three
arguments. Okay. Now run
it. Shift enter. Fantastic. Okay. So
what is this?
Uh why is it look like that? That's not
right. Oh yeah, this new uh yeah so we
forgot this needs to be one single
function. Okay. So x times let's say
plus okay so this is not a list of
functions this is one should be one
single
function okay fantastic now let's say uh
let's say 2 3
pi shift enter
fantastic and now there's a lot options
for plot for for example you type
options
S plot 3D shift enter. So you see you
got whole bunch of options. So that is
the
power and
utility of of named optional parameters.
Okay, because you have thousands of
them. You know, you don't want to like
like type all of them whenever you call
a function.
Okay. So that is this is how you define
a named option.
Okay. So now I think that's it for
today. Um am I doing good? Is this
useful? Okay. Nobody's here. Um I think
that's it. So why don't we show
something fun? Um for example, let's do
a animation of it.
Animation is most fun part of weren
language. Okay.
Um yeah. Okay. Let's do it here because
it's much
easier. Let's say
uh let's say B. Okay. So add a B here.
That's a parameter. Let's say T. Okay.
TT. So now
tt tt goes from uh let's say t uh let's
say let's
say let's just say t okay so t goes
from zero
to one
okay so we going to create an
animation fantastic now let's play
it. Okay. So, this this is not fun.
Um, so let's let me think which how do
you make it fun?
Uh, okay. So let's just
say sin x * y + t. Okay. And t goes from
1 to uh three. Okay. One, two,
pi. Okay. Fantastic. Now this is more
evil
looking. Okay. Now it's not smooth. No,
I want it smooth. Okay.
So, now I don't know how what is the
option to make. Okay. So, let's Yeah.
Okay. Let's do that. So, copy
that. So, we got this and we want to
make it smooth. So, let's instead of
using manipulate, let's first of all
create a table of it. Okay.
So, so
table okay table of this expression then
then the t goes from
uh t from zero to 2 pi and now so so
okay so let's
um so
now so now but um but you want to add
option Okay. So let's make it clear
here. So you see plot plot but now let's
add a optional parameter to plot. Okay.
So we want to say plot
range. Okay. Plot range. Uh so x goes
from
uh where does it uh goes from 0 to 2 pi.
Okay. Uh goes from zero to
2 pi. Okay.
Same for y and and z goes from zero
to 1.5
uh uh
from negative 1.1 to 1.1. Okay. So this
will create a bunch of graphics. Let's
show it. Hopefully it's correct.
Double
check. Do it. Do
it.
Fantastic. Wait, only four of them.
Yeah. Okay. So, you want go from 0 to 2
pi in increment
of pi divided by let's say
20. Okay. So, you got lots of graphic.
Now, this is not exactly I'm It's good.
It's good. Okay. So, now you got a bunch
of
graphics. Copy it. Paste it
here. Uh, okay. So, let's
just So, let's assign it my graphics
equals to that. Okay. Now, you assigned
it. Now, you just say animate.
animate. Okay, I believe that's it. So,
let's try
it. So, we're going to create an
animation.
Uh my gra animate.
Uh wait, you got a new here. Oh, yeah.
That's that comma. This trailing comma
is a annoying
thing. Okay, let's try again.
Yeah. Okay. Oh, it works. Wait, where's
the animation? Okay. Animate is
incorrect. So, you need to find out what
is the uh syntax for
animate. There it
is. Show JavaScript and uh enlarge the
window. Okay. So animate you need you
need a iterator. Okay. So but we already
have a list of um this animate. That's
what we want. We already have a list. So
we don't need
um Okay. So now let's do it. Now let's
add a semicolon there. So it suppress
suppress the list of graphics. Paste.
Run it.
Fantastic. Now, this is beautiful. Yeah,
this is kind of what I'm looking for.
But now, let's
loop. So, what you know, so we need to
make it more dramatic is by uh 2 pi 220.
Okay.
And uh and
uh okay. So it needs to move
faster. Okay, that's good. Thank you
guys for watching. I think that's it for
today.
[Music]
Uh in fact I mean this is
not this is not that great an animation
you know this this animation is been
done
uh let's change your perspective. Uh
actually stop. You know this animations
has been done like in the
1990s. So
um so we can add a perspective. So that
would be another option.
Um so let's see what what is
the option
for for like the
viewpoint so that we can view this thing
from from this angle. So that would make
make it more interesting. So let's see
view matrix view angle automatic
uh view projection viewpoint. Okay. So
we can use this
viewpoint. Okay. So there's a plot
range comma then
viewpoint viewpoint. Now this is
1.3 then
negative then two. So let's make it
flat and uh let's make it two for now.
Let's see what happens. Okay. You need
you need like
experiment shift enter. Okay. So you
need rotate it a little bit.
So rotate. So that means you need some
kind of this angle. So that means let's
say x = to 2 y = to 2. Okay. Let's see
what we get.
Yeah.
No. Okay. So now we get So uh x needs to
be uh let's say
-2. Oh yeah, y -2. Okay. So
actually I think that will get
us shift
enter. Okay. That's kind of what I like.
Now, now let's say animation uh 20
frames. Let's say 30 frames
uh from 2 pi 2 pi uh from 2 pi to 2 pi
divided by 30 that means like 30 frames
or 31 frames and
uh and
uh and uh the formula is xy + t. So t
kind of just shift
the yeah it it t kind of
shifts the frequency. So t is for
frequency. You learn that in
u in basic analytic geometry. Okay. So
but so let's now run the animation
again.
Okay. So, it's it's a bit better, but
not not exactly, you know. I don't like
the color. You know, this
color. Anyway, that's it for
today. Bye, guys. So if you like my
stuff, go to my
website.info, okay? So you can, you
know, check out my wui mod. It's free
and check out my entire wam language in
depth. And uh
so in fact all we talked about today is
all here. And if you want to know about
the graphics and animation, it's in this
section. So go to kasali.info info and
all the way bottom you can pay me,
Patreon me, PayPal and Amazon gift card
me. Okay. Send me a $100 or something.
Bye
guys. So yeah, so that's one hour. Yeah.
Or you can buy my entire website. Pay me
$300. I send you a zip file of my
entire.info website. uh and there are
about about 4,000 articles or 6 thou
thou thousand articles on programming
languages on mathematics
um you
know okay that's it bye
guys so that's what we talked about
today about defining a function in wolf
language and uh we talked
[Music]
about we we we showed how the mechanism
of defining a function in woofer
language using pattern matching and how
does it work because we showed how it is
a
global syntactical transformation system
we defined using
um where is it we defined using set
delayed okay We explain that. Then we
explain we explain the differences and
relations of default parameters with
default values and optional parameters
and uh named parameters. The
relationship between optional parameters
and named parameters. And how do you do
that in weren language?
Fantastic.