good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of South Park show so we are
going to code emac beasts today and it's
probably going to be boring uh because
it's all pure emac this technical okay
and it's a bit complex the problem uh
and if you have not already just search
for xari emac emacs this tutorial you
will find several of my uh emac
tutorials
uh live stream uh that that is for
beginners okay and today is just me
coding email please
probably try for you so this is my
keyboard exposed uh exposed keyboard and
you can you can find my review just
search for Sally
expose keyboard or sorry keyboard review
okay so let's begin uh coding so video
check audio check okay so let's change
the color here
to yeah the expose okay
that's what I'm using exposed keyboard
okay so let's begin uh coding emac Beast
uh and I'm using soft light keys
I'm using borac keyboard layout and I
view and on the on the Ping window you
can see all my command cores and
keystrokes on the pink window so as I as
I delete something or insert the
character you know you'll see all the
commands and the keystrokes I press on
the pink window
okay so video check audio checklist
let's begin so let's let me tell you
what are we going to do today so
so the other day two week two videos ago
or one videos ago we did write this
function because I HTML change local
Link in stream
okay so that's uh
2022 November 25th live stream so we
wrote this command
and today we are going to call that
command we are going to do something
similar so this command is the code the
the the core functionality the engine to
do something and today we are going to
write
uh two wrappers if we have time we're
gonna write some emacs command that uses
what we did last time so let me show you
what we did last time
so
um yeah so yeah so this is important so
let me show you okay so so here is the
command let's open the new uh window let
me show you okay
so a new windows yeah so let's put it
here so we so this is a command and
let's go to HTML mod actually describe
function and type the command name there
it is here is a command and
documentation let's jump to the source
code HTML mod so this is what we wrote
the other day
okay let me let me do a quick demo of
what that does Okay so
let's start a emac this code block emac
emac visp
okay paste the code here and pop it out
in into a buffer uh and uh yeah let me
show you what the does this command do
so let's go to programming blog so what
that command do is that you see this is
my programming blog showing browser you
can see there are several links intro to
Wolfram language Mathematica for example
go back this and Wolfram language go
back so there are several links now I
write a lot HTML so oftentimes I need to
copy this block of text which is these
links I need to move it somewhere else
let's say let's go to kasari.info for
example
info index file okay showing browser so
this is my home page study.info so if I
let's say I post it to the top
I mean I paste it to the top so
uh
you know siphon my knowledge into your
brain assimilate my sensibilities to
your spine so I pasted above that in
showing browser you can see you know I
pasted those you know links here this
block of list of links and now I click
on them they no longer works you see
because the relative URL is all
incorrect because you are changing
structure so let me get elaborate let me
show you some screenshots some some the
you know this is the tablet fantastic
okay so let me show you
uh
you know so what I'm gonna say is that
you have a directory
duh you know directory have lots of
structures you know
for example now if this is a page you
know each one of these is a directory
directory is a tree structure so if you
have a page here then you copied some
text
you know and you want to move it to here
or if you wanted to move it to here or
if you want to move it to anywhere
that's a different level
then all your local links will no longer
work you know they will only work if you
if you uh kind of copy them to to the
same
level of directory you know the depth of
directory so
it's because I write HTML so often I
need to copy paste you know part of the
link to different pages so right so
that's why we wrote a command yesterday
and this command is let me show you so
open that again now select the whole
this is HTML mod so you can see again
you can see the command code I'm calling
HTML select element
cancer for example that allows me to for
example select the link press the key
again select the outer appearance the
Ally list press it again select the U UL
list okay now delete it show in browser
so you see we removed it we uh undone it
okay good now let's go back to the
programming blog
so Lim so so let me demonstrate what the
command we wrote yesterday does okay
copy it close it
so you can see the documentation all
important it takes three arguments text
block current directory and Target
directory so we are going to call this
command first of all we have a text
block which is that one and in emac this
or
double quotes straight double quote
needs to be escaped so Let's Escape them
you need a backslash in front of it so
call command Escape quotes that command
is uh is on on my emacs tutorial just
search for name for the name you will
see it okay
so for example we just called XA oh it's
not there it's the command won't show if
you do meta X so anyway Escape quotes
Okay so so the first
um let's describe function again show
the documentation of this command we
wrote the other day so the first
argument is text block then you need a
calendar and Target okay so the so we
need two more arguments here now the
current the the directory where this
block came from is my programming block
copy the file path close it
put it here okay now let's say I want to
move it to um
let's just say
okay so copy that paste it let's say I
want to move to some file One Directory
above okay so this needs to be a
directory so that that so this function
three arguments okay let's call it
Ctrl U then call Eva last six
symbolic expression that that's what
scxp means symbolic expression
okay so here's that that will return
the result of this function of these um
you know you see we called Eva last sex
and because we press Ctrl U first so it
will insert the result here
so now you can see
you see now if you compare the links
um you see there's two dots there but
here the two dots is gone so here is now
this is the correct
you know the text blocked
text block with the correct uh local
links fixed so so this is why now let's
delete that this is why this command is
useful
but however right now it doesn't do
nothing because we have to go to you
know emac this code function and it you
know let's do it again and it Returns
the result then you
then you have to copy the results
you know you have to copy it it still
doesn't work you have to remove the
quote then you have to unescape those uh
Escape then you can paste to the
destination so that's that's not good so
we are going to write a wrapper command
that lets us let us just
let's say this command will be called
uh
this command will be called
HTML paste with paste and fix local
links
okay and and that's what we are going to
write and
and it's going to be it's going to call
this command we did yesterday okay so
this continuation okay that's the
function we want so delete this text
block let's say Define let's start to
write the command
okay Define here's a command name
documentation or important version
today's date uh
okay so this command uh what does it do
so HTML paste in fixed local links okay
so basically you copy some text block
can be arbitrarily long and then you go
to some page some file you open some
file then you can paste it then all the
local links will be correct
okay so that's what this command do so
it's documentation documented okay
paste a html text block
uh wait this won't work such that such
that local
links
[Music]
uh relative paths are fixed okay now
this this will be commit a command so
you can press meta X to call it but
however this won't work because
when you
for this command to work this change
local links in stream for it to work it
needs the original original directory
and
where this text block came from and it
also needs a destination directory
so that means if you are writing this
command
you need to somehow tell it where is the
original directory your clipboard text
came from
okay the destination directory it knows
because it's just a current file
but there's no original uh directory so
how what you're gonna do hello guys so
any comments and questions posted there
okay Jr hi and hello Sam
says could you explain the concept and
the Dynamics of inserting and cleaning
clearing a buffer
I'm assuming it is a memory data
structure if I'm on the right track
okay uh what do you mean inserting
inserting for example I can copy this
take text and just insert it here so
let's insert that's emacs you know just
or you can for example I can copy that
and paste it here
so I can open
um
open a new buffer paste it here so let's
paste that I mean that's insert so
that's insert text you can you know in
emac Beast or you can say you can call
the command insert and it takes one or
more strings let's say something okay so
this is a emac this command to insert
some text so if I evaluate it it will
insert wherever my current Cruiser is at
so if I just evaluate it if you look at
the pink window you can see the command
I'm going to call right now okay do it
you see it inserts something so that's
insert so what do you mean uh okay
explain is my answer satisfactory or if
you what is your question I don't
understand and clearing a buffer what do
you mean cleaning up over you know
delete so I'm pressing a key
for example press a key
and you can see the command I just
called is start delete current text
block or you can just call
um
you know key or word there it is keyword
to delete and also backward keyword you
can see again Q forward or I can move
closer and kill backward you know that's
so close this buffer don't save expand
above it so we are back here so that's
deleting text what do you mean by clear
the buffer
okay
okay so Sam says okay but what I am
seeing you do I would consider on the
level meta programming no this is not
meta programming I was talking in the
high level context in CPP and Java
context
uh I'm not sure what you mean so so
you know C plus plus in Java they are
general purpose programming languages
where emac is
is a programming language that's
kind of specialized for the Emax text
editor
so you have you have the insert concept
you know you can delete text you can
insert text
into a buffer you know into a file or a
buffer or whatever or you know in emacs
basically basically you are working in a
context of text editor
so you have a lot of functions that
inserts tech text DD text in this thing
we call Buffer you know for example
delete the whole block of text undo and
you can you also have the concept of
undo because we the context is a text
editor that's what emacs is and emac
this you know the code we are doing the
language emac this is designed to work
with the Emax environment text editor so
you have a lot of functions that does
text editing
now in in C plus plus in Java those are
not those are general purpose languages
those are not
you know text editors so you cannot
you know you can insert the string but
you don't really
where you're gonna insert you know
either you print the screen or something
so uh perhaps that answers your question
I want to understand the buffer Dynamics
in the case of runtime execution okay I
don't really know what you mean okay I
hope you are not trolling okay I don't
know you I don't know what you mean
have you used emacs before so if you
have not you should
um because otherwise the whole thing
doesn't make sense to you
or if you have used Vim maybe you'll
understand
um but I'm not sure veeam has a dynamic
programming language I mean it has a it
has its own
language called Vin script that allows
you to customize Vim but I'm not sure
it's Dynamic like we are doing here like
the emac lisp
okay sounds good so naturally and great
yeah so if you are new to email I mean
at least you need to have some
experience with emacs
uh then you
you know then then you need to get into
emacs this programming so emac this
programming like what we are doing today
right now is called text processing text
processing that means you manipulate
text in files you know you move files
from one place to another place things
like that text processing programming
this task is one field one category of
programming text processing in fact it's
fairly important you know for example if
you want to analyze your log you know
your web log or or sort of blog Windows
log you know you you need to find when
did something happen that's text
processing and for example you know
you want for example I have tons of
files for example right now all these
are 10 files let's delete them
okay
um
you know
so for example you have you know a
directory with thousands of files you
want to extract all emails in it
that's text processing
you want to find all links to Wikipedia
that's text processing you know you want
to generate a report containing all
links or
for example here is the HTML page you
know my programming blog so suppose I
want to extract all links
in this page you know there's
thousands hundreds of thousands of links
so for example I can do select the text
block
and watch the pink window you'll see the
command when I call it okay so I do it
you see there it is so you see all the
URL are extracted at the bottom you see
and that command
is called PSI HTML extract URL and we
can look at the source code cancel so
so here here it is HTML extract URL and
here is a source code let's open it so
here is the code here
so this what so this is emacs command
written in emac lisp and what does it do
it just given a piece of text it just
extract
or URL seeing it
so that's again this is text processing
that's what we are doing that's a lot of
that's huge part of emac this
coding is about
you know extracting you know
manipulation manipulating text text
processing okay now let's go back to our
problem
so we are going to yeah so we are
writing we are working on this command
but now the problem is we need the
original directory
okay so let's get on
drinking coffee
[Music]
wait this is a tea or coffee tea I think
wait is it
uh
so anyway let's get on
uh coffee it's not that's not tea That's
coffee I think
um yeah so let's get on so
so right now I need a command to paste a
text block with all the local links
fixed so in order to do that the
commands needs to know
the commands needs to know where the
text block came from that is the
directory it came from okay because
otherwise it cannot fix related links
so the command needs to know
where the text came from so how do you
do how do you um
I mean this is some kind of a interface
issue
because when you copy a piece of text
you know
you know it's copied so I can paste it I
can you know I can paste it again I copy
paste paste paste you know when you copy
something
there's no information about the
directory where it came from
and you cannot you know simply add it to
part of the copy
uh mechanism because clipboard is not
supposed to
contain meta info I mean you can I mean
then then you have to look into
Microsoft Windows clipboard
uh data structure or emacs you know
that's get that gets complex
or depending on if you are on the Mac or
on Linux each one has a different data
structure for clipboard you want to find
out you know how do you embed meta
information and the extract it that's
too complex so we don't want to do that
so
so what you can do is to
um let me think about this okay let me
think about this for a while
um
so
so you basically you know we have to
think in terms of what
you want you know what I want
uh so what I want is just you know
working on my HTML source code I want to
move some
block of text from one file to another
so we want to think of a convenient way
to you know what is the desired result
what what is it we want the in the most
easy way you know the desired
result
we think about that first
then
we try to implement that you know we try
to get it to work
as opposed to think in terms of what
the mechanism you know what the emac
this language can do you know
because this way when you think about
the user first then you have a good
program you want to be the user the what
you want to do is the most important
thing
uh this is a digression but it's very
important when you design functions or
commands because otherwise you would end
up like Linux where you have lots of
commands but each one is like
they are they are if they are very easy
with respect to the operating system or
to the with respect to the CPU you know
extremely simple but to the with respect
to the user you you have to do this
first then call that command then that
command returns something takes
different arguments therefore you need
to find out the argument first the type
then you do this that that that that's C
and C plus first okay those are crap
and also lots of the unix commands are
like that you know ALS for example mu MV
M is for moving or file and also for
rename they are the same you know they
are the single command but doing two
different things well because
technically they are somewhat the same
so that's a problem you don't want that
you want to think you know when you
design
when you start to write a command not
not even about implementation you know
when you run start to write a functional
command in whatever task you do you want
to think think of in terms of what the
user wants out of it
that's you you begin that's that's how
you begin to design the command okay
that's important
uh so now
you know so now I'm gonna read the
comments in a bit okay so now this
command
you know you usually just want to paste
it
so how do you
um
you see a user really just want to paste
a text
so what you can do is that you can you
can have this command and simply paste
then it will prompt user
oh yeah so one of the ways prompt user
has the user where that that piece of
text came from you know where does this
uh
piece of text came from you know you
prompt user in the user types directory
that is no good because that's because
oftentimes you don't remember you know
you don't want to require a user to
remember where this where he copied the
text from
okay so actually I already know a
solution but you know let me
talk about the the solution okay so
instead of the command paste in fixed
local links you write a command let's
say
move
text
move text
here let's just say that okay
we write the command move text here so
how does that work let me show you
so let's go back to programming blog
okay so you are looking at my
programming blog and let's say I want to
move this block of text to another file
so what I do is I split the buffer
spread the buffer go to the other file I
want for example index okay so showing
browser that's study.info home page
so what that so right now I can do is
that I want to you see I want to move
this block of text
to here
so now I can I can just call the command
that saw move
and it will automatically
move this you know the current text
block to wherever my cruiser position is
now how would emacs know where it came
from well simple because in a window you
just have two split pins so it just so
this command will be designed for moving
from one pin to the other
okay let's follow let's just do that
okay
um
there are other ways let's but there are
other ways you know so but let's just do
this uh this one okay
okay let's just do that
uh you know so we have something to work
on uh instead of instead of stuck on the
design issue okay
so let's rename this
command
uh
HTML move to other pane
okay so that's what we are going to
write
move a
move the documentation move the current
text block of HTML from
the current pen to
the other pane okay
and
to the other pins close the position
okay
now if there
is a text selection use that
else use current
text block text block is defined by a
piece of text separated by empty lines
so for example that's one text block
that's one text block okay now if we
remove the empty lines then this is one
text block okay so either you make a
selection
if you don't make the selection by
default you'll just be the current text
block okay that's what I
uh yeah okay so so move the current text
block
whole selection
okay
so that's the command we're gonna write
okay so let's begin coding that now
remove the other one
let me go back up
hello George so what's up George George
start to use go back to emacs go back to
soft light keys and start coding start
to learn emac this George is a great
programmer okay
so over there
Macy says sir you get criticized for
writing imperative styled immaculous
instead of idiomatic a lot of your code
could be condensed tenfold using
idiomatic emac beasts that's that's
that statement is so false so forth out
of the shape of the out of shape
you know
you know I've you know I've been coding
emac this I mean okay should I should I
like do a focus on technical emac basic
coding or should I start to talk random
let me
address that question okay uh
uh order obadia Macy I can tell you
don't you don't call dmac bisp you know
because usually most of the creative
systems are from people who don't really
I mean I I can tell
let me make a guess you never you have
not code you you don't have a let's say
half a year experience of coding e-max
this do you
like I'm you know I'm guessing I might
be wrong maybe you have 10 years you
know uh experience coding emac this if
you do say something you know say so
your experience so most of the Critter
season
not just to me actually most of the
things you see online 90 of it is just
crap you know they never coded you know
Haskell you know people have opinions
about this about Haskell about you know
lots of things but they they actually
never coded you know they they don't
know most of it you know 90 of the
comments are it's all like that
now specifically for me I've been coding
emac Beasts for 15 years you know
starting in 2006. you know so you'll see
a lot you know and
and so I've been coding emac Beast at
least one hour a day every day
statistically speaking or other you know
usually you know I call several hours a
day but
so for 15 years I've been coding images
that's one thing that's one fact okay
because you can check you can go
um yeah let me ramble about this okay
because maybe that's more interesting oh
Jesus I have 12
viewers okay now of you of those people
watching if you like me to go back on
focusing on emac this coding
say it okay I'll do it otherwise I'm
going to on a tangent about the
criticisms about
about my email list code okay so I've
been coding that's a one fact first of
all one fact I've been coding emac bisp
for 15 years and my emac this tutorial
is the most
practical and the most voluminous you
know most complete emac this detailed
tutorial on the web you you will find
nothing comparable nothing zero okay
my emac this tutorial has like a
thousand pages okay in my emacs and emac
this combined let me go to it
okay so you can see my emacs blog so you
drop into the directory so here's the
directory so you can see go down all the
way so there are 800 Pages now actually
that's not all 800 in this directory
then there is the miscellaneous uh SS
okay 200 150 so I have close to
900 articles on emacs and emac beasts
okay I mean I also have emacs complete
emacs manual here okay so those are
complete emacs manual with the HTML
predified okay so anyway
my original content there are
about a thousand okay 1000 emacs
and emac this articles
okay and uh and uh you know
and for emac beasts I have a few hundred
you see all these files
for those are emac this tutorials
for example EDS file functions let's
open that one oh that one page moved
that's split to you know this page is
about
emac this uh file functions so let me
just show you some example of my emac
this tutorial so you can see it split
into how to read the file
and also the part on how to write a file
so the point here is I have a lot of
emac beasts I mean complete tutorial on
this but the language Basics on
practical e-macb in terms of emac this
examples these are independent you know
actual learnable code you can just copy
and paste it and you can use it right
away and then you have how to write the
emac this major mod
and with you know lots of my live stream
since three years ago okay
so I've been coding first of all I've
been coding emac this for more than 15
years
two I have the emac this tutorial online
you know uh that's you will not that's
the most comprehensive
online on the internet you will find no
no way across not even emac this books
printed books okay you go to Amazon you
can find a few a handful
I believe there are two emac this
you know not just emacs you know there's
a difference between emacs tutorial
emacs books versus the emac Beast the
language Books Okay for the and and
either case in either case there's not
many you'll find you know
emacs tutorial you'll find a couple of a
couple of books that's 20 years old okay
this is none okay not counting the guru
emacs manual okay new Emax manual and
gnu emac Beast manual those are you know
those are the official ones each one is
about 1 000 Pages we are not counting
that obviously because that's the new
official image this manual and the iMac
this manual those are they are difficult
to read
so anyway then you know if you look for
emac this emacs books they are like a
couple two or three that's
20 years old written in the 1990s one is
by ESR Eric's Raymond okay
anyway and on emac this
none I mean okay there are maybe two
that
um
new ones I'm aware of in the in the past
five years okay and you have to pay to
buy them okay so my point here is that
my emac this tutorial is the most
comprehensive and uh
in the most popular you know you just
search for you know you'll find it the
most popular and comprehensive emac this
tutorial
on Earth okay on Earth not just on the
internet on Earth okay
so I I coded emac this for 15 years and
I have the most
comprehensive and popular emac this
tutorial online
so I'm I'm fairly popular when it comes
to emac bisp not many people
do emac beasts anyway okay so
but
but then
you do you will find people criticize me
you know there's a lot of nasty bad
mouthing about me do you know why I can
tell you why because I am a
controversial person because I don't
care about the typical white
white people okay they are mannerism
their view of things okay I attack
whoever I find that's
not good okay I opinions I mean I put
out my opinion straightforward I attack
or in in a nice white man's term I
criticize
the emacs community severely okay
Richard Richard storman is a [ __ ]
you know what his behavior he's being a
[ __ ] he's been the most
a responsible element that caused the
stagnation of emacs that that stopped
the progress of emacs and emac this
the most powerful force in the past 10
years Richard stallman okay the the guy
who created emacs
so that's just an example you know and I
have you can find all this in my in my
blog okay that you know those 9000 Pages
let me show you okay so emacs modern
modernization
each one of these is criticism of emacs
problems and emacs Community you know
emacs html.mod sucks it sucks not just
sucks it sucks donkey ass you just it's
a it's a it's a quiet you know like when
you talk to emac these people emacs
community usually you're here oh emacs
is the best thing emacs is the best
thing in this that that
okay one example emacs HTML mod is sucks
donkey ass
well this is written in 2008 okay today
it's it's much more improved today you
have HTML
um
kind of called HTML plus you know a lot
history
so anyway so my point is so
why do people why do you see people
online criticize me because
I attack I criticize lots of the emacs
community
I don't care who they are you know I
criticize now whether my criticism is
correct or not it's up to you to judge
but what happens most of the time is as
long as you start to criticize people
you know these these [ __ ] white
people okay let me just be straight
about it they started to oh distance
themselves from you because what you do
is not is not like conformant to their
way of thinking you know they say oh we
are multiculturalism we are here to help
the world in fact they do a lot of
damage okay they they don't they only
care about promoting themselves
okay a lot of the emacs community
people you know it's it's normal it's
like code you know it's a coat the Emax
code and you can see the same thing in
Python code you know in this code in
Haskell code code okay you you you you
know it you know it it have it's there
it's right there in in today in Rust
Community the rust language code you
know each one if you are there you know
they just promote they think their thing
is the best thing
okay but lots of lots of it is is just
wrong it's not true
okay so the reason you see a lot of
people Critters attack me you know they
they bad mouth without most of it is
actually without solid uh
content you know when you criticize
you're gonna have content you know so
people can judge you know you say this
is this this this this one two three
people can and you have to give your
reasons that's what criticism means okay
criticism doesn't doesn't mean just
speech Just speech it around oh this
sucks that sucks okay most of the
Malaysia and Zuma do that online on
Reddit on Hacker News you know oh this
sucks oh that sucks you know you have to
give reason
you know so people can verify check you
know whether it's correct how do you
verify first of all you have to be
qualified you know so if you want to
criticize emac this or my emac this code
you you cannot be first of all qualified
for it you know you have to have some at
least some emac basic coding experience
okay but most of the criticism attacking
me just not there's no content
Okay so
so I've been coding images for 15 years
my emac this tutorial is you know it's
uh
it's the best it's the best on Earth
okay
but why are there but but but then
another fact is that there are a lot of
people criticizing me
and what's my response why why why
you know if you are so good if you are
so helpful why is you know so many
people criticize you well my answer is
because
I attack and I not just you know I just
I don't I'm not you know I in some way I
don't just criticize I attack them
meaning that I
do not
conform to the normal you know polite uh
way of doing things okay I just call
them [ __ ] you know this idiot okay
this idiot that idiot okay that's what I
that's you know so in in some way you
can say I'm I'm not doing the right
thing I'm not you know I'm I'm
uh I'm not being uh
kojo I'm not being uh you know my
mannerism you you could say that's a
problem but still my criticism I would
say
most of the time is correct anyway that
is the reason that's that's my response
that's why you see a lot of people
criticize my things okay and many things
they criticize is just wrong they don't
know things you know they they are just
the part of the emac emacs code or emac
this code whatever language python code
you know like you can see this sometimes
like
you know when you have different
communities you know when when one
Community says this thing is the best
the other community says that thing is
the best but these two best things they
are not compatible you know you can see
that yourself
so that is my response to the criticisms
as to the specific criticism you know
it's just very uh silly like
might like for example
uh it says you know my emac this is
imperative style emac this but that's
that's the most silly to me because the
reason the reason I like emac is is
precisely because functional programming
and I despise imperatives
style okay mini meaning procedural Style
and I despise procedural languages
C plus plus C Java you know this and
python 2 this NOP this you know if you
watched many if you watched any of my
video you'll see or I attack them so
much
but then but then you you know I got the
criticism oh my emac this is imperative
stuff what the [ __ ] what the [ __ ] show
me your example show me where on my page
where I actually have one imperative
style emac this that should that could
be done the other way that's better show
me one
okay so so this idiotic opinions I don't
know where did you read that
and I monitor you know I am aware of
what people say you know let me show you
since we are talking about this
uh Sardi just search for
this there are some people there are
scums okay for example I know this one
happened recently
on Reddit okay that's this one guy bad
mouthing me
uh
so where did Sally lisp you'll find it
there it is this one okay
r slash lisp one of the Reddit you know
this community common is basically these
are common these phonetics you know the
title is responses to this post famous
programmers on how common this sucks
okay let me show you that one there you
have there's one scan he goes by the
name
this m that's his handle okay that's his
online handle l-i-s-p-m that guy is a
scumbag okay his name
his name he's this this guy I know for
15 years okay since 2003 also that that
guy let me show you where
okay so so here is the article okay here
is uh let me explain okay
so first of all turn on JavaScript
okay we are digressing and we are not
going to uh looks like we are not going
to
um continue the Deep coding anymore
um
because you know go to code is and we
got I got a you know
anyway let's let's let's talk about the
emac basic criticism this online
culture crap you know let me say again a
good advice you know 90 of the time
whatever you read online is just totally
crap by idiots literally okay people
don't know what they are talking about
if you are really serious follow read
books okay read books or there are some
qualified people for example if you
wanna know emac bisp okay
I am one of the source okay you could
you can learn from me but you can also
learn from others so if you think oh
some maybe it's too controversial you
know you think I'm doing imperative
coding [ __ ] okay that's good good
opinion okay you there are a lot of
others but who to follow follow those
who have actually coded emac this for 10
years for example a lot of the emacs dev
you know you go to the new emacs just
search for the new emacs mailing list
you know they each one of them coded
emac this for
you know 20 years 30 years some of them
you know and a lot new ones also very
good you know so you can so those people
you follow those people
so I can challenge with uh one question
did you ever find one of them who who
which one of them those people who
actually have the images experience did
you find one then you know those people
qualified emac this coders actually emac
this expert actually have a problem with
my code
they are there are some of them show me
show me the message
then I I will then I will argue why I
think I'm correct okay but first of all
show me one of such message you know so
anyway back to so I so let me give you
guys the advice okay 90 of the time if
you are a programmer you read you know
online stuff those are just crap okay
those are [ __ ] opinions you know those
are opinions from idiots they don't have
expertise they don't know what they are
doing they don't know they just you know
drama you know drama you know drama is a
drama is the thing that get things the
most popular drama okay
so instead you want to follow
for example if you want to learn emac
lisp or if you want to have if you want
to see opinions about what style is good
in emac this things like that you want
to follow people who are qualified
and
that means at the minimum that person
must be
must be encoding images for a year at
least you know at least
you know or you can judge by you know
you know you can judge by their
experience by what they have written you
know the packages they have actually
written okay you want to follow those
okay
now now what I I've said this very basic
you know every anyone have a brain knows
but instead we often have the online
crowd You Know Drama
it just spread things fake things okay
fake news so let me let me go back to
this post okay so this post
what's going on is that
um you know Reddit being so bad now they
if you don't have cookies they they hide
everything it's hard to uh show stuff
okay so anyway what happened here this
is a month ago
so someone posted an article I wrote
okay so this is the article famous
programmers on how common this sucks
okay this is the article I kind of
edited and collected from this Source
from this guy okay
he's a big creators criticizer of
communities and I you know this is 15
years ago you know this this blog
happened in 2012 okay 10 years ago
so I wrote this anyway let me get let me
get to the uh let me be sure okay so I
wrote this article this is uh this
article is a collection of of
the top emac this of the top least
common disk experts
their criticism on this common disk okay
including guy still guy still is
essentially the founder of lisp okay you
know guy steal if you name the top one
greatest you know top five guys there
guys steel is one of them okay guys
still famous for skim this and other and
other lots of Earth okay so many of
these people criticized comment this
there we have Richard Stoneman
you know there we have Rodney Brooks
Richard Gabriel Richard Gabe Gabriel is
a guy who
who participated in commonly standard
okay I think
but he is also he's the founder of lucid
Emax which is today XD Max today you
don't even know because XC Max also died
but he's a lot of history okay he's also
he's he's known for
worse worse is better okay the
the concept was is better which spread
by jwz the most drama dramatic guy Jade
Jamie zorinski you probably heard of
famous for Netscape you know the hacker
that's originally the worst is better is
from Richard P Gabriel's article okay
uh and but it's it became popular
because jwz Spread spread and alcohol
so Richard Gabriel then you also Paul
Graham you know program him you know
famous for selling
he's uh he you know he called it coming
this he wrote A online store one of the
first one or the first one so they to
Yahoo for some millions of dollars and
he started Hacker News you know program
Daniel weinrab this one is one of the
first emacs user is one of the first who
wrote
emacs in this okay not Richard sloman
Daniel weinrab is the first who wrote
a Emax that with the this language in it
okay so anyway these people I think
chaos can I don't know much about him uh
you know these are famous people
you know that these people are the top
let's say the top 10 Experts of common
disk okay and they
criticized common lisp they say commonly
sucks okay so I collected I also despise
comedies I think commonly sucks and part
of the reason is the common these people
the phonetics the [ __ ] they spread
false things okay
but common leads to the language on
technical aspect I think it sucks I will
never use comedies okay so I collect
this article because to support you know
I like it because I think commonly sucks
in this famous top communist experts
share my opinion or I you know I agree
with them okay so I collected this
now of course to the common these fans
they get annoyed they get very annoyed
because this you know this kasari Saudi
put you know because of this uh you know
I put together this uh article of course
common these people will will not like
it therefore
this is old you know by the way this is
2012.
therefore you know the Zuma generation
uh let me show you the so this rumor
generation this read it okay so they
they found because because I started to
do YouTube so they started to
noticed my articles you know
part of the marketing thing you know
so they
um let's show it okay let's show it in
Brave browser because in Bray browser I
have cookie song
oh God stuck what's going on am I still
going
okay there it is okay
so this threaded article so this guy who
saw you know who who shared the post to
Reddit this community lisp room
uh basically you know this this comes
you know
the common these people which I despise
the coming this community they you know
they want to think common this is the
this okay they you know they you know
you know back then there's a war between
common dis and skim this but the comment
these [ __ ] they want to think of
the list as the the common this is the
this okay the other this on uh oh they
are you know something else that common
these [ __ ] I despise the
communities community and the language
mostly because of these people this
online you know basically they don't
represent all common these programmers
they are just like the loud Bunch okay
so anyway
some guy was his name so some guy
uh let's see do we have a um can we show
you know this these days the Reddit
becomes so corrupted they you know they
don't show the names and stuff okay so
this guy
Frederick Raymond I suppose he's a young
guy you know Marlene James or something
he discovered My article so he shared
here and asking people response to this
post you know famous programmers on how
common this sucks you know he wants to
know of course you know if you are a fan
then you saw a diamond article about
your favorite language then you want to
know hey what's going on so he he posted
share to the red and then you know ask
people's opinion
okay so you can see this is this is how
you can see some of the funny things you
know the brainless you know the
brainless code phenomenon
so most of them you know after you read
them most of them will will tell you
their answer is that oh yeah well you
know first of all Saudi is a troll okay
don't pay attention to kasari that's
half of them you know
a minority of them will say that okay
uh and even the guy is aware of it you
know he he's aware of it he says you
know where's his um
anyway so
the other half will say oh yeah those
criticisms are old that's what we they
say they will say oh those criticism
yeah those are made by uh you know
famous common dispers you know the
fathers those are the fathers of common
lisp okay get that get that they will
just say oh yeah you know but those are
you know you can ignore it because uh
they don't apply anymore
things have changed you know after 20
years things have changed they don't
apply half of them will say that now
that is wrong that is incorrect okay
that is incorrect yeah it is true things
have you know 20 years you know 10 years
20 years has passed programming language
has changed you know the scene
programming languages and CPU they you
know choose various degrees they would
all change but those
most of the criticisms about commonly
Spokane let's go back to it most of the
criticisms about communities still
correct okay in fact many of them still
applies is worse it's even worse
because for the in the past 10 years
there are so many new languages you know
or all language with much more Fanfare
and uh much more power in coding ASCA
for example Haskell is like 30 years old
but in the past 10 years there's
tremendous
new blood and new um compilers or
whatever you know JavaScript another
example JavaScript is 25 years old it's
tremendous
new things you know and also new
languages you know but common is
no no improvement no improvement you
know basically essentially effectively
realistically speaking
comparatively speaking compare
communities to all the other new ones
you know the other one has
ten times act and a hundred times more
activity commonly speaks like dead Okay
dead
but but then on Reddit you'll see you
know this code phenomenon because they
are fans of communities you will see
them say oh yeah those those those are
just no longer true
idiotic but the most the most um
that's normal okay that's you know
that's that's what you see every day the
drivers on online especially in code you
know uh Fanboy situation but the most
offensive guy there's this guy okay
this end let me show you
this this is a scumbag I don't just mean
Tech you know he's a bad human
bad person okay
this and this guy okay this this guy
this N is a scumbag he's a German he you
know he he's a German guy his name is um
because he has always been whenever my
name appears online you know he'll just
attack me bad mouth me you know let me
show you let me show you that article
I I know him actually we ex you know I
was
you know this Fame okay let me show you
know he actually he's his name is on my
blog okay let's just go to uh let's
search I
uh what's his name let me let me find it
okay
search it his name is
um
he's a he's a old he's he's like 70
years old maybe 60 or 70.
owed this machine phonetic okay his name
is um there
Rainier Jose
okay there it is that's him
they near just week
goes by the name lisp in
and this guy you know about 2012 10
years ago I was dying of hunger in USA
uh and then
then he posted something on Hacker News
you can still find it on Hacker News
Saudi around 2000 2012 okay
2012. and here here just say oh yeah
that's that's good Sadi you know he been
trolling you know and so it's good that
he died now something like that
something to that effect and he will
keep saying oh sorry he's he's code is
just copy and paste from somebody else a
lie okay a malicious lie
illegally a lie that's uh you can you
know I can sue him for defamation this
linear drastic skin
this guy okay this m m let me show you
where he's mentioned okay so he let's so
so this one is new just last month okay
let's see search for
you see you see we you know he says for
example this guy I don't know who this
guy despise these people using
pseudonyms you know these Anonymous
facts you know then okay oh well oh
rainbow rainbow rainbow flag there's
Anonymous facts no responsibility you
know so he says
I clicked the link then realized it was
Sally you his opinions can be safely
dismissed okay but where is you what's
your reason what's your content none
Okay so
and they are you know there are some
people defending you know me thank you
guys okay now this m you know then then
this man the rainy and
says
especially given that this stuff had
been collected by William James another
nasty troll okay
but anyway he's there's another part
where he um
you see sorry is just a troll you know
what does it mean on a troll
they don't like it because when you
criticize a community they just don't
like it they don't like whatever you say
this guy you know that
this reply would be a
considered good you know he says I know
Saudi is a bit controversial figuring
these circles but some of the quotes
there are from really technical
knowledgeable first people you know for
example Rodney Brooks and program him
you know they are not just technical
knowledgeable people they are the father
of common lisp okay these these people I
quoted you know famous people who
who criticize comedies you know they are
not just knowledgeable they are the
father they are the founder of common
lisp
and the [ __ ] idiots Malaysian Zuma
idiot okay here here is the
Rainer joswick skin you know look you
know this this this is where he defend
he liable you know libel legally me
okay he says
calmed out land lisp and other groups
groups for a decade or longer without
actually having done any this
programming and without knowing much of
lisp in recent years he wrote some emac
this tutorials that's that's how he
character that characterized me what a
[ __ ] lion skin
you know
you know but notice now he's he's he's
being a little bit kind than last time
now he says in recent years he wrote Sun
emac this tutorials at least that's a
little bit positive you know in recently
you know this guy sorry don't know any
of this but in recent years he wrote
some emac this tutorial so what a
[ __ ] skin
you know because 10 years ago he posted
on Hacker News when I was dying of
hunger asking for help he you know he he
just bad-mouthed me he says you know I
never coded any these that's just P20
Force the [ __ ] skin
then he
does some explanation now he you know
now this guy this this m okay you know
this n stand for this machine that's his
handle this guy winner just swick now
this this
Rainer guy he's the old guy okay maybe
60 something or 70 years old you know
he's a this machine Fanatics so you know
he has experience from you know 40 years
ago from 80s or something
so he does know what he's talking about
okay he does know and oftentimes you
read his stuff
actually many many of them are useful
information okay so you know but then
he's a commonly fanatic so often you'll
see kind of Tainted information because
you're spinning it to the way positive
okay so he will say you explain he will
explain why Richard Stoneman this
dislike emac this common lisp and uh and
blah blah blah you know some of the
points are valid okay
okay so that's it uh I think that's it
for today
um
so you guys watching say something okay
um I think that's it for today
um
emac this coding turned out into event
uh
and uh attacking some of these you know
my enemies not you know that it's not
like they are a lot you know
basically I find the most offensive just
this guy just this guy the other guys
you know some they just say I'm a troll
that's very common you know you you say
lots of things about people online
and I accept it you know I you know for
example this one Saudi is just a troll
and some will say oh just ignore Saudi
you know but this guy
what he is doing is malicious lie okay
that is malicious lie that's a diff
that's legally different from the others
okay I think I'm shut down in uh
in a minute or two
so back to the original whoever
obadia Macy so what do you say you know
now you have you know now I have get I
give like one hour response to your
question what do you say do you do you
think I am I reasonable
do I make sense or am I like lying and
total [ __ ] say something say answer
yeah so many guys you know you guys
supporting me thank you
um okay so that's it for today
uh we didn't get to finish coding lisp
you know coding what we wanted to do but
that's okay because
um
because I planned it to be a slightly
random chat anyway because because when
you code is something more complex few
people you know really appreciate it
because you know we see comments you
know you
you get people never use even you know
you don't you haven't used emacs before
so
so coding this
you know that's that's what happens with
online YouTubers you know sometimes
you'll see usually it's a case YouTubers
you know you'll find YouTubers teaching
python teach you programming teach you
Java you know a lot tons of it and many
of them you know some they have millions
of what you know viewers my video
100 views or 1 000 views
but you know if you search you know let
me let's let's talk random okay YouTube
you know you search for Python tutorial
you'll see millions of view views
you know Python tutorial let me show you
some of it you know
python full course 30 million views oh
Jesus python in four hours full course
37 million views oh Jesus
zero two zero three million views one
years ago God Jesus cause I must be your
idiot
you know Python 3.4 programming tutorial
what is this how many views play oh oh
play list okay you get a you get a
picture JavaScript you know
so why do they you know so what they do
so you know this most of these are
idiotic tutorials okay they are they are
Their audience is for people who never
programmed before but these people you
know like Mom and papa whatever you have
you know they heard oh programming can
make a lot of money oh you should get
into stem you know be a programmer make
a lot of money so that's why that's how
you get that's why you have 30 million
views you know if you actually start to
talk about
the technical stuff algorithms you know
the real thing about the programming
language you don't get you know it's
you'll you'll be lucky if you have one
medium views a few of them you know some
they are good ones okay they are good
some of them are really good and I'm not
criticizing this neither because you
know obviously if you do something for
complete programmers you'll have lots of
view your viewers you know your audience
is Broad
so what's my point so what I was saying
yeah so I was just saying you know I was
coding this but
you you won't find another basically you
you won't find another coding like in
depth like what I'm doing you know you
you just get introduction
to emac this you know
uh
so about the amazing says like uh I
wholeheartedly agree with you I was
never again against you in any way hence
me saying do you agree with the
criticism
okay thank you thank you I'm glad to
hear okay
um yeah so
you know I I would I would say some of
the criticisms okay maybe maybe uh
uh five percent
they I I would say they are
um
reasonable or you know
on certain things I do uh for example
let me give you an example for example I
you know for example I use cgo for
variable names sometimes you you'll see
it in my code for example I can show you
so this is source code took stuff like
he's you know one of my most popular 4
000 lines of code so you can see uh
you can see you know you can see I use
the dollar sign
for variable names
starting without a sign and why do I do
that I explained in lots of my articles
just search for Sadi sijou or search for
Saudi variable naming and in fact
last week one video before I explained
live why do I I why do I do that okay
using variable names starting with a
dollar sign now this is very
unconventional this is you know the the
typical the typical these coders they
don't like that because this is not a
this convention this convention came
from Pearl and PHP okay but however I do
it
you know why so so in a sense I'm
breaking the community standard you know
you know in each programming language
you typically have a community idioms
and guideline you know so you will not
see you know you will not see a variable
with uh
dollar sign from that's not this
convention okay
but I do that so in so you can
immediately say I'm kind of
you know breaking the convention I'm
kind of an out of ordinary okay so some
of the your sometimes see criticism you
know class code you have a dollar sign
in front what the [ __ ] you know you will
not see that anywhere else in in this
code okay in not not in iMac this not in
scheme this not in racket this not in
common is not enclosure this you will
not see this
okay so first of all if you there are
criticisms of me doing that
you know so
so that can be valid okay but I do have
a reason I have my own reasons why I do
that
okay and I explained in lots of my
articles
for example and I explained in my last
video
uh for example let's go to it okay so
sound talk show
let's go to it and you can see xana talk
show uh
a few days ago okay the title title is
sijo in this closure
okay I explained why I personally
do this
and
if you search for let's let's go to
study.info
okay Saudi info search and search for
cgo okay you can see I have several
blogs about it
one two three okay closure seizure
meaning cgo for variable names where I
explain why I use it okay and see your
world language design and coding
convention okay and then you have the
Pearl this came from Pearl Pearl or
pearl made it the most popular
programming language okay so now let's
go to my articles so you can see this
one is explains the studio enclosure
this one explains the cgo4 variable
names you know my you know this
reasons analysis why you know why is it
good why is it bad but it's not
conventional should you do it you know I
give you I give my reasons okay if you
want to criticize criticize my reasons
not just oh sorry it's a draw okay
that's it that's that's not good okay
and it's more the sigil was language
design and coding convention you
analysis so what is the coding
convention why is it good is it always
good
ask your questions okay
and what are the you know variable
naming
so for example Pro uses a dollar sign
can we use something else can we use for
example Greek letter
what does it do what's the effect why
should we stick with the dollar sign is
it because it's easier to type on the
keyboard because if you use a math
symbol a quick Letter People it's hard
to type
and the English speakers the monolingual
they don't know what it is
so so so all these are you know
philosophy philosophy of coding but most
people they don't they don't know they
don't you know they never sing it this
is what a flag is is weird that's what
that that's their reaction they say just
just say oxide just a straw that's it
okay so so that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
um
and a lot more you know so not just this
articles I explained in full detail and
Analysis okay sijo and uh let me show
you okay so
variable naming Okay so here okay
let me show you a few articles
variable naming English words considered
harmful
okay
now this is one of my characteristics
this is one of the reason why you see a
lot of people say science is a troll
okay well that title is dramatic okay I
admit
but I I give you reasons okay this page
is you know uh two thousand words
for example in mathematics
you know mathematics math okay
it's the the let me show you
you see you see this um
let me show you some code okay
you see that's math you know you
probably have seen these right calculus
right
have you seen emath you know they are
using x y and z
have you seen mathematics that use you
know full variable names like this is
something this is domain from from
something
no
usually in mathematics everything is
just one single letter
okay so there's a lot more okay you know
I you know I've ended endless articles
endless
for example let me show you this one
you see these math characters
math in mathematics they use one single
letter
almost always okay not just that not
that's not enough they even go as far as
using like strange font uh letters for
example I for I is for real number the
real number is set
the the field of real numbers Q is a
rational numbers okay did I get it that
right okay here's the Z is the integers
okay and this double stroke n stands for
natural numbers
okay so you can see Q is for rational
numbers okay R represent real numbers
Okay C you know these double stroke
characters
do you see do you see you know how come
they don't type the whole thing hopeful
for words
so why is it then the question is why is
it in mathematics you stick with single
letter why is it in programming you use
four letters have you have ever have
anyone ever thought about it
you know ask yourself have you ever seen
a stack Overflow question or on Hacker
News or on Reddit where that you know uh
Slash this these idiots come and these
idiots have you ever seen they ever
asked that question even
why because they don't they don't think
okay
I I
well there are a lot of people do think
computer scientists are a lot you know
you know
so what I'm saying is that you know so I
also also thought about this so I went
in depth
I went in in depth on the on the seizure
on the variable naming thing
uh let's go back to uh the article
you know variable naming English words
considered harmful and I actually tried
for for for for half a year to program
in a programming language you know in
JavaScript
to follow the math math convention using
just one single letter for variables and
function names
I experimented and I write out you know
what's the result what happens what
happens when you do that I explain here
first of all why do I want to avoid
English words
English words such as a list you know if
you name your variable if you define a
you know if you want to assign this to a
variable sometimes you can say Beast or
sometimes x equals to something which
one should you do
you know so analysis you study your
research you know
and then so I have lots of reasons and
explanations okay
okay I think I should go
um then there's also you know naming a
variables that's a that's that's not
that's not a small topic okay in some
sense it's trivial but in some sense
it's not okay there's a predicate in
programming language naming okay
predicate for example in in lisp in
common list when emac beasts you will
often see function names ending in p
okay bound P buffer modified P cons p f
bound P feature P file directory P those
are called predicate penicot means
again in computer in programming
languages spread the cut means a
function that returns either true or
false nothing else is returned either
true or false that's what predicate
means
and email is in common is follows that
convention Okay naming of things you
know pedicate in programming language
and naming
okay in scheme disk enclosure lisp they
use the convention ending in question
mark
okay now in Wolfram language they use a
convention ending in Q capital Q Q here
means question
okay so you can see this is part of the
syntax issue you know naming a variables
naming of functions is kind of part of
the syntax issue and has to do with the
seizure we are talking about because the
seizure we are using we are putting a
question mark a standard way to
prefix variable names while in the
predicate case it's a standard way to
post fix a character or symbol after the
name of the function okay so you can see
there are different conventions okay
different and then then you can go on to
analyze analysis which one is better in
what way okay that's
predicate in programming language names
and there is Ruby okay Ruby follows the
question mark convention
okay so that's about credit then you
also have um
naming of things in programming
languages such as list Vector array you
know very confusing things okay that's
it for today uh thank you guys for
watching
bye guys
so if you like my stuff go to my website
okay sorry Dot
info
um pay me patreon uh PayPal and if you
like this video you know some part of it
you liked get the UI our timestamp and
post it okay to your blog share it to
your Twitter
um
thank you
bye guys
shut down shut down in one minute for
real okay
uh
let me shut down in one minute
so I'm just gonna get some of the links
into today's talk show so we have a
record of what we what I talked about
today
so this page is
the math font okay copy it
close it
this wolfam language type setting okay
paste it
variable name prefix CJ Pearl
Pearl is a language that made sijia
popular and pose language that actually
popularized popularized the the name
sijo
because before Pearl
you don't have a you don't have a jargon
for this kind of thing Pearl is doing
you know Pro is the first one the Pearl
mongers you know the Pearl code they
started to spread sigil they gave it the
name sijo and this seizure you can look
up on Wikipedia you know I've read it of
course you can look up on Wikipedia
they'll give you detail where it came
from you know sijo etymology see job it
came from it's a jargon that refers to a
magic you know in some kind of magic
context you know you can read Wikipedia
so procedure and then of course it
became it came to PHP because PHP stands
for pretty home page in the beginning
it's just some script of Pearl by a
teenager pretty home page and later on
they they they they they when PHP P
became the most popular language around
2000s they changed it to fake news to
PHP is hypertext processor you know blah
blah blah
PHP is pretty home page my pretty home
page look
fact that the computer programmers scams
the naming of listings in computer
languages close it and this page
predicate in programming languages
and variable naming English words
considered harmful this is quite an
article I would say because I started to
do this and I actually spent half a year
coding
in a different way
to realize
you know to I realize you cannot in
programming languages
in a typical programming language you
cannot
name your variables or functions by a
single letter or two that won't work why
read this article okay
you cannot
unless you have a specialized language
then you can such as APL
APL you know in APL the language every
function is one single character
so yeah so you can go find out why
is this copy go back here
paste closures meaning
bye bye