Good evening everyone. Welcome to
another episode of sound talk show. We
are going to code emac this make America
great again by engineering
but not by lawyers. So if you are
watching this offline play at 1.5 speed
because I ramble. Uh if you are watching
this live say hi there. And uh we going
to begin. So optimize SVG. Okay. So
uh optimize SVG. So let's begin. Okay.
So show uh let me show you why I want to
do it. So uh here is wam language code.
Let me let me show you. Okay. Inverse
circle extra. Um inverse circle. So uh
so there uh search for WL.
Uh search for WL. So lots of backup
files. Remove them. Okay. Open that.
Copy that. Go to wam language. Make them
larger. So I was working a lot on uh
wine language. So paste the code here.
So paste the code here. And uh let's uh
magnify.
So here is a code. And let's Okay,
that's too big. That's smaller. Okay. So
uh and uh shift control N to make it
type set. So now shift enter to evaluate
it. Okay. So you got this image and it's
saved to SVG. Uh let's make some
changes. Uh offset.
Oh The the the the code is like
interim. I'm working on it. So it's
right now it's not very good. So let's
look at let me show you another um
floor ring. Okay, let's show this one.
So here is a notebook. Select all. Run
it.
So you got this image. Fantastic and
beautiful. This is geometric inversion.
We talked about it several times in the
past month. Okay. and and it's saved to
a SVG here. So let's magnify.
So it's saved to SVG file there. Okay.
So let's go to that file. That file
would be in the uh document directory.
Okay. Hexagonal. Okay. So there it is.
Open it. There it is. The file. and uh
make it HTML mod. So you can see there
is the SVG. So you know lots of these
lines are like like almost the same.
Okay, they they differ in the end. Uh
they put style in front. Um okay. So
anyway, so this is exported for Wuam
language. Now open it. Go back. Close
that. Go to the directory. So you can
see it's 1 mgabyte and 700 kilobytes.
Okay, 1.7 mgabytes. So that's too large.
Make a backup. Okay, and so there is SVG
optimization. So let me show you image
um tutorial. If you search for
image video processing tutorial on
sardi.info, my website. So recently I've
been looking for uh tools to optimize
SVG.
There are several okay and uh my result
my research result is that the best one
is SVG cleaner. Okay download that. So
this is a tip for you if you're going to
uh work with SVG a lot use SVG cleaner.
It's written in rust and focus on
correctness and non lossy optimization.
Okay, so you can download it. So anyway,
I'm going, you know, I need to optimize
PNG. Okay, so let's copy that. Uh close
that. Wait. So go to talk show. Uh go to
talk show. Today's talk show. Let's uh
paste optimize PNG there. and uh
and uh okay so
yeah so this tool is great now I need to
up uh optimize that PNG so wait so go to
document okay hexagon okay so how do I
do it well you know it's kind of tedious
so the command would be so if you just
optimize one file
so open a new buffer this is the command
Okay. Basically
and uh then
so copy the file path. So this is a file
path in the same directory. So we just
say that and uh this this
SVG clean you need the input output. I'm
not sure there's a command to directly
override.
I'm guessing not. Okay. So SVG cleaner
command line. Okay. So copy that. Go to
the terminal. PowerShell much superior
than bash. Okay. So, let's
uh let's see.
Control scroll to magnify it. SVG
cleaner. Okay.
Uh dash sli. Let's see if there's a
help.
Okay. This uh there is.
But is there a flag? Yeah, this this is
not too helpful. You know what? What the
Following requirement were not
provided out file. Oh, okay. Okay. Let's
try again. The syntax is probably wrong.
So, what? Um,
so you just say dash dash help. Okay,
now it's better.
Oh god, this this is too large. Okay,
that's too large. Let's shrink it. So do
it again.
Okay. So this is SVG helper. Do they
have a option to override the original?
I forgot. So anyway, SVG cleaner. Okay.
That's one. That's a better one. Better
than the others I've tried. Better than
scal uh and better than Yeah, better
than scalp.
So but okay. So I need to code a
command, but it's tedious. So what I
have to do is let's let's say that okay
so now shrink it to one line. Now copy
it then go to this directory hexagonal
file start eh shell emac shell paste the
command run it. Okay now it says your
your image is 71%
smaller. Oh fantastic 71%. Go to the
directory refresh. Now let's see
uh okay god.
So let's see original file. So now
refresh. So you can see before it's 1.7
mgabyte. Now it's 0.5 mgabyte.
Fantastic. So that's why uh I need to do
that. But
I need to generate a lot of SVGs uh
because of the Wufam language for my
website.
Um let me show you. Okay,
you see I have I talked I talked about
this project many times. This is like 30
years old. So I'm updating them. So lots
of these PNG or GIF images, you know,
Asian. So I'm updating them to modernize
them. So I start to need So these are
GIF. I start to need and this is PNG. I
I need to uh update them, make them, you
know, high resolution 30 years
technology advancement
and SVG, you know. So I need to output a
lot SVG images. So every time I output
it, I don't want to like go to eh shell
then change file name and you know so I
want the commands in EMAC. So I press a
key then the current image under the
cursor is optimized. That's what we
going to write. Okay.
So let's copy that. Let's go back to
talk show. Okay. So let's go back to
talk show. Okay. Here's a talk show and
let's start to write the command. Okay.
So this is going to be fairly involved.
If you don't know eacisp, this is
kind of fairly involved. Okay. So let's
begin the documentation. I'm going to
read a comment uh in a bit. Okay. Define
a function. So uh define a function. So
this will be called
kasar
optimize
SVG.
Okay. Make it that
uh yeah that's a command and uh create
it today's state version today's state
okay uh and uh this will be how how so
first job is to the design of the
interface how you want the input came
from you know do you want it to be in
the at directory or do you want like in
HTML Well, uh let's see
uh
file path optimize. So, usually it's a
current file. So,
yeah. So, because uh so let's let's
let's let me show you. Okay. So, usually
so close that go back to um close that.
Okay. Go to this inverse circle. Close
that wam language. Close that. Uh
reopen. Copy that. Close that. Okay. So
there is a file. So you open it. Yeah.
So you want to work on the current
buffer usually. Okay. So anyway, let me
let me u
prepare this link today's talk show and
uh so okay so file path Z file path.
Okay
let me just uh write the documentation.
The first first the most important thing
critical this is my style of coding. I
always write the documentation first and
when you write documentation you need to
have the user interface design setup
first. Uh so but it may change later but
you know usually I start with the
documentation
uh optimize
the SVG file
of current buffer or um
or the file path under the cruiser
something like that. Let's worry about
that later. Okay. So
in EIS code
Z file path is a
uh file path. Okay. So let's begin with
that.
So uh yeah optimize. So this involves
making a shell call. So basically what
you have to do so copy that close that
uh go back here. So basically your
command is going to make a shell call
like that. Okay. So the first job is to
get get the current file path. Okay, so
the current file path will be
uh
buffer file name.
Okay, you don't need a par. Buffer file
name is a global variable that the value
is the current uh the file path of the
current buffer. You see there
the pink window by the way shows all my
command calls and the keystrokes on the
left. So for example I want to evaluate
buffer file name I do it call it. So you
can see I just call eval last six and
you can see the file path is printed in
a mini buffer at the bottom. So go to
the messages buffer. You can see so let
me try again. Okay close that. Now I
want to evaluate the global variable
buffer file name. Okay. Press press
press press. It's done. You see the
output is in a mini buffer
and the command is shown in the ping
window. Eva last sets sex and my
keystrokes are backspace WM. That's a
Vora keyboard with my glove at fantastic
setup. So the back backspace key there
is right here under my thumb. Okay. So
let me do it again. So, uh,
press press.
Wait, the wrong command. Press press.
There it is. Okay.
So, how are you guys? So, let's see.
Hungry man. Hi. Uh, what's file names
ADHD trap?
Uh, that is I we did a live stream about
three months ago that is turns out to be
very popular. So that is so there's a
GIF animation called ad HD trap.
Okay. So like you are snooping over my
files. Uh HD. So let's open it
now. That's not this one. Okay. So let
me So this one.
So let me go from the beginning. Okay.
Talk show and search for animation.
Okay. Uh, search again
wam language animation. Search again
animation. Uh,
coding geometry hyperola animation. Go
back here. W language. I mean this one.
Okay. So, open it. Showing browser. Uh,
not that one.
Okay. So, close that. Search for
physics. There it is. Kasar talk show
2025 April 20th episode 6:45
Wam language physics emulation of
bouncing balls okay so there is this so
let me show that
[Music]
fascinating
so we did this so I saw this on Twitter
so I did it this I kind of you know uh
did it in wuam language age. Okay. So,
we code this live. So, check it out. And
then a friend on Discord
uh ask AI uh ask chat GPT to
to generate code for this animation
and chat GPT draw this one. Idiotic. It
failed. Okay. So, that is this that
answers your question.
Are you making a website? What kind of
question is that? Damn nice keyboard. It
looks cool. I guess you are very new.
I've been, you know, I have a website
for 30 years, which is what I've been
talking about in the past five years
live stream. Okay. Let's go back to um
to our code. Okay. Close that. Close
that. Switch. Switch. Today's talk show.
Paste that there. Linkify. make a list.
Okay, so you can check you know see
that. So now let's go back to our code.
So um so this is very uh technical eagp.
So I guess you guys may not be
interested but anyway so let's continue
doing this. So file name buffer file
name. So we got a file name first of
all. So you need to save it as a
variable. Okay. So
um yeah. Yeah. Well, okay. So,
path. Okay. File path. Uh, okay. So, now
you need to run this command. Now, there
are several ways to do it.
Looks good. Hi, Francis. Hi, Francis.
So, let's begin with the easiest method
to make a shell command. Okay, so that
would be
that would be this command. Okay. Shell
command. Look up the documentation.
Describe function. You can see um
you can see describe function there. Am
I alive? Video check, audio check.
Everything is good. Yes. Say good. Okay.
So shell command is this command blah
blah blah. This is the syntax and it
does this that. Okay. Close that. So
that is the shell command. Okay. We can
make the shell command. So let's uh let
you know since I'm doing live coding
just let's make this the simplest
um okay define another variable and the
variable will be this string shell
command. Okay, let's not let's not do it
there. Let's just say uh the name
variable name and let's set the command
ourselves here. Okay, prettyify the
code.
Okay. So,
so set the shell command uh call this
command indent zero path coordinate
precision two. Okay. That's options join
join octto flag. Yes. Hexa. Okay. So,
name here is the file name you need.
Okay. So,
so let's concat
this string by the file name. So, the
file name. Okay. We I actually we don't
need that. So let's just put it here.
Okay. Buffer file name. That's a file
path of the current file. Uh then
then you need to Okay. Then you need to
uh concat again. concat
buffer file name by uh you need to kind
of well god
um let's for now let's just say add svg
okay so so the new file is going to be
svgsvg
because otherwise we need to actually we
can do it okay so but let me let me do
this quickly Uh so that this is like
interesting. Okay. So uh concat buffer
file name. So so buffer file name is
original file name. Okay. So
uh origin name. Okay. Well okay. So
okay. So copy that. Okay. So let's set
your name. It's actually a path. Uh so
okay so let's original file path that's
going to be buffer file name okay then
then here
okay then you want to say new path okay
and how do we create a new path well
let's do it here okay so set x new path
path file path is going to be concat
x original file name and something
something okay now so you need a new uh
local variable x new path okay fantastic
clean up the code so original file path
is that new file path is let's just say
that we're going to change it later so
you know the desired put is the file
name and two underscore two then the
extension you know so we're going to
worry about that later okay so let's
open that so go back to our code so new
file path then the command the command
is this command uh then concat with the
original file path then new file path
okay purify the code pify purify the
code now
delete that Okay. Now before we do
anything print them
just make sure that uh you know we are
calling the right command for debugging
purposes. Okay. Okay. Now don't call the
shell command actually we we can you
know so the command will be call the
shell command
of that command optional output buffer
uh ignore error buffer ignore. Okay
that's basically it. So comment that
out.
So that is our code. In fact that is
complete.
Pify purify. Okay. Evaluate the buffer.
So we got it.
So now
uh so this Z file path. Okay. Let's
remove the remove that parameter. Okay.
Now let's add
X UTF.
that is abbreviation that expand to this
declaration for lexical uh binding of uh
local variables and UTF8 encoding. Okay.
Now make a backup. Go to the diode and
by compile the file. Yes. Is there any
error? No. Fantastic. Open the bite
compile file. Close. Delete it. Okay. So
eval the buffer. Fantastic. Now let's go
to that image file. Now meta x
uh s optimize. There it is. Do it. So go
to the messages buffer. It says command
that that that that. Now did it get the
um file path correctly? No. Because you
see there's no space between the new and
old file path. So fix it.
Go back to the code.
So you forgot the space indeed there.
Okay. Now I'm pretty sure that's good.
So So we can call shell command. Okay.
Now purify the code, evaluate the
buffer, go to our SVG,
and uh let's make a backup.
Uh, wait. So, this is already optimized.
So, uh, hold on a second. So, let's
delete that and delete all the other
backup. Okay. So, delete that. So, this
is original 1.7 megabytes. Okay. Now,
make a backup.
Uh, what? Uh,
delete the rest backup. Okay. So, make a
backup of that. Okay. Fantastic. Now
open it. Now MetaX
Optimize SVG. Do it.
Your image is 71%
smaller now. Fantastic and beautiful.
Now go to the directory refresh. So can
we see? Yes. So it created
this SVG. SVG. That's a new one. Okay.
Now let's think about so actually our
command is complete now it's just the
trivial uh pretty up you see the core
functionality our command for today's
task is complete and I think I should
stop because then then it makes my video
live stream beautiful
if I continue for another half hour then
it's like oh complicated
Okay. So, well, because most people, you
know, they are not advanced eag coders.
So, you show the simplist, it's uh
usually better at least for live stream.
Okay. So, here's a command. It's already
done. So, you know, we can make it more
robust. If you are going to publish or
you're going to sell this software, of
course, you need to make the new file
path to be you know like underscore2 uh
attached things like that. And actually
you you know the better. So this is
about user interface design. You want to
make a backup of the original then
delete the then make you know optimize
then delete the original then rename the
new optimized file to be the original
file name. So that way you know we can
do that. Let's do that actually. Okay.
So first of all put the code back syntax
color show in browser.
Fantastic. Here's our fruit. And there's
a duplicate link. So, let's remove that
duplicate link. Okay. So, I think that's
it. Uh, so there's some pretty uh clean
up to do. Uh, shall we do it or shall we
like stop? We'll talk random for five
minutes.
Uh, you know, there's a lot to improve.
So besides the file name, the other
thing we it would be better is that
when you make a shell command call, it
is not optimal because when you make a
shell command call, Emacs will need to
start a shell. So it actually start a
shell uh you know and then the shell
call the command. Okay, so that's like
two-step process. It will be more
efficient
if you call the shell command directly
in Emacs. Okay, you can do that. So if
you search for Kasar eag lisp tutorial
on kali.info,
the most popular tutorial
on the web, okay, for like 20 years and
uh we want to make a shell call. So, so
you go to emacisp basics not here uh you
go to eacisp
then you go to call shell command okay
so there are several alternatives so the
first one is shell command the most easy
simplest one okay once you do that
you know once you are familiar with this
you can level up to
uh you know so you also So co shell
command on region sync shell command you
level up to co shell command on region.
Wait
uh you level up to to like start
external process. Okay. So this when you
use this function you bypass the shell.
So Emac doesn't start a shell and the
shell call that command you call the
command directly. Okay.
So that's a core process and you have
quite a few variations. You also have
co-process region and so on.
Uh but however the so there are a lot so
it's usually almost always better. It's
like there's always just it's simply
better to to not start a shell. Okay.
But however the issue is that it becomes
somewhat complicated.
So it's somewhat more you know quite you
know a bit involved in eag to make a
core directly
to use the core process or the um core
process region you know fairly
complicated
or start process you see and you have to
decide which one to use okay but we I
you know I can do that so let's see what
is this page okay close that what is
this page uh Uh, okay. That's today's
talk show. You know, I can I can do
that, but um
I'm not sure it's very interesting to
you guys because it would be interesting
to those who have programmed Emac Lisp
for at least say several months
because otherwise just just call shell
command. Okay. Now the another issue
with the with just the shell command is
that you usually have to quote your file
name. So if the file name let me show
you. Okay. So if the file name let's say
make a backup
and uh let's say uh okay so this one
let's just say uh edit. So let's say
xxxy.
Okay. Done. Okay. So this is our file.
New file name. It's got a space in it.
Now if you do it
optimize SVG, it'll fail. Uh wait. Yeah,
it'll fail. Do it. You see error found
argument something something which
wasn't expected or isn't valid in this
context something. Why? Because you know
when you have a space in shell name it
needs to be shell corded.
Worse is when you have apostrophe in
your shell name you know like in like
typically in shell names you could have
you know arbitrary names you know very
easy because it's not programming
language but
but you get a lot of problems when you
call shell command on them okay so then
so it be because to escape the quote is
very complex because it's not just like
when you manual ually escape it in
shell. It's easy.
Let's see. CD2 document. Okay. So,
directory. So, if you want to quote this
XY, it's easy. Okay. So, for example,
the uh you can X press a key and the
shell actually automatically complete
Ced for you.
um you know and there's other lots of
other ways. You can also type a
double quote x then tab and you also do
it or you can just say uh x then back
slash wait in in in powershell it's a
it's a single quote then that then
anyway
but in sh but if you want to quote the
file name you know if you want to quote
the file name in emacs when you call
shell it's very complicated because
emac this string needs to have a quote
by itself. Then when you pass to shell
so it there's a twostep or three-step
quoting escaping mechanism going on. So
it can get incomprehensible or even
impossible.
Okay. So but you have to do it. So but
in our case we can actually do by uh for
example let me show you
uh let's uh wait
sh uh was it shell quote or yeah shell
quote argument okay that that okay then
shell quote argument wait uh What?
Undo. Undo. Undo. Yeah, that's so shall
code argument. Okay, that that that
purify the code that we that should
work. Evaluate the code. Go to the file
uh x.x
y the command. Do it. Now it's
fantastic. Go to the shell and you can
see it's done.
So anyway, but but you see the problem
is that this shell quote argument does
not always work because it you know it
when your command you when when your
file name has lots of you know uh B
slash slash or double quote you know it
may not always work. So anyway,
so that's it for today and you know so
we can make this shell command. Uh so
you have to quote the name but if you
alternatively if if you call the um
if you call the call process those
commands oh god okay so this needs to go
what this is too
long. Okay. So if you call the core
process like you know start process or
or the core process then you don't need
to quote your files. Anyway I think
that's it for today. So let's see what
are comments and that's it.
Uh oh. Okay. We got a quite a few
comments. Let's see what Hi Kasar. Hi. I
like Emac this. Hi. Uh me too. You are a
Gucci. Uh are you assuming the buffer to
be backed by a file?
Uh yes. Well obviously I mean typically
yes in practice
SVG file will in a buffer is always a
file.
Uh so in this case yes in practice it's
very rare if you have a buffer that's
SVG image but that's you know not saved
to a file it's kind rare
in fact it's it's hard to create that
you know it's hard to create a buffer
with SVG uh actually well the reason we
can do that is because SVG is just HTML
so you can copy this copy the entire
buffer
quick, you know, uh, open a new buffer,
paste it, and there we have it. This is
a SVG file, and it's not a file. There's
no file associated with it. So, we can
call this command,
but in this case, our command won't work
because this is not a file. But, you
know, anyway,
so let's see uh it's not a variable. So
uh what is uh what is insane? Mutating
an unbound variable rather than just
binding it is unsaid.
Uh
you are incorrect. Okay. So you are
talking about let me show you the code.
Okay. So the code let's put it back.
Okay. Let's put the back code. The uh
let's just uh wait
put it back. syntax showing browser. So
you are saying that you know when I
declare local variables let these
variables then I'm setting it here you
are saying I'm mutating variables
before they are set actually that's
false when you when you declare with let
they have a initial value of neo okay
that's how emac this works so all these
variables they have a value of neo which
is a actual value
Okay. And also this gets us into the
coding style. Should you so
alternatively for example this um
okay so uh let's say go to uh Emacs
mode. Okay. So for example this
alternatively
what you can do is you can just
Okay. So for example, delete delete that
paste that delete purify. Okay, you can
alternatively
alternatively give them a value inside
the let by this syntax. Okay, and this
part too but this part the x command it
depends on previous
uh variables. You see?
So therefore if you put the if you put
this here it won't work because let the
let declaration does not allow you to
have variable chaining. Okay. So if you
want to do this you can but you need to
change this let to a let star you see
technicalities of emacis you see. So
compare
so this is about coding style you know
both of them works but which one should
you use you know the programmers gets
obsessive about it some certain
programmers okay I was one of them but I
can tell you the proper which is the
best way okay so you got this this
this way is
semantically equivalent to uh this.
Okay, so we got two variations. Which
one you should use? Should you just have
variables there and set them or should
you like make the make it compact less
function call you know like this is so
elegant you know after 20 years of
coding eag this
I decided I prefer this way always
why I can tell you why but but I I'm
assuming Francis you are a eac list
coder right I assume not no Because then
you need uh let asterisk. Yes. Uh global
get shadowed in lead. Uh yes. Okay.
Yeah. So I suppose you are a um
oh Francis Francis is an ellipse coder.
So anyway
uh yes there is law but uh okay. So you
know I don't have time to go get into
detail like who is saying what. Uh but
anyway, but anyway, let me just tell you
uh guys that after 20 years of coding
IMAG this I always prefer this way
because when you put the variables
inside
the let decoration then later on when
you when you need to modify it it become
complicated because let's say you want
to introduce a new variable something
okay then let's say it depends on one of
the variables. Then you know then you
okay then you okay then you what you do
is you you put it back you know you put
to the bottom here
and sometimes when you want when you you
know you need to quickly finish
something you need to modify quickly get
you know prototype so you need to mutate
a variable then you
then you cannot you know like you need
to mut mutate it very multiple times you
know So, so basically um
to make it short, you just you know this
this way is just most flexible and the
most easy to understand because here you
can see all your variables in one shot
you know
because otherwise when you have this
form sometimes it get very complicated
you know like you know some of these
variable can fill a half of a screen
gets complicated and you have several of
them and sometimes then then sometimes
you know the order depends on previous
variable then you need to change it to
let star then you modify then they don't
depend on pre previous variable then you
know the elegant coders then oh you need
to go back and remove the lead star
because it's redundant you know so it
get complicated because you know then
you have a question when you have a le
star does that always mean that some of
the variables are dependent on previous
variable. Does that always mean that
by the semantic? No. The semantic of
less dot just means that it may happen
but you it's not necessarily
that sum of variables depends on the
previous variable value. However, you
know, as a you know, someone who
obsessed about coding style, then you
want to make sure that whenever you have
less thought, you must always have
variables that depends on previous
variable values. So, you need to worry
about that. You need to edit, you need
to first about it. So you know so anyway
in summary my coding style is just
always uh you know do this you know
because I was very obsessive about this
few years ago I changed all my code like
you know 30 50,000 you know all my code
to to the let's start form because I
thought this is just the most general
you know so We just always going to have
you know like don't ever use lead again.
Everything is going to be less star.
Okay. So I I went through all my code
and changed them.
Then after a year I went through the
trouble again changed them back. Okay.
So like right now I actively
remove whenever I have code. Let's see.
Actually I have uh less star. I think
there are still a few. Okay. Um like
it's it's very tedious to uh Okay. Star
you need to back slash quote it. Okay.
So find it. Let's find or let's start.
Wait. Uh oh. Okay. I'm using star find.
So I don't need to quote. Okay. Search
for it. So you So you see let's start.
Let's start. So there's actually like
you know quite a few of them. So open
one of them. So you can see let's start.
So but but you know the reason it's
still there is because I'm I just got
lazy because every time you go through
this tedious
uh this is impractical. You know, in
real life coding, never do this in a
corporation. You know, you code when
it's 5:00 PM, go home. You know, you
don't wor you don't, you know, you don't
worry about it. If you do these things
like this, you know, when it's not
broken, don't touch it, you know, but
but for your own code, you know,
obsessive with elegance, I do that. But,
you know, it takes hours to uh carefully
fix it. So, anyway, that's a that's an
extra story of today's talk show.
Uh, okay. I think that's it. Uh, oh my
god, this fails because you have to
escape the file path. Uh, yes. Yeah. Uh,
because you don't know what is important
and what isn't. Hungry man. Hey, this is
literally a problem introduced by Unix.
Uh, how is this this for? Okay, so I can
still mutate variables with explicit uh
explicitly specified initial value.
That's correct. You see, it's too bad.
Yeah, there's another thing I'd like to
mention in EMAC. This you are not
there's no way to declare local
constants.
So you can you cannot tell the compiler
that you have a constant that you should
never change. you cannot do it actually
there is there is define constant okay
uh yeah but it doesn't work you know
actually
it's just tells the user it tells the
programmer that this this value xs is
supposed to be a constant but you can
change it anyway you know the compiler
doesn't enforce it so and there's no way
there's no way to declare local
variables Okay, which you know even
though I use set but my local variables
like 99.99%
of them are always constant because I'm
a stickler of functional programming
you know so I'm very into uh very much a
functional programmer so all like you
know all all basically all my code my
use of local variables they are all
constants
Okay, but there's one exception though
which gets us into another
technicality of emacisp which is there
is no pipe operator in eagisp. Okay. Uh
in that case let's go to uh s
programming blog and search for this
pipe. Okay. this syntax problem of
piping functions that's a major problem
of emac disp and I believe common disp
and closure list they don't have that
problem they fix it okay so basically
let me explain this problem okay that's
another digression a new topic this
syntax problem of piping functions
basically the problem is eac list this
and common do not have the Unix pipe
function. Okay. So when you when you
have a let's say a file name let's say
you have a file name you want to change
space to dash or dash to space and you
want to append a number you know like
like what we need to do today. So the
easiest way is to mutate a variable you
know set function name is that then set
function name again something then
function name and set again you know you
mutate it to get what you want that's
the easiest way now if you don't want
this mutation of variables what you have
to do is this okay replace rejects in
string that then nest basically you got
this nesting this is very problematic
Because so here's a real life example
from a professional from a expert emac
this coder okay from a friend we were
working on go Emacs okay that his name
is uh I think it's Dave uh is um
David Capello I think anyway if you
search for Emacs
it's on GitHub Okay, the previous Emacs
is the previous maintainer. The current
maintainer is another guy
Mike. But anyway, the previous guy Dave
Dave Capello, he's known for the pixel
application on Windows Pixel Animation.
Uh let's just quickly
search for Pixel Dave Capello. Okay, so
he's a great programmer. He's uh
particularly a C and C++
um
uh C C++ expert.
Okay. So I think I got you know um
there. So David Capello, yes Emacs, that
was, you know, we worked on that like 15
years ago and you go to his website and
he he's famous for oh he, you know, a
project developed by a crazy guy which
has cons reconsidered the entire EMAC
key binding. Okay. So yeah, official
website that
that kind of you know that's old
project. So that moved on. Wait, where
is the um
Yeah. Anyway, the project moved on. So
anyway, so the so now there's a new
maintainer. Anyway, so he's got he's
most famous for Aspright. Okay.
Um Okay. But this code is written by the
new maintainer. Okay. So uh not Dave
Quo, by uh by what's his name?
You know this uh kind of history. So,
oh god. Okay. So, let's go here. Uh,
Matt Fiddler. Okay. Matt Fiddler is a
professional programmer. Uh, and he also
code Emac Bisp. So, this code we are
talking about
is actual code. You know, this is a, you
know, actual code. So, but this this is
very unreadable. It's it's a problem.
Now if EMAC this has a pipe notation for
example this is woam language you have
the pipe syntax operator slash slash
okay or uh the Unix is vertical line
then the problem is solved okay or in uh
in scheme shell is just this pi function
okay enclosure list is arrow okay So th
those are fantastic but eag this still
don't have it. Okay. So that is when
you know that is when I have mute
mutating variable situation because
because this form is just problem too
problematic you know.
Anyway I think that's it for today.
Do you think there should be constant?
Yeah, I would like that for EMAC this
you know I I would like in EMAC this to
have like lead constant something
because I you know I don't mutate my
variables uh
uh mar okay yeah so there are libraries
implement macro okay I don't want that
you want that in that bundle with emac
glue Mac this you don't want you know
lisp is list processing
language that stand for list processor
okay this e emac this you know when you
do this processing you don't want the oh
you oh by the way you need to go to this
library to download it in order to do
fundamental
programming with list okay that's that's
a problem with s and t and j and I
talked about this like I've sweared at
them so much in my liveream. Okay,
that's um
that's called you should ban it. Okay,
so that's another topic that's uh I we
talked about ban something something.
No, not that. Uh what is that that
library? So search for library um
the library named S. Okay. Package S the
uh wait, what is the package named SR
something? There's a bunch
uh controversy alpha. Uh this package uh
dash okay dash my ass.
I did a live stream actually two of
them. So the the earliest one is this
one 2020 five years ago. Uh then I think
I did another one.
Okay. So this is also 2020. I did
another one sometimes like few two years
ago or three dash. Okay. Why you should
not use the package dash? You know dash
is doing trying to you know like like we
are coding lisp but you need these
things. you need to, you know, load
another library to do it. And the reason
why Dash become popular is because the
new Emacs They refuse to
change, you know, like they are the
gods. If you want to do something, you
have to beg us. You have to beg the
right way. Doesn't matter who you are.
You are the lead coder of Google. You
know, the richest men don't give a
The the the the GNU core develop teams
like they they sneer you. You know, you
have to beg them the right way. Then
maybe there maybe we'll consider include
your suggestions or code you know
implementation to extend eag you know
that's a situation you know so that's
why the dash package became you know
popular because it fixed by the way by
now it's fixed you know this is old news
I talked about this
so that's why
dash package becames became and uh very
popular. Okay, because people need to
this they need to have filter
functionalities. What the is a
programming language in this? You don't
have a filter function like what the
are these is? But the GNU Emacs
like they are gods you know what you
going to do then so Dash became hugely
popular the number one download on Mela.
Okay. Then after 10 years, about 10 or 5
years, I forgot exactly
you know the GNU GNU Emacs people saw
it. Oh Jesus, you don't have a field of
function. Look at the dash. They are so
popular and they are not cool. Oh my
god. Jesus, we need to do something
about it. Then that's when they did
something about it.
Okay, that is when today you have those
functions filter uh here sequence. Okay.
So you search for emac this basics.info
there's a sequence function sequence
type you have entire
uh you have about 20 functions that
works on sequence including basically
including everything that the dash did.
So this move of this sequence function
is precisely because of the dash. So we
have to thank to the dash guy you know
the the dash guy.
So and this this is even you know like
this is like 10 years ago. So they added
that they added the sequence you know
seq. Library in 2016. Okay. when it come
out it's not mature yet but you know uh
then you know there's no documentation
and so on and grad but but now by now
it's like nine years so now it's very
mature so a recommendation a tip for me
okay so if you are coding in Mac this if
you are still using dash remove the
out of it okay remove it okay you can
it's op you don't need like a dash
library
but to question why EMAC this still
doesn't have the you know the pipe
function I don't know that's a good
question why don't they still not have
the pipe function they should it's not
difficult to write okay okay I think
that's it I uh so yeah that's one hour
okay so that's it
uh
dash provides the threading macro of
closure. Okay, that's nice. Yeah, we
need we should have that.
Uh, it's called C remove. If not,
no, that's not Well, that's CL. CL is a
different beast. Okay, see, I'm a C I'm
a common list hater, so I won't have
good things to say about CL. And in my
code I never not one single line I will
never use anything CL dash. Okay.
common list.
Wait why would I remove dash? It gives
you the pi marco. You can add you can
you can write the pi marco in in 10
minutes. I can write it in five minutes.
Okay. If you just need that, you don't
need the dash dash thing. You know, the
the dash thing is kind of annoying.
Okay, I don't want to I've been talking
I've been talking for two hours in the
past, you know, about the dash library.
So, I don't want to flame too much, you
know, and he's a he's a good programmer,
okay? But the dash, you know, there's
lots of problems. They
they uh f, you know, first of all, they
are like they are the new generation,
okay? they, you know, not not not about
that guy, but but a lot of people, you
know, they think they, oh, oh, I'm just
going to create a complete new interface
to Emacis because I magn is Asian. It's
no good because I heard of a closure,
you know, I'm very good with closure
hard language new king in town. The
closure did it this way. So I'm going to
you know I'm going to remodel Emac this
and so it works just like closure you
know everything is like short
that's one of the problem that's that's
their mentality okay then another one is
that they're going to have their short
names you know I'm just going to name my
library s
the these are these these kind
of people are okay
I'm just going to name my library S S
for string it's going to be the new the
modern string user interface to all Emac
string functions you know that's the
this late Men Zoomer mentality okay
let's go to the download uh list by
download number okay you see dash number
one why because everyone is loading it
makes Emac slow, you know, like like
like like like this is n the the most
responsible library that makes Emacs
slow like typically you you know like
like the Java JavaScript MPM you know
how do you oh I need a function to um
determine if a number is even okay oh
there's an MPM library let's load it
and and that got 10 depend dependence
dependencies and each one got 10 other
dependencies. So you open the gate to
1,00
packages flow flow you know flooding
your computer that is a situation of the
no-brainers JavaScript coder the
generation you know mpm and similarly is
a eac this situation because these
people they can't be bothered you know
these people uh how do you do a filter
in eac this I don't know Well, let's
just load the dash because it's easy
because it's named filter. You know that
they can't be bothered. So
the the number one library responsible
for slow slowing down Emacs like
whenever whatever you do in Emacs, why
is it slow? Like OG mod, you know, like
the OG mod like to load oak mod
take a while. But actually that's not
fair because oakmog is pretty big like
you know like I'm loading it you know 5
seconds 6 seconds 7 second am I actually
loading it yeah so it takes like 10
seconds
you know does does oakmod load dash no I
don't think so because by now oakmod is
part of emacs you don't you don't do you
don't you don't you don't dash the
okay so get rid of dash okay I'm telling
you get rid of the dash and actually you
know you are not me but if you are me if
any library if I'm using any library
that download dash I kick that library
out okay
if I'm if I need some library and I saw
that dash dash or one of the other
you know dash or the other fox this s
this s and this you know they
they they like to name this new
zoomers. You know, this is this is a
phenomen phenomenon of greedy because
they occupy the shortest name in a in a
in a library repository. What while the
name is not descriptive, you know, but
however it occupy a space just like
Twitter x.com, you know, it's like, you
know, standing out. So that means your
popular has better chance to become more
seen. you know this S
whoever wrote that I I I I kind of know
who who wrote all these but I forgot.
Okay, so you know this this S for
strings you know you know the longlost
you know and and also look at their
description the way the their
mentality okay
s package the longlost Emac string
manipulation library. Oh, it's long
lost. Who the are you? You know, so
it's long lost meaning that the
implication, you know, like there's
usually implications in phrases like the
black life matters. What that what does
it mean black life matters? You mean do
you mean it doesn't matter?
You have to think about it. There's
implications. So what does it mean? This
is a longlost Emac string manipulation
library. Oh. Oh, it seems to suggest
that Emacs doesn't have a dick. If you
need a dick, you need to use his
library. The Okay. Who Who
wrote this? I forgot. You know, I you
know, I I should uh
the same guy, the Magna, the same guy
who wrote Dash. Okay. And then but then
somebody else wrote uh the F. Okay. Look
at the description. modern API for
working with files and directory. What a
These are
This is another guy. Okay, this is you
see inspired by Magna Magna. Uh but who
is this
uh description badge code? What
no names? You see this no names
ass, you know. Let me make a
declaration. Okay. Uh uh what's it? what
is it called? Um meaning that you know I
don't I don't I'm not attacking many of
these people. Many of these people are
good people. Okay. Uh for example the M
Magna guy
I think he's a good guy.
Okay. But the way he named his library
he like pushes it. I find it
problematic. Okay. I don't like it. I
think he should not. Okay, do that.
Okay, that's my uh what's what's called
disclaimer. Okay, that's my disclaimer.
And I don't know who wrote the F, you
know, the F occupies a space, a
prominent space like F and but okay,
let's find out who wrote it.
But disclaimer, okay, Pontra. Okay. Oh,
this it's a great guy. Okay. He actually
contact me and uh you know like three
years ago he sent he showed me a photo
of his keyboard which I put on my
website with his permission. a good guy.
You know, you know, all these uh okay,
Johan Anderson, okay, all these are good
guys, but but the thing I'm bitching
about is this this this kind of naming,
this kind of like this kind of naming
and this kind of, you know, pedalling.
This this is called marketing. Okay,
this is called part of marketing. a
modern this library for Emacs a longlost
Emac string manipulation library and
modern API for working with files you
know I don't you know I don't like them
I find they are like um
they are called what's the proper name
for this kind of marketing they are
called
kind of aggressive but that's not a
proper term it's it's kind of like um It
infringes on it's, you know, it's not
exactly
unethical, you know, but it's kind of
like infringing on that. How do you, you
know, there must be a proper term to
describe this. This is common. Okay, for
example, you know, let's say, you know,
you're going to need you need to write a
library. You know, name it. Let me tell
you a tactic. You know, name it a the
letter A, capital A, okay? Okay. Or
lower case, you know, or name it Z. So
your package will stand out, you know,
whatever package you write. Conceive a
way to connect to A or Z. Okay.
And then in the description, you know,
they say the modern the modern API
something.
Okay, that is that concludes the rant.
Okay. Francis says, "You can't complain
that Emacs doesn't have modern features
in immediately making fun of anyone who
tries to make it more modern." Well, you
got a point. But like I said before,
like I said, I talked about this like
for an hour, you know, years ago, two,
you know, two years ago and before that.
The problem is the part of the problem
is the glue emac. Okay, they refuse to
change. What can you do?
you know it's very hard to get your
library accepted you know
so so like I said I don't blame these
people
you know to to having done this library
in fact dash is precisely because of
dash it became hugely popular you know
like 15 years ago that made the new
emacs to create the sequence library
Okay, Dash happened first hugely popular
then the GU Emacs the Richard Stoman you
know Richard Stoman is going to ask oh
what what is dash what is Malpa uh
please someone explain to me then they
explain to the to him what is smellpa
then then Richard Sman will ask uh can
someone why why is dash popular why is
it why why did didn't these people just
put the code you know sign the sign the
paper to glue Emacs Why are they you
know creating dash then people explain
to expl explain to him happens a few
times you know search for my article
you'll find it search on sardi.info info
search for Richard Stman. Okay. And I
did several videos about it too.
So the GU so so it is because of Dash
became hugely popular. Then after five
years the GNU Emacs people and Richard
Sman saw it then they started to oh we
need to do something
okay then they decided okay uh we need
to create our own functions. Okay. And
then the guy I forgot what's his name.
Okay, they created it. Okay, the
sequence function
sequence set Q. Okay, let's go to it.
And the guy's name is this guy, Nicholas
Patton.
He created this sequence library 2014.
Okay, you can check the year. Okay,
that's after that's like 5 years after
the Dash became hugely popular.
So, I don't blame the Dash guy.
The but but he's got a problem, you
know, the the the the community, the
Emacs, you know, there's some problem
going on. First first of all, it's very
hard to get your library to, you know,
to be part of Emacs. And part of that
problem is because of the richest
throwman and because the guag dev okay
they got some kind of they they are like
a commune like the the the Jesus Christ
uh we are the free software the you know
the heaven you know they they they kind
of got a the phenomenon like that okay
and they don't they don't they sneer
what the you are like if you if you
created Google they don't give a
okay they are like that the dev
So,
so Dash became popular. Gundv started
to, you know, then they wrote it then,
but Dash itself has kind of problems.
You know, the guy he he's a like a new
generation. He's like late Malay. So, he
began around 2010.
Uh not not not a bad guy. Okay. But I'm
but I'm saying that then you know I
don't like the way he
uh like the
you know is is kind of on the borderline
on the borderline of things. Okay. Like
modern you know like everything what
what what does modern means? modern.
Does that mean 1900s,
you know, like after 1800 is modern or
do you mean after 2020? You know, you
created this this like 15 years ago, my
Jesus, that you know, can you can can I
make a poor request? You should change
your name to Ascient. You know, in the
software industry after 15 years, you
call your library modern and everything
now is built in. You you call it modern
and the the and you don't and by the way
by oh by the way let me tell you
guys another thing about dash
you don't follow the new eac this coding
you know the formatting conventions you
are like going your way your own let's
go to see it
you know you guys got got me too random
about this because otherwise I'm done
for today you know like like they they
they don't follow
uh the naming comm conventions
of of GU Emacs. So they are like going
rebel, they are going maverick, you
know, they are hot shot.
So so let's go through the code. Um
so anyway, this all all these kind of
issues. Okay. I I don't like
but like I said, you know, it's not it's
not totally their fault and they did
good too.
You know, just my personal opinion.
So if you want to call your, you know,
API modern, you know, I'm free to
criticize the way you name your things.
It's a free country.
Okay, bye guys. Now, if you like my
stuff, donate, okay?
Go to kasardi.info.
Go to all the way to the bottom.
Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal me.
Okay.
And by the way, today I turned on
YouTube ads.
You know, I turned off for the past few
years, but today I'm I turned it on
again because I saw Wuam
Wuam research their video uh have ads in
it. And I was wondering, you know,
because Google has been so nasty. I'm
wondering, you know, if I turn off my
ad, if I turn back back on, maybe maybe
uh my video will be higher higher
ranked, you know, because because
there's money for them.
Kan, no read. Well, you guys typed too
much. Okay. And I talked about this uh
too many times. So, what do you mean no
read? I'm done. If you Yeah, I'm done
for the day. We already uh like 80
minutes.
Okay, bye guys.
Shut down in 1 minute.
Close that.
Emag this.
Copy. Close that
blog im close close. Uh what is this?
Oh, this is alternative. Okay, bye guys.