Hey guys, welcome to another episode of
Casan Talk Show. Welcome to another
episode of Casar Talk Show. We are going
to code geometry today. Geometry
animation. We are going to code what's
this called? Um hypocyclloid and
apocyclloid. So you see these curves,
these are rolling circles around another
circle. And uh let's just copy the code
and let's uh start with language. Let me
show you guys. So we just going to code
it. And uh if you are into mathematics,
geometry or if you are learning
calculus, you might find this
interesting. Uh otherwise it's probably
boring for you. Okay. Coding session uh
of wam language. Now let's magnify.
So here's a code. Shift control N to
make it type set. Fantastic. Okay. 150
is probably too large. 125. Okay. Now,
shift enter to run it. So, you got um
so it's plotting all these curves. These
are called epotcoid.
Okay. There there they are. Uh, and what
we going to do today is actually
generate animation of one of them called
asteroid. This one red. Okay, this one
four cusps
like asteroid star. Okay, we're going to
code that. So, if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed. If you are
watching live here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. Okay. Uh, so you are
looking at uh, you know, Wuang language.
Um, so by the way, let me do 2 minutes
intro. Okay. So, wufam language you just
search for it. You search for
you search for kasali download wam
engine kasali wuam programming language
wra language for programmers on my
website x a h.info.
Okay. Then you know you will find a
download link. You go there to download
it. It's free. It's like four or five
gigabytes. It's huge. Okay. Wam language
and then you you can download. Okay.
Then you can download just read my
articles. Okay. So my I got this website
wuam language for programmers. You you
got the download link then you can go to
uh difference between wam language wam
engine mathematica wam script. What are
they describe description then you go
there. Then you also want to download
the woofam research woof language for
Jupiter so that you get this graphical
user interface otherwise what you get is
a um comm command com command line
terminal okay so that's the introduction
to get wang language so let's uh let's
start just to do this okay so what I
want to do today is this one okay so
yeah do do we have enough intro yeah so
I want to do the asteroid. Okay. So, let
me go to it. So, and also this is my
website. Search for visual dictionary of
spatial plane curves. You'll find my
website kari.info there. X a h le e.
Okay. Uh and my website haven't been
updated for the past 20 days because
there are some issues but that will be
fixed soon. So anyway, you go to my
website then you go down. So we going to
do today this one. Okay. So we going to
generate this. We're going to write code
for this one. Rolling a circle around
another circle. The smaller circle is
1/4
the size of the larger circle by radius.
Then the you know if you put a point on
the rim of the circle you'll trace out
this curve. It's called asteroid.
Asteroid. And it is a special case of
what's called hypotcoid. So you see all
these are hypotrocoid. This kind of
curve in the toy market is known as
spiral graph. Okay? Because they market
that toy about 50 years ago.
Um anyway so we're going to gener we
going to uh code this animation. So we
this this is about woofam language uh
doing creating a animation and what
effective what that means what
effectively you need to learn is that
you're going to draw a graph you're
going to draw a list of graphics. So
you're going to draw a sequence of
graphics then you can then then then it
became animation because animation is
just a list of uh images. Okay. Uh, and
the key to know is that you want to draw
a circle, then you want to draw a
smaller circle, and you want to know at
each graphics where to position the
circle and where to position the dot.
That's that's the essence of what you
need to know to create this animation.
Okay, so that's intro. So, let me just
drink some
juice. This is uh this is like guava
juice. Fantastic.
And this is red wine. Fantastic.
Okay. So, let's see. Let's begin. Okay.
Let's begin to do that. So, close that.
So, I want to copy the link to today's
talk show. Uh, paste the link there.
Linkify. So, asteroid. Okay, asteroid
and we so show in browser. So we go to
asteroid. We want to generate this code.
I already have the package. Now if you
don't know, just search for
wolf package.
Okay, GitHub. Kasali wam package. You
know, you can actually go to either one
of these. I got several packages on
GitHub. So So GitHub uh kar wu mode. go
to my homepage on GitHub and plank curve
plank curve generator. So there so the
this package that's for wam language
turn on JavaScript
you can find the code for this asteroid
so for that and for that it's already
done so you can just grab the code
from this GitHub plank curve generator
okay but what I want to do is to extract
it and update the code because those
code are written like almost unchanged
from 199 1997,
30 years ago. So, we're going to update
it, refresh it. I show I'm going to show
you how to do it. Okay. So, let's just
go to my git, search for generate um
blink of generator. That's a package.
And uh let's delete
delete the Emacs backup. Okay. Delete
and refresh. Okay. Now, uh now let's uh
those are images. Okay. Open. Next.
Next. Next. Next. Next.
Uh, we did this yesterday. Uh, was it?
Uh, we did this um well, we did Yeah, we
did that yesterday or two days ago.
Okay. So, the one we want is uh go
there.
Search for asteroid. Okay. So, let me
just do it. Let me show you the code in
a in a moment. Okay. non asteroid. So
search WL WL is the file name extension
for Wam language.
Um
okay, that's a bunch of examples of wam
language.
Okay, that's the one we want. And so
search for
Okay.
Search search search.
Okay. It's um
it's actually
here. Okay. It's defined in terms of
this function hypotcoid. Okay. So, we
just going to copy that. Hold on a
second.
So, we go we we going to go to um
envelope. We going to create a code
here. Okay.
I put Yeah.
Yeah, we're going to co create Wuan
language code here.
Um, yeah. And, uh, so, so syntax, go to
the browser, refresh. You can see we
started to have the code there. And the
code is going to be, uh, of course, not
just that, but um,
let's go back to the package. because
that
uh
yeah here we want to know this the code
is actually that
okay there
okay so it's uh
okay so there okay now we don't need
that anymore. Let's go back. Go back to
our code here. Okay,
put it back. Syntax code showing browser
asteroid page. Go down. Go down there.
Rolling a circle there. Here's a code.
Okay, now will that code run? Yes, of
course. Uh but we want to improve it.
But before we do, let me just show you.
Let's just run it. Okay.
Uh so it's the code is independent. So
any person see this code they can just
copy it and run it in wam language.
Okay. So let's select all paste shift
control n to show type set. You see
fantastic type setting with automatic
line
uh management. So you don't like
formatting code formatting. You can see
there's a indentation there is line wrap
automatically. You see it it's
controlled automatically.
Okay. Now shift enter to run it. So it's
done. It's done. All you have to do is
just actual code call
the function. So that's the function
name. Shift enter.
No, it didn't work. Why? Because uh oh
uh wait
astro generator uh two
not three. What
was it? Two or three? So
two. Okay. So why I copied it wrong
before? Why do we have three there? Two.
Shift enter.
So there it is. It generated a bunch of
images. And now go all the way down. So
each one of this is image. You can
export those graphics. Now what we want
to do is that but we want to animate
this list of images. So you just say
list animate. Okay. Add shift enter.
There it is. There it is.
Okay, fantastic. We got a code. Now the
job now is to
optimize the code. Okay, so now it's
about very technical details of Wufam
language. How do you
um like coding wam language coding very
technical details. Okay. And so if you
uh we already explained how to generate
this image like all you have to do is
like you you need to know at each frame
like the mathematically you need to know
at each frame where is the position of
the circle and uh where is the position
of the dot. You just draw the dot in the
circle.
Um,
okay. But how do you do that in Wuen
language? Okay, that's what we're going
to dive into. And so it's going to be
from now on it's going to be very
technical. Uh, you guys, you know, so if
you are still interested, you can keep
watching. Okay.
Okay. So um, so this is like okay very
technical wam language stuff. So let me
just do that. So asteroid version two.
So why did did we get this three?
shouldn't be there. Okay, that's a
mistake.
No. Um,
do that make sense? That make sense?
That make sense? Anyone? A everyone.
Okay. Astro in. Okay. So there's a
astrogenerator tool.
I see. So there is uh
okay. So
two and what is uh what is the one? I
forgot. What is the one?
Let's just let's just um
let's just code it.
Yeah. Okay. Let's create a new
window.
What the
Okay. The first one that is the treml of
Archimedes.
So we don't want that. Okay.
We don't we don't want the
tremor of alimedes. Okay, that's the
first one. The second one animation is
uh special case of hypotrocoid. Okay,
that's what we want. And the third one
generates animation that trace the curve
astro showing that is the envelope of
coaxial axis. Okay, that we don't care.
We did that yesterday. Uh so the we just
want the second one. So do we have like
this
inline documentation there? No. So,
so this let's rename the function
because I don't want it um
you know because this hypotcoal
generator it is a special case the
asteroid now remember this asteroid this
curve we are doing asteroid it is a
special case of the hypotcoid
you see so hypotcoid means you roll a
circle circle inside a circle. They they
are all generated by rolling a circle
inside a circle. Okay, the curve they
create is all called hypotracoy.
So the asteroid is just a special case
of hypotcoid.
So
now we don't need um you know we we
don't want actually um
like we don't need um
let's just delete this um
so actually this is what you want. Okay.
So delete that generator search um
delete that. Okay. So let's just improve
the code. That's what we're doing. So,
um,
let's say let's rename it
animate. Okay, let's re rename it
hypotco animate.
Okay, that's our new name. Okay. And uh
and okay, hold on a second. Then this
options, we don't want that because we
are not writing a package. So So we
don't want the options. Let's just
remove. So this this options is how you
define optional parameters.
Okay. Delete that.
Now we uh just going to Okay,
we just going to uh Yeah. So this is a
parameter and this is suppose this is 0
to 2 pi
in in steps of um
in steps of
2 pi divided by 80. Okay,
that will create 81 frames basically.
Delete that. Delete that. Okay, so this
this is a function actually you want to
write. Okay, there
clear. So let's start to so
clear that symbol name. We start fresh
in case you know it's already defined or
in case we need to re-evaluate it. Am I
doing good? Say hi. Okay, you know if
you enjoyed watching this, you know,
thumb up my videos. Show it to your
friends. Okay, because I don't do
dramatic So if you like my stuff,
show it to your friends and thumb up.
Okay. So, so we got the we writing again
wam language code. Okay.
A little drink
red wine.
Let's finish it
again. The good code the goal is to have
independent code. So it's going to be
just 50 lines actually for like 40 lines
of code. So people can directly copy
from the website you know like copy and
paste in Wuam language or or wam alpha.
It will generate a code. You don't need
to look for like where do I download the
package? How do you install the package
in the wuam language init directory?
where is the init directory things like
that you know like or Python like how do
you install a py uh you know package in
Python or JavaScript do you need mpm you
don't need all that just copy the code
paste it run it it'll work okay because
the code is not too complicated like 30
lines um it ops okay so I'm so that's
what we are doing writing this animation
and uh I'm doing uh going through them
with explanation. Okay. So, so first of
all, this module you don't want uh you
want just block. Okay. If you don't know
what that is, search for my website
kardi.info
um sard wra
programming
local variable. You'll find the page
that explains the difference between
module block and width. Okay.
So we should use block. Okay. Okay. Let
me let me just code it because if I keep
explaining explanation this will never
finish. I let me code it for 10 minutes
and then we can explain.
So you so this is a definition of a
function by a pattern. So hypotcoal
animate. So you need okay. So then you
need a documentation because what are
the parameters? So we did we do need the
documentation for the hypot.
Okay. So
yeah. So you Yeah. Okay. So it's pretty
copy that.
Okay.
Uh did that. Go back here. You kind of
need the documentation there
and uh
okay documentation that that that
uh hypotcoid okay so
well okay so one of them is optional
okay so let's just say that generates an
animation that uh generate a
list of graphics that trace out
hypotcoid by means of roulette by means
of roulette of two circles. Now that's
two
uh verbose and technical. Let's just say
by means of by by rolling a circle
inside another. Okay, this is more more
practical wording you know be before
that it's you know if you say roulette
of two circles that's more academic so I
don't I don't want that anymore
because
you know the society moves on it tends
to be less formal like you don't you
don't need those jargon words you know
rolling two circles is perfectly precise
and clear rolling a circle inside
another okay I mean it's clear enough so
so so that that is that that function
does that okay so actually
uh you should okay so actually delete
that okay because we renamed it
uh okay so there is more here
now okay so um charcoal animate. So this
is this generate a list of graphics that
trace our hypotcoid by rolling this is
lowerase hypot by rolling a circle
inside another. Okay. Then you can say
you can give a uh option of tmin to
t-max and t-step
uh
start
and stop at the range t min t map tep.
Okay. So that is optional.
Now uh now okay. So now actually so you
need so here are the parameters. A is
the radius of the fixed circle.
B is the radius of the rolling circle.
Okay. A greater than b.
Okay. Actually a could be uh less than
b. a greater than b. A could be less
than b.
Uh h is a distance from the tracing
point to the center of the circle. Okay,
that's important. Let's put that there.
special options are number of frames.
No, we don't want that anymore. So you
see we used to have a option um
because when you are writing a package
it's nice to have like a option like
more formal you know like every function
has options but if you are just you know
writing a code directly um you don't
want the options
you know you you that would be just
controlled by the steps here. Okay. So
if you want num you know number of
frames is controlled basically by the
step they are the same thing but but
using different ways to express it
hello from Iceland oh hi don't matter
name don't matter are you Iceland are
you mart by chance I don't think you are
mavvert
is our friend from Iceland
on our discord but I guess you are
Um, hello. So,
are you starting to learn Woof language?
Have you ever used it before? Okay. So,
let's let's go back to this. Um,
okay. Start stop. Uh, so so right now we
are doing the inline documentation for
this and also we are like
actually designing the function
parameters.
I'm a different mukver. Okay, that's
cool. Cool. Okay, so
Okay, delete that. And other options are
passed to graphics. No, we don't want to
do that anymore. Okay, control the
number of rotations. Uh,
okay. Yes, that's that's the number of
rotations. Um, it's should I mention
that here? Yeah.
Okay. Uh
if not specified an internal algorithm
will figure out the number of rotations
so that the curve is closed.
Oh that's w that's extra touch.
You see this this is actually
significant. So
I wrote an algorithm that you need to
determine
like you are given a radius of the large
circle and given the radius of the small
smaller circle. You can assume the
larger circle has radius one. Okay. So
the smaller circle is a fraction you
know or I mean it could be actually not
a real number but I mean if if the small
the radius of the smaller circle is not
a real number then I think the the curve
never repeat it never repeats. Okay, I
think you know you need you need to
prove but I I'm pretty sure. Okay, but
anyway, so
so but if your smaller circles radius is
a fraction of the larger one, then you
can determine
how many like what's the range like t
min like how many rotations it needs to
go before it repeats. Okay. So you there
is that um magic number. So where did I
say you know? So in my code it's encoded
somewhere. Okay. I don't remember.
So anyway that's a okay. So that's
that's a nice uh thing.
Okay. So those remove that because we
don't need the number of frames thing.
Okay. And also you you have this
situation
uh zero you know t mean greater than
zero t max greater than t min less than
infinity. Okay. Then you got the
example.
Well no we don't want this. We don't we
no longer want number of frames. Okay.
So
uh so that's kind of a example. Okay. So
this comment up
okay it's kind of tedious so far. So so
you see this is a usage inline inline
documentations inline documentation
string. Okay. And here are two examples
of actually calling it this. The first
one this creates a asteroid. Okay. The
second one creates you know one and two
over five. I'm I'm not sure some you
know some some other um thing. So now we
are you know now now we we understand
the parameters now we are coding. Okay.
So
so what you want to do first of all let
me let me uh write a few things. Okay. I
want to clear up the parameters. So let
me just show you so that
okay so first of all uh wait
okay first of all if there is no
parameters um
well what what happens if there's no
parameters
if there is no parameter You could say
one and uh let's say
okay one over four okay one uh one over
four then that is zero okay so if there
is no parameters let's let's just draw
the asteroid okay
now if so then
then you need to give a parameter,
right? Then you that then um
that would equals to Oh god, how do you
do this?
Um,
okay. This is more difficult than I
imagined
because
I was imagining I can just explain this
and we'll have the code and we'll you
know we are done in in 30 minutes but
actually
now but now I run into a situation that
that you see I I haven't explained this
part um
Okay, the the options uh the options we
don't need. Okay,
because we don't want options. So you so
you first of all you need to think about
what do you need want to do. So what we
want to think about right now is what
kind of forms of this function accept.
Okay, so if there's no argument that's
one form we accept. Then we we just make
it
uh do the asteroid the you know we just
assume the default parameter. Okay.
Then we also can have this form right?
Yeah. And what but what else is here
some other well there's you see you see
this function.
Okay. It does require two
parameters. Okay. Well, kind of. So, the
first parameter is required because it
specifies the size of the circles and
the distance from the
from the tracing point to the center of
the circle on the rolling circle. Okay.
So, the first parameter is required. But
in fact you can reduce the two circles
into just one radius to to their
fraction like you you can re you know
reduce them to a fraction anyway. So
that's the first parameter. What about
the second parameter? The second
parameter is um
they basically control the starting
frame and ending frame of the rolling
circle. Right?
And then the the third argument I mean
the third part is the number of the
steps okay how how much steps you do
each time.
So the steps can be
omitted if
um if you see if the radius ratio is a
is a rational number otherwise because
if you know it's getting complicated if
the ratio of two circles is rational
number then you can figure out
you then you can figure out actually the
the start and the the max, you know, the
range.
You can figure that out. And okay, the
step you can always figure out the step
you like always just generate 80 of
them. Actually, no. It depends on how
many, you know, like some of these needs
a lot of steps to be smooth. Okay. Do
you guys know what I'm doing? Um, am I
like getting too complicated? Because
some of these
parameters let's see where is today. So
we did this today. Let's see uh that you
see now better picture. You see some of
these for example let's say that one
that one takes a lot of turns you know
three four like it could be like you
have to turn make 100 turns. So even a
thousand turns. Okay. So some of these
parameters really requires you make a
thousand turns. And for those that
requires a thousand turns the number of
steps needs to be very small like 0.1.
So effectively if you want a smooth
animation you going to have an animation
with you know
1,00 frames. Okay. Now for the simple
one like the asteroid you know you just
you you just need 40 frames. That's
smooth. But for for for some of these
potentially you can have like 10,000 you
need 10,000 frames because they need to
turn you know
uh like uh like 10,000 uh rounds.
Okay. So so right now we are thinking
about this parameter you know part
beginning is easy we can always start at
zero. Now the t-max the maximum where do
you when do you stop that needs to be
figured out. Okay. So you can give a
value
it won't work because for all these
cases if you just say 0 to 2 pi they
don't draw nothing you know they just
stop right away you know like you don't
you don't get a curve you don't you
don't get this you know pretty curve you
just you just get like a a stroke.
So
well anyways the the the tax can be
figure out figured out if the radius I
mean if if the ratio of the circles
radius uh fraction is a fraction. Okay
then steps can always be figured out.
Okay. So what we need to think about now
is about the design of this function
like like what do you do you require
the second parameter? That's the
question.
Uh
you see if you do not require the second
parameter meaning that
people can omitt it then you need to
figure out what is the second parameter
but
you can't do that well
okay you run into a lot of issues what
one of them is that if the ra if the
ratio is a real number not a fraction
Then basically
you just have to like create a magic
number when to stop because it never
repeats. Okay, the that's one issue.
When the ratio of the two circles radius
is not a rational number, you have to
magically figure out when to stop. Okay,
that's one issue. The other issue is
that
when you have a situation where you know
you have to figure out how how how many
turns they stop okay when that is large
you see I don't think you want the
function to automatically generate
like two billion frames you know because
your your wuam language is going to
crash
So when when so you have to say like
some kind of maximum number of frames
um
even though it doesn't complete like
when you have this complicated case.
Okay.
Okay. So when you design this you you
you came upon these issues.
Do I make sense?
Do I make sense? Uh you guys like some
of you are know what I'm talking about.
Uh name says, "Enjoying the stream.
Thanks. Geometry visualization is really
cool." Thank you. Hi. Um
hi uh Mechi.
Okay, we we kind of got a issue here.
But let's see what I did 30 years ago
because 30 years ago because usually I
think a lot. So 30 years ago let's see
what we did.
So it will automatically
you see the so okay so indeed it
automatically generate the T minax
the optional list T minstep control
number of rotations if not specified an
internal algorithm will figure out the
number of rotations so that the curve is
closed
right
but
But if you see the ratio of the radius
is not a rational number. You cannot the
curve is not closed.
So what do you do in that situation? The
documentation didn't say okay that's a
flow.
Okay. So now let's look at the code.
Okay. Now let's you know we haven't
decided what what are the um parameters
yet. So that's so it's a bit um
you know we haven't decided what to do
there. So let's comment up
but what we
okay so let's comment out so let's look
at the code what we actually do so if t
range um let's see
so if t r range is not given
then we
okay Okay. So,
this is interesting. Um,
I think you know this is not good
because I talked for 10 minutes on very
technical details. I I don't think
people are interested
and we haven't actually talked about the
more interesting stuff of of stuff of
how do you actually find figure out
that's what people want to know. How do
you figure out at at at any time where
are where is a circle? Okay, so
you know like at given moment where is a
circle and where's a dot. So those are
in this um you know people want to know
where is the code. So anyway
the formula for for this hypotco curve
uh this cosine sign. Okay. But the the
part where you figure out which position
it is is um
is this one. Okay. Okay. Well,
you guys don't know what I'm doing
because
if you are not familiar with Wolfam
language, then you don't know. So,
okay. So, what we going to do here?
Well,
yeah. So, what are we doing? So, you
need to simplify the code. Okay. Um
yeah so previously we assumed
so if we assume this is optional so you
see if this is optional so if it's if we
get automatic that means
by default
if we get that default then um then what
we do is you get the number.
Oh, okay.
Zero to rationalize. Okay. So, you just
force it into a rational number. That's
what I that's what we did. You see?
So what happens when the ra uh when the
ratio of the
circles radiuses
uh is not a rational number
because that is a if that's the case the
the the curve will never repeat. Well if
that's the case you just force it into a
rational number like closest rational
number. That's what I did here.
Very good. Okay. Um,
yeah. So, you see that's that's what we
did here. That's the code. Um,
yeah. Okay. So, that's one thing. So,
this this block deals with
deal with when this
two and you know beginning and you know
start and stop and steps is optional.
Okay. So,
how you guys doing? So, I actually I'm
thinking of stopping. How long have I
been talking? 45 minutes. Okay. Should I
continue? Actually, I should I should
continue
until I have like, you know, complete
code so I can paste it, people can use
it. I should. Yeah. Okay. Let's
continue. Okay. So let's quickly let's
continue on that. Okay, that's what we
Okay. Okay.
So t min Okay. So let let's focus let's
go back to the design of the function
parameters. Okay. So what I used to have
is this thing. Okay. So this is what I
used to have. Now let's let's redesign
to be simpler because
so when there's no parameter just do
that. When this that parameter do that
then um
wait when when there's that parameter
what you want to do is
um
yeah so actually here.
Can we actually bring it here like that?
Uh
t min is always just zero. Okay, so
forget about t min. T min is always just
zero. So forget about that. Forget about
region. Let me just fix the code
quickly. Okay. Uh what does this now?
Okay. So t min is just always zero and t
max is going to be
Fascinating. Rationalize times 2 pi.
Fascinating.
Okay.
And the t-step is what is tep? T-step is
t max and minus t mean. Okay.
So,
and so actually you need the a there for
this to work.
Okay. So, you need quite you need a few
things. Um,
okay. So,
Okay. So you just need to define
these three values. Okay. T minstep.
You need to define them. And we can do
that by
T min is simply zero. Okay.
And T-max is like um
do I make sense? Is it good?
T-max is like that. Okay.
T min is like zero. T-max is like
actually you need to take
um
rationalized b you need to take um
numerator rationalized b
you need to take I think you need to
take consideration of a you are missing
a here so maybe it's like that okay do
you guys know what I mean um maybe you
don't so going to bed. Tune in next
time. My first time seeing Wolf, but
very interesting. Thank you. Good night.
Good night.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, we continue to to do this.
Yes. Okay. Then, uh then you got teps.
Let's say t steps equals to
um tep equals to the numerical code
value of
okay let's forget about numeric code for
now okay so
that um
okay so number of frames we don't need
that we don't have that values anymore
So t-step is just by default is um what
is the default number of frames? 41.
Okay, let's just say 40. Okay.
Uh yeah, we don't we don't have the
number of frames anymore
because we don't want it.
Okay.
Okay. So number of frames 41. So teps is
just uh divided by 41
which actually creates 42 number of
frames.
Wait.
[snorts]
Okay. So anyway, so let's just do that.
Do that. Okay.
So
Don't do that. That that that.
What is that?
Okay, that's what this will do. Okay,
wait. It's already there.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's already here. So, one A, B,
and H. Okay.
So, so this you see that defines
so if you
don't give the second argument then it
will actually create the second argument
like like here you just call this this
okay so this this part delete okay so
you see if no if you do not give any
argument then you will call that
If but if you only give one the you know
the this argument then it will
it will create t minep
okay and uh t min is always zero okay so
you don't need t min t min is always
like zero okay then t- max is
numerical b actually let's remove that b
/ a
uh then the numerator then times 2 pi
hopefully I think that's that then tep
is t max
divided by uh t-max now be careful the
capital letter so we are using lower
case so tmax just t-max divided by 41
okay so actually you don't need that
because now
uh because it's just there t-max so you
don't need that parameter anymore
t-max is just that okay you only need
one
uh local variable in that case just put
it there okay in that case you know it's
just just that
okay one local variable t-max X T max is
defined by B / A and rationalize and
then then times 2 pi then take the
numerator. Um
yeah that's how many number of turns you
want. Okay. Kind of
then then you just call so after the
block of code. Yeah. Then you just call
this
T mean zero T- max is is T max and then
the steps is T- max over 4 O1.
Okay.
After 20 minutes, we did that one. We're
trying to simplify the code. Okay. Now,
now, now here, now the full code here.
Let's highlight the ops. Okay. Now, we
got too many highlights.
Action patterns. Um,
option. You don't know. You guys don't
know what I'm doing, but just let me do
it. Okay. Remove that. And the options.
Uh, yeah, it occurs there. So, delete
it. Okay. Now, go to the options. You
don't go to the options. You don't want
this anymore.
Okay. So, delete, delete, delete. Okay.
We remove that option. And then we got
this number of frames. Let's also remove
it. Okay. But before you see, we were
defining the T-min teps. Now, we don't
need that. We don't need this block of
code anymore.
Delete. And
now um
you see now hold on a second. So tmax.
So number of frames. Let's remove the
number of frames variable. So you see
there's a local variable
n of frames. Let's see if it's still
somewhere. No. So delete that. Okay. and
the t minax is also no longer needed.
So, so this second parameter is no
longer needed.
Okay. So,
well actually it is needed. So, we so
let's uh modify that. So, it's going to
be it's going to be let me show you.
Okay. Uh
Okay. So instead of that now it's going
to become like that. So except we need
uh these matches. So these are patterns.
That means a pattern of a list of three
things. Each thing can be anything
that's the that's a low line.
And we name each one by the first one is
we name it T min when it matches. The
second one we we name it T-max. The
third one we name it T step. So so this
again it's a list of three things. It's
a pattern. Okay. And each element we
name it when it matches. Okay. So we
don't need this you know. So but but
this part originally this this part
means
means this is this is one thing it's a
pattern okay it's a pattern
of anything it could be any it will
match any item
uh except the item must be a list. The
item must have the head list. Okay. So
this part means it will match anything
but it must be a list. And then we name
it T range. Okay.
But and and also this part will also
match zero item if there's no item. In
that case it will return
it will provide this list of one value
automatic symbol. Okay that's what this
means. So but anyway so now we just
delete that make it simpler. We made it
into this form. Okay. So now when when
whenever you see this pattern you know
hypotcoal animate a list three things
and another another list of three things
what you do is then you do this uh this
this this okay um okay we are still in
the process of simplifying the code we
are making a lot of progress make a
backup uh so let me code again so this
is the deep wam language coding okay So
t-minax
do we have tmin? So uh before we do
anything
let me put the code back syntax color
showing browser. So we are looking back
at the page asteroid
this animation that's a code we are
writing and here's a code. Okay that's
we are currently working on okay so this
code let's pop it out again. Make a
backup. Pop it out. Okay. So, we clear
the symbol. Then we define the usage.
Make it clear to people what it's
actually doing. Great.
Then uh let's shrink it. Um well
uh then we have this. This is like this
is uh uh case for asteroid. Okay. And uh
and what about this one? This is uh some
hype.
We don't know what this look shows.
Okay, we don't know what it looks like,
but so those uh let's move it to the
bottom. Okay, let's move it to the
bottom so that those are actual
examples. Okay, now go back to our code.
Now go back to defining our code. So
when there's no argument uh then just do
that. Okay. When there is one parameter
then you do you do that. Okay. So
yeah.
Okay. then then otherwise normally it
should take two parameters like this.
Okay. Um wait let me define another one.
So if there is two parameters but the
second one only has two values then you
do it like um
hold on a second let me show you. Okay,
then you do it like t max
minus t min
divided by 41.
Okay.
So if user gives two arguments but the
second argument only has two items then
you automatically transform it into the
second argument going to have three
items like that. Okay. Then
then the final like the most general the
form. So when when this pattern is found
then we do this. Okay. Uh we want to do
so let's now let's look at the code.
Okay. So now
comma comma space change that for easy
reading. Okay. Uh
uh.
Okay. And uh let's highlight the
keywords. Okay. Just
highlight the keywords. Okay. Then
you need a margin. You see? So what is
margin used for? Margin is for Yeah.
When you actually finally plot, you want
a little
room
outside of the circle so that um
so that it looks nice. Okay, that's what
this margin is is.
Um
and uh this can be simplified. Let me
just show you. So
replace module by just one one two three
four uh let's say three run it
yeah so that you see so this module mod
so this part this part can be simplified
as
Um,
just multiply that. Okay. Yeah, let's do
that.
Okay. So, yeah. So, simplify the code.
Okay. So, we are close. We are close.
Okay. So, you got the margin.
Uh
then you got Okay. Margin is kind of
just a value. Now, HB.
So here is T-max T min and here you
don't need to compile. Okay, compile is
like
I don't think you want to uh you know so
this code is written 30 years ago. Do I
should I still use compile?
You can look at woof language creates a
compiled function that evaluates
expression assuming numerical values.
Okay,
you see uh basically the purpose of this
compile is just to make
it's just to make evaluating this
expression uh faster basically this s
cosine
but today I don't think you need it
you see because
if you use it then it can gets
complicated did.
Okay. So, actually that's, you know, um
let's not use compile. Do I still make
sense? Um
so, this is like a function. Okay. So
this is a function.
Let's see.
Yeah, that kind of creates a numerical
code function. We can leave it.
What?
So here you basically
basically you are doing
Okay. So, well, so what you're doing is
that
Um, and this curve function. No, let's
see.
And we color it. Yeah, you just need
one. Okay, you don't need two. So, this
color function make them one.
You can just say power
uh you know and uh let's not
compile
Okay. And uh function of x. Yes, that's
a function of x. Okay. So
Okay. So that's your parameters that's
your actual the function what the
function actually do okay and uh you can
you you don't need um
those are small numbers you don't need
compile okay so you just need to
uh power function is a function okay
function
Okay, a function of of one single value
t. Okay.
And in fact, you can just remove t by uh
that.
Okay. That's uh like
so this defines a function. Okay. This
defines a function. This function is
just two um
a single variable but returns a vector.
Okay. So you don't then you don't need
this uh compile xy. Okay. Delete delete.
Okay. Then you delete delete. Okay. You
now you simplify a simple function. Then
this uh then you need actually put that
there. That's your function
uh power function. Um then your function
needs to be mapped here. So your
function is point
paraffen
um
wait
Wait, that's duplicate.
Okay. So
function.
So what did the point? So each one is a
point.
Okay, I think I think that will do. Do I
make sense? Is anyone still watching me
like uh understand wam language coding?
Okay, not many. So anyway, so Oh god. So
thinking about this live stream I've
been doing for 70 minutes. Oh god,
coding takes some time.
Okay, that's true.
So this will generate a bunch of list
and uh can we actually just run it? No,
instead of thinking about Oh god. Then
you got the center. Why do you need a
center?
Okay, you need the center because
then the last frame you kind of don't
need.
Uh
yeah. So you see so we got lots of
things going on. We But will the code
run? I'm pretty sure it will. Okay,
let's copy the code. Let's just try to
run it. Okay. So we you see before it
was like that. Fantastic. Now copy all.
Now um
select select all paste it.
Okay. You got some issues. You see those
red?
Yeah those red that means you got a
problem. Wam language notebook is great.
It helps because now you see um you got
a problem because the red uh oh you got
you got
you got more than one problem. You see
the red is already the pattern. So you
don't need inside the you don't they are
not local variables. You see they are
already part of the pattern named
pattern. Okay. And also this equal sign
is incorrect. That should be just that.
Okay.
Yeah. So copy all
uh let's see try one more time. So that
is that that is that is that and uh then
that is that let's make it let's now
make it one line. Okay. Now copy all,
select all, paste.
Now will it run? If I run this, will it
create animation?
Possibly it will. Okay, I'm pretty sure
it just um
Let's just try it. Okay.
Okay, we got an error.
You see you see you see the you see the
circle seems to run but the dots is not
working. You see the circle is running
they are turning they are turning they
are turning but you are missing the
dots.
Okay. So we can fix that by point list.
So you see
this. Okay. So the point we got it
wrong. Yeah. So, okay.
I'm not sure why.
Let's do it again. Shift, enter.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
Fantastic and beautiful. You see we
cleaned we cleaned up the code and now
we are doing it correctly. Okay. Now,
okay. So, fantastic. Now, hold on a
second. Now, let's just uh list anime
at
that and
and copy or select or paste. You just
show animations.
So the first one is asteroid. We are
familiar with it works fantastic and
beautiful. And now we we have improved
the code. The second one is this. You
see this now here is more interesting.
You see now you cannot quite see what
the curve is because there are not
enough
um there are not enough frames. Okay. So
this is when you need to okay we run
into a issue. You see if you say 80
frame
you see you can't just say that. If you
say that then it won't it won't um
it won't create enough
turn. You see now it's nice but it
stopped. You see? So we got a design
actually. So we got a problem in our
function design. You see, you can't just
because,
you know, you need
you need a program to figure out how
many turns
it'll make to complete the curve.
So,
so if you omit the second parameter, if
you omit the second parameter, it will
figure out how many turns to do that.
However, but then you don't have the uh
number of frames. You see?
So, but if you
automatically
have a default value for number of
frames such that each turn has 40
frames. So, if you're going to if you
make five turns that's going to be five
time 40 uh 200 frames, right?
But if you do that then the problem is
for some of these parameters let's say 2
over 91 it's going to make you has it
has to make 91 turns then 91 turns times
40 frames you're going to have
two thou uh uh 90 * 41
right think of you know you uh you're
going to have like few thousand frames.
So that's kind of problem. So that means
so the issue is like
the issue is like about figuring
figuring out the automatic parameters
the default values like like it's about
the dis
design of the function. Uh that's a
headache because
ideally you don't want a separate option
that says how many number of frames.
Anyway, we we we got a code. Okay, so we
got a code pretty pretty good. Uh let's
put it back. Syntax correct show in
browser. So
you know when when my website is fixed,
you go to si.info info special plan
curves visual dictionary of special plan
curves search for it you'll find
asteroid you got this animation then you
got this code you can just copy
um you know so that's what we did uh but
we didn't but we need to make a backup
we need to uh work more on this so this
is not the final code but I think that's
it for today
Um,
Melchi says, "Have to go to bed." Okay.
Uh, now,
okay. Good night.
Okay. I think that's it. Um, yeah. So,
we um
Yeah. So, how long have it? So, it's 80
minutes coding. Okay. 80 minutes coding.
It's pretty good.
Um
the thing is that we have to figure out
you know quite a few things to figure
out. Um so it's pretty good and the code
is not the best yet actually. There's
quite there's quite a few things we need
to do.
Um,
and yeah, there's quite a few things.
Okay. Why is this range list? Do we need
it? Okay, we kind of do.
Uh
okay. So,
so we got a code but we haven't gone
through it completely yet. There is
improvements to do.
Okay. And uh
but so far so good.
Uh yeah and we need to figure out the
automatic parameters. Okay.
Do you guys know what I'm saying? It's a
bit complicated.
This is about designing of the functions
API, the functions
parameters
such that
the user do not have to figure out, you
know, it it should be
it should be able to automatically
figure out how many turns this this
thing needs to do and also automatically
figure out how many number of frames
yet
yet it's not so like overwhelming. It's
not like thousands of frames
but also you don't want a situation like
this right this right now. I mean so
this one for example it did you know it
figure out how many turns and frames but
the the the frame number is not enough.
Okay. So maybe what we can do is that
make the friend number by default I mean
compute it like how many you need then
put a maximum limit. Yeah that's what
you should
you know like the maximum number of
frames is 400 let's say we can actually
code that.
So we can code that by like right here.
So,
so if you know, so t-max t um yeah, so
actually the it's about this t-step.
So that would be here. So there so t-max
divided by 41. No, you need to um so
let's actually we can fix this. Okay,
so what you want to do is
t-max. Okay. Then t-step.
Okay. Now
tep you can say
that. Okay. That's what we have right
now. TEP is just equals to that. But
that creates a problem because for some
of them such as this the number of steps
is too not is not small enough because
it's not
enough number of frames.
So what you want is
uh
wait tmax. So that's how many number of
turns. Okay. No. So let's define another
uh
x turns equals to
something. Okay like that x turns equals
to that
then t max = to
x turns * 2 pi. Okay.
Uh so that's number of turns you need
and this is tmax. So step will be equals
to
yeah step will be equals to
let's say t max
um what what is it
divided by 41
divided by
number of turns times 41.
Okay, fantastic.
You see, can you guys see what I'm
doing? Like, does it make sense? Lots of
technical details. You see, so this
would be perfect. So if given if the
user doesn't say how many you know
start and end points then you figure it
out by comput computing the number of
turns then computing
the t-max would be 2 pi times number of
turns right then the step would be
t max
divided by tons times 41 that's right So
for each turn you want 41 number of
frames something like that
and wait but if it's over a thousand
then don't do that. So you want to say
max of
Okay. M maximum of Yeah. maximum of
either
that or let's say uh
400.
Okay. You don't want that too many.
Okay. So that see
fantastic. So copy all.
Now go here. Select or paste. Shift
enter. Let's see. Will it do it?
You see the trick is the second one.
Let's play it now. Is it
Wait. Oh Okay. We No, we didn't do
it correctly.
Oh, the you you don't want max. You want
the min
the minimum of
Oh, wait. So, actually, so
divided by
the max
Okay, I think that divided by
right. Okay, copy that. Select all
paste. Shift enter.
Okay, that one we already know. Now the
second one. Oh god, the second one is
not showing. No good. Oh, it's
still computing. What?
Okay. Now, is it using too much memory?
Looks like it's froze.
Oh, there it is. Fantastic and
beautiful. Can you see? We fixed that.
Fantastic and beautiful. Automatically
figured it out.
Perfect.
So 400 is too many frames. Okay, let we
don't want 400. Let's say 200
automatically figure it out. And also
also we want a numerical. Okay, so let's
say
n.
Okay, fantastic. We did this perfectly.
Shift enter. Let's run it again. Okay,
the first one is done. Good. Now we wait
for the second one. The second one is
the fantastic and beautiful.
Perfect. Okay, that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching. Um, see you
next time. If you like my stuff, donate,
okay? Go to kasi.info, my website. At
the bottom, you know, you can find my
PayPal and Patreon and donate to me,
okay? That's what makes the work going.
Okay. So, that is good. So, in fact, we
can actually make it uh you know, we can
adjust this a little bit more. Let's say
250 frames. Okay. And
put the code back. Syntax correct
showing browser. So, in a few days I'll
update my website. So, so the code will
be all here and correct. Okay. Now the
code is actually taking too much space.
So actually
anyway the there's needs to be more to
be done with the code. Okay.
Oh and we need to generate this one. So
this one is the rolling circle is three
over four. So actually we can do that by
just copy this. Um copy this. Copy.
So
paste it. We don't care about the second
part. Figure it out yourself. Delete. Uh
then the the rolling circle is 3 over 4,
right? And do it.
Okay. Why is it okay? So there it is.
Oh, so wait. Okay. No, wrong.
This is not the right graphics we are
looking for.
Although it is um
it is a true hypotcoid but
circle radius the rolling circle radius
3 over four. Wait.
Oh, then then then then you need to also
say the radius I mean the distance from
the bar to that is that. Okay, do it.
There it is. Fantastic and beautiful.
Bye guys.