hello guys welcome to another episode
ofan talk show we are going to code
wolam language Mathematica doing plain
curves geometry
today so let me introduce my keyboard
glove at keyboard ultimate hacking
keyboard on my website you can see
reviews and on YouTube video
reviews and next next video we are going
to do this okay it's been a long time
this is this is s board data hand s v a
l b o a Rd SP board data hand a very
special input device I think it's the
best so next
videoa talk show we'll be doing this so
so okay so that is my keyboards
introduction now let's go to the
um let's start to do
today's uh talk show so let me switch
screen there we have it okay comments
and comments okay you ask me questions
Hello steo sup what's up wolam language
coding okay so so let's uh ready
ready uh so my keyboard my emac so I'm
using emac the Ping window shows all my
command course as I move cluer or delete
things or insert things you can see all
the command names on the right and the
key I type on the left I'm using sof
keys of course you can get it free on
GitHub it's part of the G emx repo uh
Sly Keys the most efficient key binding
system and I'm using a v keyboard layout
so today we are going to do some fun
thing actually I'm just going to work on
my website mathematics okay mathematics
extremely interesting subject
I'm going to work on the project special
plan curves the project I worked I
started in
1995 or 1994 okay so it's uh visual
dictionary of SP special plan curbs so
this website is my most famous popular
website linked by a thousand you know
over a thousand universities back then
uh 20 years ago
so uh and they are Asian you know if you
look at them today it's kind of asan but
back then it's the bleeding edge
technology using uh animations uh these
are this used to be videos but now I
turned them into GIF because the codc
used used by the QuickTime movie
animation format is gun obsolet so the
video players won't play so I have to
turn them into GIF so you are looking at
hypo tror curve so anyway so this is you
know all the special PL plan curves okay
they are two dimensional Curves in the
plane uh and they have tremendous number
of properties so wolam language okay so
the good you know what's good for you uh
maybe you will learn some wolam language
so let me introduce you wolam language
you can see we already started uh if you
don't know uh let me do some
introduction wolam language X okay so
wolam language in depth you search for
that and search my name you'll find it
wam language in depth and if you are
impatient you know you don't want to
watch long maybe perhaps rambling video
uh live stream you can just go to this
my tutorial okay so
and if you want a kind of comprehensive
today I'm kind of just doing random I'm
just going to work on my you know uh
curves conic sections and uh
and uh you know but if you want a
systematic tutorial on wolam language so
you can find them on my wolam language
in depth so there's some like
introduction how does the wolam language
work uh you know so there are there are
like 50 over 50 uh videos but some of
the best I put them here okay so just go
to wolam language in depth search for
Kali
my name and you can download wolf
language for free it was it became free
about uh six years ago by now okay and
uh so you what you get is a wolam script
which is like a text
based uh for example uh What uh turn it
back uh magnify okay
so so you can start wolm script and you
get text spased so you can watch my
video I have lots of demo uh but
now we don't want that okay so wolf
language you can download it for free
but they
don't uh they don't have like they
cannot do Graphics if you use the wfam
engine so what you can do is that you
download um you know you you you
download wam engine then then you
download the Jupiter you know there's a
Jupiter package created by wolam
research by the company that allows you
to have Graphics in the Jupiter notebook
okay that is a case you don't want to
pay you know if you are the open source
like I just want free things uh but then
I mean if you are really into it you
know you can just pay and buy wolfan
Mathematica that's that's what I
recommend
okay so curves so let me show you some
curves you know so is huge amount
involute involute is used for Gears uh
the design of Gears so what is involute
for example if you take a string you
wrap it around a circle and you unwrap
the
string that string the end of the string
will Trace out what's called involute so
this is used for uh gear design and uh
gear design uh for example all these
teeth of the gears you have to be you
know like normally if you don't know
anything about gears you just think of
them as like triangles you know that
should work but act but in
practice not really I mean the triangles
yeah it gives you the basic idea but in
in practice if you want to for example
put this in car for example car you have
gears you need you need this you know
you have you need lots of these if you
just have triangles they are not not
efficient they they they you know you
you need them to move smoothly and uh
with maximum efficiency right so so in
order to do that you need you know you
need to find the geometry of the teeth
and that is an application of this
involute thing okay so tremendous amount
of um
uh you know properties very interesting
properties for example this Lem muscate
of Boni it looks like that like a
infinity symbol and here's their
equations you know polar equation
parametric equation and many properties
for example this one uh blah blah blah
the distance is such and such that you
know from here to here and here to
there there their multiplication
uh product is
constant okay something something okay
you can read it in detail and how how
this curve has a relationship to
hyperbola okay so and also if you have a
Taurus or donut you cut it around right
around there then that cross-section
is is this lemiscate the Bui okay uh
like the infinity symbol okay but you
have to cut it right there right at the
inner border okay so you cut a donut at
you have a crosssection and and you see
all these they they show you how to use
gears uh linkages these are called
linkages to trace out the lemc of Boni
and this is useful if you want to
translate a vctor linear motion to a
circular motion so for example in
robotics for example robotic dogs you
know how their legs are move only move
in certain way so you have to use these
linkages so a lot of application you
know linkage by itself is a is a field
uh in
robotics so all these uh you know so
tremendous uh uh interesting things
about plane curves for example this
orthoptics
and I optic okay I wrote this long ago
you know 25 years ago 1995 when I was
younger when I was a team you know when
I was like a hot shot uh so you guys you
know if you are young you know you don't
have nothing to do you hang full CH
every day do something you know do
something when you are
young uh so this optic also uh orthoptic
is optic actually I don't remember what
they are an orthoptic curve is a locus
of all points where the curves tangents
meet at right angles okay you know
anyway so you can anyway so there's you
know lots of information so today we
just going to I'm going to you know one
of my my project is update this website
so all this website I need to update so
um you know so update this 25 years
project okay that's what I'm doing today
I'm just going to do some plot and uh
and some wolam language code you know
some of them is easy to plot for example
the the thing we want to plot today is
um for example you have sign and cosine
or this one is beautiful this is this is
this this is algorithmic art or
mathematical artwork beautiful they are
actually a plot of a of a a 2D equation
you know they are a part of this thing
okay so let's just show it you know
paste it run it run the
code there you have it so it's simply a
all these points are the solutions of
this equation
amazing is it is it amazing is it
beautiful so that's one thing you know
you can generate artwork and this is the
illustration of s and cosine you see
this animation I created like 25 years
ago this is a fundamental illustration
of the entire trigonometry thing okay
the entire trigonometry is basically
just the sign function s or cosine I
mean the the all the sign cosine
cosecant secant tangent cotangent can be
simply defined by just by sign
okay so but what does the sign function
mean it it's captured by this animation
so the sign function is basically just
the trace of
the basically it captures the circular
motion okay
circular circular circular motion to
linear motion that's that is the essence
of what what the sign function do and uh
and therefore the entire
trigonometry okay so so when you use you
know so all these are done with wam
language actually not some of them are
not because for example these two are
not ploted by wam because I started to
use some other uh software but
anyway what we have to do is that you
know for this for simple plot you can
you you know you can just you can just
you know plot you know in
language like like you are using a
graphing calculator but some others
require programming for example this
helex
projection you see when you project the
helex like that then the projection is
actually a sign curve okay so that's
another way to generate the sign curve
you see so this is this is why these
curves plain curves has tremendous you
know visually very interesting
mathematical properties you see you
project the helex then it is a sign
curve uh of course and also if you roll
a cylinder with a a blackly cut cylinder
you know that also traces out a S curve
and then you also can see S curve in two
dimensional sign curve so this is a uh
two-dimensional uh
function uh actually a function that
takes two arguments X X and Y and
returns one single value Returns the
height okay so the graph of that
function is this kind of cubic wave so
it's basically just sign okay I believe
this is just s time cosine uh yeah s
Time s sin x * sin y you get this
surface okay uh in fact we can plot that
okay so do we have it plotted uh yeah
so our job today is simply I mean I'm
just going to you know do some PL so um
so for example um plot
3D
uh okay
three okay plus 3D that and uh what what
is the sign goes from zero
to Pi okay
then X goes from 0 to Pi then
um y goes to 0
to Pi okay let's run it okay you got one
piece of it so let's say uh 4 pi
there it is okay so you see we need to
update so that's what I'm doing I need
to update this graph okay uh there is
something we don't want because right
now you
see
it's higher than you know this I I want
them to look like
that so what do you do so any questions
comments is it
good so
so what I'm saying is that some of them
just require a simple plot and While
others require some coding okay this one
is another beautiful one I call this one
B Cube so this is this is again a simple
plot of a equation of equation of three
variables X Y and Z and that equation is
this
one okay so in fact we can copy and and
and do
it uh why is this one taking so long
taking longer than
expected oh okay there it is so once you
get the graphics you
can you can actually rotate it so this
is the beauty if you actually buy wolam
language you know if you just download
the free wolam engine you don't get that
but you can then you use the
um you know that that what's the name
notepad you know you can download it
free then you can have this
um but anyway there there is a issue
like whenever you rotate they kind of
shrink too because I mean they have to
shink within the
um yeah that's you know you can fix that
by by creating a spherical border but
anyway
so anyway I'm I I want first of all
let's update this this Graphics
okay uh
and I don't like this color okay I don't
like this
color oh all you have to do is AIS ratio
you know I mean the you see right now
they are not plotted in in aspect ratio
I mean in um what's the
name okay let's see let's do that let's
do that again mesh style plot style
let's click on that uh plot style oh you
can change color okay
so I don't like this color
Okay theme image size export image uh
light lighting lighting is always
interesting neutral okay and I don't
want
neutral
so background access
Viewpoint aspect ratio okay the the
feature the the thing I'm looking for
is
uh aspic
ratio one
oh that's the no that's the whole uh oh
you should be
automatic uh no we
want what uh okay let's look up aspect
ratio we want it to be stretch Graphics
to figure out in close
region determines ratio of the actual
coordinate values
okay so you see from here to here is one
I mean it's two but from here to here is
10 so they kind of compressed it
vertically which is uh not what I
want so let's see what's some examples
to f F
that okay so wait a minute
the aspect ratio
is aspect ratio is
um is not exactly what we
want box ratios let's
see okay let's see box ratios yeah box
ratio automatic I
think there it is now it's more
beautiful now it's
soothing okay now 3 Pi 4 Pi is too much
let's just say two 2
pi okay 2 pi is not enough let's say 3
Pi uh need a bit more let's see one two
one
two okay so it's
more aesthetically pleasing if you cut
it right on the
ridge yeah so instead of instead of you
know you have the flat boundary so you
want to cut it right on the ridge so you
can do that by simply
um
[Music]
simply start with pi/
okay
uh yeah but um
now that's good now to put it 4
Pi okay that's kind of what I want now
the next thing is that I don't like the
lighting okay so actually copy
that I'm going to use my let's see what
is this yeah close that close that
uh I'm going to use wam
language in
in emac so if you don't know what that
is I have a wolf and language mod that
allows you to
work with wolam engine or wolam script
in
emx so you can download it for free it's
here uh wait it's here okay you can
download
it so what's the benefit well the
benefit is you know you can use em Max
so you have the full power but except
you cannot do
Graphics uh but however you can still
edit it easier but
um so showing browser okay that's what
we plotted
today uh yeah now we want to change the
lighting
okay uh let's see
copy
that okay so
do I really want to change yes because
that image is like 20 uh 20 years ago
you see they don't have
Alias um but now I want to change color
okay I don't like the coloring so what
you do is you just look at
the the documentation for plot 3D okay
in particular what you need is an option
okay so let's
magnify plus
3D uh you have a option for lighting now
lighting is one of the most spectacular
thing because then you can do
transparency you can do spec uh specular
lightning like that is that is reflect
reflexive like
shiny uh you can do lots of things so
but you need
the uh lighting okay then you can change
the mesh
style yeah so and so this four
of I okay lighting okay so this is what
we want lighting
option automatic
none okay so let's just do this uh
several of them okay copy
copy copy copy copy okay so we have a
bunch of them we try different lightning
okay
uh okay so lighting what is it supposed
to to be is supposed to be automatic or
a light named light or a sequence of
light sources okay uh possible named
light
standard neutral accent okay let's
try so that is one of the um
okay
so yeah lighting standard what's the
other neutral accent 3 point
okay let's try
this see what
happens oh okay uh now this is like this
is like nuclear disaster fire burned out
so this is good
but I don't like
it you know what we see here is
the you see what we see here it was the
standard back in 19
1890s so I still prefer
that uh yeah but now you have
to so I don't like this light so you
know lighting is fairly
complicated
uh so wait uh so you might need to spe
specify three light sources possible
name lighting setting include
standard uh standard doesn't do much
let's turn on JavaScript
yes okay so you have ambient light
directional light Point light each light
source SI can be of the following forms
okay uh wa why is this
oh okay
[Music]
so directional light spherical Point
light okay so you know you can just play
with light for
hours so you have Spotlight Point light
directional
light okay so directional
light is is okay so it's like um
infinite parallel projection
okay so you give it that
then okay so you can kind
of so
lightning okay so lightning so we can so
here so we have a directional
light
here and
uh yeah
so you don't want that so but you want
this to be a list of
things so here is the RGB color let's
just say red okay and then you give it
what are these two these are two
positions okay so those two are two
points from so the light forms a
direction from this point to that point
so this is
5555 okay so this lighting is like from
top to down
seems like okay I don't think I want
that so this is a directional
light okay directional light color and
point is a
three-dimensional graphics directive
that specifies the directional light of
color from the point PT to the center of
the bounding
box okay to the center of the bounding
box okay so let's say color red then you
just need one element here so you don't
need
to and where do you want it be so let's
just say Above So 0
0 uh 100 okay let's see what
happens
yeah so you are shining a red light on
it directly then you got that
so yeah and we don't you don't seems to
see shadows and all that let's see one
one what happens
oh we do see Shadows but this
is very very strong
light so you have some kind you know you
have a red light on it from the
side yeah actually from the the light
point is somewhere here you know on the
on the x equals to zero I mean on the
plane
uh
so but if we raise it a little bit
see yeah you can you still get kind of
that like
that okay so that is a directional light
but
then it's just one lighting okay
so uh let's see blue what happens
okay this is like very
creepy
uh yeah but that's not what we so we we
do want some kind of Shadow or um so
that will depends
on the
surface yeah specularity okay okay so
copy
that so let's try this
one plus style okay so you need plus
style so
let's so you need
a plus style at Leist and uh one of that
is specularity which is which spec
specifies the
shiny the reflective properties of the
surface okay so let's try
that there we have it there we have some
kind
of oh wow look it changes as you
move let's see it
does
wow so the light is not fixed to the
surface you
see see you see quite
amazing so we here what we have uh yeah
we have Direction light and we have
the reflectiveness of the surface
and
uh so you
need you need two lights okay so let's
let's
actually put two lights let's say this
one blue
um uh red is from where red is 0 0 100
red is from the top
okay uh let's
see
100 100 100 okay that's kind of from one
corner and the other one is from a
different Corner
okay so let's try
that oops something is wrong oh yeah you
need a
comma still
wrong oh
okay
now beautiful now this is looking like a
seashell yeah but it's still doesn't
like give you the natural
look
um you know like this one is actually
pretty
good so anyway I think I need to think
about how to do this how long have I
been talking 15 minutes already any
questions good night
steel okay
[Music]
so you know I did it's
like 40 minutes spent just on this
simple
thing um so you can
see you can really spend hours to play
with this lightning
stuff but I was surprised that this
lighting changed in real time it wasn't
uh so 20 years
ago so the lightning seems to be not
fixed to the surface
which is properly done uh because you
don't want it to stick to the
surface and
uh well I mean so we have to make
judgment
on like artistic
judgment you know like which one looks
better you know this doesn't look so
right because you don't see the
here and Valley you know it looks like
you know
just so you
need
specularity let's
say 10
let okay so what so you need some kind
of ambient light okay so let's go back
let's add some ambient
light so I think we're going to finish
that and uh then May maybe that's it we
just add some so here is a point
light okay I think I prefer Point light
instead of um instead of directional
light
so yeah so there direction we delete
that so
let's see what happens with
this okay still not
much okay so but now let's add some
ambient
light Point light directional light
lightning you want
okay you see
the
there so you want some ambient
light
here uh
lighting
none ambient light orange okay let's add
some ambient light
uh what is
the ambient
lights blue red
Brown
uh blue red yellow let's see what
happens if you do yellow
okay the ambient light is
not so if you turn Li To
None
maybe because when you have lighting
then the ambient light has no effect
so if you turn all the lightings to
none this is not
[Laughter]
good what so what if you take our
specularity no you do need some kind of
lighting
so
uh you see This is complicated because
besides all these different
lighting you can also change the
surface color for example you can
see Mater material shading material
shading is a three-dimensional graphics
directive specifying that the surface
that follow are to be drawn with a
material
okay material appearance and then you
can have a color as option so you have
some examples aluminum
brass oh
aluminum that's interesting so then
there's plastic silver so let's
try aluminum or
aluminium as that as that keyword I used
to
say uh actually this is very interesting
so let's try let's try iron because iron
is easy to
type and then you have plastic okay so
here is
the
specular reflection Viewpoint specular
diffusion and light
okay let's try this okay material
shading
copy uh
uh where do we put that okay yeah that's
not what what we
want material shading material okay so
iron so that is that and how do
you where do you put
it wow very very
involved okay so you can map it to
texture uh lighting three point okay
material shading iron
H yeah that's I don't think
that's I don't think that's what
I don't think this will work but we can
try oh it kind of
worked but now it's
more crazy so now you just take out the
lightning now you just REM move the our
custom lighting and uh put it
to three point
okay three point you know the W language
started to have these string based names
which is always
problematic to deal with in a
programming language like JavaScript
also has lots of that JavaScript
especially with the
CSS you started had to have a lot of
option names that's simply a string so
when when that is the case usually you
cannot do keyword completions because
you know
but you
see for example you don't
know what possible options for the
material shading except a literal list
but
um anyway so let's keep going with this
okay okay so now we actually get some
kind of
wow material shading
iron it's just
wow spectacular actually
actually this is spectacular we can
let's just use
this you know actually yeah so consider
this like done uh what wait a minute I
want
to okay so this is this is uh iron let's
say silver
fantastic yeah let's use this okay
so this is like consider today's
work okay captured now let's go back to
my curve
page syntax showing browser and we need
to go to sign
curve um sign curve and the the surface
wavy surface okay so we're going to
replace that
by uh wait so you need to add image that
is one okay so rename
it wavy surface
okay
uh yeah okay so
that redo
it okay remove that and show in browser
showing
browser
magnify go down go down go down go down
fantastic beautiful
whoa fantastic okay that's that's what
I'm going to
use
so let's see yep going to use that one
better than this one this is is see this
is a difference of Technology after 25
years okay so um yep and I'm going to so
I'm going to copy the code so here's the
code copy
it and just put the code
here move from language put it there
syntax
CCT and uh showing browser so fantastic
I think that's it we we're going to we
just show this
one uh that already took 40 50
minutes okay any things
guys so next we're going to do is uh I'm
going to do this okay next video in two
days probably two days two or three no
more than three we're going to do
this data hand small board live I'm
going to show you guys okay and anything
else do you guys have any questions
about W
language we're going to shut down in two
minutes uh so I'm actually pretty happy
you know so one of these days I'm going
to do I'm going to code this animation
in wam language you see when you want
things like this like today what we did
is simply plot okay or we have have to
do is just you know type the function
name you know just plot it try different
color and see what we want but you you
know then you get more involved then you
have to uh do visual uh Graphics
programming like that and this one is
actually pretty simple too and this one
also you need to do some kind of uh
Graphics
programming and these two and and in all
these cases is actually pretty simple
but I can show you a more uh difficult
case Okay a more difficult case is this
one you see this you see this conic
sections so they are a double
cone then you slice them with a
plane you know parallel plane then you
get that so this will be more difficult
to do and and one of these um coming
weeks I'm going to do one of
that Luke Smith Lucas Smith oh hi for
the for the moment I thought you are
Luke Smith the Luke Smith guy lenux guy
uh fantastic good night okay uh bye
guys okay now I clean up and bye guys
so sign curve sign curve beautiful I
really I'm pretty happy with today's
result this this thing pretty happy yeah
um okay so that is that we did today
close that uh what is is close that
coning section talk
show close that Boven okay so the W
documentation okay that's it bye