good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of our talk
show today is July 13th 2019 9 o'clock
p.m. California time and we're gonna
talk about today we're gonna talk about
random some random topics some you know
stuff for my blocks so let's start up a
browser so let us yeah random topic so
see
it's been hot okay let me close the door
that is why I'm covering my eyes
that's toilet paper you tear one piece
off you fold it like this you fold it
like that
you got a square this is mathematics
geometry then you put it there so it
functions as a pack a patch so how are
you guys doing so comment in here too
just type something I welcome it and I
got this now if you are young you may be
familiar with this this is you know
a friend gave it to me this is actually
THC and it turns out I don't like it
okay THC is the active ingredient of
magic wanna THC Pandey's it is legal in
California you know where I live so yeah
so this is tetrahydrocannabinol
cannabinol you know some chemistry
actually I don't know chemistry it's
very interesting I don't know how much I
don't know any chemistry at all but you
know when I was younger you are
interested in math chemistry what what
is that came from what go back I must
clicked somewhere anyway so so chemistry
you know when you are younger you study
math physics chemistry those those are
you know so-called hard sciences those
are the fond of fundamentals of Sciences
and you know as a nerd typically you are
also interested in engineering topics
like mechanical engineering or whatever
engineering but electrical engineering
and so on
I'm not much you know what you know I'm
also interesting them but not as much
I'm more interested in Sciences so and
among science is math physics chemistry
down or interesting but I'm into math
mostly I'm into math but you know as a
note you also are interested in the
others you know physics or chemistry but
for me it turns out you know I just
never had you know never got the time I
never actually learned much about
physics or chemistry but now you know so
you know since 10 years ago I start
to have interest in biology biological
system you know biology in general
because biology you know I don't have
that interest when I was younger but
biology is quite interesting you know
molecules you know the DNA computing
that you know DNA itself it's very
interesting and it's a very active area
and and all the drugs so I was talking
about this this thing so by the way
today's topic is gonna be random I'm
going through some of the interesting
things on my website and I'll talk about
them keyboards some something about
keyboard something about programming
something about web dev okay and so yeah
I was talking about this so this is THC
this is the active ingredient of
cannabis you know Maj wanna and it's not
for me
really you know I don't you know when
you do this when you do this what you
get is like you you become stupid that's
what it is you become stupid and city
you know oh you get you know you just
can smile this is smile all the time
soothe it nothing
so turns out is not for me this thing
and on the other hand cigarette you know
a cigarette is a and coffee
they are stimulants you don't get stupid
with cigarette maybe long term but not
you know the shorten with cigarette you
actually becomes more active and coffee
you know I'm drinking coffee all the
time the kind of the you know energy
drink but these you know these are
people like this you know grass Masha
fauna that's not for me you know you
just get stupid and you know you know
like smiling all the time and when that
happens actually yes
it's that's happening let's [ __ ] have
any go on in cat forty-four were you
from what are you up to I don't know you
before I think you know you being on my
show once PETA good morning
mooch didn't okay you know so many of
you I forgot where you came from so say
you where you came from
you know like like what country or so
anyway so this so this you just get
stupid and also drinking you know beer a
lot guys you know nerds you know the
they like beer all the time like all the
New York guys nice like Opie Opie abut
beer is not for me neither you know
alcohol like you know yeah so I don't
like alcohol in general I don't drink
you know I don't drink
you know much like a few times a year
and you know what had what happens with
this you know this in alcohol is that
you just get stupid you just do to or
your senses and and for me I live you
know I live in a crisis mod almost of my
life like you know like in in countries
you have maritime law something like
that Maritimes like meaning that your
country is in a critical you know
wartime condition something like
emergency condition so you are staying
alert
at all times your country you know so
you have to you have like you know you
know law you know maritime law let's
look it up how is it called
maritime something like that or maybe
it's not called that
let's see
Adam roti law no maritime law okay
oh okay so that is that Admiralty law I
haven't heard of that term before and
see dashboard dashboard dashboard I'm
alive good morning guys so type your
comments opinions okay this is today's
topic is random so Adam or Admiralty law
Admiralty law or maritime law is a body
of law that governs natural issues in
private maritime disputes okay that
that's not that's not the word I was
looking for what is the word when our
country is in a liking an emergency
situation there's a special law like
like near wartime so Kat 44 is from
Australia part yeah part okay party is
not legal here
Oh in Aussie but have used it for 30
years in place of antidepressants okay
yeah so this yeah so it's truth is your
mind II actually it does relax you and
you know and and it's also it function
as a painkiller as well you know I
wonder I should get I should get you
know a stoned doing the show you know
the you know do just for the fun of it
so you know vote like type yes or no
should I you know if I get stoned then I
cannot talk about programming and stuff
well I can still because
your ability to program and think deeply
will be affected of course but however
as a talk show or talking about
programming I think that that doesn't
matter I mean I can still do it
it might be interesting but yeah I did
you know you do all your senses but it's
relaxing okay ten minutes so a child
tetrahydrocannabinol
tetrahydrocannabinol or what is a law
like some kind of emergency law when
when your country is in near war I don't
I don't remember but okay so so urgency
low something No
then there's also another term where at
night like around ten o clock everyone
you know by law you have apply a special
temporary law you have to state it at
home after you know Nile crocodile Crocs
something like that was that code you
know I can't remember terms I don't like
if I'm getting too old or his friend but
it's not because of these though I don't
think so
so it's my camera so Adam so talk guys
talk so anyways so I was talking about
that law and you forget about that then
yeah okay so let's talk about let's go
to the ok keyboard let's go to the
keyboard Department there's something
new interesting about keyboard okay
there is ok there is this keyboard
teletype this is a keyboard history
teletype five six twenty okay also known
as split now this is a very
famous popular terminal it's you know
it's actually created by Rob Pike Rob
Pike is a UNIX UNIX guy UNIX philosophy
when I go language you know he's a
talker
he likes mashallah mashallah
yes exactly much aho so you know in some
countries you know sometimes you have
martial law it's a special law kind of
emergency where people the country whole
country is seeing a lot
now that's law for the country but
sometimes a person I don't know if you
have a term for that eight like India
for a person you sometimes sing in a
alerted crisis kind of living style I
remember I read an article like 10 or 20
years ago
they say that Japanese people often live
you know in that kind of style like like
to like like I don't remember this is 20
years ago I think I read that but anyway
so for me my life it's almost my entire
life are living in that condition like
in a crisis you know Marshall it's like
in a crisis super alert situation like I
cannot you know so this is this is about
me you know you know I cannot relax and
enjoy it
like there's no no pleasure or
entertainment for me in general like
yeah you know like you are in a state
where you must get ready to run or you
know you know so survive survive hunger
whatever that is my kind of my life
still lifestyle this years due to anyway
so so anyway so let's get back to the
yeah Marshall oh by the way martial law
Taiwan is a martial law for like for the
past like 40 or 50 years you know since
I want you know the Taiwan is the
a party Nationalist Party who escaped
from China because they lost the Civil
War you know they've they take they you
know the Taiwanese government they you
know the KMT party
they take Americans money because you
know for you know the it was they lost
the civil war they lost to the
Communists
so they escaped to Taiwan and they did
bad things to you know people already
living in time went by anyway the Taiwan
government m'kay emptied so Taiwan was
actually in martial law for the past 40
or 50 years I think they they lifted off
10 or 20 years ago I don't I don't
remember yeah but anyway martial law
so anyway teletype this is keyboard
history by the way I recently updated my
my my blog about that's another thing
let me talk about that later but look at
this one this one teletype 50 is twenty
two plate computer invented by Rob Pike
and you know this is the first computer
one of the first not first the first
computer to feature the GUI window
excuse me Windows system you know
Windows system is interesting because
before before the Windows system what
you have is a situation like this you
know you have a monitor and you have one
terminal and that is it you know on the
whole screen you just see this terminal
you know what one term know so this they
amended the Windows system now with the
Windows System meaning that you know as
the you know we know like a screen have
several you can have several windows
each one can be a terminal whatever a
nap you know so this is one but the
first this is in 1984 it's not the first
it's one of the first you know
so they comes with a mouse you see very
interesting this this big huge mouse so
and at the end there is a video you can
watch you go to the website and you can
watch your video imaged it's you know
it's not showing in Firefox because this
video format is let's see the file let's
see so this is this video format is in
MK MKV so that's not supported in
Firefox you stupid 5 bucks
so Taylor type 56 so yeah so I was
talking about there's a video you can
actually it's nice it's good to watch
because they
so it's interesting to watch this video
you know this is one of the first tonal
you know the window GUI windows but it's
not the first remember now this is 1984
1982 now by by 1982 let's go back to
history there there's also a list
machine system let's let's have a look
at this machine let me show you
symbolic okay let's let's click on
space-cadet space-cadet keyboard one of
the most dramatic keyboard there it is
you see space cadet now you see this
list machine the first non compromised
this machine that's marketing talk from
here for sure lambda lambda machine Inc
how am i inc so you see that there is
many of these graphics and by the way
this screen is vector graphics they have
a vector screen and this is in this is
about 1979 you see so it's few years
before that Rob Pike UNIX thing at least
come first okay so that's about that
this machine let me talk about the other
things interesting about keywords so
check it out you know you just you know
go to my website sorry keyboard sorry
dot info keyboard you know you can check
it out and let's go through let's go
back to block there is several things
interesting okay there's a this is a new
keyboard I discovered do-it-yourself
keyboard summer I made it it's total of
60 keys 30 keys on each hand it looks
fine and
not bad you know I think it's pretty
good you know if you are into
do-it-yourself
you know keyboard you can you know
soldier you know by the parts by the
keycaps
by the case by the PCB you know the
circuit board by the chips you know and
assemble it yourself but actually I
don't know there's a website for this
keyboard it's actually on reddit oh but
I forgot out here bo2 spec so you it's
on github you can go to the his website
and by the way so they have this default
layout you see this layout you see now
look at the arrow keys here here here
here
that's NJ K L so they are following the
vim editor the VI editor style arrow key
arrangement which is no good is
inefficient I did a video on this topic
a month ago you can you know go to my
YouTube and you can find it anyway I
have a application here let me show you
so go back to where do we go go go back
let's go to the homebrew ok this
do-it-yourself keyboard section all
these are do-it-yourself recently I made
a updated this page so they are more
organized you see the first section is
all poor surface you know they have
concave servers keyboards all these are
do it yourself you can build it if you
like it then you have then you have a go
ducks variations in a beginning we have
a bow ducks then you know there are in
people created variations some of these
you can buy off the bat like oh go ducks
there are companies that I think there
are two companies that sells it one is a
go ducks infinity and the other one is
anyway you can you can find it over
ducks easy oh yeah oh go go ducks
Easy's
more popular I think so so there's a go
ducks in variations let me show you
where okay so a go ducks diverge redox
ago - iris fortitude okay and let me
mention another thing you know many of
these you know in the past three years
many of these keyboard they don't have
many keys comments okay guys comment
keep your comment coming so many of the
modern you know in the past four or five
years all these new to yourself keyboard
people created they don't have many keys
like 60 keys you know a Botox is only
like 80 keys its cricket let's have a
look
so ago docs 76 keys it's not that's you
know not too many okay on a typical
full-sized keyboard you have 105 keys
you know if we look at the PC keyboard
you know like a typical keyboard like
that like that you have hundred five
something like hundred five keys so and
and for the short you know for the
compact keyboard you have like for
example happy hacking one of the most
famous among nerds among hackers it has
this is one of the worst keyboard it it
has how many keys let's see I don't have
a key count here SC count
total I don't have I didn't say how many
keys total but anyway look let's look at
vortex a similar 161 keys you see they
only have 61 keys that's no good
so all these you know 16 I that's that's
not enough okay so but what you do is
that when you have you know if you
actually want like some of these Do It
Yourself what is these shoes for women
she she was 2 feet so you have you know
as many of these only have 60 keys you
know over Docs has 76 so when that
happen you know if you like one of these
you can get them but I know you know
before you let me tell you with my
thought about this okay before why when
I look at the this these one of these
for example let's say this one redux
it's only 70 keys that's not enough you
see it it's missing the function keys or
the function you don't have function
keys so if you want to press the
function keys you have to hold down one
of these buttons so that means you can
no longer you know have a single key
press mark well for example if you want
to switch to browser you can just hit
what with one thing I switch to browser
switch to terminal switch to desktop you
know that's so convenient but now with
this you know stupid people with not
this one is actually okay 70 keys now
some of them these to it yourself these
these people they created they don't
have let me show you example you know
they get the extreme for example look at
this one
both of dogs it looks pretty you know it
looks you know
but it only have one two three four five
six yeah
Yan has three rows so the total number
of keys is only forty six you know
twenty-three on each hand let's say 1 2
3 4 5 6 6 times 3 is 18 18 night you see
18 times plus five is twenty six twenty
six on each hand total forty six that's
it's no good so before when I see a
keyboard like that you know you don't
have many keys you know immediately
that's a major problem and also this HP
is very popular this is one of the you
know it's only got 42 keys you know I
can imagine some people like them you
know a lot of people I think you know it
to me it's like easy idiots I don't know
what they are thinking this keyboard
like this will get you get you a
repetitive strain injury right away it's
like you know when people you know
people who love this keyboard you can
tell right away they don't type much no
it's like they'd only type 10 minutes a
day really you know I can tell you for
sure because if you use this keyboard
and you type you know this keyboard does
not even have number row you see it
doesn't have number row so if you want
need to type numbers or any symbols you
have to press you know one of the
modifiers so it's extremely painful
especially if you need to type you know
math or I mean even for programming math
or Japanese or German or Russian you
cannot you know you this keyboard is
like out of the question you know
there's no way
but even if you limit it limit to typing
only English you know it's not good
because every time you type a number you
have to press a hoe down a modifier and
holding down a modifier is one of the
primary
attribution a primary cause for RSI okay
so you know the people liking this to me
is just idiotic
this this one is actually you know like
Phil hack hack Oberg you know he's a big
great hacker he created he's a big
closure hacker and also Emacs Lisp
hacker he is expert in both of these
languages and he is also very much into
Lua
the language Lua and you know very
capable programmer and he created this
he invented this atreus keyboard that's
the thing to me you know many these
programmers opinions I just don't agree
but and and but look at this keyboard he
created to me this keyboard is one of
the most idiotic keyboard first of all
42 keys you know this key this keyboard
is the is a stairway to repetitive we to
the doctor's office repetitive strain
injury but you know there's a lot of
these hackers types you know they seems
to you know like this keyboard because
you see this often like on you know
Twitter or on reddit
you know keyboard forums and you know so
I think you think about why why do you
why do people like this you know idiotic
keyboard you know you think about why
one one thing I can tell is that that
these people they don't type much okay
because each person is very different
you know you you know whatever wherever
you live you know your environment your
lifestyle maybe you are programmer
maybe you you are a from a rural place
so you know whatever you know even for
programmers the environment lifestyle is
differs very much especially when you
are outside of the USA okay so so each
person you know you you don't see other
people how many other people type like
you have no idea anyway I look at this I
and the people who love this keyboard I
can yeah I can like I can kind of tell
most of them they do not type
they do not type much like five minutes
a day if they 10 minutes a day if if
they type the holidays typing
continuously it's just going to be like
five minutes you know and they so so the
thing to take away here you know I
talked about in details
elsewhere in an article is that is that
one is that the keyboard choices the key
arrangement you know the style which one
is good which one is better
it really depends it really depends a
lot on a person like how much you type
that's two most important thing that
governs what kind of keyboard is good
for what kind of people is one how much
you actually type you know there are
several different categories for example
they are at the most extreme you are
data entry clock meaning that your job
isn't enter data just typing
continuously typing four hours a day you
know from you know these days this job
data entry clerk is not almost gun is as
a profession but I was a data entry
clerk back in 1992 for a year or two a
part you know secretary and data entry
so I do you know so I listen to people
you know sales people you know they come
to me they want to write a letter to a
client you know to a customer so they
you come to me and they start to read
the talk and I type you know that's back
in 1992 so that's data entry cook they
type the most you know they did hack the
most then similar is writers or novelist
you know if you are novelist or writers
so or sometimes even Camus seeing a dog
playing game you're playing some role
playing games is like you have to type
the environment your mood you know all
the time so if you play that kind of
role-playing games a few hours a day
that's you know that that's very
intensive
typing so if that actually that's part
of a second life you know the second
life the virtual world
you know if you if you do second life
anyway so so so you have you have data
entry clerk you have writers novelist
you know Oh blogger so don't you know
you know writers like you write
documentation at all times that's your
job then you have you know maybe
programmers okay you programmers don't
don't really type you know then you have
let's say mom and pop you know your mom
or dad um you know suppose they are old
you know they you know sometimes they
type you know they they they type on a
keyboard you know you know writing one
letter a day so you know that's it and
somewhat most of the days they don't
even use a computer you know so so all
these different quantity you know how
heavy person types that matters
significantly you know this matters
significantly if you are the data entry
clerk or writers you you know this of
course this keyboard is not for you this
keyboard is maybe for programmers in
lower okay for you know you don't touch
type that much okay so first thing is
that they are different amount of typing
a person might need to do every day so
that is one of the most important thing
that governs which keyboard is better
for you the other thing is whether you
touch type you know I talked about this
before touch type is a kind of stigma
it's a sensitive topic for example if
you don't touch type you usually you
don't want to say it you don't broadcast
it because you know people think oh you
know you don't touch like you know but
anyway but it is a fact that whether you
touch type or you don't touch type I
mean if you don't touch type that's fine
because if you are a programmer it's not
really necessary to
learn touch-type okay but it's actually
it's really good but if you don't if you
don't want to take the time to touch
type you to lie and you don't really
type that much that's fine but the thing
is remember if you don't learn it if you
don't touch type you will not become a
writer you're less likely but if you
know touch type there's a much higher
chance that we that you might become you
know a professional writer you you gonna
start to be interested in typing a lot
your thoughts writing a book whatever
you know so so that's a thing anyway
whether you touch type that's one of the
important criteria on judging which
keyboard is a good keyboard which
keyboard is not for you you know like
there are so many varieties of
especially organ ami ones in first you
know first of all whether you should
have a economic keyboard like this our
you know split economic and then you
have this PC keyboard which you know
just like flat one piece so like I said
before you know whether you touch type
that's very critical if you do not touch
type then these keyboards are good for
you because those economic ones they
they actually just slow down they don't
do anything for you because if you don't
touch type this flat you know you can
like five keyboard will work fine so
let's see so comments ok guys comment so
anyway let's go back to I think I talked
too much of our keyboard so let's get
back to
hey good morning Gabriel hi how are you
doing today I'm doing good what's up so
so so we have so we talked about this
history of this keyboard teletype you
know plate and you have the stock Knight
keyboard you know so
so yeah so I'm gay so so the Dark Knight
only has 60 keys so I was saying before
when I look when I saw these you know
keyboard everything you know
suppose I saw let's go through homebrew
you know I need to rename that you know
originally it's named DIY do-it-yourself
then last week I changed this category
to homebrew because you know I thought
homebrew is more intuitive like you'd
like if you tell someone the DIY they
have no idea what that is you know a lot
of people won't know especially if if
they are English is not their first
language you know Chinese Russian you
know they wouldn't know what to it you
know DIY means so I changed the name to
homebrew homebrew is more intuitive you
know we're talking about linguistic
aspects you know this interests me so if
you say homebrew you know even though
people may not know what it means but
you know but you can think of you know
home through you know home it's
something made from home but brew is
more difficult word you know prove means
B I usually prove beer so anyway I
thought homebrew homebrew is more
intuitive I think that's actually I
think it's it's better if I name it the
DIY instead that's right
do you guys agree type it okay so so if
you look at this you know this DIY
keyboard so I was mentioning you have
Paul surfaced once you have Okotoks
variations then you have two square
slabs now these two squares apps they
are interesting because they are the
most simple design they are just two you
know rectangular grids you know the most
simple design then you have other kind
of more
fancy designs then you know all these
above split to pieces you know so that
you can tilt the middle you know like
like that but then some of them are one
piece for example here these these are
all flat one piece then you have some
non-economic ones among them the most
idiotic weeks is Planck associated with
heck what they like I find the worst for
example among this page you can see
Frank is one of them you know like a
fairly popular man do-it-yourself like a
lot of people like Frank one of the most
idiotic okay and Atreus is also one of
the most kind of idiotic keyboard you
know and Andy exactly this and you know
these these liked kind of loved by
hackers because you see you see them
awaited you know often and also
including a happy hacking keyboard you
know on the other hand those that are
truly great design for example I would
consider anyway that's that's another
topic so anyway you have all these you
have these two squares slaps keyboard
okay so as I mentioned before one of the
problem with many of them is that they
only have 60 keys like to view so before
why so you know for example I I saw this
one I think it's suppose suppose you
know I think it's great design I really
love it but then oh my god it's only 60
keys that's not enough so so my rating
of this keyboard went down because I
cannot use it you know because you don't
have function keys every time you need
to press function keys you need to press
a modifier that's no good
that you know that throws away a lot of
the
advantage you know so anyway so before I
have this problem when I see your
keyboard I really like it but it turns
out it doesn't have many keys so that is
a problem
but now I have a new thought that solved
this problem that is you just buy a key
back keypad programmable key key pad you
know like if you need if you get one of
those 60 keys keyboard then just buy one
of these key pad so you can see the the
whole thing you know with a programmable
keypad and your organ ami you know 60
keys keyboard consider all of them
together is like one package you know
that way it's really excellent because
now you have like you do you really
basically you have three components you
know you like like three components and
this is actually the best combination
it's really the best combination because
on one hand on one hand your keyboard is
very small and portable you know because
only 60 keys you know almost all these
are kind of okay you know you know so
it's very small and portable and also
these do-it-yourself keyboards they are
highly programmable you can program all
sort of markers into the keys but
problem not many keys only 60 keys and
all your function keys are gone okay
solution
you know solution get one of the you
know programmable keyboards programmable
keypads you know so now you have full
set of keys and they are removable and
they are all tiny you know they are you
know like think of them as like
components so so that's what I do so I
think that's it about keyboard seem to
I've been reading some articles about
about the writing style thank you
so yeah I have the article box writing
style
show you that's on my English writing
blog like related to that blog is
related to literature writing poetry
linguistics and stuff and grandmas
related stuff and writing style so
that's that website is what in English
but so it's just such focus on writing
style so I'm kind of into these kind of
things seem to sing - are you from China
or are you from Taiwan so I wrote this
article this essay the writing style of
sorry it's kind of like you know it's
kind of like a rant you can okay let's
let's let's do a poetry reading session
my writing my writing is razor blades in
hot buns - grammarians choking dagger -
mouthing moralists logic bomb to be
reflecting morons high opener or epical
theorists iOpener - epical theorists
immaculate calculus - logicians euphoric
oxygen - english masters again orgasmic
honey - poetic chicks that is to say
when I wanna be on the right occasion
- okay so Sheen - you are from USA okay
great what state so anyway so I wrote
this you know the writing style of XRD
which kind of document about many
various issues about writing for example
you they are a lot books on writing
style guide like you know this I call
them guilt you know like you know like
Chicago writing style menu or whatever
you know ap press run in style new New
York Times writing style guide they you
know they have this style guide so you
can
to buy from Amazon let me show you some
of them I don't know if you guys still
know them Oh California great so you
know because today's generation the
millennial generation they are different
you know you know they don't they may
not know but anyway writing style you
know writing style guide you know are
kind of very popular among you know
among journalists or whatever so for
example this you have this Strunk Strunk
and white Elements of Style
one of the most idiotic book okay this
you know this this book is kind of like
a urban myth
I read this book like twice I think you
know back in 1993 or so and back then I
was you know so much you know into it
you know I not like today but then
eventually you know as you get older you
learn a lot more things you know you
find lots of them are just you know crap
so anyway the you know this is one of
the most famous book by the way also
another thing about these books is that
you see this book is actually pretty old
like you can look at Wikipedia there's a
Wikipedia on this book article on this
book it's this book must be like 50
years old or 60 or even older you see or
the author you know the William Strunk
and Eby they are dead long ago but
there's one thing about books like
publishing you know it's a business too
old you know you don't write like that
because if you write like that today
people will immediately it will stand
out you know you'll be not appropriate
often not appropriate well anyway the
thing about books and publishing is
because you see books are about
knowledge right so but publishing
there's a twist to it you see once the
author died but they say you know the
publisher whoever almost the content
still wants to make money because it's
making money so they want to keep
publishing it so they try to edit it you
know maybe they rewrite parts you know
they hire someone you know to rewrite
parts but but they keep the name you
know William strong William Strunk and
the EB White they keep the name it and
title why because you know the author
name in title they are like a brand you
know like coca-cola or Apple you know
Microsoft they are like brand they are
like a brand name burn into people's
brain so when you hear a William strike
you know Strunk and white The Elements
of Style people recognize you know so
they keep the name but you know the
author died long ago
you know the it's strong white element
of style let's look it up so let me get
some drink energy drink with vamper
juice
yeah the element of style Wikipedia so
Sheen to what you American born Chinese
oh you grew up in a USA like how do you
came here because American born Chinese
are usually very different from you know
people who did you know Chinese people
would I did did not go come here young
he's almost entirely too different you
know the the thinking the culture is
just different moved here at an early
age okay at what age that's the critical
question you know the your you know you
are basically American you know your
your your your thinking your behavior
you know your reaction your even even
your facial emotions like the way you're
talking it's like America like if you go
- okay for five you like you go you go
to China and you probably don't do you
speak Chinese maybe you do but you
probably don't read Chinese right I give
if you visit China you know you go
Taiwan or China people immediately they
like far away they all know you are not
Chinese I mean just by looking at the
way you talk and they are know right
away anyway that's that's just
interesting thing yeah that's you know
that's what culture is you see culture
is not really it's not real it's not
your skin color oh it's not in you know
technically it's not even your DNA has
nothing to do it with it
mostly culture is like your environment
the thinking the people you know the
history like in America you have
American culture which is typically you
know let's say some of the primary
elements American culture is American
history you know black people you know
the free immaculee ssin of slaves that
you know if in that independence you
know celebrate American culture American
flags
you know flag bikinis that's also you
know American culture this Disney
coca-cola you know all these all these
things in white people in the social
justice can you know the social justice
can they they like to talk about multi
culture you know but they're multi
culture is basically is basically
hundred percent white American
aggression aggression culture plus plus
you know little weird hat of Chinese you
know Chinese I post Chinese eyes or you
know oh oh the you know black skin you
know oh you know you know you know the
women they'd have to like to talk about
it all day you know like Middle East you
know it's like colorful it's basically
chime fewer white American culture purse
colored colorful hats and colorful dress
that's what they they they they also
called mana culture is about because
if you really think about culture you
know for example one of the thing in
American culture one of the thing about
American culture is democracy you know
as if you are American you know that you
know we want you know democracy is a big
topic you know freedom privacy the house
Oh big topic in free speech and so
democracy that's you know you have to
you have to remember you know democracy
the concept of democracy or at least the
way we know it we American know it okay
the concept of Marky's that's very new
no more than let's say let's say 2200
years okay that's a new concept in a
history of humanity but most American
don't know that you know you like your
concept you know you don't know so so so
you have democracy you know so but it's
only it's a new concept but all the
other countries you know some of them
also you know are thriving or in harmony
or in you know peaceful and you know
very good society they don't have
democracy but the people you know they
are governor what you know their leader
they may have you know a good time you
know Oh everyone is happy everyone is
fair but they don't have democracy so
you know democracy does not it's like
it's not like oh if you are you know if
you don't have democracy you must be
evil almost you must be suffering or you
must mean that's not the case you look
at history you look at other countries
regions you know through other times
there are many periods you know some
countries that's not the mark there not
democracy you know what the [ __ ] is
democracy they are not in democracy but
they the country thrived you know they
you know the the rulers are good people
the people are happy there they are you
know they are they are like that so
anyway back to democracy that's American
very very very American concept and it's
I would say it's pretty new
I mean the the basis of the concept is
probably very old
you know like traces back to Greek or
something I don't know but anyway so
democracy is one of the pillar you know
one of the fundamental concept in
America American culture now if you
wanted to talk about multi culture you
know other cultures then
democracy is not typically is not one of
them for example you look at the whole
Middle East and when they were to a
democracy you know that's that's that's
you American you know that's not their
concept you look at Africa the history
of Africa Africa is you know happens to
be the origin of human animals you know
actually you know if you study
anthropology you can read Wikipedia
which is what I did you study you know
actually we all according by theory at
least so far as we know all human
animals originally came from Africa so
anyway you look at Africa countries
histories they do day to day like today
democracy no and so so the social
justice people they want to talk about
multi culture you know respect all we
want different elements of all cultures
yeah but we do they allowed culture the
concept where no team democracy exists
no so basically the you know they are
multi culture from this social justice
scan ok day they are just they are just
pure white yeah you know they you know
the motor culture is it's like is as I
mentioned before the whole the whole
post-modernism the whole things that the
social justice can are concerned about
they are they are a methodology to wing
at any cost
like that you know they are not about
morality about ethics they are just the
art of war it's a it's a
ah Sofia about you know getting your
enemy by all means that's what they do
so the so the multi-cultural reason you
know much what i culturalism that's one
of the concept out of these philosophy
you know what they do is that they
anyway that that's about that about the
concept the concept so seed
Cmdr says alton says the concept of
democracy is thousands of years old but
i agree
the way we practice it is new okay
yeah I got I can I can accept that I
think that's that's what I'm thinking
you know that's yeah so anyway so let's
go back to the oh yeah we were talking
about stronger in white so how did I
digress oh yeah I was talking about Xin
twos
where you from anyway so I was talking
about strong and right in yeah so let's
look at the element of styles you know
this so the author you see so this is
published in 1920s you know why I was
reading this you know when I was young
in the 19th 1920 1992 you know in
college you know I was in Community
College I don't have a degree or
anything so I went to so so I was you
know I'm very studious person I'm a nerd
okay I'd read all day you know so so I
was so eager you know and and also back
then I was learning English and you know
so I was eager to read this because this
is supposed to be you know I can you
know from from what you hear you know
this is like oh this is the this is a
book to get you know the element of
style you know William strong strong
junior and EB white you know it's a
classic you know so that's so I went and
I saw I read it twice and I bought into
it you know you
when you are younger you don't know you
just you know but the the the the truth
I mean well you know I don't know if you
call that truth or what I mean the the
the thing about the whole writing style
is smooth and more than this book this
book is kind of silly
oh so this book is now in public domain
so there should be a copy you can
download somewhere so anyway so this
element of style it's it's a it turns
out you know it's like crass you know
the people the guys they are not expert
at you know whatever they just happens
to write this book and so anyway the
strong can write actually I have a
article about that strong anyway let's
see the elements style let's see
oh that's another one animal style
unix's literature you know this is like
20 years ago this eunuchs idiots UNIX
philosophy idiots there's a journalist
this guy Thomas Scoville he wrote a si
you know publish is in some of this
online website in 2001 now this is
history now this is back then when web
was you know the dot-com days you know
web was striving and so he wrote the
essay which I copied here because the
original is gone you know he he wrote an
essay he is like saying they have the
element of a style you know unix's
literature he is saying he you know he's
basically singing the songs of Unix
you know saying how great is Unix in how
great are UNIX philosophy and how great
are the UNIX people you know the people
who love UNIX [ __ ] it's a pizza you know
so you can try to read this article back
you know this Alka was very famous you
don't you know like today you have
hacker news right once you a while
article you know some blog gets widely
spread you know hundreds of thousands or
millions of reads you know all the
programmers are thinking you know
talking about it so this is one of the
such an article back in 2001 and you can
try to read it it's just garbage you
know it's like it's like it's like pure
drivel like it's like and you know it's
it's it's this note it's not solid
there's no real content you know this is
but back then a lot program you know
it's one of the most popular essay you
know most popular article people want to
read it people want to believe it just
as you would like to believe you know
some something today anyway so that's
that's about this one and The Elements
of Style UNIX is literature by this Co
scovia guy he's I think
I don't think he still writes you know
but he I remember like 10 years ago I
tried to search his name to see what
well what is he's doing you know like
that's that's kind of part of the
research into history you know that's
how I guess that's how I learned many of
the you know like esoteric or like
different perspective you get to see
different perspective of things you know
like like typically most people the way
most people learn is that you go to
school so if you want to learn history
there are history textbooks you know he
just read history textbooks you know
that's one way you know not necessarily
bad you know that's you know that's mass
education that's institutionalized
education but alternatively is that you
can you know if you are curious mind you
know if for example I was looking at
this you know Hanako and you know 10
years ago so I thought so what what is
he doing you know he wrote these so who
is he right back in 2001 so you look it
up you look it up I did that a lot you
know for example in UNIX you have mem
pages right in in UNIX you know so you
have the LS command you have cat command
you have guys CDs you know you have all
these commands and you can do a main
page for example men LS okay so you know
and usually at the bottom they you'll
say who who wrote this so let's see see
also standards history an LS command
appeared in version one AT&T UNIX okay
the to maintain backward compatibility
the relationship the BSD so anyway some
of this main page will mention names
like the guy who wrote it in a in the
beginnings or something like that and
you look them up you do you I did you
know I did a lot you know
just UNIX but Emacs like what I'm saying
is that you have to okay one way to
learn things about you know to get
knowledge to learn to understand the
world you live in you is that you
observe you know everyday things you
know not you know like so so what I'm
saying is that for example I'm not
turning you to begin to man page all the
UNIX command and see who they work who
wrote it and try to look up the guy see
where they are what what is he you know
I'm not saying to do that what I'm
saying is that this is an example where
you know not just UNIX main pages also
Emacs packages every everything anything
you touch you can see the author and
when you have time you know look up the
author you know maybe you'll find he's
your professor was he some famous
programmer or what's his history and how
you know and some of them are old famous
programmers or computer scientists you
know so you do this you can often you
will get then you then you'll get
connections oh you know this guy you
know Rob Pike Rob Pike is one of the
famous you know UNIX people he wrote you
know this is that and and during that
time this awk
you know a wk the UNIX to you know do
you look you look around that's how
that's one way to learn stuff you know
so anyways so I'd like digress digress
integrations writing elements of style
in English what is this let's look what
is passive voice what is aggressive
voice okay that is part of the Alec oh
damn you're gonna show you you know the
passive you know let me talk about that
passive voice and aggressive yeah this
so this article is about the element of
the elements of a style of that book so
let me read part this is interesting I
this is a blog in 2010 this is a
critique of that famous book the Strunk
and white element of style that which
tells you the nature of the why is this
page keep loading hold on a second
Google Ads so you see the element of
style very famous book and here is a
critique by this professor so Edmund ed
an Edinburgh University linguistics
professor Geoffrey Pullum has criticized
the elements of style saying the books
toxic mix of purism atavism and personal
s entries as a centricity is not
underpinned by a proper grounding in
English grammar it is often so misguided
that the authors appear not to notice
their own egregious flouting of its own
rules it's sad several generations of
college college students learned their
grammar from the uninformed bossiness of
Strunk and white and the result is a
nation of educated it educated people
who know they feel vaguely anxious and
insecure whenever they write however or
when me or was or which but can can
cannot tell you why so anyway this is a
criticism on the book from Professor
Geoffrey Pullum so it appears to me he
actually looked into the history of the
book like like what what is the
background of these two guys Strunk and
white you know
anyway and he looked you know so he
looked critically on the book and here
is you know his criticism of his
conclusions and you can tell you know
you can tell you can tell that by the
criticism it makes sense this episode I
mean there are some information it's not
this is not totally push it you know you
well you can dig into it but anyway
that's what he says about you know
Strunk and white and you can read it up
this is from you know anyways you can
read it up so so that's about Strunk and
white you know I'm not saying it's a bad
book at it you know it's been a long
time like 20 years ago 30 years ago I
read it I don't I although I read it
twice like back then I have my own
opinions about writing of course like
writing style how to write better you
know yeah I can we can talk about that
another day I guess have to you know how
to write an essay so anyway I I was
talking so we were talking about the
rainy style of sorry so this is kind of
a turning check kind of turning check
summary of many writing issues which
it's not well it's actually these this
is this is what I follows for example if
you look at writing style there are
things like for example article on
versus a for now capital I versus
lowercase I
sexist sex and genitive James car versus
car it's very complex and also notice
the term sex and genitive that's you
know when you study grammar you know
grandma is one of the most worthless
okay the most was less worthless aspect
in
in writing and in linguistics it's like
yeah it's like the most worthless and
anyway so so anyway this article I
summarized some of the things I stick to
when writing for example should you oh
one of the popular thing is about active
voice was as passive voice
one of the most idiotic advice from
these writing guilds you know it's you
know almost it becomes like open you
know it becomes like a saying that
nobody thinks about you know you have to
be you have to write an active voice and
you know so yeah so typically people you
know when you look at like like right
you can do it right now you can like if
you search for writing style guide you
will see many of these spammy websites
you know they are they have to make ad
money now you'll see many of them they
will tell you you know like ten rules
how to write things like that and one of
them is you you you should write in a
passive active voice and they give you
examples of what's passive voice what's
active that's completely wrong okay
that's totally incorrect in with respect
to the actual grammar fumbling from a
linguistic experts such as this guy you
know it's just I'd like because I read
it you know I read from one of their
discussion about that it's just active
voice versus passive voice so what I'm
saying is that the the way most people
understand active voice in grammar is
just totally wrong it's just incorrect
factually incorrect it's not the crap
it's not it's incorrect grammar that so
anyway so so I wrote the here's another
essay I wrote about it's kind of humor
okay anyway so that's
so let's active voice passive voice yeah
so let me talk about that a little bit
I'm not okay so so actually I prefer
passive voice you know why because why
you know hold on a second hold a second
is got some comments I have to come in
but let me talk about the active voice
first okay so active voice - you know so
I like to write in a hundred percent
pure or passive no voice no active voice
at all
why because let's see why I'm well I
have to I have to kind of explain what's
active always in what's passive voice
but um anyway let me be the comments so
Vega
Vakil okay I have to cover my eyes
because I'm going cross-eyed cuz I hate
so what happened to your eyes Captain
Hook
oh yeah so because sometimes you know I
have course I a little bit cause I since
I was even when I was young so but
sometimes you get bad so when when I get
back like I can look at you from either
one of my eye you can tell right eye
left eye right left eye so and you know
sometimes I get double vision so that's
why I cover it so I get beat up or
something no you should read Robert
Greene's book that name sounds familiar
but I don't
remember who is he Robert Greene Robert
Greene
Robert Greene boom 1959 his American
author known for his book on strategy
power and seduction
he has written six international
bestsellers so usually when someone that
has that that's no good you know meaning
that it's he's the guy is probably no
good you know whatever his content
he has written six international
bestsellers 48 48 laws of power the art
of seduction the third the 33 strategies
of war the 50th law yeah I don't think
it's good it's pop you know it's like he
you know when you see this kind of I
don't know for sure but just by now my
impression is that it's just you write
for the pop you know you write whatever
crass popular you know so so you so you
get isn't you know it's like cat
pictures on Twitter it's like that's
that's you know everyone so everyone you
know you write something not
sophisticated to please the population
the masses so everyone you know like one
of the book men are from Mars Women are
from Venus was it's that's like that
most idiotic so Sir Robert Greene okay
and writing comes from the heart
exactly good point imitation is the work
of apes with writing utensils you should
never copy your writing style okay so
can so anxiety a sophisticated surfaced
specializing in sultry seductive
sciences of speech really does that
describe me sophisticated Sophists okay
surface is someone who make you know who
surface is basically a snake snake or
your Petra you know he like it means on
the surface he's making you know logic
and reason and philosophy and teaching
but actual the actual content is
actually twisted it doesn't you know
it's not logical it's not solid it's not
true you know that's what surfaced me so
how can you how can wine define surface
you know like I said I mentioned these
few times in past videos I used to the
way I learned English is by reading
literally looking up dictionaries 100
more than 100 times a day and I've been
doing this for modern for more than 10
years like for 20 years and I still as
co2 you know like took up dictionary
like now every almost every day but you
it used to be like more than 100 times a
day for over ten years so to the degree
that you know any word you know I can
you know a dictionary you know I can I
can like I can like I can open exactly
on that page with you know that that
page will be the world you know and I
can also for me was I can define like I
can give you a definition from the
dictionary almost word for what
especially the merriam-webster
dictionary so surfaced so surface the
someone who practice you know the
dictionary USA stuff is someone who
practices sophistry okay that's one way
they say it now so what is sophistry how
do you define it I mean what how would
you define
dictionary so Sophists would be not you
know Safi streets of history's surf
history would be the I I'm probably
wrong because you know I haven't looked
up dictionaries like before but it would
it first of all what its does it mean it
means sophistry how can you so what what
we are trying to do what I'm trying to
do now is try to explain sophistry in a
dictionary style you know so as you know
so sophistry is
oh that's interesting so sophistry is
anyway so I think I've been talking too
long don't you guys agree so okay I got
seven people oh my god I've been already
talking for 80 minutes you know one of
my problem with my video is that oh no a
second
so I'm the problem with my video it
because it's not pre-announced so in the
beginning 30 minutes nobody is here but
then after you know after an hour
there's more people right yeah only six
or seven my neighbor my roommate is back
so so we were going to define sophistry
I give up
so sophistry is let's just look it up so
what is this close this close this close
sci-fi Keys sucks our talk show let's
try that so sophistry possible but fat
Philippe fallacious Oh argumentation
okay plausible but fallacious and
argumentation to a possible but
misleading of fallacious argument
okay that's sophistry in explained in a
manner of a dictionary so a surface so
sorry or some sophisticated surface
specializing in sultry seductive
sentences sciences of switch what are
you talking about a surface is an
philosophical magnet attracting
audiences with captivating debates on
the intricacies of cultural and
linguistic factors so you're saying
you're talking about me the best way to
learn English is to study the Sophists
philosophical debates with us oh credits
Socrates that's how you supposed to
pronounce it so carefully for the use of
clever but force arguments especially
with the intention of deceiving yeah
that's a good way to put it
so anyway I think that's maybe that's it
for today you know random topic so we
were talking so what about green Robert
screams so
is what's good about him 48 powers 48
laws of power greens Facebook the 48
laws of power first published in 1980 a
is a practical guide for anyone who
wants power observes power or wants to
arm themselves against power okay so the
you know the law our distillation of 300
3000 years in a history of power drawing
on the lives of strategists and
historical figures like niccolò
machiavelli since yeah so I suppose
that's a good book it's pop book yeah
you know I remember I think yeah I think
I remember hearing about this book this
is not from 1998 you know I think anyway
so element of style
what's passive voice what's aggressive
voice you know I like passive voice I'm
not going to explain what they are but I
like in my writings you know I want to
be the most pass passive possible
because when you would actually achieve
that you have written the greatest you
have written in the in the style of the
greatest mathematician okay
the suitable for mathematics you don't
want to you don't want active voice
you don't want active voice okay you you
you want right you know not always okay
in certain context especially when you
are writing about mathematics okay
Oh science research paper for example
you want to be the most passive possible
meaning that in your writing you never
address the audience you know you don't
like you don't write oh maybe you you
know you you want your writing to be a
scone
as austere as possible never address the
audience never you know contains any
emotion words you know nothing like that
you describe you know technology or
mathematics or some science theory
science theory as coders oh skiers you
know as a lot as logical as possible
it's almost like you are ready like you
you you can you can write the whole
thing in symbolic logic you know with
that's a different thing okay without
any English any English words at all
symbolic logic you know that that that's
another thing but anyway so but if you
are writing English you know you could
write in such a way and in fact I I
think quite a few mathematicians do it
that way that's that's a style I like
okay and it is also a style in in much
of my in lots of my web not today though
in a lot of my writings you know as cold
as possible you know and and so you know
so why why because you know because that
way when you like when you were right
math in the in the most passive style
what it actually means is that your
writing becomes pure content I mean it's
it's you know like you know for example
pure content it's like hundred percent
pure content you know like recently I
read you know like some someone died by
accident you know people don't know if
it's a suicide owner it turns out it's
an accident why because he he drunk
something in the morning he you know he
blog he did a video blog he drinks
something him he makes something protein
powder or something and he drunk and the
next next day he's dead turns out he put
a tablespoon
of coffee of the coffee condensed coffe
coffee power okay
pure coffee power caffeine you know
powder caffeine powder one tables 1
teaspoon kills you
caffeine powder because it's pure you
know so that's that's what purity means
when you have something pure there's
nothing else like a chemistry element so
when you write mathematics in when you
let's say when you talk about I'll give
you a web presentation you know you are
teaching you know new theory you found
or whatever you are teaching math
describing a theory when you can write
in the hundred percent purity that every
word I describe the the logical content
of your thoughts exactly
that is pure and and when you have em
and when you have that such a writing
you will see that it's an absolutely
passive it's absolutely passive it's not
that it's not the active voice okay so
this ETF people with the studio active
voice you know this you know pop you
know popular that's what it is so
carefully fold yeah so so Vargo macro
may colitis so what are you Mack Raghava
colitis says sorry a cornucopia of
conscious considerations to condense
collegiate clutter into into queries
clarity okay a an X attention an
existential egalitarian existing in a
esoteric earth well emulating
educational earnest T yes what are you
saying so what is your problem what is
your beef so you must
you must have read something you know
maybe a lot about me say it okay let's
say whatever so that's it for today I've
been talking for 90 minutes in random so
there is something I want they are
actually they are so we talked about
alliteration oh is that what he is
that's what he's doing
oh yeah under the undergraduate math
degree courses that's interesting I
wanted to talk about that math blog
oh that's a lot of things to talk about
Galois Galois theory you know cholera is
one of the most way or no mathematician
because he he's because of his dramatic
life stories he died young like he died
when he was 19 in a duel
you know like pistol okay I guess pistol
duel over a girl something like that
okay says skull oh is it supposed to be
pronounced Carla is he's a French
mathematician and but he you know but he
created one of the great basically he
invented group theory he's not so it's a
favor you know anyone who study math
history we are now he one of the most
well known Galois mathematician and this
is how he looks like
Sawako make the tease Margo maker
Leiter's says a larger-than-life
luminous light of liturgical license
okay God wah and a bow is also a great
mathematician they are related I mean
because their study happens to overlap a
lot and Abel this Neil Henrik Abel also
died young he died when he was 20 years
old
in poverty but he also you know did
great math stuff and you know math stuff
logic free variable and logic principles
of explosion principle of explosion
anyway so that's math complem 14 oh yeah
so I wanted to go to anyway that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
any questions or comments or last what's
your last word you have ten seconds to
type it
they now address it or maybe not you
know until tomorrow do you have any last
words dot dot dot
peace out