am i okay am i back online this [ __ ]
modern technology this [ __ ] modern
technology [ __ ] no audio so let's repeat
again mm today's 2020 may 6th 3 o clock
39 minutes in afternoon San Francisco
time am i doing okay hi guys
okay I'm back online
yay there we go beautiful data structure
the [ __ ] modern technology [ __ ] you
know so I can actually my head my head
says set is not plugged in and they are
rotating and then the OBS crashed and I
have to restart and restream ok so today
we have quite a few topics I prepared
for you let me show you ok let me show
you magnify wait okay magnify and show
in browser so we have three major topics
and let me know which one you want me to
go first because they I think they are
going to be long so the first one is
male and female voice singing so they
are spectacular Chinese singers who is
male not not the Western trans [ __ ] okay
Chinese smell but they sing in female
voice I mean exactly female like you
cannot tell you know it's just female
and they can switch between male voice
female voice and voice acting voice like
anime anime girl voice this fantastic
incredible and we have castrate our
singing which is people eunuchs singing
so I'm gonna talk about that there are
several songs I'm gonna show you I'm
gonna tell you the links in so you can
listen to them afterwards so that's the
first general topic male with female
voice singing then we're gonna talk
about the other big topic is keyboards
and mouse how to avoid Mouse hanpan
and Logitech G hub the new logic tech
software for their gaming keyboards and
mouse is worst [ __ ] and best mouth
best mouse buttons map okay I'm gonna
talk about that and middle middle button
Mouse middle button and mouse right
button the intricacies and complexities
about those things you know there are
there are many things to talk about them
so this is my current mouse many things
to talk about them
so that's the so first topic female and
male voice singing then keyboard and
mouse and so the other topic is Chinese
okay I'm gonna tell you about Chinese
writing system and Chinese input system
how do you type Chinese I'm gonna break
it down so it becomes easy to understand
and Alan Alan here is our expert Alan
studied Chinese for like ten years
Alan is a linguist so which one should I
go first
male female voice singing type it okay
or keyboard and mouse or the Chinese you
know write in Chinese I'm gonna
demonstrate writing Chinese like with a
pen with a pen tablet because I have I
possess this I possess this
I possess this this modern technology
okay you see tablet so put so type it
which one shall it be
and which one shall it be so let's see
mouse ergonomics okay let's let's talk
about that so let me read the comments
mouths okay mouse to person once mask
good morning Emily good morning Alan
morning mark
bearers of are you in Russia
good morning Ripper wotty wotty theory
who needs comic anyway Emily needs it
first time here hello and Alan in from
over the world Mexico saludos saludos
Mexico okay so you guys coming in ribbon
and Gateway is indicating show so okay
so let's start talking about my mouth
okay yeah I did I did a video talk about
writing in Chinese but you know we can
do it again so anyway so let's go back
to the topics the mouse okay the mousing
okay the first thing is I'm gonna tell
you key a logitech you know Logitech
came out with a new software for their
gaming keyboards and mouse it's sucks it
sucks donkey ass to such a extreme
degree that I would start buying my
Logitech mouse and keyboards okay so so
Logitech has a new let's see if again
but Logitech G hub worst mouse software
and worst keyboards over weather worst
[ __ ] you know what they are trying to do
is that they are trying to catch on with
the cloud system so before so before
this version G hub their software is
called Logitech Gaming software
basically your keyboard driver you know
so when you buy a gaming keyboard or
Mouse from Logitech you install this not
detecting any software so you can you
can hold on second so you can program
all the mouse keys for example program
into the memory in the mouse so that you
take the mouse to walk to any computer
Linux Microsoft Windows or Mac you just
plug it in and your mouse buttons will
be what you programmed it to be you know
because they are stored in memory on the
mouse that's fantastic and this this is
a Logitech Gaming software that's the
name but however about in 2019 they
can't come up with a new version which
is I think it's a complete rewrite a
total new software it's called Logitech
G hub the [ __ ] gaming chemist idiots
so what G hub you know so G hub is
trying to be more like cloud it's trying
to be completely cloud so that I mean
the goal I suppose the purpose I mean
the intention is that you know if you
are a gamer you know you don't engage
your camera idiots you play all the big
games you know tens tens of games so
that your mouse you want it to be you
know depending on which game you are the
mouse button changes you know changes
you know so in order to do that you know
either you have to put a lot more memory
so you have more profiles or you can you
know connect to internet cloud-based so
they so that's what they are doing
cloud-based but the problem is that
first of all the jihad' software is
extremely lousy you know GG hubs
software is very bad and you know GG hub
software is extremely lousy like you is
how to use not intuitive and also I
found that it's difficult to program if
you want to you know set your keys or
map your keys or buttons into thus the
hardware itself
so that's the Logitech G hub is really
really sucks donkey ass it seemed
impossible to use you know because I I
found out because I was trying to you
know I want to reprogram my mouse you
know I want to change some buttons so I
went to Windows I downloaded you know
the latest G hub software and it
basically bricked my mouse like because
I cannot set the buttons I want to I you
know I started to change it and I cannot
able unable to change it back so I stuck
with buttons that I never use you know
so it becomes you know I have five extra
buttons on these Mouse then but after
using a software those screwed up so the
buttons they are doing functions I don't
need the Logitech G hub [ __ ] and this is
followed by you know the razor don't it
never ever buy anything from razor razor
is doing that razor with the earth you
know this camera idiots there's you know
they they cater to gamers so their
software always have some kind of fancy
name for example Logitech G hub you know
hope their ass and razor have their you
know what they call you know there is
some idiotic name razor the software
some electron some [ __ ] you know the
gamers like that key or you know
whatever the doom or whatever
idiocy so Logitech G hub ok don't buy it
so so so they are new software screwed
their software so bad that I think you
know before I think Logitech is the best
software possible a man or gaming among
those gaming mouse devices brands I've
tried algae tech is the most the best
software because for me I'm not exactly
a gamer yeah actually I'm a very
addicted to games you know but that was
before you know in the 1990s so today I
don't play I don't haven't played three
games games but anyway my point is that
for me why buy a mouse I want a gaming
mouse because usually almost always
skinny Mouse has much more functionality
for a programmer ok I'm a programmer
also I browse the web I have a lot
custom buttons and setups for example I
can press a key to do things I don't
have to control something something you
know [ __ ] up your fingers everything is
single press for example copy/paste
switch to last tab previous tab close
tab back to previous page next page you
know it's all in zoom out zooming you
know magnify it's all within the mouse I
don't have to switch my hand you know
between mouse and keyboard and dude you
know a spider hands [ __ ] with ctrl alt
meta [ __ ] those those eMac thing those
are is I inducing so you want to avoid
that so so so so for me a programmer you
know I I wanted so first of all you want
to usually some other mouse are good ok
but they are not gaming mouses for
example let me show you so here is my
you know you just search for Kasauli
keyboard and you'll find my keyboard
block in Mouse so all these Mouse's you
know most of them are you know branded
as gaming mouse but some of them are not
you know for example this one Logitech
MX master those are not branded as
gaming but so they are very good as well
and also Logitech MX
energetic MX ago the trackball very good
but but in general the game in mouse has
far more much more features you know
like 1020 buttons it allows you to do
lots of things so the choice of buying a
mouse usually you want to go with Gaming
Mouse usually but these two Logitech MS
MX master is good so giving us but once
you buy a gaming mouse you are kind of
into the gaming community [ __ ] you know
so their gaming software usually looks
extremely ugly impossible to use you
know they want to appear to the gamers
like high tech you know none standard
buttons non-standard window with fancy
borders new young you know like high
tech you know [ __ ] space out spaced
out [ __ ] you know impossible to use but
anyway the Logitech does their software
Logitech Gaming software before is very
good but now with G hub you can now it's
hard to program your mouse and stuff so
that's one of the thing
so any comments questions so what the
[ __ ] how can now have a how can the [ __ ]
how can now have an ergonomics what myth
consciousness says okay manual ara says
I thought you were going to have a
trackball Mouse yes I have I'm from
Russia actually but I do not live there
I am in UK right now ok break the loop
says but setting them up with Chi hub is
pain yes and here you figure out the
config interface so the good news is
that Logitech might still have onboard
memory yes that's a good news big loop
break the loop says Logitech G hub
interfaces indeed annoyingly in early
intuitive you know it's not just any
really intuitive because I try to use it
I there's something I cannot do you know
I cannot set the buttons to what I want
so it's I think it's I don't know for
sure but I think it's beyond just being
into an intuitive because it kind of
breaks my you know these mouse you know
I I was using it so great but I was
thinking changing some buttons then
there is good data
but luckily here's an important thing
the logitech came in software you know
the older version named logitech gaming
software is still available on their
website so you go there download it now
and download it save it okay just in
case you not be available anytime soon
but the question you know there's one
thing I don't know for example I'm
thinking of I want you know I'm thinking
of getting this mouse for example this
gaming mouse this is new in 2009 so if I
get this mouse
you know I I'm am I stuck with the G hub
you know you know you if I cannot
program my keys into the memory then
then basically I would have wasted my
money on these Mouse but so the question
is is the Logitech Gaming software you
know the older version will work with
these Mouse I don't know so you know
this is a pretty bad situation for
Logitech so that's one thing okay let's
talk so let's let's talk about the other
topics so go back to keyboard and go to
how to avoid Mouse hand pain okay so
some people it's a frequently asked
question someone you know asked me about
they have hand pen with the mouse so how
do you avoid it so two things I think
that's the most important okay one thing
I do is you use a Hoover Creek that
means when you move the mouse cursors
you don't have to click like I never
clicked with my mouse that's a great
time-saver I mean that has saves your
hand it's incredible I'd like all the
things you see I'm doing right now I'm
not clicking anything I just move the
mouse stop there and it does a quick
quick so this is usually called trail
you know yeah I just covered Hoover
quick so I have this article that tells
you how to set them up for Linux for
Microsoft Windows and for Mac yeah they
are available for all these three
platforms and I'll tell you how to set
them up you can just search for Sally
keyboard blog and you'll find this
article so so Hoover Creek is the most
important thing in my opinion if you
want to save you know if you have hand
pain with the mouse then the other thing
is okay when you hold the mouse okay let
me show you some videos then let's see
hold on a second let me see if I can
show the big picture
no I don't have it set up so in order to
set that up the OBS might crash and I
don't know so let's try to think doing
this so you see my mouse so so this is
normally on a second let me see if I can
so no more reaction actually I don't I
don't I never heard the mouth like that
you know the palm grip this grip this
grip is going to do you do you hump
because because you you you you want
your hand to be in general like that
like natural position you don't want it
to be a flat like that
so if you do and and this puts tension
like tension and whenever I see people
do this on movie movies for example
Jurassic Park you know I see them do
these smooth things and click you know
it's funny like you can see extremely
awkward you know they quick that's pain
so usually I just I try to not hold your
mouse at all
I just nudge it push it push it around
especially with the auto click so I
don't have to click you can see my
windows turn let me show you you see my
windows turn I'm not clicking anywhere
and I can scroll let's go to a lone page
I can show you my skull you see
[ __ ] well so it's fantastic so let's go
back to there
okay so I'm back here let's put the
so yeah so avoid mass spent try to use
Hoover Creek you know there's one thing
important about Hoover Creek is that you
have to get used to it because you know
by now I have used it for like seven
years or eight years but I remember the
first time I tried it after one day I
cannot get used to it because every time
you stop the mousee your to a quick so
you are if you are not used to it you
know it's very annoying like of a sudden
you it's switched your windows very
annoying so you have to actually you
know spend stick with it for a few days
get used to it
basically you'll be you get into a habit
of always parking your mouse somewhere
that's not active like you know for
example you know otherwise your click
into a link for example I you know I put
it on a link or quicker link so you have
to try to stick with it for a few days
to get to you used to it by the way now
they sell you know I tracking devices so
I haven't actually used that and I think
that is a good device to use with kuva
click like when you stay at something
you do a quick but I'm not sure how good
that is
some cameras are using using that so
Hoover click is a one great way to save
your hands from mouse pain mouse in pain
the other thing is you know just don't
hold your mouse like you know palm grip
you know it like not you know don't
touch it at all when you are not using
it
so that's the most that's and I have
instructions on how to set up the Hoover
quick so that's I think that's the most
important thing the other thing is about
you know how to buy so you can try
economic Mouse for example this one I
think it's very good trackball and also
this trackball topic so this is I think
these are the best ones Logitech MX ago
become huge trackball Emily has that
Emily is using it ever come deft
protract wall in Kensington you know
this one is a cheap cheapest one the
only problem with this one is it only
has two buttons
so anyway I'm not going to talk too much
about trackball because we did before
about how to choose a trackball what
what are the differences of the many
travels of course you can also get a
vertical mouse you know so this one so
let me show you some vertical mouse for
example you have things like that very
vertical so like this one this one
Logitech MX
you know this one I've never actually
used the vertical mouse but they are not
very appealing to me because what
happens is that with the normal Mouse
when you press you are pressing down you
know there's a gravity you don't have to
but with a vertical mouse because it's
sideways then you have to exert force
you have to kind of like squeeze some
sort of squeeze motion so that you know
that means more stress for your hands so
I'm not sure I don't know for sure but I
never because I never used the vertical
mouse but that's it they are not too
appealing to me I'd rather you know for
example this MX scoped it's not extreme
vertigo it's rather you know still kind
of flat so I think maybe this is a
better choice and there are also also
other weird ones for example these 3d
ergonomic ones it's a it's a stick you
know you move the whole thing I think
it's too much trouble and also you could
always try you know the you could always
try the paint habit for example it you
see do I have a hold o click on
yes I have you see I just moved my pen
but actually when you use a pen you want
to turn the auto click off because
otherwise it's very annoying because for
the for the pain it's very easy to click
something
on the Maggi the paint's problematic
because since the upgrade yeah anyway so
you could try a pin so what else break
group I'm actually trying Auto click now
and I like it hello super fantastic I'm
going to try a little quick okay so what
do you think so mark says what do you
think of the wait that more and more
laptops now just have pads to move your
finger instead of mice which use your
whole hand so track trackpad you are
talking about trackpad so if you are
using a trackpad you know one way to
avoid problem is that you want to turn
the touch click on so you know you just
touch the trackpad here do a quick
because otherwise you have to press hard
on about usually on a bottom side you
know of the trackpad that's very hard in
annoying creates han pin and also track
track pad pad makes force your hand to
be that way you know usually you want it
that way so the trackpad force your hand
that way I don't like trackpad trackpad
myself because then your fingers is
rubbing on a thing all the time
you know that's kind of very I do not
like that feel using your fingers to rub
your on a pad
so reaper says repossess the way you
suggest moving a mouse with your fingers
seems like it would work even better on
a large trackpad yeah so you know so
Apple Apple their trackpad is actually
very good you know the latest version
because typically on a trackpad you can
feel when you move your fingers on the
surface your finger doesn't feel good
okay just like your phone you're you
know robbing you know robbing your
fingers are gas very the feeling is not
so good but however however Apple
there they are trackpad if you have seen
it touched it you know the the version
the white version
it feels quick but however I don't think
I like trackpad because with trackpad
your your finger after a long use you
have this symptom of you have this
syndrome of you know making your hand
like in this position or in this
position all the time you know because I
you know because I'm using a tablet let
me show you
actually let me set up the can set up my
can I set up my so I'm going to set up
my camera so it you shows full screen
okay but I might be out for a minute let
me try it
you
yeah the OBS have a problem because
every time I
every time I try to set up the
Preferences it crashes every time I
saved by preference it crashes so I
cannot so let's not do it then so let me
just show you this trackpad okay so I
mean this is my Microsoft [ __ ] and I
won't show the [ __ ] on my table this it
so this is my Microsoft Surface tablet
it's it's not the best one okay it's
it's not bad okay but once you use a pad
that you have to your finger is you know
stick stuck in this position after a
while you don't I don't feel good I
rather prefer to use a pen pain is much
better so that's about that what so next
next topic okay
so how long have I been talking okay I
don't
I cannot tell now is that data somewhere
here twenty nine minutes already [ __ ]
okay this is talk about next thing
so that's how to avoid eyesight for your
mouse end so let's see next thing this
mouse buttons for browsing web okay let
me show you
so I've got this so my mouse right now
is this one not that one they have this
one is Wireless I have a holder wired
version so this this is my mouse and you
know this is my setup for browsing the
web okay so I'm not sure you can see it
let's let's do this
okay so what you got is browser back
button and wait not this one not this
picture default said this is this one
okay so this is for Windows browser back
button this is close the current tab
these two keys are the most easy to
press and browser back verge back-end
close tab is frequently use these two
buttons our next tab in previous tab and
the mouse scroll wheel you push it to
the right it's zooming push it to the
left is zoom out you click the middle we
owe the mouse wheel its default zoom and
that's about it and this button this
third button
I said it to middle quick so you know
there's not enough buttons actually I
also want a button for copy and paste
copy especially copy it's one of the
most frequently used command because
once you select something you want to
copy typically one after you select you
almost always want to copy it so
normally you press the right button then
a context context menu then you have to
select it that's no good you want to
rather you know use masters like and
press a button a or just copy or you
switch your hands back to the keyboard
and control C that's no good so you want
a button on a mouse for copy and also
paste would be nice but Percy but I you
know I this this mouse only have 1 2 3 4
5 kind of five extra buttons is they are
all used ups so the more buttons are the
better
so that's about that for keyboard and
mouse anything else
yeah so another thing let me tell you
another thing so you know actually so I
asked people I did a poll on Twitter a
better way to treat or banned me
yesterday so I Twitter banned me
yesterday let me show you the picture
okay
okay so new knee motion new motion she
calls sicko are you the guy on discord
so he says why don't you control +
squawk wheel to zoom in in Windows yeah
that's very nice window has that feature
however the problem is on the Mac you
don't have that feature which is painful
on the Mac you cannot the you know
there's no shortcut you cannot you know
control squawk wheel or the command
scope wheel or the option doesn't work
you cannot zoom in zoom out that way so
it's a problem so you see for example
right so I got this mouse so I have
three profiles for example right now you
are seeing readies for Mac Brewis for
Windows and white is for Linux so I have
three profiles and this mouse only
allows three profiles so when I'm a Mac
I'm using my profile on windows window
father why because on the Mac so big
because
for example on Windows if I'm on Windows
then I do not need you know to program a
button to zoom in zoom ah because on
Windows to zoom in zoom out is very easy
you hold down ctrl key and and push the
wheel very easy and intuitive because
you know zoom in zoom out they are they
are actions such that it's most fitting
for the wheel it's just like volume up
and volume down some volume but on the
Mac you don't have that so so on Windows
so here's the problem you see on Windows
I do not want to program a extra button
for that why because that saves me you
know those buttons for doing something
else that I need to do such as copy and
paste but if I do that on a Mac then I
don't have the you know I cannot sue me
and zoom out easily so so so that's why
I have to do it on a mouse but in
general you see these these things
create frictions because I'm using these
mouse so I'm used to you know I'm used
to merge the mouse wheel right or left
to zoom in zoom out now but if I switch
to Windows sometimes on my windows you
know
if I want to make the button map to be
the most efficient now in the case of
Windows I do not want extra buttons for
zoomin zoom-out but however the thing is
I'm used to this Mouse so so I have the
muscle memory to do that you know to
zoom in and zoom out so there's kind of
a conflict you know which one you're
gonna choose you want the most optimal
efficient but a mapping for your
operating system
or you want to have the convenience of
muscle memory you know staying the same
muscle memory everywhere with this
particular mouse you know so there's
these kind of issues so why why is this
issue interesting because this is
interesting because when you for example
me biomass or you you know you want to
you want the most optimal you know we
are nerds we want the most efficiency
efficient mapping of the buttons but
then you run into this problem you know
you have two choices either you have the
most optimal efficient mapping of the
buttons such that the most easy buttons
are mapped to the most frequently used
functions you know that's the most
that's the best mapping optimal mapping
of the buttons either that but if you do
that then you have a problem because you
use it using the same you know hardware
but once you are on a Mac you have to
change your thinking you know because
I'm a Mac this button to something else
it's no longer your muscle memory in so
in that sense it's inefficient because
you is it's kind of like modo okay you
have to know which you know you have to
know what is your current software so
there's this yourself so the point here
is about the concept of optimal you know
at most efficiency it's not an absolute
idea so there is you know there's
trade-off there's no absolute idea of
what what is the most efficient key
mapping it depends on you know there are
issues complexities so that that is the
point
to say because normally you know we you
know notes without thinking you know
without actually actually going through
all these we intuitively think there is
one universal most efficient you know
keep you know but a mapping or chemo
almost but I'm mapping but that's
usually not the case the other thing
interesting is that you know that's
that's true you know the other thing
interesting is that for example I design
a lot keyboard mappings you know for
Emacs for example South like keys and I
also have tons of shortcuts on wheat for
Windows or Mac so
just just like the mouth situation you
know I'm thinking I want the most
efficient one you know one map to rule
them all the this this mapping is the
most efficient but actually that concept
is kind of it's not absolute because I
realized you know you know I've been
doing this I've been remapping keys
every week for like past ten years every
week every time you relearn you know
trying to find the most optimal mapping
for for these Emacs use so I want the
best ultimate efficient mapping but I
realized there are issues just like the
mouse for example I realized for me
there is a difference between the
ultimate efficient mapping for me
personally versus the ultimate efficient
mapping for the general users out there
because there's there's a there's a
significant I mean a difference of these
two choices so if I you know if I create
the utmost efficient mapping for me it
would not be good for other people so
that's a problem
so okay so maybe I think that's it for
today I kind of what do you guys think
Kathy says it does zoom in windows
motormouth Murdock's our motive stuff
like his smarts okay so so so what's the
next topic let's talk about random then
so mark says I know this is not related
to Mouse but by any chance have you read
any collagen and if you if so what do
you think of him okay I can talk about
that you know so I was in Community
College back in 1991 to 1993 Fujioka
Munich all Community College which is a
they are like the first two years of
University in USA but it's very cheap
you know that's why they are called
community colleges so I went to
Community College II so what one of the
class I took is psychology so I studied
psychology you know so they covered
Carson Carson you know as you know one
is one of the big shot in psychology my
impression of him is is he's a idiot
he he is you know he's what's the word
he's you know one of the personality
these disorders skis or podo
that's season now his season here
you know so anyway anyway they mean it
just finished as what's the name what's
the technical names ski so it pit or
something anyway it's there are there is
a personality disorder such a you know
some people is very weird such that they
always talk about nonsensical ideas they
have like it's almost like they are
talking by a god you know it's like they
have a vision they talk in a very
strange way you know some people in
history are like that very famous
mystics you know the we usually call
them mystics
so not ski so there's a difference
between schizoid and schizotypal okay
that's the world yeah
wait a second we need season to be here
let me show you skis ot pole yes he's
our tipo personality disorder so let's
read some of it
so magnify with my mouse shortcuts
magnify you know without going to my
keyboard just one single button press so
schizotypal personality disorder is a
mental disorder characterized by severe
social anxiety thought disorder paranoid
ideal paranoid ideation hotel there's a
word ideation we decide the proper word
paranoid ideation the realization
transient psychosis and often
unconventional beliefs yeah
so that's season I believe she she told
us people with assists OSA disorder vo
extreme discomfort bah-bah-bah but I I'm
pretty sure this is the right word or am
i confusing with another one schizoid
schizotypal I'm pretty sure I asked sot
PO okay so let's see symptoms come
mobility bah-bah-bah
you know the academic job ins
comorbidity Genet genetic social and
environmental diagnosis here ideas of
reference strange beliefs or magical
thinking yeah that's a one so some
people you know ideas of reference I'm
not sure exactly what that means Susan
would know she can tell me in detail
encrypted in great depth you know the
the thing with personality disorder is
that if you don't if you don't have it
you you cannot you don't you don't
understand it unless your relatives or
friend has it then you you know then you
kind of know but otherwise you for
example when I read this I I'm going
like what you know for example he says
one of the symptom his strange beliefs
or magical thinking
so I've if I have never seen a person
like that I know I have but if I haven't
then I wouldn't know you know what do
you mean by strange leaves like what for
example like what
so anyway one of the you know symptoms
is strange beliefs or magical thinking
and abnormal perceptual experiences and
strange thinking and speech paranoia
inappropriate or constricted effect
strange behavior or appearance yeah
lack of close friends yeah so anyway
it's somewhat similar to squeeze okay
anyway the the thing I want to say about
this personality disorder is like
mystics okay some people are mistakes
like they have connection with God they
talk in a strange way they have like
they they'll tell you they see something
you know like what here says you know
strange beliefs or magical thinking
so culture when I was in college you
know taking a psychology course that's
what I think you know he's one of those
sky the strange [ __ ] you know he's
talking about weird ways to you know do
things so I never I never had I never
had high thought of him car junk I think
if he's some sort of crackpot and he oh
here's the interesting thing until you
know these days Jordan Peterson Jordan
Pederson I'm sure you guys know become
it become became extremely popular and I
have studied Jordan Pederson in the past
few years you know watching and watching
quite a few of his YouTube and Jordan
Pederson I highly respect him you know
you know this personality some of you
may not agree the this so-called
controversial persons
MSU alive its check
so children Peterson so it turns out you
know I highly respect Jordan Pederson
you know I think he is extremely
knowledgeable he has content he has real
content but however he has been saying
he is saying you know he's he can see he
often mentions cardroom so it appears to
me and he often talked about culture
appears to me he highly respect Karan
so I was like kind of surprised because
I I think costume is like crackpot but
anyway Jordans Peterson respect respects
him so maybe he's good so that's that's
my opinion about Hojo anything else
what's up Alan so should we would that
be it for today or something else let's
see for 24 we begin at 3:30 so we have
we can do 5 or 10 more minutes
anything else guys say say something
okay so that's it about mouse and
keyboards and car John so let me talk
about something I want to say ok so so
here you know the Japanese keyboard so
this is a economic keyboard Japanese
keyboard in 1983 it began as a word
processor you know Japan is really
ergonomic progressive you know they had
they had economic keyboards since 1983
lots of them actually you can see our
pictures Japan has you know 1990 1983
they have quite a few different economic
keyboards from different companies
strong and you see another n you see
there are different M type you know and
this this PC something and they have
thumb shift keyboard from 1980 so Japan
you know they are
they are far ahead when it comes to
ergonomic keyboards but actually that
you know it's it's a funny thing they
never actually caught up because in
Japan mostly vast majority majority of
people they still using basically
American keyboard just just like this
almost exactly the same as u.s. keyboard
but anyway so so this one is all
keyboard and someone you know from Japan
there's a video you can watch typing on
this new input method so someone bought
one of these and took it apart and and
swapped the key switches to Cherry MX so
you can see so this is the key switches
and they swapped it to Cherry MX key
switches so now this is how it looks
like
okay what uh what else what what sir
okay so what's the next one to talk
about keyboards we talked about
keyboards Chinese let me show you some
write in Chinese okay so because I want
to show that
so I was working on this there's a new
keyboard okay George
showed me this one actually I've seen
this before but George showed it to me
so let me show you that new keyboard you
can buy just go to my website Saudi
keyboard and you'll find it so this is a
new economic mechanical keyboard it came
out in 2000 19 September so I just wrote
this page basically I didn't do much
study on it so I didn't I haven't read
the reviews exactly what what people say
who made it is it really good you know
do the full analysis on this keyboard I
haven't done that yet but however it
appears to me this is a very pretty good
keyboard okay and it's not very
expensive $120 on Amazon if you buy it
in USA
so I you know I don't know who is this
company call you know they call themself
coal mechanics project zero zero zero
one so this keyboard is pretty is very
similar to to this Kinesis freestyle
they are kind of in the same category I
know this one Kinesis freestyle this
Kinesis came in you know they branded us
Kinesis gaming but the real actual model
name is Kinesis freestyle edge keyboard
this one is very good and Ripper has it
and this one uses the same software as
my as my Kinesis advantage to right now
I'm using right now I'm using let me
show you just for a change
you see I'm using my my ultimate hacking
keyboard which is fantastic and by the
way you see my my Tanjung system you
know that's a whip show you this ok this
is a hand grip so when you are tired
that you grip it you put force on it and
I have my of course my toting boss
okay what what else oh yeah the writing
systems so let's see if I can create its
turn off auto click and put my keyboard
back to the thing cursed window save us
discard changes new
okay is see if I can write yeah
[ __ ]
why is what white background so I don't
want any selection
Oh so
now there is something wrong with this
pen setup [ __ ] why haven't I tried it
before right now it's not working
correctly
okay I you know I know what to do is I
need to
just change stuff I how are you doing
welcome back
so Emily says m-type I should do
something with that
with what Cody theory Cory theory coffee
theory
Cory theory is dependent on Alan I just
came here from watching one of the Joe
Rogan interviews with Jordan Pederson
yeah so I respect Jordan Pederson you
know when you talk about these
controversial personalities you know on
the web you know the all kind of opinion
flag flies you know some people will say
do these millennial idiots you know this
youtuber they know nothing they don't
they are not even qualified to say
anything about Jordan Pederson you will
see some of these youtubers you know
they have sizable followers you know
like let's say 10,000 of 50,000 100,000
a few hundred thousand followers in you
know this YouTube millennial YouTube
videos in general they are all eat
idiots you watch you their channel
there's nothing nothing that you know so
what's what's the difference you know
when you create when I criticize someone
you know the there is a thing called
substance ok substance what does it mean
you know there are tons of youtubers you
know you almost youtubers are the
millennial generation because YouTube
you know YouTube began you know in began
became popular in 2000's and that's
basically the millennial generation they
started to thrive you know there are
teenagers so the vast majority of
YouTube as you know the with million
followers or something they are all like
Mullane Millennials so I I have studied
them you know you watch them you know
you watch all of them basically they you
know the
many of them are gamers a lot a big
chunk of them are gamers then there are
also political commentators then there
is Joe Rogan you know things idiots like
Joe Rogan you know anyway so these are
youtubers you know the famous YouTube
stars they have millions of followers
and they make in many cases they make a
lot money more than programmers in some
cases there are millionaires just by
doing YouTube so you watch them so what
they are they have no substance you know
they are like 0 they are [ __ ] idiots
you know it doesn't matter what's their
subject matter you know some of them
they talk about gaming okay some of them
talk about political commentary some you
know some some are anti social justice
people a lot of them I watched you know
I've talked about this before you know
then this team poor get impo idea you
know they talk about their things
I watched him no substance okay so for
example there is a green it is this girl
you had a very kind of nice girl called
green what was her name green something
lassie green light Laci green lassie
green okay she is she's you know think
she think of herself was the sex expert
you know she do educational stuff for
you know women things so teaching how to
have sex you know what your vagina you
know [ __ ] [ __ ] how to how to use a
dear oh dear the way things like that
dating you know there is some some talk
about you know some women talk about
dating stuff and and also a huge
category of them are makeups women are
into that you know it's a huge industry
makeup they just they teach you how to
do makeups
except Assad you know who's got
substance that's right okay let me
explain why I you know so you watch
their stuff almost doesn't matter what's
their subject you know they their
channel is focused on you
in summary you find that there's no
substance no content zero notice what
what does that mean by substance
substance i what i mean is that suppose
you are talking about programming okay
you can talk about programming no you
what's a good example to pretend my case
you know let's say programming okay i
mean some some subject there is actually
you don't need substance such as makeup
well you need some artistic skills but
it's not like you have to study it for
ten years you know but for example let
me talk let me say something i want to
say for example let's say when you are
talking about the subject of religion
okay
or when you are talking about the
subject of politics you know a lot of
youtubers they come and they do
commentary on politics or if you are
talking about a subject of say it's a
programming ok programming now you guys
are programmers right so this is a
subject we know some programming so it's
let's say you you you want to talk about
programming but you have to have
substance okay meaning that you spent
ten years not not just the average as an
average programmer you know because
everyone gets old eventually everyone
will be like dang you know they have ten
years or twenty years experience in
programming okay everyone everyone you
get old because everything everyone will
be but substance means you really spent
like up to twenty hours a day like like
out just in scarf i study on one subject
you know you type you put your blood you
you know you you cough blood to type
into it then you have substance okay you
have substance you know you know the
subject well you have you you react you
you know you know it inside out you know
what's going on then if you do youtube
you talk about that thing that
substance okay so you know that way you
know you know one way to judge YouTube
okay you look at them whatever they are
talking you know you think you know are
you you know do you did you actually
spend ten years on a subject such that
you actually have something you know
this you know substance to talk about
vast majority no they don't have nothing
for example one of the popular you know
I youtubers you know many youtubers
become popular because they are talking
about politics you know once you talk
about politics if you are on specific
side then you will have followers you
know turns of followers tribal you know
because they want to your site to win so
many of them become extremely popular
especially if you know how to manipulate
people you know one of such example is
Oh 100 and you know the black girl you
know she's she's very kind of sinister
character although I support her because
she is anti social justice but she is
like there's talking [ __ ] you know so
there's a difference you know one thing
is that you can become extremely popular
there are certain things you need to do
to become extremely popular that's one
thing but that does not mean you have
substance you know you don't even know
what you're talking about
on the other hand you know you can be
the great in doing something like Jordan
Pederson for example
you know a lot of people on YouTube has
criticized Judah Peterson you know like
they think they know what they're
talking about
Oh Judith Peterson he's a idiot because
you know oh god is this that oh [ __ ]
yourself you don't know nothing
Jordan Peter said no things okay I can
tell even I don't know religion you know
that much but you you you watch to us
and you can tell there are decades of
diving into all the books you know on
the subject matter that's the point have
you have have you'd you know turn into
books for ten years you know not going
to parties or watching movies you know
that that's what the substance means
you know what I wonder is that you know
look at Google now Alan posted a lobster
emoji okay look
and Google is censoring it what a [ __ ]
what kind of world are we living in you
post a lobster
Google is censoring it you know that we
the [ __ ] social justice [ __ ]
have created a society like us you know
the situation you posted a lobster you
know emoji and Google is censoring that
why because there if there it is Emily
because you know why because lobster is
associated with Jordan Pederson because
he often uses the lobster analogy
because you know the social structure of
lobsters you know you talked about that
and you know in his book so Rikuo is
sensing in that incredible you know that
live the world we are living in
censorship heavy heavy censorship and
repo is like whip ripple is like a way
but this average American know about it
oh you you you are just reading Twitter
too much actually social justice
actually it doesn't exist it it only
happens in kind of wanted look look
what's going on in the world well anyway
that's the world we live in you know
that's you know depends on your
perspective you know like some sometimes
it's pessimistic sometimes it's
optimistic but I I don't think you know
the u.s. eh
our situation is that good okay I think
it's but anyway yeah anyway so okay I
think that's it for today we talked
about our anything else laughs a
hierarchy so I'm gonna write read
Candace Owens yeah that's a girl a black
girl you know what maybe yeah and oh and
by jamming okay let me tell you about
those people because I've studied them
you know you study them you look at what
their character what's their nature
where you look at what's new
Candice Owen okay she's a right winger
you know I support her you know I follow
her because I am very much against the
social justice [ __ ] so I support
her and social you know the American
left
I talked about this before anyway I
follow her so but she she's not a good
person
okay she's she she she is um let me just
pinpoint the interesting parts she is a
she is a political she's a politician
okay she's a politician type of person
she know what to do to get followers so
in the mere two years you know since
about night 2018 or 2017 she became a
superstar from nobody from a nobody high
school student she became a herbal
superstar on YouTube on Twitter you know
you she's God I don't know 1 million
followers or something she became a
superstar and now she has her she has
her own radio shows you know like like
me talk show she talk and she has good
set up you know professional room you
know studio and inviting guests to talk
about you know political stuff but
anyway she her nature she say um she's
not a good she's not exactly a good
person she is a politician type
everything she says is almost precisely
aimed to create more followers okay
that's her character and you know Fame
you know the good player in the game of
politics that's what she is
and Owen Benjamin car Benjamin is that
car Benjamin oh oh who is that
so car Benjamin it's yeah
right I think you are talking about
college Benjamin does wait I don't know
who is Owen Benjamin okay I don't know
this guy but I know Carl Benjamin no you
know also Noah's sargon of akkad
now he know okay so first of all oh and
Candice Owens
she doesn't have substance okay she is
just bullshitting she's just
bullshitting like you kind of like Trump
okay she's like the same kind of way to
grow grow followers she know exactly
what to say
and she has you know and another
important thing about this YouTube you
know the stars that you you need to have
a pretty face that's one of the
characteristics to get to gain a lot
followers but let me talk about car
Benjamin you know also but what the [ __ ]
is going on reconnect successful
okay I'm still alive right let me talk
about let me talk about car Benjamin you
know the Sargon of Akkad
so he is also someone he's like no no
substance okay now I also saw Gong of a
card car Benjamin I respect I think he's
a great person you know online and also
you guys you know you you read you know
everyone is opinion some someone will
say oh I don't like car Benjamin oh he
is idiot because these are that but to
me car Benjamin I respect him and I
think he's solid I like you know and but
however however I would say he has no he
doesn't really have substance okay he is
someone who is smart who read you know
who lead who started to read about these
issues a lot and you know a rationalist
she is just a rational rational is
average not a great you know it's not
like he is a great thinker she she
doesn't you know he doesn't introduce
anything new there is no fantastic
speech or you know that anything there's
nothing new the disease just you know
some smart guy and become a YouTube star
ok I think that's it for today so reaper
says demonic I think we've been talking
for 100 minutes already almost let's see
60 15 minutes okay so let's see
demonic violin play so Reaper says how
do you clean your mice and keyboards I'd
actually never clean them can you go
over you're rich man I'm a lazy bum I'm
not and I'm not nerd my my room is a
mess here is better anyway my I I almost
never clean my keyboards but after maybe
five years when they become extremely
extremely dirty then I might take out
the keys and clean them I did that once
okay that's it that's it for today I
guess
stream being shut down by Google for to
too many lobsters
bye guys have a good day