Hello.
Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Xah Talk Show.
We are going to code Emacs Lisp today,
or technical today. So, if you are not a
Emacs user, this video is of no interest
to you.
And let's do
and also I'm going to talk about some
news about Xah Fly Keys, okay? So, if
you are watching Xah Fly play at 1.5
speed,
if you are here, say hi.
Okay? So, let's talk about Let me tell
you about some news update of Xah Fly
Keys. Okay, let's stop this.
Let's stop this.
Three people watching. Say hi, okay? So,
news So, there's a major update of Xah
Fly Keys.
So, Xah Fly Keys
is a key binding system for Emacs. Let's
go there.
So, there's a link there, Xah Fly Keys.
So, it's a efficient key binding system
for Emacs. There's a video you can watch
this. Quite a few tens of videos.
So, it makes Emacs more efficient than
Vim or Evil mode. It's basically the
idea is that you don't have to hold down
control keys or old keys.
Uh and I'm using supply keys. So, for
example, I can delete the whole thing
there, delete the whole thing, or
whatever.
And the pink window shows all my command
calls and keystrokes. The command name
on the right, the keystroke on the left.
And I'm using a Dvorak keyboard layout.
So, if is my video doing good, say hi,
guys. So, Dvorak keyboard layout for
efficiency reasons. If you don't know
what that is, that is a keyboard layout.
So, let me show you. So, this is QWERTY
keyboard.
Uh
and that's Dvorak, QWERTY, Dvorak,
Colemak. I've talked about this topic
tens of times in the past
4 years of video, 5 years by now. So,
anyway, so
I'm using supply keys and uh
and uh yeah, so what's new is about
supply keys. So, let me So, there's a
lot changes. Uh so, let me show you
demonstrate.
Supply keys in terminal.
So, we are running supply keys right now
in terminal. Right now, it's in
PowerShell. Um
Wait.
So, can we increase the size
font?
Oh, the increase
uh well, in terminal, the
the font size increase doesn't work in
Emacs, but can you do it in uh
So, anyway, this is supply keys in uh
Wait. In uh in Emacs. So, let me
increase the font size here.
Wait.
What?
So,
control
Yeah. Okay, so.
So, that control and scroll up, that
will increase the font size. So, now
let's start
Emacs.
Okay, so.
Xah five is Xah five keys in Emacs.
Let's go to Xah today's talk show here.
Uh so, what's the news? The news is that
so, improved a lot in terminal and you
can see by default now by default the
current line
is highlighted when you are in command
mode. So, this is insert mode command
mode. So, when you are in command mode
the current line line is highlighted
even in terminal.
Same thing with in GUI, okay.
So, that's one news and which keys,
okay? So, Emacs version since Emacs
version 30, you have this switch keys.
That means when you
whenever you press some key, then
subsequent keys that's available will
show up here and together with their
command line. Uh I mean together with
their command names.
Okay, so for example, uh cancel. So, I
press space. Then
it shows me uh what's other keys
available. So, I can type uh
you know, for example, this Xah fill or
M fill. So, that makes it into one line
or single line or multiple line, okay?
So, anyway, that's uh which keys mode.
So, that is on if you are on Emacs 30.
So, basically what it does is it show
you subsequent keys you can press and
their command name names.
Okay, uh so, that is on also by default.
Uh it's in Emacs 30, so I recommend you
Emacs 30 is available like few months
ago. I recommend recommend that.
Uh, and highlight lines we talked about.
That's a highlight current line. So in C
of like keys when you are in
command mode, the current line is
highlighted, so it's easy to tell
which mode you are in. Okay, so that's C
of like keys which line mode. That's so
that's the news about C of like keys,
okay?
Now let's talk about some So the next
thing I'm going to talk about is some
Emac Lisp advanced Emac Lisp.
So in
Yeah, so let's see Okay, so let's quit
that quit that quit that.
Let's see open open C of like show close
C of like show index close to do close
close Emacs. Okay, turn off terminal.
Uh, so next thing we are going to talk
about is Emac Lisp function
keyword parameters.
Now Emac Lisp does not actually support
keyword parameters, but there's a
convention to do so.
So the you know, when you have a
function, you have
you know, like
uh, named the parameters also known as
keyword parameters. So normally it's not
supported by Emacs Lisp.
However,
so it's not supported natively, but
however, they they kind of
do it. Uh, so
we are this we are this so-called
keyword symbol and property list. So
basically this is what you call. So when
you have a command, my test,
the first argument is a
uh
normal parameter ordered arguments. So,
three, four, or whatever. Then you can
see this colon A, that's a keyword
parameter. Then the value is T.
You know, in this code and keyword B
and then value. So, pairs of pairs of
names and value.
Similar to
uh similar to like when you are in bash
or PowerShell.
Let's see.
So, I can go to uh let Let's close that.
Let's uh let's open
open
this directory in terminal. So, you can
see it right now we are in the sound
talk show.
Okay. So, I can say the
which is the list children. Okay, so
there's a huge amount of stuff. Okay,
let's do it again. The
and uh
the
you can say recurse or not.
Uh let's see uh let's say filter, okay?
Dash filter.
So, that's a keyword parameter. Filter
is the name. So, what do you want to
filter? Let's say filter JPEG. Okay?
Then give another
optional parameter
recurse.
Okay, so you can see
uh
recurse. Okay, so filter is a keyword
parameter and uh there's value. So, you
do that. So, now it shows subdirectories
of JPEG and you know, stuff.
So, that's the concept of
keyword parameters. You have that
available in Python, in JavaScript, you
know, quite a few languages.
So, Emacs does not support that by
default, but you have this like make do
uh
So,
and how do you do that? Uh
how do you do that? Here is
example and tutorial. So you can go
check it out.
And I'm going to go into I'm going to
actually work on one of my function to
change them from
you know, all the list parameters into
keyword parameter. Why do you want to do
that? Let me show you example, okay?
So this command find text regular
regular expression, okay? So we are in
sub talk show directory and we and there
are 1,500
files, okay? So let's search for
let's search for
all these files any name containing
Haskell something, okay? Find text
rejects, okay? So this function
find text
uh
find re
Wait, where is the function?
Find text rejects.
Describe function
find text regular expression there,
okay? So here's a documentation.
Here's a key and you see here is a bunch
of uh
parameters. So let me show you how to
you call that.
Uh
So here is a command. So find text
regular expression. So what regular
expression you want to search? Let's say
has
Haskell, okay? H A S
uh
Okay, Haskell programming language, but
I get let's put a dot there. Dot stand
for any character. So that's a regular
expression. And input directory
let's just say input directory is
is this this one, okay?
That's the input directory, okay? Then
path regular expression. So, you need a
regular expression to filter out files.
So, that would be dot HTML.
So, dot is a literal, so you need a
backslash.
And uh then
then you want to say end of line or uh
let's just say dollar sign. That means
match at the end end of line.
Okay? Then recurse. Do you want to
recurse into sub dir? Let's say well
recurse, let's say true, okay?
Then fixed case search, true. Then print
contexts, true, okay? So, this is how
you call this call this command, okay?
So, the problem is
you see, the problem is when you have so
many options like this TTT, you forgot
what they are. Which one is for
uh
you know, which one what does this mean
true true true?
So, very confusing. Like when you edit
some of it
you forgot what's the position, you
know, the this this neo, you know, you
forgot what's the position. So, you have
to like constantly look up, you know, so
recurse so it should be recurse, fixed
case search, then print contexts level.
So, if you don't want recurse, neo, you
know
is the first. You know, so that's why so
instead instead of this so this is
normal ordered parameters.
So, instead of that, what you want
something like uh what you want is
something like let me show you, okay?
Something
like
that's lower case, okay?
Like keyword parameters.
Recurse, true. Fixed case, true. And uh
then this uh print context level nil.
So, you want you want to be, you know,
the parameters to be something like
that. So, you can easy remember and and
the order doesn't matter, you know.
And they are optional. So, if you don't
have them, that still works.
So, that's keyword parameters, okay? So,
that's about that's this page, okay? Let
me read the comments, then we're going
to dive into technical detail of of
of
coding this function. So, let me show
you the source code.
Describe function x-find text regular
expression correct.
Am I alive and doing well? So, you guys
can see me, right? The audio is on, so
good. So good. So good. So, let's go to
the source code. So, here is the
definition of that function. You see
this
this one bunch of parameters.
Okay, so we're going to modify we're
going to change we're going to transform
this function. We're going to
modify mod rewrite, you know, this
function to use
keyword parameters instead of this bunch
of ordered thing.
Okay.
So, make a backup. Now, let me read the
comments, okay? So, but let's copy this
function
make a new buffer, paste it and save it
save it as xx
today's date
function name  el.
Okay, now go to the directory. There is
a function. Now, change the space into
underscore. So, press press fantastic
convenient command.
Now, that command is x-star tired rename
space to underscore.
So, you see this pink window shows all
my command calls.
Uh
Oh, so
Now, open that. So, we're going to
modify this, okay?
Make a backup first.
And you can see cosmetic backup and
save. And if you search this on You on
on the web chances are you will find uh
the source code. There it is.
Uh this guy this scum
well, SL, you know, Wesley, he I think
he bought my tutorial
10 years ago, something. Then he put it
on the website.
Very annoying. So, now when you search
Brave
you know, it goes to his website. You
know, I I sent him an email about a year
ago. He didn't he ignored it.
So, this guy needs to be sued. He's like
a pastor or something.
In UK, I believe.
Of you know.
So, this guy is not good, you know, this
So, anyway
you search for it, you know, cosmetic
backup and save. So, Brave is not a very
good search engine compared to um
compared to Google because it's not
showing my website.
Instead of it's showing this, you know,
this other guy's mirror, which is like
10 years old.
Uh but
you go to
uh it's if you try Google, it will work,
okay? This scum, you see, his website
for some reason shows up.
But you go if you go to google.com,
but Google is very nasty, so I stopped
using Google.
Turn on JavaScript.
Ching ching. Ching ching. Who who is
paying me? I bet I'm I'm guessing it's
Hank.
Cosmetic backup cosmetic backup and
save. So, search for it.
Ah, Jesus. You know, Google is starting
to become very So, these bicycles, you
need to
past bot test.
Am I a bot or human? Oh, I don't know.
Let me see. Check. Bicycles. Check.
Check. Check. Check. Is bicycle wheel
a bicycle? Well, it's not a bicycle, but
it's bicycle wheel, so it's part of
bicycle, I guess. And now, what is this?
I suppose it's a bicycle.
Am I a bot or not? Let's see. Am I
human? Oh, Jesus. I'm not human.
Stairs. Okay. This. This. This.
Okay, that
That's Is that stairs or not? Let's see.
Okay.
Finally, I'm human.
Cuz I make backup and save. There it is.
Backup current file. Click on that.
You see, you can get a code. So,
for example, go to directory.
Uh
refresh, you have a backup there. Close
it. Make a backup again. Go to
directory, refresh, you can see it just,
you know, you can make backup by
pressing a few keys of the current file.
Okay, so that's is that That is that
That is that. Now, we're going to dive
into a deep dive, okay?
Uh Emacs list advanced. Ching ching.
Hello, Hank.
It doesn't look like you done anything
on Emacs spreadsheets yet, according to
your website. That's correct.
Spreadsheet.
Um
well, Emacs is not usually used for
spreadsheet. So,
yeah.
And I don't think you use Emacs much.
So, anyway, Emacs uh is a spreadsheet?
Maybe. Let's see. Spread.
Okay.
Uh
no match for spread. Okay, so
yeah, I don't think there's a
spreadsheet in Emacs.
Uh but the GNU, you know, the
organization, they have a spreadsheet
application called I forgot what's
called.
Uh let's see.
GNU spreadsheet.
Numeric. Wait, is it numeric? Yes,
numeric. Yes. Kind of uh fancy name,
numeric. Okay, let's read the comments
and let's see. It's tables in org. Okay,
so the tables
in org mode can function as a
spreadsheet, I guess.
Okay, let's see let's see the comments
and and and we going to dive into God.
Control. Uh
control.
Minus sign.
Okay. So, now
how much time could this save? Simple
Postman. Hi, thank you for Soft Keys.
Fantastic. Thank you.
Soft Keys is one of my prime product of
my life. You know, like imagine I'm
dead, you know, I I I'll be dead in 10,
20 years,
then what am I known for?
Uh maybe Soft Keys a little bit, you
know, that's my main product.
So, how much uh time could this save?
Save you hand pain and tremendous time.
Hey, man, what's the name of your
whiteboard?
Oh, this one?
Oh, that's the
uh Glove AT keyboard. Okay, this is
ultimate hacking keyboard. And uh this
Okay, let me Let me Let me Let me go uh
random issue, okay?
So,
Glove AT keyboard, ultimate hacking. I
I've been talking about them like for 3
years, like almost every video I I tell
you what they are. So, you must be very
new. And this is This is uh Svalboard. S
V A L B O A R D, okay? Magnetic keys.
Mag- magnetic key switch, fantastic. I I
will be using it. Not yet.
Um
So, that's my keyboards. And go back to
end. You can find them all
by searching for Xah keyboard blog. Then
you'll see the Svalboard.
Okay, lots of photos and detailed
reviews reviews and videos. Uh you know,
Svalboard, okay? Ultimate input device.
Then Then the other keyboard, you go to
the ergonomic keyboard section, you can
see the Glove AT,
which is my favorite keyboard.
Uh okay. So,
yeah, and ultimate hacking keyboard is
also here.
Okay, these are great keyboards.
You know, I I have like over 100 videos
about keyboards.
So, I talked about them before.
Can you explain ACP says, "Can you
explain
that encoding and lexical binding
comment at the top of your snippets?
When does it apply?" Oh,
okay. So, let me So, that's a Emacs Lisp
technicality, technical detail. So, uh
where is it?
Yeah, okay. So,
So, whenever you have uh let's let's add
one, okay?
X UTF-8 a brief fantastic, you know, it
becomes that. So, that
you know, you can also see in this in
this file. So, that Okay. So, let me
just briefly explain this. So, in Emacs,
so this is a comment in Emacs this,
okay? This
is comment. You know, comment syntax.
So, this is a comment. So, in Emacs you
have a convention where you can make
Emacs
when you open a file, you can make Emacs
read
certain variables. So, basically this
means So, this line, let me take it
apart, okay? Uh let me add So, let me
let me add
So, now it's easy to understand.
So, you start you you make a comment,
then you you have that and that bracket
in the text. So, this means
the coding variable
is UTF-8 for this file.
And the local variable lexical binding
is set to true for this file. Okay? Just
for this file. So, this is a convention.
So, and and and those coding is actually
variables. Let's say uh
Uh in this case it's not a variable, but
but anyway.
So, you can see that by this, you know,
uh
if you search for Xah Emacs tutorial
um
and search for um
encoding, okay?
Or search for UTF-8 UTF-8 declare
encoding for one file. There it is.
So, you can see it is explained here.
Now, if you have multiple variables,
that's why you started to see this
semicolon, you know, that's why.
And by the way, this convention was also
used for Python and for Python 2.
Uh
for this Okay, this is a mistake. I need
to change that. It was used for Python 2
and also used in Ruby.
So, they picked up Emacs convention like
10 years ago, but not today. They
because Python 2 changed into Python 3.
So, in Python 3, everything is UTF-8.
So, you don't need that anymore.
Okay, so let's actually
let's delete it. Go back here. Copy the
URL. Go to the talk show.
Uh
showing browser.
Okay, yeah.
Oh, I haven't demo demonstrate running
that
uh
those yet. Okay, so anyway, paste it
here.
Uh showing Okay, so this this uh Emacs
this code anyway.
Yeah, so Py Python, you know, so they so
Oh, yeah, we need to edit that. So, open
that showing browser. Okay, so Python 3
go to top, search for Python. Okay, so
this actually should be Python 2.
Okay, color everything, remove that, and
actually remove that, remove that. Okay,
add a Python 2 tag, cut that, put it
here.
Syntax correct, showing browser. So, now
it's fixed.
Anyway, they don't they don't use it
anymore. So, I probably should update
this page, you know, That's this is like
they don't use that anymore.
So, anyway, that's what that means. Now,
lexical binding, what about the other
thing, lexical binding? So,
so you see there's another variable, so
you can so describe variable, there it
is, lexical binding. Here's the
documentation.
Lexical binding is a variable defined in
C source code. Enter. Now, if you have C
if you don't load it downloaded Emacs
source code,
then you press enter, you'll jump to
that C source code location. But,
anyway, this this variable just means um
makes the
um
makes like the let construct to be
lexical binding because so this is new
about 10 years ago since Emacs 24.
You know, there's another annoying thing
in Emacs
uh news file. They don't they don't say
what date it is. Okay, so
you know, they don't say what date
in in the news file, they don't say what
what date is Emacs 24. So, you have to
go to my website instead or search the
web. Emacs version history, you search
for it, you'll find it on xahlee.info.
So, Emacs 24
is
was it Emacs 24 we talking about? 2012.
So, it's like 11 12 years old.
13 years old. Okay, so in 2012 they
added this
this
this lexical
binding.
It's a major change,
kind of improvement because before that
all the let
is local.
Uh for example, when you see
uh
yeah, there. You see, this let is for
creating local variables.
But before
before Emacs 24, they are dynamic
binding.
So, and then again, what's the
difference? Well,
dynamic binding is the no-brainer,
easier, time-based local variable
binding system. While lexical binding
means what you see is what you get, you
know, like
that's what I like to call it. Uh for
example, this, you know, here all these
are local, you know, just just local to
local to this parenthesized expression.
So, when you have lexical binding, all
these are local to
God, local to whatever this, you know,
this let.
But however, there's a there's a trick.
Like if you always code your code in a
functional way, you never abuse, you
know, global variables you or you never
do like you always make your function
pure function, that is
whatever is the function's behavior
output purely depends on the
on the parameters, then this this local
and dynamic lexical
you know, dynamic binding and lexical
binding does not matter. Okay, it
doesn't matter. So, for me, I don't
really care about that because I always,
you know, since like 40 since I begin uh
programming Wolfram language, I always
code in a functional style.
But to other people, like to many
Lispers, this is a big deal, you know,
they they get excited, lexical lexical
binding and stuff.
Anyway.
So, at this rate, we are not going to
talk about technical stuff. So, we
already like 30 minutes, okay?
So, okay, let me mention that that's
what we talked about. Let's go to talk
show.
And lexical binding and this declaration
and okay, so this declaration it's need
put it into Emac this code syntax
correct.
Showing browser.
And what about this this garbage, okay?
That demonstrate
So, we haven't
demonstrate this command. Let me do so,
okay? So, let me put them into a Emac
this code block. Cut cut.
Paste there.
Now, pop it out. Okay, now it's proper
syntax color, okay? So, if I run this
code, it will search all regular
expression has
.cow in my talk show directory.
And uh
And and I forgot what those parameters
are. So, and uh
recurse true, fixed case.
Print context, okay? So, recurse true
true true, okay? So, if I run it,
you see fantastic. Then you can jump to
a currency's Haskell. They found Haskell
Haskell, okay? So, press enter, it will
jump to it. Press a key, showing
browser. So, so talk show 2019.
Okay, so that is a command. So, but we
want it to be in this form. So, we know
you know, what uh those t t t d t, okay?
Okay, anything else? Let's see. Do you
like JavaScript? Uh no, JavaScript
became crap. Became one of the most
complex programming language, okay?
Question, have you ever been interested
in designing your own keyboard,
3D printing it and so on. Yes, of
course. Now, let's put this back. Syntax
color, showing browser. Now, we got the
proper formation.
Okay, about keyboard. Okay, let's let's
digress, you know, maybe we won't we'll
skip the you know, the technicality of
the Emac Lisp because few people
know that much about Emac Lisp. So,
your question about keyboard. So, let's
go to search Xah keyboard blog
and
keyboard search.
Xah keyboard.
k k e y b o, okay. So, let's see how
many articles? 58. So, keyboard blog
archived Okay, I don't want archived, so
minus archived. Okay, 10 results.
Xah's truly ergonomic keyboard layout
best best ergo ergonomic key keyboard
guide uh
Safely keys layout, okay. Uh Xah
keyboard testimonials. That's praises of
my keyboard blog.
Xah keyboards, okay, that's my keyboard.
This one Xah no code keyboard, so let's
go look at them.
So, that's my keyboards.
You know, many many keyboards.
Uh this is these are my battle stations.
Okay, so you can see Glove 80
and Kinesis 360 and Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard and Ultimate Hacking Keyboard
and Ultimate Hacking Keyboard double
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard Ultimate of
the Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard.
And this one is Kinesis Advance
Advantage 2. That's the old one.
And here Kinesis Advantage two with
ultimate hacking keyboard. And my
others, okay? So I you know, I've done
like hundreds videos about keyboards
before. I haven't been doing them
because
because now I have Glove 80 which is
satisfactory and also the small board I
need to get into.
And also because ultimately keyboards
stuff, you know, the keyboard
is you know, it's not significant
topic because every year you got new
ones and you know, you need to do
coding, okay? Coding and mathematics,
that's how you make America great again
or
whatever your country.
You know, keyboard keyboard is not. So
you are asking my personal design. Yes,
I got one. That's this one.
Ksar no core keyboard from 2011. So that
is
my goal for this keyboard, my my
imagination. So it would look like
something like this one, okay?
My the idea is that you want the cheap,
you don't want fancy expensive $300 one,
okay? I'm thinking creating a cheap
keyboard, $50, you know,
and that's very ergonomic and efficient.
So it would look like almost exactly
like this one, okay? Like this one came
from 2018.
I designed mine in 2011.
Okay, but you know, the do-it-yourself
and China they
they made it.
Um
probably independent from from from what
I
from my design.
So anyway, so this is my
design of my you know, what I thought is
ideal. I want I like to make it cheap,
you know, $40.
Uh and uh make it standard, okay? So,
anyway.
And uh so, what about
doing it, you know? I'm I'm too old and
you know, uh so, I don't know the 3D
printing it takes, you know, a lot time
to learn. And I'm too old, you know? I
need to spend my time on
uh several math topics such as
differential geometry, proofs theories
and
uh lots of programming like lean proof
system and F sharp.
So, I don't have time to do this. And
also,
it's not easy.
You know, it is easy if all you want is
just like do it yourself, you know? You
could just create one for yourself.
Okay? And there are thousands of
thousands of them. You can see on Reddit
mechanical keyboard club or whatever,
you know? Yeah. There are millions in
Japanese
do-it-yourself community.
Okay, let's copy that. Shrink. Let's
paste post a link here so that we get uh
a record of what we talk about.
Close that.
Uh What is this? Keyboard blog. Close
it. Okay, hold on a second.
Uh let's just paste that there, okay?
Cuz I know
uh so, that and also paste that there.
And okay, and
Okay. So, yeah, so if you
They are they you know, here is a
million do-it-yourself keyboards. You
can see, you know, the creativity. Uh
Dactyl very popular and Dactyl Maltron
form very popular.
Uh and uh colosseum, this is from Japan.
I believe this is
from Japan do-it-yourself community, and
they have Jap- Jap- Japanese has lots of
these cute things.
Unlike American, you know, American
don't have cute things. American is like
huge and square, you
But
Japanese always have lots of cute
things.
Uh and, you know, Asia, basically
Japanese and China.
And so, you got Then you got, you know,
these, you know, so many. So, if you
want to create something like that, you
can do it.
But if you want actually to manufacture
it, like make make it for other people
to buy,
then it becomes 100 times more difficult
because you need to Then you become you
became a entrepreneur. You become a bus-
businessman, basically. You need to go
to China to manufacture it. You need to
talk to factories. You need to talk to
other businessmen. You need to talk to
lawyers.
So, it's
So, I you know, that's not for me.
So, anyway, that's all
that answers your question, I think.
My jacket, you know, this jacket is from
a friend
from China, my wife's friend, actually.
So, this jacket
is worth talking about. This jacket is
actually
a uniform in China, Nanjing Nanjing,
okay, there's China big city, Nanjing,
like known in America as Nanking
Massacre.
You know, happening World War II. That's
probably the only
phrase you heard about the city, Nanjing
Massacre.
Okay.
I like to mention it because you you
know, the because there's a lot politics
against
us, you know, so anyway, you can look at
look it up. Okay, so anyway, that's a
Nanching Nanking City.
There's a high school
and apparently a high-level high school,
you know, like uh you know, uh elite
high school. So, they So, this jacket is
their uniform. I mean,
I mean, the a a uniform uh of the
jacket.
So, a friend, actually my wife's friend,
gave it to me.
So, let's see. What's next? And are we
about done? 40 minutes. So, let's see.
Uh yeah, we talked about these things
these things these things. I'll leave
the coding to myself then. Okay? Because
it's going to be boring. Techni- techni-
technically, you know, very technical
Emacs these.
Jeff said said something and message
retracted.
Vortex cycles, hi.
Sefa So late, bless you. Bless you.
Uh
I think you will also be remembered for
your knowledge base. Mm.
Uh my knowledge base website, yeah.
Your opinion on God mode. Uh okay,
that's the worst [ __ ] possible. Never
use God mode. Okay, that's ancient news,
you know, like I talked about this like
Didn't I just talk about it like few
days ago?
So, God mode. So, in Emacs, there's
quite a few packages that
enhance Emacs key binding, make it
easier. So,
and and maybe five of them or seven of
them are fairly popular. The most
popular is evil mode. Evil mode.
And Mike soft like keys is, you know,
you can is very popular as well. And the
another one I I created is Ergo Emacs,
very popular. Okay.
And
So this are, you know, evil mode, soft
like keys, Ergo Emacs mode.
These are popular. But then there's like
five or six more. Okay. There's um you
know, people created after
I created first kind of Ergo Ema- Emacs
mode.
So God mode came after, you know.
It's one of them. It's also popular and
there's quite a few I don't, you know.
You know, I'm kind of getting old. So,
you know, I talked about this like 10
years ago every day. But but I guess you
guys too young. But God mode I don't
recommend it. Okay.
And there's also Hydra Hydra mode. I
also do not recommend that.
So I do recommend soft like keys
or Ergo Emacs or evil mode. Okay. Just
use these three.
One of them.
Uh
do you want to
do you want to also free be free?
No, I talked about that many times.
Okay. I have like
10s, 20, 30 1-hour video rants about
open source and free software foundation
and Richard Stallman. Just search on my
YouTube.
Okay. So I guess you are new. So I think
that's it. Anything else?
So we talked for close to 50 minutes.
Anything else? Let me check.
So, we keyboard blog, keyboard blog, by
the way, there's over 1,000 articles,
okay.
So, keyboard blog, showing browser, back
to Emacs, go to the directory, go to the
bottom, 1,400
HTML articles.
Now, if you count image files, then it's
going to be 3,000. Let's see.
duh
filter
uh
duh
Let's magnify, okay.
uh duh file
uh file and uh
and uh
duh file recursive
Okay, let's just do it. Okay, this mega,
mega, giga.
And pass it to measure, m e a s. So,
this is PowerShell.
So, there are 6,000 files just in the
keyboard directory.
What about if you say just HTML files?
uh filter
star HTML wildcard, do it.
So, 1,100
articles and 6,000 files, okay. So,
keyboards about this include trackball,
you know.
uh you know, I I I talked about this so
many times, you know, the everything
everything you want to know about
keyboards, mouse, trackball, keyboard
layouts, and and and and typing, typing
habits
uh repetitive
repetitive strain injury, how to avoid
it, keyboard layouts, letter layouts,
key binding design, and so on.
In fact, uh last week or two, I think I
talked about this went over again.
Uh yeah, so let's see. So, let's so
design of my custom layout.
Are there any cases
Simple Postman says, are there any cases
when ordered function arguments are
better than keyword name parameters?
Yes.
So, basically, the principle is that
okay, so this is a general tip for any
programming language. May it be Lisp or
Emacs Lisp or Common Lisp or Scheme Lisp
or Python, JavaScript uh or Java
or uh doesn't you know or or Wolfram
language or Haskell or Rust, okay? So,
when you write write a function, you
have parameters. You have two kind of
desire
Okay, it can get it can get com-
complicated including in Bash or
PowerShell, the command line, you know,
like parameters like this, okay?
So, in general, the most basic
concept of function parameters is just
ordered parameters, okay? So,
so meaning that, you know, so you can
say if, you know, call this function
a b c.
Okay, you know, at least the parameters
and they are ordered, okay? It it you
know, all of them are required. That's
the most simple case.
Then, you have the concept of optional
parameters. Then, you have the concept
of keyword parameters is all which is
also optional. Then, it gets
kind of fairly complex because when you
have optional parameters and
you got lots of things, okay? So,
let me write it out.
Ordered, okay, most simple. Ordered,
parameters.
Okay?
Like that.
Okay, so let's see.
Okay.
You
You may also have
uh
optional.
Okay?
You may also have keyword parameters.
You may uh let's
why you may? Because it depends on the
language.
You know, some language has this but
doesn't have that, you know, depends on
the design of the language, okay?
But if a
you know, so first of all, of course,
depends on the language, how the
language creator design, you know,
which one they have or don't have. Then,
once you have this mix of them, then it
becomes then you got other issues, okay?
Then you may also
uh let's just copy that. Copy that. You
may also have
uh
keyword parameters, then
keyword parameters aka named parameters,
okay?
Then you may also have uh rest
parameters.
Okay, rest parameters means
means like uh
like plus, okay? Plus three, four.
You know, you can have like lots of
uh
arguments, like infinite.
Uh then then
Okay, so the the complexity is when you
have all these features, then
then it becomes a problem. Wait, it is
my live stream still going? Something
Something went off.
Oh, [ __ ]
Stupid YouTube.
Am I still going fine?
Uh probably so.
Suhas, why are you still doing this? I
remember his blog from 15 years ago.
Yes, I'm persistent guy. I'm the
persistent type. You know, people call
me a troll. People say I'm the, you
know, the biggest troll on newsgroup
like 20 years ago, 10 years ago.
And these scums, you know, they died
out. You know, they become quiet like
the Pearl people. Pearl was most popular
programming language like 15 years, you
know, and the Unix [ __ ] with their
Unix philosophy.
You know, they spread, you know, they
say Unix philosophy this or that like
[ __ ] total fake news, total lie,
you know, by these Unix, Linux, and
also open source people.
You know, but then like so think, you
know, 20 years ago then
they died out. They disappeared. You
don't hear them anymore.
And today, you know, you can see they
are just totally wrong.
I want them to come back and get
flagged. You know, I want them punished.
But they disappear, you know, they
become, you know, they get married, you
know, they they don't talk about
programming anymore, or they become
managers, they don't talk about
programming. They they don't know. They
forgot that they you know, once you get
older, you forget about programming, you
know, that's not
your thing anymore.
You know, whatever, or they become or
they passed away, you know, some of them
very old.
So, that you see
So, the time goes by each generation,
let's say each 10 years, you have this
fad and pure fake news like today's Java
Java the landscape of NPM the [ __ ]
who created NPM JavaScript JavaScript
land, you know, you have the community
and today you have the Zuma generation
doing, you know, they they think you
know, they don't know history, right?
Nobody can know, you know,
when they were born they don't know
about what happened before.
The only way for them to know is read,
you know, read history. And when you
read history you can really know because
you don't you haven't lived through it.
So, anyway, any every generation you got
this fad and fake news and like people
used to believe earth are flat.
That's a prime example.
So, anyway, what I'm saying is that I'm
persistent,
you know,
I'm still doing this but they but those
people who like saying I'm a troll and
stuff, most of them like vast majority
of them they disappeared. You know, they
say Pearl is the best language any
anyone who disagrees is a scum [ __ ]
and they ban you. They actually try to
ban you. They say for example one old
another old thing is that
by the Unix philosophy [ __ ]
they say that you you you you know, you
cannot have one line, you know, for
example let's make this
uh
capitalize
capitalize and let's add period at the
end. Okay, so sometimes you have a you
know, your lines formatted long, right?
They say you cannot do that in Unix, you
know, if you do that they going to ban
you, they going to complain, you know,
this his name is Christensen something
of Pearl God.
You know, Pearl is one of the most
popular, the number one Pearl and C
programming language for like 10-15
years, okay?
From about 1950 1995 to 2005, Pearl.
So, during this time every programmer is
is chanting about Pearl and and chanting
about there are more than one way to do
it, you know, lots of slogans. Everyone
know, you know, is doing it, the
programmers and and one of them is the
you know, one of the these priests, I
call them priests, Pearl priest, is Tom
Christiansen.
Okay, I believe that's how you spell it.
You know, this guy.
Tom Christiansen, okay? One of the
[ __ ] one of the scum.
Okay, he's age 62. So,
he's like, you know, 5 years older than
me,
4 years older than me, okay? Not not too
old. So, I'm still around, but he he
basically this you don't you don't see
him in anymore. The last time I saw him
post on Stack Overflow is maybe 5 or 10
years ago.
Anyway, but back then, 2008,
yeah, that's the time, you know, 2008,
you know, actually from 1990s
to to 2000s, he's like everywhere. You
know, there's nobody who doesn't know
him, okay?
And what and one of the his thing he say
he chase people on newsgroup who post on
newsgroup and who do not format their
lines into the way Unix philosophy
[ __ ] the scumbags, demands.
So, in Unix philosophy, you know, you
need to
you should
every time you write email or post to
the newsgroup, you need you should
format your lines like that, okay? No
more than 80 characters.
Okay, so you can see
you know, you know, the Emacs ruler mod.
Okay, so you can see 80 characters,
right? You cannot you know, you cannot
if you have a line more than 80
characters that they consider very bad.
And this guy, Tom Christianson
Christianson is well-known.
You know, he he chased people.
Uh
I think did he chase actually uh
uh
uh argue with me? I think yes, once or
twice, maybe once.
But anyway, what he's well-known for
chasing people on newsgroup telling them
that you need to format your lines like
that.
You know, like total blatant
fake idiotic force
bad opinion.
Okay, but he push it pushes it.
But the thing is, you know, these people
these scumbags, they disappear, right?
Af- after 10 years, they disappear. They
uh you know,
it's So, this one of the my what you
know, it's one of my complaints
about these [ __ ] heads.
Because today you look back, you can see
lots of their, you know, the Perl the
trolling the Perl you know, the more
than one way to do it, that's total
crap. That's damaging to computer to
programming computer science.
But these people as they spread it.
Okay. By the way, this is my opinion
only.
Uh you know,
it So, you know, these people cannot sue
me. And one of them, another guy very
famous, but he's a good person, is
Randall Schwartz. Okay, I talked to him
many times.
And he's known for, you know, he So, he
is the law of programming, okay? There
is There was this so-called Schwarzian
transform.
You guys today probably don't know what
that is. But that's basically a
technique when you want to sort a list
of things, you know, like typically you
have, let's say, a list of pairs.
You want to sort by the key, or you want
you can you want to sort by the value,
right? How do you do that How How do you
do that? Well, back then, programming
language don't have that built in. So,
what you do is you
you um
you you you you make a copy of the list,
and uh
you you you you extract the Let's say,
you want to sort by the value. A list of
pairs, you know. The first item is key,
the second item is value.
Let's say, you want to sort them by
value.
If you just do the normal way, sort and
pass a function to sort,
that's uh inefficient, because for every
comparison, it needs to extract the
value twice, you know.
It
not more than twice, because every every
time you do compare, you need to extract
extract the value. So, extracting the
value is done, you know, many times,
inefficient. So, what do you do is you
you you create a new list of just the
values, okay? Then
then you
um
then you sort by um
How do you How do you How do you do
that? I I forgot that moment, but I
mean, I I know, but I just right now I
cannot
uh
try to explain it in a cogent way, okay?
So, you you get a value as a list first,
then you um
How How do you do that? Strachan?
Anyway, I haven't done this
uh
for a long time because today this kind
of thing is building in a programming
language, for example, in Python
since maybe 10 years ago.
And uh you know, so you know, if you
want to sort by some key, you just say
optional argument key, you know, key
second or whatever.
Right?
So, and I have a article on this doing
this too. I have a article, just search
for
um
Yeah, I have quite a few articles about
sort, actually. So, uh okay, let's let's
let's show it.
Uh
some code go to search the root
directory and uh sort, okay? So, you got
sort, you got 22 articles, Wolfram
language sort, JavaScript sort is
fragile, most complex and convoluted,
and by the way, that has been fixed
uh too.
And Emacs sort file by time, sequence
sort, reverse Emac Lisp sort hash table.
Okay, so let's go back. Wait.
Okay, so next uh Emacs sort lines, array
sort, JavaScript array to sorted, okay?
That's another very complexity, ugly
JavaScript because they
you know, they they they try to fix it,
so they created a new function. Uh
JavaScript sort map, Linux sort, There
There it is, one of my earliest article
on this Strachan transform
[ __ ]
Okay, by these scumbags.
You know,
basically in summary is that they this
this idiots, these people, these Unix
hackers, these Unix philosophy [ __ ]
heads, they like they like juvenile
humor. They like to create jargons, you
know. So, it makes you feel, "Oh, what
what is this strash strash and
transform? It sounds like advanced math.
I don't understand. Oh, Jesus, this guy
is a genius. Strash and transform." By
the way, that that phrase is mentioned
all the time.
Everyday, you know,
by these [ __ ] heads. By by these elite
coders, okay? Today, they are on Hacker
News, you know, these type of people.
So,
but technically, it's just a technique
to sort by, you know, by first
extracting the keys. It's, you know,
it's nothing. And and and
you know, so so, let's let me show you
my article, okay?
So, JavaScript find jaws, you know,
there.
Okay, so this matrix and so you can so
here is a article.
Uh
This article is put up in 2013, but this
is written like 2000 like in year 2K,
okay?
25 years ago.
In fact, I have a pearl library in
public somewhere. Um
You you can you can you you'll find it
if you try to search it. To sort uh to
sort matrices, okay? Basically, this
strash and transform is just useful for
sorting matrix matrices, okay?
So, so you so uh let's see if I explain
here, okay? Compare as number or as a
string, that's another tricky issue
depending on the language. Uh sort
matrix, okay? That is what you want to
do, and uh this is how you do it. And
the reverse order sort complex
objects, okay? Uh so, for example, you
want to sort these things, these file
names, but you want to extract the
number buried inside the file name.
That is the part you want to sort, okay?
So, that that's a that's a complex
issue.
So, that's how you do it in Pearl.
Uh I wrote like 20 20
25 years ago, okay, in year 2000s, okay?
Then did I explain
did I explain the Schwartzian transform?
[ __ ]
Okay, so here's my library. So, this is
dated 2005,
but actually written in 1999, okay? Uh
sort matrix, okay? So, so what it's
doing is using the so-called the idiotic
jargon by these scumbags, by these Unix
[ __ ] heads, the Schwartzian transform.
You know, why they create the jargon?
Because they
well, technically, because this guy
is a not bad a person, okay? This guy um
uh this guy Randal Schwartz, very famous
for for other reasons. You can he's well
known for details, you can read it,
okay?
They wrote books, you know, this Tom
Christiansen and uh and uh and uh
and uh Randal Schwartz, they have
written books. He he, you know, Pearl
books, one of the most famous O'Reilly
books.
Uh so,
so the Schwartzian transform is named
after the Randal Schwartz because he's
he made it very popular among Pearl, you
know, the most popular language, you
know, creating, you know, so so that is
why named after him, but it's just but
but
But when you
But you see when a computer scientist or
these programmers read this is like
insulting.
This technique is known in like in all
other languages before before who you
know whatever [ __ ] when you made it
popular.
But
But anyway, the Perl guys you know.
So it's like nothing you can do. It's
like today's Twitter you know, today's
social network. It's just tremendous
fake news but
you can't say it because everyone is
repeating the fake news.
Just like you know, like this Trojan
transform [ __ ] and that's why you don't
hear it and much more you know. This you
know
Like nobody says the Trojan transform.
Okay, that's an example of that.
Okay, bye.
Okay, SCS thank you guys for watching.
That's it for today.
Uh that's rant. That's a good rant.
Okay.
Sort
array you know, here's a story about
array
I mean about sort in JavaScript you
know, JavaScript sort is fragile and
most complex and convoluted. No doubt
and here is JavaScript specification
ECMAScript [ __ ]
But You know, so
But they okay actually I was addressing
something else. But anyway, look at the
spec you know, it's very convoluted
[ __ ]
But back then JavaScript sort
You know, so what what year is that?
JavaScript sort this is 2000 2017 okay.
But now it's fixed you know, because
JavaScript you know, so by spec sort is
stable since
Java ECMAScript 2019. So, 2019, 6 years
ago, they fixed it. Bef- Before that,
sort is unstable, meaning that if you
have like
um
neighbor things that are equal,
but after you sort, they go somewhere
else. Okay, they go um
Yeah, they they move they get moved
about, okay? That's meaning of state
stable sort and unstable sort, okay?
That's it for today.
Now, pay me, okay? If you like my stuff,
you can you can like buy my JavaScript
tutorial.
Uh click click click click go to the
home page of JavaScript in depth
and uh go to the button
and you can see where uh
wow, which plugin have you used to do
this thing? None.
Okay, that's my tutorial. No library, no
framework.
I show you how to do it pure by pure
JavaScript, okay? You and you can buy it
here.
You kind of just donate to me, 35
bucks. You you get the JavaScript you
get the download in a zip file.
Nobody
you know, you don't really need it
because everything is online free, okay?
So, you just sort of just donate to me,
okay? So, go to donation, go to
uh sardi.info
home page.
sardi.info and all the way at the
bottom,
you can Patreon me, Amazon gift card me,
PayPal me, okay? If you are working,
pay me 100, okay? Once a year, that'll
be good.
Bye, guys.
Thank you, Hank.