hello guys I am alive welcome to another
episode of sound talk show we are going
to code emac
lisp okay emac lisp emac the most
powerful editor if you are here say hi
love to see your comments keep them
coming if you are not here skip around
play at 1.5
speed because I ramble all
over okay let's begin let me uh let's
begin uh let me show you my keyboards
glove 80 fantastic there's a YouTube
review by me ultimate hacking keyboard
fantastic there's a YouTube review by me
nulia tracko fantastic YouTube review by
me actually for some of this keyboard I
have more than one YouTube
review and this
thing I like to mention again SW board
okay SV a l b o a r d
now right now it's hardwired it's
plugged
in hold on a second so you see the left
hand and the right hand they are
magnetic
switches there's a YouTube review by
me about a year ago but you check out
other V uh videos by other people
because I've been you know outdated so
magnetics magnetic switch so I'm going
to hop onto this okay I'm gonna yeah
sorry I haven't done so before so but
let me show you me you know so today so
we start to uh you know so right now
it's Hotwire so for example let me show
you you can
see wait is
it you know Annoying Windows like like
when you have a USB it
jigle when you jiggle a little bit it
um wait why is it not
inserting oh because the other part is
unplugged oh [ __ ] well anyway so I'm not
going to show but uh but this is just
fantastic okay actually I press
something that closes the window
do you want to uh save changes to
Untitled okay cancel okay let's begin
eemax dis coding the most powerful
editor comments
okay so uh am I ready so yeah sofl Keys
that's what I'm using search for
it I introduced in every of my videos so
many times so this is sofly Keys okay
ping window shows my command course and
name okay and the keystroke on the left
and uh so as you know whenever I do
something in emx then uh I'm using a
keyboard layout okay so let's go to talk
show
today sound talk show Okay so let's
begin uh let's make this right so we're
going to write two commands today write
a HTM
insert doc type that's one job we going
to
do insert HTML doc type okay the other
job is we're going to write a command a
wrapper to rot 13 so let's begin to show
you okay so Road 13 is a Elementary
encryption technology from about 2,000
years ago so let's say
something okay
selected call in emac Road 13 region you
see do it you see now it becomes cryptic
you don't know what it saying copy that
paste now select it again call the
command R 13 region do it back to
something okay so the algorithm this
encryption you can actually look up web
or ask AI chatbot okay 13 Wikipedia so
you'll explain so basically you have
alphabet so this this shows you know so
you have alphabet of 26 letters a b c to
Z okay so a becomes the
13th next letter so the 13th letter is n
so a became n becomes n and B becomes
the next letter 13th down the down the
down the rank so B becomes o c becomes P
okay and one nice thing about R 13 is
that is half of 26 the total letters of
English so when you want to change n so
after 13 letters after n that's back to
a so that that means they are symmetric
the encryption and decryption are
symmetric okay so it's called symmetric
Cipher technical jargon okay R
13 uh is that is that the cipher okay I
I think I got it right let's see
symmetric key algorithm yeah so that
means the key to deip is the
same for the key to inquip so Wikipedia
say symmetric key algorithm are
algorithms for
cryptography that use the same
cryptographic key for both the
encryption of PL text and the decryption
of PL of cyer text okay so rad 13 is
2,000 years old symmetric cyer uh the
earliest I think so if you read
Wikipedia you'll know the detail you can
ask chatbot
okay so let me double check my video is
going
uh okay two concurrent viewers okay
video is going fine yeah okay so we
going to write the command so what's a
problem you just call um so let's see
describe CH Ching crystals thank you so
much two bucks that's good for half of a
cup of coffee 2 pound pounds the British
pounds has been
degraded since it was so high uh before
I have a question I have a question it
big diversion feel free ignore okay ask
your question
Crystal so symmetric Cipher uh row 13 so
let's see uh describe uh
describe see the documentation so the
command is called row 13 region okay
uh so let's make it um text okay so this
is a text block real 13 region it's a
symmetric Cipher showing browser so we
explained how how it works now the
problem is whenever you have something
you want to you know the word you want
to R 13 it you need to First make a
selection first that part is annoying
okay I want to call command you know
press the key then the current word will
be Road 13 I don't want to make a
selection you know so you have to you
know press the key start selection
select know
so write a wrapper to R 13 uh to the
current world okay but if you have a
selection then it will do the selection
so saves you the trouble to actually you
make a selection
first and why it doesn't um complicate
things because when you if you have a
selection you'll just work on the
selection okay so I'm going to write
that so let's do let's go let's go
Brandy let's go
brandle let's uh so
so uh current word give it key okay key
binding Okay so
okay so let's
quickly
Define
documentation this will be R 13 okay and
uh okay
so okay so the command is row 13 region
let's write a nice
documentation cor R 13 region on current
word or selection you see make it
convenient okay now let's make it a
bracket you see this is the markup emac
lisp markup in inline documentation so
that it'll link to
that function okay so create
date version
okay so let's evaluate this eval buffer
okay check out the pink window it shows
all my command course eval last
SE then you can Cod describe function
SAR R 13 okay so you see s r 13 is an
interactive interpret interpreted
function okay uh call this function you
see this link you can enter and you go
to that functions documentation
see
nice that is why you see this back tick
and single quote that's what they it is
four or markup okay we're going to begin
right this um
and let me answer the question
crystals I'm sure you've been around for
when
programmers and uh let's
see I'm sure You' been around when
programmers and other Tech geekers die
uh usually they pass Specific
Instructions to friend what to do with
site hosting domain bounceback email but
notice on front page put notice on front
page have you discussed your actions
plan
for okay yeah I know the what you're
saying and I have thought about it
because during around
2012 I've been actively thinking about
that so
uh yeah so let me answer that question
so. info.org so this is my primary kind
of primary website cad.org so you can
see then it links to I have right now
two domains I have like six or seven
before but now it's just two
kali.org
and.info
so there's
you go to kali. info
click and that's all technical topic so
you got programming blogs emac keyboard
blog everything you need to know about
keyboard emac programming coding web dev
math unic code blog okay so then you got
this uh
topics Unico search uh you know keyboard
character frequency you can just paste
any text here your compute for
example you can type here and it will
update
dynamically as you type okay so this is
Javascript
typescript so these are some of the fun
things uh logo design fantastic
beautiful I study logos okay what makes
a logo great what logos are
idiotic you know there's a lot idiotic
idiotic
logos by the tech
idiots okay so there there's why
Microsoft suck you know like complete
documentation why Microsoft sucks like
almost in every way Microsoft
Windows uh the the you can play Chinese
chess okay
so that this is um you know s.
info okay classic
move Chinese chess and then you have
programming language
tutorials uh then you have a bunch of
essays on the hacker code like the Unix
phonetics what does Unix philosophy mean
why is it idiotic why python sucks
plan ping the design of programming
languages on the syntax issues for
example you are looking at syntax
algebra this is more advanced than type
algebra type Theory
algebra uh you know so this this this um
you know so many articles tens of
Articles then you have semantic noodles
semantic issues why I hate see the most
idiotic language why I love Goan why I
love poell 10 times better than bash
idy uh Powershell complexity that's the
issues with Powell so you got you know
00 articles semantic issues of
programming language design and uh all
articles related to
this programming language and why python
sucks you know so back to kali. info so
these are all technical topics math
programming keyboards okay then then you
go down then you have mathematics okay
so that's c. info now go back to
kali.org
kali.org so on kali.org you have bunch
of non technical non engineering non
science related topics such as linguis
ICS
vocabulary atmology a pit of History
musing on style notation and writing
systems like that's the orthography and
uh writing systems you know you know you
have Chinese you know 10,000 characters
you have Egyptian you know that's also
logo logograph you have
Arabic alphabetic system abjet you have
then the English you know alphab atic
system English French Latin alphabet so
you know understand dear indigenous
English you know understand you don't
understand a thing okay language and
English and uh then so this is kali.org
so you got issues on writing so there's
a
Blog then you got humanity and songs via
Human animals songs you can have a
glimpse of what they are thinking you
know for example in America we Western
English speakers you
got Prince
1999 you know what does it what what are
they saying this you know this is one of
the so popular songs you know on the top
10 charts for decades you know Prince
1999 Jeffrey EP Jeff Jefferson Airplane
White Rabbit that's another very popular
song this is very popular in the 1970s
1980s you know that's the pop star
before my time but fascinating song okay
so you got collection of like um let's
go
back uh collection of annotation of
let's see how
many 500 songs including piano classic
music okay my
annotation um
you know so you the Via as the white man
would say V are the lens of what human
animals are doing okay or more
academically that's
ethology and
ethnology of this you know you we are
those lenses you look at the songs what
an anthropology
anthropology ethology eth ethnology okay
that's the academic way of saying things
make you look
better
so so you know 500 songs in annotation
so and then s
arts uh lots of Arts uh art you know and
my comments on classic art uh Western
Classic this is what white men loves
especially today today there's this
white man eth nor ethn you know white
white man ethn State you know like a
movement in the past few month
especially on Twitter so they would they
they get excited about this look this is
white man's thing and and Jesus is the
king Christ is the king you know by the
way this is this is this one in
particular it's fling a human that is
you kill a man you you you
peel his skin and this is
Christianity okay that's not a thing I
believe in okay this Michel Angelo one
of the greatest Western
Art flame of a man and then you got
others you know you got uh um you know
lots of you know this also very famous
painting
1827 uh death of s palus
you know by Eugene
delor okay romantic painting then you
got this modern this this this is called
Art Deco Beautiful by this also very
famous woman Tamara the depa something
okay all Deco
style so you can see so this is
uh Human animals and uh they artwork
they are visual arts and there then
there is this technical art art by
Leonardo la vin viny you see this is
[ __ ] this is technical illustration
of
[ __ ]
okay so you got this paintings
annotation so all these are nontechnical
topics not related to math not
engineering not unic code not keyboard
uh they are so they are on kali.org
kali.org is all non technical so then
you got this beautiful you know another
wide cultural thing flaming
June this
symbolizes women okay they they they
they are hot you know they are the
center of humanity like you look at all
the artworks you you look at like
suppose you are God you can look at the
billions gab billions of all artwor
majority are women and all those women
majority are young girls okay that's
artwor why because women girls young
girls are the center of
humanity okay this this is contrary to
the white men's thinking you know like
today's today's American they become
idiotic they don't know they don't know
a
thing so this these are uh one category
of artwork this Western classic Western
artwork okay then you can go into you
know there's seashells then there is
modern kind of the uh back in about 2006
there's this modern there's a movement
of drawing bad girls so you have all
these different styles of bad girls each
one is
like you know I I I select I'm a uh so
I'm a editor you can call me I compiled
you know the bad man bad girl
drawing uh
phenomenon edited
byali okay so for each one I criticize I
give you a um you know my commentary
about why is this one special you know
there are so many different styles and
these are by people you know like on the
internet uh I'll get you to your
question okay uh
so you can see the bad girls you see you
got this style which is quite unique
okay then you got this style is very
beautiful this is classic demule by an
artist girl okay then you got this style
which is amazing also extremely
beautiful this you know this you got a
particular style okay so you see she
depict part uh badgirl in this way know
very um you know grotesque it's there's
a beauty in itself okay then you have
this kind of more mainstream you know
comic book artwork mainstream but there
is a unique element here that is her
content what is the the message you know
so when she draws bad girl she is
imagine this this this um this uh what's
her name that you know that what ivy
poison ivy you know like she's beheading
the B girl okay so that is that is
something you will not see in typical
American Comics the style is American
Comics but the content is not okay so
that's that makes this one this piece of
artwork
unique so that is my like my
critique then you got this style like
kind of modern um kind of like art deco
but but with that so these are
fascinating you know fascinating uh
study of artwork and Human animals then
you got this style you know like diverse
okay I collected uh lots of them so
that's one part you know part of the
modern
artwork 20 years ago 20 06 this is the
beginning like like the 2006 is like the
thriving of Internet that's that's when
Wikipedia just began two years ago
forchan just began two or five years ago
uh
redit just started I think redit just
started 2006 uh you don't have stack
Overflow yet I don't think you don't
have GitHub yet you know that's the 2006
okay go back so you got lots of artworks
you got you know then you have this qu
Circle
phenomenon uh most of them vast majority
of them are beautiful geometry this when
you look at the cop Circles of
course they are talking about UFO UFO
and aliens you know like the Joe Rogan
monkey you are getting the Jo ran
experience
The Joe Rogan idiotic
monkey but the other aspect when you
look at crop circles is this geometry
this beautiful geometry so for example
if you are a young student you want
inserting math look at any of the crop
circle you can divide you can know you
you know it becomes a
puzzle given a geometric configuration
like this one a cop Circle photo your
job is to determine how is it drawn what
is the geometric configuration that is
can you draw it on paper you have to
find out you know so just by looking at
this picture you have to like reverse
engineer what is exactly is its
geometric configuration now this one is
a little bit harder but we can pick
easier ones you know maybe maybe this
one you know so you kind of
so you have to figure out
yourself then if you are a programmer
you can go one step up you know you draw
this in wolam language Mathematica or
python if you are into python or
JavaScript you know you have to you know
code and draw this can you do that
that's a interesting thing you know this
is superior than
[Music]
the need code you know whatever the Zuma
idiots that like so have you done NE
code or
whatever can you do that can you do this
you see this picture reverse engineer
the geometric
configuration then use your favorite
language python JavaScript wol
Mathematica or Julia or
hascal or uh or
F recreate it okay and there's tons of
you can you can
do and look at this for example these
Stars uh uh for you know so so for
example these
Stars
pentagraph this five pointed star
technically is called pentagraph
pentagram okay so you got to draw this
this is this is actually a fractal
version of it
pentagram you can see kind of a fractal
pattern and you can Contin
continue the factor progression can you
do that that is question okay like my
live stream is very rich can you do
that recreate this Factor okay so that's
that's another example of a sector of
artwork then you got photograph okay
beautiful photos index these are you
know photography is a
latent uh phenomenon of art you know is
it art kind of you know not not really
but some of the you know the
photographers they think it's artwork
however in photography indeed some
photos are extremely beautiful and they
capture you know this many type of
Photography some of them they capture a
a piece of history or some of them they
capture certain Beauty you know let's
look at this bubblegum girl you know
this this captures the kind of the the
past 20 years of
American Young
Generation phenomenon
of uh of of memes okay thought thought
girls okay Jesus I'm losing my audience
so let's yeah so let me finish this okay
so so so many so these are you know
great photos this here is Iron
Man you know great beautiful photo so
you got this ele musk and
her um she's a very bad person okay
Amber her but however this is a
beautiful photo okay the Iron Man Iron
Man and the Amber Hood you see this
classic photo you know she's doing her
girl things with a kiss mark on
Ellen's check check okay so these are
beautiful photos okay and this one for
example this she is Miss Russia amazing
most beautiful girl and this Jack Hinton
is kind of a character okay he's got a
million or two followers on Twitter and
on the right is the most beautiful girl
Russian Miss Russia
Anna
linova okay so these are beautiful
photos Okay and then you got um you got
then you got the meme kind of artwork of
the past 20
years uh then you got sculptures kind of
dramatic lurd sculptures you see this
you see what does that mean to me that
means you stop here you means the white
man okay you white man drama about this
symbol okay you stop here don't [ __ ]
around don't [ __ ] around that's I love I
love this one
Buddha uh then you got you know the
Western drama kind of you know thing
that's every time you have this like
it's all like 1 million views um um uh
you know and then you have these
so-called sculptors they doing poem
basically you know so you have this
class of
sculptors in USA or in UK in white man
Nations you have this special category
of sculptors they consider themselves as
a artist okay but what they do is they
do pawn okay the you know Britney
spheres Pawn
and Paris Hilton po okay but they say
it's there's a message this this is Art
this is philosophy of art this is
important social message this is social
philosophy because I depict you know
Paris Hilton this a message meaning and
[ __ ] idiots these
[ __ ] you know they they haen
themselves as artist you know doing
great artor but actually they are just
like pop
you know like they are just like the
online
grifter okay so this Britney spars
happened in 2006 the sculptor Daniel
Edwards a
[ __ ] Daniel Edwards a [ __ ] then
then the Paris Hilton I think this also
by him you see you see this you see this
he's like a doctor you know he's GNA you
know he's very serious doing
artwor then there's scam scammers you
know I got a message from this guy this
this copy track when wres
International uh it says Ste deer to to
whom it may concern on your website you
have this picture you need to pay us
$100 for one time use okay otherwise we
going to otherwise contact lawyer you
know
scammers this you know so you have also
the people online you know they send me
oh
€220 you know they want me to send them
€220 because I have
this photo on my
website but actually they are they don't
represent you know they are not the
actual um copyright
owner but they scam you know most people
when they receive that oh you know they
better take it off or pay or
something so so you got artwork you got
then you got classic
architecture you know then you got you
got Asian you got um Western
architecture you got many beautiful
things okay also all these uh artworks
then you got performance arts these are
also extremely beautiful so these are
not stat this is human performance
acrobats uh artistic cycling beautiful
you know very difficult too and
acrobatic G uh gymnastics
okay you know this is quite dangerous
and it's not easy
okay uh then you have and this this one
is the most difficult actually this one
is a human foot juggling another human
so basically you are just kicking
another human in the air this is this is
the most difficult you will not see this
often it's very quite rare okay fot
juggling
human uh then you have figure skating
that's classic you know that's a well
known and you you know you got all this
then you got juggling Rings you know you
got also beautiful so you got lots of
and also dance is a
classic um performance art especially
when
it's well what you know one part of it
is acrobatic Dance So This Dance
requires High acrobatic skills okay so
especially this uh type of dance called
um uh what is it called a [ __ ] BG I
think I forgot
so I collect them you see I collect this
uh you know for example this is tumbling
beautiful amazing I love I love
acrobatics you
see so that's another aspect of art okay
then you got uh you know you you got
domes or architectural Beauty
domes uh you love it because
geometry you know the the essence of
beauty of architect when it comes to
architecture what is the essence of the
beauty of architect it is geometry okay
mathematics if you can you know condense
it to just one concept that is geometry
it is geometry that makes architecture
beautiful okay so all architecture you
see about uh may it be Cathedrals or uh
you know the Western thing Cathedral you
know it's all
geometry and you have Arco you know Arco
another beautiful uh ERA this is in
America for example this one in America
this one is in India um Okay so so you
got
um then performance are then humor then
then classic anime okay so anime and
cartoon so anyway there's a lot so I got
you know like a thousand Pages or
something so s.org is anything non
technical then Second Life okay so the
question okay here is the answer to the
question the what do I do if I die so
what I'm going to do
if I didn't die by
accident I don't want to die okay right
now I'm okay I'm I'm doing fine I'm
happy okay if
you you know when you talk about
politics when you talk about about
serious
politics and if you are you know big you
know I'm kind of small but if you are
big and you talk about serious
politics then you might have an accident
you know
maybe you drove your car you have a
mysterious accident okay I don't want
accidents I rarely drive cars okay so
I'm fine okay I'm happy so
but back in like 10 years ago I was not
doing good and I was
considering and what to do my with my
website because that is my life's work
it's all on my website
so I was thinking just create a zip
file you know so hi I'm gun here is my
here is a ZIP file for the entire
website uh you know do whatever with it
that's has been what I was thinking so
that answers your
question H so so now we have eight
people you guys missed the good parts
you guys missed the good parts okay now
let's go back to code this okay just no
okay so we already talked for 40 minutes
let's see if we can do this in five
minutes so I already demoed you guys
don't do do you guys know so for example
select that call rotate 13 region do it
it becomes encrypted do it again then
it's back you see so but I want to write
a function so that I don't have to make
a selection for first you'll just do the
current word if there's a selection then
use a selection okay so let's quickly
write
that let begin end that's two positions
so if so uh
Set uh
uh sequence set okay set I want to set
begin and end position of the curent
turn word okay so sequence said if
region active p uh region active P so if
there is a region then
you return a
vector region beginning region end okay
you return a vector if the region is not
not active then you return um then you
return got thing at point so
um uh let's do okay so then then you let
again uh X bounds
okay uh
so bounds of thing at Point okay so you
want the word okay uh let's I want the
symbol okay
symbol so that Returns the bound so
actually
that returns a cons pair okay so you
want to extract it so then return return
Vector car
expounds okay then k which is the second
part of the cons pair
expound okay
so kind of uh okay so
let's clean the pufy the formatting Okay
so so so let's see yeah so so set
sequence set set this two positions if
region is active just region beginning
region end if region is not active let
the boundary equals to bound of thing at
Point symbols which select the current
kind of the word then Vector okay so
that gives you the beginning and end
position okay then what you do then um
then you want to call rotate region okay
so let's look at the documentation for
this function you see start end okay
fantastic so we just call this function
then give it X
begin X begin and X end okay uh yeah
that's a current you know so I think
that's it so clean up the code pretty
five pretty format it now
evolve the region evolve evolve okay so
now let's
say
ABC now let's callar 13 okay ABC call it
meta xar 13 do it symbols value as
variable is void X begin okay something
is
wrong symbol value is void so why didn't
I
uh something is not
set okay let's try it again if like do
it okay symbols value is void X begin so
X begin is NE basically it's not set why
is it not
set boun of thing at Point okay yeah and
Vector car bounds and C bounds that
should be it I don't understand I know
understand somebody help me understand I
know
understand
so message X
begin uh that won't help let's call it
do
it symbols value as variable is void so
this not getting a value but where is
it so if you have a selection do
it it's still the same thing so same
error so where did
I oh of course you gotta you know you
going to move it inside the paren of
course yeah so cut move it inside we
don't want that and uncommon
okay now Evol the region Now call it do
it fantastic ABC BEC
n call it again do it ABC again now
Alice in
Wonderland do it do it Alice in
jaot
fantastic call it again do it Wonderland
now make a selection do
it fantastic make a selection do it
Alice in Wonderland fantastic we
complete so color the
buffer keywords fantastic so that is
done okay so with this another one we
can do uh uh write a HTML insert do type
but let's do it next time
tomorrow is uh so is everything
good massive derail yes massive derail
so when I you know
that's you know the death
thing I don't want to talk about it too
much you know I would but not you know
I'm trying to get away from posting
political stuff that's a thing
that injects
fear
uh andry hi okay I think that's it
um well let me finish Co coding this
okay insert do type that if I do not
digress this would be five minutes 10
minutes job but if I want to talk about
the type which
is kind of Rich topic again you know
then it's a digression and rent for 10
minutes 20 minutes on the history of the
HTML markup you see in the beginning
it's
sgml that's before my time in 1980s or
something then you got HTML which is a
simplified version of sgml
okay beginning around
1990 or 1991 something then then you got
XML which is more simplified and
regularized you know so it's much more
simpler XML much simpler than HTML XML
then that's around year
2000 and part of XML is xhtml
which is HTML in XML syntax so XML XML
is very simple you know every tag
matches you there's no like special case
irregularity like you know when you have
a image you know there's no end tag for
example there's for example this this
thing link but there's no back you know
there's no slash link to close it so
some tags
you you you need a closing tag some some
of them you don't need some of them
don't even have a end tag you know like
this link you know it's you
cannot you know it's illegal if you
actually add a like this you know it
doesn't exist so so HTML is like one
bunch of
crap okay so XML it's not like that XML
is very simple so every tag matches then
you have what's
called self closing
tax so that means when you open you you
you use a slash greater than that will
self close
syntactically so whenever you have a tag
like that that means you don't
need this end tag so it's like regular
you know every tag has end tag except if
you don't want the end tag then you add
this slash you know at the beginning of
the tag you see very regular easy to
understand there's no you know you can't
admit some tag like oh oh by the way you
can admit the body if you want to uh if
you have a list oh by the way you can
Adit the ending L you know it's like
incomprehensible like
irregularity like the C derived syntax
you know one bunch of irregular [ __ ] you
have to
memorize so XML is a like a revolution
beginning in year
then in year
2008 the commercial [ __ ] by Google
Apple and Opera they started HTML
5 you know they are thinking is no no no
we don't want XML we want we we want to
go back to the syntax soup
of HTML but but new H HT HTML 5 we're
GNA do a
revolution you know anyway I talked
about this before so that is kind of the
history of
the of the dark type you know it's it's
a mess you know like before then they
made it you know like like like who the
[ __ ] created a doc type like that you
know with a u URL in it and this you see
this Dash SL slash w3c SL SL DTD HTML
4.0 transitional slash
slash then a URL
like extremely idiotic but that's
because if it's a you know because
standard you know back then the
programmers say You must follow standard
it's a standard but they but why is the
standard become
so difficult to understand because they
are corrupt you know the and the
programmers don't know a
thing especially the Unix
[ __ ] okay that concludes you guys
are late okay the good parts are in the
beginning we talk
about human animals behaviors in songs
in art and things like that so so I'm
closing down thank you guys for
watching and andu says I've I've newly
discovered emac related things glad to
see more such content thank you um it's
better way to live life doy hello um so
that's it for today thank you guys
yeah so today we just
did R 13 region a simple rapper that's
good for beginner lisp and uh then we
talked
about you know some things ons.info
and.org uh introduction of my website
contents okay that's
it bye