good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
today is 2021
december 5th
and we are going to talk about xrfl keys
sci-fi keys it's an e-max package
that provides efficient key binding so
all the
keystrokes to move cursor and so on in
e-max
they are replaced by another key system
so it's very efficient minimum minimal
number of keystrokes you basically never
have to press
uh control x
or meta
almost
okay so this is software keys so this is
what we are going to talk about
and i'm going to introduce so so what
what are we going to do so this is very
focused today maybe 30 minutes
uh so we're gonna i'm gonna explain what
it is and install it from scratch and
mention you know what keyboard layout it
supports and explain the major operation
you know give you a basic introduction
then maybe we're gonna do some vim golf
so if you have questions uh ask me okay
just ask me in the chat
chat so let's begin because i fly keys
so first of all so it's a efficient emax
keybinding system uh i you know i would
say it's even more efficient than vim
you know if you are a vi user or vm user
or evil mod in you know in
emacs evomod the vin based key binding i
would claim sapphire keys is more
efficient than vi or vim
uh if you know we can do
vim golf and test it you know we have
done that before
like long time ago a year a year ago
um
okay so so
it's a key binding system for emacs so
let's install it from scratch okay now
first of all let me tell you that uh on
the left
on the pink window is all my key strokes
you can see and command cores such as
moving the cursor right to left or by
character or by word or move the cursor
up and down you see all the keys and
command cores
uh
on the ping window now that's a command
log mod so i'm working in emacs and i'm
using right now i'm currently using
software keys you know that's why the
keys so you so normally for example the
move cursor to the right is ctrl f
you know for
stand for forward charge but
it's good so
for me to write to move the cursor to
the right one character i just press
this key so the right hand
has a inverted t so you see
move character to the right cursor to
the left or up down so no control key is
involved so that's what sapphire keys is
and it supports it supports you know
many of the
uh ergonomic keyboard layouts such as it
supports quality it supports vorack and
supports cormac or comac bh and workman
and actually support some others such as
neo bop
uh car parks and so on
thank you for you know thanks to these
people who
contributed the layout for you know
different efficient layouts
so it's a key emacs keybinding system
and i'm right now i'm using it
and uh so
and by the way the keyboard this is uh
kinesis advantage 2 and this is ultimate
hacking keyboard if you search saudi
keyboard you can find my reviews and
video reviews about them go buy them for
my amazon website
link
so um
and also i like to mention you don't
have you don't need you know these fancy
batman keyboards to use stuff like keys
because of that case is designed if you
just have a
normal pc keyboard that will just do
fine so
you know if you have any one of these
normal pc keyboard it it it you know
improves your
uh keystrokes much better so okay so
let's
now let's install from scratch okay
questions comment post it okay
let's install sapphire keys from scratch
okay so first of all
so let's go to emacs um
dot emacs you see this is my emacs init
hide the unix part so this is my emacs
in it
and let's rename it
okay
let's say backup
okay so we we don't have so so that's
renamed uh did we rename it yes okay so
we renamed our dot emacs our emacs any
file now let's
right so we want to
install software keys from scratch so
let's do it go to powershell let's start
emacs okay so my emacs is in my download
directory
uh
emacs
okay there okay so emax27
go there
duh
you are looking at powershell on windows
cd bing
and duh
so you can see that one of them is uh
let me just do it okay run emacs
uh okay so
let's just do it so what uh
[Music]
so downloads
e-max
thing run emacs okay that's the emax
command let's launch it
so this is this is the
the player minimal
glue e max you can see
this is a bare minimum of glue image so
let's install some black keys
so how um
okay
okay so so yeah install software keys so
let's go to stuff like keys let's follow
the instructions
so you can download it on github so
github is right here so copy it
open a new buffer
paste the url go there
uh there it is sapphire keys you
so let's download it stuff like his el
one single file okay
raw
let's just say raw okay
let's just copy the whole thing i mean
there are so many ways but let's just
copy the whole thing so
so now you see emacs when you launch gnu
emacs it created the dot emacs.d
which
which um
you know stores or your emacs can fit
config so split the window
and let's open a new buffer paste it so
here is the the whole entire supply key
save it
dot el okay so we have saved it into
this directory now normally by
convention
the directory for these packages is
dot emacs.d lisp okay so let's create a
directory list okay there go there and
move the soft like keys file over there
okay
so now let's open this so you can see
this is a soft like his source code from
github
you know you can use wicked you know
there are some new ways you go you can
clone a github you know whatever
ways to grab the file the point is you
have to grab the file so the file is
here now
now let's uh let's create a dot emax
init okay so
open a new buffer save it dot e-max
uh wait uh init it's called
um
save it in it dot e-l okay
so let's put the date so this is uh our
e-max init file you can see
you see it's right there so emacs you
need file so what you want to put there
so
stuff like keys instructions manual
install so grab the file and put it in
your home directory dot emacs dot d
slash lisp then
copy this list code
put in your init file that's it okay so
copy it here so let's see add to this
load path uh yeah the load you know make
the lisp
directory available for looking for
packages
require software keys all right
specify a layout stuff like his layout
quality okay since i'm not using qwerty
i need borac
you can see a list of supported uh
key
layout here so i'm using varax so let's
say borax so in stuff like keys 1 that
means turn it on so save this init file
so you can see
you know we have this init file saved
close it okay now let's re restart the
gnu emacs okay
so close that
back to powershell
run emacs now it should load sunflower
keys did it no it didn't
wait oh it did okay so actually so you
can see
you see i press this key i'm using varia
keyboard so i press this key it will
move closer to the right i press this
key it'll move closer to the left that's
why because that's soft like keys i
press this key it'll move cursor down
now if i press number six it will select
the current block of code you see look
you see so that's start fly keys now
cancel okay
uh ctrl g to
remove the selection so we have soft
like keys installed okay so you know so
i can operate with ease emacs tutorial
enter close it save no so fantastic now
how do i
magnify the font in default um
emax so let's let's say 16 okay courier
new okay let's just
okay so yeah just so let's
do it again
uh
set default font okay uh courier new and
let's say 18 for now okay fantastic
sapphire keys now i can go to diet uh
you know just
you know close you know go to diet is
space m
on the roll rack on the qwerty it's also
space same so look i press space
m it goes to diet and
you know so anyway so we have some fly
keys installed smooth very smooth so we
don't need this anymore so
yeah let's uh create emacs i mean crit
the new emacs we just installed this is
all you need okay so now we installed
stuff like keys now let's go back i mean
go back to my my traditional my my own
emacs setup so
so that let me explain to you
what is sci-fly keys about okay
now it's a vision key it's a it's a
efficient key binding system for emacs
okay uh any questions comment no okay
efficient emacs keybinding system for
emacs and it's
model just like vi or vim okay so you
have command mod and you have insert mod
so when you when in command mod so let's
open a new buffer show the pink window
in command mod right now i mean command
mod so
okay close that yeah okay close that
don't say go to open bookmark um
bookmark not there because
because i renamed my
you know remember i remained my renamed
my dot emacs.d ini file you know stuff
so right now you cannot find my
bookmarks so let's rename them back okay
so this one we just created is new and
the one i had is rename it back okay so
now you open it this is what i had okay
so now i can open let's open a bookmark
so i want to open um
yeah
today's talk show go to talk show show
in browser
so i want to tell you now about uh let's
see
supports or organ layouts explain
operation command mod and insert mod
okay so i'm going to explain what's the
command mode insert mod so it's model
based so you have so when when you
insert mod for example i press a key to
switch me to insert mod then whatever
you type let's magnify okay
whatever you type
is inserted that's insert mod okay now i
want to switch back to command mod the
default key is uh
you can do control x
you can also do uh old x i mean control
space there are many ways okay so
the main point now is that there's two
mods control
insert mod
which allows you to type type and
command mod command so right now i'm in
command mod how can you tell because
look at the cursor when the cursor is a
square you are in command mod when a
cursor is a kind of i-beam you are in
insert mod and you can also tell by the
first character in the
in the mode
line okay so you see i means insert so
if i switch to command mod it's c c is
for command mod
so
right now i'm in insert mod command mod
okay when
when when you are in command mod every
keystroke you type is is calling some
kind of command not
not insert characters for example i
press this like i press this key that
will move cursor to the right by one
word so you can also see you can also
see the command name there so you see i
press w
it calls the command
forward
i press this key
which is uh
vorack g or qwerty
uh qwarak g
and it moves
cursor backward backward word so when
you are in command mod every key you
press is
doing some kind of command so
so for example i want to delete that
paragraph i just press one key that
calls this command cassatt current text
block okay so i can move my cursor by
paragraphs or i can you know delete that
whole paragraph delete or paste them
back
you know undo
okay undo again you see
and showing browser so
so when you are in command mod if every
key is a command you don't have to press
ctrl or meta something so it's very
efficient
so
now let me talk about let me explain
what is the so how do i you know so why
do i need this you know i created this
about you know it began as ergo emax mod
uh
that began in 2006 2007
uh with help of david capello so let me
show you some history okay so history of
south lake his history
so i'm i'm a quality typer since 1987 i
switched to vorax since 1994. i started
to use emacs in 1997.
yeah i start i i started to touch type
quality in 1987.
then switched to vorac in 1994
then i started to use emacs 1997
then i live in emacs
every day you know all the time you are
in emacs then
okay the main point is that i started
ergo e-max mod in 2007 because because i
started to have some kind of rsi uh
issues
and so 2007 is ergo e-max mod you can
see it's still available but it's right
now it's maintained it's
led by matthew fiddler
you know so so this is a ergo e-max mod
that's a bit history of soft like keys
so refresh let's
let's turn on javascript yeah so this is
the urban emacs uh of course it's also
open source you can download on github
and then
so that's ergo
mod
in 2007
but then in 2013 i started stuff like
keys so ergo e-max mod is not like veeam
it's model it's
it's not model okay okay emacs mod you
have to press the old key to move stuff
uh so
in 2013 i began safely keys which is
model just like vi because when you use
the model system
you know i did a lot study it you
actually save about i would say 10 to 20
percent keystrokes
the count of keystrokes will you will
save 10 to 20 percent
so it's rather uh
significant when you use computers long
term you know for years ten years
so sapphire keys so began in 2013 and
so the design so
so why don't you just use vi you know
why don't you just use vim you know
especially you know so ergo emacs and uh
stuff like keys they they actually began
before the evil mod you know before the
evil mod
which is a vim emulator in emacs so
anyway so so why don't you but
but still why don't you just use vim key
binding i mean there's a
there is a um
beam emulator in emacs called uh called
the viper mod i i guess before evo okay
so let's try
yeah so there you see this there's a
command viper mod let's show the
documentation so it says viper mod is
autoloaded blah blah blah
turn on viper emulation of vi in emacs
so there's a info documentation go to it
so it you know viper mod is building in
emacs since
since 1990s okay very early on why is it
called viper because
back then you know originally there's vi
then there's uh different versions
written by different people one of them
is called viper
and one of them is vin today veeam
became the most popular and there's also
elvis
you know
vi begin there's a vi then there's a
different versions viper
elvis
veem
uh and other
a few others
so but
you know after 30 years today veeam is
the most popular you know people don't
know about others but in vi
i mean but in emacs
there's also a viper mod so it's a vi
emulation
so anyway so why do i you know what why
why should you use why should you use
software keys why don't you just use
evil mod well
the evil mod the vim key binding they
are kind of historically based okay they
are not designed from the offset so many
uh keystrokes are not the
not optimal okay not the best
uh
uh choice
when it comes to the key
keys
the key mining choice and the
command so
that's you know so that's why i created
software keys so in vi for example in vi
or evomod the most famous
keystrokes are moving cruisers hjkl
you see so let's see if i can select it
yeah
for some reason
and let's see
this is uh svg so it's kind of hard to
select so anyway h j k l that's the most
famous key binding for vi
but you know i did a lot study um i
think the optimal
slightly as far as with respect to the
arrow kusa keys the
inverted t i j k l is slightly better i
mean so there are much many other things
in vi and that's not
optimal okay in my opinion you know i
actually believe because i did a lot of
study
so most of the key binding uh and
command map choices they are based on uh
statistics from emacs command frequency
okay so let me show you where history uh
chat forum testimonial uh
frequently asked questions okay how does
it compare to evil mod
evil mod is pretty good okay if you have
hand pan you have eyesight you know
use evil mod or sapphire keys
of course if you ask me i would
recommend you know my own big
uh well okay yeah so um
so how long does it take how long does
it take to learn you know it'll take you
about one month one full month if you do
it every
an hour a day it'll take you a month to
learn and that month will not be present
so let me just warn you one you first
because it's it's like you are learning
vi for the first time lots of
frustration
especially if you are already familiar
with vi because you you have building
muscle memory so it will take take you a
month to learn okay so but let me talk
about the key binding okay via
keybinding versus emacs keybinding let's
talk about let me show you
um
um i forgot where but anyway so let me
show you okay so
so i'm going i'm i'm i'm going to tell
you
what is the choices made for the key
binding i mean so what's the efficiency
i claim it's sufficient uh that is based
on emacs command frequency okay so let
me let me show you where to find that so
emacs site um go to
any comments questions
okay i'm gonna answer it in a moment so
you go to the side emacs site then go to
emacs keys
then there is an article about emacs
commands statistics here
emacs command frequency statistics so i
did this in 2007 when i was designing
ergo e-max mod so here is a
you know statistics summary of all the
frequency of e-max command cores so
based on this i designed over e-max and
eventually it's applied keys
so
so that's that's the origin
i mean that's how flag keys the the
keystroke the keys the key binding is
designed it's based on okay
basically
the most frequently used emax command
should have the most easy keys
so
what does the most easy keys mean well
for example the home row would be
considered easiest then maybe the top
row
and those then then any key pressed by
the pinky
is not considered bad okay so you want
the most frequently used command
to have the most easy key
so that that is the basis of the design
of software keys okay
so uh let's see qwerty yeah let's show
quality so
so and in general on the right hand
basically all the right hand is about
moving moving cursor okay so let's go
back
so
all the right hand let's show the pink
window so i can switch window you see i
can switch cruiser
i mean i can switch
the window yeah open a new buffer
close this buffer so
the right hand is in general all about
moving cursor so i can move by paragraph
i can move up by paragraph i can move to
the beginning of buffer i can move to
the bottom buffer
and i can
move by character
or i can do selection okay select
one word
select a line
let's let's try it again okay select the
line okay move here select the line
press it again you select the next line
press it again select next one or i can
select the whole paragraph you know so
right hand is like
either moving cursor or selection in
general okay now left hand is all about
destructive deletion deletion and things
like that for example let's move to here
delete to the right
by word dd to the left by word delete to
the right by character
delete to the left by character
delete the whole
block press again to delete you know
delete again
you know so if i if you want to undo
right hand okay undo
okay too many undues close it
don't save no reopen it by the way i'm
using some macros here so
uh
well i can you know so
so it allows me a single keystroke for
example magnify the window what magnify
the phone
so in software keys you can do that by
by by many ways okay let's not get
unfocused let me yes so
so this is how
right now i'm focusing on you know this
is how the key bindings are designed
based on command frequency and ease of
keys
right hand is in general moving cruisers
or moving or selection non-destructive
the left hand is in general
destructive uh for example cut cut cut
the current line the left that's the
left hand x
you know the quartix
press it again to cut again so you can
cut a lot and paste this v
one single key press you see all the
command names are here and there's no
control key because if i press the ctrl
key you'll see on the right you'll see
it you see uh wait let's see control g
you see
control g is keyboard quit
uh okay that's that finishes the
introduction of sci-fi keys and how the
key binding is designed
okay i think that's that's about that's
it that's about it for today and you
know maybe we can do some 10 minutes um
uh
vi golf you know vm golf
that's a puzzle
for vim
users so you know so we can com it's a
it's kind of a competition to see given
a task given an editing task
who can do the minimal amount of number
of keystrokes to complete that task
that's a vim golf so maybe we can do
that
so there's a website
full of these uh there it is
so
so i would say you know you know using
stuff like keys you will have
you you you will be able to use less
number of keystrokes than than whatever
these ring golf
best results
or about the same actually less if you
do a lot of them
soft like keys will be less number of
keystrokes
okay any questions and otherwise that's
it for today or you know i want to keep
it short today uh and maybe we'll do
some vim golf should we
let's see
i'm not sure about wind golf because
when we start to do that then
lots of
you know maybe i i hit on a problem
and stuff like keys require more keys it
doesn't look good
but i'm pretty confident confident
okay so what uh what are questions
there's a question i'm black do you
think i could figure out doctor keyboard
what do you think ask yourself
uh
but vim evo is more ubiquitous yes
that's one of the advantage
of vim and evil mod you know if you are
thinking uh whether should i learn
sapphire key so should i learn evo or vi
well
you know i would say sapphire keys is
more efficient but however you have less
users but if you jump into the vim
or evil mod ship you have massive
support massive number of users and you
can also use vim on unix any unix linux
they have vi building that's one
advantage
yeah exactly same with quality you know
if you want basically you if you want
kind of a more advanced system you tend
to have less users and so on
i don't know any about i don't know
anything about hacking okay i don't know
hacking i mean hacking in this context i
suppose you mean um
you know cyber security issues like how
do you break password i don't know much
about that
anonymous stop trolling okay stop asking
nonsensical questions i don't know how
how about you anyway let's uh i think
we're gonna stop today so let's try some
some some of these okay let's try even
golf let's just try one or two
okay innocent monster eight entries so
what is this what day is this
first of all i need to know i want to
know what is the
date this
puzzle is created
do they say somewhere
okay anyway i don't know where is the
date but let's try to do this ryovim
ninjas count every keystroke do you
pick a challenge fire up theme and show
us what you got okay let's turn on
javascript maybe because sometimes uh
okay
so you have the tools just create an
innocent monster that's the title of
this puzzle so start with that
and with that oh
this is the ascii art
what
innocent ma okay this one is will this
one will be difficult to do let's so
open a new file
um you know open a new buffer
and
so it says start with that
and we want to
end with that
so i assume
you cannot type it you have to kind of
just
copy and paste the
copy and paste characters from here
uh this this okay wait so
okay let's try that uh
this this problem is kind of
i mean this this is kind of artistic
problem this is not practical coding
i don't think okay so let's let's try it
let's try it okay
so
they wanted to end it like that okay so
so we have to start to count keystrokes
let me just do it try to do it okay so
how many
so first of all turn on the
turn the
show
show white spaces mod
so how many
how many characters are there 10
characters
and how many characters are here
14 characters so one two three four five
okay
so okay so let's do let's see
one
three four five one two three four
then
let me try to do this
in the most efficient way okay
ah i need to concentrate back yeah
yeah
wait
yeah this is
this what what the is this okay so
let's try this
and and i suppose you are not allowed to
go to insert mod is that right something
like that
okay
there's no more that
yeah made a mistake
back miss mistake
yeah okay
and okay so i'm gonna you know so this
is my first try
one two three four five copy that
and paste it here go here
then you need three dots and go here
copy that go here go here
go here add mistake and go here go here
three dots
then cut that char move that that okay
that's that's
that's
like that's it
okay you know this is not a good problem
i don't know how many key strokes i can
try it again you know you want to refine
it until you know until you
got the minimum number of keystrokes so
let's see solutions the best way to
learn this is to practice blah blah blah
unlock three remaining solutions by
signing in okay so
number four 93
key strokes okay
so what's the minimum number of key
strokes
okay 62.
see
62 keystrokes so we can you know we it's
you know it's possible we can do it 62
key strokes
okay so yeah so we can do that in soft
like keys six i'm pretty sure
uh we'll be somewhere around there 62
that's a you know
because stuff like keys has this command
to manipulate the bra the
parent for example look at that i press
one key
and we got that okay now i go to the
beginning of the line
paste it here
enter a new line
you see so we got that
so especially for the eye for example
for for this eyes it's
i believe we can do that much
much less number of keystrokes than vi
for example let's do this eye
you know i move move the cursor to the
center here and and one key one more key
do it wait before we do it we want to
grab one of the
one of the pupil okay so
start
the mark go here
move by one character cut it
back there paste it here
move
right by two characters then cut the
whole eye
go to the beginning
paste
one two three four four space paste
again
we got the eye
and
one key to remove the rest of line so
so i'm
let me make a claim i'm fairly i'm
ninety-nine percent certain in star
flight keys you can do this your b your
beat beam less than 62 characters that's
one okay that's this problem okay let's
copy let's copy it and
let's do another one and that's it for
today
okay so uh
put a new line after every 10 lines in
veeam okay so what is this
so put a new line after every 10 lines
in v now that's that's so easy
so okay so
so beginning file and end file okay so
okay let's start that so every 10
so it
put a new line after every 10 lines okay
so
here we are going to employee
[Music]
a e-max marco it's it's gonna beat vim
for sure okay so let's let's try this
add a new line everything for uh after
every 10 lines so
start the marker so what watch the pink
window okay and we need to count strokes
but
so you count the keystrokes so
start the macro three keys
one
two three four five six seven eight nine
ten
okay
now
go here
add a
new line
okay
add the empty line okay
then
that okay
one two
three and the macro okay
now let's call that a marker again
one two
three
three key strokes okay
now
we can we can do that three key strokes
again to repeat but it is even shorter
because now let's use the repeat last
command okay
one two three okay
now look one one one
one one
one
done okay maybe do they require the last
line to have an empty line maybe they do
by the spec okay okay there's no more so
so how many key strokes we did so let's
let me try to count so
one two three four five six seven eight
nine
ten
10 plus
10 so
so first of all three keys to start
macro then 10 keys to move the line and
one key to add a empty line
then three more keys to end the macro
then to call the macro
to call the last marker is three keys
then
the repeat last command is
three keys then for each repeat it's one
key
so here one times how many uh how many
are there
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten
okay there are 10 of them so 1 times 10
10.
so a total of these number of uh
of this number of
keys okay so let's actually let's
compute let's see how many
emac this
that's just 10 okay so don't be stupid
33 keys
if i'm miss not mistaken let's see
what's the result
what a 10
what
that so they did it in 10 lines oh
yeah that's the reason is
in vi you can
you can enter a number to
to jump you know instead of 10 keys for
moving 10 lines you can just
type
we can do that too so let's see let me
try
universal
uh
argument then type 10
okay then type down arrow yeah that that
does it
so so that means reduce this 10 by
uh
two
keystrokes to start universal
then another two keystrokes to type one
zero
so how many how many how many um total
27 okay so that's still not enough
well the the last 10
can also be repeated i believe so can we
do that
anyway that i think that's it for today
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching so that's the introduction to
stuff like keys uh if you like it you
know use it it's free
and it's also open source uh but if you
like my stuff pay me okay so support me
donate
you know donate paypal patreon um
i have a link somewhere somewhere on my
website paypal patreon amazon gift card
or or just or you can buy my packages my
emacs packages there's quite a few of
them
thank you guys
bye
so one more minute i'm gonna shut down
in one more minute so let's let's try
this again so this we this
so let's see
i want to see how many uh let's see
i can probably i can do it in 21 key
strokes
but yeah okay so in vi is just 10.
wait let's think add
add a new line
after every 10 lines
so
so let's try again
okay
control u
down arrow
okay wait
one two
three
four
five
six seven
eight
wait
yeah
one two three
four
five
six seven
eight
nine
13 14
16 17
19 20
21 22 23 24
24 key strokes i can reduce to 20 but
not maybe not okay bye guys