good morning everyone
this is not talk show you are watching
today is 2019
November 19th Tuesday noon in the
afternoon well no not after noon noon is
not afternoon so we have a lot people
thank you guys for coming and that is
the preview that is the previewed of pre
dude so let me stop this video and let's
see what's in the chat and I'm thinking
today we are going to do either
miscellaneous live coding of Emacs Lisp
oh let's do JavaScript plus SVG live
coding doing a live rotation of platonic
solids and if we're gonna do JavaScript
that's going to take one hour you know
40 minutes something like that so it
looks like something like that
we did this like three days ago and we
are going to continue doing this so if
we are going to do this I'm going to do
live coding and kind of teach explain
how you do it
so either that or eMac B's because the
JavaScript one will take like 40 minutes
or more so we cannot do both so so you
guys you know so it depends on what you
guys want so type what you like you know
just type it and you will see how many
prefer JavaScript or eMac this for the
eMac this you know I'm doing live coding
of miscellaneous emag list commands in
the first explanation things like that
so today so what what is it going to be
type it okay type it in a chat and let
me read the comments and let's see today
is a fine day Tuesday Tuesday is walk
week day people are walking morning Bart
good morning Emily good morning
thank you you too time to make a hot
chocolate oh yeah hot chocolate so I'm
going to drink my power drink my power
drink as usual this is well energy drink
energy juice and today I have the juice
of choice is grape and apple basically
100% juice no sugar no sugar
okay natural sugar in fruit is okay but
don't drink sugar okay sugar do bad
things to your body and Geus and guys
join discord okay ignore part okay what
is keeping talking about his is thing
it's not gonna work but you know move on
gets you know mover so discord let's see
where are we what is this okay discord
where is it okay here
discord okay so emily is apparently
emily is running low swung and she's got
this lotion mom book
okay anyway that that's not today's
topic let's see what you guys so so emag
bees or javascript
cheers Cheers so let me read the
comments i have to magnify magnify the
font so you know so look at the UK
person sparrows cozy as cozy okay yeah
okay let's go up see you again thank you
too hard to catch you you too hard to
catch you hola hola
you know attempt to make a hot chocolate
okay so look at UK person cozy Emily's
got a cozy home yes she does
okay so let's let's miss start to
talk about something interesting so some
people should answer your Emacs
questions on the forum but now my hot
chocolate fast the mud so I decide to
name so heat
krub okay but Scott forum okay okay let
me well but but has okay but what is
your forum written in okay what what so
it's I mean what language I mean what
it's sorry that way it's not talk that
email stupid thing close Twitter sir
talk dot ml you know these domain names
that's no good just used outcome dot oh
darn it you know Donnie Mia is no good
but once you start already beginning
then it's no good to change
okay so Mao is what what country is
email so guys JavaScript
okay so they'd say I guess let's to
JavaScript in just one person saying
that okay so anyway Bart's got this dr.
Amy out that is before I had this scored
bodies you know he planned to do this
it's supposed to be you know Mike's our
talk show forum so we can go there but
before he announced it ready went to
discord
so this forum is kind of hanging there
so this is not be be so what is what is
not be so bad like what technology is is
so anyway if you guys like to use this
you know go there
join parts forum so bad
but I'm gonna I'm not gonna walk give up
Linux rules go using X okay what but
what technology are you using like what
is this what language or what framework
is this how your browser does not
support JavaScript okay let's turn on
JavaScript
pay for calm Oh Amy how is free it Oh
Mao is free but what country is email
when I got enough people are we
improving work you know it's not likely
you get a lot people here you know
because what I mean is really because
you know I'm you know I'm gonna it's not
likely like if you do a talk show and
you are the focus of attention then
people then you then you create your
form then people go there you know but
because I'm doing it and I already have
this code and your form is great but
it's not going to son it's just not
going to work okay so so let me actually
we should start to talk about javascript
polymerase so so so javascript i guess
because you see I don't have a schedule
I don't dislike random so every time I
have a problem of what to talk about I
don't have a schedule I don't have a
plan I don't have a schedule topics
usually that's what you should do if you
want your if you are doing YouTube and
you if you want to grow your audience
because because people in modern society
they they need to they they don't have
time and but you know that's that's
something I have to do but that's just
it's not happening at least not now
so every time I do a talk show I have to
choose a topic and and usually I need
the top
to be something of interest to the
people currently present because then
people talk about you know because if
I'm doing JavaScript that and if most
people don't know anything about
JavaScript then it's gonna get cold but
on the other hand if I'm doing eMac this
for something else a lot of people are
interested in it then people like you
guys chat about it then I saw the
messages then it becomes more busy so
anyway so I'm unsure I'm unsure and
uncertain that is the story of my life
unsure and uncertain and undecided and
and undecidable the fundamental theorem
of mathematics undecidable everything is
undecidable well if something is
decidable then it is not interesting you
are working a system that's not
interesting at all if you are working a
system that's interesting then and
things are undecidable you owe me so
what I don't know you okay I'm okay so
wait wait what
hello beautiful people so pay for calm
okay
but so what is the interesting question
is that in L you know what Sawadee start
ml like what country is it why is it
free dot a male domain name so that a
male domain name okay well actually I'm
starting to talk random so II Maglis for
JavaScript so Alden so let's do
JavaScript then I know Alan is
interested in JavaScript and then since
we have another guy god I can't get
better with reading the messages and not
keep scrolling up and down so
everything is falling apart no that no
schedule no nothing it becomes so you
know the the way YouTube is going is
just random chat like Brenda and Chad
took some JavaScript okay let's do
JavaScript so so let's yeah this is it
let's do that then let's see how long
have been talking eleven minutes
okay so JavaScript so let's go to show
JavaScript and we are going to add some
let's see
holy okay Paulie in the sauce start
command log mod so on the Left window
for you Emacs users you can see all my
Emacs command cause on the Left window
here okay and we are going to show you
this one so showing chrome opening
Chrome browser okay so we got now it's
improved since last time because now
it's rotation of the polyhedra yet you
don't see the background so it's not
wireframe so this is improved you can
rotate it and it needs a lot
improvements you know it needs really
needs a lot work and and one feature I
wanted to add is mouse rotation now I
don't know how to do that yet because I
mean the part I don't know is how do you
control so if you want live rotation
with a mouse how do you like what event
is it in JavaScript how do you like how
do you do it basically so you know the
the rotation is interesting because like
the user interface of mass rotation is
very interesting because I'm going to
explain but however that's not related
to JavaScript technology it's related to
user interface design so let me explain
that yeah so let's just talk about
whatever but we're gonna focus on
JavaScript today
so rotation is interesting why because
because let me find the article okay so
you have this space navigator
okay space navigator this is a great
device for using with Google Earth or
any kind of 3d rotation thing Google
Earth blender any kind of 3d software
this is a fantastic input device so you
can see you can you know originally this
device looks like that this is like 20
years ago year 2000 he looks like that
it was used in NASA you know space
control Space Shuttle or whatever it was
called space boss so so what is it it's
like a joystick okay it's like a
joystick first you can also pull it up
or push it down oh and plus you you can
also twist it okay so the easiest way to
understand what this does does is you
know it seemed basically just a joystick
plus you can pull it up push it down or
twist it that's it okay that's that's it
so originally it was designed for NASA
something like that okay and eventually
becomes looks like that it becomes looks
like that so I have a videos here so if
you go through my website let me show
you guys so saw talk show today's talk
show let's paste the link here and
magnify and before we do anything hold
on a second so we gonna get the URL so
URL you can you guys can go our go edit
and buy it buy it I get a dollar or
something $0.50 buy it on Amazon okay so
the space navigation so we I'm going to
talk about why the use user interface of
rotating 3d object its there are a lot
quite a few variations that's
interesting to discuss
and what I was going to do so I need to
go to this in Chrome okay so let's go to
income oh yeah so click on that so this
space Navigator is great for 3d software
for Google Earth so this guy is
reviewing it
okay so he's doing a review so you can
see how it works and I tried it once
when I went to Google you know I have
friend said Google you know I have
friends at places so will you enter the
Google building they have a giant Google
Earth like huge humongous screen then
you have this device in front so you can
you know it's really fun I love Google
Earth Google Earth is such a fantastic
thing okay Casali Google Earth 101
geography 101 you know you Google Earth
is like if you are a gamer you know
young people wait ok I got a few
articles about this all very interesting
of course now Google Earth
let's see Google Chrome good ok so let's
close that and Google you can also use
it as a flight simulator you can you can
do that I don't know they still kept
that feature but at least 5 years ago
you can so I tried it
you know suffice simulator but anyway so
Google Earth is very interesting so you
know a lot cameras you play games right
Oh video games or shooting or whatever
driving and Google Earth itself is kind
of like a game so instead of you know
playing games you play Google Earth you
explore the vast places on earth you can
see you know so many things you know you
can spend your whole life in Google
Earth literally and so anyway I was so
anyway so Google Earth so this device is
very good for Google Earth and and you
go by it okay now the next thing
interesting we are going to I'm going to
talk about so one topic leads to another
is this thing ok let me show you math
models of 3d input control ok so this
this thing is gonna be you know we
cannot talk about this is very
interesting
it will be 10 minutes math want models
of 3d input control so let's see what's
comments
I resent my polyhedra rotate yeah so I
was talking about ad we are going off
for attention but the rotation in
JavaScript so we are talking about first
of all I'm going to I was going to talk
about the user interface variations for
doing 3d rotation with mouth that is
what I'm going to talk about and that
topics then relates to the mass models
of 3d input control ok that's related
but then before that I was going to talk
about how do you do that in JavaScript
and Dom how do you actually code it that
is you know the technology so that's
another thing then you have the math
aspect of rotation then that that I know
so Allen is working in JavaScript you
know everything is that's his job
Allen's job so a salad you know how do
you do that so he he has he actually has
a page that that showed it weighs it and
let's see I think I haven't had it here
huh ok he here's another one but he
let's see so he in from implemented
mouse mouse rotation so then did you
scrap that one
how do I math polyhedron rotate I think
did you scrap the the old one where you
oh hello beautiful people thank you for
the super chat pretty money where
so God very common but anyway Alan did a
mouse rotation I didn't I haven't got
time to look into the code yet so I'm
going to look into and grab his code
just going to grab whatever you know the
part I want to know anyway so so that so
so let me talk about the 3d rotation the
UI aspect oh by the way before I mention
that before let me also mention so there
is a OpenGL of course this is this
OpenGL technology which they with so you
can use JavaScript 3GS framework that
allows you to program 3d object like
like again you know 3d object using
OpenGL via JavaScript so I try to learn
this a few you know you know like one
time you know but every time I learn
OpenGL or WebGL it always become so
complicated like you know like 1,000
lines of code just to do a rotating cube
meanwhile in Mathematica it's one line
of code and in JavaScript it's 20 lines
20 or 50 lines of code okay in fact I
can show you Mathematica okay
is Z Tron crazy party system crazy here
so in Mathematica here's what you do
well we are digressing but but in
Mathematica here is what you do okay so
I can I can type it okay so cube cube
one cube you give to coordinate let's
say negative 1 negative 1 negative 1 I
think you know my syntax may not be
correct because I haven't been coding
Mathematica for about 10 years but cube
graphics 3d okay then you put cube
inside then you just then you just do so
you paste that in Mathematica it'll show
a cube okay with where the corners are
negative negative one negative one and
one one one that's a two opposite
corners I think you know Mathematica and
but if you want to rotate it you can I
think you can already rotate it just by
default in later versions of Mathematica
but if if you are not sure you can say
manipulate okay manipulate takes two
arguments okay and the first argument is
the graphics primitive then the second
argument is what variable you want to
change so I I don't remember the syntax
but it's something like one to ten so X
from one to ten so you can change so
here's what you do okay so you add
viewpoint now I don't remember this is
the correct syntax but this is something
like that
so viewpoint X let's say X 1010 so that
that is it so let me show you that
so this is the mathematical code for
creating a live rotation of a Q so you
say graphics 3d and inside graphics 3d
you give a some graphics primitive every
you know such as cube or triangles you
know you just just give the vertices the
coordinates then you say view viewpoint
now I'm not sure this is a correct
syntax maybe it's some other thing but
or you say rotation okay then you give a
perspective like where you want to look
at the thing then you wrap it around
manipulate that will generate an
interactive user interface with a slider
so you grab the slider that will change
the value of x which we in turn change
the viewpoint so you can see the
rotation of a cube so that's Mathematica
so that's how many lines of that one two
three four four lines okay or in
Mathematica the entire thing is one line
so it's just one single line now in
JavaScript in JavaScript where is our
JavaScript so let's go to JavaScript
holy okay so we got I got several
versions so viewing from this is an
earlier version so there you go so in
JavaScript how many lines is that that
is me magnify 200 lines 289 okay now I
remember I tried WebGL that's 1000 lines
[ __ ] [ __ ] WebGL [ __ ] OpenGL fact that
the the low-level programming nodes the
C and C++ people yeah the programmers
are they they are nasty dinos yeah I I
don't
well to be fair you know they are not
talk show they the the the type of
programmers the hacker types they are
always anyway the reason they are like
that because different perspectives
because the the hacker types typically
the hacker types like they talk
big talk on Hacker News these type of
people they typically their interest
they are perspective on computer science
is that they you know they the way they
are like that they always like to talk
about you know see tsipras first memory
references int float you know that the
other crap they are like that because
they they view the you know computer
science from the from the machine
manipulating the memory the that
perspective which is which is necessary
and perhaps the proper perspective
because that's what you really need to
do you know to get the whole thing to
work you have to know the CPU you know
how you know how it works the memory the
efficiency there then then the low-level
code assembly then see you you have to
do that so that's typical you know the
hacker types of programmers you know
they that that's their perspective me
meanwhile they know nothing about
mathematics they don't know nothing but
they adore mathematics that I gave all
the hacker types late they did be God
mathematicians of God like they oh my
god this is getting into a tangent of a
massive tangent rent you know they so
they are like that you know meanwhile
they are dough mathematicians meanwhile
they know nothing nothing about it they
like to chalk up like they like to use
math jargons everywhere they have a
chance like the Haskell idiots they are
like saying category theory everyday
catalog category theory monads meanwhile
they they what they know about category
theories [ __ ]
that is like misleading crap that's what
the Haskell program must I talk about
everyday you can see it on blogs on
Twitter everywhere on how can use now
remember that that here's a take away
every time you see a Haskell programmer
talk up math SAS ace treated as entire
garbage okay don't don't even pay one
minute to it entire garbage like
misleading crap like this you can verify
this
by asking any mathematician okay
wherever program in fact more generally
whenever programmers talk about math
treated us entire [ __ ] okay that's
that's these programmers these hacker
types but however when they talk about C
she prefers offering systems
Kano's okay that's good okay that's good
but anyway so my problem with them is
that you see I came from a math
background so I of course I also have my
opinions on programming languages but my
perspective don't mesh with this you see
and they don't see my perspective
because in their entire life they have
never seen one single line of math
oriented programming language such as
APL matlab mathematica julia okay these
are math oriented programming languages
i have articles on that it's just such
four sorry math math oriented
programming languages so these typical
programmers basically they I'm talking
about the hacker types like they tell
you about programming styles what you
should do how you should intend how you
should you know more than one way to do
you know per style the Perl code of high
pythonic you know each language they
have their terms like pythonic you know
the [ __ ] then this dismissed dismissed
or whatever each each group has their
like particular jargons for your code
being conforming to their particular
thing anyway these people so so one of
us was i talking about i forgot so these
people you know these these the hacker
types that's that's the type i'm talking
about who are you know pretty loud and
they are opinion typically are the the
establishment you know they tell you if
you don't confirm they think you are no
good and if if you are loud they think
you are a troll that's that's what
happens with these people hacker types
but but then but they don't you see they
don't know method or the in their life
they have
have not even I mean they might have
coded seeing one lines of Mathematica or
MATLAB especially today because of the
data science you know then they might
have seen MATLAB you know ah you know
the language are or Judea some of them
start to do that but but basically vast
majority of these hacker types [ __ ]
they've never coded seriously you know
in any of these math languages so you
know so my opinions don't usually mesh
with this and you and whenever they talk
about you know how a race should be you
know away one of the most confusing
things in computer languages is is these
jargons array lists or this kind of yeah
this basically captured by array or list
you know this usually refer refers to
nest you refer to linked lists and
arrays anyway so you know and one of the
one of the thing you can see one of the
good example you can see about this is
that they this type of hacker types when
when you know they like to say you know
some way over the example that
illustrates this whole thing about the
programmer hacker types of programmers
versus anyone who knows something about
math math math oriented programming is
that almost all all the hacker types
like I know most of you guys are
probably that type because you know we
are in computing industry after all we
are nothing
you know I'm not really a mathematician
so you know you guys are all you know
the industrial programmers so so so so
so you people usually oh yeah so here's
an example that illustrates the the big
thinking difference you you ask people
what when you know should array big
index array index begin with zero or
what okay
vast majority of programmers they will
tell you with like with strong opinions
okay man I have a pinion on this and I
have a strong opinion on this is
that it should be issued start with zero
most vast majority of programmers will
tell you that and they will insist not
not just you know oh I think maybe zero
is better they will insist these hacker
types of facts okay am i right
so do you guys most of you think it
should be start with zero right I think
I'm correct correct on that so so I you
know I when you offer a tangent [ __ ] I
don't know if we should go back to
JavaScript if it's too late so so these
programmers you know you ask them array
which you know should array index begin
with zero what they will always say with
strong opinions like this they say
issues with zero okay but if you look at
all the math languages they all start at
one the real math languages like
Mathematica APL to Leah okay you know
MATLAB for example these for these are
math oriented or scientific languages
which is entirety of a different nature
than C++ Java Python Ruby or all of them
JavaScript including including this not
now including Haskell okay even includes
Haskell Haskell is kind of this kind of
this thing
Haskell is not math language Haskell is
not a math oriented languages okay
despite this this hacker [ __ ] you know
has cow Haskell Aeschylus they insist
they talking about math all the time
meanwhile they know nothing about math
so anyway so so so array index started
zero one so actually I talked about that
in previous video so sorry ray index
start as zero or one okay you'll find
that article so what I'm saying okay so
here's the thing here's the interesting
thing you think you see this language
this hacker types
people they think array language I mean
they think array should speaking with at
zero okay they should start at zero the
index however when you ask them the
reason half of the time they will say
because of mathematics extreme idiocy
fact that these people [ __ ] these
people yeah
extreme idiocy okay you know you ask
them you know you when you talk about
this online like hacker news raided or
Twitter you know you see these
programmers they will say did you know
they will start to give reasons right
have that reason half the reason is is
like like this they think oh math you
know if you actually respect math
mathematician they should start at zero
okay you know it's just factory 100%
factually incorrect okay why because
these programmers they idolized math
okay so they you know the reason they
think math should you know if you are a
mathematician you know they think
mathematicians should want a race start
at zero is because zero is somehow the
more dramatic number you know the like
like like the UNIX people you know the
[ __ ] UNIX philosophy like they think the
these hacker types they always prefer
something more difficult more esoteric
that's that's too weak leave a case so
they think mathematicians you know in
math 0 is actually you know in human
history in history of math you don't
have zero in the beginning you have you
know one one is natural like one two
three then you know later on you have
more abstractions then you started at
with zero then you started have have
negative numbers then you started to
have complex numbers things like that so
0 is the more dramatic between 0 and 1
so that's what that's why this
programmer ideas [ __ ] [ __ ] heads they
they think they you know they should
start at zero because they idolized math
meanwhile they are completely wrong the
other reason they think array should
start at zero is because see the [ __ ]
C language and their reason is true is
false - they think C they think they
should start at zero is because o memory
addresses therefore when you start at
zero then you can add memory addresses
things like that so therefore issues
issues begin zero which which is
factually incorrect - you know so I have
I wrote an article here you can read
later so let's copy to my you know okay
today is one giant rent I guess oh well
where is my croissant actual page let's
go to croissant actual page I yeah we
got so talk I don't know if I'm losing
my audiences or if I'm Kennie audiences
you see usually if you talk drama you
can actually get more people watching so
this is a mathematical code ok
mathematical code in fact my
mathematical code I'm pretty sure it's
incorrect if you run it you'll get
syntax errors but basically it's it's
that so anyway array languages array I
mean array should start at 0 1 so these
hacker types of programmers their reason
is wrong too because there is this guy
you know this guy Mike Hall Oh Mike oh
yeah how do you pronounce his name he
did research into the topic and so he
took up the reasons he looked into why
why does C begin with 0 in the first
phase you know why does C 3 didn't begin
C followed from C study which is which
is the BCPL you know language pc p a--
because pc p a-- was starting with this
zero
okay but what's the ultimate reason I
mean who began with zero in the first
race because because back in those days
now you have to read his article for the
details for the historically
historically accurate detail but I'm
just going to tell you my reason okay
because back in the days you have main
friends and you have punch cards you
know you don't have like today you have
punch cards you you you know you program
offline you you make the punch cards
then you insert them to the mainframe
you know billions of dollars you know to
process it then if you get 0 because
some IBM executed you know the reach the
boss who owns the machines he needs the
machine to run his yacht races you know
to compute his yacht race score
something
therefore it began with this hero haha
the array index oh my god what what a
show that is okay now I'm know I don't
know where I am now I don't know if I
should go back to JavaScript oh it's so
entirely screwed up indeed lot of
comments interesting what is this oh
well I don't have time to look at that
so let's see how long I have have I been
talking chat revenue okay four point
three uses chat revenue thank you again
beautiful people forty minutes so I've
been talking for forty minutes so let's
yeah I don't think I don't think we can
properly start JavaScript today so no
I'll do another one then another video
so anything else
what should we so so do you guys have
counter counter arguments
to my arguments or do I make sense that
this do I make a little sense on my
rants about hackers you know about their
perspective why I always said we know
why they call me a troll why I always
have problems with their opinions do I
have like me and this makes some sense
you know because my life
you know my life is known you know my
accomplishment in life is is a
truck-sized online you argue with
programmers it's gonna it's like it's
going nowhere it's like I cannot go
anywhere there is no constructive like
there is no at least you know you hope
to us establish you know some way until
we find out you know where we disagree
but typically that's not happening are I
you know typically like after you act
argued for days you know like you there
is no you know they you know and that's
a case with online arguments you know
it's religious arguments like Emacs
versus Beam or common lisp vs. scheme Oh
Python versus Perl is kind of like that
okay so okay that's a giant Rambo so
let's see where I am and let's see where
I am and let's see where do we go from
there so let's read the comments from
the bottom so Alan says I would add that
hacker types are trapped in a particular
model of the world but this sort of
behavior is very common across many kind
of subculture yes indeed that is true
you know so you know I've been doing you
know IIIi I tend to be you know I always
wanted to look at the whole historical
human per sec perspective and see what's
going on so for example if I have
disagreement with hackers you know I
what I try to do get
you know just exactly what's going on
thank you man am i just complete bizarre
you know crackpot oh you know I don't
think I am you know so what is wrong is
they are they you know so anyway so part
of it so yeah it's true you know it's
culture you know it's a subculture and
you know larger largely culture and
subculture so that's why you have these
hacker types you know they are they have
a particular in a way and habits you
know this the convention you know that's
what they are and then you know
different culture and different
subculture they are obviously different
that's why they are you know subcultures
and and the other reason I think has to
do with it is also corporations
corporations you know the in programming
industry of course it's evolving around
corporations it is the corporations that
make things move money basically you are
programmer you walk you know you have to
walk most of you you know most
programmers have to work in our company
you know you so you know the coke
corporations they make money and they it
is money they that makes the corporation
survive so money has a lot to do with it
so money creates corporations you know
comment goes in many corporations die
and new comes on and corporations
because of money they evolve around it
they have to make ways or many of the
habits or the way you see things in
programming is due to you know folk of
complex complex reasons it's due to how
the corporations are run you know how
what what makes money you know their
products that that is why so that I
think that has a lot to do with it as
well for example why is see to this day
so successful I mean well so at least so
popular why is C so popular why is all
the CPUs Intel you know it's so
convoluted but yet it's like the number
one you know CPU design why because
backward compatibility and
you know that that is because
corporations you know if you eliminate
backward compatibility then people don't
want to adopt you know for many reasons
natural reasons habit you know people
don't adopt then you die so that's so
that is why javascript is backward
compatible so we have 20 years of
garbage in JavaScript you know this is
the JavaScript people you know you talk
to them the JavaScript you know
committee they are creating the eczema
2015 16 17 2019 you know every year you
know you think you know if we are all
just programmers if we have nothing to
do with corporations or anything we can
just design okay
in 2020 we are going to have JavaScript
that eliminates all the garbage you know
20 years of you know package then then
it's gonna be good but once you talk to
them they are not going to do that you
know do you think they are just nerds
and but but they have many constraints
and you know because most of them
actually work for corporations it is the
it is the Google Facebook Microsoft they
are putting the money into you you know
and into this committee for JavaScript
design you know they and you need
membership you know like corporate
sponsor membership money is talking you
know and also again history you know you
can't just eliminate compatibility
because then or the browser break you
know many many reasons and in the same
way back to our you know the other topic
we were talking about the arrangin the
array index starting at zero or one okay
now in math communities is always one
because one is simply better easier more
human more natural to work with
especially when you have matrixes or
tensors tensors is essentially like nest
nested matrices so you have so a matrix
is like nested array okay tensors
is like more nesting of arrays so higher
dimensional nesting so that's tensors so
you have so in math they started with
one because if you begin with zero then
then you have nesting then then becomes
very unintuitive
like it's hard to you know find specific
array indexes you know the tensor
indexes that's why you know in math they
start with one
but again in computing you have to deal
with habit you know most languages they
all begin with zero now yeah well at
least industrial programming languages
you know Python Perl Java C C++ C sharp
Haskell you know just a bunch of crap
you know they all start with zero so
there's the habit going on so when you
have a new language let's say someone
invented a new language and I suppose me
or you you want to be popular then when
it comes to decision about array index
where should it begin even if you think
it should start at one but you can be
sure because if you started one you will
know for sure you will lose people you
will lose people because people are
habituated with zero you know they don't
want and they have you know they have
lots of misconceptions like when I talk
about you know they think you know their
reason for starting at zero is so
basically factually incorrect you know
but but there's nothing you can do they
already believe you know the mass in
obedience of people they believe that
already which even if it's forced so are
you going to like fight that you know
it's hard so if you are going to create
a new language you are probably going to
one based on the C syntax okay
even it's the most [ __ ] you know the
most crap syntax possible but that's
that's the way things are if you start
with some other syntax people are not
going to like your language then your
language is not
then you die nobody uses your language
it's a fact of life and then same thing
with array index you're gonna start with
zero so that's a problem that's the
thing
so maybe okay so that maybe that's it
for today so tab or spaces some of thank
god that's another topic of course Solly
tab versus space I have an article on
that and not just one article I have
more than one article on that and that
is that's a big topic and you know I'm
gonna talk about that for hours
ok so I think maybe that's it for today
so that today is just that let's see
live streaming 17 people are watching
for likes fantastic like it like like it
everyone like like myself 51 minutes
okay so no JavaScript cultural
revolution destroying the venerable ODEs
convoluted Dom yeah Dom is the massive
pain in the ass
DOM is you know we're programming okay
not javascript is the worst crap
possible even with today's you know 2008
my script 15 but then you have don't
like my god DOM is zombies and also it's
impossible to understand don't you know
it's really I tried if you really want
to know the technique code details then
okay so chapo versus mouse okay that's
another thing
oh well we haven't actually so we
haven't finished talking about what is
the what is a deal with user interface
about about about 3d rotation we haven't
talked about that
so yeah maybe we've finished that okay
so where is that
okay so 3d rotation about okay so let's
go to brave and let's see okay that's
not here okay then let's go to Google
Chrome I think it's here
close that okay so Google Chrome they
begin to show yeah okay D here so so
this is about this math models of 3d
input control actually there are two
things about it
one is the math models of 3d input
control but the other thing related I
wanted to talk about is the the actual
user interface variations about 3d input
control like when you want to rotate
with the mouse so let me talk about yeah
so okay so let me talk about the math
models of 3d input control you know you
know I'm this is not formal okay this is
not you know it might be too big a word
to say math models but anyway let me
tell you what's interesting what's going
on so when you'd use a flight control
okay like flight simulator so you fly a
plane and you see this right and you
have various controls you want to
typically you want you they call you
know each one have their Chagas like if
I control you have the peach so this is
suppose this is your airplane so how do
you so this is your app airplane you fly
forward so you have pitch which is
whether you should go up turn up or turn
down you know going up or going down
that's speech then you have row that is
you rotate around
the path you are traveling solo you can
roll right and typically you all turn
right you can roll left okay so that's
row so Petrie's is turning like that row
is turning like that then you have yo is
that right called yo right
yo is like like turning that you know so
I don't know if you understand me but if
you if you do flight simulators if you
play that you you know what I'm talking
about
so that's that's one thing about flight
simulator okay now if you are playing a
3d game let's say some real-time shooter
how do you go that like World War two
you know how do you call as some of the
names well what's what's some of the
names guys the game games where you you
control a character you're going through
you know you hold a gun you can shoot
you can look and you know I cannot
remember any names when I'm talking to
people let's see
don't okay doom doom no originally you
have to then you have then you have
half-life okay then you have half-life
yeah then you have folk you know CS wait
what no not then then you have you know
the you know the you know many any name
anyway real-time shooter games you go
around so basically you control a
character so to control that it's also
3d right so you have you have forward
movement to control your character
forward backward then you can you have a
turn you can turn your character left on
alright then you have strife kind of
like you you don't turn but you move
your character left or right like that
okay so
and so that's that's you're moving your
character but usually you don't yeah
quick quick is another one exactly Craig
yeah so so in those games you have
several movements going forward backward
turnleft turnright and and strife kind
of move your character parallel to the
screen so that's one thing
then then another thing is that if you
can fly
well that then that's becomes like a
flight simulator okay okay that's one
thing then let me tell you another thing
para rant pad panorama
okay so para ran lemma is another
interesting interesting thing with 3d
control now you know what you you guys
have seen parent panoramas right of
course you have so let's pick something
you know let's say that
so you so here you can control so that
you know you have different kind of user
interface controls but but in here
basically you can rotate kind of rotate
the whole scene you know you you
yourself you don't go forward you don't
go back walk backward but you can rotate
the whole thing or rotate up and down
you know the host whole scene and you
can but some some paramatma you can also
pet you know they they have a jog on pad
like that is you move your entire screen
you know movie up trend like translate
move it up or down so that's pet okay so
that's panorama panorama yes then
another thing which is also common is
when you are doing 3d modeling like in
blender in blender or in maiya you know
they change their name over the past 20
years so you have auto cad blender you
have maiya or whatever whatever is the
current
you know they so in those cases usually
you have a object let me show you let me
show you in those cases you have a
object that you want to rotate it looks
like okay let me it looks like this okay
so this so here is the object so
typically you can rotate this thing you
know you can rotate right left up down
or sometimes in your angle you rotate it
so so we have all these different 3d
kind of scenario where you want it all
has to do with 3d and it all has to do
with rotation in some some way okay like
rotating our object around its center or
panorama is kind of you rotate the scene
kind of or then you have pan then you
have then you have again you know
shooting game you move your characters
forward backward left right and strife
then you have the flight simulator yo
and that so I'm thinking you know all
these things can you somehow unify them
you know like how do you think like when
you how do you think them in some kind
of unified way like you know K obviously
they must be you know so that's that's a
question to explore that was what
happened I was thinking you know so
obviously yes of course you can unify
them in fact that's how if you program
them that's what you have to do so
basically doesn't matter which one it is
it's a game it's a flight simulator or
it's a panorama or it's oh it's a math
subject you want to rotate you when you
when you try to implement them basically
all of them have what they happen what
happens is that you have a scene okay
like for example this is a scene this is
a scene you know the
is what you know like you have a 3d
model of a 3d space then you have a
camera now the camera represent your
position of your eye okay so basically
what what it amounts to is that you can
move your camera forward backward left
right Oh think of your camera as a P you
know you can you you can also move your
femoral like move your camera like a B
you can move the camera in any path
that's one thing okay you can move your
camera in any path but also the camera
itself can have different orientation it
can point up down or even backwards so
that's the two parameters that's the
thing you control okay so you can move
your parent cameras up at up and down I
mean the oh okay so two things the path
of the camera that's one thing the other
thing is the is the orientation of the
camera okay basically that's the two
parameters that controls the only other
different scenarios okay so so in a case
of rotating your object what happened is
that your camera does not move stays put
and the cameras orientation doesn't move
neither it just points to you know it's
facing an object so when you are
rotating the object you can think of it
as rotating the object or you can think
of it as actually moving the camera so
you are moving the camera in a way such
that the distance between the camera and
the object remains constant
so in other words the camera stays on a
sphere and while the camera moves on the
sphere it always points to the center
the object so that's you know that's how
you think about this you know either you
can think of rotating the object the
camera stay put which is
or you think of the object remains not
moving you move the camera around the
sphere so that that's one thing and if
you want to zoom that's that's you
that's moving the camera closer zoom out
is moving a camera backward backward so
so that puts the whole thing into one
coherent thing you know which is this is
not rocket science you know just you
know so you know I was looking at this
so I'm thinking so that's obviously so I
found the answer that's how you do it
that's how you think about these so when
it comes to panoramas what happened is
that the camera stay put but meanwhile
the camera changed it changes its
orientation you know if the camera
changes orientations so then when it
comes to 2d game I mean fede game then
in that case the camera typically stay
near the bottom it can move forward left
or right or backward and it also can
turn you know change the orientation but
it never typically never goes up or go
down you know it stays on the floor so
so once you know these so you know the
the actual 3d model then many of the
kind of the the UI now you have a better
understanding about the UI about how it
falls into face so so that is what I'm
talking about so this is about the math
model of 3d 3d 3d games or panorama or
or math visualization software you know
3d modeling software things like that so
you understand this model then the other
thing now is about the input the user
interface control for example you know a
3d game in a 3d game
by convention you use the arrow to
control your basically your camera
movement you use the mouse to control
the cameras orientation like typically
you know when you look around that's
controlled by your mouse the cameras
orientation now in a flight simulator
how do they do that in flight simulator
I guess similar right yeah so you use
you know you use the keyboard to control
the the the airplane path you know row
row peach and and yo then then you also
use the mouse to control that your view
I mean your your camera orientation so
so that's that know the okay so now the
other thing I want that becomes
interesting when we are talking about
rotating something for visualization
like in JavaScript there are several
ways to implement it this for example I
think in vast majority of 3d software
I mean math visualization software where
you visualize a object usually they they
only have two rotational axes so you can
rotate the object around X or you can
rotate it around Y so let me show you
that so that is the case with the
polyhedron here so let's go to anyway I
don't know if this is interesting you
know I took too long to talk about this
it becomes boring because people
understand what it means already so for
example let's say a cube okay so let's
say let's say out I soak each one so I
can press my my mouse up or down I mean
my arrow keys up down so that's rotating
around the x-axis oh I can press right
and left arrow it moves it rotates
around the Z
axis so there's only two rotation axes
y&z okay but with this combination you
can orient the object in any way you
want with just these two rotations now
if you are going to do the mouse now I
haven't done that but if I implement in
the mouse I can do the same thing so
again for example typically you you hold
down the mouse you dry start to drag it
then you drag it to the right and you
release the mouse depends on how fast
you release the button that determines
how happy how fast it rotates so it will
but the thing is now so it will so it
will rotate in in y axis and also
rotating at x axis together like you
combine them into one so that's one way
to do it another way typically like when
you we okay let me explain this way when
you have a like you go around you look
for you know math visualization like
rotation almost never okay it is almost
never the case where you can either
press a button or use the mouse so that
they wrote the whole thing rotate like
that okay it oh it's almost never the
case
but however some software they did that
so what I'm saying is that you see they
are different ways to to implement the
UI like how do you want the mouse to
work with the how do you want to the
rotation to work for example yeah it's
actually they are quite a kind of few
examples I can explain like right now
you are seeing the way I do it okay so I
mean this is the way I do it now there
are other software where
well I actually take a lot to expend
when you talk about 3d things unless you
actually show an example yeah I don't
have an example here but well I can just
tell you I mean I'll try okay so there
are some software you know for 3d
surface plot in software where you can
rotate the thing around the z-axis then
your keep rotating around that axis then
you you press another button it doesn't
it doesn't work like the way I have but
rather it keeps rotating around that
axis so you just see it's like a tough
okay it's like a tough so you can start
the top it will rotate then you can you
can teared it you'll just keep rotating
like that you see what I mean it doesn't
it doesn't like start to flip like say
in some weird way like like what I have
here like the one I have here
let's try cube you see I'd rotate you
know I rotate right in that and I rotate
then it flips in a we away you kind of
lost orientation on your hand some
software math software you just rotate
like a top doesn't matter how you rotate
is still you know it shows like a top
you're just viewing it from different
perspectives so that's what I'm talking
about you have quite a variety zuv
trying to do the rotation UI for
rotating a object okay that is what I'm
saying so which one is better for
example in blender you know so Allen you
use blender right so what does blender
do I think blender typically they would
do just like the way I have it you know
you rotate around two axes oh you know
so I don't know what blender does so
anyway let's let's think that's that's
what I have that's what I missed
that's today's talk show guys okay any
I'm gonna read the comments and
for five minutes and that's it for today
one hour and 12 minutes are you modeling
a play-doh yes
why are the players in a room smaller
than your eyeglasses what potato oh
those are not potatoes those are pears
okay you guys give any demo the
demonstration of perspectiva tea
the juices are coming up I don't want to
drop them those are pears delicious
so that's it that is it that there was
there was delicious Paris juicy pears
when I dropped them the juice comes out
so and that's it for today thank you
guys for coming I'm and I'm going to
read the comments for a minute or two
and that's it I don't think there's much
comments serious ones I guess
no JavaScript culture okay so we did I
saw that
good morning Kathy good morning Fitch
now Fitch Fitch you are in Germany right
good morning Kathy to UK now rowcount
okay enroll count guys
Nabby young Nobby is from California or
was it
California right and an Allen in
California California the great
California Emily in UK and I would read
that hacker types are trapped in yeah so
any more people
okay so nappy nappy young Ram Prasad
Hey Ram Prasad I have crossed the path
to zero so far back I think I will be
confused what I forgot what that was Ram
Prasad
we are euphoric where are you from
good morning hello beautiful people
bye guys I guess
and that is true bye guys