Hello, good morning, good evening
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
talk show. Uh we are going to uh do some
coding mathematics geometry special
plane curves with wuang language. But
the first two minutes let me introduce
my keyboards. This is UHK80
ultimate hacking keyboard. Fantastic.
This is Nia trapo and that is Logitech
mouse with a infinite spin wheel. Okay.
And here is the Huang
E H uh UI O N. I believe that's a brand
name. Huang um drawing tablet. Okay,
that's introduction. So I got a review
on YouTube for each one of them. Uh so
let's go to my screen. So go to it.
Okay. So, so today if you have seen the
YouTube description, it's just me coding
working on my special plane curves
mathematics geometry. Okay. So, what
does that mean special plane curves?
It's this okay this project
and we just going to go easy. Uh I'm
just going to work on my website. I mean
so it's my working session coding woof
language and along the way I'll explain
some interesting things about these fan
curves. I did this 30 years ago 199
uh 3 to 1997
to uh 2000s. Okay. So uh fantastic
beautiful plane curves. Okay. So, we're
gonna code some of that in Wuam language
and uh uh just casual. If you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed. If you are watching here,
say hi. Okay, play at 1.5 speed. Uh and
I'm using Emacs, of course. So, uh so
first of all, you you need to know.
Okay, so my keyboard, search for
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. You can see a
lot fantastic
videos and uh photos, okay, on my
website kasali.info.
Search for it, you'll find it.
kasali.info. Uh ultimate hacking
keyboard uh80.
Okay, fantastic review. And you can also
find of course my um so this is you are
looking at talk show kasadi.info my
homepage. You'll find it this in today's
talk show and uh my equipments ultimate
hacking keyboard of course and uh Nia
track ball M505.
Fantastic. That's this one on the side
here. Okay. Yeah. Fantastic. And and and
Huang H640P
uh pen tablet drawing tablet. Okay. So
that's some of my um devices. Okay. And
wam language that's what we're going to
do. Uh and uh so if you
don't know here's my wam language
packages. So I wrote this 30 years ago
and I updated them about a year ago. So
you can draw all these amazing and
beautiful plank curves and show their
illustrate their properties. So these
are my woof language packages. Of
course, it's free. Uh you just download
it on uh GitHub, okay? On GitHub link
here. Just search for it. Plank curve
plot package by
X ahl
my name on.info.
And this not you know and I got quite a
few of the packages. plank curve plot
package that's the most popular
allows you to plan a lot properties of
plank curves. Okay. Then you got plank
curve formulas. So this is just a
collection of formulas. Formulas for
each plane curve you have you know
formula is hard to remember. So you know
you have kind of like a database
actually just 39 of them. Okay. So then
then you got plank generator package.
This package is fantastic because it
generates animations. So you can see all
these special ways due to the properties
of plank curves. You can generate them.
Uh I can't play because uh because it's
not animation anyway. You can see it in
in my plank curve package in my panc
website. So all these are animations.
Fantastic. Okay, that's so you can
download this package and you can
generate them. Okay. So, and I have
other uh so besides plank curve, I got
this one is more uh kind of more
advanced. This is for tilings and
tidings and uh uh plain tidings and
patterns. Okay. For kind of creating
decorative patterns, fantastic and
beautiful. And also I have a package
that's uh wam charcoal plot and well
this one. Okay. So go back transform 2D
plot. So this this package is designed
for to for plotting complex functions or
rather it's more like for plane
transforming plane to a plane 2D plane.
Okay. So because of this package and
others, I got contacted by a Nobel Prize
winner
whose name is uh something a glass or
something um from Berkeley. He so this
is around 1996
around 1990s. Okay. So he contacted me
uh so I was you know so this is kind of
my story. He contacted me around 1997.
I I still have the email somewhere. And
he was wondering if I would work for
him. So, he's a Nobel Prize winner. Uh
what's his name? He passed away. I
noticed. Uh he passed away about like 10
years ago.
Uh no, let's see if we can find the
name. Nobel
Prize.
Uh a glacer physics, I think. Is it was
it physics or uh something? Okay.
Uh Glacer, Donald Glazer. Okay. I think
that's the guy. New uh American
physicist and new neurobiologist.
Okay. Let's check. I think that's a guy.
He's at Berkeley
uh in the 1990s.
Okay. Now remember in 1990s we don't
have Wikipedia. Not like you guys today.
you can enjoy Wikipedia, find
information easily. So, but in the
1990s, we don't have that. So, when
someone contact you, you you know, you
might notice he's a Nobel Prize uh
recipient because of his email
signature. Then you have to look up, you
know, you have to check uh in books or
in list encyclopedias. Okay. So, let's
see if is this guy. Yeah, Berkeley. You
see Berkeley. So, he passed away 2013.
you know, I was kind of idiotic, you
know. So, anyway, I'm talking a little
bit about my personal life story. I was,
you know, I'm a nerd. I am a nerd. I
still am all my life. I'm just like
focused on programming and mathematics
because I truly, you know, enjoy it. Um,
but I was also somewhat a failure. Okay.
So, you know, he contacted me. I would
have I probably
you know, it's probably better if I
Yeah, that's, you know, you know, I just
go and work for him or or work for Wuan
Research. Anyway, so my life is kind of
complicated
in part because uh failed family, okay,
problematic family. So, so anyway, I
didn't do anything with the guy. He just
contacted me. He contacted me because of
this uh in particularly because of this
package. Okay, this uh transformation
transform 2D plot. I wrote that in like
1995.
Cheers. So, here is a red wine and some
grape some uh red wine plus grape juice
plus
um blueberry.
Uh yeah. Was it blueberry or raspberry?
It's called blueberry. Blueberry juice
plus um
uh apple.
Freshly fresh juice. Okay. Not not from
bottles. It's freshly uh chopped up.
Hello, Roan Drew. Must be cool to have
talked or interacted with a Nobel Prize
winner. Yeah.
Uh yeah, I was kind of, you know, I you
know, I can say I'm lucky.
Um but um you know but you see life is
big you know you you you know you can be
ambitious like like typic like
depending on the person like a lot you
know like I would want to be
a known mathematician
you know but I I kind of failed so I
wasn't a known mathematician I kind you
know so my life is kind of like at the
end near the end uh I wasn't known known
mathematician nor was I a you know
famous professor nor was I a like a
Nobel Prize winner of course not
everyone can do that but
you do you may have the ambition so
anyway so it was um anyway it's it's
it's
a um it's a good thing it's an honor to
to be able to say. I kind of like he
contacted me and I don't know anything
about him actually. So I haven't you
know really looked into what exactly u
but just know because email you know he
sent me an email anyway. So I wanted to
do so let's kind of introduction. So
let's um you know so let's do let's
continue to do the random things I'm
going to do. I'm just going to do
Yeah. So if you guys don't know, you can
download Wuam language. Okay, I talked
about this a million times. Okay,
download it. Uh and and my wam language
from the tutorial for from the ground up
for programmers. Okay, there's lots of
information you can uh learn from today.
you know today you got not just me, you
got YouTube, you got lots of other
also professors and uh also you know
lots of uh qualified uh teachers and and
encyclopedias and so on. Anyway, so
let's see what I want to do. So let's go
to the plank curves. Okay, so so this
project is 30 years old. I wrote it when
I was young, when I was like in college
like
uh I started late. So at that time I was
like 20 20 years old, 21 pretty late
because I don't have the normal
childhood like let's say average
Americans where you go to high school uh
or you go to college when you are 18 or
17. But I was pretty late so I didn't
you know I anyway so I you know so I did
this 30 years ago when I was younger. So
I wanted to
let's just update some random. Okay
let's see uh let's see some of these
images are still uh low quality. For
example this uh why is this low quality?
For example this hyperola.
Okay, even that is not true. So, let's
copy that. Let's start wam language.
By the way, we did this before like uh
maybe a year ago. We did quite a few
videos doing this. Uh these are all
updated by the way. So, we did this live
actually in live stream and we also did
several animations. Uh so, do we have
like a
Yeah, we did it live. So you see this is
this is um
Mhm.
for example we did that live in one of
the videos. Okay. So, wra language paste
the code and let's magnify it.
and
uh shift enter. Shift enter to evaluate
it.
Fantastic. Isn't that fantastic and
beautiful? That's the power of wam
language.
Every time I see it, it's beautiful.
It's just beautiful, you know.
So, and you press a key control shift N
to to format it in in a mathematical
type set. And also I need to show this.
You see, you don't have to worry about
indentation or how you format your code.
It's automatic on the fly. You see
interactively in real time. They form
they can wam language notebook can
format the code in real time. See? So,
not like the Python idiots or C, C++
idiots. They say, "Oh, you need to, you
know, tab versus space. Let's make it
all uh hardcoded so you don't have to
worry about it." You know, it's idiots.
It's a industrial coders. Idiot. I I
must emphasize this again. So the
industrial coders you see programming
activity in the programming industry
which is a human endeavor well not just
you know not just endeavor but it's a
part of the industry business you know
enterprise which is a critical industry
because pro programming you know you
banking they they all need computers
right it's a big industry but they uh
but But it is true that u certain you
know the way they do things I mean it is
true in general in human fields and
activities sometimes they for a long
period of time 10 or 20 years they do
things in a very stupid way like the
[ __ ] stupid way
for reasons okay for for reasons like
like you know they don't know at that
time or whatever so you know what so one
of the thing I want to claim is that the
the industrial coders like typically C,
C++ coders and today most coders like in
you know like whatever you do like Java
coders uh you know coders today
JavaScript coders, Python coders,
professional coders working at Google or
Microsoft you know all these coders like
when when it comes to uh code formatting
like they have no idea what is good and
What is bad? This is my claim. Okay. You
see this wuam language feature like they
don't know this. They don't know. They
never seen it. They have never seen it
in their life. This prof professional
Google coders you know JavaScript
framework creator whatever these fancy
people you know like but you know or C++
you know extremely complicated. Oh, C++
game engine creator in their life like
most of them most of them like they've
never seen
the a concept that somehow the co the
editor should be able to like format
your code like in real time. This this
idea like they never seen it. They never
seen it. Meanwhile, their idea, this
this fancy coders, you know, Python,
kiddo von Rosa, I created Python
language. I tell you what to do. Their
idea of formatting is that that that you
should make it, you know, no, you know,
more than um
[laughter]
code should not be more than 80
characters per line. Where does that
came from? That came from punch cards.
That's a
that's a history like habit from punch
cards. Okay. By the way, the other day
uh a few month ago I went with a friend
Cortez
to the computer museum. So I actually
took some photos of the punch cards.
Anyway, here's the punch cards, you
know, used like 60 70 years ago.
So,
so this is the origin
of the 80 characters per line like
convention that you you will hear to
even today even today you know the get
you know get they will tell you please
do not have your line more than 80
characters you should try to format it
you know
[ __ ] extreme idiocy.
Okay, can can you guys see it? Do you
guys see what I mean? So, so we have the
phenomenon in the programming industry
of of these people like they don't know
they don't know they don't know it you
know they just don't know
but but things are slowly improving.
Okay. So for example in the past in the
coding you know community programming
coding community or uh
or software engineers that's another
term for our community is that we you
know we we learn things we do learn
things and improve change slowly. So for
example we started to learn okay you
know you should have automatic memory
management even though it's
controversial you know but then you
started have rust you have you know or
goland you know you have started to have
new languages and then you learned about
oh okay new is maybe not a good thing
you know there's a famous guy who
created a article a talk about you know
a famous computer scientist what's his
name I forgot at moment but he created
did a talk uh five or 10 years ago about
like the million dollar mistake N okay
from the guy uh what's his name I forgot
he's a one one of the well-known uh
computer scientist okay you know no so
we do learn mistakes gradually you know
so no is probably not a good thing and
the C has lots of issues um you know
it's not really high level language it's
kind of you
uh C++ got lots of issues and then
eventually now you know we have Goland
which was created as a C++ replacement
okay it didn't it did not exactly
succeed
the way the author intended but however
it did succeed it replaced lots of other
you know it's very popular
and then you do have rust which is uh
kind of another approach you know and
and then also functional programming uh
has came up and fair you know became uh
you used in lots of industries in for
example in stock trading in financial
banking industries you know so we do
have improvements but it's kind of slow
okay so anyway what so again let me
emphasize let me tell you guys this this
this code formatting feature Okay. Now
what does this involve? I you know I can
talk about this. You see I can talk talk
about this uh
for hour or two. Um you see this this
this
um in order for this kind of uh
capabilities if you want that that has
to do with also the programming
languages syntax. Okay. It's like
intertwined. they are intimately tied
together with a programming language
syntax. Okay. And also, you know, by the
way, also you can see there's a
mathematical type setting. I can turn it
off. Control shift I. Okay. Wait. Uh
what? Control Wait. Control shift
I. Yeah, you can turn it off. But you
you turn off the auto the mathematical
type set. However, you still have Oh,
wait. Not control shift I. You still
have the uh automatic format. Okay. So,
let's see what is it. Uh cell convert to
um
input form.
Wait. Control Shift I.
Wait, control shift N. Control shift I.
Okay. No, you don't have the automatic
and Well, actually, you do, but um
I can just paste it. Can you see?
Can you see now if I magnify it? You
see? You see? So what I'm saying here is
that this automatic on the fly
formatting is not tied to
uh is not tied to the mathematical type
set. Okay, they are separate things.
Mathematical type set is one feature.
Okay, you can see the square root there.
Okay, the fraction that's type setting.
Okay. So you can have integrals, you can
have summation. That's mathematical type
set. Okay. Now this feature is distinct.
It's separate. Okay. With the um with
the automatic formatting. They not
necess uh not tied together. You see? So
this exactly the same code here.
It's not type set, but you you still
have this automatic formatting. Okay. So
anyway, that's one thing. So I so
let me say this again. So this is a
formatting issue of programming language
code and what I am saying is that in the
coding industry vast majority of
majority of people like they don't know
they don't they don't understand they
don't know they never first of all they
never seen this they never seen this for
why why haven't they ever ever ever seen
this because wamin language is a
commercial product also it's mostly for
doing it's like for engineering between
scientists, for physicist, for
mathematicians. It's not
it's not not typically uh like a
programmer's tool not the industrial
programmer you know web web dev coders
uh Linux oper operating system coders
you know it's not
usually it's not it's more more for
mathematicians physist engineers who
needs to build cars which you know
engines uh bridges which in turn require
you to do lots of mathematics. Okay, so
that's a kind of the background of wam
language and also it's a proprietary
uh software. So vast majority of the
coders you know like the programmers the
industrial coders they don't know that
is why they haven't they don't know this
they don't know they never heard of it
okay um and you have to pay you know
language well today it's like free you
can download you know for your personal
project you can use it but for the past
20 years it's like you have to pay
$2,000
okay So, so, so you know, first of all,
most of the industrial programmers,
professional coders, they never seen it.
Then you have the idiotic idea because
of the habit, you know, because of of
the punch cards.
Can you can you see how incredible like
the incredibility, the idiocy, the the
the because they because of habit from
punch cards? That's why oh you must
please make your make sure your code has
only you know lines doesn't go more than
80 characters long
let me show some code okay to illustrate
so
uh search
okay let me show some code to illustrate
so here is the here is a typescript
javascript code okay so they these
people will say uh show ruler mod okay
Please do not format you know oh this
long this line is too long please make
it um like uh they would say like uh
please make it like like that. Okay. And
and other things you know like these
people. So so these people so so so
why do they have this kind of idiotic
concept but most of them do not realize
it. Like for example, you show them my
video, do that. I would be uh pleased.
Thank you guys. You know, show them show
people your friends my video, right? You
show them most of most of them will get
offensed offended. They they don't
agree. They think no you are wrong code
must be you know you must manually hard
code you know let's say um
you know show spaces you know you can
see. So every time so there's a return
there's a return this is the way things
should be and you you you know
you know like they they have they you
know you you show them you tell them
this uh about this feature you know
instantaneous formatting technology this
by the way this began in 1996 okay you
show them this they think oh oh that's
nice but but the next day by tomorrow So
they forgot about it. They are back to
these you know C C especially among like
the industrial coders, Coders,
C++ coders, the Java coders and Python.
Python Python is like the worst. Python
made the you know this kind of
formatting
um hardcoded. So you can never it's so
py python
made a decision in their programming
language so that so such that this this
automatic formatting is is now
impossible.
Okay, that's what h that's what uh
Python did. Okay, this automatic
formatting is like now impossible
because Python they the GO van roam the
idiot. They they forced they they they
forced hard code. It's like a image you
know like bit map image instead of SVG
you know they like
so you must display them at certain size
otherwise they got [ __ ] up just like
just like the 80 lines per character you
know like if your windows is is only 70
uh characters wide then you you see jack
lines that's what happened you know
that's this these idiots okay so again
what I'm saying is that these industrial
coders for the past 30 years we we do
have this flaw this phenomenon this
these people they just um
you know they just don't know. So so it
takes time to improve slowly slowly.
Okay. So but this is by the way this is
not a new phenomenon.
This is not a new phenomenon. for
example, keyboards. Okay,
now most of you know, most of you guys
know about the quarty keyboard layout.
Okay, uh so let's go to let me show you
if you guys haven't heard of it. Uh
quarty, okay, laptop do it, do do it
yourself keyboards, ergonomic keyboards.
Uh we want to go to key caps. No, we
want to go to keyboard layouts. Okay.
So, layouts and let's just jump to uh
the keyboard layout. So, you see this is
a keyboard layout. A sdf qwy.
That's the keyboard you are familiar on
every keyboard. Let's say for example
Apple Apple keyboard, right? So, this
letter arrangement that's called quatty.
Why is it arranged that way? because
it's the most because basically it's
they it's that way because they want to
slow typewriters down.
Okay, there's controversy but basically
they just they want to prevent jam and
basically effectively slow typ you know
touch typist down. So that's why we got
the quy and it stuck it stuck with us
for for 200 years since like 200 years
ago since the invention of typewriters.
Okay.
Uh since the invention of type
typewriters okay so what I'm saying is
that so why are we stuck with this like
like like this idiotic you know like
this
thing? Well, that's just the way they
are. They, you know, we happen, you
know, because for lots of reasons. This
inertia
habit, you can't force people. People uh
habit is one of the most sticky thing.
Okay? You don't want you know you like
you cannot force people to change
because they already know this. They are
familiar. Familiarity is the critical
thing. It's not that they don't want to,
but they just they I mean they they they
you know takes time to learn things. So,
and also you can't force every keyboard
to like uh manufacture to like change
their design, you know, that that takes
you, you know, takes a lot of money. So,
there's a lot of reasons, you know,
things are stuck that's not good.
So in the same way so this you got this
formatting issue okay this this
industrial coders like they never seen
this like they don't know [laughter]
they they think that you should have
like 80 characters per line and and
Python you should have like Python
Python syntax indentation
okay extremely idiotic okay I think
that's it for today for you know we just
talked about that
So, who is watching? Do we have like do
I have like eight people? Oh, Jesus.
Three.
Don't books also have a convention to
limit the number of characters per line.
Yes, books do. Well, books do because
books books are physical. Books is not
like computer screen. You could have you
know
you know like a movie screen in theaters
or your phone screen is just like less
than 80 characters per line.
So in books of course you have to you
know you can you know you what happens
when you reach the edge you have to do a
return of course.
Okay, we started to talk about random
this that that that thing and uh so did
we um
wow so I going to work offline then
so I need to work offline on my curve
stuff uh okay
so let's um so let today's talk show be
focused on the formatting okay so let me
show you some examples of um articles
I've written. Okay. So let this let
today's talk just be focused on
about the formatting issue. Okay. So now
close that. We did a screenshot of that
uh unic code fun. Okay. Unicode is fun.
Fantastic
special plane curves. So let's go to um
yeah let's search uh formatting. Okay
this
uh yeah let me mention a few things. Um
I have quite a few articles about it
actually.
Um
okay lots of articles. Okay. So, let's
see.
Uh,
[sighs]
okay. So,
so there is some uh some Emacs for you
Emacs people. Okay. Change file new line
format. Okay. That's not what I want.
There are uh format HTML code. So for
those of you who are Emacs users, so
there are some tips of code I've
written. So you can press a key to
reformat or HTML code. For example,
let's go to today's talk show. Let me
demo. Okay. So here is today talk show
in browser. That's what it looks like.
So let's say go to uh you know. So you
know this is a list uh you know. So this
is a list. So let's you know let's make
them look like that show in browser. It
doesn't matter. Okay. But however
sometime you know sometimes you want to
format it. So you can press a key it
will reformat the entire page HTML. For
example if I put this would they format
it? Yeah they you see they break them.
You see the URL. So you see there is the
URL there and there's another unordered
list. Okay. But if you combine them,
let's say save it. And let's say also
this uh this section which is this date.
Let's say you also make them one line.
Make them one line. Save. Okay. Show in
browser. It doesn't matter. But let's
say if you want to format it. Let's say
make the whole thing one line. Show in
browser. Okay. It clear. It still works.
Right now let's say you want to format.
Okay. So you just press a key. That by
the way that command is saw reformat
lines. Okay. So press a key. Fantastic.
Can you see they got you know
reformatted the whole HTML page. So this
URL this URL that's one the YouTube uh
you see that's the
and and then this URL is the live
stream. So anyway, the point is that I
got a command uh so that command is
called um wait what is the command name?
So let's see. Describe key. Press the
key. Wait, what? Describe key. Press the
key. The command is HTML format buffer.
Okay. And you can get the command
on my website. Okay. So I can so there.
Okay. Uh yeah, search for it. You'll
find it. Emacs format HTML code. So you
can so just press a key in your buffer.
You'll do that for the whole file. And
you have that for CSS as well. And you
also have that for JavaScript. You also
have that for Python. I wrote I wrote
this. Okay. So it's free. You can grab
it open source. You also have that for
Goland. You also have that for
PowerShell. PowerShell is kind of lousy.
Uh by the way most of these also rely on
a uh external program. For example for
HTML and CSS
uh it requires the Deno JavaScript
engine. I highly recommend Deno. Okay.
Deno
uh for JavaScript also Deno for Python
it requires the black. There's uh one
thing called black. Okay. So if you read
my page usually I I will give full
detail. For example, what is the black?
Black is a tool in Python community that
reformats Python code. Okay. According
to a standard written by this Lucas
Langa guy. Um it doesn't support Python
2. Okay. So black how you inst to
install it. What are the command line
line options? And by the way, there's
alternative called YAPF
for Python to format format Python code.
Okay, so I talked about um Okay, so let
me let me let me just do this because
I'm going to talk about that more later.
So anyway, so Emacs, you got Python,
then you also got Golan. Golan requires
Golan, of course, the Golan compiler.
Then PowerShell requires you install to
um kind of a PowerShell tool. Okay, that
install module name PSS script analyzer.
Uh PowerShell one is not very good.
And there's a list one which is uh
problematic. Uh anyway, someone has
written a list one uh but I haven't
integrated.
It's kind of it's got some problems.
Okay. But anyway, you look at this page,
you'll find out which one that is. They
there are a few. Okay. Uh most of them
like they don't work except one of them
works kind of I believe last time I
checked. Okay. Check out the guy.
What's his name? Um
so we did a talk show about this
formatting issue. I think I did actually
quite a lot about this formatting issue.
Okay. So this uh so what is the guy's
name anyway so this this is about
automatic format this code okay so
anyway that's all these are emac this
code
now is there something else I want to
talk about yes um
okay no well okay so anyway yeah so
actually more so actually the other
things I want to tell you guys is that
Um
yeah so this is about one line
formatting code so uh this is about the
hack of cint f format string okay that's
very interesting but I wanted to tell
you about um
okay let's go to um
line let's just say truncation okay now
these are my rents Okay. Line
truncation. So, open that. Open that.
So, quite a few
uh so you know the line truncation. So,
it kind of it came from Unix. Okay.
Because Unix in in the 70s, in the '9s,
they have uh the nasty habit to silently
cut cut off your lines if it's more than
80 characters. Okay? Remember guys,
that's from Unix. Unix did it the most
nasty operating system. The most [ __ ]
Unix. Okay, Unix like silently truncate
your lines if your every if your line is
more than 80 characters that came from
Unix like perase pervasively in all its
tools. So in the early days it just you
know sorry line is too too long and they
silently truncate it like just cut it
off so bad you know like when you have a
tar fire when you t it it is silently
truncate if the path is more than like
120 characters.
So I have documentation of it and also
uh in MySQL
uh documentation uh this is around uh
they also cited my um my article. Okay.
So in even so in even 2001 Unix tool tar
still truncate long path file names.
Okay. So if you have a directory you
want to tie it and if so happens some of
your directory has long names so such
that all together it's more than 120
characters the tar tool will silently
truncate your file path
you know that's how bad it is from Unix
the Unix [ __ ] the Unix and C
[ __ ] they created this situation
okay
so that's you know so So, so this this
this idea of you should have 80 lines
per character that's very harmful and it
came from Unix which in turn came from
the punch cards. Okay, like we we were
talking about the punch cards.
So that's very bad. Uh
so I hope you guys you know hear about
that and stop doing that. Tell your
friends to stop doing that. So this is
one of my earliest video about this
formatting and line truncation. So this
one is 2019
May 3rd Unix philosophy truncate line
closure concurrency AI consciousness.
Okay
then. Okay. So then there you know
there's series of events the harm of
hard wrapping lines 80 characters per
line. That's another art article because
this this issue is one of the biggest
issue in my life. So I've been writing
about it for like by now
25 years you know or 30 years.
So it is a Unix the extreme idiots the
Unix and C type of people. they like
they don't know about this. They they
they like even today pro today you talk
to most coders in the programming
industry may it be C++ Java they will
probably tell you oh you shouldn't have
you know lines longer than 80 characters
why because well it's easier easier to
read you know because their idea you
know they they they don't know about
this uh like they forgot about this
automatic line wrap like they don't
think That's like you see in a browser
when what what happens when a line is
too long they automatically wrap of
course and in woven language language it
does even better it wrap in a smart way
for code. So you can see this
indentation. You can see this table for
example you look at watch the beginning
of the table that's indented. You see
now if your window is white there's no
in you know it's like one line you see
smart. So, but normally you can do that
for text editor like you know like Alice
in Wonderland land or whatever it wraps
your lines right
but when it comes to code
like these idiots the C C++ Java coders
Python coders Golang whatever language
Ruby you know all like all of them like
they they forgot they forgot about the
the like the automatic wrapping or even
in Discord
happens in Discord on Twitter
everywhere. Okay. Like happens you know
like on on Twitter
like do you if you don't press enter
every 80 lines does that mean your like
does that mean your your your words will
disappear? No. It automatically you see
it automatically wrap right? It's called
soft wrap
right. So why do you have to hard return
at every 80 character? You don't have
to. This is trader and here is discord.
Same thing. Okay. Wait. Here is discord.
You see does does that mean you know so
you have this very smart
automatically adjust to your window size
by a soft wrap. So you don't have to
manually like the manual idiots like I
need to count how many characters so
far. Oh not 80. Okay I need to do a line
return. That's from the C idiots Unix.
But to this day when it comes to code
most of these people will still think
that oh yeah you need to you need to
have a line return that this you know
when when it's um
when it's 80 characters you know turn on
the ruler mod you see these people like
can can you guys imagine how how did how
how is it possible that they this they
think that way
okay I'm telling you guys okay this guy
this issue
to this day. So this how uh it's like a
huge damage uh you know.
So let's go back to the browser and I
think that's it. Uh so I got several
other um so I was going to I was showing
you guys you know some of the articles
rent I wrote starting in 2002. This is
my first one I think Unix RFC line
truncation 2002. Okay, I think that's my
first article about this issue. Then I I
wrote a lot about it, you know, like the
uh uh line truncation issue. So there is
uh yeah so the harm of hard wrapping
lines. This here's another article
and uh uh 2005 then there's tab versus
space in source code which is a very
controversial thing tab versus space you
know and which which one is better tabs
okay tab is better if you have to do it
manually but then the Python idiots they
did they went with space but Goland Rob
Pike made the uh made the right choice
tabs Okay, Tab is better and the F
people by the Don whatever what's what's
his name the the guy who uh created F
compiler for Microsoft I think his name
is Don something he they they went with
spaces idiots incredible idiots okay so
the so there's a tab versus space uh
which I wrote you know my long rant in
200 2005 or 2006.
Okay. Uh and then there's al another
related uh what does it mean when white
space is insignificant in programming
languages? Okay. I think that's it for
today. Okay.
Have you checked out the Zim browser?
No, I haven't. What? Vertical tabs.
Vertical tabs. Well, vert vertical tabs
is now in Firefox.
uh and as well as in um in Brave
browser.
So
I don't know what is a Zim browser.
So okay that's it for today. Bye guys.
Okay. Zen browser. Interesting. The new
browser. Zen is a Firefoxbased browser
with a M pushing your productivity to a
new level.
Whenever you hear that, that's kind of
[ __ ] Okay.
Uh browsers, you know, there's a lot
effort to create new browsers. They
usually, you know, come and go like they
they begin then after a year they
disappeared. Uh so what about Zam
browser? Zen browser is a free and open
source fork of Mozilla. Okay. in 2024
with a focus on privacy, customers,
customer custom ability and design many
of the layout changes. Okay, the key
question is who created it? What does he
want? That usually is the key that
determines the fate of this browser.
Who created it? What's his background?
What does he want?
That's a key. Okay. Like for example, is
he like part of the deep state? Is he
just like, you know, what what what is
his mentality? What is he thinking? What
what kind of person is he? That's the
main question.
Okay, let's see. Since the browser
composed that the Arc browser was no
longer going to receive new features,
Zen has been considered major
alternative. Okay. So, okay. So the ark
So arc died. Apparently the ark died.
Okay. So you see arc is the other thing.
Um
so I you know so
anyway so yeah
um
major alternative and the continuation
in spirit. Okay. License under Mosilla.
Okay. Well, good luck. You know, I hope
it's doing great, but who knows?
Um,
okay. Bye, guys.
Okay. So, I need to So, I'm going to do
my plane curves offline.
Okay. Bye.
Now, if you guys like my stuff, donate.
Okay. Go to si.info.
Yeah. I, you know, let me just go
through this. So, you because this is
important. Uh, go to sardi.info. Okay.
Just go to atxi.info
my website. Then you go down, go down,
go down, go down, go down, down, down,
down,
down, down, down, down, down. And you
can see PayPal there is so send me $100
if you have a job. Okay. Patreon,
PayPal, Amazon gift card.
Bye.