good morning everyone
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
sound talk show today's 2011
2021 july
28th it's 11 o'clock in the morning
san francisco time and today we are
going to do a bunch of
uh we are going to do mostly i'm going
to talk about keyboards
and emac this coding and wufam language
coding
okay now there's a question celtic
orthodox since you have not indicated a
topic
i suggest lily pond or emacs [ __ ]
okay lily pond i haven't used ddpond
is a emax um uh emax package
for doing uh musics
lilly pond okay uh i haven't used that
i'm
not sure it's good okay it seems good
okay lily part music notation for
everyone
lady pound is a music engraving program
engraving you know they have to use that
word
engraving program i'm not sure it's
proper
you don't you know i i don't think you
engrave
music notation possibly in music
community that said that
but i'm not sure okay so it's a music
notation program devoted to producing
the highest quality sheet music
possible it brings the aesthetics of
traditional
engraved music to computer printouts
lily pound is a free software and b
and part of the gnu project okay so
music engraving software that's uh
that's interesting but
how does it work okay lily pound is a
powerful and flexible tool for engraving
tasks of all kinds
okay now it's all kinds for example
classical music
like the example above or complex
notation or early music
okay let's see what they are early music
modern music
tablature tablature welcome vocal music
lead sheets educational materials
large orchestral projects customizing
outputs or even schenker graphs okay
let's see what they are
what are you talking okay so this is a
complex notation
okay so it looks like these all these
are
the same page with the pound sign uh
jump points okay so let's see what they
are
and about uh [ __ ] i talked about [ __ ]
is sup cox emax cox sucks i talked about
in
recently uh you shouldn't use that i'll
give you an alternative
to [ __ ] okay so let's so
in today's uh so
let's post today's topic you know we
talked about
uh and okay so let's finish
talking about lily pond first okay so
let me see diddy pond okay
magnify magnify if you are here
say hi okay raw account five people
watching okay so
so let's see okay lady part uh lily
pound beautiful examples classical music
yeah
click to enlarge okay let's see okay
bach no this is use uh
your hand sebastian bark okay complex
notation
okay let's steal classical music
okay early music okay
modern music okay uh
mother music what is this what is this
contemporary
contemporary composers finally found
well suited to display
unusual notation here's an ex excerpt
from
trevor bajas curry for
unaccompanied bass
flute unaccompanied bass flute
i called bamboo okay so celtic orthodox
so what's your
i suppose you are a music musician and
i suppose you use lily pond or what i
mean what do you what's your question
like don't suggest me your topic ask
any questions you have do you have a
question
uh so really upon efficient flexible
creation of performance materials but
anyway so lily pond is just for doing
music notation
of many types okay not not any kind of
thing it's just
for music notation of any type lead
sheets so this is guitar by the way i
i got a guitar a friend gave me a guitar
now i have to show
you know i hated guitars i hated guitars
because the the shape and all that is
idiotic so i never played guitar before
but now i got a big guitar
beautiful sound
[Music]
no i don't know how to play i don't know
how to play econ at
all
so um but i do play piano and it's been
it's been 10 years you know the over the
my poverty
for for 24 for about 20 years i have not
played piano
but i love piano and recently
last month also i've been looking you
know in the 1990s i
i play piano i learned piano play played
some in practice uh mostly classical
scales and
and looked into synthesizers
so anyway little pond i don't know
anything about it i wonder how it works
though
how how so it's an emax package right so
celtic are you still here say something
okay questions comments say something
what
what what's what is your interest in
lily pond what do you want me to say
about it
you know so according to the you know
their website it seems
pretty good but you never know with this
open source
that you know when you try it you never
know but i heard
you know lady pound has is pretty old
it's more than 10 years old
okay i never tried it
i would be i probably would try it if i
was you know in the 1990s
because you know but now i'm getting old
so
i don't have time to uh you know
so close close close close close close
all that
because they are all just um
so let's he so here's wikipedia lily
pound is a computer program and file
format
file format okay for music engraving now
now let's look at look up music
engraving why do they use the word
engraving
music engraving is a is the art of
drawing music notation at high quality
for the purpose of mechanical
reproduction
the term music copying is almost
equivalent
though music engraving implies a higher
degree of skill and quality usually for
publication okay
so apparently uh okay the name of the
process of
the name of the process originates in
plate engraving a widely used
technique dating from the late 16th
century okay yeah so
i guess so the the the term
music engraving is historical
you know that so i suppose that
in the music printing business music
notation printing community
sometimes they still say music engraving
but it's you know it's uh it's just
music notation printing okay computer
engraving computer settings
you know so you know in a similar way
type setting you know type setting the
most idiotic
crap type setting you know you call it
type setting
although you you actually you don't set
things anymore you know
you have the typographic blocks you you
set them up
then you can print them so but that's
not what you do today
so uh yeah okay music engraving i talked
about typesetting many times
typesetting is one of the you know unix
phonetics linux you know
these hacker types idiots they love
typesetting
you know especially kerning those are
crap okay those are
uh time-wasting useless crap in fact i
would further go on to say
the western font the western printing
the concept of font is one of the
greatest waste of time
in humanity
okay so i need to show you some articles
okay i talked about this uh
for for for an hour or two uh in
my past videos a few times so
so i just want to point out uh one of my
articles on
font and
okay font size problem typography
sucks okay so this article so i
here's our talk show uh 2020
october 3rd white topography
sucks topography you know the those
those of you emacs users linux uh veeam
users
you you know typically these people love
typography they get excited they get
they piss in their pants when it comes
to font a new font you know
every few years some nerds created
new font oh this is the best font the
worst idiotic
uh time wasting crap possible
typography type not not just the not
just among the nuts
the concept of font and typography
in western society is a western society
thing okay typography
in chinese in you know you don't you
also have
calligraphy and well you do have
typography when you print something but
it's not
it's not the same thing you know it's
not it's rather uh
very different okay but anyway
the typography the world typography as
we know it in english
is a kind of a western tradition it's uh
not just a tradition it's a
establishment you know you have you have
photography is part of it then you have
the
uh foundry you know the the
houses usually basically elite
you know foundry uh uh
houses they make fonts you know they
create fonts
anyway so typography is a it's a
it's a waste of time okay it's no good
it's idiotic
you know so i you know when in my talk
show i
dramatize my words a little bit so it's
not exactly you know it's a
it's part of the culture so you can't
say it's a waste of time
just like dancing you know it's dancing
a waste of time
well in some sense yes you know you are
wasting your time you should spend it
down you know
go work make food and
make money make food or something but
you know
dancing is part of relaxation and you
know
and anyway so part of culture okay
typography is a western culture
but um but it has
so the way to say is that it has been
greatly exaggerated their
importance by typically
typically by not idiots and also you
know foundry and you know
donald knuth and steve jobs donald gruth
is the most idiotic
victim of typography he fell into it and
he created tech
one of the most the worst technology
possible for typesetting mathematics
i did a talk show about that you should
look up you you should
check it out okay because
you know because when i say you know
there's also article okay
uh
talked about this many times tech
pestilence why
tech la tech sucks they just you know
they suck
not just sucks but they suck donkey ass
in the most fundamental way okay
and uh so you should you know you should
um okay you should check this check out
this article
and also one of my talk show i talked
about that i did a lot of talk show
about that okay so but
okay i got a lot of things to say hold
on a second
so the tech pistons you should
read it and there's a talk show at the
bottom then
you go to xr code which is my home page
then the video here 2021
may 6th wufang language
type setting tech problems of
traditional math notation
syntax and proof systems they are all
related okay they are intimately all
these topics are
intimately related type setting
tech traditional math notation syntax
and proof systems okay because when you
do math
you know how so how are they related
so for example type setting right now if
you if you want you if you are a
mathematician okay
you know you should go so i'm saying go
watch this video okay i explained so
if you are doing type setting if you are
doing mathematics you need math notation
when you need math notation you need
type setting you type setting is used to
do it and also sometimes you can
use that you know you choose to use
latex or tech
so they are related and also syntax and
proof systems so what's the syntax
syntax is a related to notation
syntax and notation so what's the
difference so notation
notation is a way of
a particular way or system or style
and tradition again all related of
of writing of presenting certain you
know written material
so for example math mathematics so
that's a notation
but what's the syntax syntax is like a
notation but it's a more
systematic okay it's more it has a
grammar
it's most codified
grammar and syntax to you know the
grammar to go with it it's
so it's a system so you can so in short
syntax is
kind of a system for a notation okay
so and proof systems so when you do math
you so math notations you have to do
that
notations then tech latex or traditional
math notation then
then it relates to proof systems because
when you write math you
you know math you have to do proofs and
proofs
are heavily so what is proof systems
they they
they are you know they are logic they
are foundation of mathematics in the
field you know
the code the the name of the field is
logic okay mathematical logic
and when you do logic uh you don't just
verbally
talk about it you have to write it down
so logic constitutes a
you know there are so many branches
logic but mostly you write them down to
do
proofs okay so logic and when once you
write it down
you have to write in a systematic way
notation then
then then especially in the past 100
years it becomes
systematic so in fact it becomes a
computer language as you know
haskell uh [ __ ] co coq the french you
know the proof
assistant so-called proof assistant
systems so these are really anyway
so watch this video okay so
okay so let's click that so this is the
website for that so
let's post that and also let's go to
let me write down what we talked about
okay
this is a homework for homework for you
guys
to to to um to study okay so this video
i failed to have a link to my uh
to to my you know canonical
uh link so let me do that okay so
split the window open that show the pink
window the pink window shows all my
emacs command and keys okay
now search for youtube so here is the
youtube corresponding to there i want to
link to the canonical link on my website
for this youtube
so where is that that is in talk show so
go to
star talk show and you need to find the
date okay
so okay what that's a bookmark so search
for the date
uh here 2019
march 23rd okay search for it there it
is
so this one okay so open it so show in
browser
so that is the canonical uh url for
this exam talk show okay now click on
now go here paste it linkify
so the title is download group text
instruction set architecture
mathml mathematica act okay
so download fake instruction yeah so
there okay so now show in browser
go all the way to the bottom there it is
a link to the canonic canonical um
my page
so okay highlight there is a highlight
okay so anyway
so you can you know usually my talk show
is long i ramble over so this one is 90
minutes so
skip around so if you are watching my
video my youtube
um you
you know i i would appreciate if you
watch my videos some you
make comments okay not just online but
when you are offline you know make
comment to my youtube and also
uh one of the great things if you
highlight certain
time stamp and comment on it
yeah that will be appreciated also if
you watch youtube
if you uh you know go youtube watch
youtube
youtube in the past few months they they
have a new feature
they have a new feature which allows you
to show the transcript
let's let's see that okay uh
here okay you click on that open
transcript
okay so uh so you can actually copy the
entire transcript so if you are a busy
man
you know in modern society you have a b
you are a busy man you don't have time
to watch
a video you need one minute videos so
you can open transcript and copy it and
search and find what uh or just read the
transcript okay the transcript is
fantastic close that
okay now we talked about um tech
presidents close it
uh then what is this page start talk
show yeah so do i have a link
yes uh okay so i need to
uh copy that too paste that
here do that that that that
let me just edit it okay so you don't
know what i'm doing but i know what i'm
doing
so tech pistons that's the article
why tech sucks typography
then this video i talked about i give
you a video talk about these topics
then then this one is uh this is this
one is the most technical this is uh
wufam language
type setting i demonstrate type setting
um language why
it illustrates why tech and latex
sucks the donkey as the worst technology
the
you know wasting mathematicians time
okay so this video okay so i all linked
on my talk show page
so later on i'll update my website
you know you just you can find it
tv okay so this is today and
i'll be updating it to my website sync
it
okay so uh so talk show so we so so back
to lady pond we haven't finished that
so it looks like today we're just gonna
talk about this
uh yeah so also i want to show yeah so
this article
again there are there's another talk
show i talked about this uh
quite a few times uh type setting it
gets on to
my nerves
western obsession especially among the
hackers emacs
veeam you know the programmers they they
found
you know i have on my website i have
like over 10
over 20 articles about font oh
you know i despise typography and that
despise
the obsession with the font okay and
you know i have so i have a lot articles
and
um one one of the problem let me talk
about this okay one of the
major problem of font not this is not
really related to what we were talking
about why topography sucks but anyway
this issue font size problem is a
practical a a very big problem today on
you know for web dev uh the css you know
you know today we are using computer
funds right
so anyway it's a big problem it's a big
practical problem and it's not solved
it's
uh you know i i'm not sure it will be
solved
and uh and i have not seen you know in
my 20 years so you know
all the hacker news the reddit the slash
dot
the tech geekers they're talking about
language and so
on for 20 years i have not seen anyone
talking about this issue that i
i found but actually i did about two a
year ago
i did find someone finally
mentioned exactly the same problem i see
it's a big problem you know but it's
just that the
nerds they they don't it could
you know they don't think that that's
why the nerds they
they just follow fashion and facts they
hear what others say and they repeat it
like emacs is the greatest editor oh vim
vim's got new version
neo vim they talk about that all the
time every day day and night
the idiot hacker the hacker types and
programmer emacs
win people so francis problem what what
is problem let me let me
give me one minute summarize okay font
size so in css you can specify font size
right
in css you know uh uh i
by the way i have a tutorial on css okay
complete css from the ground up
okay so if you want to study css you
know
you can check out my tutorial so copy it
paste it to um here so we have a topic
of a record of what we talked about ooh
what's going on so
uh yeah star talk show so visual css
okay so
my css tutorial okay go check it out
now but we were talking about font size
problem okay font size problem
do i have a no i don't have a link so
let's
link it as a record of what we talked
about today
there it is font size problem so what is
the problem so we do
you know say webdav you use c you know
you specify font size by css
so so you say font size 48 pixels okay
and from family sign series and so on
and then
but the thing is the font size you
specify your size
but actually the the size you know it's
48 here it's also 48 here but
apparently you can see they are not the
same size what the [ __ ]
is going on what the [ __ ] so this means
you know you say you specify you know so
you say you will uh for example title or
whatever you say you want two for
you want the font size of 48 pixels okay
but then tomorrow you you think okay
maybe uh i prefer to have a
you know a serif font or something you
change your font
then your font size [ __ ] changes
because everything will become a
mess because they go they
you know they they go over the box or
something they they got
wrapped in their own place you know
that's a problem that's a big
problem this is a major idiocy of the
tech
web tech industry the hacker types you
know they're talking about
haskell lists every day oh we should
improve so this
is a better language haskell is a better
language and so
they never talk about this this is this
is actually far more
bigger problem the practical problem
these idiots
so fun size problem okay so so you might
be wondering so
let's look at this this picture
illustrate the
problem so you see the blues box
that's what mint that's what is meant by
font size so when you say font size
it is of a given font you know it
actually it has a blue box okay so this
two blue box
it's called uh what's the what's the
name
anyway the blue box okay it's a d this
is the the type
type of typography people call it a
design box or something
okay so that's the font size but then
inside that blue box
then you design your font okay so for
example these two font
now remember both of them are serif okay
it's not like oh one is sensitive once
one is every
serif therefore they are different no
both of them
any font okay both of them are exact
i mean you design your font
inside this blue box there is no like
there's no standard specified that your
bottom should
be at certain point and there's nothing
like that so
so what that does that mean in practice
that means
the font size you know thing is like
meaningless a meaningless [ __ ] this is
in css
okay the fact that whoever you know the
who who created css
the person who created css is
a in my opinion is a [ __ ] he is the
same guy
who invented the opera
browser okay opera browser in the 1990s
it's one of the best one
but white but i don't you know i i think
i don't like him because
he is a heavy microsoft
hater okay he's a scandinavian okay he's
a heavy
microsoft hater so he blather
you know third you know fear
uncertainty uh
you know they he blathered lies okay
fake news about microsoft all the time
like he's a
major hater of microsoft but anyway he
he created opera the browser which
eventually become bavardi
i'm using you know 20 years history
bavaria okay
this is a browser this is variety so
he's a hater of
microsoft and he you know and i have
article on that okay
like uh um
like every like like um so opera sucks
okay uh restore last session in in
ie firefox safari chrome opera okay
how to disable javascript no those are
old articles those are you know
irrelevant today because technology
changed the browser
they changed their settings and you know
but anyway so
so what is this one opera browser can
load twitter css
oscp error okay i don't even remember
what is that one
uh so this is 2013 uh i don't know i
don't remember
what's that but anyway this so this one
is
2010 why opera browser sucks okay this
is 2010.
opera began in the 1990s 1990s
around 2000 and back then it was one of
the best
uh browser but it's always always weird
okay so
digressions okay but let me copy it so
um so paste it here and what's the other
article i don't remember this one
okay so upper browser so so
i have a article okay so i detail so i
detail wipe
opera browser sucks now remember this is
in 2010 opera just
since 2010 about it just degraded and
degraded and degraded and got sold i
think it's got so
to just to channels or something then
then it
you know because it cannot make money
you know this open source [ __ ] you
know this
opera the boss of opera you know he's
trying to
he hates microsoft but then he floated
anyway so he so so the um
so so 2010
i detail why opera sucks in 2010
okay then oh yeah so eventually uh three
five four years ago opera switched to
the
google chrome's browser engine
called blink i talked about this in in
my recent
recent videos like last month or so for
one hour about browsers
so anyway opera pin okay uh
okay our product does not support size
scroll by scroll wheel
okay and so on uh
microsoft hating okay so here is a
passage i want to mention
i think um
yeah so this guy
anyway this old article okay so there's
uh
anyway it's the old article so why opera
browser sucks
okay so let's see what's okay
so show my talk show so a log of what we
what topics we talked about close that
uh
we ignore that you know that close that
back
font size problem yeah this is a
this is a good one okay remember this
one now i do remember a year or two ago
someone else
actually talked about this issue uh and
uh
do i have a link no um
you know so it's this is a big issue and
it's not
likely to be fixed anytime soon
you know it's just been that way okay
yeah back to what i was saying so
opera the opera guy you know
what whatever he's his name he he
created
he he us he is essentially the inventor
of css
you know this is back in back in year
people are proposing to the w3c
organization the you know web standard
to
to have a way to specify style so there
are
many proposals and eventually the css
cascading style sheet one okay
but it is not him okay this font size
problem it
is not him who created this problem i
would blame
who created this problem donald gluth
the idiot donald gluth created this
problem
no not now this is not to blame okay he
he he created the problems um indirectly
okay
so he's not really like he created the
problem but
indirectly because he failed to see
because because what happens is that
photography okay
i want to show you the wikipedia the
font the the
the um
the typeface and stuff okay not weak
wictionary
photographer wikipedia okay
photographer is a fun editor okay i
don't care about
uh digital fonts okay let's click on
digital
uh let's click on typeface
uh i want to go to uh type design
i want to go to typography okay
typographer then uh
type typology type topography okay
uh type settings okay so anyway here's a
picture i want to show you this so this
is where the concept of font originates
from
i mean there's something else before
this but this is uh one of the
you know so each one of this metal bar
a little piece of metal you
set it you know you you set them you you
know
each one is a letter you place them in
in this thing
so that's setting you know you set them
up
then then when it's when it's all good
then you can print it okay that's why
it's
type setting and each one of these is
called a type i guess
something like that so anyway so
you see this technology is very
different you know today we use
computers
you know there's a lot of changes you
know so but but
many of the concept that's relevant to
this
got passed over which became irrelevant
and one of the such issue is the font
size
okay the font size okay the but the
download gruth
this guy this you know i never liked
i i i i never liked you know donald
gruth is a great computer scientist but
i
turns out i never liked his writings i
don't like the things he did
i don't like his creations i don't like
his writings
i don't like his writing style okay
there are other they are good you know
there are many other
computer scientists and mathematicians i
do like
their writing style and so on i just i
don't like donald trump and it so
happens
among the eunuchs c c plus plus this
idiot
unix linux c c plus they they are
chanting down a group
every day typography idiots okay so font
size
so so where does this problem came from
well i you know i haven't i don't know
the history in detail but i'm
i'm pretty sure it came from you know
it's inherited from these
okay because the size back then you know
they they don't use pixels
they have pica and and p you know let me
let me show you okay so you go to css
you go to my css and there's a css unit
so font they use yeah so here's a
traditional unit for
for font typography okay point and
pica okay pt and pc
yeah a point is 172
uh a fraction of an inch and a peak car
is one-sixth of an inch anyway so those
sides what does those sides refer to i
suppose
they refer to the the the actual you
know
like like i talked about you know that
like the
they refer to some physical sites but
not not the actual
printed part so that's why today it's a
problem okay
so that's why we got this problem font
size problem
you know google you know google and all
these giant corporations get you know
they they are saying oh they are
creating new technology this and that
but did you know if you are really
trying to help
humanity fix this font size
[ __ ] problem this google or this
you know this standard organizations w3c
or the you know the what the [ __ ] group
anyway that's about typography okay
so another rant over typography
now let's get back to lily pond i guess
so we talked about font
music engraving okay so apparently it's
called music
music engraving so let's
okay so they call it music engraving
then lily pond so what i do what
do i want to uh know about lily pond
i don't know movable
type that's another you know that's
another old
um you know irrelevant concept movable
type
yeah so so movable type refers to that
so let's see
so movable type refers to
yeah so this is a seal it's kind of a
similar to the idea of a seal
okay so that's a history of movable type
from china okay ceo
which is which is just a stamp okay you
stamp things over
but okay so here it is this is a type
founding
that's the thing then this this is a
ligature
this is the [ __ ] obsession with the
western people obsession with the
ligature
idiotic idiots you know
like if you have fi like if you you
you know if you just have fi you know
these people
they got they got a problem in their
brain okay so this is
fi and the way when they see this they
say oh no
you cannot have that they need
they need to have let's see what what is
the
do i have yeah they need to have the
weight uh no that's
that's that's what that's a greek eye so
okay now i need to show you the new
local ligature okay
okay so i let's show it then since i'm
showing it
so you go to my unicode and search for
fi
then let's search for aiga okay so these
are ligatures this uh ligatures you are
seeing
so fi
you know another thing interesting is
that
you see ligature okay
yeah so for example this fi but you see
they are not
connected okay that's another
interesting thing
about uh unicode okay so
okay so in here it is okay so you see
this is a ligature this is
fi so when these nodes the typography
idiots when they see
this fi they say oh no you cannot have
that
we need to have you know they need to be
closer
then you got you you got this
you got then you got this um
um
how do you what's the word
anyway you got this ugly crap but to
them this is the better way okay
anyway so this is the concept of
ligature okay
so actually um let's copy it let's go
back to talk show close that let me
paste it
okay let me do some emax magic so you
can see
so let's magnify so let's put it here so
i press a key so this you see this is
one character
i press a key and it becomes marked up
with a unicode
mark okay so so so let me type
l-i-g-h-t-u-r-e okay so this is one
the most common example of a ligature if
i so show in browser
so go down magnify so you can see
here okay it you know over here it's
it's showing two distinct letters that's
not how it's supposed to be it should be
it you know it should be um what
it should be like that yeah uh what
you know it should be like that wait why
is that
oh yeah okay so it should be like that
now let me talk about another thing
that's very interesting so
so this is the unicode ligature okay
let's go back to the unicode search okay
let me also copy that and put it here so
we have a
history of our topic of talk we talked
about okay
so ligature so you see
this this is a unicode ligature okay
let's magnify
so this character is actually one single
character in unicode okay so
if you go down here you can see
uh where is it
there okay so this character is actually
one single character
you know with chord point code point six
c
you know six four two five seven or in
hexadecimal fb
zero okay that's one single character
unicode character
and the name of the character is latin
small ligature
f i okay but however notice
why what the [ __ ] why is it not
connected that's a point that's a whole
point of ligature
why is it not connected it's is that a
bug
who who who designed this fund you know
they must
be an idiot right
what the [ __ ] it's a literature but it's
not showing us a literature what's going
on
well it turns out when you study you
know i'm into these things i study this
in detail so it turns out the unicode
literature
okay this character do the unicode you
know organization
they say that this the font for this
needs not
necessarily be actual a literature
but rather they provide these characters
so that
so that so that it's more compatible you
know for transcoding for you know
for trans transcoding you know character
sets
from one to no on a another and so on so
they can
so for certain other reasons they they
have this character
but unicor says the actual font for this
character
needs not to actually be ligatures okay
so you have lots of complexities
okay so for some font it will show as a
ligature but
for other fonts for example the one i'm
using i believe it's area okay so for
example you can see
developer tools inspect uh
so we are using vavaldi does yeah so
it's
area okay so the the the
the what's going on yeah so here
is the so this the font of this
is actually ariel it doesn't use
um so unicode says that's that's good
that's good you know that's not a bug
because unicode does not require you
know the font to be
located so that's you know so that's
more complication so
this is another you know why
software industry is extremely complex
okay so i want to show you xr code
so this is part of the complexity and
tedium of software engineering you know
you work every day
you work at google you go there code
every day
for eight hours a day or something but
actually most of you know
in practice usually you code an hour a
day the rest of the time you spend
talking
uh you know me meeting and stuff
but anyway so you know this literature
thing is another complexity and
tedium of software engineering you spend
all your day doing this and
oh god this doesn't work why is it not
showing that
you know this crashed or what's going on
with the unix
shell bash you know incomprehensible
complexity [ __ ]
okay that's that's a giant digression
to another event about type type setting
okay
so close that so it all start from lily
pawn
okay the book you know donald knuth uh
you know one you know one of the
greatest computer scientists you know he
wrote the book
the art of computer science i i
you know i that's a good book i suppose
but it's not really
my style okay but it's a it's a great
book
uh you know i read it in 1992
i tried to read it in 1992 the the
volume one
i don't understand it because
now i know why well yeah so now it's
30 years you know it's like my life is
over so you look at that you look at
you look back at your youth and you know
when you are young you have lots of
questions in life and
in technology you know you have lots of
in mathematics you know i had
but but usually when you um become old
you
know what's going on so back then i read
it you know because
well donald ruth you know his book the
you know
volume one is he's he's um using
assembly language okay he's
he's using a assembly language
to illustrate algorithm
you know who to to teach algorithms okay
many uh issues and concepts in
algorithms
the art of uh no the the book is the
the book is called the other programming
not the art of computer science
okay i i guess that's what you mean okay
the other programming
uh you know the
okay so and you know i guess all of you
know
know this book by now i mean you i don't
have to show it
so here is his website donald grunts
website this is
website 1999 style
[Laughter]
i'm not sure he even uses css let's have
a look
control u okay and
you know okay so html4 yeah he's
you know he's you know html5 what the
[ __ ] is html5 what the [ __ ] is all that
stuff
it's html4 so this
is this is website you know yeah very
simple you can
you see this is a classic website web
web
source you know you web dev today you
javascript idiots
this is classic you know you can
actually understand
everything in the source code of html
you know
here's the list item you know here's a
paragraph
p very uh uh very
um readable okay readable
h3 you know header three are supposed to
today's javascript look look let's look
at lidi pond source code
okay the led princess code is still good
okay these are the
new nerds okay but if you look at you
know
any of the twitter or google search or
any
basically any uh new york times cncn
this fake news
any website you look at their source
code they're [ __ ] incomprehensible
like job jumbled up you know it's a mess
is a javascript you know technology uh
react
react.js [ __ ]
so anyway gnu's website okay so it's
interesting
so glenu's website so so yeah so his
book you know he he
he he tries to teach the art of
uh computer programming he tries to
teach algorithm or
related concepts by using a assembly
language
okay which is uh is yeah assembly
yeah which is the base almost the lowest
level of programming language for the
actual machine the cpu
and the assembly language he uses
is actually a artificial one okay so he
created
it called mmix okay
so mma x homepage jmaxx
news page mma mma mmi
x wikipedia okay let's go to wikipedia
so yeah he's got this uh you know
classic uh how do you say classic logo
mmm ix okay so here is the wikipedia
page you can see
now you know the logo is not bad but
yeah oh god
bitmap somebody updated to
svg please you know donald trump is
getting old he's like 80 years old or 90
or something okay
he's you know he's pretty old now i met
i actually
saw him about five years ago
at computer science museum you know just
down here
uh 30 minutes walk from where i am
it's nearby you know google headquarters
and computer science museum
and my home is all like nearby 30
minutes
walk so i met you know five years ago so
it's very old you can also
watch him on youtube you know he doesn't
i don't think
anyway he's got old videos and uh
and you know so he uses the mix
you know so let's read it okay mmix
mix is a 64-bit reduced instruction set
computing architecture designed by
donald knuth
with significant contributions by john
l hennessey who contributed to the
design of the mips
architecture okay so these are related
to hardware you know in recent years i
spent some time to study computer
hardware
because before that i don't i don't know
anything about computer hardware
i don't know anything about cpu gpu how
exactly they work
but in the past five years i started to
read um some so i have some under
understanding so i'm more into
mathematics
high level mathematics you know so i
don't know
you know this uh cpu hardware or
c c plus plus programming so i don't you
know
so anyway so he you know he he is using
this
assembly language okay and the reason is
that
he believes in order to actually teach
you
to for you to actually really understand
computer programming you need
to get down to the to the to the machine
okay that's what he's that's his reason
okay
yeah that's true but i i guess you know
in some way that's true
but on the other hand you know for
comparison
for example there's a six six
six book okay let me let me show you
[Music]
okay this book
now this book is also written by
reputed computer scientists they are
famous in this
community for his you know harold
eberson
gerard j sussman and julie sussman okay
they created i believe some of them
you know they basically they are the
founder of the scheme this
programming language in the 1970s also
so and this book is very popular very
famous
but very well um you know they
reviewed you know so these are also
computer scientists
but their book their book doesn't talk
nothing about the assembly language crap
okay so i'm giving you two different
perspectives
this book also by great computer science
they teach you
uh programming okay they don't they
don't they don't talk about assembly
they're low-level cpu crap
but gluth believes you know he in his
opinion
you know he he wanted the assembly of
assembly you know the machine called
assembly language
perspective because he believed that way
you actually learn better or something
so you know i so what i'm trying to say
is that
it is not absolutely true that to teach
you know this computer programming or
you have to know assembly that's
you know that's just not true uh there
are
pros and cons in either you know uh way
okay so that's why so back in 1990s i
i tried to read the you know volume one
because this is the best book everyone
says you know i
i i read a lot review of books
so you know before i read the book i
have to spend
days reviewing you know which in this
field what you
are considered the best books you know
so i know about
the other computer programming i know
about mathematica for the same reason
you know if i want a math software which
one is the best what people say you know
you you do research for days
okay so that i bought mathematica in
back in 1993.
so anyway so i tried to read it i don't
get it
but i know now i know why because they
you know they
you have to understand assembly and you
in order to understand that you unders
you have to understand basically you
have to have the whole picture
about how computer works you have to
first of all you have you need to have a
machine
it may be a cpu maybe abacus or or maybe
your fingers okay those are also
machines okay computers your fingers are
your hands is a computer
okay for example one plus one you do it
the algorithm
is like that then you count one two
one plus one equals two okay so
you have first of all you have to have a
machine then you have kind of uh
instruction set that that that
that says what what can be done to the
machine you know how do you operate the
machine
instruction set okay so raise one raise
the
right hand index index finger is that's
the instruction set
okay lower the right hand index finger
that's another instruction set
so you have like 20 instructions set for
your
fingers machine so you have an
instruction set
then from instruction set basically
the instruction set forms the assembly
language
so you can have a writing system to
describe
how to raise one finger or how to lower
one finger so
you start to have a notation system like
we talked about
with syntax so that becomes the assembly
language for your fingers machine
you know so so so you can actually write
code
to to to do finger calculation okay
that's assembly language so
gunus says that you have to so you have
to understand this
so gnu invented one mm-ix you know
that's the
assembly language for a machine for a
for a virtual machine you know
so once you understand so once you have
assembly language then
then you can have higher level
programming language which is kind of a
wrapper to the assembly language it
translates through assembly language
or translates to the instruction set
so higher level algorithms then you
start to have you know
programming languages different
programming languages uh then
then what does the source code mean so
scope mean just means as particular
written
um it's you know a specific written
instruction
set to to do something that's a source
code
and what's a programming language
programming language is a particular set
of keywords that
you know that ultimately translates
through assembly language
okay so once you oh so i start
you know i did for 20 years i didn't get
this until
like you know 10 years ago so once you
know this
the whole picture then well if you
okay so then you can you you would
understand this
uh you know growth way of thinking you
know
his perspective very well so you you
have to
you you have to have the whole thing
of course but of course like i said this
is not the only way
okay you don't you know for example you
can deal you can talk about
uh lambda calculus or you can talk about
tuning machine or you can talk about
uh combinators all these are foundations
all these are kind of abstract machines
you know
and these when you talk about this you
can you can build the entire computer
science
on lambda calculus or on combinators
or on tuning machine okay you can talk
about the entire computer science
on this without without you know the
mmix or the assembly line or cpu you
know the
the actual intel or whatever cpu
okay that's a background
about nuth so i don't i don't really
like the gnu's
inventions and style okay uh
i suppose today i can read this book but
i'm i'm too old i need to study math
you know other than this i already know
how to program
pretty well and also his book his his
book
today is less and less useful because
his book is talk about he's talking
about fundamental algorithms
okay fundamental algorithms that is
you don't need them okay you don't need
to understand them because every
99.19 19 you know
one in a million programmers do not need
to understand
any of these you maybe you are a web
programmer maybe you write drivers
maybe you are a linux kernel
well maybe not linux not but you know
vast majority of programmers you
don't need to know much about algorithms
at all because it's already
written in python libraries in
javascript you know it's already in c
libraries python called c c has
libraries okay so you don't
most of the time that's much you know
one year medium you don't want it
you don't need you don't need it when do
you need it
when you actually when you are linus
you know who created when you are
writing a operating system
yourself then then you need glute
book because you cannot just when you
are writing an operating system you are
you cannot just oh
let's call a python library oh let's
call wufang language
so that's you know so so it's very
fundamental okay this out of computer
programming
so so we talked about
70 minutes already okay okay so we
didn't do anything we
i wanted to talk about and we haven't
talked about
um uh emacs [ __ ]
yet uh but maybe that's it for today
so what are you guys saying anything
oh we have now i have 12 people watching
12 concurrent viewers so
so celtic is a violent
violinist okay uh bar says
okay prayer do you just turn around
you're violent
uh code bamboo what are your thoughts on
vim and its input mods
veeam's extensibility what a strange
question have you ever watched my videos
i mean i i got soft fly keys which is a
model mod just like veeam
okay uh chaotix says concerning the
idiocy of tech
do you feel the same about trove golf
yeah or are these program programs
utilitarian useful
i don't really actually know trophy and
growth you know those are the
kind of the type setting the uh
documentation technology
of unix in the 1970s
you know that's where unix man page uh
came from you know you write unix man
page in trough
and or graph then
you say compile or format or whatever
then you come out the man page
then you can use a man something to read
it
okay that's unix man page so i actually
never used it
trough and you know i never used it i
never uh
studied it so they are pretty much dead
technology you know trophy and growth so
i don't know much about it
uh but i wouldn't say so but
i would not i do not blame trough and
growth
as i'm as much as as i would blame
tech techies actually i consider tech is
like a crime
because trophy and growth is just the
tool okay it's
you know every 10 years you gotta have
to have some tools they
are not perfect but they have to solve
some problems you know
printing man pages you know both you
know part of the world you want to be
bold and so on so trophy and growth
1970s but tech tech and later
is kind of a crime tech and la tech
because they
you know they are meant to they are
meant to do a mathematical type setting
but the way the way group went about it
is completely wrong he you know he
so let me explain this in essence okay
type setting
so type setting is about
mathematics right well mostly that's a
group
intention original in intention he
created it
to do typesetting for his you know the
the art of computer programming so
math notations that's what you want you
want the technology
stop this you want the technology to
print
math notations okay
i talked about this you know like check
out one of my video where i talked about
wufang language
type setting the way gnu did it is that
he
approached the problem from
the traditional typesetting perspective
so
you know what is traditional type
setting that's that
you know he came he came to the problem
you know of of doing math notations in
with computers by
by by kind of following the steps of the
traditional type settings so basically
he
what he did is that he converted this
technology into computers
this this you know this
that's a that's that's a very bad way
you know that's
he just went the wrong way okay so
the result so what is the result what's
the problem the problem is this okay
you look look at this incomprehensible
[ __ ]
look at this one okay so for example we
want to do the sum for the first
one sum n from 1 to k
sum 1 over n okay just this okay so the
way you write it in tech is this
backslash sum underscore
braces and equals one bracelet you know
and frack
backslash frack frack your ass
that you know so he created you know
that's what he did
gnuth this is tech on the other hand
look
at this notation okay i talked about
this i i demonstrated in this in
mathematica in my video
so on the other hand in language this is
all you do okay
this is how you write very easy to
understand and readable
you know sun sum 1 over n and
from 1 to k greater than
integrate 1 over x
1 and k plus one that means from one to
k
plus one you know
like that you know very readable
and ascii you know no no backslash and
slash the crap
the idiocy of the growth and the idiocy
of the linux unix
these hacker types this unix philosophy
dribbling open source facts
let me just quickly type out the sum so
you know i did the video
you know so you should check out that
like like i
mentioned before so first of all magnify
so you can see so let's type three
start the kernel and the sum
okay some one over x
so so so uh
sum well x
x from 1 to 10 let's say
okay so that's that so what if 2
infinity
okay so that's that now if you
want format this in the tab set notation
you just press one single key you see
and if you want to format it in a
traditional notation
just press oh press one okay
what press ctrl shift
t for traditional notation okay you see
you see the difference let me copy okay
so first of all let's make it into input
mod okay
so wait yeah so let's copy
okay so three different ways
one is the input form
okay just like that then we have the
standard form it types it like that
then we have the traditional form it
types it like that
you know how simple how easy how
comprehensible is this
syntax why the [ __ ] why did someone the
[ __ ]
a smart guy tell tells
us to write backslash some underscore
this crap
this this is the harm
of typesetting because the thinking the
brain
when he you know when someone invented
the brain came from the typesetting
realm that's that's what you got that's
what you got
i mean i i live where google is at
google
okay google headquarters
have you found practical use case of
your own work that utilize ufam of
course
that's you know yeah yeah of course i
talked about this many times
you know my project since 1990s you know
the most popular
uh math website online
you know a visual dictionary of special
playing curves okay all these are
written in mathematica
in the 1990s and this is the most
one of the top let's say top 20 most
popular
math website on the internet
from 1997 to
19 to 2007 so for 10 years
this all these are written in
mathematica is you know
the most kind of educational there are
other universities
math department linked to it so you you
know you study
you know you teach math calculus you
know you you study
so though these are done in mathematica
analytic analytic mind says i use linux
vim
latex electrophography and ligatures so
i guess i'm not the target audience for
this
i know i know most my audio well
most my audience are like that that's
because that's my community
but i i i'm trying to say what i'm
trying to say is that
do you find my opinion reasonable at all
because you know i'm not like here for
trolling i'm not like
you know most of these people you say oh
it's just running no
what the [ __ ] is the troll i'm talking
that's this is my opinion i believe it
to be true
and the way i see it that the unix linux
kind of starting with unix philosophy
okay that's a code
meaning that many things they believe is
just untrue
sometimes blatantly untrue okay this is
what i believe
this is my honest honest opinion so
so i and i give you reasons i i i just
spent one hour to explain
you know the type setting why this sucks
you know in detail reason
do you think so so do you think do i
make sense
okay that's all i am asking do i make
sense
if you think i make sense maybe you'll
change your mind maybe then you start to
you know oh you know you think about
things
maybe you use your you know not to
be a fanatic about tech or linux anymore
maybe
that would be great because i you know i
would be feel happy because i
i like i persuaded you you know of my
honest opinion
so yeah that's that's that's all i'm
saying so so
you know so so to me so it's a coat you
know it's a it's
you know it's a and it's not like
that's that's why it's a code it does is
it's you know it believes many things
that's
patently false but however it
persists persists now over for like 30
years
you know also linux you know the unix
philosophy you don't hear much
about it today anymore you know most
young people they
probably don't know much you know they
haven't heard of it
except maybe you guys you know we still
have few people but it's
kind of already dying uh and we have new
generation malaysian
chin and that's another different things
okay that's
okay that's it for today uh i'm not
going to talk about
gnu emacs [ __ ] because that's uh i guess
that's it for today
any more questions uh because yeah so i
think that's it
uh 90 i talked for 90 minutes
oh yeah so about so you bought the book
you know the art of computer programming
you you you bought it a couple days ago
and and you are struggling are you young
you know i you know you just
persist okay i think it's a great book
uh just persist uh and also one tip
i can give i think is that when you read
mathematics or or programming stuff
especially math when there are some
parts you don't understand just skip it
okay that's actually a very good
practical advice when you read some part
of math you don't understand just skip
it
eventually you'll come back you know
when you need it or when you
when you really feel you want to
understand it you'll see
it will automatically sit in your head
after a few days
or months you know or even years
you'll come back and you're sometimes
you'll understand you know so
so that's that
okay there's a question about um well
yeah so you see that's a kind of what do
you say a vicious loop
okay so yeah this is also a reason i
despise
tech latex and unix so much in linux why
because they are free
you know what you know these people this
this cult
people sometimes they say oh
tech tech la tech is used everywhere
look
academia look the american association
of mathematics you know they
they say look why because tech is really
the best technology
okay that's sometimes they say that and
sometimes then they they will
say oh tecla teddy is the best because
it's free meaning it's
open open source okay it's like a free
software foundation it's a
principle of ethics then sometimes
they'll say um
then some then sometimes they'll say oh
you should use tekken la tech because
it's free meaning it doesn't cost you
anything you can just download it right
away you don't have to pay
so three reasons okay tech
is successful or linux you know you you
can interchange
tech or linux okay there are great
fantastic used by google
you know used by servers look the
industrial servers they don't need
linux you know so they
one one way they say is that it's that
because the tech
is superior technology that's one reason
sometimes the other reason is you should
use linux
or tech because they are
uh they are ethical you know they are
the open source they are the free
software foundation they are communism
they we should share we you know we
should not make money we should
something like that you know there's
details so that's a second reason you
know
free software foundation open source
ideology
the third reason sometimes they say oh
it's just free download it you know just
download it you don't have to pay woof
and research two thousand dollars of
them you know
download it and use right away
these three reasons they they conflict
with
each other they in you know they
conflict with each other
because
because just exactly which one is it so
you know because for example it's free
so for example for example let me just
give you an example if
linux or tech is not free you have to
pay
okay if you every time you use linux or
every time you
use tech or latex you download it you
have to pay
let's say let's say just ten dollars not
much just ten dollars
every time you download it i would say
linux and tech or whatever google
software they will die
within a year they are kind of just like
disappear completely within a year
so these people this open source they
live in
on a lie okay they know it too because
they they know it
if you actually require people to pay
they don't die so they mostly you know
the the reason most let me tell you
what's the reason
the most there are many reasons but the
most important reason
that tech and linux
they are kind of popular it's because
they are free
that means you don't have to pay that is
the most fundamental
reason not because they are all ethical
they are you know
they are following you know the ethical
software share or whatever open source
or because because the source is
available no that's not because that
the one most important fundamental
reason
for the whatever popularity the little
popularity of linux or tech you they
enjoy
it's because they are free in a sense
like
cigarette given to free to children
[Laughter]
drugs given to children you know that
that's that's that's the most
fundamental reason and and most of you
you know it too
you know but you but the you know they
living a lie okay
and also anyway that okay that's it
about that
um so yeah so why is it so so there's a
claim you know oh
yeah but um you know all the math
organizations they accept
tech they don't accept mathematica why
is that well because
they are organizations they too they
want money
you know they don't want you know they
don't want
to pay someone you know they they um
how do i say this um
anyway that's it for today okay that's
it for today
bye guys
bye guys bye guys bye my tutorial okay
you feel like
my thing okay i was going to generate
this i was going to do this in
language today but i guess that's it for
today
uh so if i like if you like my my thing
you know
patreon me amazon gift card me
paypal or you can buy
you can buy my emacs tutorial
emacs and emac this tutorial here
pay now or you can buy
my javascript tutorial javascript
in depth thank you