good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
today we are going to do emacs uh
emacs uh workflow and
i'm going to show you what i'm going to
do so this is my emacs blog
uh let's check video video check audio
check
good uh and okay so
hold on a second let me pop the chat out
so i can see okay so emacs
so we are going to do let's see let's go
to
stock show some talk show page for today
click on that and click on
topics showing browser so
i'm going to do
so there is this command
html rename source file path i'm going
to show you what that does
and i'm going to uh
show you what i'm going to do so copy
that copy that close it
on the pink window you can see all my
emacs commands and
keys okay paste it here showing browser
so html rename source file
path so let me show you what that
command does okay so go to emacs browser
so you can see
my emacs blog so open a new section
show in browser and i'm going to
go to diet directory then i'm going to
go to
a image directory so let's see emacs
logo and then
let's go to image directory so let's see
okay so let's see i i have this image
copy it copy the file path close it
close it
paste it here so that's a file path make
a link
yeah make a link shrink the window
showing browser so you can see i have a
file image embedded image
now when you if you write html manually
by hand
you often sometimes you want to change
the file name for example this file name
uh let's say you want to change the file
names because sometimes you want to file
name
appropriate you know particular
so let's say you want to change the file
name so normally what you do is you open
the file
go to diet so here is a file so magnify
so here's a file
then you call dire rename file
and let's say let's say
s something okay so now
commit now so you rename the file then
you copy the file path
close that close that shrink it show in
browser you see because you changed the
file so the file no longer works the
image embedded image so you have to
so here's a new file name the file path
so this is a new file name you
make a link again so you can see the
file name changed
then you delete the old name let's let's
let's just comment out for now okay then
showing browser
now it it's done so if you want to
rename a image file the file name it's
tedious
so now i have one single command that
lets you do it in a few key strokes
so let me show you okay so so right now
we have this file name
this is the new file name let's change
the file name back okay
so if you look at the pink window you
can see all all my keys and command
cores
i'm using stuff like keys and i'm using
voice keyboard
so okay so you call a command which is
two key press
size html rename source file path okay
then in the mini buffer you can see uh
okay it's too big so in in the mini
buffer you can see
it prompts prompts me to change the file
name so i delete that something
and i say okay so you see now it's done
now in in the mini buffer you can see
the old file path
and the new file path and also it also
updates the link for you
so now if you show in browser you see it
works
uh you see so now let's magnify you see
let's see uh yeah so let's uncomment uh
uh the last one so you see these two now
uh
basically identical except
except the old string here so anyway so
that's the command
that lets you change a image file path
um and also update
the html so that's a command
and this command also works for uh
links uh not you know not just html not
just
image files but also for for example
this one for example let's
show in browser let's open it showing
browser so this is a page about html dd
tag
this is another command i wrote
that lets you delete html tags
but let's say i you know i want to
change name i want to
uh let's say you know i want to change
the file name because
it's incorrect or something so let's say
instead of tag i say tag pairs
so i can just press a key and start to
type the new name
and press enter you see now it's updated
now if you show in browser go down
and click you see here goes to that file
now when you use this command remember
there may be other
pages that links to the same file it
does not go through all your files to
change them you just change
the current current tag so this is good
for
when you start to uh just for new images
or new files you just started to write
about so let's first of all let's change
this
name back because there are other uh
places on my website that links to the
file so okay
so now it's done go back to browser uh
wait go back to browser showing browser
so
there you have it so that is the command
html rename
source file path now what i'm going to
do next is
going to i'm going to create a new blog
entry
and containing the source code of that
command
okay so okay so that's that's the
workflow part
so that's what uh that's what you got
going to see
a real life emacs usage workflow
so first of all clean up that so
actually we don't need this image here
because i just i was trying to demo so
delete that delete
showing browser okay so now what's the
command
now now let's start to add a new entry
to my blog
about that command okay so that command
is the
so first of all add a new section
uh new block of entry and uh what's the
command name so describe
key i press the key for for the command
okay hold on a second describe key press
the key
so here is the documentation for that
command so this is uh
html you name source file path okay so
that is command that's what we need so
so now so that's a command i need to
create a file name so
what's the file name going to be so
let's see
that's gonna it's going to be emax html
rename source file path okay um
yeah okay so that's going to be the dot
html okay so i have a
another command it's our new page that
will
create a new html page with the file
path
and link all done for you so you see so
this is good
so now i need to make some minor pretty
files so
emax my according to my website
convention
so the first part is emacs html rename
source file path okay
and capitalize uh the first letter of
every word okay
so now make a paragraph block
and uh okay shrink the window
open the file show in browser okay
that's a new empty page that's good
now i need to okay so close that so this
is a function we need to add put in that
file copy it cut it open the open
here so so let's start to write the
block
this command lets you
easily rename a
embedded image
link file name
and also update the
link so that
you don't have to
rename the file
manually
and update the link
okay so something like that so this is a
draft draft
version okay showing browser yeah that's
like that
so this command so this is
so this is a command this command put it
here
and make it a code link so it shows up
as red
okay so now we have the command now
let's see the source code we need to put
the source code in this page so go down
go down uh emac list
template so you can see your source code
template
that's the pre tag so now we just uh
yeah we need the source code so let's
let's describe function uh
wait
describe function so now we can jump to
tab
to jump to the source code so here is
the source
source code so you can see uh it's about
50 lines okay
now before we uh let's compact the
code here so okay so so here's the code
we need to
uh and also my file my one of my
convention is that in the
docs string i want to put the url so
when whenever people read the docstring
they can go to my website
page and find it okay close it so the
copy the file path of the html reopen
that
source code file paste the file path
here
and it's shrink so paste paste the file
path here
and make it from change the file path
into a url so you can see it's a url
so now now emacs convention to put the
url is like that okay so
let's do that that that
okay so now the inline docs stream
contains the url that's what we want
okay so now copy the source code
copy now just go to open this html file
again
open it and go back to the
the pre section paste it here show in
browser
there we have it we have the code okay
something
okay yeah so we have the code now it
it shows up like that like a link
because
you know in your docs docs stream you
have some html code
that's not escaped so you need to press
a button
to syntax color the source code and take
care of all the
um entities html entities
so go back to browser go to the top
refresh
now it's good magnify magnify so you now
you see
now this is almost done okay so so now
we need to change
the file title remember i want to
capitalize the first letter of each um
each word you know a proper title so
okay
so again another convenient command that
will change both the title
and also the html h1 tag okay
so press the key so look at the mini
buffer okay
so do that okay and do that
enter showing browser fantastic
now this html also uh needs to be
the whole world needs to be capitalized
so let's do it call that command again
do it showing browser fantastic now it's
done
now there are more things to do uh so i
need to add a panel
so okay also also also this navigation
uh button back to emacs fun that's
incorrect
this should go to uh let me show you
where it should go to so
you go to emacs website
so you go to blog for example then you
go to for example this delete html
delete tag
so the back tool should be back to emacs
back to my emacs home page and also i
need to add this navigation panel
okay let's do that so
copy the url from the browser of this
file because we are going to paste the
navigation bar
in in the panel from here from these
files okay so
close that close that okay now we are
back in the emacs blog
split window open that file open this
file so first of all go to the
top navigation bar so this is the
navigation bar you see
that's the back to emacs okay so copy
that
now open that go to the top paste it
here so here's the new
and here's old so delete the old
and also we need the the navigation
panel okay so go back here
so search for panel so here
is the whole panel copy it close it
open that go to the bottom and
paste it here so we have the kind of the
navigation panel
on you know the big so show in browser
fantastic emacs html rename source file
path so this is a new entry for my blog
so people
emacs users they might find this command
useful
they search the web then they make they
might find it and they can put
this in their init file and they can use
it you can use it
and this file by the way this is part of
site html mod
okay so you can uh if you want to you
can use
you know html mod it's part of it
okay so there is that so close but it's
not done yet okay let me show you why
it's not done yet close that so
so uh open my emacs blog again
now if you look at this one you know uh
emacs so you you open that
emacs html dd tags so you can see
you have the navigation panel on the
left that's a generic navigation panel
you can go to emacs tutorial you can go
to emacs init tutorial you can go to
emacs keys
keybinding tutorial or you can start to
learn emac list
so and so on so that's a generic um
[Music]
panel so we can click on that emacs
tutorial emacs init tutorial
emacs keybinding tutorial let's turn on
the
uh javascript so you can see my videos i
did in the past
so you can go to emac this tutorial you
can go to emacs
examples lots of examples so if you are
uh if you are not familiar with emac
list you can learn it okay i
highly recommend it because knowing a
little bit
emac list will expand your um
uh your knowledge about using emacs uh
greatly so anyway so this is the generic
generic emacs uh navigation panel
let's now let's go to my blog again
so that's you can see
uh this page we've done this this is
good okay but
so on the left you have generic
navigation panel but
on the bottom of this page you have
another navigation
panel that's um
that's that's all the pages related to
this specific page about editing html so
you can see at the bottom
all these pages are related to
uh commands that work on html
html so i also need to add this
panel so let's do that so okay so open
this delete
html tags page and go to the bottom
and you can see here is the panel i need
to add so you can see there's a name
topic x topic
excel html so okay
okay so we're gonna copy that close that
then go to our rename source file
path page and go to uh here
above the add adds button
template paste it here showing browser
okay scroll down fantastic
you can see the the html specific
navigation panel
now there's one more thing to do now in
we need to add
this page we just created into the
uh topic specific navigation panel
okay now where because uh it's related
so where do we want to add it so let's
see
uh html rename source file path
html rename source file path so which
part
would that be related so all these are
about dealing with tags and all this
about dealing with links
and css and okay so it should
go to miscellaneous okay and where
should we put it
let's see replace hdmi entities update
title so
let's put it after update title
for now okay now as time goes on you
know
you know i work on my emacs
blog emacs true almost every day so
next time when i see so today is just a
draft
so it's you know tomorrow by tomorrow
next month i might come back to this
page and i see oh
uh it should be more relevant somewhere
else or some other fixer i'll do that
for now let's so let's add it after
update title okay
so
search for update title so here we want
to add it
uh after this uh tag after this
uh list element okay
so so first of all so so
what does this what do i have to do in
order to add that
so you see this topic box is repeated in
every one of these page
so for example i click on that then i
click on that
okay then go to the bottom then i click
the next one i go to the bottom
then i click the next one so you you see
this topic box is repeated everywhere
so essentially i need to i need to do a
find replace
of all such topic box a string
in all files in your directory
so that's what i'm going to do so this
is going to be a find
replace uh in you know if you use linux
unix you might know it as set
which is uh i have a better command okay
so first of all the text i want to find
replace is this whole thing topic box
okay try to do this in set you're gonna
run into problems because
there's a lot new lines okay so
copy that call the command supply and
replace text
and what text you want to replace okay
paste it
so the text i want to replace is this
whole
huge thing okay enter okay now what's
the
replace string you want to replace okay
the replace string is going to be let's
cancel it
so what's the replace string first of
all i need the file path for this
file okay so copy the file path paste it
here so you can see
then so you this is the file path and
make a link
make a list link so and
so now so we need to also so let's show
it here like that
okay so here we need to modify this
because we don't need to say emacs html
because it's repetitive
so rename source file path okay so we
don't need the
uh url tag neither so delete that so we
basically just add this
item okay cut shrink
showing browser i mean cut shrink okay
then
that's called star find replace again
okay something replace search string
okay
press up arrow to to the one we used
previously okay
that and what is what's a replay string
press up arrow
then go down go down
then you go down you can see
uh here see so we want to add it
your paste so you can see there is a new
item
okay that's a replace string enter so in
which directory this directory
and what's a file path regular
expression
that's dot html enter right changes to
file
yes fixed case in search yes
fixed casing replacement yes make back
backup yes
okay so it's going to do
to search you know a thousand files in
in my directory and
do this replacement so that's done so
let's go
let's magnify that string so you can now
you can so that's a result
you can use the left and arrow key to go
to all occurrences
and you see the pink lines are all the
files that changes
changed okay so that's that's done okay
shrink uh wait shrink close
okay now show showing browser again
showing browser
so let's see html rename source file
path
scroll down there it is
html source file path let's click on the
next one
markup function names okay now scroll
down
there it is rename source file path so
it
you know made the change to all the
directories so that's
it so now close that
go to the browser close it and what is
this one close it
go to the browser and open the
my emacs blog again so that there it is
okay
now the file name is still incorrect
because we made a change so now let me
show you another um
convenient command i want to copy so
i can you know just update the file name
here you know the
you know here or another way
is i want i can copy the file path
the copy the link path
which is here okay but i don't have to
go there and select it i can just
press a key all file links
in the current text block are copied
so you can see i go here paste it here
there it is that's a file path
then i call a command to make it a html
item again
now showing browser so you can see
you see this way is usually better
because
i don't have to manually change that i
just press a key it will automatically
link it
and auto automatically grab the title
whatever title
is on that page and put it here uh
and actually i don't want the list i
want a paragraph so make a link make a
paragraph
so go back here delete that showing
browser
there it is one more thing to do is that
i want to add to the atom
web feed rss
so so what we do is we move the cruiser
here to the link
press the key it's done okay you can you
can see
it added this new block of text a new
entry
atom uh web feed
in a file okay so close it save it
showing browser that's it now one more
thing i need to do is just to update to
uh sync to my website so press a key
go to uh powershell then up arrow
go to the uh the rsync history that's a
unix command so
okay so now it
so now it uploaded synced to my web
server so you can see all the files uh
that has been changed
so now if you go to xsa
emacs blog
click on that there it is
today's fruit click on that there it is
fantastic okay now that's not green
because we
have javascript off let's turn on
javascript
you see green means the current uh
file fantastic that's it that's that
that's the main thing for today let's
see what else if are there people here
there are
indeed people here seven people so
what um okay i can shut down now
or we can talk about something else so
if you have questions comments post it
now okay
uh let's talk about that uh i'm thinking
so what time is it 4 37 so i can talk
for another
uh 15 minutes
so we have uh people new people here
gribble gym
is the most based man in the universe
these statements cannot be refuted
true hey hey first time catching a
stream
thank you btx 5
bathroom you are not asleep yet it's
late for you thank you for joining
uh okay so
okay so any questions so
so i have 10 minutes free 10 minutes
let's see
what are we going to do
we haven't done a talk show for a while
you know
there are so many things to do in life
you know because
uh i guess because my personality
there's so many
fantastic tremendous things every day
i'm busy about
we need to do and about society about
human animals
uh like every day i'm on uh in a panic
mod that's my life story every day is
i'm in a panic mode
and let's have some coffee
so
okay break
so that's about emacs for today so let's
talk about something
uh something random i guess let me show
you what i've done
in the past you know uh two weeks
or so um okay so talk show let's go to
talk show
uh i need to my eye patch you know
so i have a bit close eye so you can
like
it's i think it's getting slightly worse
okay
so anyway go through my talk show yeah i
want i want to put my patch
so i can see better that way
i need to get new glasses
so go to cuz talk show today
rename so rename the file name
uh now it's gonna be xrtv uh wait
what's going on yeah press a key
uh xtvxr tv today's date
showing browser yes xr tv is shorter and
it's more memorable
star talk show although even star talk
show is more descriptive
but i think xrtv is a better
marketing term uh suits me better
because
you know my talk show is kind of weird
so saw tv's got the
panache so delete that we don't need
that
anymore so uh you know you see that we
don't need that
anymore so we talked about rename file
source code so
okay showing browser so we need to you
know change that into a link so again
this is emac workflow so go
let me do it fast okay close that close
that
i mean that that that that that that
okay there you have it now okay let me
show you
let's talk about random so let's uh
let's not waste your time
let's get on something interesting so i
talked about
there's some keyboard lists some
programming let's talk about some
keyboard because keyboard is always the
easy topic
okay so uh keyboard so there's a new
mouse this is a do-it-yourself mouse
proopy okay uh
proving mouse they came out with a new
version poopy mini trackball
i mean trackball not mouse so you can go
buy the kit or you can go they
also have a build pre-built uh version
uh and you know so
i think it's pretty good but it's pretty
expensive so if you want to buy a
pre-built
pre-built version it's gonna be 100
which is you know all things considered
it's
not that much better i wouldn't you know
big why because i mean it's not
all things considered 100 for this mouth
it's not that much better than one of
these commercial made
mouse you know these are commercial
grade mouse or
essentially all of them are under 100
50 you know
you know so because for a mouse uh what
do you get
for a do-it-yourself mouse well what you
get you know first of all it's kind of
you know this
uh material this 3d printed thing is
usually ugly
you know you got these uh usually ugly
and clunky you know it's not you know
it's not
smooth look at how smooth are these are
shiny
you know so what but what's the
advantage
uh with a do do-it-yourself mouth
the main advantage is programmability
okay because they are using the qmk
software
which i have article about uh somewhere
somewhere here qmk
uh not here software you know qmk
software is very powerful
but it's very uh geeky you you have to
spend an hour or two
to actually know how to use it so anyway
what i'm saying is that the advantage of
a do-it-yourself
mouse uh possibly two things
one is the dmk qmk you know
programmability because that software is
very powerful if you can program the
mouse keys uh
to almost anything okay but however
that's here's a problem however
you know a mouse is uh is unlike a
keyboard
a keyboard a programmability
for the keyboard is super incredibly
important because keyboard you know you
have modifier keys control
meta control alt shift you know and
function keys macro uh
you know or disable the window key you
know many of these
or even increase the volume up and down
the sound volume
all these are very useful macro uh
shortcuts and also shortcuts you know
if you use photoshop or browser for
example i showed this many times let me
let me show you my keyboard a little bit
okay
so let's see uh my keyboard okay so
just turn on so turn down you can see so
that's my kinesis
connected advantage 2
keyboard and this is the ultimate
hacking keyboard i showed many times
i also have full reviews on my website
if you like my stuff
go buy it okay go buy it on my amazon
links
okay so let me show you okay so that's
my that's about my keyboard let me show
let's talk about the
the let's talk about the trackball again
so trackball so yeah fantastic
powerful programmability but however on
a trackball
the programmability is not that useful
because on a trackball you only have one
two three three buttons
uh in this case three or four possibly
four with
counting the wheel and typically you
don't want to change the functionality
of those buttons
well you can if if you want to but then
you lost some functionality you you know
you only got four buttons
four or five so on the track and and
what you're gonna change for the
trackball the ball itself you know you
don't want to change it you know
maybe change some speed that's all you
know so
so for a trackball the
powerful programmability is not that
useful
okay so that's one thing so so even
though these two
it yourself trackable uh is great
programmability but you know down tribal
you're not gonna do
much with that that's one thing now the
sixth
second thing where do it yourself
trackable
advantage over over the counter you know
over the
these commercial ones is that
is that um is that um where is it
is that yeah the the how fast you can
score the ball
okay let me show you because because let
me show you okay
all these commercial ones you know
you they the ball you cannot spin it you
know
for example i showed you the spin wheel
okay
you see i showed you the spin wheel so
you can see
you know i the the wheel can spin for
like 20 seconds or 30 seconds
in the same way in the same way
it would be fantastic if you can have
that for the trackball you can just spin
the
trackball so let me show you article
that explained that
uh trackball spins okay both sides
trackball history trackball controller
uh tripol that can spin okay i
actually i need a video i need to show
i need i need a i need an icon here
because otherwise link
this link is not very obvious
so let me talk about the spin wheel
trackball swing so
it it would be ideal kind of okay
not necessarily but let me talk about
that later it would be it's a fantastic
first of all it's a fantastic idea to
have a trackball where the ball can just
spin
this one does talk about it so like the
ball spins very freely in any direction
you can spin it and rotate it which
trackballs can't do as
you see they push it just like the spin
wheel it can spin for 10 or 20 seconds
that's fantastic
and unfortunate so this this is a video
i don't know
where is it from from 2014
and uh i didn't see any update you know
i don't i
i didn't see any do it yourself
trackball that uses these
uh this prototype they are talking about
it
but it appears it appears that nothing
comes
out of it and there are several other
videos that talk about spin
spinning track balls you know some uses
air you know
magnetic or magnetic
uh uh levitation or some use
air pressure uh things like that some
use
for example these actually do spin uh
this trackball 150
or 200 hard to buy so anyway i have a
collection of videos that talks about
spinning trackballs how fast they can
spin how smooth they can spin
now that's much and for example this one
they this guy modified you know modified
the kensington
kensington uh this one is called expert
mouse they modified it so it actually
spins
they replace you know they they put in
the
they put they put in both ball bearings
on it
so so i have a collection of all these
track balls so
you can see some of the mechanisms here
so for example
they use a uh wheel
but anyway vast
you know basically essentially all these
they cannot spin
you know you try you doesn't matter how
hard you try they spin for
at most two seconds so
spinning trackball is a a fantastic idea
okay
so let come back to what i'm talking
about
so when you have a do it yourself
trackball
this is possible for example this guy
uh tribology do it just yourself travel
he
you know he is doing research he tried
all
different type of spinning of the
bearing
ball bearing mechanisms and you know
tell you which one is the most
smooth so you can read his blog blog
uh i'm not sure there's a product you
know i have to check their update
you know i'm not sure this update so
anyway so that
that's my point do it yourself
trackballs
have this potential possibility of a
actual spinning trackball
and here's another guy by a japanese uh
you know who created this trackball
uh use ball bearing use kind of the
spinning
um boss
so anyway that's my point so poopy so i
don't actually know i haven't looked
what is the mechanism of poopy i think
it's uh it's a bar
but i don't think it's that smooth i
don't think you can actually spin it
so anyway that's about the proofie okay
so what's uh what comments do you have
so yeah beatrix ask your questions okay
just ask your questions just shoot
so yeah so it looks like windows 11 is
coming up
yeah windows 11 actually i've been
reading you know so on our discord
uh we have you know people have been
talking about it let me turn on this
code okay but before
i do let me let me hide my video
okay i'm back so you know people we have
been
some people has been talking about
windows 11 and i actually tried to read
it
so it actually has a wikipedia entry
about windows 11 now
early even though it's not out yet so it
looks like there's some
um some some
some uh large user interface overhaul
you know windows you know you know i
i want to talk about you know one of
this video maybe my
next talk show i'm going to talk about
the user interface
uh yeah the whole video i'm going to
talk for one hour about user interface
okay let's okay that's that's it about
the trackball
uh let me digress and let's jump to the
topic of user interface
okay so uh wufam language fantastic
that's a technical programming language
design
uh technical writing and this is also
fantastic you should you know you guys
check out my blog okay and i got tons of
stuff
i need i i need to talk about i need to
tell you guys
so windows okay let's talk about windows
user interface design
so i have this collection of articles
which is about user interface design
now user interface design is one of my
obsession
actually even though i haven't written
much about it most
mostly mostly you know you've seen my
you know hundreds of articles about
programming language
design about syntax design
about um and also
keyboard design keyboard and trackball
design you know i study the technicality
of
the design issue issues you know user
interface and so on
so so design actually design is one of
the if
if you want to characterize sas writing
you know the whole life my whole life
what i have been done
my 6 000 articles uh manually
hand written in html since 23 years ago
if you want to characterize my um you
know
what are all the things i've done one of
you know one of the aspect is design
you know i'm obsessive about design
issues
uh design many aspects of design
computer computer language design
syntax design and user interface design
and
writing systems design okay which
includes all the unicode
okay okay i'm gonna
yeah you know unicode you know i showed
this a thousand times
uh you know you know i'm just
now i'm like all over the place okay
let's go back let's go back let me focus
one thing
user interface designs okay so on this
page i have a lot of huge collection of
articles i've written about on different
aspects of user interface design
so what i'm saying is that one of these
maybe next one okay i want to do a full
video a full one hour
star talk show on on these articles user
interface design
because you then you start to see the
extreme
idiocy of the industry you know the
program you know the industry the
programmers the union unix idiots
and the windows idiots mac mac
apple they are the best at design but
you know
no there's no debate about it apple
computers
i mean they have lots of other flaws but
apple
apple can computers apple
they are they are one of the best or the
best
at design of things okay especially user
interface the
the linux people are the most idiot
people and we have jonas
you know i am going to start to flame
jonas in the square
they root no idea what they're talking
about yeah
okay so back to design so this is a
connection about
user interface design and then
you'll see the edc let me show you one
of them okay
peeps your windows you'll see this
everywhere uh let me show you a real
life example let's go to twitter okay
so do i have twitter on so let's go to
twitter you know let's say i want to
post something i
opened a new you know a new tweet and
look at this
you know i you know my
screen is like
24 inch or something 30 inch you know
food you know
but now i'm forced into these two tiny
two
two inch screen that's twitter this
this this phenomena you see this
everywhere in every everywhere
in stack over you know so i have a
collection of
records show you the records you know
why
how they happen everywhere on twitter uh
microsoft windows everywhere
on uh on what is this twitter okay again
twitter you know
this private message
you know they you you know as time
progresses in the past 30 years
of my life you know we beginning 1991
okay i bought my first apple color
monitor
13 inches and the resolution is six
640 by 480 okay that's about
that's about this you know how big that
is
640 by 480 let me show you how big that
from 1991 okay
so 1991 when i bought my first
the best basically the best uh
monitor you know colormonda apple
13-inch monitor search for that you can
find it on wikipedia apple
rgb 13-inch monitor 1990
also for one thousand dollar one
thousand or two thousand one thousand i
think one thousand dollars
your whole screen size is uh 640 by 480.
you know actually i also have article on
that
um okay i have lots of digressions okay
so
let me show you okay yeah okay but let
me show you
anyway um digressions okay so let me
show you
let me find the article let me show you
and let's go back to
and this great text on white background
that's extreme
idiocy you know then then you have these
screws
you know the css design gurus telling
you what to do
and including those okay you know those
at google google says oh
oh oh you should design this way then
you have the skeleton screen
you know have you guys seen this you
must have you know starting this begin
this began about five um about two three
years ago
okay skeleton screen you go to a website
just
you know you load the page then you see
this okay a lot
huge uh anyway so that's about user
interface but let me digress a little
bit let me show you the
um let me show you uh
the uh the screen size okay we were
talking about screen size
so uh so
search for screen size comparison okay
so
uh there it is okay so here
here's a page screen size comparison dvd
you know dvd iphone ipad macbook blu-ray
so in 1991
the screen size is this big 640 by 480
vga screen
you know six you know that's resolution
but however it's a 13 inch screen
and basically this lasted uh almost the
entire 1990s until you know then then
then it be then dvd came out then then
cd came out in 1995 then dvd came out
and oh my god it's high resolution dvd
the net
you know the technology you know you
guys
dvd is there today but but that's
history you know that's what happens
when you get old
you know so to me i remember that they
did when dvd came out that's a new
technology like today
you guys are talking about oh windows 11
oh my god excited
you know apple mine chip and whatever
it'll pass you know after 10 years it's
like history
so anyway in in 1999 around 1999 dvd
came out
my god hot new technology 720 by 576
resolution
[Laughter]
then the owners are talking about you
know the you know the
the you know before it was interlaced
anyway that's getting technical
interlaced but now it's a
what's they called um it's not in
interlace any anymore but anyway dvd
came out then iphone
then iphone came out 980 by 640 then
ipad okay and by the way this page
was created in 2011 so this page was
created 10 years ago
so i was you know all this technology i
was like i want to have a
overview just just how much screen has
been increasing you know
so you know iphone ipad macbook air
the macbook pro then you know then then
xsga you know plus screen
and then uh 1600 by
1000 you know basically
but anyway this is 10 years ago today
you know
today is like even bigger so i haven't
been updating this page okay so
anyway there's also a wikipedia article
you can go read about it
so that's a screen resolution you know
so that's what i'm talking about that's
that's
you know i'm showing you this page
because my first monitor
okay let's go back to um
you can thank mobile for shitty design
um
part of the reason cannot be playing
everything on mobile mobile is a
significant
okay mobile you know mobile phone
i cell phone cell phone starting around
apple they changed
they have a tremendous impact on user
interface
on use interface across the computing
industry because iphone becomes the most
popular because today
most people don't have a computer they
have a phone well that's their computer
so there's a huge impact because you
know because then
the computer is no longer for nuts
before it's
generally for nuts for programmers then
for nuts then
every mom and pop have a phone basically
iphone
or android you know phone that's a
computer in their pocket
so phone made a tremendous impact and
change to user interface design
but however however the issue i'm
talking about all these issues
uh actually most of the issues i'm
talking about is not
due to the phone although phone has lots
of also created lots of problems
for example the responsive design crap
anyway i you know to talk about this i
need to get
into detail because uh so i have about
20 articles here
and each one you know some of them may
take
one hour to explain then you have the
dark themes you know
because i if i just say you know dark
theme sucks
then a lot of people don't know you know
they will disagree lots of you guys too
you know say oh my god because i say
dark thing sucks actually dark theme is
the best thing you know
so i need to get into detail then then
you can see
my point why it sucks
it's not you know it's not just blanket
it's not just it's not uh
in absolute sense that dark theme sucks
but however
lots of dark themes you guys are using
and microsoft dark theme sucks donkey
ass
it's the extreme idiocy okay microsoft
they don't know what they're doing
you know they uh anyway
so i have these articles so let me go
back let me get back to one thing okay
uh let me so i was talking about uh
the peep shoe uh pip show windows so you
see this everywhere okay
so let's see
let me show you so so you can see so so
let me show you an actual example so
let's go to windows
okay i need to go in five minutes so
uh so okay so let's show let's show um
so we are in windows now okay
i'm going to show you the one of the pip
show windows in windows the
extreme idiocy so i mean in my file
so you know i want to go to options so
you see i have a 13-inch screen
then it pops up this this this this
model pop-up window crap the text is too
small
i'm getting old i cannot see it you know
on windows you have the
font magnification because but doesn't
work here
so i cannot see it i have to get close
then you go here okay you go here
then you know then you got this
claustrophobic
claustrophobic this
you know this kind of thing is
everywhere on windows
the extreme idiocy you know
this is this is a crime okay
you know what let me show you so what
what is the significance you know you
guys are living in a lie and you don't
even know it okay
now so let me stand back and let let's
not be you know
be a nut job let me cover this let me
talk about this in
a uh in a way you can understand
you can appreciate now first of all
all these things i'm talking about it's
just user interface design
okay now i'm saying they are extremely
bad okay it's
not not not major it's not like not it's
not like oh a million people
dead okay i'm just saying they suck
very badly they they are extremely bad
but however
most people do not realize it i mean
including
especially the linux idiots you know the
especially the programmers the you know
the elite
hacker programmers who are telling us
what to do for example the python
priests
the python coders you know they tell you
uh you know python idioms or whatever
you know the css gurus the google google
microsoft
you know they tell you what's the best
user interface they are
they are live they don't know you know
so
okay let me retract okay so
but you guys don't know so including
lots of you guys you know this you know
you you code in c or whatever
like you don't like i almost never hear
a complaint like for example in this
case people show windows i've never
seen anyone else complain about this
but however to me even you know if you
believe what i said is true
if you agree with me this sucks this
sucks major you know this is
incredible this is a this
this is the worst design this is the
most obvious design
idiocy and yet nobody nobody sees it
you know you go to hacker news or these
tech geekers you know nurse elite
idiots they talk about programming or
things about user interface
they talk about font for example a lot
of you will talk about font
and kerning you know idiocy you know
you're driving about
a new font this is fantastic okay
fine but however i have personally i
have never seen
one guy that talked about this
patent idiocy of the user interf phase
design pipshot windows
i've never i've never seen anyone talk
about it
about it on the hacker news one million
articles every day
never so what's what what is going on
what is going on in our society
when you when you have this user
interface that sucks extremely
but meanwhile nobody talk about it while
other elite hackers and user interface
design
idiots they talk about uh font you know
they talk about lots of other things but
they never addressed
you know one once this this
this one you know this one of the issue
this people should
what word are we living in so
so this makes me angry okay angry in in
the in the sense of this context okay
you know did i think that go this that's
that's why you know that's why in my in
my
talk show you hear me talking about
these idiots idiot you you
guys this idiot that idiot that that's
true
you guys are idiots and also you know
since you know
and a lot of you guys are emacs users
right emacs users you talk about oh
which one is better which way it's
better which one is efficient
but among emacs users i've never seen in
my
in my 20 years you know wallowing in the
imax community i've never seen people
complain
about this pipshow windows situation
incredible so that's that is my point in
in in you know in in lots of my writings
you know why am i
getting angry about calling people idiot
you know so
so i want to know how do you feel about
it what
you know what i said is that true am i
just like
am i the only person saying this do you
guys not see this
is it not true that you see this
everywhere in windows
not just windows okay now some of you i
know the linux phonetics will you
your reaction will be oh my god no
that's
size right windows is stupid this
doesn't happen in
linux no it happens okay let me show you
let me show you the stack overflow
from you guys idiots from you hacker
idiots
stack overflow so you go to snap so
here's a screenshot of stack stack
overflow
you you'll see this design uh you know
we can actually go there
you know actually i don't have time i
gotta go so you'll see this comment okay
when stack overflow you go to stack
overflow
you know when they post source code and
if the line is too long
then they use this interface where you
need to scroll
this little scroll box to see the left
and right side of it
extreme idiocy i don't know what the the
guys i think what
what the what is their brain used
for this you know
stack overflow is not a one-man site
it's a
corporation it's a billion dollar
corporation it's not owned by
who owns it did they get sold i don't
know i forgot i don't
anyways but it's a it's a big
corporation you know one of the
at least very popular so they have
they have dedicated design gurus
over at stack overflow not just one and
they have you know qa team and so on so
on
they follow all the you know peso core
so-called best practices
of the industry that's spread on hacker
news the extreme idiot
spread over best they follow best
practice then
you see this okay now so i now have a
question i have a question
so do you see this is actually a better
design
um now does this not make you like when
you see source code does not
does it not make you to grab your mouse
and try to scroll this thing little
bar to see the code does that is that is
that true
or am i just like talking
so what is alternative so that you might
ask you know what is
alternative alternative let me show you
you look at our website
you'll see the best alternative okay
let's show you our website you see you
see okay let me
let me let me pop out this window okay
so you see
this is uh website let's magnify you see
this line
this line is very long okay it's very
long now but however now let's shrink
the window okay
let's shrink the window hold on a second
let me let me
let me uh highlight the line so you can
see
shrink the window you see it doesn't it
doesn't
create a horizontal scroll bar so that
you have to scroll
idiocy okay it doesn't create
that idiocy you see
this is a better design so if you shrink
the window
you see the first of what i mean the
left panel goes away then you can shrink
it
and you know it looks like that you
don't have to and if you copy the source
code
it doesn't add new lines characters
there you know you are actually copying
for example let's copy it okay let's
copy
copy it go to emacs magnify
new buffer paste it here magnify oh wait
did we copy it we didn't copy okay okay
copy it new buffer
paste it you see this is still one line
not because you know this it doesn't you
know it doesn't
uh become truncated or added new lines
this is still one single line
so this is a so i would claim this is a
better user interface
design okay
so you see the problem i'm talking about
this
you know so the cycle of uh what the
idiocy
and and what and and these design gurus
you know they are
you know they are living at stack
overflow they are living at microsoft
they are living in google google you
know every year
you know google take conference or
microsoft conference
they're gonna talk you know they're
gonna hip you know
clean cut boys they go on stage and and
nice
we are helping the world and today i'm
going to
demo uh we are the new interface
new interface design we created the
idiots
okay that's it that's it about that i
think that's it for today
about user interface design not just you
know not just this one single thing okay
pip show windows okay not just one of
these okay
watch my videos you know uh
remember what i said okay go over it and
not this is not just
this issue this also this starting about
10 years ago
great great text on white background
this extreme idiocy
and they are adopted by racket you know
this elite
you know these hackers racket skin
this okay great text on a grey
grey text on white background the fact
it's all fashion and facts
in fact i can tell you
of the user interface design of the past
30 years i lived through
are they getting better no i don't think
so not really
okay my that's my alarm clock
[Applause]
okay i gotta go so that's it for today
so the user interface design in the past
30 years
have they get gotten better not
not really okay you know actually i can
go
a level deeper i can tell you why this
happens okay that's another that's
that's another
uh a deeper level but first of all i
first of all i need to go through all
these things first of all you need to
actually because most of you you know
all the people the hacker news
they don't they don't they've never seen
this never seen this
never occurred to them these ideas and
linux dribbling about linux
linux idiots the unix idiots the hacker
idiots the python you know the lisp the
emacs the veeam idiots
didn't these issues i'm concerned i'm
concerned about design
they never occurred to them
then then then what happens okay so
first of all i need to actually go
explain each one of these in detail then
you can actually see what i'm
what you know what is my point you know
some of this gray on white
and then you have this orange on gray
and this is not
just a one-man website this is us
technica one of the classic
old very popular website very technical
and usually very good okay
us technica in the 2000s they are one of
the best sites i'm not sure about today
because there's
lots of crap today so you know then
then you have this orange on grade can
you actually read it
and then some of these you know
you know today today i have a big
high resolution quality monitor i bought
this year i
you know you go to my keyboard page just
search for sally monitor you'll find it
so you know i i have actually a good
monitor very high quality but i don't
have before
then some of this gray is actually very
hard to read
you know for example this is a racket
scheme you know
how to read uh
i gotta go okay so so first of all you
see all these
issues about user interface design
i need to go over so and and
this one is from firefox okay
disappearing buttons
[Laughter]
this disagreement you know you have the
back you know let me show you okay you
see
you have the backward arrow forward
arrow
so about five years ago 10 years ago
80 years ago the firefox idiots the
idiots at firefox these are hacker types
you know open source firefox
loved by you guys you need to use
firefox which donates to
antifa if you don't know search for it
oh by the way oh you cannot even find it
because google
now censored your search and also those
original videos are good
uh firefox donate donated your money
your donation goes to antifa
uh so anyway the moving buttons okay so
firefox eight years ago they
they have a new user interface where
when you
where when there is no forward button
they the button disappears
so like so like when you are browsing
the the top you know the top
the window top they just they moves like
when you are looking at your page the
things
shift a idiocy
of course now they reverted that so so
many so many idiocies okay then this one
is about
microsoft windows colorful tabs colorful
like you cannot tell which one is the
the current tab
okay so this um so first of all if i
you know i maybe next day uh possibly
because i
oh oh this one is amazing look look at
this one okay 30 study this one
easy um
so first of all i need to go over all
these user interface design issues
then so you guys so you know people can
you you hacker types who follows me you
know we are the nerds type
you get you get what i'm saying uh
then you might agree with me then
there's a deeper level to go
into that is why
it happened why does society why does
this happen
of course i've thought about that then
trivially i thought about that i can
tell you why
but you know if i just tell you you're
gonna you don't you don't you don't hear
it you
because you don't understand you don't
get it you don't get it
but i've said you know i've said this
before the reason this happens
uh there are several causes one of the
main costs is money
okay the corporations google microsoft
stack overflow and so on all the
facebook twitter
they design their website their user
interface design
is not based on the premise you know
first of all you need a goal what are
you going to do what you know what's
your criteria what you
what do you want to achieve with your
use of a interface design
what kind of thing what aspect you want
to maximize you want to optimize
that's a question for every everyone
in general it is assumed the
the goal of user interface design the
criteria is that
users you know users will have the
best the most the user interface design
must be the most
intuitive is most easy to use
and most efficient to operate so you
don't have to like go here click that
little button then click
that to do this thing you know if that's
a frequently needed command you know so
that's
the issues that in general the unsaid
and the unsaid assumption about
quality user interface design you know
quality is redundant you know user
interface design
is that you want to optimize the
efficiency
the intuitiveness the ease of use
for the customers for the users of the
software okay
that is a implicit that's a goal of user
interface design
design is a word you know mini implies
implied in that word is
good design quality design okay
but however facebook google and all
these companies including phone iphone
you know iphone or
android
originally that's their that's also
their design goal but
however they have another important
element that is
they want to optimize
among different user interface design
choices what they want to
optimize is that the users gets added
addicted to your website and you know
they want to optimize the user user
interface design
so that the bottom line is that so that
they can make more money
okay so that their ads you know so users
are more likely to click their ads for
example twitter okay
twitter so that they want to optimize
their user interface design so that
you have more users users will you know
stick
your keep using your software user will
be addicted you know more likely to be
addicted to your website or or your
phone or whatever your product
and user will likely you know they they
have jargon words
engagement you know you have increased
engagement
so that's the bottom line okay that's i
can tell you
one of the major reason oh we have all
these lousy
design is because
the user interview interface designed by
these companies
it's not really about you know ease of
use intuitive
intuitiveness yeah those are part of the
their design goal but
but as much as important
the the thing they really want is they
want to get users
keep using their software okay make more
money
see their ads click more engagement with
their ads and you know stuff like that
that that is this is the
primary reason that okay one of the
reasons the primary reason we have
all these ups but by the user
interface design
by these corporations and also
then there are other reasons the other
reason for example one of them is
incompetence which is a lot of microsoft
uh let me let me tell you why for
example
for example this uh for example the pip
show window
the picture windows for the you know
those
tiny windows in the case of window
microsoft
windows operating system why does do
they occur
well in this in this case
it's not because money it's because
the complexities of corporations because
microsoft has become so big
their operating system has become you
know 30 years old
so there's lots of code so they cannot
so they don't have time
you know they don't they don't
prioritize
you know these to update you know this
old code
this uh modal dialect dialog boxes
that's that's the reason for this
in this specific case okay there are
many reasons for different cases for
example
twitter why is twitter you know using
these pipshot windows well
in that case that's because money
because twitter found you know they have
they have a b test they have lots of
jargons engagement a b test you know
they have a whole team to see which user
interface gets them
the most money they find they find that
possibly
you know the user interface this way the
pip show window gets them
the most money because they they don't
want you to like
anyway that i don't have time i have
lots of things to cover okay so then
here's a google plus case which is dead
today
um then what what about what's the
reason for the stack for overflow case
why is stack overflow designed this way
the case of stack overflow is because
uh because the i i think it's because
the css design
idioms that kind of you know the best
practice the idiocy also ease of coding
anyway that's that's another topic
another day okay
i think that's it for today uh
and i'm tired i gotta go yeah uh so okay
bye guys
uh it's hot getting hot uh
so what is like going on 15 uh people
uh watches okay you're gonna if you like
my stuff
put money in my pocket okay if you find
my talk
worthy and stuff donate
bye guys i gotta go
and if you have questions you know you
either post to the discord or something
i
anyway i don't have a scheduled uh
youtube
i don't know when's the next time i
don't i'm living a chaos life