welcome to another wondrous show of
South Park
I'm alive today is May 20 2009 teen and
we are going to have a lively session
and I'm going to talk about several
things you know I've been doing this for
half a year now so as experience
accumulates I explore possibilities
let's see if I'm doing okay yeah I'm
doing okay I'm alive and I'm talking and
I'm going to try to do multiple small
topics possibly let's see how it goes
and okay and while people are coming in
let's just begin let's begin go through
my blogs and four topics cover some
topics on the on this page list okay
math fun okay Oh first of all let me
change the date so people don't get
confused confusion is confusion
confounds us all okay let's go to this
small topic let's look I got this trick
in Emacs
okay so let's saw start command log mod
so you can see every command I call in
Emacs you just show up on the left
window in case we are doing some Emacs
demo Emacs is my life okay go back okay
and let's call Emacs command let me show
you okay this is co Emacs man wave open
link in brave browser do it
to it okay that opens that link and this
is going to show you what is his name
accessing window we don't need that
close that okay this guy's telling me
things but that's not we want hold on a
second to me let's wait for that to come
up create a page why is it taking so
long
oh my god this this what is this oh this
is elite Lisp okay let's try that again
OpenLink him brave do it okay so one day
I was doing this Ethiopia Unicode page
then I run into this picture this is
this is fascinating well you know is
that Ethiopia yeah so one day I was you
know in my usual usual course of doing
things computing and everything in a
world studying so I was doing this
Ethiopia page let's have a look okay
so many interesting things we did that
photo go anyway so this is Ethiopia
Ethiopia script for Ethiopian language
it's quite funny you know it's quite
wonderful and so you know when I'm doing
this
this is Unicode and so I'm when I'm
doing this I also by the way they have
interesting punctuation you see these
characters these are all punctuation new
internal on JavaScript so you see these
are punctuation
this is section mark this is word space
this is full stop
so this is period for dots so this is
Ethiopian language and this Ethiopia is
located here
what's called the rhino horn of africa i
think it's rhino home yeah
Rhino home of Africa you know ye side of
Africa so that's their country and so
you know I'm reading about a country and
Ethiopia Ethiopia is pretty old language
is it I'm not sure how old it is it but
this one is from 1607 but anyway then
yeah I think it's pretty all right don't
remembered but then you have then I went
into this picture this this is sticking
ok so let's do this again showing brave
good morning Daniel Daniel and no is
Langille lag no is LAN low is
so so you got this picture I found this
picture from Wikipedia and this picture
is amazing in several ways because first
of all look at the picture okay it looks
like a from a movie of Hollywood movie
this is this picture is from Wikipedia
okay and it doesn't it didn't provide
any context so this picture is this
photograph is fantastic in several ways
first of all it's kind of strange I mean
this guy holding a gun you know are they
kind of like rebels or armies or
something you know I don't know and they
looks like a tribe you know some kind of
primitive tribe you know with these face
paintings and this I think those are
scars on the face I'm not sure and she's
naked you know and you know so this guy
holding a gun so I don't know if they
are a rebel or rebel force or 100 or not
but on the other hand you know it's not
like just it's not just like military
because then you have you know young
girls and you know is this a guy this is
a guy with flowers on her he's his head
and babies and mom oh grandma you know
so it's kind of very strange you know
you don't know what it is and but also
it's aesthetically beautiful so this is
this is the photograph that would win
awards you know in my opinion so you
know it's beautiful it's the composition
and everything so yeah in many ways it's
very strange photo and yeah so that's
about that Ethiopia that's you know just
this picture I found that's interesting
so that concludes the mini talk of the
first topic daniel lang Louis says I
wrote DC there because I forgot to write
borac because you forgot to write
varrock Oh what do you mean TC TC is
varrock let's see what this is varrock
ej now DC on vorak is Courtis EC no no D
wait
it's core thi oh so that means hi okay
so that makes sense okay so yeah you are
still trying to learn more AK while
maintaining quality skill why would you
do that that's very bad that's something
you don't want to do you know okay let's
let's see how many people are watching
this is critical
five people oh my god okay so next topic
this next topic the next topic is let's
see I want to cover this topic
okay math font Z now this is fantastic
JavaScript web application I just wrote
yesterday so let's open a new window
paste new window paste here go there
okay so this is about Unicode okay in
unicode the you have these symbols these
letters this is called double stroke and
this is mathematical Franco okay and
then you have mathematical board you
have mathematical italic then you have
mathematical script now these are not
you know these are unicode symbols so
that means these are characters they are
not for example this M scripted M it is
not M then you say it make it italic
then make you know is just a character
by itself with a party you know font
that just shows thing like that so you
can copy for example you can copy this
and paste it to Twitter or anywhere and
it will become like that you know it was
showing any editor for example let's go
to Emacs okay open a new buffer magnify
paste you see and I can now I can call
for example describe cha and I have
information about the character the code
point and the character name
mathematical both Frank to capital P so
you see this is not you know like
applying styles is just a character by
themselves have these shapes so I wrote
this JavaScript application you can go
and use you know you can change anything
you want let's see once upon a time no
this is real-time by the way let's use
math math script something in the water
that does not compute and I need to save
princess princess okay so now you got
that you can copy that copy it go to go
to my Twitter then go to cancel that new
post
new post okay paste
it's super slow god yeah okay
now you see the shows up scripted you
know this you know the in the scripted
style so that is about that
and you can just go to my page and use
it you know it's wonderful the website
is this one you know just such folks re
Unicode then you go to the math font
over here then you'll see a so that
concludes another topic this is my
second topic by the way this is this
interesting this run you can also try it
blunt okay so you know check click it
and you got these runs run script now
run script is very interesting it turns
out it's a ancient yeah script and you
can let's see unique ok runic alphabets
were used around year 150 to 1500 s it
was used to write various German
Germanic languages before the adoption
of the Latin alphabet so this is runic
script very interesting and you know it
the the superhero Thor that's his
country so he's granddad he's dead he
starts that stairs that uses this script
ok Daniel Liang Liang Louis says yay
being Barack is 10 once upon time is
something in the water that does not
compute I am typing to practice in gorac
okay okay so we got this math font I
want to talk about that's a mini topic
that concludes that mini topic let's see
what's the okay next topic
next topic would be cover some topic on
this page okay math fun that covered
okay so so what shall on the next topic
T excuse me so if you guys are watching
if you have a questions posted that is
the purpose of our talk show you can ask
me anything and in particular you know
go through the exotics your homepage and
you'll see a list of topics so I'm going
to go to let's start my third topic so
let's go to my programming blog actually
just go to Kasauli info sorry that info
website so on the keyboard Department is
here something new not really okay this
thing this thing is interesting to talk
about the ctrl key and caps lock key
position in ode keyboards you know among
programmers especially the elite hacker
types for example Emacs users
you know those Emacs users or VI users
they they have a misconception they like
to insist that on other keyboards the
control key is at where today's caps
lock key the positional caps lock key
now that is false
okay that's the this hacker idiots
hacker types I despise them let me show
you what I'm talking about
okay so let's go to the Sun Microsystems
keyboard this is the this is one of the
keyboard law you know a man you know
hacker types a love that by the way this
is my office in 2001 Edna Tapia I woke
it on top here back then Natalia got it
got bought by AMD known on AMD but by
Motorola in 2006 or so anyway in 2001 I
was working at not hope yet so this is
my office it's quite spacious you know
you know you don't have that these days
today you have like Open Office it's
like idiotic open office like a giant
warehouse they just have rows of tables
and everyone is just seen there you know
anyway this disrespect in 2001 I share
this is a big office ok this is only
like a quarter of it it's a room by
itself you know so four times as large
and I share it with another engineer so
I have two computers here these are Sun
Microsystems I think it's a Sun blade
you know back then it's like few
thousand dollars expensive Sun
workstations some Microsystems of course
it died some resistance died and bought
by Oracle and so look at this keyboard
this is Sun Microsystems type 6 keyboard
so you have a control key here you see
so a lot hacker types they like to think
that you know all the old keyboards have
the control key at this position then
Microsoft [ __ ] it up they they have
the habit of you know the it's in there
my always blame Microsoft everything
they do they just they hate Microsoft
these hackers I hate this hackers ok
because what because these are just
untrue for example you know so today
we're gonna look at just X ok we survey
we take a survey of all the old
terminals and keyboards and let's just
I'm gonna show you
they don't have it's not true that their
control key as is always at this
position ok so let's look at that so go
back to go to keyboard page go through
my blog and I just
this page so this page discusses the
detail so let's see Danielle
okay see you at 10:10 yeah okay how many
people are watching five okay
again comments opinions type it okay so
ctrl key and caps lock key positions so
starting with this printing terminal
1965 from IBM you see this key there is
caps lock okay so 1965 right there you
have a caps lock key now this is IBM
printing terminal now I am not exactly
sure what it does exactly because it
just looks like a IBM electric you know
Selectric you know very famous electric
they let's have a look
IBM printing terminal okay here is the
key layout you see the caps lock is is
you know beside a so IBM 2741 was a
printing computer terminal introduced in
1965 compared to the tight to compared
to the tailored typewriter machines that
were commonly used as printing terminals
at the time the two 741 offered slightly
higher speed much higher quality
printing interchangeable type fonts and
both upper and lower cases alphabets he
was used primarily with the IBM
system/360 series of computers and was
influential in the development and
popularity of the APL programming
language okay yeah so anyway this this
machine is somewhat popular is one of
the the popular old you know terminals
of machines you know so I don't exactly
know
why but I think I guess it's because
it's one of the it comes with you know
the Apr programming language a PR
problem in language is also very
interesting we are now going to talk
about it today but it's a it's what so
called array language okay
similar is Mathematica or Julia okay
basically math or scientific programming
languages are array languages basically
what rate languages means is that when
you use map you know usually you have
map function in in today's languages
like Python and Ruby in JavaScript you
map a function to array you know you
have a function map but in our real
languages you do not need a function map
whenever you are apply of function to a
argument if that argument is a array or
list it automatically map you know
that's what array languages are an array
languages are typically on the
categorized as the math languages such
as Mathematica Giulia APL okay math
languages is better than the C C++ Java
and Ruby Python this crap okay so anyway
so this IBM terminal let's go back then
then we have tech VT 52 terminal 1975
this is also a extremely popular
terminal now on the left side is hard to
see but you have control caps lock a
okay so basically you know that position
is caps lock control caps lock a okay I
don't have a bigger photo here but you
know anyway so there it is there next T
Tech VT hundred terminal 1978 again the
key bit to the left of a
is caps-lock okay then after that you
have control okay this is also very
extremely popular terminal now these are
very popular terminals the 50 to the
vt100
you can like when program you like
today's program older generation 60
years old you know sometimes they they
tell you like oh they've been using this
terminal for you know many years they
have found memories you know
so let's next you have these and harbor
and Arbor ambassador 60 terminal 1982
again you have cash lock to the left of
a then control to the left of that this
this terminal is kind of funny-looking
its championed by the jwz guy you know
you probably know jwz jamie zawinski who
is who who is famous for his nets
Netscape walk you know he he putted the
netscape browser to unix experiment and
you know he's on the TV show you know
you know the show Silicon Valley or
something so you can see okay so this
keyboard has controlled to the left of a
okay let's go back let's see the
Commodore now no Commodore is also very
popular so to the left of a is shift
lock shift lock is actually slightly
different from caps lock you know
because shift when when you press caps
lock well then you press the number key
you know such as 8 it does not you know
type the parentheses
for example let's try you max open a new
new window let's not try it because I
actually don't have caps lock key
because I don't use it so I remapped it
so anyway Commodore 64 then you have at
Apple Macintosh come on in song those
are general colors on that terminal
those are great colors on that terminal
yeah the green on black is that what you
talking about I think that's the one
yeah let's see old days you know I also
I also have my terminal in that color
you know you know the color in terminal
is funny you know before so in in a you
know 1870s and you know and even up to
90s you know these terminals in packing
70s or 80s they are monochrome so they
don't have colors they only have like
green that's it basically one one one
color green green or seein
sometimes it's seein I mean not seein
but kind of orange amber amber yeah
green or amber and they only they can
only display characters not like today's
you know monitor you can have you know
graphics they can only display
characters like 80 characters by 24
characters kind of like the terminal I
have here in fact it's smaller
you know the whole screen is like let's
see 80 by yeah the whole screen is like
I have my terminal emulator here that's
the size you just magnified you know you
know so you know it's funny about these
things because as programmers like today
you have people concerned or playing
with themes color themes all day day and
night you know like I have my most
popular Emacs page is you know guess
guess which it is you know I have turns
of Emacs tutorials in it set up
tutorials Emacs keybinding tutorials and
eMac this tutorials
but the most popular one of the top five
most popular page is about color themes
it's this is so funny and and they
actually pisses me off it's not
something important you know it's always
something like trivial let's see where
is it theme oh it's in it set up I think
game yeah color themes this is one of
the most popular page so it tells you
know it teaches you how to set up colors
you know like yeah so you know this is
almost like the so called bike shade
problem because the story of bike shades
bike shade is that you know a nuclear
facility you know like a corporation you
know when when you have a meeting and
some nuclear issues you know we need to
decide you know but most people don't
have opinions on that but when it comes
to what color we should paint the new
bicycle shade then everyone's got
opinions and to argue about that you see
so the the morrow is that the most
trivial things everyone you know talk
about it all the time but the important
things very few people you know talks
about it part of the reason is it simple
to understand because you know important
things you know it takes more education
more knowledge to actually know what it
is about you know so but the bike the
color of the bike shade shade everyone's
got opinion so in a similar way
you know these themes you know even if
you go to Reddit a max place you know
you have people asking about themes all
the time or found you know this idiotic
programmers the hacker types you know
the they want to talk about what's the
widget is the best font now that's
another big rant of my okay they talk
about they have opinions about the
aesthetics of font you know which one is
more pure
like which one would they prefer which
one you prefer you know each one each
person has their own preferences
preferences you know oh I like this
color thing I must use this font because
it's better this way or that however
they don't did you know this Emacs
people Emacs people supposedly they are
concerned about functionality you know
they don't like GU eyes you know these
many of these hacker idiots they they
want to remove you know the scrollbar
they want to remove remove the menu bar
you know this idiots okay III cause I
don't like them despise their opinions
so you see they why do they want to
remove this Koba because to them they
are like they are
I'm the hacker okay I don't want
scrollbar because that's GUI that's too
easy to understand I don't want that I
like things to be difficult like the
terminal you know I want to use the
Emacs in terminal I what I'm the real
man that's that's this kind of you know
that's what they are thinking but you
know so so so they they like to say they
are concerned about functionality
because you know GUI distract them you
know because they want to control no
Mouse you know they want to control
things precisely sufficiently but half
of those their Creed's are [ __ ] let
me take first of all let me tell you
about the scuba the scuba is the most
effective efficient visual signal for
you know which part of your page is is
you are on what kind of position give
you an idea it's much better than the
line number you know like those hacker
types they prefer the line number like
at the bottom you see here it's more
efficient than that because you know you
can test test this scientifically you
know you you blink your eye you know
just for half a second you test two
situations you blink your eye then you
can tell what position it is versus if
you have to if you don't have this
about you look at the numbers you know
the line number the percentage right
here you know 22% right here so you know
compare this to the score bar is
certainly superior you know well anyway
so Emacs people the VI people the UNIX
philosophy type of people you know the
hanker types
they usually you know that's what they
say they like functionality over
everything else the over GUI you know
they like efficiency half of their
queries just force for example the score
buys is is a example okay but I'm going
to go back to the theme and talk about
that so so yeah so they they prefer the
idea of functionality but however when
it comes to font their preference it's
not about functionality is at all they
are concerned about this little trivial
crap okay like today even today you this
been happening for 20 years even today
you go to hacker news or read it often
every every month or two you will see
the programmers discuss about fun you
know someone we oppose the new font okay
like this phone is more aesthetic you
know you know found what is one of the
fat in in anyway
so anyway programmer talk about fun you
know they debate about oh I like this
one I like that one okay but they don't
they are not actually concerned about
functionality why let me tell you why
about the font thing okay so the
founding let's go to my Emacs block
let's go to in it set up
okay that's such full font okay font set
up so this page is a tutorial about
everything you want to know about how to
set font in Emacs okay and I'm going to
show you the page where
I talk about best fonts font topic okay
proportional font sycophant so it's not
here okay so we need to go to Unicode go
to practical Emacs on a second search
for Unicode Unicode topic yes and
Unicode basics Unicode tutorial best
unicode font for programmer okay let me
tell you what is my concern my criteria
for which font is the best okay you see
these unicode symbols and lots of
mathematical symbols for example these
mathematical symbols you know i you say
you know so my concern about font is
that first of all they distinguish you
know 0 from capital all from lowercase o
because that's important for programmers
that's required for every font choice
choice and the letters one versus
lowercase L versus capital I you know
you know these are hard to distinguish
distinguish anyway but anyway you want a
phone that kind of distinguish them then
for programmers we wanted to be mono
space okay but then my criteria is that
they the font must contain commonly used
unicode characters such as math symbols
for example all these arrows double
arrows right arrow left arrow summation
sign product sign you know circle plus
and so on and in some of the Greek
characters alpha beta for degree theta
for degree lambda for computer science
you know lambda function and so on
so that is my concern that is you know
when it comes to fun because I'm
actually concerned about functionality
this is functionality you want a found
that contains these characters yeah but
no but when you look at the reddit you
know or the hacker types when they talk
about fun this is not their concern this
issue never comes up you know it you
know it depresses me you know it's like
what are you talking about these people
you know the most of these people I
assume they are Americans okay they you
know they so yeah all these all these
first about fonts but you know the font
they they recommend you know you go to
Reddit or how can you search for fun
the the font the type of fun they
recommend do not contain any you know
use usually almost always do not contain
this Unicode characters and white so why
are they obsessed about you know
particular the particular font why were
they prefer that fun because they talk
about oh I like this one because it
looks better because you know these
idiots okay the [ __ ] idiots is this
hacker typing you see everyone has
preferences I'm okay with that you know
everyone has opinions you you prefer
something that's fine I prefer something
you prefer bananas I prefer orange okay
but the thing about these hacker types
is that the way they think this UNIX
philosophy these facts these these [ __ ]
heads okay
the thing about that is that when they
present their preferences they have this
entitlement like the way they think is
that this is the way okay if you don't
believe this where you are idiot that's
the way they present their things you
know things you know it's almost in the
UNIX philosophy types you know the you
know those people who prefer terminal
only types the Emacs few types of in
type same types this is the same thing
when they present these ideas
they always come with this attitude that
if you do not agree you know then you
are stupid you are idea that's that's
the thing so that's a problem that's why
I have this hatred okay over my life you
know this is like it's like my career
rant about again is these types this is
what bothers me okay now this is in
contracts so in contrast for for example
to let's say Microsoft programmers or
PHP programmers or JavaScript
programmers back in 2000 okay
these communities they they don't have
this entitlement thing going on you know
like you know and most often the
Microsoft programmers or the PHP
programmers or the JavaScript
programmers they are often left by this
UNIX philosophy hacker Fox okay
yeah people this UNIX fostering
entitlement they usually reticular the
PHP PHP never use PHP you know because
the language sucks you know song and we
JavaScript in the Microsoft okay these
people despise them but however when you
dig into details about this UNIX
philosophy philosophy type of people
their ideas their thinking you know it's
a crap you know the function of fontys
example i just talked about you know you
don't have unicode so what the [ __ ] is
your idea about functionality nothing
then okay funnies example i talked about
the GUI you know the score bar is
another example you know this is
function if you really concerned about
functionality you want the scuba and you
want font that you know that contains
unicode characters because if the font
do not contain unicode the commonly used
Unicode characters okay then
the font substitution technology kicks
in the practical meaning of that is that
you'll get ugly fonts because you have a
measure of different fonts you know when
you have right arrow characters you know
any of these Unicode characters or math
you know math symbols that's an issue
so we digressed we digress into you know
the you know so let's get back to the
control key position on the asian
keyboards you know this is again another
of these UNIX philosophy type of people
hacker types you know they'd like to
think which is also wrong okay the old
keyboards they do not always have
control key you know to the left of a in
fact it's actually kind of like half and
half so I covered several and then Apple
key keyboards you know in so Apple
Knight Apple 2e keyboard has has control
key to the left of a okay this is 1983
and 1984 the Apple Macintosh keyboard
has caps lock to the left of a okay so
you see it's a kind of like back and
forth then the so-called Apple standard
keyboard 1987 again has the control key
to the left of a okay but but but you
know but then the Macintosh computers
basically they all have they all have
caps lock to the left of a okay the
Macan Macintosh basically after 1984
yeah
then we look at lists machine keyboards
this machine keyboards they are quite a
few of them they don't have control key
to the left of a nor do they have
capsule to the left of a their control
and caps lock is in fact in
different positions in kind of unique to
list machines then we have IBM PC
keyboard again the story here is mixed
okay so in 1981 the first IBM PC
keyboard they have control key to the
left of a but in 1984 they have caps
locked to the left of a and some have
have controlled to the left a so against
mixed but after that after 1984 is so
caps lock to the left of a so you know
so anyway so here is a that's the survey
of the position of control keys so caps
lock key on old keyboard so we can see
that you know basically it's a mixed bag
you know yeah so that is that that I
think that concludes this mini topic so
let's see Sean says those are great
colors okay the VT 52 okay so he's
talking about the VT 52 let's see which
one is the VT 52 oh the VT 52
oh you have used it like your setup
seems very efficient and easy to read
agreed hundred percent we have made
advancements like the score bar for a
reason okay designer master says law
[Laughter]
okay I was probably ranting about
something I forgot what's the context I
need to get into a habit to read the
comments sooner because after a few
minutes I lost the content context okay
now we are 45 minutes into the show and
let's get back to so what what's the
next topic okay let me also mention you
know a lot programmers you know
especially if you have strange if you if
you use Emacs and also especially if you
have repetitive strain injury you know
with your hands
there's also another law among hacker
types that tells people to switch you
know to swap control key and caps lock
key you know so especially if you use
Emacs you know put you know don't do
that okay with qualifications okay in
general that's okay basically do that on
laptop laptops
okay if you are you know if you are
using laptop so often okay do that you
know makes your caps-lock key to control
which is which is good but actually you
shouldn't be typing on laptop Keys you
know laptop Keys is how I got my first
eyesight back in 2005 I have a lot of
stories about that you know I have like
several articles about that that
documents my history of RSI if you go to
my Emacs blog go to Emacs keys section
then you can see let's search for swap
caps knock can control why you should
not swap caps not gain control
so I tell you you shouldn't okay and
again this is one of the
one of the myth that these hacker types
tends to cling to you know they spread
this every every chance they have you
know every heavy opportunity you see it
every month or every few months hacker
news on reddit you know like a
generation you know it's like undying
myth and I was seeing cred you know but
if you the thing it's a myth because if
you actually dig into the detail it's
not a good thing you know it's not a
good solution it's one of the solution
for avoiding RSI okay but it's not
really a good solution okay first of all
you know don't touch you know on a
laptop it's a good solution okay I grant
that on a laptop keyboard you can you
can you can you know makes your cat
start to control because laptop keys are
jammed together and and the caps lock
position yeah that's really a good
position okay but an alternative is
actually to make your Alt key to control
so that you can just press it with your
thumb in fact a even better solution is
just if you are using Emacs just use a
use Evo mod or use stuff like keys okay
so I give you detailed explanation on
what to do you know what's the
alternative solution and I have seen
like when you take into this detail and
there are a lot people that you know who
have tried to press you know make have
start to control
that's a that's a problem because if
you're gonna do that and if you're
typing load is a lot you know you're
gonna have problems with your pinky you
know but you know these laws they
persist because most people they are not
paying attention you know you know so
they spread but if one day if like if
your boss tell me tells you today like
today we're gonna have a big project you
you have to finish this in a week then
you have to type few hours a day then if
you are doing you know using caps
lockers control you're gonna have our
side right away okay no kidding
then then you're gonna become one of
these people you're gonna have it you
you're gonna see a doctor you have
you're gonna have pain then you're gonna
see a doctor you ruined your career
something like that then you become this
one of these minorities like every time
when these hacker types on Hacker News
SoCo they go to read it but they spread
this myth oh you should you should just
make you a caps lock to control and blah
blah blah you crap okay then you're
gonna say something there you can oppose
there but you are minority your post is
gonna nobody is gonna upload your post
but on the other hand all these idiots
they up the upload upload all the all
the recommendations about how you should
swap your control with the caps lock hey
meanwhile you are never heard that's
what happens yeah the cycle continues
until one of those guys you know got
paying one day you know then he becomes
the minority groups but then there's a
new generation of idiots like new
generation new generation they don't
know they just keeps telling you oh you
should you should swap to your left
caps lock to control key and then
they're gonna say oh all the old
terminals they got you know control key
you know at the right position it's a
Microsoft who [ __ ] it up this this
[ __ ] this UNIX philosophy types of
[ __ ]
so I despised them okay I did in my 20
years of computing career now my career
is mostly focused on UNIX and Linux I
never actually know Microsoft
technologies and I don't know apples
technologies okay so I'm open source
coder since since 1998 okay so why
because
the eunuchs for us what the eunuchs the
hacker types attract me I don't you know
i don't like cooperation so in many ways
I share the my mindset with the hacker
types because I like freedom okay I like
I like self-control I like you know
freedom free speech and in my own
control and I learn things on my own
you know so I like I like that you know
but I guess I have some differences with
some of the some with many of these
hacker type of things they spread you
know UNIX philosophy you know all these
hack hacker types they they are to me ok
for my study for my research you know in
my career 20 years 30 years you know I
think they are just wrong there they are
just factually incorrect ok wrong is the
dramatic word you know the technical
word is they are what they say is
usually factually incorrect in Queen of
UNIX philosophy you know I talked about
this in my past a few months ago of an
hour on that you know UNIX philosophy
every item you know it's just it's just
what these are this hacker laws okay
this control key have sake you know this
hacker what they what they say they
think the way they are like that is
usually is simply put is just because a
coat it's a method of code formation
what they say these caps lock keys you
know using terminals you know not using
the mouse avoiding GUI
oh this kind of thinking ok they are
just simply as a creed of a code and
that's how they spread how they build
how they recruit new generations you
know you know Andy the most half of them
is just fact
in correct but the coat you know kind of
you know this a train they keep going
Emacs is part of it Emacs and VI is the
major part of this thing this code thing
okay that that should conclude the topic
about the control key and capslock key
so about the control key and capslock
key whether you should switch you know I
have like several articles about it not
just this one and you know meaning
others what you you want you know yeah
that's like that's another whole topic I
can talk about for 20 min minutes about
so if you don't switch caps lock to with
control then what are the alternatives
so yeah let me just say that then okay
so one alternative first of all do not
type on a laptop key okay don't do that
for for more than ten minutes okay try
to keep your habit because for me it is
using the laptop keyboard for you know
five hours a day you know for
exclusively for two years I start to get
RSI I don't have is I fifteen years
before I've been typing for fifteen
years you know every day you know since
1991 and I never having any problem I'm
using a normal PC keyboard in fact I
don't care for ergonomic keyboards you
know never had a problem until I got a
problem because of laptop keyboard then
I switch to Microsoft
ergonomic natural you know that
Microsoft keyboard anyway so all these I
have detailed documentation you know in
my Emacs pages over here you can you can
read so first of all don't try not to
use laptops you know key keyboard by a
separate keyboard and by a mechanical
keyboard preferably split you know
ergonomic one
so I have a suggestions on what which to
buy but you know a lot of people are not
used to and if you are young you don't
have handpan you know you rather you
know you don't touch type you know you
you know a PC keyboard no more wine is
fine for you then that's okay just buy a
normal keyboard that biomechanical ones
okay mechanical keys those those are
actually does help with your hand health
okay so so don't use laptop keyboard by
an external external mechanical keyboard
okay then there are also many other
solutions to the control key first of
all well if you buy one of these split
you know then you have you know many of
them has you know thumb keys so you can
set these keys to control so that solves
a lot of problems you can set this
spacebar to control for example this
miss stoper Roco keyboard or the
ultimate hacking keyboard you can also
do that xbox eboard you can you know
control is right under your thumb you
know this is truly organ omec and all
smart yeah you see many options that is
why I do recommend this you know Batman
keyboards in this split organ AMA
keyboard they really they are really
good design okay so beside that you can
also if you are using eMac I highly
recommend you use evil mod or use some
fried cheese now some Frankie's is a
creation of my own so you know that's
you know my own thing so I you know of
course I recommend it but it's up to you
I talked about suck like he's a few
times in my past talk you know so you
can you know check it out check it out
so anyway that that should conclude
that's the topic about ctrl keys and
versus you know caps lock command key
care sock
so that's one hour so any questions any
questions
penis comments type it please
so these design masters phase Linux
philosophy mugs so design master says
never thought of using odors control
thanks ah yeah that's a good alternative
you know that's that's good as only are
you using Emacs if you are a Emacs user
then I would highly recommend you switch
to you switch to evil mod hooks off like
keys or economic ago Emacs mod oh these
are alternative key binding systems for
Emacs I highly recommend one of these
not any other but one of these that we
are beat that will beat swapping control
and odd okay you know because all these
solutions because when you look at all
these solutions so I've been controlling
old I have experiment explore them all
because you know because I have RSI and
I was you know this is my obsession
since 1994
I created a software for vorak on Mac OS
you know efficiency and keyboard is is
kind of my obsession the concept of
efficiency you know I would spend days
just to you know first over minor detail
about which one which one is efficient
more the more efficient like 0.001
percent efficiency you know I have to
obsess about that so you know since I'm
the hacker type you know that's what I
do
I waste you know years you know first
thing about these issues that has no
practical
in a sense it has no practical relevance
so okay yeah so Eva Maude okay Eva Mari
is great Eva Marie is great man
so I think maybe that's that's about it
so we've been talking for a long hours
so that's some of some some good topics
and also I like to mention you know by
the way you know if you know there are
many people who may not agree with my
rant about you know he connects people
you like type of hackers that's totally
fine you you know feel free by the way
feel free if you don't agree feel free
to post it I may or may not address it
you know so I don't you know I don't
mind disagreement at all you know you
can say whatever you you know of course
if you have reasons solid reasons for
supposedly but I've been you know
arguing with this unique hacker hacker
types so I kind of have seen all kind of
you know reasons responses you know I've
been trying to get this my opinion out
that it doesn't work because it's in my
in my opinion it's like fighting a code
like you know when you when when there's
a code you have no chance but you know
so you know I'm getting old you know
it's really somehow being be done for
you know longer in the industry and you
know so you I've seen you know
generations you know so you have new
generation of programmers right today
you know you have the millennial
generation you have younger generation
to JavaScript generation the front-end
generation the UNIX philosophy idea
the slogan itself he's already gone you
know you don't hear that much anymore
you asked young programmers today you
know like majority of them or
significant majority of them are like
JavaScript coders run in yes then what's
you know if philosophy what the [ __ ] is
that
so that is that era is also kind
gun anyway so I've been trying to
express these ideas but they anyway yeah
you know to me it's like a coat you know
it's hard to you know get you know throw
them away but but it but however you
know society to move on you know the
generation especially because generation
you know there's a famous saying among
programmers even Steve Jobs said it you
know Steve say it's it you know like
there's an interview somewhere I asked
him about something about was it
keyboard or programming language or Java
language I forgot with what and he just
said no we just have to wait you know
the old people to die so this is a
popular idea basically the idea is that
programmer so in general people okay the
habit coat don't what go away the
preconceptions whatever you had they
don't go away until you really have to
wait until the new generation comes up
the new younger people that it you know
totally new they were born they never
heard of what you were taught so they
were born they learn new things they
didn't know you know yeah so until you
that's that's when things changed
you know revolution revolution is always
started by young you know students
generation you know in history always
young people there's good about that is
bad about that but anyway it's a fact
that it's usually the young people that
change change makes a change so anyway
so so about this code or you know UNIX
philosophy these things yeah so the new
generations new programming language you
know they kind of kind of change by the
way it's not because they are good you
know they know they are smart no it's
just because they are new you know they
younger people they don't know old
history so they they learned whatever
they learned you know so they is it's
just new then wait them then they
becomes out
the next generation you know kind of to
take over you know so that's that's just
how humanity you know that you know
works you know you have the phrase
generational gap you know you kind of
like them so who knows about keyboard
for example you know in a in the
next-gen you know in twenty years
maybe keyboard itself will be a relic
and also also as you may know how
keyboard came from typewriters you know
mechanical typewriters which is really
CD you see why there's for example let's
go to keyboard design you know many of
the keyboard things we are used to they
are just stupid designs they came from
like two hundred years ago mechanical
typewriters for example the arrangement
of the letters QW ERT why is it that way
it's just you know it's just historical
reasons it was that way because mostly
to prevent key jams because the
mechanical things under you know you
know and today computers you don't have
key Jam for a problem but we are stuck
with the QWERTY layout and also why are
they slanted in this way you know it's
slanted in this way also called
staggered because you see the the metal
bars underneath them because those metal
bars needs to be equidistant to each
other that is why we have this staggered
layout which is really silly you know so
that so that is another reason I
recommend you know these ergonomic new
Badman keyboards you see all the keys
are aligned in a grid or matrix layout
there's no no more this historical you
know stagger you know so there are many
things about you know design we and why
is a spacebar
mungus you know they occupy on the Mac
they occupy five keys but in order
keyboard they occupy like Nikes sweetie
this vt100 from 1978 they occupied Nikes
you like you do you need to press your
spacebar spacebar like that they don't
need to be like way it's that way and I
also have looked the recent space so I
become that large is historical again
there's a typewriters spacebar history
you can read it's kind of it just
happens you know there's a you know
someone anyway you can read that you
know by the way this is odd this one
mechanical typewriter
this is calligraph typewriter from
nineteen from 1891 at that time you
don't have spacebar but you have space
key which is like two things on the side
these two things that's a space key so
in and one day they did you know someone
decided why don't we have a you know a
bar then yeah why not you know so that
that just happened so we have space by
and up to today
so these all these you know stupidities
and the shift key shift key is called
shift key key because you have to shift
the gears when you press the shift key
down all the gears got moved you know a
little bit then you type a letter key
that's why the mechanism will strike the
capital letters so all these things you
know so we still have it the shift key
is called shift and the way you you
press them is that you have to hold down
shift you know you shift gears you have
to keep it ho down in personality then
leave the shift key so that's the
concept of code keys we have today like
control
see control-x owed something you have to
hold down control press the key release
that key then release control must be in
that order specifically well why is that
you know that's because the mechanic
mechanical typewriter because the shift
key you have to it shift gears so what
this is rather you know stupid but it
became a habit so that's why you know
usually we don't want to change because
every time you change habit it's very
annoying it's it's because so you know
so there's a like a struggle between
habit or between revolution you know
between really good design when things
change you know so you should see how
fast those JavaScript philosophers
touch-type on their phone screens okay
so I think that's it for today
any more questions yeah that's it for
today I I'm kind of getting tired I'm
gonna go eat or something or maybe sleep
so any more questions type in text 10 in
20 seconds
type it then interesting in 10 second we
will see it then our answer that and
then that'll be it for today
designer master designer master we were
you from have fun and thanks thank you
thank you for coming to our talk show
so the the end of the show let me show
you this yeah so that's my keyboard so
you can see my pin so I'm gonna twirl
the pen so you see so i-i've been 20 in
pain since I was like 12 years old or 10
10 years old all right I do this all day
day and night it's very frustrating when
you learn it though because you drop it
every day so the the the way you do this
is first of all you learn to do you
learn to do these okay just one time one
shot you learn to do this then you learn
to take it back like that take it back
so you first learn this one shot one
shot one shot then you learn to do these
you know together like push it back push
it back okay then you learn to do it
continuously like that okay thank you
guys for watching that's it for today
bye