good morning everyone welcome to another
another episode of xl talk show
so today's we don't have a topic are you
guys here yet nobody here so i'm going
to start to talk random
and i'm thinking today is going to be 30
minutes or 40 minutes
uh
so i'm going to talk random okay so
let's start so today is 2011
and
11 2021
uh
november 15th
now the month names are interesting
because in english for example you have
a specific name for each month january
february
you know march april
uh and so on in november october
november december you know one mouthful
and the name the name of the month if
you look it up the etymology of the
names they are quite [ __ ] up because
for example october october is the 10th
month of each year you know 10.
i injured my finger i talked about
in my previous few videos anyway october
is the 10th month
right but the english word oct act you
know octopus that you know act stand for
eight octagon for example article
octagon
octopus
but why the [ __ ] is october for the 10th
month you know so there's a
you know it is incredible school up
there you know history of the
month names and october so september so
uh june july june is six july seven
uh
then june july august you know august
you know like
august august um
[Music]
you know i'd be i i think that august uh
came from the
uh roman empire um
emperor you know august i think since
august season i think
i forgot
then september october november december
especially november december is mouthful
november stand for
i don't remember but december you see
december the the beginning decimal you
know decimal numbers that's actually 10
supposed to be was it 10 or 12. do you
uh wait do your decimal anyway it's one
[ __ ] up
naming okay now while in many different
other languages for example in chinese i
know they you know we don't have a
specific name for each month
instead for january january we just say
first month february is the name of the
second month is second month okay so it
goes by numbers so for anyone you know
by now i'm very so you know since i
lived in uh i'm a
i'm a u.s citizen and i lived in usa for
uh
much of my adult life 30 years
30 30 years and so
you know by now i'm so familiar so you
know
given a month name i can immediately
tell you what number it is but
but to many english speakers they
you know you have to you have to like
what so what is uh july you usually you
have to think about it now this is uh
you know this is also interesting
because on credit card you know they use
uh month you know they use the number
system so whenever you say you have to
say what's your expiration date on
credit card you have to kind of mentally
translate what number is to what month
name
nobody is here where is andrew andrew
wanted to talk about you know what
andrew wanted me to uh talk about emac
beast
so andrew come here and you know say it
so anyway so today is random so okay so
random i'm gonna talk for a while and
let me tell you about uh
mathematics okay so so you know you know
since this year i've been spending a
whole lot of time with wufang language
uh and watching stefan wufang
you know i've i admire the guy stefan
wufang few people you know i talked
about this before um so he's a one of
the you know you could say computer you
know
uh computer scientist or you know more
properly he's a physicist
uh an entrepreneur
and uh
yeah and you can say he's also a
computer science scientist especially uh
you know uh with uh
uh expert in cellular automata you know
that's he's that's his primary
i would say primary expertise and you
know uh physics so anyway he's a this
here's a guy i admire and in in this
year i've been uh watching and reading
quite a lot you know and doing wufang
language as you know my wolfram language
tutorial is now kind of complete it's
kind of complete okay
so i've been reading uh and watching a
lot of stefan wufang you know and let me
finish one thing at a time okay so
let's talk about
uh wolfen language
so i want to show you my tutorials
because um
okay so wolfram language tutorial so you
go there just search for the wolfram
language tutorial you'll find it okay
you'll you'll find my home page for
wufang language website then you will
see you know several videos uh and then
i have completed some of the
uh you know wolf i'm like you know some
of the introduction these are fantastic
okay last time i forgot to mention in my
past uh video the the one before i
forgot to mention wufang language my
tutorial gives you a in-depth
understanding of language the technology
how it works
you know so this wufam language tutorial
okay this one and uh also this one
wufang language syntax okay you go read
them
i would claim you know so these two i
would claim would be better than any
wufam language tutorial out there you
know wolfham website has lots of
tutorials and actually stefan wolfe
himself has written a book
you know uh
you know he wrote many books but uh but
about four years ago he wrote a new one
introduction to wufam language
and in my opinion mine is even better
for understanding wolfram language okay
for a beginning tutorial for
understanding how the wolfram language
works
so
so this tutorial is good for
uh let me show you where okay so here so
this tutorial is good for
programmers you guys okay if you are
already a programmer and you want to
start you know you came from python ruby
javascript java c
c plus plus c sharp or even haska you
came from those backgrounds and this and
you want to study ufam language you know
in my opinion it's a magnitude beyond or
uh today you know there's not nothing
like it
so you want to start to learn with a
language so
and you and as a programmer you want to
master it master it i mean you want to
understand how it works so that whatever
you learned is like provides a
fundamental core idea the the the
the core ideas that allows you to
understand the language like you don't
need to read every every page of the
tutorial so once you get the idea you
get it
then you can um
you have you
you know once you you know the core
principles of language you can do a lot
programming you know so similar to unix
for example the unix philosophy you know
you kind of you know
kind of you know so once you get kind of
the philosophy well that's philosophy of
unix you
you will uh get further ahead without
you know you will be more efficient in
using unix for example that's not a
great analogy but anyway so in this
tutorial i teach you about wolfen
language okay
so you go read it okay this is a talk
show but you go read but anyway i want
to tell you about these uh two videos i
watched
uh two weeks ago okay
fantastic amazing okay
these two videos
now wolfram
stephen wolfen he is you know he's a
well-known you know
award-winning
genius a certified genius because when
he was 18 he won he's the youngest
person to want the
author awards you know he published when
he was 19. you know he got a phd and
published in physics journals when he's
19 also and he created he wrote you know
he's one of the wolf he's the creator of
wufan language he's coded it's written
in c
so he you know he
he he implemented this pattern matching
symbolic pattern matching which is kind
of a lisp lisp and api symbolic pattern
matching language back in 1989 so
you know so he's uh um so i really uh
and you know
so he has the
he he you know he is a well regarded uh
computer scientist and i i particularly
admire the way he see things okay so
anyway i want to tell you so in the past
so here he's he's already accomplished
you know accomplished
programmer and uh
and uh physicist okay but
but he's pretty old you know he's 60
like some 60 something years old okay
now
you know but however there's a lot of
things he doesn't know you know he
actually there's a lot of things he
doesn't know because today's technology
you know the sciences is like go growing
expos exponentially so he's got a lot of
opinions on ai on machine learning on
cellular traumatic physics and so on but
there's a lot of things he doesn't know
and
and what are they for example for
example category theory
proof systems
uh category proof systems um you know
the kind of modern
modern development in the past uh let's
say 20 years you know he's busy with his
uh things his ideas but there are
certain
uh
fields in math he
does not know much you know
so in this video this is a wolf and
physics project let me let me play a
little bit so you can see the nature you
know
uh so this is a wolfram physics project
and this this guy is this guy is
spectacular okay he's a young star
jonathan gorad
so you guys have a question so uh do you
have do you like uh why do you like
mathematics passion or just job
requirement passion okay passion
do you have listened to stefan and
and lex friedman podcast yes i've seen
that one but lex friedman is the
greatest idiot on earth lex friedman
you know if you search saudi youtube go
to youtube go to sunday youtube search
search for saudi ai okay video search
you will find an episode of talk show
where i talked about lex freeman he's a
idiot okay extreme idiot
i have no respect for him whatsoever
well i have no respect for whatever his
intellectual
uh doings idiot lex friedman and he
tries you know he tries to be the host
you know he he tried to be now he's a
youtube star like joe rogan joe rogan is
also a great is one of the greatest
idiot joe rogan he so lex friedman is
like joe rogan doing interviews of every
fame other famous people you know anyway
i don't respect lex friedman okay
so
good evening alan so let me finish this
uh what i'm saying so i was watching
wolf and uh you know wolfram's physics
project stefan wufab so in this episode
so the title is walking session wolf and
physics project working session uh
november 2nd 2021 uh you know a few
weeks ago so i was watching it bit so
this is two hours and 30 minutes so in
this entire basically the entire video
stanford and wolfen
uh you know the the jonathan uh garad is
kind of the one of the you know
co-founder of the wolfram physics
project apparently they met you know and
um
i don't know their history but
you know it seems like stefan wufang
likes him and so they
kind of collaborated
so so in this whole video so my point
the the thing i want to tell you about
this video is fantastic okay i highly
recommend you watch it and both of them
so you can find these videos just by go
to star math blog okay so in in this the
first video will find basically
basically jonathan
is explaining lots of the modern
category theory and proof theory
like the modern uh foundation to stefan
wufab you know it's a big topic because
those topics you can you know you can
study four years to get a phd for but
anyways so
in this uh two hours and two hours and
thirty minutes video stefan wufang is
basically asking a lot of questions
and jonathan is explaining jonathan is
an amazing guy you know he's a young
you know a star a young star
uh he is a um
i'm not sure he's already a professor
you know he's a you know
you know the one of the top uh
researcher in
math foundation in and uh
proof systems uh homogeneity type theory
category theory types theory um
you know the logic and set theory you
know he's one of the
experts you know
in the modern take of these subjects
and in fact so the first video jonathan
jonathan garage apparently he just
published a
paper you know in in in the prestige
math journals about a a kind of a new
take on the meaning of real numbers you
know
so anyway in this video
jonathan is explaining all these things
you know all these topics category
theory topos you know model theory to
stefan woofer and stephen wolf
looks like a kid in this video i mean
he's already
very accomplished but he doesn't know
much about these topics so he keeps
asking questions in jonathan jonathan
it's amazing it's amazing you know he
just explained the thing and so it's
amazing to me personally
very much too because very much so
because i i watched the whole video and
i learned so much things i you know i i
started to have a passing interest in
category theory you know i don't like
you know i you know i don't usually i
treat them as like you know fat in
fashions but anyway
i you know i know about category theory
since 1990s you know there are several
books very popular anyway my point is
that i i learned a lot from
uh this video you know from stefan
wolfham you know on other things but in
this particular video uh the star is
jonathan garad
uh i learned some so so many things
about you know
what is toppo's theory okay toppos
category theory i mean i mean you
you learn them just because
this is informal okay so this is not a
like traditional lecture where you know
they define things and so on no it's not
like that it's rather kind of just like
me chatting fun
but i watch them so they go over things
and all these theories so immediately i
get so much
i learned so much from from uh their
talk okay
uh
especially you know especially the way
stefan wolfram you know stephen wolfman
he has particular personality in
or
particular uh perspective on seeing
things for example what does he think
about computer science what does the you
know each each you know mathematician
you know uh or physicist or whatever or
computer scientist for example donald
knuth
they all have their particular take you
know when they explain things you know
you they have their style so stefan
wolfham has his a very particular style
when it comes to you know physics or
computer science so
usually if i may summarize usually he
likes to say so what like when he's when
he when you know when he
you know
touches on something he doesn't know
he doesn't understand understand yet he
will say what is the nature you know
what what is the nature of this thing so
in one sentence explain what is category
theory you know he really pushes on that
you know like in one sentence okay what
is category theory no don't don't give
me the bunch of jargons crap okay just
tell me one sentence what it actually it
is okay he's like that okay
so he so jonathan
uh garad is explaining all these very
advanced topics okay you really if you
really want to know understand them
you'll take few years actually you know
it's not just
you know it one it's not just one
reading you know it takes a few years to
understand what they uh is
actually uh about even
but yeah because to understand them you
actually then you need
you kind of need a uh
familiarity of the entire math history
the foundation of mathematics you know
uh set theory set theory for example why
why why do we need it you know
set theory um
you know the beginning of set theory the
question about real numbers what you
like what do you need no you know what
what do you need but you know uh um
um many jargons okay okay math history
so okay anyway so
so jonathan garad is explaining all
these uh this uh bleeding age leading
edge uh
uh
topics um
related to the foundation of mathematics
okay so stefan wufan
so he's explaining them to stephen ulfah
means stefan wufang pushes for simple
answers like simple answers so and
so they this kind of a dialogue you know
you might say it's like a plateaus
dialogue so it's
uh
tremendously rewarding you know to me
personally
so generous you know so i recommend you
guys watch it if you are interested in
math okay so and then i started to watch
some other videos by jonathan garad and
this one in particular and also it's
amazing so i learned a lot okay that's
what i'm trying to say about these
videos
so alan says joe rogan could beat you at
chuchisu yeah
he certainly can
uh
so an
analytic minded says when i was a child
i dreamed of understanding andrew wiles
proof yes indeed a fermat's last theory
but i think
but i think now that dream will not come
true uh well
i think they can you know uh no you
don't know for sure how old are you you
are not older than me are you
i'm 50 you know i mean my early 50s
and today i can confidently say
i'm you know i i also wanted to
understand andrew wyo's proof of
fermat's last theory you know which
happened i remember it vividly inc when
i was in college
1992 or 1993 okay then there's certainly
a big news andrew wyatt andrew wiles you
know format formats last theorem has
been proven by andrew wilde you know
1993. i remember it vividly while i was
in college
and i remember you know i was taking
statistics
uh a course on statistics by a guy
mcneal i think that's a professor mcniel
i remember i still remember he you know
that professor
so
you know back then i was so much into
math so i remember that and i really
want to understand it uh but
it never happened you know they then
then the marilyn
the marilyn's savant who
is you know
has the highest iq as recorded by
guinness you know the guinness
organization you know she she wrote a
book
uh trying to explain you know the
andrew wiles proof of fermat's last
theory that's all beyond me okay i i
read i actually bought the book i read
read it i don't i don't think i actually
read the whole thing but anyway it's
kind it's kind of beyond me
but
but what's amazing is that you know in
the past few years i started to do math
again i mean mostly just reading reading
wikipedia wikipedia is amazing today so
i just walk around read wikipedia you
know for a
few hours a day
in the past like in the past three years
i've been for four or three years i've
been doing that
and i would you know it's amazing so so
what i'm saying trying to say is that
you know i i was thinking oh that's
hopeless you know i'm i'm done for okay
as far as i always wanted to be a great
you know
at least one of the great mathematician
that i'm done for
there's no hope for that
but however in the past few years i
studied you know i read a lot math and
especially in the past two years i i
learned tremendously like all the things
suddenly uh made sense to me you know
topology and
uh many of these ideas so
so i would say you know honestly that
today
if i keep doing you know if i keep
continuing continue pushing for you know
reading of two hours uh
mathematics i'm confident to say i will
be able to understand that
andrew wiles proof of format's last
theory
i'm pretty confident yeah so
so um i i think you know this is not to
say you know oh you uh you know this is
just i mean this is just to say that you
you mathematics of course you have to be
you know
you have to be you know
smart in some some at least a little bit
okay you you you cannot be an idiot you
know to do math but but you have to just
keep keep doing it you know
so that's what i'm saying so i i find it
uh amazing uh
uh one thing i what i i hope to do is to
understand
uh you know uh understand modern proof
theory uh for example exactly what
stefan wolfram and jonathan garat is
talking about
the modern proof theory you know
especially in particular hormatabee type
theory okay
and i you know i i would say i
understand i i learned a lot you know
i feel that yeah so
highly recommend to you guys i hope
that's uh you know
inspirational
justin scarfie just since just
justin scarify the mathematician the
professional mathematician from canada
are you a professor yet i asked you that
many times you don't
i don't think maybe you told me before
but you never answered are you like a
professor now
but anyway justin scott
scarfa is a professional mathematician
of course you understand it otherwise
and us and in particular that's your
field right that's your fear that's yeah
that's really that's your field of study
justin's got
scar fi amazing character
i'm glad you are here thank you for
watching
talk show
so alan says how is going alan and how
is your live stream
uh
you know so alan has been doing live
stream about technology and society
um
the scott the star cell nutritional
supplements so we so we don't have to be
idiot in math
so uh uh yeah that you know
um
so my thing is is is you know it's
very interesting but of course it's not
for everyone
uh
so i think actually you know we don't
have a topic here and i think maybe
that's it for today you know maybe 10
more minutes so what's up guys what else
so yeah anyway i want to say
i truly enjoy these two videos so watch
it okay um
you know so also i want you know so
maybe this is an inspirational uh
talk about math maybe so because i want
to say is that even if you don't you
know if maybe you are a teenager you
know maybe you just you know you don't
you didn't study calculus yet but
you know but but you have an interest in
math
so i would say even if you don't
understand just just watch it you know
watch the whole
um
it will get to you because by repetition
that's one way to um get it
uh how does lex friedman get a big
audience of course he interviewed inter
you know uh celebrities
you know for example me you interested
in ai uh you know machine learning
programming languages you know he
interests he interviews celebrities
so even if he's an idiot you know lex
friedman i don't you know i don't like i
don't think you know i think he's an
idiot yeah so but that's not a point
people still watch his show because he's
actually you know people are going to
his show to watch the other person he's
interviewing and
in that regard
you know you know perhaps in that regard
that's why he's a youtube star you know
he's a star youtube star and you know he
makes a lot of money a reasonable amount
i suppose and he
you know he's successful you know
you know at least he is a successful
youtube star
but yeah but i don't you know but you
know i think you know every every when
he does interview he interview other you
know interesting people for example he's
done that with stephen wolfman
uh and a lot and few others i've seen
you know he
i don't i don't like his show he
actually made the subject idiotic just
like joe rogan you know just you know
joe rogan this idiot whenever he
interviews some you know he interviewed
a lot of people celebrities you know
not not not in tech of course but uh
politicians uh
you know the basketball stars kung fu
stars or whatever martial arts stars you
know he interviewed a lot you know
jordan peterson and a lot lots of people
celebrities you know
and and whenever you know whenever joe
you know joey rogan's interview whenever
the guy is actually saying something
interesting that i'm really into
interested in their opinion then the joe
rogan idiot
he redirect the conversation to
something entirely
an interesting [ __ ] idiot joe rogan
[ __ ]
but you know jeroga is a as is he he's
now as obedient you know a
multi-billionaire or you know me you
know 100 you know he
is a superstar youtube
okay
it's about joe rogan so um what else is
interesting
uh okay um so okay so nothing nothing
any any guy anyone alan anything
so um
i think maybe that's it okay uh so
wolfham language you you guys go out
there
get it for free
or buy it
and read my tutorial okay the greatest
language okay let's close that let's put
that here i talked about
uh what else okay famous emacs users so
today
so i have a page about famous emacs
users so here's donald gluth
of course
pretty much the older traditional
computer scientists yeah i mean the old
computer scientists they are all uh
emacs users so trump he's here's donald
grunt screen he's very old now 80 or 90.
uh julian assange
happens also to be a emacs user in fact
he has contributed he has written
a emax package back in uh back in when
uh back in 1980
uh wait do i have a date i must i have
the date somewhere anyway so here's the
julian assange and with richard stowman
and here's a detail of his package
uh
where is the um
anyway i have a date here somewhere okay
so julian assange oh you know he's also
an emacs user
okay so then
uh
the mad sky the guy who created ruby
he's also an emacs user uh in fact he
did a talk about it he won a word from
richard stowman the
the free software foundations award you
know the libra planet conference
whatever so
ruby okay ruby is
the lineage of ruby the language is
pearl and
imaglisp okay that's a lineage of ruby
uh so then guido von rossum he's also an
e-max user yeah i don't like that guido
though he but he's an emac user and
jonathan blow
this is a kind of young young celebrity
you know the millennial generation
celebrity
jonathan below he's he's famous for the
game braids you know he made the game
and he is now creating his own language
jai language the jai language is
supposed to be you know i don't know
much about it but
you know from i read you know a little
bit it's
i read you know from his video he's
supposed to be like
he wants you know he wants a new
language that's better than c plus plus
okay
okay so what is this inductive jai okay
so that's a
so there's a wikipedia i believe on
child language or maybe not
so anyway
he want to create a new language you
know replacing c plus plus c plus plus
you know is the standard language to
program games and games is his bread and
butter so jonathan um
so wait wait wait is my
uh so jonathan
the jonathan this guy so let's let's
view
the whole thing full glory so wait
yeah
okay so anyway so you know he's also
he's using imac he wanted to create a
sea plus first replacement
and he looked at
you know he looked at rust he looked at
golan
uh you know he don't think those are
good candidates or at least he he wanted
something else because one of his
criticism i mean one of his the reason
he he
thinks we he needs a new line jai
because he believes that all these
languages golan rust they are trying to
create a language
that prevents
or make it impossible for people to
write bad code
for example memory management for
example in golan it just eliminates
eliminates it you know
this c c plus plus d drink idiots no you
cannot do that at all in golem you know
just wipe it out there's no this you
know you you don't you don't manage your
memory okay it's automatic let's go let
go land philosophy which i like i like
golem very much i think golan is the
best one of the best language
for c you know for kind of low level
tasks golem
uh on the on the other hand rust you
know rust is also a low level language
but the first idea is that
okay you want you you want dealing you
know you want teaching with memory or
inflow and that kind of [ __ ] yeah you
are you sure sure you know
you should be able to do that but you
know that's a worse idea however
we are going to provide you with several
you know means to prevent you from
shooting yourself
on the foot you know that's a typical
thing you see sleepless plus people like
to say hey we started to add more people
um so anyway so
so rust is kind of complex language low
level but it's designed to prevent you
from doing bad things as or at least
they say
but jonathan below below his idea is
that okay yeah
okay he doesn't buy those philosophy he
believes a language you should be able
to
shoot yourself in the foot okay so you
don't want you know in his idea from
what i know is that he wants to create a
language where
you know
where the programmer who knows the
language well can use it
very well without
the language preventing you from doing
something
okay so that also means it's possible if
you are idiot if you know if you don't
know much about language it's possible
to
uh have to to write a program that
that's very bad
but he believes that the programmer
should have full control
so that's what i understand you know so
he's creating this jai language i don't
know anything about it
uh
which which in my opinion
that's just his opinion okay that's
that's just his opinion in my opinion
mike snotty's opinion you should have a
language that's everything is automated
just like wufang language or golan
depending on what level you want to go
okay
you know don't you know automation like
this this let the compiler figure out
things for you not you didn't dealing
with stuff
i believe that's um of course i believe
that's the future of course but it's a
kind of a degree a spectrum of you know
things that like
like for example the assembly language
or the machine language you know at the
lowest level you you still need them
because you can never do away with them
because the ai or whatever a smart
compiler they are not going to write the
program for you okay that's not going
that's not
going to happen it will never happen
okay many you know today we started to
have a lot of fat and eating you know
idiotic fat that says oh
google whatever is creating you know
they started to have a tool that writes
a code for you no it will not happen
okay maybe they'll do some suggestions
that's it
artificial intelligence this is my
opinion artificial intelligence
intelligence is never going to write
code for you okay for for programmers
for real programmers okay
when
there's one possibility you'll happen
when what one condition that will happen
when artificial intelligence is
is what they say strong ai
that is
the day when artificial
intelligence will kind of replace
programmers is when
artificial intelligence reached the
human consciousness level of
intelligence that is you can check you
can tell the machine to do anything
human can do
in other words
at that level at that level artificial
intelligence will replace any human you
don't need humans anymore
that is when in my opinion that is when
artificial intelligence can write
programs for you can replace programmers
okay
but we don't know we don't know if that
will ever happen okay when that happens
human animals you guys we are done for
kind kind of
when artificial intelligence reaches the
human
you know exact human intelligence level
uh so that's uh that's my opinion so so
jonathan blow
he
okay close that close like back here he
also used emacs
and his apparently so he's doing uh
live streaming live coding
regularly like every week a few times
apparently on on twitch
uh
interesting guy okay i think i like him
uh you know but i
didn't watch a lot of his videos because
i'm i'm too busy with mine
then
simon python jones you know he's so i
also discovered this today so he's uh
also an emacs user because you can see
from his screen you know he's a
he worked he works you know he's a one
of the lead
developer of haskell one of the creators
something like that of haskell haskell
is pretty old but now haskell is uh
25 or something years old okay it began
in
uh 1980s i think
so you know haskell is just he's pretty
old actually so it just got a
um popularity lift around
2008 something like that
you know this new gen you know new kid
in town you know today we have a lot of
programmers oh haska oh monet oh you
sound you need to learn haskar
anyway so haskell is pretty old um and
you know and
simon python jones is one of the primary
designer or something you know it's it's
it's haskell is actually designed by
community okay haskell is not created by
a single person haska was created
when
back in 1980s in academia the concept of
functional programming is undergoing
heavy research
so these academicians you know they
thought why not you know we need a
language so that we can
speak the same thing you know doing
functional programming research so
that's when the haskell idea came up you
know it's a it's created by committee
okay haskell
so anyway so the simon pi python jones
uh
jones you know the the the naming
america you know there's so many
variations
j-o-n-e-s
j-o-h-n john jones or j-o-n
or you know there's a lot of variation
anyway so he he's also imac you say i
wonder who is this
woman
this woman is does anyone know who is
this woman is who is this woman
so you know he is also using so so the
simon python
jones is also using a microsoft uh
natural keyboard and the microsoft mouse
in teddy point
and which which which hiki the closure
creator is he's also a emacs user
yeah you can see it from his video
presentation and joe armstrong the
creator of erlang is also an emacs user
he died he died about five years or so
five years ago
four years ago
yeah he died for four or three years ago
uh joe armstrong
and then other people i don't know quite
well andre alexandre the you know this d
land creator or co-creator he's also
e-mac user stefan wufam i know he's an
e-max user he was a e-max user because
back in 1995 when i was at wolfram
research i've seen he
asked emacs questions
um
and more people okay there's there's
quite a lot of emacs users
okay that's it for today i think
github co-pilot who is that
german molina says what about github
co-pilot who is that
so okay let me add let me and let me
read the questions then that's maybe
that's it for today
uh
joe man molina says it's funny when he
says something like maybe because i'm
russian i'm a romantic
what id the meaning of life
the guy this guy okay i don't know
yeah i don't know much about this guy d
lan
dan crispin hello
hello
so github co-pilot so who is that
i don't know who is that
okay hey uh let's see what else i'm
gonna shut down
uh
44 okay maybe five more minutes so let's
see
if there's something interesting okay
math
category theory you know uh fantastic
okay
you know i in fact in the past few weeks
i started you know because i watched
these videos i started to have a
a grasp
shall we say a grasp of category theory
you know um
anyway so
so let's change your subject okay let's
uh
let's see what else do we how many
people no people
maybe that's it okay so thank you guys
for watching
you you know if you like my stuff buy my
stuff okay
you know donate patreon paypal amazon
gift card or buy my emacs tutorial by my
javascript tutorial and stuff
okay
oh uh lex friedman okay
okay bye guys