good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh we are going to
talk about some programming idioms or
programming and programming languages
and relations programming language and
it's machine so let's go to my computer
blog let's see if I'm live
yes I'm live
that's good okay computer so I wanted to
talk about why array access why is array
obsess constant time now this is a very
very interesting aspect you know when
you have a array for example you know
this if you've been programming for a
while you know that when you have for
example my array and you want to access
it let's say you want let's say VAR x
equals 2 you want to take the 99th
element now compare this to a list you
know typically programming you know they
will teach you in computer science
classes or programming classes they all
say that array access is constant time
random access meaning that you can
access any element in array you know and
the time it takes is small its constant
doesn't matter which element like 99th
or 10 millionth array element ok however
this is a different from the the other
data structure called least typically
called linked lists if you access a
linked list you know if you access the
99th element it will take you know the
the further back your element the
element you want you take longer to
access it
so so array access time it has random
constant random access time but why is
that you know you wonder why is that
because let's see how many people are
watching to say something guys
ok let me modify the date so you wonder
why is that hold on a second let me
modify the tricks on talk-show okay so
you wonder why is that you know first of
all let me tell you what is a
programming language and what is
programming language what is a machine
for the programming language well before
I say that you know just wonder like why
is array access time has constant random
access time you know I have tried to
learn this I struggle to learn this for
like ten years
most of mm you know so not until 2010 or
so
you know I start to understand you see
what what these come to I mean the the
wisest person is that you know a
programming language is basically a
programming source code is pretty much a
recipe okay recipe like cooking you know
it it's basically step-by-step
instructions
that's what algorithm means now now step
by step instructions you have to write
down the instructions you know using
some language for example English when
you know when you are cooking English is
your language you know you could lay
eggs you break the eggs you mixing floor
you're mixing water that's instructions
and instructions
the written instruction must be in some
language so you have a language English
you know for cooking but
of programming that is programming
languages and the source code basically
the you know the recipe book or the
source code your program that is the
recipe that is the algorithm so so you
have two things here you have algorithm
which is a step by step instructions and
you have a programming language which is
the language that these instructions are
written in you need that because for
example to communicate you speak English
or speak Chinese or Russian and so on so
you so you have algorithms which are
instructions you have recipes I mean the
programming language to write down your
recipe your algorithm then you also need
another thing that that thing is the
machine you are operating on for example
when you are cooking mmm when you are
cooking you see when you are cooking you
are doing with things you know you take
eggs you take water you place the eggs
in this bowl you take the water in that
cookware and you put them on stove
those are your equipments I mean those
are the things you work on you know
let's call them machine you know without
that it doesn't make sense because you
have cooking instructions you have
recipes but you see you need to you need
to actually do you know take your hands
you know your hands you know take the
eggs break them put the water here
that's the things you work on so so all
these things you we you know in
programming we call it a machine in a
same way you know another way to easily
understand this this whole programming
concept is with a abacus you know you
might have seen a because
so let's see abacus so abacus is one of
the most primitive computer computer
computing machine so here you have an
abacus this is a japanese-style abacus
you know you you move the beads around
to different positions you know and here
is a oh this is a Chinese style abacus
Chinese style abacus has two rows on top
and he is is a Japanese style abacus
which only has one one blow on top in
Asia in Asia you know in Taiwan and when
I was small we have abacus lessons but
anyway abacus is like a calculator it's
the earliest computer you might say and
what does it do but basically the abacus
is just like stones on the ground you
know basic you know a bunch of stones
you move them you perceive position them
in different ways and you read out you
know it has some meaning to you so the
easiest way to understand programming
and computers is with the abacus so with
abacus you have first of all you have
the machine the machine is the abacus
good morning Isaak
so the app because it's a machine
okay which is like today's CPU okay so
abacus is a machine then you need you
need instructions that is you tell it
what to do you know suppose you want to
add one plus two how do you do it you
know you know you move these speeds here
or you move you push that beats there
you know those are instructions then you
need a programming language which is a
recipe
I mean wait hold on a second the
instructions is the algorithm is the you
know step by step instruction you know
that tells you what to do that's the
algorithm which is your recipe so
algorithm you know recipe they are kind
of the same thing but you need a
programming language which is the
language your wrist recipe is written in
for example for abacus you have for
example manuals you know there are books
that teaches you how to use an abacus so
that's the abacus manual so that is
basically the you can think of it as a
programming language so here we covered
three things the machine you operate on
that's the abacus the programming
language which is you can think of as
the tables in a in a abacus too Toby oh
you know programming language then you
have the actual instructions which is
you know algorithm written down that
tells you exactly how to calculate
something so machine we have machine we
have programming language we have
instructions you know algorithms then
then we also have input and output
that's that's the essential thing you
know input is like what you want to do
you know input you have certain input
coming then you have certain output
it's the input output that makes the
whole thing useful because we you know
we want to add one plus three you know
that's the input we and what is the
answer that is the output you know the
output is the answer we want so you have
input output you know when you have an
input you follow the instructions which
is which is algorithm
you know algorithm that you know that
tells you what to do you operate it on
it and the instructions lock up
algorithm is returning a programming
language you know it tells you what to
then you do it
on the machine which is the in this case
abacus or a bunch of stones you you move
them around
then after that you have the output you
just read you know where the positions
are then you know the answer
good morning George also so okay so so
that's a because so why am i talking
about this because abacus gives you a
very clear understanding what algorithm
means what programming language means
and it also shows you the importance of
a machine you know because there is
always any algorithm any concrete
algorithm requires a machine because if
you look at the arabic abacus you all
know if you just have instructions
without machine what does it mean that
you can you know instructions is you
know step by step operations on a
machine you know so that is why it's
important because when we program in
Python for example Python lists or
JavaScript
we usually forgot we forget the CPU
because today is things are very
complicated you have compilers you have
machine language you have you know CPU
and nobody you know a few people
actually understand how CPU works
you know it's billions of billions of
transition transistors in electronics
but so when we today's programmers when
you know when you program Python one
plus two you know you don't think of
machine you know like where is a machine
you just you know print one plus two and
you know three comes out you know but it
when you want to understand computer
science when you try to when you take
into the details of programming
languages you know there are programming
language design programming language
programming idioms
you know programming styles the
semantics of programming languages all
these things beast versus array which we
are going to talk about today when you
talk about programming actually it's
important to realize there is always a
machine behind it you know machine can
be there all type of machine
abacus is one machine today's CPU is one
machine there are so many different
types you know as you know you have arms
a RMS kind of architectures CPU you have
Intel CPU you know i5 i7 and so you have
the AMD CPU then you have GPU you know
gets more complicated but anyway all
those are different machines I mean
those are practical machines we are
using but you know but then there's also
abstract machines like to me machine
there to mean tapes you know you might
have heard of and you know Turing
machine cellular automata state machines
register machines you know those are
kind of more abstract or even lambda
calculus you can think of it as a
machine so so so yeah so remember there
are three things when we program there's
a machine is a programming language
where the instruction is written in you
know and then there is the algorithm
algorithm is just the actual instruction
now why do we need the programming
language because you need to write it
down like when I write to a letter to
you you know it may be Chinese or
English it's written down so that that
is why so that is what programming
languages are now when you look at this
way you understand that they are
different programming languages you know
they are actually different because you
know it's almost like natural languages
they are different because there are
different ways to express same thing you
know for example so that's why there are
different programming languages and you
can also see you know by this you know
since we are looking at the whole thing
in this way you can also see okay so
algorithms you know they're you know
algorithms are step-by-step instructions
in a specific programming
language you know the language is
written in you know a source code where
you read and it is for specific machine
you see all these three things are tied
together there can never be a like you
know abstract algorithm or generic
algorithm actually that doesn't exist
because the very nature the very
definition of an algorithm or
step-by-step instruction is actually to
you know to operate to work on things
you know and these operations are
expressed in a programming language so
machine programming language algorithms
they are all tied together they must be
concrete you know basically they all
eventually rely on a specific machine
the machine can be your turning tape can
be you know CPUs today's CPUs a specific
CPU can be of abstract you know state
machines register machines and so on
it's important to realize this because
when you are you know when you dive into
programming language design seems in
stuff it's important to know this so but
today we are going to talk about array
you know you see when we programmer you
know with we we we learn that array has
random you know constant random access
time but why is that you know why why
you know for example let me let me try
to explain why this interesting is quite
you know this is interesting question
because now because array is a
programming language construct so we can
you know let's try to put the whole
thing the whole array concept into the
abacus or into let's say let's go
primitive and into some a bunch of
stones on the on the floor you know
let's say we have 10 stones okay ten of
them we put it on our desk you know on
the on the floor and let's say our
is is a machine so we can take this
stone you know maybe think of the stone
as abacus you know like we can we can
move over here
this column and move push this stone up
and they move to another column pushes
tongue up you know and so on so what is
array array is a you know list of items
that each item holds a value you know
but let's just think of the stones on
the ground you know let's just think
like the abacus you know so we move our
hand to here you push something and we
move here and push them push another
stone so why is that you know how is it
possible when you have you know
something like array 99 or a knife for
example somehow it's like constant time
I mean I mean if you think about abacus
obviously you know doesn't matter which
position it's not constant constant time
you know your hand doesn't magically
disappear from here and up here there
you know each you know there's a
distance involved you see so so anyway
so there are a lot of explainin on on
the webpage or even in textbooks they
are in my opinion they are kind of all
wrong they don't they don't cover the
heart of the thing okay let me show you
okay why is a ray obsessed time constant
let's go to Wikipedia you know we
compete here you think you would trust
Wikipedia let's let's say what Wikipedia
is how how does Wikipedia explain things
okay so let's go to Wikipedia array
again remember the thing we are trying
to understand explain the topic is why
is array has constant time random access
why our list you know yeah why why is
the Rhea's constant time random access
time so let's see Wikipedia
okay Wikipedia is now it's like a bunch
of articles now okay an array is a
systematic arrangement of similar
objects usually in rows and columns
okay that's music science biology
computer science okay
Wikipedia is getting more and more
complicated so now it has a rate data
structure a rate data type and
associative array okay the one we want
is a readiness stroke structure you know
Wikipedia is actually really improving
because because when I dig into computer
you know I studied this kind of things I
I do realize you know I do see it's
actually improving incredibly in the
past 20 years every year you know I
because I check it every year
let's see let's see if I'm still going
okay so Wikipedia you know because many
things I I was confused you know I see
there's a confused confusion in the
popular generation you know after a few
years I see Wikipedia actually cover it
because one of the one of the thing I
mean I think there's a major difference
confusion is a read data structure
versus array data type exactly now
you see now wikipedia has actually two
articles distinct from each other they
are not the same thing because when we
program programmers there's there's a
turns of a confusion you know after it's
not until after ten years
you you actually start to see okay these
two things they are totally different
that's why you know so many people or
you get confused in you know back then
anyway a rate data structure in and
array data type in programming languages
they they are distinct concept anyway
let's go to and this is also why when
you talk to programmers you know like we
have arguments about programming online
you know hacker news or other way you
know online forum a stack overflow for
example Stack Overflow there are tons of
questions usually they are confusions
you know like we say you know oh you
should use an array or you know you
should not use an array but actually
different people have different concept
of array because array itself have
different meaning in each different
languages like for example JavaScript
array it's not really a weight you know
it's not data already not have it's like
it depends on how you you know
javascript is very complex you know
sometimes it's actually just a hash
table you know javascript array and you
have PHP array in PHP means entirely
different thing then you know array in
PHP is kind of a mix between again its a
mix between hash table and array okay
it's kind of a like hash table where the
keys are numbers okay same thing with
JavaScript they are actually hash table
where the keys are numbers you know but
Python Python array is is kind of a true
array you call it smart array extensible
array okay and you know you know so in
but in Lisp arrays actually called for
example in email
miss array is actually called vector so
you know different languages you have
that you have different jargons you know
they use the same jargon but mean
different things and even the actual
things in these languages are not the
same when we when you know when we are
you know typically when programming when
programmer you know when programming
textbooks or tutorials to speak of array
what they mean is they typically mean
the array data structure as in C
languages on rate the data structure
okay so let's go to this article array
data structure let's see if they you
know if they explain why constant you
know how a reg random has constant
random access time so he says in
computer science an irregular structure
or simply an array is the data data
structure consisting of a collection of
elements each identified by at least one
array index or key okay an array is
stored such that the position of each
element can be computed from its index
Topo by a mathematical formula okay the
simplest type of data structure is
linear array also called one dimensional
array okay it it gets complex so it says
the array on array is stored such that
the position of each element can be
computed from its index terpil by a
mathematical formula well right this is
a bad definition the memory address of
the first element of an array is called
first address or foundation address okay
it's this gets complicated because it's
getting into kind of implementation
but let's see
yeah it's kind of getting it's
complicated but actually it is rather
very complicated to actually define to
give a definition of what an array is
anyway you can see here they show the
algorithmic so-called algorithmic
complexity about array access which
means you know how fast you know the you
know the time properties of getting
elements or setting elements you know
comparison with other data structures
linked list array dynamic array okay
balance tree okay so on anyway
yeah the Wikipedia article is getting
complicated
but okay but let me just tell you why
then let me just tell you why why
accessing array is actually constant
time well the real reason is because
electronic circuits it's it's just so
happens okay it so happens array in
modern CPU okay again remember computer
programming languages and algorithms
source code for me language and machine
the machine it operates on are tied
together so when we talk about about
array we are talking about today's CPUs
so array in in almost all programming
languages today they are implemented it
just so happens that the CPU they are in
you know the way they it's done is by a
memory chip and the electronic circuit
and it so happens that when you access
an array the CPU instructions you know
it is simply put is just parallel
electronic circuits you know so it's
kind of like parallel computing like we
you know in a circuit you have you know
you
you know you have all these wires going
in and and and they are the wires are
wires in such a way that they are not
like you know checking checking one
element at a time you know better it's
like you know also cat going at one time
and come out like eight one eight of
them is eight bits or 16 bits or 32 bits
at one time and I come up and that is
why array obsess random it has constant
access time okay that is it so so this
is very curious this is very interesting
because this is not you know so what I'm
saying is that you know this array
access time it has nothing to do with
mathematical properties of algorithms at
all and you know because we don't think
of that way because no normally for
example when you program in Python Java
Ruby or whatever for example if you are
doing your loop you know you know you go
through each element and you can you
know you talk about algorithmic
complexity you know how fast you know
how much how fast is this function or
loop or how much memory it takes you
know you analyze it you know you know
because each each statement you make you
know x equals to something you know it's
a step so you have to measure how many
steps you are taking that's how you
measure you know the algorithmic
complexity of an algorithm or function
but when it comes to array this is
interesting because you have array 99
but however it's like it's it's it's
instantaneous like you don't have to
jump 99 steps you know it's actually
just one step somehow but however for a
list you know for for a list for example
if you have a list here then then the
story is entirely different easy
like suddenly you have to jump 99 steps
but meanwhile there you know the code
for example myarray for example the code
is entirely different my array for
example in whatever language is is let's
say 1 2 3 ok let's say chain ok so here
we have you see we can generate an array
by this syntax or we can generate the
list by this syntax you know different
language has different you know
functions to generate a rail list so
this is what we are doing you know we
see this and it looks almost exactly
similar but however so what I'm saying
is that you do not see the algorithmic
steps in the code you know it's not
apparent but suddenly but you know this
code looks similar it's you know it's
not like when you have a list you
actually have a loop you know it's you
know you don't see it here but however
when it comes to this part suddenly they
are entirely different you know the
algorithmic properties are entirely
different so that's that's that's that's
what I'm saying about this thing about
this the strange strangeness about these
non-apparent
nests of algorithmic complexity ok that
that's that's it for that maybe that's
it for today depending on how are you
guys doing so Isaac and George five
people so guys say something so so let's
go back let's see what we want to talk
about this may be other interesting
things let's see
keyboard review gallery what is this
Oh PC keyboard reviews okay let's go to
providing blog so today I just actually
operations operators control so array
obsess constant time but yeah so this
this is a very interesting question to
me it's me there's something I'm let's
see if I there's something I want to say
about this yeah so I anyway that that
that is the issue I want to say you know
like if you go online online you know
let's say you know all the answers
online is basically wrong because I've
been trying to understand these for 10
years for example let's say Y array has
constant time you know let's say you
type that and see what others say
why does accessing an array element
takes constant time so this is on Cora
now Cora is not really good quality so
here another question on Stack Overflow
why does accessing my element array
takes constant time okay so let's check
some of the answers you know I bet they
are just they are just so this guy on
Cora says before I answer it completely
know that array linked list map set act
everything that you program creates
would be in ran during your program
execution
that means ran part is ruled out what
okay then array the fundamental concept
here is that the elements of an array
are stored in contiguous memory location
okay it is this guarantee that guarantee
that makes array obsess constant
yeah so he's talking about memory yeah
in general if I know the base address of
array I for example a zero I would get
the address of an arbitrary element in
array a I by simply doing address of you
know precise you see yeah okay that's
basically what he's saying so easy is
because it's in it is stored in
contiguous memory location but that
doesn't explain nothing the you see that
doesn't explain you know so what do you
mean conditioned it you contiguous
memory so the real answer is that this
memory address because of the circuit
and electronics because the computer way
computer are designed you know you have
six six six sixteen bits architecture or
32 bits architecture they operate
something like that it's because the
parallel nature of the electronic
circuit okay okay so let's look at the
stack overflow and so let's see what
they say so what does accessing Iron Man
you know array it takes constant time
answer just to be complete what
structure is accessed in linear time
okay
linked list structure is accessing
linear time okay an array is more
similar to an hard disk every point it
is accessible in constant time this is
the reason the RAM of a computer is
called RAM random access memory you can
go to any location if you know it's
address without traversing all the
memory okay yeah so it again he just say
it's because it's in RAM you know random
access memory the memory chip yeah but
it doesn't say why it is why it is that
way you know so
yeah
so anyway so the first time I actually
found the great answer to this question
is this guy this guy by ying wong he
wrote a blog about it
why array you know why is indexing
faster than binary search you know so he
talked about the issue that answered you
know that really answered my question
you know I had this question for like 10
years and in his blog he actually showed
you the circuit design you know because
you know because in the past when you
know because if you think of array you
know if you think you know array like
the code we have before you know if you
look at them as you know if you think if
you try to answer the question by
thinking that it's some sort of
mathematical property you know it's
because math you know because algorithms
because you know algorithmic complexity
you know because of math that is why
array access time is constant if you
think you know if you try to think of
that way that is wrong you see so that
that is why it's a great puzzle the real
answer is that it has nothing to do with
math in a sense it has nothing to do
with math rather it's just because it so
happens that the memory circuit is
implemented in parallel that is why hi
Otto good morning so I think that's it
about this array access yeah so this is
the first time I understand this is you
know I saw a clear explanation inspire
disguise block by the way he this guy in
in Wong Wang Ying he is a very
controversial guy and he's very
well-known in
one of the most well-known blogger and
you know he always he constantly write
you know blogs with opinions that are
you know completely controversial you
know okay and many of his blogs are City
how so Isaac you also you also read
Chinese I sack wait Isaac you are in Los
Angeles right and I was like you are
American born Chinese right so you want
to write Chinese
so okay that's about array okay let's go
let's go
so today I actually kind of reorganized
some of these bunch of articles on my
website so you have these articles
programming language design issues the
ontology of programming language a class
of computer languages math languages and
you have the other topic a bunch of
articles about programming idioms in
style
and another bunch of articles under the
group grouped title of programming
languages and their machines so these
articles are related to programming or
programming language issues that that
are actually has to do with the machine
yet operate operation and today's
example about array access is one of the
article you know it's you know it has to
do with the CPU
so so anyway so if you're interested you
know you know read this article
programming language and it's machine so
so I don't know much about CPU
I never program was never a systems
programmer systems programmers means
those people who write Hardware firmware
you know you know who write programs
programs that's embedded on the hardware
chips or those people who write drivers
you know for mouse keyboard or who write
Linux you know operating systems those
kind of kind of programming you call
system programming and you use languages
like C sometimes C++ or sometimes colon
to program those kind of thing or
assembly languages sometimes so this you
know systems programming usually means
that your program must run very fast
extremely fast for example if you write
the operating system you know because
everything else depends on top of it it
must be very fast and also it it is very
low level you know so you know you deal
with machines itself you know the memory
locations you have to do that kind of
thing so that's kind of system
programming that's what so-called
systems programming or low-level
programming and I I don't have any
experience in that including assembly
language so you have machine language
assembly language and you know then you
have C you know and so on so I never
have much experience so I about that and
I don't know much about that but in
recent you know in the past few years
five years I try to learn something
about it
you know and that's tremendously I
learned a lot so so you know check out
this article programming language and
it's machine you're learning if you know
if you don't know about systems
programming you might learn a lot of
thing
you know something from my perspective
my experience is mostly for math for
mathematics
you know nothing with Oh Thea reticle
computer science or math you know that's
my that's most that's my interest in my
background well my experience my
experience is mostly web web
applications web programming I was
working for back-end server servers and
websites you know so but my interest is
mostly theoretical computer science and
algorithms mathematics mostly
mathematics so the way I look at things
so I don't have much experience with
systems programming but it's very
interesting though so you know you check
out this article you will see my
perspective on it you know there's a lot
about it about CPU design and it's you
know it's an entire field and and it's
like it's not just it's it's you know
entire field in but it's actually like
so fundamental because you know all the
programs the machines we run they need a
CPU and you know these corporations
Intel you know AMD IBM they design the
chips they the machine controls I mean
it's not like for my point of view from
high-level point of view you know math
point of view I'm always interested in
algorithm so elegance of programming
languages language design programming
language design you know functional
programming versus object-oriented
programming you know different styles
which one is more you know you can
analyze it you know you know math you
know or lambda calculus so you know but
however you I realized that many of the
programming languages you know these
high level programming language issues
they you know the CPU actually dictates
what your language can
be you know so this ties to what we've
talked about today about you know
programming language about a machine
first of all you need the hardware a
machine a specific machine you know
different machines you know you need a
machine then you have a programming
language then you have the algorithm so
instructions the actual source code or
recipe you know a machine programming
language then the recipe or source code
or algorithms these three things mix up
you know the whole programming and these
three things are intimately tied
together I mean so forget about the
general idea concept of algorithms like
almost that it doesn't exist even if you
say one plus two you know when we say
one plus two we think obviously the
answer is three there is no machine
involved but actually there is because
when you say one plus three the machine
is actually a mathematical model then
you go into a set theory you know you
know the foundation of math there is
basically you are working with a
abstract machine the set theory you have
the concept of one then you have a
concept of two then you have the concept
of addition you know instead theory
terms which which means you you know to
take the next elements and you know
anyway so that's math point of so when
even if you say one plus two you are
working you know that's a instruction
let's say algorithm and you you know you
write it down in math notation which is
the programming language you know one
plus two then the machine is actually
set theory
you know that's math so but normally we
don't think of it you know we don't
think of it as you know doing your
machine we just say one plus two you
know or print print five you know but
actually the much it's important to
always have a machine to think of a
machine so the machine and a programming
language and the algorithm or source
code is actually they are intimately
hi together and and mostly you you
cannot just design you know I'm going to
design my own programming language
that's better than a scowl you cannot do
that I mean because when you do that
actually the Machine actually dictates
what programming language you can have
or what kind of programming languages
you can have or what kind of programming
languages so what can what actually it
tells it controls the machines the
fundamental thing you know that's that's
what I learned the machine the CPU the
CPU architecture you know although we
can generalize a lot of it but actually
it is the machine that controls what
programming languages you can have what
kind of design you can have because then
then from your programming language it
controls what kind of problems it can
solve so that the CPU is actually
fundamental and you know so let me talk
about what different kind of machines so
machines we can have calculus we can
have you know different type of CPU
Intel i5 you know or C on architecture
or arms processor and all different sort
of machines then we have Turing machine
we have state machines we have you know
silver automata all these different
machines and we can also have you know
you know today we have quantum computer
that is a machine you know content
computer and you know like I said before
what machines you have governs what kind
of programming language you have and
internal governs what kind of algorithms
or the recipes you know all the problems
you actually solve with it so when you
have a quantum machine
you don't program it with Python you
don't forget with Python or Lisp or
whatever you have a specific programming
language for quantum computers color
computers is a machine and we also have
you know biological based computer
like DNA machines you know dia machines
you know that's you throw a bunch of
molecules you know it's amazing you just
throw a bunch of molecules think of
molecules as some sort of marbles you
know you so you know billions of them
being a box and they automatically you
know arrange themselves you know paint
you know let one to each other and
that's the answer you know they do it
automatically by itself billions upon
billions of them you know that's what
DNA computing is about and so that's
your machine so in this case you don't
program it it with Python you know you
have special language for it
so anyway I think that's about what I'm
saying about the machines and languages
ok so let's see what we need to look at
the comment a Z
hello a Z a Z says you are pregnant are
you serious hey Z so you are a female so
Sean says Sean
Panthera good morning gonna check that
out
systems are mysteries to me so and Sean
says seems like the machines is like a
box it has the size you can overfill it
some boxes are larger than others the
size of box dictates its contents yeah
you can say that but it's more than size
though because you know we have to I
mean as far as analogy goes you know
because almost all these machines we've
talked about they do have a size too you
know like CPU have you know didn't
different number pins or or an abacus
can have you know different number of
columns you know
so all these machines do have a size as
part of their
as you know aspect of property but they
differ in many so many other ways so
anyway I think that's about it so in
guys so easy easy this easy girl easy
woman so you are a girl you are pregnant
how did you find me how did you find my
channel that's interesting because
usually my channel followed by just
nerds so are you also a programmer or so
yeah so that's so yeah that's the the
thing I want to talk about so you go to
my website that's under semantic noodle
and yeah I did some organization you
know like I wrote these articles in 20
years you know I wrote a meanness in a
span of 20 years yes it's 2000 and you
know I have so many articles and usually
they are chaotic you know they are you
know it takes tremendous time to
actually group them like you know this
set of essays are related to this
category of topic you know you have to
reread them you know it's really tedious
and usually and also another interesting
thing is that when you read a blog
sometimes when you write a blog they
don't fit you know and blog article they
don't fit into a particular category
like they talk about something here but
they also talk about some other things
over there in that category so you know
part of it is a tutorial about how for
example how to you how do you create an
array then part of it talk about you
know something about the design of a
computer and programming language you
know so so yeah array I mean blogs blogs
blog the nature of blogs the nature of
blogs is very different
from tutorial and also very different
from an essay actually so you know
because when you have an essay usually
it's a focused on particular topic when
you write a blog blog is like the is a
bottom it's a you know it's very loose
you can be anything you can be it can be
what you ate today like you know I mean
yeah and also different like the style
can be very sloppy it can be a dialogue
it can be a lock between a chat between
you and your friend about any
programming topic you know so blog is
very loose you know it's hard to I mean
even if you wrote blogs for 20 years and
you usually Bronx are ephemeral like
they are right once in throw away like
the next day they become less important
in a month they become irrelevant
sometimes after year they become useless
that's the nature of blogs so it's it's
different from tutorial you know so if
you are a blogger if you know if you
guys blog you might want to pay your
attention when you you know about these
because usually if you just you know
write blogs as you go you know usually
they the value of a blog article they go
away they disappear quickly you know
especially like Twitter or social
networks Facebook those are what you
call Micro blogs they are value usually
go away within one hour
you know you post something on Twitter
we think well nobody ever read it you
know after one day you know some of your
friends might maybe they all check it
but you know usually you know like
within 10 minutes the value is gone
nobody you see it that's one of the sad
thing about blog about social networks
and blogging and
and that is exactly how Twitter and
Facebook
that is exactly their intention as well
because they they want to make money and
they want so they want to people to keep
posting so they want to make sure that
you know they want to make you know they
want to make you to keep posting so you
know they designed that way so any post
has no value after an hour or after a
day something like that you want to you
know repeat what whatever you say okay
no comments then that's it for today
then thank you guys for watching
I'll see you guys next time