Evening. Welcome to another episode of
Ex talk shop. We are going to code
uh we are going to code JavaScript and
cascading stylesheet. So I'm going to
tell you something I discovered. Okay.
So S talk show welcome and uh check
video check audio check. So let's do it.
So I discovered about a month ago when
chatting to AI that something new I I uh
I was wrong for the past 20 30 years. So
I discovered the wide gamut colors.
Okay. Can you guys see it? If you are
here say hi. Okay. And play at 1.5
speed. Uh so you just gonna watch me
ramble. So this is I'm a old programmer
for over 30 years.
Uh hello physics.
Okay. So uh let's double check last
time. Video check, audio check.
Okay. So yeah. So I discovered so so
basically in the past 30 years I was we
we were taught that the color is made of
red, blue, green and each can have 256
values digital colors RGB and that
should cover all
uh colors human can see and that is
incorrect.
That is my alarm clock. Every uh 30
minutes I it beeps. I get up tells me to
get up and walk.
So the idea
red, blue, green, RGB colors. Each one
has 256 values that can display all
possible colors. That is not true. So up
to until around 2016,
we begin to have monitors or computer
display that are capable of displaying
colors outside of that. So the the
standard idea of RGB of 256
8 bits per channel or 256
levels per color for red, 256 color for
blue, 256 color for green. So altogether
that would be uh uh 256 times uh uh
raised to the third power. So uh so we
can do that. So let's see
256.
Okay. I got this I got this fantastic
code automatically increment
256. So 2566
raised by in Python I believe that's the
uh that's the u double asterisk that's
the syntax for power. So you got
basically 1.6 million colors. So you
know I thought uh that is what we can
see but actually no there are colors
that you can that's beyond that. So you
see so typically you see this diagram CE
lab very complicated. Okay. So uh can
you get the larger view? Well you can
you can if you go to Wikipedia. So
basically what the RGB color we see is
the smallest triangle here. Okay. So
there are colors you can see these are
for human eye. You can see but
cannot be displayed by uh your computer
screen for the past 30 years.
until around 2016 or 2015
uh several HP was the first then Apple
their phone they made display so that it
can display colors outside of this 256
RGB color. Okay, this
this RGB 256 levels per color channel is
called standard RGB sRGB. Okay, that's
called sRGB. So remember that. That's a
kind of the standard 256 colors per
channel or eight bits per channel. Eight
eight bits means um
eight bit means binary number. Two uh
eight binary numbers. So that the result
is 256.
Then you have three of 256.
So that that's how you get uh
uh 100 uh 1 million. So this is uh this
is in Python you can do that. Okay. So
let me get the math right.
That's right. So let me show you. So
this is um
eight bits. Okay, eight bits
has total value of 256.
Okay. And
eight bits per
color channel
means you got 256
to the powers of three times itself
three times. So you got 16 um medians
color. Okay. And turns out that's not
enough.
I mean we can see more colors than that
but however the computer displays
monitor for the past 30 years can only
do this can only do this much color okay
so copy uh cut that and uh let's put it
here uh since we are like uh giving a
lecture so this is Python code okay show
in browser so this is today's topics um
so I'm going to tell you okay so so
these colors if you are able to see if
if you have a color standard that's
that's bigger than sRGB standard RGB
that is called wide gamut color okay
white gamut color and there's a standard
for it it's called HICP3
and Apple kind of remain it cap Apple
branded branded it like with a minor
change and Apple calls it display three
uh P3 display P3. Okay. So when you shop
for a monitor, computer monitor, you can
see what is the standard output. If it
says sRGB, that means just 8 bits per
color.
But if it says it supports display P3 or
HICP3,
then that means it can display vivid
colors that most computer monitors even
today you cannot. Okay. So, but you can
see this vivid color. If you go out, you
know, just look at those big giant
screen TVs. You can see like shiny vivid
blue red, you know,
and and for the past 30 years, so I
didn't know that, you know, there are
these colors that we cannot see. Okay, I
mean we can see however all our monitors
cannot show. Okay, now so so this is
called white gamut colors. very
important because this is this is like
changing technology you know you know of
the past 50 years or 30 years we cannot
you know no display can possibly it's
like technologically impossible to show
colors outside of this 8 bits per you
know outside of this sRGB but now we can
since about 20 thou 2016 and [snorts] uh
such monitors is becoming more popular
so when you buy a monitor you want to
make sure your monitor supports
uh white gamut colors or display P3.
Okay, you can you can go to your Windows
and check your monitor uh spec. If it
says display sRGB, that means it doesn't
support white colors. So now now what's
what's interesting is that the image
format you know the the the format uh we
are most familiar with JPEG PNG they
actually don't really support uh white
gamut colors okay so meaning that the
image format the JPEG itself
you know when you store an image you
cannot see it first of all you need the
monitor you need a monitor to uh for P3
monitor to be able to see those colors.
Even if you have that and some someone
sent you a photo image file, JPEG,
the JPEG file
technically actually supports white
gamma colors, but usually not because
they there's a lot of reasons because
they they store the white color gamma.
It requires a ICC profile color profile
which is the meta data which is often
deleted. So basically in short in
practice JPEG does not display white
gamut colors. So any photo taken you
know you it the the the application to
uh display the JPEG will not show the
white gamut colors or it has been
removed because usually it's not
supported by lots of monitors. So that's
very interesting. Okay. So you want to
check you know the image format.
[snorts] So JPEG technically support
white gamut colors but not really and
also JPEG each color um channel is 8
bits only. Okay. Same thing for PNG and
same thing for uh webp. So webp is
interesting because webp is this
Google's new image format but it doesn't
support more than eight bits. But what's
new is that Apple begin around um
you see Apple MacBook Air M1 the from
year 2020 is supports white gamut colors
and also Apple iPhone uh 13 2021. Those
are what I have.
Physic Lab says I saw a old video of
you. No, that's um that's uh past that's
during my poverty days. Okay.
Kasan food. So you can see it. Uh that's
like my most popular
video that that one. Okay. That was uh
the poverty of the poverty in USA. I was
about to die.
Okay. I'm doing good now. Thank you.
Uh because I'm writing Python. This is a
revolutionary. Hey Mo actually I write a
lot Python but I don't you know Python
is a circus language. I wrote a lot of
Python though. Python is one of my
earliest tutorial. So actually I wrote a
lot in Python. So you can see uh yeah.
So let me just flame Python for for a
minute. Okay. So for those you guys uh
new guys you don't know um so there it
is my Python tutorial there there's a
poem there's a python py mighty listen
and tabby algorithm it puffs conundrum
it snuffs and cherished by those savvy
so this is like a positive you know uh
poem for python but [snorts] I learned
python around 2005
you can see the date there 2000 year
2005 because I hate, you know, because I
got so tired of the pearl [ __ ] The
pearl are the Unix [ __ ] You know,
they say, "Oh, you can dream. Do what I
mean." You know, that like full of
jarens and sloppy, you know, who who
cares about computer science computer
science? [ __ ] computer science. You
know, in in in in theory, they say
theory is everything. But in practice,
no. That's what Pearl people [ __ ]
say. you know they are the kind of the
Unix [ __ ] let's be let's do you
know let's just get things to work you
know this pearl [ __ ] with lots of
chant and jarens so I got tired of it so
that's when I started to learn Python
and also a lot a lot of people learn
Python [snorts] back then because of you
know they got tired of pearl and and
funny pearl died you know it's
impossible to believe like today but
back then pearl is supposed to be like
it's looks like pearl is going to be the
last scripting language forever like the
greatest Swiss army knife you know like
like people say like
well anyway so that that is the story of
Pearl okay so I learned Python in 2005
so I it's great change because Python
doesn't go for the sloppy syntax or you
can do whatever you ways you want you
know let's have fun you know what
whatever fun means you know so Python is
is
doesn't have those issues Okay, they are
not for like Unix philosophy [ __ ] you or
or abbreviations you know like cryptic
abbreviations like those pearl people
enjoy like every function name is like
cryptic you can you don't it doesn't say
what it does you know but Python is not
like that so but but after being you
know in Python for 10 years you learn
this ski van Rosen scum you know he's
like a particular
He's he think he's smart you know he
want to do mathematics he's like we want
formal you know formalization we want
you know there there should be only one
way to do things but but in fact his
language Python and the way he you know
himself is low IQ okay and Python is one
of the worst programming language the G
von Rosen is a aggressive passive
aggressive guy okay Python so you And
you can read about my Python tutorial
for beginners or you can you know so so
there's a lot so so
uh so Python tutorial let's say uh let's
see god so this uh font is so huge
um so let's uh python tutoriio those are
old scripts like you know 10 years ago
old web qual web crawler okay I wrote
this 2014 web caller. Okay. So anyway,
so there is Okay. So, so why Python is
popular? Uh there it is. Okay. So these
two why Python document sucks. Okay.
There's about 20 30 articles. Why Python
document sucks. Python documentation is
one of the worst in computing industry.
And there it is. Keep this under your
pillow. This Python [ __ ] Skidov von
Russen. This is his humor. He he, you
know, you know, he enjoy, you know, this
is fun to him. Keep this under your
pillow. If you go to the official Python
documentation, you'll see that uh
phrase. Okay. But but but the Python
documentation, yeah, if it's great, I
keep it under my pill. But the Python
documentation is the worst [ __ ]
possible. Second to the Unix man pages.
Okay. The Unix man page pages are the
worst [ __ ] possible. That's number one.
The second one is the Python
documentation. The worst crap like
passive aggressive [ __ ] the Python
documentation. So I got like 20 30
articles about it in detail if you want
to dive. Then there is this uh Python
sucks. Why the Python the language is
[ __ ] you know all all over like almost
in every aspect the GO vonrosome idiots.
Okay. So, why for for example the the
Python the kido von Rosome [ __ ] he
he wrote an article
uh he wrote an article. Okay. So he
wrote an article he's he's this passive
aggressive guy uh uh let's see you know
he wrote article back in 2010 the fate
of lambda in Python 3000 you know and
he's got a name Python 3000 you know
he's like he he he he he's a vision you
know he's an idiot but he has a vision
he want Python to be the most easy to
learn programming language for all
children which basically failed Python
became popular because of Google. Okay,
Google like saved Python. Python, you
know, Google started to use Python that
made Python known by other people. Then
around 2010, Python is just [ __ ] too
lousy. It's about to die again, taken
over over by Ruby. Then Google saved it
again because of the machine learning,
you know, Google churns out Python code,
you know, like Python, you know, so
that's why Python became popular. But
Python by itself is like dying like
because it's [ __ ] But the Gavo van
Russamome guy he's he's like a you know
he's an idiot but he's like he's got a
vision and he he think himself is like
one of the great uh uh language designer
you know like he wrote articles like
full of that attitude
passive aggressive you know he he not
like me oh I'm the greatest what you
know whatever claims you make or oh I
hate that [ __ ] I hate this [ __ ] he
doesn't say that okay because that's not
polite These people don't do that, but
they but they like they have a passive
aggressive way to say things. That's a
Gon Rosen. The fate of reducing Python
30,000. What does it mean? It means he
[ __ ] hates functional programming.
Okay, that's what basically that's what
he means. And he don't understand not a
thing like you read in detail of his
crap. He he don't understand the P glo
[ __ ] Okay.
So he wrote this article and he's he's
made fun by the scheme people of course
uh you know so the scheme these people
the fate of lambda in PRT scheme 3000
you know this is this this article is
incredibly insulting and idiotic to the
extreme because on one hand he wanted to
dis functional programming because he
don't he you know either he he he don't
like it or he don't understand it
somehow it doesn't you know fit his
brand. So he he wrote an article saying
that in Python 3000 which is Python 3
you know this is written in 2008. He
says oh we're going to remove uh reduce
in Python 3 which they did. Okay these
[ __ ] ghosome idiots he removed
reduce in Python 3. Okay. But but you
know the but but you don't say you know
like like normally you could just say oh
you know I'm thinking about you know
what like about reduce in Python 3. But
no he's like he needs to be dramatic the
fate of reduce in Python 3000. You know
that that this is a classic typical way
showing his writing style. You know this
passive passive aggressive [ __ ] is
gavon rom the fate of reduce in python
3000 okay so well on one hand he wanted
to remove it because he you know the
reason is idiotic you know he doesn't
like functional programming basically
but on the other hand he's trying to
defend you see he's trying to tell you
in this article the fate of reduce he's
trying to tell you that this reduce is
this basically he's he's trying to say
functional programming is no good
effectively. That's what he's saying.
Okay. So, so that's why most functional
programmers, you know, they don't like
Python because and also Python's lambda
is broken and cannot be fixed. Uh where
is that article? You know, this is very
well known Python lambda broken. So the
the the the how Abison who wrote this
famous book he made a comment you know
he's they started to teach uh using
Python because Python is popular uh but
however you have this lambda problem
well they you know they're going to
accept accept it
lambda uh okay anyway I talked about
this uh many times before that's a huge
digression
uh he removed it because it exposed a
weak point about the language itself,
namely real parallelism.
Oh, really? That's interesting. Yeah.
Uh
some Sara Ziza says, "Hi, I've enjoyed
your videos and your website for a few
[snorts] years now. found you when I
discovered Emacs and this about five
years back. Hope you are well. I'm well.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Uh yeah. So I well yeah my my life is
kind of uh a tragedy shall we say.
Anyway, so so there is um so there there
was the rant the huge rant about Python.
So I was I wanted to tell you guys so I
got this Python tutorial okay about I
don't know few hundred pages or 100. So
let's go let's see how many pages
actually
uh Python go to it go to a directory go
down only eight 180 uh about 150
articles okay so my Python tutorial is
actually not big small um and not
advanced but great for beginners okay
but I wanted to tell you is that go to
the bottom there's there's this
collection of why Python sucks
This for you guys, you know, you might
want to read if you are a beginner, read
a Python tutorial, okay? But otherwise,
you can, you know, if you are uh
seasoned, you or Unix hacker or
whatever, you might check out why Python
sucks and there are like 30 50 uh
articles and then why Python
documentation sucks. The [ __ ] Python.
Okay, that's a huge digression. So uh so
we let's go back to the color space. So
we were talking about the colors. Okay.
So close that. Yeah. I wanted to talk
about the colors. So you so I I I
learned for the first time about this
about the fact that we have colors that
we can see but it's outside of this 256
colors RGB [ __ ] Okay. Because I because
you know because since like 1992
when you know back then uh a monitor is
either monochrome like black and white
only two colors or you can display 256
colors. Okay. Only so and
then then later on you can display uh
millions of colors because of this
three 8 bits you know RGB. So then they
say, "Oh, you can that's all the
possible colors you can see all the like
every like like that's the marketing
that that you know set into your brain."
But that's not true. So today we know
well a lot you know people know this
long ago that RGB is just small colors
you know we can see in fact there's so
many more colors that we can see outside
of this sRGB. Okay. So that this journey
so I started because I was chatting to
uh AI.
I chatted to AI by voice for 20 minutes
you know [clears throat] AI taught me
you know so like I was learning you know
why do I know how did I know started to
know about this because I was doing uh
CSS okay I was catching up uh with my
CSS tutorial CSS tutorial CSS cascading
stylesheet is getting
very complex you need a PhD D degree to
understand. Okay. So I have massively
expanded my
visual uh cascading stylesheet tutorial
in the past two months almost working on
it every day. Okay. So it's very complex
now but it's very interesting because
you know anyway so watch my past few
videos I talked about uh which which are
about CSS. Okay. So, but one of the
thing is about you you got this colors
thing. Okay, you got this um web
tutorial. So, let's go to web blog. You
got this
incomprehensible color thing. Okay, so
you got this. They added HW
B color. Like you are you are wondering
like what what the [ __ ] is HW color? We
got RGB. We got HSL. Why do we have this
HWB
color? And they call it color space.
Okay. So you got the you know you got
your standard RGB look like that popular
among the Unix idiots. You know this
three hex you know six hexadimals. This
started by the CUNIX [ __ ]
Then you got uh you know RGB you know
function which use number instead of
instead of hexadimal. Okay. Then then
you got um then you got HSL. This is
more intuitive because you can hue, you
know, hue is just a rainbow. You can
increase the uh uh parameter and change
the hue basically rainbow. Okay. So,
saturation from gray to fully colored
and lightness from black dark to bright.
So if you put saturation 200 and
lightness to um let's say 50 then you
got the full saturation red and this and
hue is the rainbow. Okay. So red,
orange, yellow, green, blue, um purple,
violet, purple, right? So very
intuitive. Okay. So you got HSL, you
know, hue hue, saturation, lightness.
Okay.
much better than the R, you know, RGB
[ __ ]
But most people, you know, the the idiot
industrial coders, they they like RGB.
They always, you know, it's like the C
and Unix [ __ ] They spread this
[ __ ] in comprehensible [ __ ] And why
250? That just happens to be because
because your bits is like eight bits.
That's 250. You know they they so so so
each color channel you have like 256
levels. Why the magic number 256? Just
because you happen to your bits happen
to be that way. Okay. This Unix C idiots
I despise them so much. So but anyway so
we got HSL uh model which is in CSS like
over 15 years ago. That's great, right?
But then but then but but then today you
look at the you know color spec you got
HWB HWB is also is still the sRGB space
they they just it's a new model it's a
hue whiteness and blackness okay so you
got so [snorts] okay one of these days I
need to add a uh interactive app uh app
uh so then okay hi
That's white blackness
uh hue whiteness blackness. Okay. So I
need to add interactive app. So here's
some color samples. Then you got um then
I explained the white color gamut which
I discovered. How I discovered because
the because CSS when you look into the
CSS then you got this lab color LCH
color. Then you also got um
OK lab color, OK LCH color. Like what
the [ __ ] are they? You don't know. Okay,
so very fairly comp complicated. Okay,
so basically there are so many of them.
But basically the basically the OKLC is
is is
a intuitive color space. They call it
color space. um intuitive it's like HSL
okay it's like the hue
it's it's like the hue saturation uh
brightness
but however
this hue saturation lightness is got
some problems because actually you see
even if we set the lightness at 50 it
doesn't change okay we just change the
hue but however when we change the hue
the percept you know we don't perceive
them as the same lightness you see some
of them are darker like the when you
when the hue becomes blue you know it's
it's it's significantly darker than
let's say when be when it's c you see so
what they want what people want is a is
a color system such that
you know hue is just changing hue while
brightness remains
remains the same as as we human eyes
perceive it. Okay. So that basically the
result of that design is the OK LCH.
Okay. Then the OK lab is a is a is a
linear version.
OK LCH is like a polar version. Okay.
Um
okay. and and before then that's why
that's how you have the lab lab and the
LCH so okay lab and okay LCH is derived
or improvement from the lab and the LCH
color so each one is very complicated
you know the color science by itself
requires a PhD okay then you also have
color function you know like color you
can specify what the color space like
you can say display P3 which we talked
about or recre 2020. That's another
standardized color space. Or there's
A98-RGB,
which I don't understand. Adobe RGB.
Then there's Prooto RGB. I don't
understand. Okay. So, there's sRGB,
which we understand. That's just
standard RGB, 256
levels per channel. Okay. [snorts] Then
you got sRGB linear. Then you got XYZ
D50. Okay. I don't understand. So color
very complex. So basically I was trying
to improve my CSS tutorial about colors.
Then I discovered what the [ __ ] are this
this okay lab and and weird name too you
know. Okay LCS like then I discovered oh
oh so there's the so so so all the past
30 years I I got the wrong information.
there are colors we can see but it's not
possible with the sRGB [ __ ] you know the
8 bit [ __ ]
so I learned a lot okay then also about
the color um image format so that's of
course uh tied with it because uh
because the image format the JPEG and
PNG they don't support basically they
don't support um
this this uh wide gamut colors. Okay.
So, I learned it from talking to AI when
I was asking about some CSS question
like what what is the sRGB? I heard of
RGB but I don't remember ever heard of
sRGB. So, I asked AI. Then AI started to
tell me one thing after another. So, I
learned oh Jesus you know very
interesting.
So that's the how I learned that about
this uh white gamut colors. Okay. and
display P3. Then there's image format
because even if you have the right
monitor
that can display white color gamut, but
the image format does not. So meaning
that the vast majority of images of the
JPEG or the PNG, they don't they simply
don't support it. Okay, actually they
do, but but most people I mean they they
simply ignore it. I mean so they in so
practically speaking JPEG and PNG they
basically practically speaking they
don't support the wide color gamut. So
even if you got got you know you know
someone send you image and you have the
nice monitor you cannot see it because
it's this uh format doesn't store it. So
what you need is
this Apple HIC
uh hicc format or AVIF or JPEG XL. So
you need this uh image format. Okay. So
that's uh that's what I want to say
today this discovery about this um and
WEBP is another format. WEBP is a format
by Google starting about 15 years ago
and unfortunately
it's no good. Okay. it. Um
well actually Amazon is using it. So if
you go to Amazon
Amazon.com you can see so let me show
you. Okay so if you go to Amazon um
uh click below to continue shopping
because they are trying to check if you
are a bot. Okay. So let me do a
screenshot.
So if you go to Amazon and let's say you
just uh watch. Okay, let's drag that to
my folder. Okay, that's PNG. Uh, drag
this dress to my folder. That's also
PNG. Um,
uh, wait, that depends on what, uh,
that's also uh I think it depends on
your browser.
They what kind of image what type of
image they serve depends on your
browser, I think. Let's see. Uh track
ball
what
Amazon luxury no all departments
okay let's see if I that JPEG okay so
okay it depends on your browser I'm
pretty sure if so if we go here
uh
No,
Amazon.com.
Okay. What the [ __ ] is this?
Okay.
Now let's try again.
Watch.
No.
Okay. No. So I think you need to let's
say track B
because I was just checking today there.
There it is. You can see it returns a
webp.
Uh you can check the file name. That's a
webp image. Okay. So, Amazon is is
heavily using the WEBP format.
Uh, but WEBP is no good. It turns out
it's only 8 bits per channel. So, it
doesn't really support the white color
gamut
for the future. And uh and also um
well, I mean, yeah. So, it doesn't
support that.
Okay. So, I think that's it for today. I
was going to code
uh I was going to code some JavaScript
still. Should we do it? Yeah, I think
so. Let's why not since I'm you know
just random doing talk show. Okay. So,
showing browser what we have here. So, I
wanted to code. So, we talked about the
white gamut colors. We talked about the
AI chatbot and we talked about the new
image format. HIC, AV, AVIF, JPEG, SL,
XL, they all save the same image much
more compressed than JPEG. So JPEG might
be 1 megabyte with one of these that
might be you know uh half of it or you
know they are much more better
compression also [snorts] they support
white gamut you know they and also they
are each of them they are all more than
a bits per channel.
Uh so these are like these these are
basically the future you know that like
like the um and they they've been around
over 10 years ago. They've been around
even even 10 years ago but it's very
slow to catch up. Okay. So anyway so the
so about colors. Okay. So what else? Uh
I think that's it. Then the next thing I
want to do is to
actually I want I want to code. Okay. So
I want to code JavaScript. So that for
example
uh yeah do I want to code? Yeah because
uh for example if you go to HSL colors
at the bottom I have this um these color
samples. So you can see
what happens if you increase one
parameter. Okay. So this is HSL hue
saturation lightness. So if you increase
hue that's the rainbow you change the
color then if you increase saturation
you get you know more saturated or dark
gray or if you increase lightness you go
from black to white.
So I want to do the same for HWB. HB is
white black I mean hue whiteness
blackness. You know this this image
format is quite id idiotic this color
because when okay so the way it works is
that hue is the same okay rainbow hue
okay but the whiteness is like the the
greater the number the more white it
became okay that's the whiteness part
the blackness part is the greater the
value the the the more black it became
okay it seems intuitive you know hue a
mix of whiteness and blackness. Okay.
But then what happens is that if the
whiteness and blackness
together they are some is over 50 I mean
over 100 then you get all gray. So you
you see look at this example. When you
increase the whiteness and the blackness
together
after 50 it's it's all gray. It's it's
all you know all the same color become
all gray.
So I
someone thought you know the the guy
whoever you know invented this this
color uh format.
I don't think I don't think it's
intuitive at all. But anyway this is
part of the sRGB. So this is 100% the
same as the RGB
and also the same as the HSL. Okay.
These are not white gamut. Okay. So
important to remember. So the RGB
and the HS
RGB and the HWB they are all they are
all the standard RGB color space sRGB
space. Okay. Now if you want colors
outside of them then you need then you
start with um lab LCH
uh and uh the okay LCH okay LCH is
considered the best. Okay. So what I
want to do is I want to create like
like all possible patch of um
colors that shows what happens if you
increase the parameter. You see this is
very odd because well first of all my
monitor the one you are seeing cannot
display
white color gamut. Okay, that means when
you have colors outside of the sRGB, my
monitor will show them as the same
color. Okay, so
so first of all, even if I do this, I
can't, you know, I cannot see the
difference. I need to go to my iPad, I
mean my iPhone, iPhone, if you have
Apple phone, it can show the difference.
Okay, one of the site you can check is
that there are white color gamma test.
Okay, colored let's say search white
color gamma test. So there's a website
here. Okay, white gamma test page. I
don't know who is this guy, but I
suppose it's
you know I'm pretty I know it's not
virus. Okay, at least you can you can
just go uh check. So if you So you see
there's a red image here.
Now on my monitor it's all just red but
if you are on iPhone you'll see a W.
Okay. You will see a W. I I checked I
saw it. Okay. So only on some monitors
that can is capable of white gamut
you'll see a W.
But my screen cannot do it. Okay. So the
the the screen I'm using now. So,
so that's a thing. Um, and uh,
yeah. So, that's so very interesting. I
find this, you know, very interesting.
This is like in interesting in the sense
it's a technology progress.
You see,
you know, in the past 30 years, we we we
we cannot make monitors that display
more than eight bits per channel, but
now we can. It's one of the technology
progress and that made you realize
that's how you realize that you know
what what possible colors we can
actually see.
Uh you know by the way the display P3 is
not all the colors it's actually only
half of the colors we can see. So you
can see you know you can go check
Wikipedia they will show you lots of
these you know image diagrams CIE color
space. So actually the sRGB is the
smallest that's 8 bit per channel right
but then you have larger triangles
that's
DCIP3 that's a display P3 even that is
is not all the possible colors we can
see. So we can see all these color this
kind of funky shaped you know we can see
all of them like in nature you go
outside the flowers or whatever but
but you see even Apple's you know latest
iPhone display they can only show like
half of the possible colors we can see.
So that's uh interesting. Okay,
I think that's it, you know, but I was
going to, you know, so yeah, so I was
going to code JavaScript to show the
uh I don't know. So
physics says
uh what uh physics says, do you think we
would have Emacs if Unix and C never
existed?
Yes, I think so. I think by the time
Emacs was created, there is no Unix.
Okay, so physics lab, are you still
here? Now, how long have I been talking?
Uh, maybe I should get start. Uh,
I've been talking for 47 minutes. I need
a drink and I need to
if we are going to continue either I
stop now or
I need a break. I need a drink. Okay.
So, let me get a drink. So, I want to
code.
So, the question uh do you think if we
would have Emacs if Unix and C never
exist? Yes, we do. because Emacs was
created
before Unix existed. Okay, we can ask
well we can the easiest most convenient
and fun way to know the answer is just
ask AI because it's just incredible.
Okay, but
uh Jesus, what super growth? I don't
want super growth [ __ ]
Or I can show you um
I can show you my documents about em you
know I can show you historical documents
about
Emacs. Okay. So like Wikipedia let's the
easiest way is just ask
Did Emacs is exist before Unix?
>> No. Emacs was created in the mid70s on
Unix like systems at MIT. Unix itself
started in the early '7s. So, Emacs came
after
Okay, it says no because it says that
Emacs was created. Wait, stop. Stop.
So, it says Emacs. Okay, magnify. Emacs
was created in 1976 at MIT. That's
correct. On the IT operating system.
That's correct. However, Unix
development started in 1969 at Bell
Labs. That's true.
And the first Emacs that ran on Unix
didn't appear until early 80s. That's
what I that's what I mean. Okay. Well,
so I mean they are they are independent.
Okay. Emacs didn't begin because of
Unix. Emacs began on the IT operating
system. Okay. So even if Unix did not
exist, Emacs
uh exist.
Okay. So I uh going to get a drink and
uh uh oh actually let me actually
either stop or continue. What do you
guys think?
Broad doesn't know EMAC history. I know
about techco and early Emacs and modern
Emacs tidy integration.
Okay. Modern Emacs with tight
integration. Wait, you see this is still
listening to my talk. What the [ __ ]
You know you you have to know that GNU
Emacs G and U.
Okay. Wait.
You know sometimes this AI kept
listening to me. You see even I stopped
it. Stop.
Hello. Are you still eavesdropping on
me?
Yes, it is [ __ ] stupid. Can you stop
listening?
Are you still listening?
It's got a problem.
Refresh.
Hello.
Are you still listening?
You know, sometimes it shows it stopped,
but actually it's still listening to
your talk.
Uh, [sighs]
so one solution is just turn your
microphone off.
So anyway, one thing to remember is that
GNU Emacs, the GNU stand for GNU is not
Unix. Okay? So Richard Sman he doesn't
you know he hated Unix because Unix was
commercial entity. So GNU so so Richard
Sman created GNU [snorts] GNU is I think
is the first so-called recursive
acronym. Okay, that's what nerds call
it, but it's idiotic. But anyway, he
designed GNU to be GNU is not Unix.
Meaning that he doesn't want Unix. He's
creating Emacs and GCC compiler and and
the the uh what's his operating system
then to replace Unix. That's what is
intention.
Okay. He don't want Unix because Unix
belong to AT&T proprietary system. Okay,
that's a short digression. Okay, so
that's Unix pests.
Uh Unix is a proprietary system
uh you know owned by AT&T. You can see
you can see from many of these old
uh t-shirt you know so this BSD you BSC
Unix is poking that thing that globe
that's that's um that is used to be
known as AT&T
death star okay that's a logo of AT&T
okay so let me show show you some guys
something. Okay, I keep talking until we
going to stop soon, I think. Okay, kasar
code kasadi.info.
Then you go to uh logo uh history. Do we
have here somewhere logo design software
industry? Okay, then you enlarge this
window. Then you go to uh let's
okay then you go to uh AT&T. So this is
logo design of software industry but you
go to purpose of logos and principles of
logo design. Then you can see some some
of the examples of nonsoftware
corporations logo. Okay. Such as so by
the way herd is the operating system
Richard Sman was going to create to
replace Unix but it is it became the
greatest vapor wear because after 40
years it's still not there. I mean
there's a version like like beta you
know but basically not practical. So
Herd is the is Richard Stman's operating
system. Okay. GNU herd remember GNU GNU
stand for GNU is not Unix because
Richard Snowman they despise the Unix
because it's proprietary by the by the
blood sucking AT&T corporation you see
so here is the logo of AT&T this logo
was known as the death star
is A
death star is a joke from the
Star Trek movie. You know this kill you
know you know this death star. Okay. So
I'm [laughter] I'm talking about this
because you zoomers probably don't know
because you want bone. Okay. But every
everyone knows this in the past 30 40
five 50 years. Okay. So, so AT&T
back then is owner creator of Unix and
AT&T is a big super greedy commercial
organization. Okay? Like they they they
do everything you can to squeeze suck
your blood. That's what AT&T the like
the it's like today's um Google, okay?
It's like today's Google, Microsoft, but
back then AT&T, you know, they owns a
telephone like all the telephone
networks. So the government, so they the
su government split them off things like
that. Okay, so AT&T is the AT&T logo was
that they changed it to like this about
15 years ago. Okay, they kind of
simplified it. But this logo which I
think is was a great logo but it is
known nickname is AT&T Death Star. Why
death star? Because most nerds you know
they don't we don't like this big
corporation. Okay. It's from Star Trek
and the AT&T. So you can see the AT&T
logo here from the Berkeley. Berkeley is
from UC Berkeley. But UC Berkeley is a
university 1 hour drive from where I
live. Okay. In San Francisco.
So the UC you know that that's the
beginning of the BSD the Unix. Okay.
That's kind of the the university branch
of uh Unix. Okay. So they you can see
the this is the uh beasty uh uh this got
a name. The name is Beasty, right? So
this character is the mascot of
free BSD. Okay, BSD before there's no
different branch of BSD. They split.
Okay, that but anyway, so this is the
mascot of BSD. So they were poking
making fun of the AT&T.
Okay. And this this shirt is from uh I
don't know when I forgot when so like 18
1980s. Okay. 1980s.
So what I want to so what I'm telling
you is that you forgot you know like
young younger people you don't know you
thought oh Emacs is for Unix. No,
[laughter]
Emac. Emac is not for Unix. First of
all, it is on the IT operating system,
you know, it's completely nothing to do
with Unix. It's, you know, and then glue
they hated Unix. They wanted to replace
Unix. The the least people and the C
[ __ ] they don't get along. They
hate each other. Okay. So, it's the the
Emacs is not Unix. Okay. Emacs
everything the way Emacs you know the
big monstrosity the list is nothing like
Unix the man page the Unix small is
beautiful for [ __ ] nothing like it okay
so I despise the Unix I I love Emacs I
despise the Unix [ __ ]
nothing like the Unix okay so you guys I
mean the you new people don't know
because they thought today you know it
is dead l is said they thought oh GNU is
just Linux I mean GNU is yeah
you guys don't know even you know even
Unix is history like the some ecosystem
the HP Unix they are all history
you know so you don't even know this you
know all these Unixes you you just know
Linux and you thought you know oh yeah
Emacs is designed for Linux you know
that what
oh god
I'm 40, man. I grew up with AT&T. Oh,
okay. So, yeah. So, okay. Oh, okay.
Sorry, I didn't know. Well, I mean a lot
young people. Okay. Still,
um
I don't mean you. Okay. So, uh I think
Okay, that's it.
E replacement for some Unix tools.
That's true. That's true. G is throwing.
Yeah, rewrote the Unix tool. Right. So
the programming interface was same
similar. Yeah. They you know you know
like most Unix Linux you know the the
the Unix tools in Linux most of them are
from KU. Uh but
anyway
well see well so about what Emacs was
written in there's you know that's a big
history because Emacs was not wait the
first Emacs is of course the tech maros
which is not it's just a macro for the
tech editor okay I never used it, but
it's like it's key macro. Okay, key
marker from the teco text editor. That's
what Emac stand for.
Uh uh it's called uh EMAC stand for uh
what is the E stand for? Techo Marco.
Okay, Emacs like you can find it uh in
Wikipedia. Okay, so originally the EMAC
stand for editor Marco. That's right,
editor Marco. And that editor means the
techo editor. Okay. So, [snorts]
so then people I think the first then
then Gossen James Goslin the guy who
started Java he wrote it in
I think he's the first one who wrote it
in C and the
the wine bike guy uh what's his name? Uh
who he wrote Emacs in um Lisp the first
Lisp. Okay.
Anyway, Richard Stolman took the Emacs
from James Goslin and basically from
there on
no there there's there was a Emac
version written uh by um what's his
name? So okay. So
there was a EMAC version by
let's go to EMAC tutorial. Then let's go
to EMAC uh miscellaneous. Then uh Emacs
this miscellaneous index. EMAC this
misellaneous technical SS index. EMAC
vers index. EMAC miscellaneous index
there. And uh um
there is the uh
non techchnical essays on emac dis. No,
I want the emacs controversy part. Uh
okay, it's not even here. So it's part
of that.
want.
All this I got too many articles that's
hard to organize them. Yeah. Controversy
index. So why is this not on a homepage?
Okay. So anyway, you go to the Emacs
controversy index. There is Daniel
Wineb. Okay. Daniel Wreb
who died
he died in 2012. Okay.
So he he wrote the first Emacs entirely
in lisp. Okay. So
uh so here you can see this is a page
from his blog about Emacs history. Okay.
Okay. Bye guys.
Bye.
So anything else I missing? Uh let's
see. Uh that's good. That's good.
Anything I want else I want to say?
Okay. No.
Bye guys.