hello guys welcome to another episode of
some talk show
we are going to code emacs lisp today
so thanks to info who is sponsored for
today's talk show so i'm going to write
a emacs list
emacs command we are going to write
command that does this bionic reading
okay now what is bionic reading if you
go here you know there's it looks like a
new fad you know i don't believe it but
info
think
uh thinks that this might be fun so
basically bionic reading uh you know
this is something you know basically
they change the word you know beginning
of every word
uh they bold it so supposedly this makes
reading easier
uh
especially maybe for some people with
dyslexia or something
so this is bionic reading so we are
going to write the e magnificent command
that
that does that okay that you know change
text in the emax buffer that does that
so let's begin okay so
so this is just going to be pure emacs
the uh emacs list coding okay am i alive
in a live and kicking
video check let's see video check audio
check
streaming uh is
is is going okay so let's see
okay so we are going to start code now
and if you have questions comments and
post it about emacs okay and on the ping
window you can see all my command calls
and key strokes i type okay let's code
this bionic reading okay uh
write the emax command info bionic
reading let's do it okay so let's begin
hopefully in 30 minutes i think maybe 40
minutes we can finish it okay
so let's start our info
bionicreading.ell
create the file open new buffer create
it and save it okay already saved so
define
fun paste info bionic reading fantastic
and let's put a version date
version number
let's say uh bo documentation all
important board the first
a few charts of each
of every word okay
in current buffer
okay so this is gonna be your command
but maybe later on we can turn it into a
minor mod or major mod i'm not too sure
about that because if you are if it's a
minor model major mod it may interfere
with whatever the mods highlighting so
i'm not sure which one you want to be
priority
you know it's probably doable but anyway
for now let's just you know
you know simple you know uh command so
you can highlight it and call it and
you'll make it the first few words bold
okay so
let's begin so uh it's going to be the
entire buffer right
or is it going to be so so first of all
decisions about the design of this
command
so is this going to be if there's no if
there's a selection then do everything
on the selection
and if there's no selection just do the
current paragraph
now let's um
or
or just do the whole buffer you know
that's
design decision we can decide later on
for right now let's just say uh
let's just say current region okay let's
make it simpler simpler so if you do r
so let's say begin end okay so let's
give it two parameters and you put the
interactive uh this interactive line
makes
makes every emac makes the
the function the emac this function to
become a command that's what this
interactive okay hold on a second uh
calculator no
that's what this interactive is for and
when you put r to the interactive that
means region that means
emax will automatically feed the
functions parameters beginning end to be
the beginning and end positions of the
region okay so that's what this
interactive art makes it a command
and
feed the beginning end positions to the
parameters of the function okay so now
let's do
okay now so we have a region begin end
so let
so we have okay let's uh let's let's
begin coding this hello hello luis
audio video check okay uh got stream
live hey hey hey hey cherry
okay so
so we're gonna start to call this bionic
reading okay um
so now we got a region now we want to
bold
the first few characters of every word
um
so both the few first characters um
of every word okay so
and how many characters to bold i'm not
sure yet but it looks like according to
this you know their website you know uh
according to their website you basically
bought almost the
the first half of each word
you see half or less something like that
now
do they um break at
vowel points or something we don't know
let's just you know
both the first half
letters of each word okay
and uh
okay
both the first okay so for every word
search for um
so how we gonna do this
so
so i want to do this quickly you know
i'm doing a live stream so i want to do
just just start to code you know
but still i have to think about
something so
for every word how so for every word how
do you um
skip charts for let's see skip charts
forward
so there are two problems
the first problem is that you know you
have a buffer you have a region you know
lots of words
you want to do this to every character
so how do you like
do you
so there are two problems one one of the
problem is given a word you know
beginning end position of a word you
just spoke the first few characters that
part is easy now the other part is how
do you
how do you repeat this process
how do you repeat this process you know
there are many ways but
how do you repeat this process
so we think
um
let's just put the first word okay let's
just start to code you know instead of
talking and thinking so given a word
uh let's see
length okay so
given a word okay so p1
would begin let's let's start to uh
add some
uh local variables okay word begin
word end okay
so that's uh
suppose we got that position then
okay so
let me let me just do this okay current
word okay
so current word is a function
that
um
let me show the pink window current word
is a function that
returned the word at
okay we cannot use that
because it returns the word as a string
rather we want the position beginning in
position of that so we cannot use that
uh in that well in okay so let's look at
let's jump to the source code let's see
you know this is this is
this is pretty
you know this
it's narrow to defend okay so this
function current word is kind of long
and that also means it implies it's slow
so we don't want that
but anyway we want the start and end
position so
yeah this is to um
skip syntax forward
okay we can use that
that gets you see the start and end
positions skip syntax forward sync taxes
program
so this is a part where we want to find
each word and
let's just uh okay so let's not use that
we need a position
so the position
of a word the current word is let's see
okay
emac list let's go to my emacs this
tutorial so because i have thought this
out before so let's see uh mark region
uh
emac this tutorial
so we want to grab uh okay work with
lines get both a string there get buffer
string from region from selection from
current character current word okay
okay so it's you know current word
that's not we want
because
it doesn't return the position we want
the position
so get kind of word and the
syntax table syntax table is no good get
current line
get thing at point thing at point is
what we want
okay but thing at point is slow okay so
anyway let's just blast through
uh thing at point okay so thing at point
so what there it is
uh in fact that just return the current
word as a string but what rather we want
the boundaries we want the positions so
uh
bounce of
thing at point
okay that's what we want so
it's going to be what
okay bounce of thin point it returns a
cons pair so
bounce okay so let's uh
set q
okay god we need to go this way we need
to go faster because otherwise it's
going to be
not done in 30 minutes
okay so now bounce is the beginning and
end position it's a pair so now we get
we we we we want to get the pair so
let's say position one uh instead of
let's say p1 xp2 okay
yeah
you know i have a habit of changing uh
variable names obsessive making them
anyway so let's
set
car
bounce
okay that's how you get the beginning
position from from the bounce okay
and copy that
and word end is cut
okay
that's how you so now what begin
what end is the positions begin end of
the word of the current word now
now we got a board
we want to
add text properties we want to bold it
so in order to build it how you do it is
you add text properties okay
so
but first of all you need to know the
length
okay so
okay so what length so a new variable
let's add it here
what length
okay so
x what
and
minus
x
would
begin okay
so
now we have the
count of letters of the current word now
next
so next
we have the count of the letters of the
current word okay
now
divided by 2
and
and divided by 2
okay now we need to divide this by two
divided by two now if it's even then
it's good but if the character number is
odd let's say three
then we get a fraction so let's see what
we um
three evaluated so in the mini buffer
that says one
so it returns the
um
[Music]
the floor of the division yeah this it
returns the
the uh
dividend divisor and returns the uh
hey how do you call that division um
quotient it returns the quotient as an
integer and ignore the remainder okay
okay we got we're gonna do this
faster it's more to go so
so this works fine so what what if it's
two
so
if it's true it also returns two what if
it's one let's see
you know these are edge cases
okay when when the single character
searches a a you know the capital letter
a
then it returns zero that means
uh so that would mean do not build a
single character letter so he said so
let's look at their example do they have
a example of a single letter do they
okay they also bold it
okay so the easiest is actually just
divided by two and add one okay so
so increment
that
okay
cha
two bold okay so that's another
uh variable
number of charts to both okay
so chart to bold
set that
that okay so remove that okay so this is
the number of characters we want to bold
it
okay so now
so
now we we arrived at the uh now we want
to get the beginning position we want to
start to bold and we want to get the end
position we start to bolt so let's add
another
variable
uh you know for fast coding purposes
bold and position okay let's just name
that
so this we this is going to be plus
uh the
x word begin
plus
that
okay so actually so that is already a
there
okay that's
so expo end position now now let's board
so the
we want to bold
at these two positions okay
at these two positions
that's right we want to vote at these
two positions and uh
how do you how do you do that you know
you go back to the emacs tutorial
and you want to
text properties okay
okay uh click search and uh
txt properties
okay there it is text properties so this
this is how you do so let's copy that
code
okay i'm gonna show you how to do this
so this is a full code uh and we are
going to
comments questions am i doing good
uh so we are the the the main thing we
want the main part is this line okay
put text properties okay so let's paste
it here
begin end position here
okay and the font lock font lock face
foreground red let's say just that for
now okay then delete this part
okay so now we complete we we kind of
have a preliminary version of this
function it actually just
both the current word okay so let's
evaluate it
open a new buffer
something in water okay
and
turn off this highlight and put the
cursor here
and let's call this command and
hopefully it will uphold
the first three characters of this word
okay
coet
info bionic reading
oh
it worked
fantastic fantastic
fantastic
okay so now
okay we need to of course we need to
there's a lot to do so wait
um
so if you do it here so yeah you can
just do it for each word you know for
now it's red we can make it a bold
instead
so now it works for each word
uh
now we get back to the problem of how do
you repeat this thing okay so that you
know there are many ways
so now okay so this this section
basically
this this section
uh
this section
okay here is the bounce okay bounce of
the current word
let's let's see for what okay move to
the beginning okay so let's see
so right now it takes a selection
uh let's not let's forget about the
selection let's just
walk with
let's just do the whole buffer okay
we can change it easily later
but for now for simplicity let's just do
the whole buffer
and
okay so now
for the whole buffer so first of all you
need to go to
buffer beginning okay
point mean okay point mean returns the
first position of the character
basically the beginning of the buffer
okay
uh
position one okay so let's see
okay that's position one then position
two is uh go to child point max
actually you don't have to go to a chart
so
what am i doing
uh yeah just go to chart okay don't you
don't need a position yeah
so go to move to the beginning of the
buffer
then
you want to do this okay this block
that
do the first word okay
uh and
so
this block is kind of a sub function
okay
go to chart
so so we need to
repeat this okay
so go to the beginning of the character
then bold it
uh
be sure we are not moving cruisers here
so we are not moving cursors here
after you voted
then we
forward okay forward word
that moves the cursor to the next word
okay
then we
basically do this again now let's just
be silly and do this repetition just to
make sure
you know our code works you see here
this block of code is repeated but let's
run it okay eval the buffer
and let's test it okay
now let's just copy for example let's
copy this text
new buffer paste it there okay let's
just call the command
it should bold at least the first two
words okay the emac these okay do it
okay so it's
it doesn't work it only did the first
character the first word okay let's go
back
let's try it again new buffer
call it
i want to i want to see where the cursor
ends
okay so it ends at here
yeah that's
so that that is expected because we
are at the beginning of the buffer then
we move forward what one time so that's
expected
so we need to fix this
okay put this here okay
go to the beginning of a buffer then
forward word
okay then um
then do it
then forward again
okay you are the buffer
new buffer paste the
whole text call the command do it
fantastic
we did it we did it fantastic
do i prefer wolfram lang or emac these
of course woofam wufam lam wufang line
is the magnitude beyond the emac beast
you know because and woof online is a
general purpose language emac this is
only
for emacs for basically
basically useless outside of emacs and
mostly primarily it's just for text
processing you cannot to you cannot use
it to write a server or
uh you know
or artificial intelligence machinery you
cannot you know
you can kind of if you push it but you
know it's not suitable
so
so the proper
comparison would be wufam language
versus
commonly or skim disk or racket is you
know there then it's more proper
comparison because
these are general purpose languages
and in that case i prefer wufang
language by by far because uh language
is much more higher level i did a lot of
videos about that okay that's a
decoration let's go back to this
okay so now
now if we repeat this you know now we
repeat this three times eval the buffer
now we can um
new buffer paste paste paste paste okay
now let's try it it should uh do the
first three words
do it fantastic okay now so we now we
got the pattern we started to see
uh you know how this uh works so we can
just do a while loop or something okay
so it's
it's
calculus
turn off
okay uh wait what is this uh okay so
let's
yep
link
okay so that's what we did today you
know we are writing this code
okay and so far so good so far so good
yes so good
uh so here is the pattern we started to
see so we
can
do a while loop so let's write it while
while
something something something okay now
that something something would be
forward i think
you know it each time it moves closer by
one word
then we highlight it then do it again so
so the critical thing we want to know is
the forward word does it does it return
neo
when it reaches the end of the uh buffer
you know we want it to return we want
something that returns
false
so that the loop will stop okay
so let's read the documentation describe
function for what is the interactive uh
however
okay so normally return t
if an edge of the buffer or a field
boundary is reached point is left there
and the function returns neo that's what
we want
okay
okay we did you know now it's 30 minutes
good we are on track so this is what we
want so
so um
so while forward word
then
then this block of code okay remove
remove okay
prettify the whole code
and move to the top so you can see the
whole code so there it is this is this
is our command so let's double check
before we run it
while
so first of all go to the uh go to the
buffer beginning then while
forward word
then
both the
first half of the world to the left of
kuza
kuza okay so that's what this block do
so
okay that's i think that's it now
eval the buffer
create a new buffer
go back here let's copy
copy this whole thing
paste it there
and we if we call the command it should
we should have this bionic reading
let's see
you know let's let's hope there's no
infinite loop because whenever you use
while loop in images sometimes you get
into infinite loop so make sure we saved
it
uh you know
okay call it meta x info bionic reading
do it
oh fantastic and it's fast
that's a success
success
now we just need to change the red to
bold okay
yeah it's good
now close that
now we uh so
so change the
color to bold that that would be this
part
so foreground red so here you can just
say both i think
let's
okay
eval the buffer
new buffer
paste paste paste previous okay we got
the whole text now called meta x info
bionic reading
fantastic
then
it's let's double check okay let's let's
uh let's copy their code oh god this you
know this modern zoomer male engine zuma
website you cannot copy text
you know it's funny they
they do bionic reading but they they
don't you know they put an image here
okay let's go so but we need
we need the text to compare right
and you know they put the image there
yeah incredible
idiotic zoom off
out there then there comes you know in
the viet
anyway so
bionic reading okay so uh yeah well i
cannot copy that this text so we cannot
do actual comparison
do they actually have some
that's the image again
yeah
okay it's created by this guy
okay
okay so
yeah but looks like this is uh let's
let's type
ionic reading is a new method
facilitating the reading process by
guiding the eyes through
through text with
artificial fixation points okay
okay let's
do it
let's go to the top
let's compare a little bit
bionic
reading is
okay so you see this uh sometimes you
know i mean it's exact not exactly the
same so is
in our in our case it's both highlighted
but in their case it's just the first
letter
but i think it's uh it's the same okay
basically
okay
i think that's it for this command uh
info is at work so he's not you know
watching this
with us right now
but i think that's it
so so of course we need to clean up you
know so basically this is a command
right now this command does the whole
buffer
we should write a another version that
does the region it's easy okay it's
trivial let's just do it
purify the code prefix so copy the code
and put it here
and name this region okay so that means
it will only work on the current region
so
begin end
so by my convention i use capital
letters for parameter names
beginning end then you you need to
remember to put a r here for the
interactive clause
then
you need to
you need to add the beginning end
somewhere here so
so yeah so in this case it's not from
the buffer beginning but rather it's
from
[Music]
uh go to char
not point meme
uh
basically we need we need to start at
beginning and end so we need to so let
me show you how to do that okay
uh
narrow to region that's very useful so
narrator region begin end there it is
so we narrow the buffer to the region
and save restriction means when the
command is done
revert it you you know
remove the narrow region
but so so this part just focus you know
narrow the
the buffer into a specific begin
position then we just put our whole code
here
cut
put it here prefi that's it
yeah so we you know
so this is a region version beginning
and end then interactive r
which means when you call the command
meta x it will automatically feed
field the parameters begin and end okay
so then we now to region and you know
okay eval the code evaluate the buffer
then let's um
let's
let's let's again copy this
paste
okay now let's say
let's make this
short okay
okay so let's say let's select this
region okay we don't want to do the
whole buffer let's select this region
and now call
info
bionic reading
uh by
bionic reading region
do it
fantastic it just you see
perfect it only did to this region okay
close it
okay now we have two versions of the
command now
so so this version should be uh named
buffer okay more properly by emacs
convention you know if you if you have a
command that works on the whole buffer
you should uh
the command name should you know contain
word buffer okay so we have a buffer
region buffer version we have the region
version
um
[Music]
i think that's it okay yeah let's let's
let's you know that's it for this
talk show
okay again thanks to info on our discord
who requested this who sponsored this
and uh
and you know that we can do some
refinement for example this can be made
into a minor mod or major mod
but it
you know
not necessarily a good thing because
you know because
if you make this into a minor mod
that means you know it interferes with
the coloring of the current buffer of
the current major mod
so
i'm not sure it can co-exist well you
know you know we have to look into
and if you make this into a
major mod
then the problem potential possible
problem is that
you know then you don't have the you
know coloring the default coloring of
programming languages or whatever
so that all depends depends on what you
really want the command to be i mean if
if you all you want this command to be
is for bionic reading
of only
you know text
that you you know like a novel
not arbitrary email or whatever then you
know but anyway right now this this
command is convenient okay so
so make a backup copy it
go to back go back to talk show that's
it for today thank you guys for watching
okay
uh let's go to talk show so today's talk
show let's put the code here so
emax lisp paste the code showing browser
fantastic that's a code and now let's
sync text color it back to browser
refresh that's what we have okay
okay bye guys
now i'm going to set up for a um for my
next talk show you know recently i did a
lot so i'm gonna set a youtube
within the next
hour or two i think i'm going to do
another youtube
uh in in two or three hours
on keyboards on um
let me show you okay lots of tons of
keyboard new stuff i worked on keyboard
in the past um
week
okay so check out my youtube okay
bye guys
you