hello guys welcome to another episode of
Pixar talk show so today we are going to
code wolfam language on event of code
day four
okay so we are going to an event of code
and hopefully it's fun and but it's
probably going to be boring for you okay
for so if you you know skip this video
or watch my past videos more dedicated
tutorials through emacs or Wolfram
language lots of videos uh live stream
in the past you know Google recently
made a change to the to their YouTube so
that you only see my videos which
uh but mostly I just do live streams so
you click on the tab live stream that's
my you know more recent video since
since about two years ago
live stream it's all live stream because
I prefer live stream because live stream
is real it's not like edited and
prepared uh
which is uh you know more useful focused
on prepared video mode useful for a
topic but um
uh doesn't work
I ca I can do that but I prefer live
stream okay so live stream let's begin
so nobody watching okay good
so I'm just going to focus on the
problem then to code uh the window code
and by the way I'm on Odyssey so which
is great you follow me on Odyssey
eventually you know I'm hoping so every
so all my videos are archived on Odyssey
so it's permanent at least uh and
YouTube is very very corrupted you know
one day I'll just you know depends you
know so we have you know Odyssey I hope
to be my main
Okay so
so follow me on Odyssey okay
Odyssey also means Libra Libre or
something like that it's uh open source
and all the videos are archived by
blockchain I believe I haven't figured
out exactly how it works which is uh a
major thing for me to do
uh so okay so let's begin today's uh
sound talk show on um
um
at the end of code problem number four
okay day three so we finished day three
about events calendar okay
okay there it is number four and let me
recapt
let me recap
so we did Advent of
code
uh day one problem day two and day two
problem two so there's all code there
let me show you the code okay so you can
see I want to show you the power of
Wolfram language so they what if every
problem is a single line solution single
line
80 characters okay
let me take out take off my coats
so this is the day one solution here
uh
and uh let's open them
day one day two day two problem two day
three Okay so
day one solution one single line
Day 2 solution
one single line this this line
and day two problem two
one single line okay and so today uh in
day three
problem one one single line
problem two one single line you know
those variables you can just combine
them eliminate them and in particular
particularly in Wolfram language
it's prudent advice to never have any
variable at all you know so it's you
know since we are talking about uh
coding challenge so in in various
different languages you have a
particular way
that's idiomatic for example in Pearl
you say um
uh how how does a pearl people call it
you know in Python for example you hear
pythonic you know that's when your code
is approved by python the way Python
language fits the Python language
idiomatic to python Pro it's a jargon
that what's a
um
what's what's the jargon for Pearl it's
been a long time so I forgot I've been
coding Pearl from 1998 to
2004. uh in in a job
in your day job so so but in wufan
language there's a particular thing that
is no variables at all not a single one
even a temporary one like local variable
you know you can code your woven
language so there's
effectively the doesn't matter what
problem the entire you can
well it's an exaggeration but you can
almost code any problem I mean any
source code of wufam language is one
single line okay it's just many many
characters okay but technically it's one
single line like when
nested you know single line anyway so
here's a solution for uh so that's uh
day three and today we're gonna do day
four okay so let's let's start to code
it now
uh oh and yesterday yesterday
there is a question asking me about my
keyboard exposed okay let me show you
yesterday one guy I wasn't paying
attention you know in the beginning he
asked about he asked about exposed
Crystal okay so let me show you expose
Crystal
okay go to search just search for Sardi
keyboard you will find my website so
exposed night and there is a exposed
Crystal that is a good one okay but too
expensive that's a special one uh did I
actually have a page about it
uh no I I did talk about it on Discord
but I guess I don't have a
yeah so exposed this is a special
version basically exposed crystal is a
version of expose such that you see all
the keycaps they have special keycaps
for example this size you know you it's
rare to find those special sized keycaps
for example this old this space key this
enter you know so the exposed Crystal
they don't use that the every key is
standard keycap you know either size one
you you know these are called one you
size one unit or two U so so all the
keys are standardized keycaps so that's
a excellent point about it
so you don't have the you know special
special keycaps is actually good but if
you stick with the standard keycap sizes
then
it's kind of more flexible so because
you can swap you can buy different
keycaps and so on so X expose Crystal I
think it's a good one let me just show
it okay and then let's uh
so exposed crystal is a special one I
think they they make a special uh
you know special version so you can see
all the keycaps are standardized size
but
um
for two two hundred dollars so it's like
fifty dollars more than the more than
exposed night I think I'm not sure go
check go check them out okay I recommend
it they send me you know I did the put
you know the Expos came out about three
or four years ago so when they came out
they sent me a version to re for for me
to review you know they gave me free so
I have a review of it
uh and it's fantastic it's one of the
keyboard you know I have quite a few by
now ergonomic keyboards I've split or
whatever so every time I use expose
for periods of time because you know
sometimes I use it on bed sometimes I
want to change just you know every time
I basically the point is that every time
I use expose it's just a pure joy you
know I just
although it's One Piece One Piece has
Advantage but anyway my point in this
idea is it's a joy I really love it okay
and because my very first one this is
when uh 2017 so it's five years now my
very first one is the it's one one of
the earliest so
the firmware doesn't work anymore by the
time they have the software to program
the keys so I cannot program the keys
and a few months ago about three months
ago they sent me a new one so which is
the one I'm using right now and it's
just fantastic I did I did talk about it
so you go to my website you'll see my
video
so that I recommend you know there are
many others I also recommend you know I
cannot like recommend each and every one
that you know some of them you know this
Kinesis 360 is also excellent but too
expensive well I mean 500 so if you make
a lot of money if you are a professional
programmer well get it okay get it but
otherwise you you can get the old one
also expensive 320.
I still use you know is you know so but
I have so many so I can't
so for a change that's why I'm using
Xbox but this uh I really highly
recommend uh the Kinesis as well so then
this one is also fantastic plus it's
wireless okay I never used it it's not
really out yet so they still you know
it's a
you know they it's one of the small
startup uh Kickstarter so you can you
can buy this one order at I don't know
when they come out you know check them
check their website you'll see so this
is also good
um
okay so that that that I I like exposed
I like and the Apple maker this I just
discovered yesterday this is uh this
layout is called Alice layout
you know Alice layout I always find it
uh not good because what's the point you
know if you're gonna have split you
should just use a grid layout okay so I
never liked Alice layout I think it's
idiotic okay this Alice layout
but now yesterday I discovered this one
I it changed my mind this one is very
different I mean sick
it looks the same but there's a very
significant difference than the others
that is look at the arrangement look at
the vertical vertical line on the left
side they they reduced
significantly of the Stagger so it's
almost like a grid so now this one you
got a split keyboard and it's almost
like a grid so you I mean for you coming
from a standard Microsoft or Logitech
keyboard this is a great
uh
Evolution you know you know you can
adopt your typing habit and plus you got
extra thumb Keys you can change this key
to something else of course and it's
compact it's got arrow keys fantastic
necessary you know as opposed to the 40
or happy hacking no arrow keys not no
arrow keys is a major pin okay and it's
got page up page now
very useful
you know Arrow key is essential page up
and page now is extra you know plus
because these days you use a mouse
scroll wheel or or the Apple a track
pack pad or whatever or you can buy a
pen so I have a lot reviews here paying
input
you know a lot uh so for you if you are
want a gadget for Christmas you know uh
check out my website okay so I can use
my pen you can see
uh yeah okay let's get back to so you
can
you see my pen here I just right here so
you cannot I have to adjust I need I
need a camera
I need so donate okay if you guys like
my stuff
my videos my live stream my tutorials
interest you you benefit from it pay me
okay twenty dollars
or pay me regularly something five
dollars uh and I like to mention diyang
which is my biggest sponsor
okay uh so he uh you know Dion so he
patreon me a lot regularly
uh okay so so
oh yeah so this is yesterday's problem
oh I didn't close it so close it
so let's start Wolfram language uh
this is yesterday's problem
don't save
close let's start fresh
uh wait a minute why do I have this
emacs instance I forgot to shut down
okay so start the Wolfram language we're
gonna do Adventure code day
four
okay
so start
launch the kernel okay Wolfram language
okay so any questions comment post it
okay
video check audio check good check check
wait
what uh check audio Yeah okay audio is
going
okay so that's about keyboard so this
you know fake Alice is great I recommend
it so you can go to my website and buy
it
that's my Amazon affiliate affiliate
link okay so let's begin
uh
uh about this code so I run a discourse
Discord so called server you know so
here you can come here to um to enjoy
talking about chatting with other people
and me but for those of you coming young
people or Zoomers or coming from you
know Reddit you know uh fortune in
particular if you
you know come here here this is a place
we discuss real life that means you use
your real name real photo your family
talk about your family your your work
your business whatever real life okay
don't come here like the typical you
know maybe you are used to online read
it you know you just create account get
banned or whatever create a new you
don't care posting memes you know
you know whatever
uh we I don't like that you know come
here you if you if you want to know me
uh I get to know you and know other
people here and we talk about real life
stuff okay not posting random
opinions you know like who cares
whatever and you know typical online
situation which become very bad in the
past 10 years
so I hope you guys you know join my
Discord but you know
if you pre you know that's that's uh
uh do something meaningful you know just
it's not you know not another website
you just go there and do random
okay so let's let's
um
let's do at the end of uh code so today
so okay so let's begin
so we talked 20 minutes so far
uh so yeah so they go there
okay so start a
wufam language so we uh code Advent of
code number four let's see how far we
can go
okay I want to get some
my drinks
apple juice this is apple juice
and this is T
no it's not I don't think the live
stream is not on Odyssey
so
but Odyssey basically copy it over after
the stream is done so you know maybe one
day I'll do a live stream on Odyssey but
I haven't figured out yet
so oftenio if you know
about
Odyssey technical details
post the link on Discord okay because I
want to know exactly how it works the
blockchain and stuff any you know if you
find some like you post a lot
quality videos I think so if you find
something about Odyssey from a nerd you
know not commercial like you know from a
nerd that gives you detail about Odyssey
where they how they started and things
like that history or Libra you know
Libre how they call it you know
post it okay it you know it takes a lot
of time to dig into these things
like eventually I want you know for
example on my website right now I have
YouTube embedded but I I much rather
prefer to embed Odyssey but if I you
know embed Odyssey For example so for
example this video at the end of code
this is uh number one top day one okay
so if I embed
for example share okay
hold on so you can stop
share so you you have you have quite
choices for example if I copy that paste
here
uh then that's you know that's not
embedding but if I want to embed let's
see this one okay
um
copy it
okay post it wait that's not that's the
same hold on a second so
hold on a second so let me yeah let's
just do random we don't need to be
worried about focusing on the other end
of code okay for example so this is the
embed code
so it's a frame but you can see the URL
so I mean this other sort of thing I
need to figure out for example let's
copy this URL so you can see
you know the UIL differs
um by quite a lot you know you want to
figure out what's the parameter you know
so that I have full control you know
YouTube has become so corrupted like you
know in the beginning you guys probably
don't know because you you guys were
young YouTube is older than you than
many of you but for someone like me or
many others
you know you see when you stop you see
this this random other videos
you Google okay because when
they begin they specifically have a
parameter that you know they tell people
oh please you know do please do embed
you know YouTube to your blog when you
know at the time blog was popular you
know blogging got killed by Google
basically around 2010 Google Google
Reader you know maybe you guys haven't
heard of it
so anyways so in the beginning you know
it's Google specifically you know Google
is the do no evil company specifically
have a parameter that tells people you
know that welcome people to embed if you
don't like you know this random video
because maybe you are doing something
focused you don't want it to show some
random crap there's a parameter you can
say that this this doesn't show
okay but about about seven years ago
they they removed it I mean even if you
have that parameter on it doesn't do
nothing it still shows these you know
they try they they become so powerful so
rich 10 times more
fatter than before but then they they
need they have to do this you know
Google has become very very corrupt scum
uh
but you know Society becomes like you
don't care for a lot of you Zoomers so
you know let's just use another side oh
let's you know use ad blockers and those
you know like they don't have
responsibility they around and you
around so everyone just around
that's what chaos means Society like
like right now
chaos you know you're gonna around
you know you're gonna go to Saudi
Discord and pull po post
whatever and if you because I don't like
it ban you oh yeah that's normal you
just create another account that you
know happens already everywhere
that's chaos no responsibility no you
know you don't know what it means
anymore
so that's a state of that's a condition
of The Social Network I mean the uh web
okay so enough rent
so let's let's go back to coding okay
anyone here interested in coding
Okay so
Advent of code number four okay day four
so cancel that
okay so let's start coding then I have
to and start think
ing so we I already talked for 30
minutes
uh so I'm not sure how far we're gonna
go but I can probably finish today's
problem
I was hoping to do more than one
so space needs to be cleared before the
last supplies can be uploaded from the
ships
and so you know now I get a sense of how
the problem description goes so instead
of reading each and every word to
understand it that's not the way to go
you just glance over and basically
basically discover what is it's really
asking what is the problem okay
okay space needs to be cleared before
the last supplies can be unloaded from
the ships ships okay space needs to be
cleared and so several elves have been
assigned to the job of cleaning up
sections of the camp okay every section
has a unique ID number okay every
section has a unique ID number and each
elf is assigned a range of section IDs
so you have lots of IDs and a group of
them is assigned to an elf okay so you
essentially the ID is a set you have ID
set and you have certain partition of
the set that's a mathematician's jargon
meaning that you group the set into
subsets none overlapping
okay however some of the elves compare
their sexual assignments with each other
they've noticed that many of the
assignments overlap oh that's a problem
to try to quickly find overlaps and
reduce duplicated effort
the elves pair up and makes a big list
of the section assignments for each pair
okay the the the the elf's pair up and
make a big list of the section
assignments
for each pair that's a bit confusing
so for example
okay so this is by the way this is an
example of bad technical writing and bad
storytelling because
you see at the end of a code so far they
went to day four of this year
they they explain the problem but
incomplete and imprecise
but however they resolve that by using
the example so this example is not a
pure example this example functions as a
helper to further to actually explain
what the problem is you see this is my
this is my point of view from a
mathematician type of mind okay so I see
this so
alternatively what you really want to do
in in some optimal sense is that you
when you describe a problem that
description should be 100 fully
Standalone which is not the case here in
this case they describe the problem you
know incomplete but they use example to
further clarify the real meaning okay so
this
in some sense is imperfection in the
description okay
so anyway so a big list of section
assignments for each pair I I don't
quite get it for example consider the
following list of section assignment
pairs okay
uh two four six eight two three four
five can you guys read this
uh let's see
okay so partially hidden
there
I think I think so
okay so for the first few pairs this
list means
within the first pair of elves
the first elf was assigned sections two
to four okay well the second half what
was assigned section six six to eight
okay
the elves in second pair were used to
assign two sections okay
it's a second pair
the elves in the third pair were each
assign three sections
okay yeah two three four five okay
that's two elves okay elf pair so the
elves in the third pair were each
assigned three sections so that's five
six seven and seven seven eight nine
okay
one got section 567 the other got789
so you have each line
represents two elves and their ID the ID
they got
uh yeah the ID number okay
each line is two Elves and the ID two so
you each line is two sets
of ID
okay
and uh the ID May overlap you can see
there okay
this example this use this example this
uses single digit section IDs
to make it easier to draw
your actual this might contain larger
numbers
visually these pairs of section
assignments looks like this
blunt
you actually might contain larger
numbers
visually these pairs of section
assignments looks like this
so 2 4 is what
two three four okay
6A is six seven eight okay two three is
two three four five is four five
okay so they represent the ID is as some
kind of what is they trying to do what
is it trying to say
so they represent the ID numbers numbers
as a integer is that what they are
trying to say I don't know okay some of
the pairs have noticed that one of their
assignments fully contains the other
okay for example 2 8 2 2 8 fully
contains three to seven and six to six
is fully contained by four to six okay
in pairs where one assignment fully
contains the other
one elf in the pair would be exclusively
cleaned in sections their partner will
already be cleaning
so this seems like the most in need of
reconsideration
okay in this example there are two such
pairs
okay let's recheck the pairs one two
three four five six six pairs so let's
check here example one two three four
five six one seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve
okay so
um so basically
what it is trying to say is that of
these pairs several pairs some pairs
the one part is fully contained within
the other
okay
lousy writing you know I must say
yesterday I talked about this I think
the Advent of code their problem
description the story is not good okay
you know by the way there's a video of
the Advent of code guy talking about it
about two years I saw it on YouTube you
can just search for Advent of code the
the background story you know so so the
guy is a Christian apparently and he's
doing this
you know anyway you can go watch the
video
but the you know and you know you can
see he's very proud of himself you know
he in the when he talks about this
Advent of a code
you know obviously it's successful you
know it's very popular you're very
popular by now and but the way he talks
about code you can see there's a proud
you know he would say for example I you
know I have designed by now 200
uh puzzles
so
in his point of view he has designed
these puzzles you know so so he's like
you know it's it's just a programming
problem but
it's not uh you know well he's it's a
push to say that he designed the puzzles
okay and The Story So Far
you know there's another interesting you
might call a field of creating
programming problems with a story okay
so there are many ways to do you know
like for example some of you are
interested in fiction writing or
interactive fiction writing or mud you
know you program text oriented game
you know which kind of involves the
story you know you see a monster you can
turn left right or straight you know
things like that so there are many ways
actually to design like writing a novel
to to to first of all find a problem a
programming problem and then you have to
come up with a story to describe the
problem that's one way to go or you can
begin maybe you have a story first maybe
the story came from real life
programming about you know real life
coding then you simplify it you know so
you you start with almost the story
first
then
it becomes a precise problem so there
are many ways to do this but but anyway
for my judgment his the event of code so
far the description is pretty lousy and
confusing okay
so what is the problem here so some of
the pairs Okay so
given two pairs of sets of IDs so
sometimes wine is wholly content within
other in other words a proper subset
or just a subset okay
yeah what hap what happens if the two
sets are the same it didn't say here so
anyway the point is sometimes one of
them
is a subset of the other okay
so in this example there are two search
pairs let's see
uh
okay here is example 2837 okay
and six six four six okay
and what's the other one
this one two three four five
so to identify
whether one is subset of the other you
just check the N numbers okay the N
numbers must be equal or less than
for the beginning and for the end or you
swap them and test again okay so
so the question is in how many
assignment pairs does one range fully
contains the other okay we got the
problem already we know the problem so
so all these all these you know this
section for example as far as the story
storytelling point of view this section
is idiotic this extraneous
unnecessary and confusing you know this
section like visually this pairs section
might look like it's idiotic okay you
can remove this section
and the story
of this problem will actually be better
so basically you you just want to find
you know given a line
each line is two sets of numbers
consecutive integers
you want to find where the
you know one set is a subset of the
other that's all you have to do find
accounts okay count how many lines is
that
okay that's all you have to do okay so
suppose this is a input okay
okay so first of all let's assume it's a
it's a list then okay
X input yeah I mean assume it's a um
string so we begin wait we begin with a
string
uh then we
what do you do
that's a wolfam language so we begin
with a string first of all we want to
split
okay
split the string
X1 equals to you split the string by
what
by a comma okay
then
no actually you split the string by your
list okay then you X2 equals to
then you map a function you want to
split string again
so map let me write down the so map a
function to
X1 okay this function will speak as
string by so this is argument
by
um
by a comma okay
so that way then you
X3 equals to true expression
X2 so this will give you a list
of least
it will give you a list and each element
is a list
of
two things okay hold on a second
uh wait not to expression uh so
so basically now the problem is you got
a string like that
what you're gonna do with it you you
need to turn that into numbers
okay so
um so first of all
yeah you want to turn that into numbers
so you need to map again
you need to map it to X2 and map it to
the leaves okay now map the map function
is just like python or JavaScript or
lisp you know you map a function to a
list but wufam language gives allows you
to have a third argument that specify
the level that that like
you know typically in Unix is called
depth you know
you can specify a range of depth you
know root to third you know depth three
or you can specify a specific depth like
like second level or third level or you
can make it negative one that means
counting from the leaf so negative y
means map to just the leaves of a tree
okay so that's the power of the Wolfram
language you don't have this in any
other language not not any not Haskell
not a land not a camel not any of the
lisp not closure not
not not any not Java JavaScript not
python not Ruby not
not PHP I have not seen any programming
language has this very powerful if
you're gonna write this yourself it's
very complex okay you're gonna do a loop
and check the depth very complex
but here is just one line okay so let me
get work this out so so you split by a
comma then use uh then you spit by a
dash
foreign
okay let's do it one shot okay two
expression you can use
um
you can use a add sign add sign is a
shortcut for f something so F bracket
arguments you can just say F at
the argument okay
so to expression
um
let's copy it let's try it
but before I try it I want to see
yeah okay that's correct the I'm
checking I'm double checking the
the operator precedence
okay so this is one function this is
this function we'll split the string
you know this the argument this pound
sign stands for the argument such as 226
it's a string so split by the minus sign
you got
you got two streams which are numbers
okay then you two expression that turns
it to an actual number
Okay so
I think that's it okay let's try it try
it
there it is you see how beautiful it is
fantastic so we got the list of numbers
now it's much easier to check to work
with now all we have to do now
X4 equals to now we just need to check
okay
for example let's work on this one
we want to know if one of them is a
subset of the other so you take the um
the first part
[Music]
you compare there they should be either
equals two or less than
equals true or less than so
you know I can code it right away but
I'm
I'm thinking if there is a more
efficient way okay
uh in Wolfram language usually they are
generated not equals to Designed okay
anything else you guys are saying
that's no private info just spit your
appointment
what
I don't know what you're talking about
[Music]
okay so let's go back to the problem so
you want to find
[Music]
okay so let's see
so this is the input basically now you
want to write a function to see if one
is a subset of the other
Okay so
we can suppose this is a b
X Y so you want to check
a
less than
X less or equals to X
and
B is less or equals to Y okay that's
essentially what you need to do
that or
the other way okay
that's what you want to check
now
if this is true then that means one is a
subset of the other okay
okay very easy so now what we do so okay
we we write the function so
and let's just say F1 okay
if everyone takes
an argument okay
X1 takes an argument let's write it this
way x uh f equals to
uh
function
okay
and uh
here is
the
yeah that's not right this way this
right this way have
you let's use pattern matching okay
a b
X Y so F takes one argument which is a
nested list of two you know two items a
b and X Y so okay
then we need to say
clear F because when you whenever you
define your pattern matching you better
have a clear before because otherwise
you have
other rules you know you want to clear
just in case
so once you have that then you just
return that okay so
you even need that
okay so that's that's that's about it so
so this function
do that
hey
this or equals to
X be less or equals to y or the other
way around okay
okay so yeah
then we just X4 equals to
map again almost everything we use is
map map the function to X3
okay
that's that's right that's that's almost
it
that's it okay let's try it
one shot coding no trial and error my
style
oh
incorrect it's incorrect because
apparently the f is not applied
if it's not applied because the pattern
doesn't match yeah of course we got that
wrong we got it wrong we forgot the
low line so you can you need to add a
low line that means anything so this
means this underscore low line means
anything and we give it a name y
same same for x and a b there okay so
let's now do it again
copy copy all
paste run
true true false false true
okay that's the result but that result
is incorrect
oh yeah that's incorrect because our
function logic is incorrect
so to check the subset you
so you have a b and X to Y A to B X to Y
so
first of all
a is less than x
let's see how how does this go
uh we got it wrong okay so a b x y
now it's better if I write it with the
pen but anyway
it's not then so a b x y
yeah it's better if I you know this is a
time for
so you have a b and X Y okay so if one
is a subset let's say a b is a subset of
X Y then you have something like that
okay
so a is greater than x
this is true greater than x and
and B is
um
okay let's see let's write it this way
more logical
and
that's a logical symbol for end
B less or equals to Y okay on the other
hand if they are swapped then you have
okay that's that's uh that's what we
want that's a correct logic
so let's modify this
so let's
uh less or equal yeah so that's all
equal that's right
X
a
and b y okay and here
a x y b
a x y b okay remove that okay copy all
paste run
false false false true true Force
yeah I think that's also wrong
force force
okay this should be true
what our logic is wrong what the we
there are two such pair that's true okay
well
is I mean the answer is correct but
um
for each individual line it may be wrong
so
one is a subset of the other so which
one is a subset
two three four five no five seven
seven nine no two eight three seven
two eight three seven so that's one
and six six four six
that's two
oh actually our answer is correct
okay our answer is correct
anyone else watching comment
okay we got it correct I think that's
the answer okay let's double check one
more time
so which of these lines is a subset of
the other
not the first one
two three four five not the second one
five seven seven nine not the third one
two eight three seven yes three seven is
a subset of two to eight okay
and six six four six six six is a subset
of four six that's right so these two
one two three four five four and five
okay so our answer is correct now all
you have to do is count the number of
true okay so how do you do that let's
see
uh
uh cases okay cases cases return
the number of
I mean it
it filters out
elements that does not match okay so
so we just want uh cases true for
example let's try it
you see then then all we have to do is
just uh
get the length Okay so X5
that's that's our answer
okay let's copy it again it's it's
do this
copy
paste
run
two
fantastic now
let's put it back
syntax color it
showing browser so this is today's talk
show that's a code
this one single line you know you can
combine them into one single line that's
but first of all let's try the actual
puzzle input okay
so copy your copy
here
new file save as
a domain of code
uh four
day four and today's date text okay drop
to diet and change space to underscore
rename them okay and
okay let's copy that
copy the file link close it
uh wait
paste the file link here make a list
linkify
there it is
okay that's the input
select or copy
okay let's go back to Wolfram language
paste it
okay and now let's add semicolon to
suppress the output
that's the answer are you sure yes I'm
sure 538
and submit
that's the right answer congratulations
hello Greg and dark video online what
does that mean
okay you are one gold star closer to
collecting enough star fruit okay
continue to part two
okay fantastic now let me show you let's
go back to the Wolfram language code let
me show you how the techniques of
condensing make it elegant the woven
language code for example I have said
before in wolfen language almost any
code doesn't matter how long you can
you can you can technically you can make
any arbitrary long you know doesn't
matter it's median lines of code you can
make it one single line of just sequence
of function calls let me demonstrate how
that is done okay so for example here
let's um
okay so let's let's start to do this
okay here is the actual function
uh
she is the actual function so let's for
example
yeah the input input is just input Okay
so
we first of all
remove the variables X2
and by the way this can be written
in a much better way by
okay and this can be written
this way
and
okay
okay that is just that
okay let's let me add
paren so it's more clear about the
operator precedence okay so that's what
you have to do
then this part
let's put a paren on it
cut it
put it here you don't need that map you
still need yeah
so now you don't need X3 anymore
so this line is X3
cut
you know so you want to
this is X3 now
all you have to do is you say
slash dot that stand for the function
replace all okay and how you want to
replace
uh that's this is this part okay so let
me show you
okay replace
okay this is the pattern that let's
let's let's put them into a separate
line okay this is a pattern
replace by
okay
and uh
[Music]
okay so hold on a second let's let's
open a new one it's
make
make these
hold on a second let me show you okay
okay so we don't need that don't need
that okay so now it's just the input and
we don't need this one
uh eggs for
oh yeah so we don't need that anymore
so
but let's test
this first
okay you need them to be one single line
to make sense okay
copy that
paste
fantastic okay
now you have to do is just
add parenthesis
delete it
put it here
okay you don't need the X5 here
so you can see one single line solution
okay copy the whole thing
paste it here
fantastic and also let me mention this
again in Wolfram language the formatting
of the code is on the Fly then
automatically
can you see if your window is large they
format them put the line endings in the
appropriate
appropriate place by the syntax
of the language so for example this
slash dot that means replace all you can
see that little pop-up that means
replaceable so that's that's appropriate
place
to break the line because all the things
before is one expression syntactical
unit
and the other part is the other
expression the syntactical unit you can
okay also you can double click it will
progressively select the syntactical
unit
each time you double click your expand
or press the control dot let me show you
so for example control dot you see
that's one unit synthetical unit
and because of the
mathematical Wolfram language syntax is
similar to lisp nested expression
therefore any syntactical unit also
corresponds to a semantic unit so you
see that string exp that's also
a semantic unit okay
so expand you see now it's a function
expand paren expand so that's one
syntactical unit and also is a semantic
unit okay expand parenthesis expand now
that's again syntactical unit and the
semantic unit expand map the whole thing
now if I expand again you include
the whole basically the whole uh
including including to up to this part
okay up to here
let me show you okay do it you see
then do again current then cases you
know the argument for the cases select
all then that slash slash is the
post-fix notation like the Unix pipe
okay so let's do again you see so
so that's a demonstration oh wait cancel
let's undo and do okay that's a
demonstration of the Wolfram
the mathematica notebook okay you have
automatic formatting you never ever
manually add a you know return or indent
that like the industrial
programmers idiots
including C C plus plus Java C sharp
JavaScript python you know
or that
but about 10 years ago they improved
beginning with Golan automatic
formatting of the entire source code but
it's still manual you know you you cover
command your entire your it will format
your source code
of the whole file or entire directory of
files okay that's a significant step
you know after 30 years of the C and C
plus plus in Java in Pearl it these
idiots no idea you talk to them they
don't they don't understand they they
say you are a troll including the lisp
and in particular in particular come and
these idiots okay they don't know what
you're talking about
and Tio 2010 2008 also Golan began the
GoPhone man okay I talked about this in
my previous video so that revolutionized
this
woof but who fam language is still one
step far ahead you never even have to
format at all it's automatically done on
the Fly by the editor okay you can you
can you see that
and this began in 1997 okay starting
with wolfam language three okay this is
a point I want to emphasize I have more
than 10 articles on my website
saudi.info
okay that's why my my hatred my deep
hatred with the industrial coders
you know this C C plus plus these
hackers this you know idiots extreme
okay can you see
automatic form formatting on the Fly and
you know there's no intent there's no
type character anywhere the whole thing
is one single lie and in the
Wolfram language with the meta syntax
you can you can the your whole code can
be done can be coded this way okay
one million lines of code becomes one
single line
okay and functional programming no
variables there's zero variables in this
code and you can do that you know in
fact this input if you want to you can
move it to here so there's not one not
even temporary local variables okay
and you can rework the code so that the
input is at the end anyway
okay we solve the problem number one
let's go to problem number two
okay
let's drink some tea
okay so let's clean up yeah so let's put
this back to the browser
syntax color it
saw HTML mod in emac Beast showing
browser
so we can see today's code oh you forgot
to syntax color the other one do it
showing browser
okay
so to this code first version is easy to
understand okay you have five variables
second version one single line it's the
same thing actually
okay now
day four problem two
okay
okay day four problem two part two it
seems like there's still there is still
quite a bit of duplicate work planned
instead the elves would like to know the
number of pairs that overlap at all
okay so instead of a fully a subset you
just want to find
pairs that overlap okay
so you know above the example the first
two pairs 2 4 6A and two to three four
to five don't overlap okay well the
remaining four pairs
do okay
and here is a further explanation yeah
okay
so in this example the number of
overlapping assignment pairs is 4.
okay
how many assignment pairs do the range
overlap okay
very easy to start
all we have to do is change this line
you know this logic this this function
determines the subset
okay whether one is a subset now you
just need to change it tweak the greater
or equal to then you will get the
overlap okay very easy so
in fact it's simple I think okay let's
code it
uh okay let's code with this example
because it's easier to understand
by the way this one line thing that's
great but it's not practical Okay so
you know this is the most elegant that's
true one single line and but it's not
practical because in Practical code you
need to maintain it this single line if
you have one million lines of code in
one single line it's hard to uh
to edit and debug You know despite all
the
features of syntactical you know
selection and all so okay anyway so
okay let's that's all we have to do is
modify this line
okay so now you want overlap so let's go
back to uh
um
to uh pad this drawing pad and you see
this fantastic in the pen computing
and I said so let's see so how do you do
how do you check this
um
subset this is how you check subset now
you want to check overlap
so overlap let's see
a b
x y
you want to check overlap or you have to
check is just B and X okay
so B and X
oh you have to check is
end of a pair to the beginning of the
other pair okay but you also have to
swap them so you if
so you can check
overlap so if they are equal they also
count as overlaps so
b equals through X or b equals B is
greater to X
greater than equal x so that's one case
or
X
wait oh
and you have the other case of
x y
a b so
Y and a so o x equals to
y greater or equals to A okay that is
the formula
save it
okay B greater than equals to X and
let's double check
y greater than or equals to A so
yep
bxya greater equal
BX
y a okay
that's it
let's try it
paste
run it
okay incorrect
true true true true true incorrect
uh
oh yeah so
truly content overlap
right
wait okay so this logic is missing
something the logic we are using here is
missing something
so here B
we have to think about this
okay that is incorrect so Greg and dark
says
you know why is from language so much
further ahead than other languages okay
then he says but unfortunately we'll
find scripting language is not a real
programming language it is only a
scripting language for woofer math
engine so it's not like you could use
the scripting thing to make computer
programs that's false okay
that's force uh
maybe possibly you are trying to say is
that wufan language is not suitable for
writing a kernel for example a printing
system
Linux
but other well because it's not a low
level language it's not open language
it's not C it's not C plus plus it's not
Java okay but however within language is
is a complete programming language
you can compare to python JavaScript
Ruby PHP Lua you can compare to all of
them every feature in fact all this
language all those languages
they are subset of Wolfram language okay
so you can in fact the Wolfram Alpha or
you can use wufan language to write the
wolf web server or any server any
massive parallel Computing server and in
fact that is how it's done at Wolfram
research and in fact they
much of the Wolfram language itself is
written in Wolfram language okay so it's
not you know that's a common
misconception because the typical
Industry Program must have no
experience have no contact with Wolfram
language well first of all because these
days it's not open source you know so
they they just blind themselves
like like a pony you know like the pdsm
pony
you have the blinders so they reviews
you know they don't do anything that
they don't know they don't they don't
use it
okay so um
and that's you know then we can get into
an interesting topic how do you define
your language you know and true
incomplete you know that hello George
you're pretty late we already solved the
problem one so you can see the solution
is one single you you missed some
interesting discussion about single line
with a language code and formatting so
go back like 20 minutes
uh prior okay anyway so we are trying to
solve the problem too the second part
day four and we are having I mean there
is a logic issue so
let me finish this and that'll be it
five moment ten ten more minutes
so uh
so right now we want to determine
overlap so how do you determine overlap
let's look at our notes
how do you so how do you determine
overlap
B is greater than x given a pair a to b
x to Y first of all B must be greater
than x okay
and what about a b
I mean what about a and Y
oh
so if B is greater than
X we also make have to be make sure that
a is
um
a is less than y okay
so given this pair a b x y we have to
make sure
a is less than y so let's write it down
a is less or equals to y
and
okay and that
so either that's the case or
X is less or equals to
B
and okay that's our logic
correction
save
the power of pain Computing now back to
e Max
okay so modify just have to modify this
parts
so a minus a
so here is a
less than equals to
Y and B greater or equals to X okay and
the second part is
the second part is x b y a
okay I think that's correct now copy or
go back to refime land paste eval
4 that seems correct false Force true
true true true okay
so he says
yeah fantastic we are ready to go that's
the correct logic but now
a little digression showing the power of
Wolfram language you see
so we have a logic expression here
you know
there are many ways to do this logic you
know when you have a you know you want
to determine if they overlap you know
and the the way that comes up to me
right away is this way okay but that but
there are many more equivalent so you
want to find the logical equivalent that
may make your code
do less comparison
okay so how do you do that
so we want to simplify this expression
okay
let's simplified let's let's try
maybe that okay at previous output there
it is
what
God it really truly did simplify what
but this isn't that what we did before
and it's wrong
well yeah that's what we did before but
that was wrong
why is that
what
yeah because we did that before and it
would be that's incorrect
let's try
okay so if we do this
I thought
yeah we must typed wrong
a less than one a less than why wait
before we had B greater than x
y greater than a
oh before we used or it should be end
but anyway the Wolfram language so you
see you can simplify it to that okay
yeah okay so that that does it
but let's go back to our original
because this is more intuitive you know
you check four numbers but actually
all you have to do is this okay so now
let's go to the input
so copy that
paste it here
but now we want to get the real input
for today's problem
which we have in here copy it close it
now
the real input
paste it there
and add semicolon again to suppress the
output
bring it
792 are you confident yes
792.
are you sure
yes
that is the right answer you are one
gold star to close uh you are one gold
star closer to collecting a Nerf star
fruit fruit okay so we finished day four
and it's been 90 minutes
okay half of it is talking about some
other things I think that's it for today
90 minutes I mean so day four is done
fantastic and now let's clean up we shut
down in
four minutes or so
so let's show in browser that's that's
our code fantastic and here is program
one problem two wait we didn't
um
yeah so let's do it
cut
and add a section
let's say part two
okay and remove the date
and the input let's move the input down
and also that
okay
select or cut section
part one
paste here
and remove the date and the syntax color
the whole show in browser so this is
today's fruit part one
solution okay part two solution they're
all just one single line okay that's it
now we
going to let's see I've got this huge
and see if there's something interesting
highlight I want to copy and paste
copy and paste this one
before we do that let's make it
original font size okay
I'm going to copy that
move from language
and we want to
show this part
the simplification of logical
expressions
highlight it
okay
so I can put into my
website
okay
bye guys if you like my video pay me
okay go to my exaggery.info you'll see
PayPal patreon
20 bucks five bucks
you know pay
uh Services you like
bye