good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh
today is July 26th midnight five minutes
after midnight
San Francisco time and today we are
going to talk about math algebraic
structure a combinatorial exploration of
algebraic structure now let me set up
these this stupid you know this this OBS
I always have problems with the video
okay maybe that's that's fine so let's
see if I'm alive yes I'm alive okay so
see get this I got this stupid camera
this logitech 920 in which is extremely
bad okay don't buy it
yeah it's still no good okay maybe that
then that's not big enough you know if
this okay so let's let's fix this knit
so we have one person here say I and
this is getting silly it's becoming
small and no good
okay let's just do it it's just too like
that okay so we're gonna talk about
interesting stuff the combinatorial
exploration of of group like structure
so so you guys say hi here okay type
something so we're gonna talk about that
and what else something else you know
maybe something else but we're gonna
start with that I guess so guys if you
are new here type ok type your
thoughts/opinions whatever just say hi
okay that way the video will be better
so we're gonna talk about these group
like structures now I did a video like
so right now it's after midnight so I
have to keep my voice low and I did a
video about 2 months ago that's where I
teach about group theory ok I teach you
good theory which is a fundamental part
of mathematics for mathematicians but
you don't need any math background so
you can learn cool theory very
fundamental it's like ABC for every
mathematicians group theory ok the
basics of group theory and you can check
out that video you know just such my
name on YouTube my channel look for
group theory and symmetry so that's one
our introduction you know a pretty good
one on group theory so if you are
programmer my main audience are
programmers you know you know it's a
good to learn but today we can't we
cannot talk about something similar so
in math there's a branch called haja
bruh the primary branches of math
classic readers analysis geometry and
algebra okay analysis is like calculus
it's like you study infinity and
infinitely small numbers and continuity
things like that derivatives integrals
that's all analysis now R Chopra is
about structure we're gonna which is
what we're gonna talk about and then
there's another topic of geometry they
are kind of all interrelated but anyway
classically math are divided into these
these three main branches analysis
algebra and geometry okay so we're gonna
talk about group theory group structures
ok so there's something interesting so I
was reading Wikipedia about these
different group like structures so what
what are what is a group like structure
let me show you ok let's see what I want
to say oops ok groups the nature of
associative property of algebra ok let
me let me relax okay so in big group
structure
it's amazing you see all these amazing
beautiful abstract pictures you know
they say math is the most the beauty of
math lies in its you know the beauty of
math is so abstract its austere that is
the beauty of math you cannot see it
it's intangible but well but sometimes
you can represent them as you know
pictures and you know they show the
structure of math so all these are these
are cyclic you know representation
graphic graphical representation of
cyclic
oops you know group is groups is about
symmetry so as oh these are dihedral
groups then we have cyclic groups you
know all these are groups you know it's
called groups in math groups is
basically a structure a meter I'm going
to explain what group is okay so you
know this is just a warm-up
say hi okay say hi type type your
opinions type where you came from so so
I was reading about this so let me tell
you what is group about what what are
these structures about okay so and this
is very interesting I was reading this
and I was thinking about something and
there's some questions I do not
understand you know to understand you
know it would be you know to understand
these fully is like it's basically like
a mastered master's degree in you know
mathematics anyway so let me show you
what is a group let's see should we go
to Wikipedia and use the group
definitions okay okay group this is a
group abstract this is the abstract
definition of a group so
okay so this is abstract definition a
group a group a group is a set and a
operation binary operation on the set
such that the binary operation satisfies
some axioms you know some requirements
so a group which is a it's a set let's
say s okay we denote the set was s in a
binary operation we write it like that
for example let's it's okay we we write
it like that it can be any symbol in
this matter so on the set so you know a
binary operation operation on the set
such that the binary operation satisfies
these axioms so first of all
now let's just go to Wikipedia I'm not
so ready ready today
we add all the requirements are here
actually associative key because
associativity identity invertibility and
commune community VT okay which is not
required yeah
so let's write out associativity
identity inverse okay I tend to G
inverse associativity had identity
inverse and community of G okay so a
group of is a set of things s let's say
let's say the set is okay so let's say
ABC okay the set has three things a and
B and C you know three letters and let's
say the operation is denoted by a star
sign okay and so the binary operation
okay so so for example a times B equals
to something okay and you know P times C
equals to something and same thing for
over for every two elements so the
binary operation the reason it's called
binary because it takes two elements so
you take two elements and equals to
something equals to another elements in
the set okay and so P times C can be
anything anything you want
doesn't matter it's not required in a
group definition but as long as you have
a binary operation on any two elements
in a set you return another element in a
set that's that's what binary operation
means
so but the binary operation must satisfy
some axioms one is associated and one is
identity and one is inverse so
associativity means it means a B times C
equals to a associativity means this
meaning that you you use the group
operation or any two elements its switch
is a way
you have high associativity on any two
elements then you apply it with another
elements we are equals to basically
amount amounts to order so a B first
then multiplied by C we are equals
through B times C first they multiplied
by a so ABC are any elements in a group
so if this is satisfied we say that it
has associative property for for this
binary operation okay so that's one of
the requirement so when you have a set
and a binary operation such that is
satisfy this it's one of the requirement
if you want to call this thing a group
you know a group is a set in the binary
operation so there is identity identity
identity means a times I equals to I
times a equals to a let me write it this
way okay so there is a element we called
I such that any element time is that
element equals to the element itself you
know a times I equals to a and I times a
equals to a to so ap a can be in any
element or it requires is that their
eggs there is a element you know there
is a you know element you know in a
group such that these two are true and
we call this element I the identity
is called the identity element or simply
just identity okay and another
requirement is the inverse element for
any element X there is another element
we write we write negative x such that x
times negative x equals to hi okay and
okay and negative x times x equals y
yeah so these are the requirements when
when when you have a binary operation
and you have a set you have a binary
operation that operates on the set any
two elements returns on other elements
in a set and if this binary operation
satisfies these three properties then we
call this whole thing we call it a group
that's what it means
abstractly
okay so that's a group now you see this
table you see this table that there are
all these properties properties are
listed above then on the left side the
different names mathematicians give to
the structure that satisfy this property
you know the properties are totality
associativity identity invertibility and
community with a commute commute to
commute commutativity so what that what
does I mean for example group we talked
about group we you know we discussed the
definition of a group so if we look at a
group the first property totality what
does that mean that means it basically
it just means that the binary operation
the output of the binary operation the
return value is always an element in a
set you know if it doesn't become
something else you know so that's a CV
requirement but anyway that's what
totality means over here and
associativity we discussed identity we
discussed you know there's a element
such we had a I equals to a in IAE quest
to hey when there's inverse element we
discussed then there's a communit
commutativity which means a times B come
here
community with tea coming to tea with
tea which means a times B equals to B
times a you know basically it means
older doesn't matter by the way the
binary operation we use this notation
but there is another notation we can say
functional notation so if you are
familiar with functions in programming
that we would write this as a P equals
to C we write it like that the C equals
to a you know this is the functional
notation so let me put some
these are the group axioms one two three
and this is what commutativity means now
a group does not require these okay
now let's go back go back and look at
the table so you have these properties
now you see this table shows you know
what the structure names mathematician
calls for various if they satisfy
certain certain properties but not
others
now this sorry so I was reading this
today and there is a very interesting
thing I was thinking now I'm pretty sure
I'm pretty sure that mathematicians has
studied this before but however at one
time I asked I asked a mathematician
John bass and he told me he have not
seen it basically okay I'm gonna expand
when you look at this table what do you
want to know is what is the nature what
is the nature of these properties I mean
so what so what is identity you know
okay we understand identity basically
means there's an element you know such
that does not matter what that element
is combined with any other it will
always return the other element so it's
as if you know identity element
functions like you know it does nothing
you know it it just returns the other
elements you know so you want to
understand you know I want to understand
you know as a mathematician you want to
understand what is the nature of
identity so for you know we so you know
in a thought process like we are
exploring what it really means
so we can see the definition of a
identity element so it you know we
usually say so there exists an element
such that you know such a such and that
these two equations are satisfied so it
seems that the item identity element is
something something about a special
element in the group you know in a set
or in other way to to say it is that
when we define our binary operation we
we make sure that you know this happens
you know there's you know there's an
element such that it times anything
returns the other thing P you know so
that's what we are doing you know we are
I'm trying to explore you know like look
into the nature what is the nature of
identity so what what do you mean by the
nature of it you know for example you
could cook up any things you know any
property up here and you know so why is
you know so one of the question is why
are these properties you know listed in
this table why not others for example
there are many other you could cook up
many other requirements you could say
you know you know if the binary
operation is such that you know eight
times itself five times equals to an
identity element you know you could just
say anything and you could put it here
then you have more you know different
structures so why what what is it that
makes you know what is the qualification
for these you know properties listed on
on this table
now one perspective is that we could
simply say oh this is just historical on
this this is simply you know historical
you know just because mathematicians
happened to look into these particular
things but that's not a good answer
because when we study math we we really
want to actually look usually okay it's
almost always there is something
intrinsic something critical something
you know it's like a defining quality
you know if such if something satisfies
these then it changes you know it has
important consequences or it changes the
nature of things you know suddenly black
becomes white you know something like
that
you know oh you know that is what the
defining quality means you know so if
you have something your all or sometimes
we say it's a characteristics of
something so if something holds some
certain property we can say oh this will
always behave this way that will always
behave that way you know we want to
capture the essence you know math is the
heart of math is all about you know
capturing the essence of things so when
we look at this table you really want to
know you know what is the why are these
properties on top you know what made
them what what is the defining qualities
for them to appear you know these things
on top so that is the that is the that
is the main thing I'm looking into you
know that's you know today's topic
that's that is why I started to look
into this find this interesting
okay that's one thing so so we have you
know we try to explore what is identity
then what about invertibility
invertibility you know we can see that
invert abilities means you know x times
the inverse of x equals to I the
identity elements so the definition of
inverse relies on the concept of
identity so the inverse element you know
so inverse at in you know and identity
these two things are related but right
now right now we I don't understand
exactly what is you know what captures
what is the nature of identity yet
now you see there's a difference between
definition and the essence of things for
example so what is identity we know what
is identity by this definition you know
this element you know it combines with
anything returns the other thing that is
a definition and it's simple enough but
what I want you know what we want is to
to see White Way is identity important I
mean what Qualis qualify it you know
what what makes it what's the difference
does it make you know that that's the
thing so anyway we try to explore the
you know the the nature of identity and
we try to look at invertibility so
identity we are we are not sure exactly
what what is its nature you know I think
one way to find out is to study all
these structures you know studies
structures that does not have identity
requirement and see how it differs from
structures that has the identity
requirement you know maybe if we think
about this for one hour you know two
hours like you can do it you know I I I
might do it you know like take a walk
and think about it you know look at you
know look at simple structures like a
set with only two elements or only three
and you can write a computer program to
enumerate all possible binary functions
on the you know on a set of three
elements so yeah actually that's that
may be something I'm going to do you
know so you enumerate all possible
binary operations on a set of three
elements then you know you have a you
have different structures and you can
see which one satisfies identity which
one does not
and do the same thing for four elements
or two elements then maybe you'll see a
pattern maybe you'll see a pattern then
then at that point maybe we all realize
we all see what is the real significance
you know the essence of the identity
thing so that's one of the thing you
know we you know we we want to study
identity and then in what ability we
already talked about it apparently it's
dependent identity concept now
commutativity which is you know very
simple a times B equals to B times a we
know that for now
well let's not ignore let's talk about
that okay come here
commuted commutativity that's very
simple concept it simply means the you
know whether the order matters you know
so why is this significant this one is
obvious because obviously when you have
a binary operation you know a function
that takes two arguments so then there's
a situation you know whether the order
matters that's you know that's just
nature it just happens there's this
situation whether D if you swap the
order they come out the same thing so we
can see so that is the commutativity if
the order does not matter then we say
it's communicative you know order
doesn't matter so but what is the nature
you know what is the heart of
commutativity this part we really
understand well because because you know
I'm trying to explain the way I think
because you know why is so so what is
the why why is this one important
because
because it's a natural condition that
happens you know the community like once
you define the concept of a binary
operation you have a function that takes
two things and return another thing once
you you have the very concept of binary
operation then you have this situation
where whether the order matters that is
commutativity so we can see you know
when we study these you know groups you
know abstract structure we can see why
this admin becomes you know we can see
why this column is there because you
know it's just you have this situation
you need to talk about but so far it's
not so clear to us you know why we have
this identity thing and invertibility
thing I'm not sure I don't know ok let's
let's go to the other okay so what about
totality now totality we talked about
you know basically when you have a
binary operation then you have a result
the result is either you know part of
the set that is a requirement
so that's totality which is not very
interesting because obviously when we
when we want to study a set and in the
end a binary operation on the set we
require it returns something you know
it'll be a value is something in the set
otherwise it does not make sense for us
so this totality thing is here we
understand what that is but why is it
here you know it doesn't seems
interesting the reason it's here is
because apparently for mathematicians
there are situations when they study
many you know math same math same things
or physics things there's a situation
where you do not know the domain of a
function so when you have a function
which but you don't know exactly you
know what what is a set of possible
input use you say that function is
partial function so anyway it's just
something that happens mathematicians
happens to have you have total function
you have partial function total function
means a function that where at every
elements in a given set can be the input
to the function partial function means
only parts only a subset of a given set
can be the input arguments to the
function you know that's partial
function but it turns out you know when
you study physics or math you know there
are some situations you don't know
what's the domain of the function you
know the function you know you you know
the definition of a function but you
don't exactly know you know the you do
not have the exact subset so that's why
you have partial function so this
totality requirement is here I suppose
it's just because it's convenient for
mathematicians when they study you know
both things they can see oh how these
have you know totality requirement or it
does not have totality requirement in
other words the table parity is sometime
it's called closure you know just means
a function that returns an element and
that elements also belongs to the set
the domain of the function U when this
property is satisfied you say the you
say the function is closed you know you
call it closure so anyway we have looked
at all these different properties now
there's another one
that's associative 'ti now this one is
also very interesting associativity and
I do know what is the nature of
associate associativity so I'm going to
explain so in this table we understand
so far we understand the nature of
karmic commutativity and we understand
the nature of associativity I'm going
which I'm going to explain but the
identity we don't quite understand what
is its nature and invertibility which is
in turn depends on identity but we have
talked about how do we explore that it's
very interesting so let me talk about
associativity then then let me talk
about a combinatorial extra exploration
exploration of these the whole thing so
what is associative ax T I have written
an article here now there is a funny
comics funny video
now this video is not about
associativity but is rather about you
know about operation precedence that
nummy-nummy show that um this video is
wrong should be like that
silence display narration apparently
it's a Korean game show you know so she
made a mistake anyway so associativity
so where does associativity came from
now remember associative 'ti is is this
property this property okay it's also
written here in here I use the symbol
plus sign but the symbol doesn't matter
you can use any symbol so when a binary
operation satisfy this we say it's
associative so why why do you have this
you know it appears you know like for
commutativity it's obviously about order
you know a times B or B times a but then
the associativity it appears to be older
but then you know it's hard to explain
the key to understand this associativity
why is it there I mean you know what
made this happen I mean why do you have
this
what made it happen the key to see that
is this if you rewrite this operator by
a function notation so you write it like
this so f is our binary operation so we
say a P then you say
f oops wait a second I got screwed up
somewhere okay here so we say function
first argument second of the second
argument okay it's equal to BC so his
equals two so that's what it means you
know we read it this way so this is the
notation using operators and this is the
notation using functional notation so we
call a function and two arguments and
the first argument is again calling a
function with two arguments a B so this
means you you call function a B you know
FA B it returns a thing then you call F
again on that thing and see it returns a
value now as opposed to the other way
you call F a B you know as a second
argument then you apply the function
again with a so if you do it this way if
you write it this way you can see it is
about order you know over here using the
binary operator notation you kind of not
sure because parentheses means to it
first you know but with the functional
notation you can clearly see it's kind
of about order okay so we can see that
associativity is kind of a nested
application of functions now this is the
him this is important so associativity
is actually about nesting
functions okay and okay so so why does
it happen you see it happens it happens
in a natural way
just like the commutativity so it
happens when you have a binary operation
okay there's three things that made it
happen one you have a binary operation
when you define a binary operation when
you define a binary operation the first
thing that happens is you have the other
thing you know the commutativity issue
that comes up okay so you have a binary
operation then you have a elements you
have a set of three elements okay you
have a set of three elements at least
three or more it doesn't happen when
when your set is only two elements but
when your set has three elements at
least okay and when you nest functions
that is you apply the binary operation
twice you know at least two times then
you start to have this situation you
have this situation called associativity
that is you know whether this is equal
to that so you can see associativity
it's just like commutativity it happens
naturally you know it happens naturally
you have this phenomenon that occurs you
know whether these two equal or whether
they do not equal it just occurs
naturally so now if we go back to the
table
if we go to okay a mess go back to the
math blog you go back to the table you
can now we look at all the properties we
can see now we understand what
associative T we understand the nature
of associativity okay so that's that's
the first thing we want to explain you
know we want to understand the nature of
these properties you know why why they
are there so so far we don't know why
identity is there we don't know why
invertibility is there and we can find
out by writing a program that enumerate
all possible structures have two
elements and three elements and four
elements you know all possibly you know
we create a binary function you know all
possible binary functions and we can see
which one of them will have identity and
which one we are not then maybe we will
see a pattern you know and then we can
maybe you understand the nature of
identity why it comes up okay that's one
thing you know so far we that's one
thing we talked about you know we which
is about trying to understand the nature
of these properties now there's another
thing let's talk about you see this
table so we have these properties now
you look at for example you know so you
have different structures depending on
which property is required you have
different names for different structures
now notice that there is no structure
that says that satisfies totality as
chitta vritti identity but not
invertibility and non commutativity you
see so we want that first three columns
scream but we want the last two columns
read we don't see that you know it
doesn't exist here so that's a question
so that means that means one either that
structure is impossible
you know it's mathematical
mathematically impossible to have that
it see it is impossible to have a group
like structure such that it has
associativity he has identity but it
does not have invertibility and does not
have commutativity okay maybe that's the
case that is why such a structure does
not show here but on the other hand
maybe it's because this table is not
complete you know it does you know maybe
that structure exists maybe it's not
named or maybe simply because the table
just do not list it so that is the thing
so at this point we can see that why not
let us do all the possible you know we
we want to enumerate all possible
structures you know doesn't matter they
have a name or they don't have a name
you know we could you know you know
because you know each of the cell is
either green or red so it's like you
know yes and no so we want to create a
table of 1 2 3 4 5 5 columns of all
possible combinations you know 5 columns
so yes yes yes you know no no things
like that
oh hi hi hi Syd come Oni such a
structure is there on a tape or a third
form lasts more noise oh yes Jesus how
could I have missed it oh my god okay so
yeah so you are right so but it's you
know come back so so it is possible I
mean so what we want to do what we might
try to do is you know make all possible
combinations of 1 & 0
you know true or false so there would be
1 2 3 4 5 5 columns each column has two
possibilities true or false so that
means 2 raised to the 5th power so what
is that 2 raised to the 5th 5th power
4 so 2 raise to 2 is 4 4 times 4 is 16
16 times 2 again is 32 so that there
should be 32 32 rows now of the 32 rows
obviously some of them may not be
possible
you know mathematically not possible so
we removed them so what we will let be
left with you know a bunch of things and
maybe that will be exactly you know like
what this table shows you know maybe not
I'm not sure because because this table
is from Wikipedia this table is from
Wikipedia you know Wikipedia's thousands
ten thousands of math articles about
these algebraic structures so but is in
the table here we say no oh it's
actually here much magma okay so the
table here it doesn't you know it
doesn't exactly say what is the criteria
of this you know it doesn't really say
and at least a bunch of profit but so
anyway so my point here is that you know
so we you know that's something we we
want to do I mean if you have a
mathematician this is something when you
read this table that's probably
something you want to do because then
you I mean if the result is exactly this
then you know okay
you know you would learn something you
know these are the you know actually the
essential because all the others are are
impossible okay so so far we talked
about two things one is that we want to
look into the nature you know the the
nature the order the the defining the
quantification of these properties I
mean why are these properties there why
not others for example other properties
such as you know if you have studied
group theory you know there's a symmetry
group there is a cyclic group there is
dihedral group you know they all have
more requirements so why are not those
you know visited here for example so in
other words what is the defining quality
for these properties to show up here now
we have understand we have understood
two of them one is the commutativity
which happens when you have a binary
operation do you have the other thing
you know it just happens naturally and
we understand associativity which is
when you have a binary operation when
you apply it twice and when you have a
set of at least three elements then you
have the situation of associativity
whether it's true or whether it's force
so these two things commutativity and
associativity we understand why it
happens and we can see why it is
important because its intrinsic it just
happens when you have a you know when
you define this kind of thing but I
don't
and then at energy we don't know
totality we know okay that's a you know
that's the first first thing the nature
of these properties so the other thing
that you're the idea is exhaustive list
of all possible qualifications I mean
all possible combinations of these
properties and to see Ariat match you
know the table on the left if it does
not match then you know it's very
interesting then we try to find out why
we try to find out what is a
qualification for Wikipedia to list only
these roles and not others for example
so what I'm saying is that you know as a
mathematician or programmer interesting
math that's what when you you know when
I look at this that's what I want to do
you know that you know now there is
another thing last thing so before we
talk about two things there's one more
thing I want to talk about you know four
or five minutes and I'll be it for today
so the last last thing is that
[Music]
okay the last thing is actually related
to what we talked about now let's go
back to the Hanako about associativity
okay this is really interesting so let
me show you where okay the combinatorial
listing of binary operations in a set so
what do you do is you know you have a
set let's say you know beginning with
two elements but two elements is to
symbol you know you have binary
operations on two element sets you only
have four possible you know results so
you could have three elements and after
you've done with three elements you
start to explore four elements you know
set with four elements and so on in five
and six so you you you want to list all
possible binary operations on a set of
three elements then you can see you can
see all you have all these possibilities
oh and this also you apply the binary
operation twice so you have all these
possibilities and you simplify you
you yeah so if you remove the commute
you know the commutativity you know the
order if that doesn't matter then you
use you simplify it down to these these
three possibilities and that's you know
that that that is basically that becomes
the associativity the question of
associative associative property so in
this way by you know just enumerated all
possible application of binary operation
we can see how associativity came came
up so this but there's more you know so
so all all so far we talk about binary
operations but what if a function takes
three arguments so you have a function
taking three arguments so so you can see
when you have three arguments now the
commuted commutativity property is gets
more complex because before it's just
two things you know you swap their order
but now you have three things now
there's six possible permutations you
know order so so you can see you know
when you have ternary operations you
know an argument you know a function
with three arguments you you started to
have more complex ideas that's you know
that's similar to commutativity and if
we go further we apply the function more
than once so we apply a function and
apply the function again you can you can
see that we started to get a very more
complex version of associativity so you
see the community VT and associativity
they are they are kind of just the
result they are just a natural situation
when you have a function and you know
how you apply and how you nest them
I mean not how but you know whether one
version of nesting is equivalent to the
other net version of nesting
that's what associativity is about okay
so the and then there is also
distributive law now distributive law is
when you have you know B when we talk
about this group like things we are
talking about one single function binary
operation but when we talk about other
structures like ring rings and fields in
math you have two functions so there the
the interplay between these two
functions is what distributive law is
about you know so so yeah so this is
what I'm I want to talk about so so we
we are trying to do you know as a
program this is something we are
interested we want to simply by brute
force you know he numerator all possible
combinations and see what happens okay
yeah that's all that's that's it for
today that's that's kind of what I'm
trying to say so what what's up with you
guys see it
I remember you before but I don't
remember exactly it so wait were you
from
so yeah and it's I mean drink
Oh Mexico Wow Mexico it's fantastic okay
what what's up anything else anything
have you studied math before like like
are you you know have you been studying
group Theory haja brah
okay so that's it for today I guess hey
Daniel Anglo is you are late you are so
late we are like done here so what's up
you know okay let's chat randomly for a
while
oh you studied math so did you get a
degree
oh also master oh so so can you
explain so can you explain what's going
on I mean because I remember I asked
this you know what I want to do you know
what I want is a you know like a convent
combinatorial is exploration because you
know because I have never seen I have
never seen associative 'ti explained in
this manner you know big you know I was
you know I was wondering what what is
this associativity property about you
know what you know it because it doesn't
appear natural you know come you come
you tative nice I understand you know
because it's a simply swap about us but
associativity is like you know you don't
quite get it then I I started to think
about it then I came up you know they I
realized it's just something happens
when you have a binary operation and you
applied it more and more than one time
all three elements so but I have not
seen this explained also where you know
I know I haven't and then so I'm
wondering you know all there you know
math expose exposition so you know perp
you know papers that
explore this kind of approach
you know just list all possible
you know binary common you know all
possible functions you know um and
nesting on a set and and this way you
know you will realize you know something
you know you realize something happens
and that is why we have certain you know
things like associativity and stuff and
distribute distributive law so I
remember asking you know I asked John
based mathematician he said he haven't
seen this before but he's you know but
I'm you know I'm thinking this must have
been studied before you know I'm I'm
pretty sure because but anyway that's
interesting you know that's interesting
thing that's interesting you know but so
I like to know if anyone know where you
know if anyone has has seen this kind of
approach of explanation you know show
show me you know if you're not here
right now you know type in YouTube
comments
let me know and by the way so far we
only talked about the definition kind of
thing we have you know mathematicians
they actually study the consequence you
know of the structure for example when
you have a group you have many different
groups you know symmetry group dihedral
group you know cyclic group and you that
we have not explored you know so far we
are only exploring kind of the most
fundamental you know what what makes
them together anyway
so so Daniel says being road tripping up
to San Francisco and back to Los Angeles
you should have you haven't contact
me we should have you know meter being a
coffee shop seat says I have now seen
such approach usually binary operator
operations are studied or explored via
listing of table operations yeah Daniel
says the associative law does not work
for subtraction or diversion and that is
just a commutative law well
well subtraction and diversion I mean
they are usually you know classically
they are not treated as such
I mean subtraction is is basically you
know you don't you don't have a process
whole function called a subtraction
rather you have a you know a process of
a function called addition and
subtraction is defined you know addition
with the inverse of some element and
similarly for the version you know
typically that's how you know cut in in
a classic way that's how they define
addition and subtraction and then end
diversion so sometimes the properties of
seed says sometimes the properties can
be seen from the table for instance
commutator commutativity means table is
symmetric along the diagonal axis yes
but I have not seen such extensive
combinatorial study yes yeah so that's
you know that's what I find interesting
you know this one thing I have always
wanted to know you know I wanted to know
what you know the associative property
if you look at the you know
multiplication table will we be able to
see visually when something is
associative with that you know I've been
wondering about that you know these this
actually we can do you know we can you
know as programmers we can start to
write a program and just color each cell
and we will see what happens visually
with the associative property you know
maybe maybe you will become visually
distinctive like when we see a
multiplication table we can eat we can
tell right away or did this
has associated property or it doesn't
you know but I wonder how it looks like
yes then you know that has been a
question on my mind okay so I think
that's it for today and it's getting
late here so thank you guys for coming
thank you
Sid and Danielle bye