okay now there is sound oh my this this
happened to me all the time I don't know
what am i doing
no sound for five minutes incredible
oh no sound for two minutes okay it's
not so bad
thank you good morning Pablo to Spain so
okay let me start over then
so today so welcome to a talk show and
today is September 27th Friday 2018
Niall Clark a.m. San Francisco time and
today Pablo if you have a question or
topic just type it okay and today I have
prepared several things very interesting
we're gonna talk about sleeping sleep
sleep dream inception I have a
experimentation with sleeping schedules
you know they say that some genius such
as Leonardo da Vinci he or some other
genius you know they have special
sleeping schedules supposedly some of
them sleep only you know four hours a
day or something like that and I'm going
to tell you my story I haven't slept yet
by the way so I'm going to sleep after
the talk and we're gonna talk about okay
so sleeping schedule and we're gonna
talk about netiquette anthropology tells
of Technica's annette ethology or at
ross confection now note this is
confection not confession okay this
connection and this would be fun this
this this collection of articles would
be my story of being a troll so to speak
okay I don't I don't think of myself as
a troll I despise that concept you know
troll you know most the UNIX hacker
types they they they have a picture of
the troll then you know they think of
someone who is you know just trying to
disrupt things and things like that also
the deafening that you know we can talk
about the history
of the word TRO the meaning of troll
changed over the past three decades okay
every like yeah more or less seen in
every 10 years the meaning changed so
today it's just like today is like any
almost like anyone is a troll so if we
we can we cannot we can talk about the
history of the world troll and anyway so
he on this page is a collection of my
articles on that topic you know some
people a lot of people especially in mm
you know mm least Lisp programmers
common least in particular programmers
Perl programmers Python programmers they
have called me at row so they I have you
know a lot of stories to tell and you
know in some of them add and also I
discuss netiquette you know in some of
these articles I discuss the meaning of
troll and some of the articles I discuss
netiquette you know netiquette is a
popular jargon back then today you don't
hear it it much anymore and I discuss
many of the typical mindset of these
people you know these nerds these
programmers they many of them are
vicious they you know so so that's about
this page and we're gonna talk about
newly's so someone made a comment asked
me a question about new list this is new
lease pieces scripting language that's
very interesting so we cannot talk about
that and some of the more topics Kinesis
laptop that's interesting that's like
that okay so yeah well instead of just
showing you what we could not talk about
why don't we begin oh we got I got $180
a month right now thank you guys so I
want to thank you my patreon
patrons patrons yes thank you guys for
the patron patronage $180 good okay so
let's see what we have comments and who
is here so Pablo Pablo is no questions
no topics okay good morning green deck
good and bad syntax okay that that is
going to take one entire hour more than
an hour so if we talk about that maybe
we should we maybe we should talk about
that because since it since you asked
you know so nicely and so early but
otherwise I was going to talk about
these other things so let's look at the
yes
so syntax what is a good syntax what is
a bad syntax and for that we go through
this section which we say index of
articles or about syntax now by the way
so this this is a funny picture you know
someone posted on Twitter it came from
Twitter a few years ago you know this so
you are in Russia right good morning to
Russia
Queen Dec but this is in America so this
this is a bookstore and you see they
have a section on computer science and
the books are Facebook for dummies
Spotify for dummies WordPress for
dummies in Pinterest for dummies these
are these are you know computer science
for the general population so anyway we
cannot talk about you know if the syntax
you know if we talk about syntax that's
gonna be the whole day that's gonna be
like the several hours about syntax so
maybe we pick some specific topic
because I have like you know the 30 hour
ago articles on syntax just on syntax
alone in fact
okay yeah and since we since that I'm
talking about this subject you know you
know I look at the Holocaust I have like
tons of things to say like there's this
fire burning I just want to talk about
them for more definition of systematic
grammar
yes that's a you know so I you know this
this subject I really want to tell you
about they are quite a lot so we
actually we have to like pick something
a thing or two so if you have said you
know Green Deco anyway if you have some
particular things you see you we can
talk about that first because because
usually otherwise I I start with a topic
and you just hung in on about that yeah
so all these for example the first six
articles are related to systematic
grammar
okay when we talk about syntax we
typically like C C++ Java Perl almost
all languages okay including Haskell
meta language okay mo f sharp C sharp
Python Ruby okay all all these languages
a PR and a PR and Judea okay or they're
like oh they are syntax is like one time
syntax tip in general they are not
systematic that that is they are just
random almost random like you'd use for
example if I'm the you know why singed
okay why see syntax is bad okay I'm
gonna tell that tell you that okay Pablo
says I'm okay with your topic for today
okay so so they are sesame so let me
finish this I was talking about
systematic grammar okay I was talking
about so all these languages basically
all languages we know industrial
languages
they they are syntax is whatever the
designer just created one time you know
for example I'm going to create a
language and I just created just by my
preferences just by you know whatever my
thought it's not it's not it's almost
always it's never wear a thought okay
for example C syntax now I don't know I
don't know the detail I don't know the
detailed history of C syntax but I think
it came from the language T okay there's
a language be the before C oh I think it
came from Arco I'll go there's a
language code I'll go okay it's a lgo
okay so that let me magnify lgo okay so
let's see Wikipedia let's see I'll go
there it is I'll go is a an algebraic
programming language developed between
1959 and 1961 let's see what what Agro
syntax looks like I haven't seen it
before
okay that's that's not that that this
this syntax is like basic yeah this or
this so anyway so so see I think I don't
know the detailed history of where C
syntax came from but I think it came
from P there's a language named be okay
but basically I mean if you look at the
C syntax okay it's it's just ad hoc you
know they say ad hoc meaning that you
just create you know you know you just
create one out of the blue there's no
there's really no logical reason I mean
it's not it's not really thought of it
just happens so just just like Emacs
keybinding VIMS keybinding just almost
just like everything else like
the keyboard layout you know the Corti
keyboard layout
it just happens you know we need to do
it you know you just create one so it
just happens on the spot it is really
there is no it's like it's not like from
a systematic study of syntax then you
create one it's not like that
and speaking of C syntax why is why is
it bad like let me tell you why is it
bad okay so why is the syntax bad its
first of all its ad hoc okay it's a oh
wait hold on a second before we go let
me finish the previous thought okay so I
was saying all these languages they are
syntax is just one time design you know
whoever designed it just not systematic
not you know it's not after you know
five years study of seem possible syntax
then you create one it's not like that
most of all these languages they just
happens you know like for example it
includes Python Python syntax came from
there's a language before Python you
know the guy Devon Rossum who created
Python the he created Python because he
was used to the other language do you
guys remember what's the history of
Python what's the other language that
Python came from there is a language I
think it's called ABC am I correct
you know we you know you can easily look
up Wikipedia and you will find the
answer but Python is based from another
language guy dog was some stupid guy
okay Ruby syntax for example Ruby syntax
came from mostly Perl Ruby is supposed
to be your improvement improvement of
Perl Ruby is the mix of Perl and Lisp in
particular eMac B's okay I have so many
articles I want to show you it's like I
have so many so many topics right now
you know I am I'm gonna blow up and it
so we need to write it down actually
because otherwise we
so let's listen write it down then okay
let me talk about systematic syntax most
languages syntax are just odd ad hoc no
design what so what so ever talk about
okay
some language syntax can from design
such as APL now API is language whose
syntax came from you know really
thoughtful design not now you guys
probably haven't seen API AP outright so
I maybe I need to show it I have so many
topics right now so API yeah so today
it's gonna be a long talk and you know I
can't use too many topics APL so some
languages syntax came from design such
as APL and what's and API and and and
others let me come back to that okay
then we have systematic syntax syntax
system okay then we have this this thing
called syntax system for example
Mathematica now Mathematica syntax first
of all it's it came from Lisp kind of
okay but however it's rather very
differently but but it but the point I
want to say is that is is that it's a
system it's a sin tax system we will
have to explain that okay so most most
languages in that syntax are just ad hoc
no design whatsoever some languages came
from design such as APL and
and the least okay we can count miss
here and and in Haskell okay Haskell Oh
cam o ml f shop okay
for example for example a pl so let
let's cover the subject one by one so we
keep on track
okay mo NP mmm I'll stand for meta
language okay I've shot okay mo email
f-sharp they are basically the same
language family okay
f-sharp is Microsoft's version now has
cow okay so do so let me talk about that
so first of all let me show you a PR
okay then then we okay then we're gonna
talk about why why C syntax sucks show
the article why I hate C okay I'm gonna
show that article in order to talk about
that why see why C syntax sucks okay
then we gonna talk about what is a good
syntax
what's a bad syntax how do you judge
things like that okay that that's a that
we're gonna follow those topics so both
yet Basquiat says how do i we map the
keys in Ubuntu so that in every input
box I can use path shortcuts Mac OS how
do I be map kissing Ubuntu so that in
every input box I can use a short cuts
in every input box okay you mean like
everywhere like also in browsers and
everywhere right right so how do you do
that on Linux in every in everywhere you
want basically you want the bash or
Emacs basic Emacs set of keys I don't
know offhand I have to look into let me
show you the articles maybe we can find
that later but okay so you know you can
so in order to do that you want to have
press control something control a for
example control a goes to beginning of
line yeah I have some suggestions
suggestions I can tell you but I'm not
sure your work for you because for
example okay let's go to Linux keys okay
so you go to you know there's such folk
sorry Linux key binding you'll find this
page and what you want to do basically
what you want to do the the kind of key
binding you want is that you want
control something like control a then
you want to bind that to a command okay
that that's the type of the key binding
you want to do and in order to do that
you need to use let's see is it expand
keys
yes I think that's that's one you you
want to try so download you know read
this page expand keys okay I have not
tried what you want to do by the way I
don't think that's a good idea okay I
think it's a terrible idea basically
basically what you want to do is
basically you want Emacs Keys everywhere
that's a terrible idea
you got you're gonna get in first of all
it's very inefficient okay it's very
inefficient meaning that you have your
hand has has to you know Bend into weird
shape or move around more than necessary
to do what you want so also that also
means you're gonna get repetitive strain
injury okay
faster then if you don't do that so I
don't recommend that so but if you
really want to do it I you know I
recommend look into explain keys in fact
let's look at this one in fact since the
since okey okay yeah look at look at
these articles you know the expand Keys
you know look at expand keys and XV KBD
but actually I would recommend you just
go to one of the Linux forum and ask
them they will because this is a
frequently asked question a lot of
people will want you know they would
want to have Emacs keys throughout Linux
so you go to one of those forums I'm
pretty sure someone has you know already
have a specific set of instructions or
tool that you can just install so do
that okay now let's go back to the
syntax let's go back to talking about
syntax
okay good morning bathroom you bother me
I'm on the phone so sometimes the
connection will drop okay
good morning Derek boss here says I just
want what Mac OS has don't you use the
shop Cody Matt no I don't never ever use
Emacs keybindings
yeah I'm telling you like I'm Tony I'm
gonna tell you one more time
don't do that okay do not use Emacs
keybindings at all I mean if you use
Emacs change them do not I do not use
any code combination do not ever if you
can avoid any any like without the
control key on your keyboard rip it out
Reaper without the the the odd key
control out the windows key rip them up
okay I have like you know just search
for sorry key code you know like ban key
code okay you go to my key bind keyboard
blog you'll find an article okay let's
not talk about that today I did a video
two days ago if you know the key
bindings on keyboards or that so you
might check it out check that out so I
don't recommend it don't do it
only good morning Matt so today we got
we are talking about the syntax issues
there's there's a lot to talk about so
let's get back to that so so most
languages syntax are just ad hoc no
design whatsoever okay and that applies
to okay and some languages syntax came
from designs such as APL least Haskell
camo
okay let's start to talk about that so
so APL if you don't know what a PR
language is let me show you okay welcome
to APL a PRG pedia there APL stand for a
programming language
I mean it's a weird name but that's what
it's then for its a math oriented
programming language and and it's also a
what do you call a ray do they say here
a ray language okay ray yeah ray
language the parody me array like
Mathematica okay it's a math oriented
programming language so a PR language I
just want to show you the syntax okay
the syntax of APL in fact actually
actually let's go to Solly APL okay
because I have examples and I have lots
I have a number of articles about APL
okay we have two articles here and APL
code okay there are three articles so
first of all APL now first of all let me
show you this page this is the unicode
APL symbols now you see AP out of the
language these are the symbols it uses
for the source code of APL so it's not a
ski it's very you know it's this API was
very well known for this you know you
got all these math symbols so this is
the APL symbols
okay and and this is original keyboard
for the APL that supports the API
language so this is IBM to 741 I
it's called teleprinter teletype I think
back then you know it's actually it's
not even a terminal so anyway you now
you know the name IBM to seven for one
you can look up and we keep here so
this is original keyboard for APL an APL
began in APR began in what year 1966 ok
very old it's like about the same age as
Lisp so anyway that's APL and in this
article I show you if you are you know
coding API I can I show you how to
program your keyboard so that you have
the API layout
first of all you need to get unicode
font then you know I show you how to do
it on a Mac on Windows on Emacs and you
know and also you can buy this keyboard
that has the APL symbols on the keys
okay and also you can buy key caps so
that so that for example let me so I
showed you that APL symbols they are
unicode okay they are they are this
Unicode APL keyboard and and you can buy
the key caps okay if you buy a
mechanical keyboard with the Cherry MX
switches then you can buy a special set
of key caps so that you can just plug
them in you know so your kibo have APL
symbols some of them looks pretty good
you know actually I can show you but but
we have a lot of topics to talk about
so I mean guys if you if you have any
questions you want to stop me or you
want to make to you know go faster just
let me know okay so we already talked
about 30 minutes we haven't began
talking about syntax yet so if he our
language okay so that's a PR language
now my point about APA AP our language
is designed by this guy
Kenneth e versa now he spent significant
time to study syntax so eventually he
APL and the APL syntax you know is
invented by him so so so the APR syntax
is uh it came out from design you know
he spent significant time to design the
APA language syntax a PR language syntax
came from dedicated design unlike C ok C
is the C is the extreme opposite no no
thinking at all no so ap our language so
we talked about a P out then let's see
what's the next topic so some some
languages syntax came from designs such
as APL this as you know this - you know
lease is is almost uniform rat uniform
parenthesis nested parentheses so he
came from the list guy so in that so
that is also this by design you know he
thought about it and he you know by
design
now the Haskell or camo ml meta language
F sharp those those family of languages
their syntax also came from design but
they but it's actually the most idiotic
let me show you the article about that
has cow this Arco
the garbage the garbage truck just
passed by so anyway this this arca okay
the most idiotic article the article
this article is written this arco is
written in like my god the god the
garbage truck is very loud do you guys
hear it
okay I'm waiting for the garbage truck
to go away okay it's gone
almost so you said you didn't I mean you
like Haskell okay so you you like the
hassle okay you know this is just my
personal personal opinion I don't like
the Haskell syntax at all I think it
sucks but anyway let me tell you what's
our engine of the Okemo syntax has
carson hex syntax can't kind of borrowed
from oak ammo okay now where does the
Haskell syntax came from let me tell you
the history okay originally the Haskell
people Haskell is created created by a
bunch of academics okay professors you
know who wants who are studying
functional programming languages so I
mean so so because the functional
programming language is a kind of common
concept among you know professors who
study languages so they are thinking you
know let's get together and create a one
creator language together so we have one
unified unified functional programming
language that was there was the engine
of Haskell but originally they wanted
they want they want the syntax to be
based on Miranda there is a functional
programming language in commercial okay
it's a commercial functional programming
language not free UK you know you have
to pay or something to use it it's
called Miranda okay let me type it
Haskell syntax originally wanted to be
based on Miranda okay there's a language
called Miranda if you search Wikipedia
you will find it such former on Miranda
language okay it's not there okay but
anyway so they they talked to the
creators of Miranda you know because
there's copyright stuff like that and
the Miranda guy turned it down we
refused declined so
so there has got people borrowed their
their syntax from oak ammo or camo
so again okay I talked about this many
times okay
in the beginning you have the meta
language okay ml you can look up
Wikipedia email stand for meta language
okay there is there is this language
called ml then you have variations
standard ml which is s ml or then camel
okay then you got Oh camel okay then you
got F sharp F sharp is made from
Microsoft
the latest variation it Microsoft about
ten years ago created a shot
so all these languages ma our standard
ml camera or camera F sharp they are the
orders basically the same same language
in little little variations so so a meow
the syntax in quick so Haskell
eventually borrowed the the syntax of
Haskell came from Mao okay but where
does the ML language syntax came from it
came from this article this idiotic
article the article taro is the next 700
programming languages okay
and this is the origin of idiocy of okay
moe and Haskell syntax one main squawk I
swing okay this the article title is
called the next 700 programming
languages you know it's a clickbait this
is a quick Peck packing what what you is
is 1966
oh my god so we see the history here
here is the lineage of a Kokomo syntax
so you have this article this article is
known as ice swim okay
i SWI am why is it called that because
I forgot you know if you read this
article you you oh no ok so it's called
I swing I is W I am I think it's stand
for I I do not understand something is
kind of fun I forgot
anyway this article is known as I swing
so this article is written in 1966 then
the language amar began in 1973 Oh camel
amine camo in 1985 they Oh camo in 1996
then F sharp in in 2007 something like
that ok so so the syntax of email came
from this article and this Arco is the
most asinine you know you can read it I
have the it's a PDF ok I got details
here oh yeah it's a PDF ok you can read
it it's a PDF article the the next 700
programming languages by this guy PJ
Landon I think in 1966
I think he's I'm not sure who exactly he
is he you know I think but anyway he
seems to be a hotshot at the time you
know like today's hacker news you know
some articles becomes hugely popular and
everyone is retreating it you know
things like that so back then in 1966
somehow the historical you know the next
700 programming languages becomes widely
popular that that is why the Mao adopted
this syntax and I read this article this
article is very difficult to read ok and
it's bad to be written in my opinion the
writing style it seemed it's very it's
hard to understand yeah not because not
because the subject matter is how to
understand but rather because it's a bad
writing you know that in my opinion it's
a lousy stupid writing style so that so
I don't like it you know I because why
try to learn Oh camera okay and okay my
and a scar I realized I don't like the
syntax at all like who the who the
invented it
so I trade you know so I looked up I
study you know I traced to the history
then it came from this idiot so
it's a so you you know you can call this
mean you know this is 1966 meme of the
1966 oh you know gun viral so anyway but
however at least at least this syntax is
not out of the whim it's not it's not a
just a ad hoc you know this article at
least it has systematic thought about
what how syntax should be you know he
this guy he's trying to think about me
what he is thinking you know the title
next 700 programming languages what what
he's thinking is that he tried to you
know think of all possible syntax you
know however it may be you know like he
was he's thinking for the next 700
programming languages you know so he his
mind you know he is going to create you
know of all possibilities he is you know
trying to think of what would be the
best syntax you know audible
possibilities so it's very ambitious but
they came out in my opinion so
anyway at least at least the MIR
language or camel o camel come they came
from a design okay this is supposed to
see you know okay so that so that
is about that so let me so we finished
talking about APL Lisp has Kokomo you
know those these languages came from
design they are syntax okay now
Mathematica now as I mentioned before
vast majority of languages including
this ap are this Haskell
they are syntax doesn't matter if you
it's ad-hoc Oh or from design even from
design still it's like just it's just
like one time syntax there's no system
there is no grammar to it I mean not
grandma is not the right word there is
no in other words let me put it this way
you cannot you know every cinta every
confirming language has a you know
syntax right and every programming
language syntax has a grammar
okay to specify the syntax but the
grammar is ad-hoc okay so deo grandma is
like so so what is a systematic syntax a
systematic syntax is such that the
grammar of the syntax has the grammar
itself okay that is Mathematica in fact
I can show you many examples in my in my
articles here syntax OOP
here's the list yeah formal okay so so a
year ago two years ago I realized a
formal definition of systematic grammar
and I talked about that hold on a second
let me see if I
okay let's let's talk about systemic
grammar
okay so let's talk about this article so
systematic grammar
okay I'm not going to read the whole
thing you can read it offline you know
just just find my article you'll find it
just such the title sorry and the title
basically or systematic grammar is
basically your grammar the grammar of
the syntax such that the grammar spec
itself has a grammar and a simple one
first of all the syntax must be regular
okay like Lisp for example you know list
right
Lisp is basically almost not hundred
percent
almost purely nested parentheses so his
unit is in a sense uniform or regular so
first of all you should have that then
then
I'm not sure how to explain this they
you see the problem with how done
secondly I'm not sure how do I go about
this let me check the comments so if you
designed a programming language
what would it look like I have some
sketches but that let's talk about that
some other day because it's gonna be too
much to talk about
nice clickbait yeah maybe I just like to
okay so let's continue with the syntax
system systematic grandma okay so so so
let me tell you what what's what
how do I explain this
okay here's what I want to say about
these this is I consider okay this what
I'm going what what I am about to
explain is basically mathematical syntax
not just mathematical syntax but the
syntax system does the systematic
grammar of Mathematica it's a system
okay so first of all why do we need that
first of all what my personal preference
is that I do not want ad hoc syntax
actually let's let's explain C first
let's explain why C syntax sucks
okay let's explain that first let's go
to semantic noodle
then let's search for C
okay not here and syntax OOP
see
okay so syntax OOP least know not only
syntax OOP semantics syntax to semantics
noodle there is an article here why I
hate see there okay so let's look at C C
syntax why is it bad foot in my opinion
okay my own preferences I hate it so bad
because it's ad hoc you know basically
that that word captures the captures why
I hate C syntax because there is no it's
not systematic like every every every
command every statement you have to
learn a new syntax for example you have
I press first purpose I you have for you
know for loop for loop is a very
complicated syntax you know some part of
it you can omit some part of it you
cannot then you have wire loop then you
have the braces you know the braces
usually makes a code block then you have
you know this ternary expression you
know you know about this generator in
turn every expression like it's a if
expression you know expression question
mark expression 2 then colon expression
3 you know that's a if expression then
you have print or sprint
that's a worst example okay so so let's
talk about the sprint statement yeah are
you guys familiar with that if you know
C you know C++ or Perl you know this the
Sprint syntax basically is powered to
every language they are in Perl in C++
in in : I think in Java - in Python so
it so this is why I hate cc and UNIX
they are you know they just they
are they are worse and better you know
they are the worst possible but but
because it's so popular is free free
free beer so it becomes you know the it
goes to suppress prices goes to
everywhere so
every every language now today inherited
the spin of a sprint the command the
function the subroutine sprint so why is
it bad because if you look at Sprint you
know like you know what I'm talking
about right for example even in eMac
miss let me show you so this wave
function format okay
so you see this is what you get you get
this bunch of you know percentage
shortcut kind of cryptic thing
percentage s for stream percentage D for
signed number percentage over for octo
notation percentage X you know so on and
so on and and then you have formatting
float then you have this extremely hard
to understand you know impossible to
understand now if you code in any of
this language involving format or string
you know what I'm talking about so it's
almost just for this single subroutine
strings sprint it becomes a mini
language by itself like you know so so
that's my point about C syntax it's it's
not regularly in fact it's the extreme
opposite of regularity like every every
function has its own special syntax I
don't like that I hate it okay
what I like is first of all regularity
no exceptions such as such as Lisp
syntax that's one that's one of the
example what are others others are X
example such as APL okay we talked about
APL oh but I forgot to show the code so
here is a example of APL code here's the
example of AP our source code okay let's
magnify okay here is a example of a AP
our source code and this is actually web
server
I think let's see this is a APL CGI
script okay it's a CGI script yeah I
think it came from new somewhere on a
goon website yeah it's upwards on edge
yeah so so here is H ap our source code
let's look at it now APL is another
language that has systematic syntax
regular okay regular syntax so in
regular syntax is such as Lisp and APL
basically what happens is that the rules
are extremely simple like you just
learned about two or three things it
applies to the entire language you know
no exceptions that is why I like regular
syntax okay that that's one thing so in
my opinion okay in my own proof I don't
like C because you know the syntax is
almost every function has its own syntax
its you know the reason you don't you
don't find it odd you know most you know
I suppose most of you guys or any new
programmer any any average programmer
you don't find any C syntax odd you know
they are because they are also in you
know JavaScript Java Perl even in Python
almost in you be you know you don't find
it out because because you are so used
to that's why is that for the same
reason you don't find English odd but if
you are Chinese to learning English for
the first time you'll find it's you know
this this is total garbage in the same
way if you are learning Chinese or
Russian for the first time or French or
German
you'll find it complete you know garbage
because it's totally irregular you know
you have to learn 1,080 ins and the
grammar has 1 million special cases you
know things like that so
this applies to C programming language
you know irregular everywhere for
computer language it should be regular
you only learn two or three rules then
you know the entire language you know
you can this you can type it correctly
without syntax errors so that's what I
like you know regular syntax now by the
way if you study passes or compilers now
regular has a special meaning there
that's not we that's not what we are
talking about okay regular language or
regular syntax in in the subject matter
of passing they have a special meaning
but that's not we are talking about what
I'm talking about is a normal sense of
the English word regular or you can call
uniform uniformity okay no exceptions
you know everywhere looks about the same
that's what I mean so I want regular
regular syntax now I want something else
now big why because if you have a
regular syntax then it's very difficult
to do something for example for example
let me show you okay I have an article
here let's go to on Lisp okay and we
want to find the article that is on this
we want to find our code that is about
operators okay so let's see
okay okay here
okay let me magnify so I'm going to show
you some examples of the problems the
problems of regular syntax okay the
problems of regular syntax now the one
obvious are obvious example is that for
example one obvious example is if you
are coding in Lisp suppose you want to I
want to do what 3 plus 3 plus 2/5 square
root the whole thing I mean divided by
the whole thing by 7 for example let's
say this simple expression in this it's
very hard to read in this this will be
for example that 7 then then that 3 then
that to 5 okay this is the Lisp notation
it's regular all right but however it's
impossible to read it's hard to read
okay so this is the one problem of
regular syntax and I show you some of
the other examples of regular syntax
like you can have variations for example
this is another example of regular
syntax this is like this is a normal
functional notation where the operator
appears in front the function name
followed by parentheses okay
it becomes like like like that it's
unreadable how to read okay or you can
write it this way yeah this way this way
traditional mathematical notation
function name first followed by
parentheses and inside the parentheses
arguments separated by comma okay this
is traditional hard to read but what you
really want is infix notation or
sometimes called algebraic notation you
know like that
but this notation is not it's not
regular because especially when you need
to mix with for example a sign you know
science or function you know something
like that then becomes not regular
because for example parentheses here is
used for grouping but the parentheses
here is not for grouping it's function
arguments function functions arguments
you know so you have it becomes
irregular you know the traditional math
notation is not regular okay it becomes
irregular very fast especially when you
have name for example sine x squared for
example sometimes people write it like
that you know sometimes people write it
like that or sometimes you can write it
you know normally actually what we
really want is like that you know so you
have all these ambiguous cases you know
that's all traditional math and notation
traditional math notation is very bad
okay I can talk about that for our day I
have several articles of abet they they
went to hacker news now and then
anyway so the that that is the problem
of regular syntax when you have a
regular syntax it because it some often
it becomes unreadable and inconvenient
that is a problem
okay that is the problem of regular
syntax ok the problem of regular syntax
okay and the problem is usually it
becomes unreadable or inconvenient
I am Co NV and I
ing okay yeah I inconvenient such as I
gave you examples now how do you solve
that the way you solve that is by you
can solve that one of the way to solve
that is by us sin by a syntax system so
let's copy that
let's see okay I already have that so
one way to solve that is by a syntax
system and that that is what we were
talking about so so okay in order to
talk about that so okay let me just give
you a quick quick quick quick
explanation okay
so so for example let's explain
Mathematica that's gonna take another 10
minutes or so how long we been talking
one hour already okay so we are taking a
long time so so let's see what we want
to do so yeah I'm going I'm going to
explain a syntax system basically the
mathematical syntax system that solves
the regularity problem so that you could
have a syntax that's regular on one hand
100% regular but meanwhile also you can
write it this way so it's that it so he
said so it is extremely readable and
extremely flexible but meanwhile
maintain 100% regularity meaning that
you learned just you learn just a couple
of rules you understand the entire
language no exceptions whatsoever and in
fact the syntax once you have this
system the syntax can have so much
variation it's even more variation than
power okay for the same
raishin you can read it in different
ways more different ways in Mathematica
than Perl okay this is true but in order
to okay I have you know that so I have
actually I explained this many many
articles here if you go to if you go to
a on Lisp index page and I explained it
in many of these articles in detail
mathematical syntax versus Lisp
so actually I'm not sure I'm going to
explain it because you take a lot of
time you know take like 10 minutes or
something actually I did a video so
actually check out this video because I
explained the whole thing for an hour
this article okay so talk-show 2019 July
19th Lisp syntax symbolic expression
meta expression Mathematica and meaning
of sugar syntax yeah so this video it's
like 90 minutes I explained the whole
thing in detail so you might check check
that out so so so in summary we are
talking about the problems of regular
syntax basically because it becomes
unreadable or inconvenient in practice
so therefore we solve it by we solve it
by creating a syntax system so that for
every function or every operator okay
here let me here is two minutes
explanation so first of all you are
going to have a regular syntax like in
this form okay
okay everything looks like this okay you
start with a function name function name
can be you know function or any any any
of any ASCII okay you start with a
function name then you will follow it by
square brackets then inside it is
arguments okay
XYZ or whatever then slip separated by
coma
okay now any of the argument X X Y Z and
so on is again of this form okay so that
is the essence of Mathematica syntax
okay so you can see this is hundred
percent pure now now let me show you an
example now remember every source code
in Mary Mathematica can be written this
way so you know it's just a function
function named square brackets and
inside inside our arguments separated by
coma and each of the argument is again
the same form this surprise for any
Mathematica source code can be can be
written in this way let me show you an
example so here is a example down here
okay not not that page but this page
here okay I'm just going to show you
quickly what I mean by so here is here
here is a mathematical function written
in this form you can see look you know
look at this code it's purely nested
function notation nothing else you don't
even see a symbol like plus sign or
minus sign you don't see that at all
everything well you do have minus sign
in for a sign but you know you get what
I mean
you know it's just nested function
notation so this is regular okay but
however how does mathematical solve the
readability problem you see this this is
not readable it's regular yes but it's
not readable so the way you solve it is
that for every function for example let
me write it okay time a B okay let me
write first a B ok least a B C okay let
me just show you quickly some power okay
okay and divide okay list and let's see
okay let's say another one equal okay
here are some of the functions in
Mathematica time just means
multiplication okay a times P plus just
means a plus B or you can have a plus B
plus C okay now list is just a list okay
ABC is like a Python array or you know
JavaScript array power means X raise to
n okay these are mathematical functions
the right means a divided by P okay
equal means you know returns true or
false whether a equals to B owner he
returns true or false
so these are Mathematica functions
now what Mathematica do what Mathematica
does is that for many of these functions
it has a equivalent syntactical form so
for example time can be also written as
as that okay
it's syntactically equivalent meaning
that before compared us to every
anything at all it just transformed this
form into that form okay
syntactically equivalent this is
important now I mentioned in that video
I so I talked about that in detail
for one hour so remember this most of
you are familiar with the concept
concept of sugar syntax that is kind of
abused that phrase is abused that you
don't really know what it means like
every every time you have to something
two things are similar you call it sugar
syntax but it's not actually the this
this you know for example this math math
math America these two lines are not
just should sugar syntax
they are syntactically equivalent
meaning that people before compiler do
anything this is transformed into that
so they are hundred percent exactly the
same in compile time in runtime in
whatsoever they are just the same
they are only different to you in the
you know to your eyes so so Mathematica
for many functions you have a
alternative syntax you know since in
different forms so so for example for
lists you can write them like this okay
like that so so for power you write them
like that
okay for the write you write them like
that okay for equal you write them like
that okay
so he so for many of the functions in
math America there's the equivalent form
and by the way so and and
any form can be mixed so you can any of
these can be mixed about ready you know
for example anytime you have this you
can replace by that or anytime you have
plus you can replace by that so you can
you know so so how does this work so so
this works because so when you have a
syntax so for example let's write this
in Mathematica okay let's let's write
this expression in Mathematica so let's
copy that and move it down here so let's
have so that in Mathematica would be
would be that oh I can write it let me
let me show you many ways to write this
okay so okay that's that's one way to
write it or I can I can write it like
okay I can write like that oh I can oh I
can for example go further like that oh
I can remove part of it like I mean not
remove I mean like that okay and I can
oh I can I can write it like this okay
okay
so all these five lines are equivalent
you see now you get to see how it works
so this is Mathematica okay so this way
you still have regularity because in
Mathematica you can press a button
because they so come back to grammar
because the syntax the the equivalence
they are all way of defined so that
that's what I'm saying the grammar
itself has a grammar and it's very
simple it's all regular so you can
easily transform any one of these to the
full to the fully let me let me try
another one to the full notation okay
plus okay then we can write this as
divided to five okay okay now you see
the complete full form the complete
nested form so it can transform you know
so any of these can be transformed
easily trivially to this form then you
have you know then it's regular its
regularity in fact this is whenever you
do pattern matching or symbolic you know
pad imagine symbolic pattern matching in
Mathematica it it works spaced on this
form which is like this Marco's so
anyway so that's that's a lot of talk so
you see what I'm saying
I guess I'm hope I am NOT getting boring
here
so in summary the syntax I like is
regular syntax which you know you know
you uniform no exceptions so you only
learn a few things and you know the
entire language no exceptions whatever
you know and the opposite extreme would
be C C++ those kind of you know C's C
syntax where almost every function has
its own special syntax
you know it's like bizarre idiotic to
the extreme so I like you I like regular
syntax you just learn a few things and
you know you just learned like two or
three rules you understand the entire
languages syntax but also once you have
a regular syntax you may have a problem
where it's not practical you know it's
unreadable such as you know such as this
you know when you see when you see this
line it's regular but it's unreadable
you know you rather want you rather want
to see it like that so how do you solve
that you know you so you can solve that
by a system systematic syntax system so
that's what I mean by saying that
Mathematica has a systematic syntax
system okay let me let me do Demi so we
can show this in browser
okay showing browser so so that's what I
mean by a syntax system so that that is
the syntax I like okay I like that
syntax now this now we have just
explained Mathematica Mathematica syntax
system but however this is not
necessarily the only one you could have
easy you know I you could easily have
another syntax system that is regular
you know but looks very different from
Mathematica so I'm saying this because I
don't want to get the impression that oh
I'm just a fan of Mathematica no rather
I want to emphasize that what I you know
it so happens you know Mathematica is my
first language and I love it but the
idea of syntax system is not necessarily
just Mathematica for example you can if
you go to a syntax OOP
you know read this first six articles
for example on construct you know they
are all related on you know this
Archelon constructed unconstructed
languages computer languages and their
grandma complexity you can see similar
ideas where I talked about so the the
grammar complexity of c and c++ is you
know astronomy astronomy co you know
it's like a huge number on the other
hand the the grammar complexity of Lisp
or APL or Mathematica will be very low
you know so that's about this article so
let's look at the next article
composable syntax okay when you have a
regular syntax such as Lisp APL or
Mathematica then the syntax is
composable like you only learn a few
things and you just combined them
together you know you which is not the
case for C for for C subverts first for
example
some operators some statements some
expressions and some trachoma like in
Perl
you have pragma that you cannot mix them
together you have learned you have to
learn 100 rules 100 exceptions
ok that's idea composable syntax so this
is almost like the idea of functional
programming you know you compose
functions on you you know if you apply
that to syntax then that's the idea of
regular syntax you you compose you know
things together once you know one rule
you know applies to the whole language
then it comes to it comes to syntax
algebra and then we come to the concept
of formal languages you know this
article is from what do you see here you
know it looks very fancy it came from
this arc oh ok Galois connection
calculus for abstract interpretation
it's it's about mathematical logic
something like that I don't understand
ok so abstract it says we introduce a
color or connection calculus for
language independent specification
abstract interpretation used in
programming language semantics formal
very opaque formal verification and
static analysis ok it's very advanced I
don't understand so I think justing you
would like that you know it's a s cow
it's you know related to a scow so
anyway you can see that it's oh it's all
very fancy math you know it looks like
math fancy math but however the way I
see when I see this I'm thinking of
composable syntax that's what I'm
thinking composable syntax so this comes
through idea of formal languages it's
all about syntax where you know that's
so so so one day with with languages
like these okay with language like this
you you almost it's almost like you know
you are not concerned about semantics
anymore all you are concerned about is
syntax you just can put you know you
just put them together compose the
syntax you you know and the syntax
almost like they don't have a meaning
anymore however it they can do proofs
you know it's it's the idea of formal
languages okay I think that's about that
that I explained about you know the
systematic language the syntax
I like okay so you are there any
questions about this ask me now and we
will be done yeah we'll be done in in
two minutes or five minutes
so
[Music]
I used to think execration is anyway to
this book convinced me not yeah so let's
see what what are the comments I'm
getting tired I need a drink
so today's drink is this this energy
drink and how is my how am i doing I
think I have a articulation problem you
know yesterday yesterday Israel is
accusing me he's he's saying I I you
know my English I have a lousy command
of English actually the problem is not
my English actually is just me like the
person you know because when I talk in
Chinese it's the same thing you know
where you you just see ramblings in code
like incoherent rambling and sometimes
stuttering and you know it's the same
when I talk in Chinese too you know I
grew up with Chinese right so it's the
same with Chinese so the problem is not
my English you know my command of
English rather it's it just is some sort
of it's just being a schizoid or
something I don't know exactly what it
is but that's a problem and that that is
also my that my my sour point because I
always thought I wanted to be someone
with perfect English you know like no
accent you know like New Jersey accent
you know the standard broadcast accent
no accent and I want you know I want to
be this perfect guy who and who can
articulate so we're helped and extremely
logical but but now I've seen my own
videos you know that it's like no way
okay I talked so bad you know but that's
that's something actually I can improve
if if I really want to you know
just have to practice on that okay so
let me read the comments and that'll be
it for today for a few minutes three
more minutes something like that we were
then we'll be done so let me read the
comments yeah that's a huge garbage
truck
so elixir has great syntax and he liked
elixir is a great improvement over our
land yeah Olin syntax is pretty weird
Maxo Reiter who did who asked the
question Maxo Reiter Oh informatics
informatics are you still here
so informatica question is I'm wondering
what operating system you use if I don't
if I didn't get my Mac for free
okay well that it will probably I was
going to say you're probably be your Mac
you know if I have you know if I can
choose you know if I have money
yeah you know I've been using Mac you
know in from from 1991 to 2008 okay
basically among Windows and Mac and
Linux Mac is just the best you know it's
really the best buy by far sec the
second best is Windows Linux is truly
the worst unless you put qualifications
such as you know such as you know if you
are a programmer if you are programmable
for Ruby Python emag B's then Linux is
the best okay I mean if you are you know
open source developer then every if you
all you do everyday is programming okay
then Linux is the best no question about
that but if you use it for a desktop
sometimes you want to play music
sometimes you want to Skype
your friends or video chat or whatever
or composed music Linux is the worst
by far not just he's liking you know by
by by by a magnitude but if I have
to you know if I have money I can choose
one I was going to say to pee Mak but
I'm not too sure because they all have
problems they will have lots of problems
on Mac be like today Mac you know Apple
is so evil they make you a phone slower
on purpose every time they have a new
phone things like that and also on a Mac
you know they they make your CPU slow or
intentionally because because that way
because they they don't want the fan to
turn on okay because you know if you go
to youtube there are people are talking
about that in detail I think Linda's
leanness talked about that yeah Lina's
you know the guy very popular doing
doing Hardware reviews and so on you
know they so I learned the Mac they they
don't want the fan to go on because way
of the fan go on people don't like it so
they they you know for PR public
relations they don't do that how they
but how talk but how do they avoid you
know the CPU heating up they they avoid
that by slowing the CPU down you know
they actually do that they slow it down
they don't and so meanwhile they can say
oh this is running you know I call you
know whatever the late
Intel I call seven oh I cannae or I call
1000 okay but so they are running the
latest fastest CPU but meanwhile they
actually slow it down so so the fan
don't come up and the consequent result
is that it's actually so when you buy
when you use you know a Windows machine
you know that's not even with a you know
previous generation of CPU is faster
than the Mac anyway so you know Apple do
all these kind of things because their
goal is just to make money
but on the other hand if I go by windows
so I don't want Mac you know I really
don't want to use the Mac because I
don't want the company on the other hand
if I go to Linux yeah then I don't worry
about this cooperate
you know greediness problem but then
every day you spend one hour
this research that go to our clinics go
to wiki you know this is a headache on
the other hand Windows is kind of in the
middle then but they their privacy
issues then you have to worry about
virus okay now Windows has thought my
virus not because window is not secure
okay
Linux is far worse if you actually think
about it is far worse
the reason Linux don't have much virus
because those who write viruses they
don't write for Linux they write for
Windows because every time you spend
time to write a virus for each Linux
user you have 1000 10000 Windows users
obviously you want to write virus for
Windows you don't want because there's
no you know you want more bang for the
buck that is why Windows has more virus
not because Linux is secure secure my
ass Linux is actually was in my opinion
less secure than Windows ok anyway so if
I choose if I go to Windows now I have
to worry about virus then this is
Microsoft you know he's trying to take
your data by all chance possible you
know you know on the surface they
provide you options to turn it off but
in reality you have to go be very very
hard ok so that's a problem
so Linux Mac Windows they all got
problems in fact it's like that since
1990s I mean I I talked about this in
one of my articles you know you if you
search for saudi search for the article
sorry
switch Mac to Windows you'll find it
ok the situation has been the same for
the past 30 years on a Mac it's more
expensive you pay twice the money ok
and and and everything is nice
everything is nice what just things just
works but Apple sucks your blood on
Linux you don't have to pay you see it's
a cheapest possible you don't have to
pay but but every day it sucks your
blood you have to spend every day every
week let's save three hours every week
spending on you know dealing with Linux
fixing things with why something doesn't
install oh you don't have you know
something doesn't you need to update the
driver this or that first of all
you have to spend ten years to be a nerd
before you can actually use Linux and on
Windows you have the virus problem then
you have Microsoft's problem and by the
way on a Mac is most if you are
concerned about privacy Mac seems to be
the best and even on Linux
today you have Ubuntu they have all kind
of crap you know learning anyway that's
about that info Mac informatics I hope
that answered that question I don't know
if you are still here ok so
okay I'm getting tired I don't know let
me just answer the questions addressed
to me Bartholomew says how easy is it
for a math loving person to learn
Mathematica it's very easy without
knowing in computer science or another
programming language oh that's so easy
you know Mathematica they're depending
on how deep you want to go you know most
vast majority of Mathematica users they
are simply using it as a calculator you
know like a graphing calculator so you
want to solve integrals you just type it
you know it give you sense you want to
get derivatives or you solve linear
equations or differential equations just
type it it gives you the answer so
that's actually majority of mathematic
Mathematica users are using it as a you
know like a graphing calculator now for
you bathroom you you are you know you
are kind of in between the you know
computer science and media right so
Mathematica is actually very good for
you so you can use it as a scientific
you know like a graphing calculator you
you almost you don't have to learn
anything you know just just follow you
know just type things and you give you
the answers and graph and you can rotate
it you can also change parameters then
the graph will change in real time
things like that but if you want to type
deeper you want to started to learn how
to program it or how the you know like
the syntax we have been talking about
you can so that's when you start to dive
into programming Mathematica and you
know depending on how far you want to go
you can spend you you can you can you
know yeah it depends on how what kind of
expertise or math mastery you want to go
you can be like me spend 10 years seeing
it you know I spent like two years in it
and I wrote a program back in 1994 to do
playing curves so I got there I got
hired you know I went to work for wolfin
so depends on how how much you wanna how
far you want to go so okay I think
that's it for that
dad what about Debian 10 hider TV good
morning have not seen you before you are
new here so what about Debian 10 what
like what do you mean
Debian was the like the Richard Stallman
approved system in a beginning but I
actually I never use Debian so is there
something special about Debian 10
you know debian you know debian is you
know like linux is open-source right
they and you know so they don't have
money and you know even you know so obon
to is the most popular and it sucks so
bad you know and and when you know when
it becomes popular it's just like it's
just like everything that sucks yeah
that like it becomes like windows like
you you you install ubuntu then you have
this software what they call software
store just just like Windows Store
Chromebook you know Google's Android you
know stole chrome store and Apple Store
they start to have this store then use
such programs then it comes up comes up
or like 99% is garbage you know for
example I'm a um a funny I'm a Linux
user right I'm an open-source phonetic
okay I'm a Emacs phonetic so I want to
you know so I want to for example let me
show you okay so let's say you know
Linux okay so I'm new I'm new to Linux
back in two thousand two thousand eleven
or something like that it's my first
time where I use Linux as my desktop
every day okay I was system admin for
solaris back in 1998 so those of you who
wants to say I don't know UNIX shut up
okay
so anyway I was using Linux as my
desktop in 2011 first time was my
desktop and so I wanted to know okay
what what are the what what are some of
the music programs I can use awesome
let's say image programs image viewers
okay I want to know what what are the
some of the image you use I can use so
for example I have written down all my
experiences here image viewers so in
this page I give you a introduction my
research you know I tell you what's out
there so you have G thump which is from
big with loud
of features and slow okay you have I of
the genome you have Katie East of
Grandview that which is default in KDE
back then at least they change all the
time this thing then GQ view you have LX
t GP g peak view in ne and then you have
the red with ristretto
from xfce okay anyways so that's my
survey of image viewers this is a
natural question ready if you are using
some operating system you want to know
what's the best you know
but on Ruben to you you see you have
this app store you know just just like
Windows app store you go there
then the bunch of ads you know whatever
old you know like you know ads
you know for for the normal people you
know then if you type image viewer you
have like 100 irrelevant facts like
before the image viewer folders further
you know for the non-technical users or
something but basically no good
basically then they started to you know
open - back then few years ago they
started to do all this you know storage
yeah they are trying to copy because you
know the you know remember we have
what's you know Google have Google Drive
right before Google Drive you have that
you know what's the other one some box
some box Dropbox
okay so woman who is trying to do that
too then you know two years ago so three
years ago they failed you know they did
you know like open source they are
trying to squeeze money if you don't do
you you don't you don't make money they
try to you know how did woman choose
begin I tell you let me tell you okay it
began by this rich guy from Africa why
is he rich he is rich because he became
rich because he was selling certificates
okay certificates you know the the the
HTTPS SSL certificates what's the
company varisai it was very signed back
then I think he then he sold it then he
started moving to okay
that that so that's the basic story and
you know so and we went to oh yeah we
went to I remember yeah they'd they
started to close they call their driver
I think one drive or something by God
service a software service because with
open-source you cannot make money so you
go to the cloud service and I remember
using it it sucks so bad you know it's
like impossible to believe impossible
it's impossible to believe sucks so bad
then eventually they killed it and they
have lots of other stuff you know ideas
like that that's a story of open-source
another another rant I guess so that's
it for today come on email good morning
meerkats browser is your image view
yeah so Linux is good for what is Linux
good for Linux is good for for nerds for
those of you who are programmers or
those of you who are into technology you
know then it's really good because you
also learn it you know but it's not you
know when in any way we're mostly Knox
fanatics you know they say Oh Linux is
better than Windows that's total
you know then they fail they
forgot to add the qualification you know
if they say yeah Linux is better than
Windows if you are a programmer or if
you are interested in programming or if
you are a tech tech head you know you
really are interested in CPU and how
things work yeah it is better than
Windows for sure because every time you
spent to learn these partitions or the
you know boot boot put booting steps
you know the bootloader or whatever you
or the kernel what is the kernel what is
a driver what is this that you
know the key binding systems what is
excellent the windowing systems yeah you
learn it that's because you know you
want to but your mom you know for each
one of you who are into you know
programming technology in UNIX they are
1 million who are not interested you
know the most they can use they cannot
use Linux so when you compare which one
sucks you have to consider that not oh
if you yeah you have to put into context
that's a thing good morning Kathy Matt
yeah exactly so matt says for people who
just want to get stuff done I would not
recommend Linux I have both Windows and
Linux
ok that's it for today because then this
is gonna be a infinite talk we most
today mostly we are talking about syntax
ok thank you guys
thank you guys for watching and if you
like my stuff subscribe if you have not
already subscribe and click the bell you
know the YouTube everyone is you know
and put money in my pocket okay
I have PayPal and patreon and stuff put
money there a discord yeah
discord is actually I forgot what it's a
it's kind of a social network like
Twitter who face good morning with who
face okay bye guys
tomorrow now your crack okay same time
for this week two more days