go live
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
today is 2021st
june 22nd and today we are going to
do emacs lisp live coding mostly and
stuff like keys okay and uh so if you
have questions
e uh questions emacs related post it
okay
or if you some have some other questions
you might post it
then i'll see if we can we have time to
talk about that
so go to talk show today this is
today's talk show page uh wait
so we uh so let's begin to code let me
let me tell you what are we going to do
today
so yesterday you know in in the past few
videos
i did a lot emac this good morning btx
btx5 uh so in the past few days we did a
lot of video of emac disk
coding especially on uh emac this
command on html
and uh by the way this is kinesis
advantage 2 keyboard and this is
ultimate hacking
keyboard and i have
reviews on my website so you just go to
my website
and you go buy it okay ultimate hacking
and kinesis
i have reviews there it's fantastic and
also get red switches
i bought this uh three months ago red
switches
350 dollars and it's worth it okay
kinesis
advantage too so anyway so back to emac
this so
we did a lot emac this coding in the
past few days
so if you are emac user eback this
uh learner you want to watch them we are
going to continue
so let me tell you what we are going to
do today so
okay so there is this command because i
html select current element
which we did uh two days ago i think
and i'm going to modify the code so that
it will
extend the behavior for example for
example let me show you my current
keyboard block okay keyboard blog
you see go down here you have these
allison
alice marshall keyword okay so what this
command does
is okay let me show you so if my cruiser
is here so for example here is the image
right
image tag you open it is image so here's
the image path
so if i if if my kusa is here i
call the command it will let me show the
pink window the pink window shows all my
command cores and keys i'm using soft
light keys
with vora keyboard so if my cursor is
here i press a
i call the command it will select the
current tag which is the image tag
so if my cursor is let's say here it
will select
the entire outer tag which is the
link tag you see the a href
link tag so if i my cursor is here
you know it does that but if my cursor
is here
uh is you know if it's here then it does
that
what i want is to press the key
again and have it expand for example
if i press the key again now it doesn't
do anything
but i wanted to i want to select
like this okay you see expanded so if i
press it again you'll
expand selection to the outer uh html
tag okay so there's a lot a lot to do
actually so let's go to the talk show
page
so first of all we're gonna code this
okay
that'll take maybe 20 minutes then we
are going to
let's see audio check video check yes
good uh okay then
i'm going to there is a pull request
stuff like keys i haven't checked for a
long time someone added
um neo layout and neo2 layout and people
layout so i'm going to commit that so
you can
kind of see the workflow so it's a
workflow
actual workflow demo so i'm going to do
that
then i'm going to also add delete select
selection mod
to stuff like keys so what what that
mod does is that you know in emacs if
you have a selection
and if you press the delete key
okay if you press the dd key
in normal text editors it will delete it
but
not necessarily so in emacs
because that depends on whether you have
this delete selection mod on
if you have it oh let me show you okay
so because right now i have it on as
i type something something selected
and if i type any character you will
just override it
okay but if i have this off so let me
show you okay let's
let's set it to off evaluate okay
then something selected now i
i want to type something it doesn't you
see it doesn't
uh delete it it just that's kind of city
but you know emax is pretty old so
anyway so dd selection mod
basically i want to turn it on when soft
light keys
is on so i want to add it into stuff
like keys package
so you're gonna watch my kind of
workflow and whatever associated
information uh for you emacs users okay
okay so that's what we are going to talk
about so
first let's modify this code emac this
coding let's
commence the coding okay so here is the
code
copy it uh describe function
type the function name go to the source
code
okay then we want to modify this code
for
first of all make a copy new buffer
paste it here
select the file select the function name
save it
as a temporary uh
function okay so i'm gonna name this
like that okay so you can see
so you can see this is a temp name we're
gonna work on the
you know it's my convention where file
begin with
xx are kind of temp files so one day i
may just delete them
you know delete them all but anyway so
here is the code
let's switch to xsa emacs list mod
okay so the code is 41 lines okay
fits in the ring window so now
we are going to modify the command so
that
if the last command
code is the same command meaning it's
repeated
then just then just expand
the region okay actually that's not
so trivial um so first question is how
do you
determine if the last command
is the same command as this okay the way
you do that is
um let's let's try to put the code here
the way you do that is uh this command
okay so this command is a variable let's
call describe variable then you'll it'll
tell you
this command now being you know the
command being executed
so for example the value the current
value is described
variable because that's what i called i
call describe variable
on this command to see what is the value
and that value is described variable
because the value of this command named
this command
is you know use whatever command you
just called
so this will give you the this command
and this also
uh last command okay so for example i
call describe variable on
last command then you see
it tells you its value is stuff like
command mod activate
because i mean soft flag keys i can
activate insert mod
or i can activate uh you know a command
mod it's like a
vim uh okay so last command
holds the value uh a string or the
symbol of the last command being execute
so if you want to know if the command
you called right now
is the same is as the last command
meaning that
you know you've been repeating the
command this is one way to find out
so we can just say equal
equal this command uh last command okay
something like that
so we want to make an if statement
then check if they are equal then
if it's equal that means it's repeated
otherwise you know
do whatever here okay that's how you
determine it
but before we go on let me go go to
sasso's code
then let me search for um
search for the word last command because
i have
of course i have coded this before yeah
you see
lots of these occurrences because many
command
their behavior depends on whether it's
being repeated
for example this is a good example of
this command copy line or region
so if you call it for the first time it
will copy the current line
okay but however if you call it again
and again
and again it will continuously copy
lines like copying a block of
lines instead of just copying the
current line for example let me
demonstrate okay
so for example i press it i call the key
you know the the
keys j in row rack
so let's try again do it okay now i open
a new buffer paste it you see
that now if i do it
now go back here paste it you see it's
that but now if i
do it continuously copy copy copy you
see now i go
to this buffer paste you see you get a
sequence of lines this is super
convenient because this way
it saves you you know keybinding spots
and it's you know it's just convenient
so
that is the we are talking about
efficiency so this is part of the
efficiency of
stuff like keys the this is why
in terms of efficiency in terms of
number of keystrokes
on programming tasks stuff like keys is
uh better than vim okay
okay so well that's my claim you can try
you know you can go through the
vm golf and try it uh you know we've
i've done
that we've we have done that before a
long time ago maybe we should do it
again
uh anyway so back to
the yeah so we were we were talking
about
uh you see this part this command so
this tells you whether you are um
you know calling the command again okay
so let's see
so if if it's repeated do something
otherwise to whatever it was doing
before okay so
so okay so let's see
it's magnified otherwise uh what is this
so uh program yeah that's trying to
select the tag
okay so uh yeah so then
if it's in tag
okay so let's
it's trying to find out what's the
structure here okay
so anyway this this whole thing
let's move it here okay now prettify the
code so
so we are working on sideshield
selection element okay now let's add
some kind of a let's add let's modify
the
dark string
select the current
or outer element under cursor if called
for
first call will
select current element
repeated call will
select alter will
expand selection to outer element
okay that's what we gonna add
okay and let's change the let's update
the version date
okay so now we're gonna do is this part
so what we're gonna do
so okay so
you know in order to do this we have to
think now we have to think about
you know we are doing live coding we
have to think so if it's repeated that
means there's already a selection
when there's already a selection you
okay so okay so let's let me just begin
coding okay because live coding is
better if i just keep moving
instead of you know stuck and doing
nothing and just thinking about things
okay so let's keep moving so so so let's
begin
to have uh set
p1 now i want to rename p1 so it's
colored okay so
yeah let's not okay let's continue okay
set p1 equals to region beginning okay
then uh set p2 to
region end okay so that's the beginning
and end position
of
of the current selection okay so p1 p2
is the beginning and end of current
selection now what we gonna do next
um now we gonna
okay go to char p1
move closer to the beginning position to
the left okay
then search backward
you know i'm just gonna start to code
then we we try it if we find problems we
fix it you know this way
it's more suitable for light coding so
search backward
we want to search for this character
okay that's the
html tag kind of thing
so search for that optional bound
neo no arrow true uh
but we want it to be we say move
and no no let's just say true okay
so search backwards
okay search backward okay now
now now in order to
let me let me go to uh let me show
something here
so let's go to talk show
uh what
okay close supply keys go to talk show
okay so we have some html to look at so
you know suppose we begin like that
then we call the command again it should
expand
so first of all we are moving to the
beginning of the region
then we want to search backward to the
next
left angle bracket that's right so
that's this line
is doing okay
then search forward okay okay i got i
i think i know what to do so let's add
four more variables
tag position
one two three four okay
let's add four more variables
okay then set tag position one
okay then search forward
for that optional bound neo no arrow
true
then
set tag position
two to be the current cruiser position
okay then
go to then go to the end of selection
which is p2
okay then go to char p2
so what's going on is that you see if we
begin
like that we move the cursor to the
beginning of
region then we search for that then
that's the
tag position one then we search forward
for ending
uh angle bracket that that's tag
position two
you know that's this one then we go to
char we go to char end of region which
is here
then we again search repeat okay
so so
we can actually copy this code so then
we go to that
then we search for word for that then
tag position four then we search
backward
uh actually uh wait
i think so we search for
that that's tag position four
then search backward that that's tag
position
three then
[Music]
okay so i believe this so this tag
position one two three four
they are basically you see let me let me
explain this
so you see we begin like that
now tag position one will be
here tag position two is here okay tag
position
three is the end three and four is the
ending
tags you see tag position one and two is
the beginning tag
begin and end tag position three and
four
is the ending tag begin end okay so
that's what
you know this kind of uh so you need
four four positions to
specify uh html
element in a in a text
in a you know in a string so tag
position one two three four so i hope
that's
uh clear yes so now
so once we okay yeah
so once we have that it's very easy so
now let's just say
what we have to do now is just turn on
the mark okay mark and region you know
turn on the mark um tag position one
and move cursor to the attack position
four okay that's yeah that's all we have
to do so let's see
uh go to chop okay so that's actually so
that's
so so this is the code we need
okay push mark
tag uh push mark
tag position one
and go to char
tag position
we we forgot to set dd selection back to
one so that's why i'm having
problems let's let's let's do that
evaluate okay now
yeah okay so go to chart tech pack tag
position
four okay so that's it clean the
prettify the code that's i think that's
it what we need okay now let's
clean the code
so this command okay now let's magnify
so this command
has it this command
okay it's right now it's 66 lines
and has two parts so first of all
if whether this command has been
repeated
if it has then do this part otherwise
you know otherwise do the uh
the second part okay so that's a clear
now let's
let's compact these uh things so
so they don't take so so many lines
magnify okay
so now let's double check the code i
think we pretty much are
done so if it's repeated then first of
all
get the beginning position the of the
region and end position of the region
then go to the beginning position of the
region then
search backward for the
uh html angle bracket
so we we do that
to get the position of the opening
beginning position of the opening tag
and
in a similar way we get the beginning
position of the
end position of opening tag then we get
the end position of the closing tag
then the beginning position of the
closing tag
then all we have to do is push push mark
fantastic
i think there are a little uh problem
because
there's a some problem when you run into
uh let me show you
when you run into self-closing tags such
as
br or hr you see those are self
closing attacks but i haven't thought
about it but let's just run the code
okay
uh let's okay run the code fantastic
now let's try it let's try it okay
do it now we're gonna do it again let's
see if it works
do it fantastic do it fantastic
do it oops that's incorrect
that's up okay
oh yeah okay i know what's going on so
this is easy to fix
okay so
so once we have the beginning position
okay so we once we have the beginning
and end position of the opening tag
you know we don't want to use the you
know html you know angle bracket to get
the closing
you know the matching tag instead
we need to do some kind of passing to
get into the
matching tag and that command is this
html skip tag forward okay
so so we want to use that okay
we want to use some kind this code this
this part of
this code
and why is it no completion that
this code is part of uh in imax hsgml
mod
written by a uh xml expert
and his name is let me show you who that
is james clark
very famous he wrote the most used
c library for passing xml
james clark and he is also a open source
fanatic
okay he lives in uh malaysia or
something there's
south asia he's pretty old too i think
probably maybe 50 something or 60.
james clark okay because 20 years ago in
year 2000
2000k year 2000 i was working at utopia
you know
uh you know uh web order you know
online shopping uh engine
you know like yahoo store or you know
amazon
we are writing those engine and we need
to have xml passes
and uh you know it turns out so i use
the library that's from
that's c and it's you know written by
them by him
james clark and he has a website too
actually
and also he he also james clark is the
one who
you know he wrote html mod the sgml mod
is like 30 years old or something
let's see you see 1992. he also wrote
the nxml mod with uh about 10 years ago
in emacs that turns out to be the best
xml editor on the uh on earth
okay james clark and h
let me show you okay let's digress a
little bit
because you know we've done a lot emac
this let's uh let's
digress a bit okay let me show you the
the mod okay
this is the mod you see the you see the
status
bar the mod line the mod line
nxml okay so let's describe
variable major mod that's how you see
the actual value of the mod name okay
so you can see major mod is a variable
defined in c
blah blah blah and its value is nxml mod
okay then let's look at in
in xml mod okay now it doesn't have a
link okay
but let's describe function and go there
there it is
so nxml mod is an autoloader
blah blah blah a major mod for editing
xml okay it doesn't say much
yeah uh
so this is you know it's back then 10
years ago it's the best
xml editing mod but not many people know
that
because uh issues okay anyway so let's
go to the source code
you see here's the source code for nxml
mod and you go to you see
right now it's a 400 lines 2458
lines of code and go to the top you can
see the name james clark
uh so this is written beginning in 2003
and something something
okay so he's a you know he's a true xml
expert you know he's in the xml standard
back then but unfortunately xml got
killed
by opera and google and apple fox
they replace it with html5
a sad uh you know history a
miles
history point in the technology history
of
web technology killed by google apple
uh with their html5 why are they doing
that because
for example apple wanted the canvas
you know they they want canvas too so
they can
to so they can have games on their
iphone
uh you know opera then google joined in
google wanted html5 because google want
to push forward with
javascript technology whatever because
that's google's business bread and
butter
advertisement online so they want more
and more powerful
html and javascript and web technologies
you know that's what they push for
so we do have to thank for google for
the advancement
of basically all technologies on the web
you know not you know we have webgl you
know all kind of things gaming
or on phone google but
while they are doing that they also
up lots of good
things such as xml okay
validity of you know correctness and
things like that
so anyway that's a chapter of the web
history okay web technology history but
anyway we digress
so that's that's in xml mod
and we are looking at sgml mod
okay close it now so in sgm armor there
is this very convenient function
which uh what it does is that it lets
you let me show you okay
it lets you jump from one tag to the
beginning tag
to the matching beginning tag of or
ending tag for example
uh section i can jump to here you see
you see without this function
you have to basically write a password
next you know kind of
uh these decent you know recursive
password something like that
because you can't just search forward
for the you know for the for the bracket
that don't know you you know you have to
search you have to find the next tag and
check if that's the same tag as that and
and so on and
you know so this
this function is you know it's
tremendous helpful
i'm just working on top of this you know
this this is this is a
uh let's let's see how many how much
code is that in this function okay just
for
curiosity okay
okay so let's copy that paste it here 37
lines okay it's 37 lines but however uh
but however it uses
html syntax table skip chart forward
looking at oh my god these regular
expressions
uh toothpick syndrome because emacs
regular expression sucks
uh then fix me oh there's a fix me this
research for what we'll mistakenly match
tag like text inside attributes okay
then blah blah match beginning
oh actually so this code is actually
not that long but how do you how does it
deal with
nested um
skip chop how how does it deal with
nesting
i'm not sure am i seeing some other
complex oh there it is
okay it's kind of a recursive
okay so this the implementation of this
command is using a recursive approach
no wonder it's short
so you see it does it checks certain
conditions and
blah blah blah then recursively
go into the next um
yeah kind of uh something like that okay
uh okay but it's quite interesting so
this
command does not actually taking that
much
code but however it does call up list
that's
you know at least is uh it's for lisp
and it's navigate you know up list is
up list is another
kind of parser like function it's used
for this code for navigating nested
this code basically nested parenthesis
so i don't know why is it
calling up list because of this it does
not deal with
html tags it's only it only deals with
nested parenthesis
and you can also see there's a forward
list
so possibly for some reason
it's using up list to navigate
uh html you know xml
nested syntax if that is the case
then that's a tremendous uh
employment of this function because of
this
is not you know easy to write
i mean it's not that easy because then
you have to ask
you know you have to deal with escaped
parentheses and
and strings and so that and all that
so
anyway so we are digressing we don't
know what's going on so
uh stream you're saying okay so anyway
okay so anyway close that close that
so we are going to just use this okay
so back to so we do have hello what's
the topic today yeah on google first
launched angular
uh primer pi primer pi
google first launched angular i forgot
what's the context
oh when the when they introduced html5
uh okay so okay so
sgmail okay so let's see html skip tag
forward that's right so let's see we
let's go back to the
uh our condition so
close that
so we have so we select
select select then
we repeat then that's that's when it's
wrong
so okay now
now we have tag position one tag
position two
then
[Music]
we
okay here i know what to do so we then
then we have to check if if the
the the tag you know that the tag we are
looking at is actually a self-closing
tag
now if you don't know what is a
self-closing tag
well i yeah you know i have a you know i
want to show you
my page that's why uh
there is so here are the self list of
self closing tags
so you want to check if it's a self
closing tag so how do you check
uh okay and
[Music]
how do you um
so here's one way to do it
kind of annoying you know you if you do
it this way
it relies on the fact that your
self-closing tag actually contains the
slash
but that slash is not
required since html5
you know it's required in xml so this is
one of the reason xml is much better
because
think by the syntax alone you can find a
lot of
information you know whenever there's
you know how do you know if
it's a self-closing tag just look at the
ending
you know if there's a slash there but
because of html5 they you know it they
don't
have that requirement anymore so you
don't so now it's a problem
how do you know it's a self closing tag
it's it's kind of
problematic you have to then you have to
keep a list
then you have to check you know if the
tag name is one of these
you know it's uh problem
okay so okay so let's uh let
let's let's uh let's go to html mod
i do i have a code that checks self
closing tag
so let's this matching lines so i do
i do have a function that already that
checks
self closing text so let's have a look
okay so i do have a function yeah
so let's use this function then
you have to give it a tag name
okay okay yeah let's let's call this
function that's more
robust instead of just checking for the
slash
because people don't add that slash in
html5
okay so so then
but first of all we need to get the find
the tag name okay
so set cue tag name
so we need a new variable added there
secure tag name you know first of all so
how do you get the tag name
so go to char wait
uh buffer substring no properties okay
tag position
tag position okay
text tag position one and two so
we get a string from this function that
would be the tag name okay so
set the tag name to that okay
so this there's your tag name then
then code then call this
html tag self-closing tag to see if it's
self-closing okay then we need the if
statement
if
okay if it's self-closing then what you
do
let's go back to html okay
uh
okay so what you do if it's self-closing
let's
say let's add a self-closing tag here
so if you find this if it's self-closing
okay i know what to do so if it's
self-closing
then you just extend the selection to
there okay
so if it's set if it's self closing then
we are done basically
we are good
so if it's self closing then push
mark to position one then go to
char
p2 okay
otherwise otherwise you need more work
to do
so otherwise you need to start to
yeah otherwise otherwise here okay
otherwise here okay
so is it self-closing or not if
it is just push it and move to
uh region n okay if it's not
self-closing
then go to char
go to chart
tag position one okay
so let me show you what are we doing so
so if we are here we need to go to the
you know left you know like
we select okay then we're trying to find
the next tag to the left
of the selection which happen to be
self-closing here
but however if it's like that
then we're gonna find this one so
it and this is not self-closing okay so
we need to move the cursor there
which is this line then forward char
forward chart one okay
forward charge one which means move one
character to the right okay
then we call the html skip tag forward
which will let me show you what the
wheel does you see we call it
it will move to the matching end tag
okay
then okay then we search
then we search backward
okay then search backward then
then that's gonna be tag point three
then we search forward
then that's gonna be tag position four
then like before we push mark okay
clean the code so actually so that's the
code let's
let's see if we so that's the whole code
how many lines 68 lines okay so
again the code has two parts depending
on the if statement
so if the previous command is the same
command
then we do this part otherwise
we do this part
okay so so if
it's the same then we basically we
repeat we you know we find the left pair
then
okay anyway let's do it let's let's
let's call the function let's evaluate
function then let's try it
but first of all i want to make sure one
more time last time to see my code is
correct
so so if it's a closing tag
uh or not if it is
then just do that so what what what is
the options for push mark let's see
describe function push mark option local
location no message that's right
activate
uh we don't want to activate oh we do
want to activate yeah
okay yeah okay so okay so let's
eval the buffer let's try it now let's
go to the html let's try it
uh let's try two possibilities one with
the self-closing tag and one without
okay
now coed good
coil again good
coil again wrong
oh okay now i know what's wrong because
once we are over here we search
backward to to get this figure
and for some reason and by mistake we
assumed
this is a beginning tag but in this case
it's
uh not beginning tag it's ending tag
okay so that's a mistake but now let's
try this case
do it do it okay that's also wrong
if there's a if there's a self-closing
tag
uh that's also wrong
now br is oh okay wait we
we now we got this is wrong
but for substring uh yeah this part is
wrong okay
uh we're getting along
finally i'm catching you being like
hello
uh how long have i been talking i think
this is getting boring right
12 we've been talking for 15 minutes and
we haven't done this
yet uh we haven't completed
yet uh okay so i know what's wrong
right here i mean we have two cases
both are wrong one case is that when
there is no self-closing tag
beyond the current selection the other
case is when there is a self
closing tag beyond the current selection
both cases are wrong
and in either case i know what is wrong
in the
in the self-closing tag case it is wrong
because we didn't get the
tag name correctly because the tag name
the way we select
we get the tag name is just so right now
our tag name is actually the whole thing
that's not correct
so in order to do get the tag name so
what you have to do
is okay let's try try this save
excursion
okay let me just code it
um go to
char tag position one
okay then
uh then then forward char okay
then
skip char forward okay skip char
skip char skip chart forward
okay we want to skip any of
tag names okay which is a to z
a to z tag name is only uh
alpha alphabets okay limit
let's say limit 20 okay we don't care
skip chart forward okay then
then then the then that's the
then buffer substring no properties okay
so actually we don't need
then both for substring no properties
from
tag position plus one to
current position okay now it might seem
complex but
if you code enough you might be split
you know you know i kind of know what
i'm doing
so
so what this block of code is doing is
getting the tag name and the way it's
doing that is
first of all for example you move the
cursor to the beginning of tag
here then you move forward one character
then you search forward up to space
that's the skip chart forward then
you you take the
string from the beginning of the tag
plus one which is there to the current
position so that's how you get
the contact name
yeah okay so let's
okay so let's um okay evaluate the code
let's try it now let's try it over here
do it
do it uh it's still wrong what's the
is this correct
any comments questions how many people
are watching
five people okay four uh five people
eight people uh
okay this is getting too long uh
let's try this okay br let's evaluate it
which is true right yeah so this is true
so bi is true so why
is it so if bi is
true then go to
[Music]
uh that yeah i don't see why is it not
working okay
so maybe we want to message tag name
okay so
debug tag name so it will print
what's going on evaluate it let's try it
here
now show the message buffer so we can
read
okay then let's do it
okay let me show the pink window okay so
let's do it here
code call it
it's not even printing to the messages
what's going on this
is all wrong why is it not printing to
the messages
it's not printing to the messages
you see we have a message going on so
eval evaluate
the file again let's actually rename the
file to add a
dot el okay
okay open that again evaluate the file
then do it
do it oh there it is
wrong file wrong type argument symbol
forward char
oh okay so yeah so so the syntax is
wrong the set cue
the second argument all together they
may need to be one expression
not you know one two three four five you
know expression they need to be one
single expression so
all these will be programmed there
like that
yeah evaluate the buffer
back to here let's try again do it do it
fantastic something is wrong though i
mean it should
it should be it should be like that
because we are extending the selection
but however it did something
uh better than before so okay let's see
what is wrong
so it also prints tag name so did it
print tag name
uh mark set and wrote
wait it didn't print the tag name but
let's see
so tag name so message so if if the tag
name is
self closing then push mark then
go to chart p2 now why is p2 not correct
p2 is end of region here
evolve the buffer let's try it again
do it do it
that's not correct do it
okay
okay this is taking too long do it do it
any comments
my paypal is up to date yes thank you
pay there and i'll get your money
because i at xavi.org
okay so what's going on so what should
we do now
should we abandon
the completion and
that'll be it for today or should i like
continue
[Music]
with seven people watching because right
now we kind of
you know it's getting uh because by now
i mean new people call me they have no
idea what's going on
unless you watched from you know like 15
minutes ago
but you know we're getting into very
technical details about
so right now i don't understand why is
the tag name
not even printed
so so we get
a go to chart tag position one 4
char then skip chart forward
let's see did we get the syntax right
yeah it should this is correct
yeah okay
then buffer string no properties one
plus tag position
plus then the current point okay
then then that's the tag name
and we are trying to print the tag name
it's not printing why is that let's do
that
eval the buffer
do it do it okay now it's finally it's
printing it we can see it now
search for br why is it not showing
before
yeah it is
okay so
okay now so if it's self-closing
then push mark
that and go to chart p2
now p2 is the
p2 is a region end
so why is it not
oh wait uh what
i i don't know what why is it not
oh it works now hey
[Laughter]
let's see do it do it it works now
what's going on so if the koozai let's
try it again do it
do it it worked what
do it do it do it
fantastic do it fantastic
okay now for some reason it's working
out wait wait what did i change
yeah that's still correct that that that
correct no that's incorrect because
okay now let's okay let's push on let's
fix the other problem
the other problem is when they when the
expanded tag the beginning one is not a
self-closing tag
so which is the part is here
so go to chart tag position one
forward char then actually now we have
to determine that
is you know the
the tag to the left the expanded tag to
the left is we have to
find out if that tag is a beginning tag
or closing tag so that's what we have to
find out
so we can find out by let's see if we
i if i have already a function okay
let's go to
html mod
uh beginning tag okay let's see if i
have a function that determines
let's list of functions of defend
uh let's see okay defense see if we have
already have a function that
list you know list
these matching lines okay this matching
line is different
then let's search for uh tag
okay get tag name
oh we actually also have a get tag name
should we should use that
okay so let's search for self closing
tag delete pair
uh cursor in tag get tag type
skip forward okay change contact okay so
we don't
have a function that tells me whether
it's a beginning tag or in
tag
do i no let's write it then let's
write it ourselves
okay so let's write it now i'm going to
guess
okay okay i guess let's go back to
here let's go back
see comments kang is it actually
recognized a self-closing
save excursion what is
recognizer self-closing
we determine whether it's a self-closing
tag by calling this command
self-closing tag true or false and give
it
a string tag name now the way this
function works
is basically you you just check a list
of tags whether
it's one of these you know tag name then
self self-closing
that's how that works and save excursion
uh well save you know i'm not going to
explain that just search my exciting
imax tutorial save
excursion basically it saves the cruiser
position uh
and return it return the original
cruiser position before the user calls
the command
you know otherwise after you call the
commander kuza jumped
jumped to other places
so right now we need to fix is that we
need to determine
if that is uh if a tag is a
beginning tag or in tag okay the way to
determine that
is very easy okay so go to that
and uh here okay
this is this is how you do it
is in tag okay
by checking compare
because if it's end tag you know end tag
and tag they will you know they will
always
the second character will be your slash
okay
that's how you so you equal character
you know you check if it's
it's equal to a sash okay so this is how
you determine
n tag now if
uh okay i don't know what uh are we
doing
so there's another question okay let me
just push
push coding because this
basically this function when we expand
selection of
html elements we are basically writing a
function that
navigates nested structure so when you
navigate
nested structure there's a lot of
complexities for example you can jump to
the
you know because every next nested
structure is basically a tree
structure so when you are on a tree
you have the option of going to the
siblings or you go
have you have the option going to the
parents or go to the children
so at each point you have several
options you have to make a decision what
your command actually wants to do
uh so he's that's why it's a bit complex
so for now let's just um
let's just so if it's m tag
let's just um
okay i i i want to stop this video i
think
because okay no comments and i want
to
stop this video because we did a lot of
code and
at this point it doesn't it's not very
fruitful to go on to do a live show on
this
so that's it for that today
and there are more things i want to do
but let's do it another day then stuff
like keys yeah
so we today we just uh
yeah yeah yeah okay okay thank you guys
for watching
if you like my stuff buy my emacs
tutorial okay
you can you can find the links uh almost
everywhere
uh just go to my exci max
just search for xymax website you'll
find
links for patreon and paypal
or buy my emacs tutorial thank you guys
bye
you