Welcome
to
Xah Talk Show.
Today is May 18th, Saturday,
2019.
The spice must flow. Good morning,
London.
Oh god, you are on time.
Like usually
Well, how are you?
London, so where are you from? Have you
been here before?
And what is your interest
in my talk show? What would you like to
me to talk about? About
programming languages, about Emacs,
about keyboard,
or about non-technical stuff, meaning
you know, today's event, current events.
Politics and
any anything goes.
London, so answer, please.
So, today what we're going to talk
about? Well,
first of all, I guess I'm going to you
know
I'm going to just show you all Xah Fly
Keys versus Evil Yes.
Now,
okay, let's talk about that. Good. Thank
you for the question.
Vogue Voguev
Voguev, thank you for the question. And
let's talk about Xah Fly Keys versus
Evil mod, the most evil thing in the
universe, Evil mod.
So, in that case, let's start Xah
command log.
So, this is when
you can see all my Emacs command, you
see?
All my Emacs command will show on the
left panel,
the window there. Let me see if I'm I
can
Yes, you can see it. Yes. So, you can
see all my all the commands I call in
Emacs is showing is going to show up
over here, and also the keys I'm using.
For example, I'm
right now I'm calling uh
end of line of block, you know, that's
how I navigate my cursors, and you can
see
the keys. By the way, I'm using a Dvorak
keyboard,
and I showed this many times in my
video. I'm using this keyboard. This is
Kinesis Advantage 2 keyboard with my
Logitech mouse,
and uh
and it is using a Dvorak layout.
Uh let's see where where where where
where where am I?
Uh
Yeah, okay, this this looks good.
It's kind of
somehow
Hold on a second. Somehow Okay, now it's
now it's like straight.
Xah Fly Keys versus Evil mod. So,
so
first of all,
let me show you my keyboard blog. So, go
visit my keyboard blog. This is URL,
okay? xahlee.info.
Uh you know, just search for Xah Lee
keyboard, and you'll see
uh this is the keyboard I'm using, and I
have a video review there as well. If
you like it,
buy it.
And what So, what is Xah Fly Keys? Xah
Fly Keys is
uh let's go to Emacs.
ergoemacs.org.
This is my Emacs blog.
And you can see ergoemacs.
Uh Xah packages.
Xah Fly Keys. Xah Fly Keys is a key
binding system for Emacs. Now, Voguev
uh
Okay, do you have any questions specific
any specific question? Have you used Xah
Fly Keys before?
Or are you just are you interested?
You like to hear me like hear some
introduction?
Or is it
are you already using it or something
like that? Are you are you are you using
Evil?
Like let me know because you know, I
have no idea, you know, all the people
following me. I have no idea
you know, which direction to go.
Uh
So, Xah Fly Keys is a key binding system
for Emacs
uh because Emacs key binding system is
very convoluted, and it's um
it gets you repetitive strain injury
because you have to press control keys,
control meta, you know.
Um
So, Xah Fly Keys is a alternative system
key binding system to operate in Emacs.
For example, I can write my blog here
uh for
for example, I'm writing my blog, okay?
For example, I can copy it, paste it.
You see? Now, if you look at the keys,
there is no control involved.
There is no control involved, my friend.
You will never When you use Xah Fly
Keys, you will never ever
need to press control or meta.
Actually, you do need to get press
control when you when you do control
X then something because that's for
major mod. But anyway, that's
the purpose of Xah Fly Keys, you see?
Right now, all my operations
you see
there's no control key. Like everything
I do in Emacs, there's no split window,
go to E-shell,
you know, there's no close close buffer,
there's no control key or meta involved.
So, that means it's it's extremely
efficient. The system is designed to be
efficiency
uh oriented, efficiency and ergonomic
the science of ergonomics.
So, Vogue
Voguev
says, I saw a a Reddit post about Evil
key binding being
uh new uh
mnemonic, and Xah Fly Keys all about
functionality. Yes, that is true.
Uh what is your take on mnemonic versus
general func- functionality? Yes, I have
a good answer for that. Because
I have So, but let me ask you, have you
used Xah Fly Keys before? I guess not.
I mean, do answer that, please.
Have you used Xah Fly Keys before? And
have you used Evil mod before?
Because if you haven't not
then you know, I might go you know,
explain that. Um
So, anyway, Xah Fly Keys is efficient
you know, ergonomic key binding system
for Emacs.
Uh now, Evil mod
is also Well, Evil mod the purpose Evil
mod is also a alternative key binding
system for Emacs.
But however,
Well, the the Evil mod the purpose of
Evil mod is modeled after the VI or Vim
uh editor, you know, so
uh basically it you know, whatever Vim's
commands, Vim's keys,
you know, you use that in Emacs. That's
that's the purpose of Evil mod.
Okay, so you haven't tried Xah Fly Keys
before, but you have tried Evil mod
before.
Yeah, okay, so
first of all, for those interested, if
you want to know the difference in one
sentence, you just go to Xah Fly Keys
homepage, you know, just search for Xah
Fly Keys. And at at the bottom, I
actually I I give you a uh
frequently asked frequently asked
questions about For example, here, how
does it compare to Evil mod?
So, Evil mod is basically just Vim keys
in Emacs.
Uh and the advantage
Okay, first of all, Vim keys Vim key
binding is much more
much more efficient than Emacs default
keys.
Whatever you do, if you use Emacs, do
not use Emacs default key binding, you
know?
Control control F, control P, the [ __ ]
it, those Whoever says you should use
Emacs default key bindings, or whoever
says you you should who whoever says
that it's fine, you know, you should try
it, it's fine. [ __ ] them, okay? They
they they they don't know what they're
talking about.
This is serious because Emacs is the
editor that has caused in throughout
history in the past 30 years has caused
so many people uh repetitive
repetitive strain injury. In many cases,
ruined their career, you know, I Richard
Stallman is one example, you know, Jamie
Zawinski, JWZ is another example. And
Ben
uh
so many, you can you'll find stories
every day. But anyway, so
do not use Emacs key binding system.
Now, Vim key binding system is much more
better is much better than Emacs, okay?
So,
you know, you can use Vim, you know,
Evil mod. So, Evil mod is the emulation,
you know, of the Vim key binding in
Emacs.
Uh
So, you can use that, and one of the
benefit of Vim,
you know, besides, you know, better
keys, you know, less prone to repetitive
strain injury, one of another advantage
is that it has fairly
large number of users, you know, uh
I suppose a few thousand.
Um you know, fairly large number of
users. And uh
Yeah, that is it. If you compare Okay,
so
a lot users and it's better than Emacs
default keys. Now,
so why Xahflyy keys? What what why can't
you just use evil? Well, evil is fine,
but
the
the but the Vim key binding is not
optimal because the Vim key binding, the
VI editor,
they their key binding is evolved from
history, you know, it's not
it's not like someone sit down and
design, you know, think about what is
the best key binding, what what is the
most ergonomic, what is the most
efficient, and they you know, they
design the key binding. It's not like
that. It it It came from, you know, so I
have actually
quite a lot articles, tens of articles
about this issue. So,
okay okay, so just go search for Xah
keyboard blog and you go to
uh
you go to history.
Okay, and you see all these old
ancient terminals. So, VI key binding
came from this machine, this terminal.
Back in uh 1976,
this is the machine that VI key binding
originates.
Uh this keyboard, you can see there's
actually arrows on it.
Uh and escape key is right here.
So, anyway, you can read this article uh
in detail and you will learn a lot
history, you know,
so the this is the layout for the this
terminal. You can see that HJKL is kind
of arrow keys and escape is right here.
Uh that that is why VI used it uses
that.
And you have
Okay, you know, go read this article
offline
and
um
and there's another article I want to
show you here. History of Emacs and VI
keys. So, in this article I discuss the
history, you know, how did the Emacs key
binding came from, you know, the control
meta, you know, control meta super
hyper.
That's uh
this is the Lisp machine keyboards,
which by itself is a, you know, very big
history, uh
very interesting. Lisp machine
keyboards. Yeah, so so Emacs key binding
system, they
they kind of came from they were they
came from the Lisp machine uh keyboards.
And VI's keyboard
key binding
originates from this ADM-3A terminal.
So, anyway, that's history of Emacs key
binding and uh
VI's key binding, okay?
Uh the hardware aspect. Of course,
there's more than just hardware, but
anyway, those are the hardware they came
from.
They
uh and but so I was saying
So, so VI's key binding system came
from, you know, the ADM-3A terminal in
1976.
Uh and what I was saying? Oh, yeah, so
So, both Emacs key binding and the VI
key binding or even shortcuts like
control C, control X from Photoshop or
from Apple command C, you know, copy cut
copy cut paste uh undo open, you know,
command O for open, command P for print,
those are Apple. They they came from
Apple kind of.
I have a article on that as well, but
you know, go to my website, you know, if
you like it, link, you know, I
So, this is my advertisement, you know,
go read my articles because I have like
hundreds of them articles about these
details.
If you like it, link to it, okay, in
your blog or social networks, Twitter,
and whatever.
So,
So, the VI key binding system both VI
and Emacs or even Apple's or whatever,
you know,
they are not designed to be efficient,
you know, because in the beginning, you
know, people, you know, the the very
concept of keyboard shortcut or key
binding is kind of new, you know,
almost every invention in the beginning
they just want to make it work. Then,
you know, they
there's no concept the concept of
ergonomic is not there, you know, it's
almost like that.
So, anyway, so the VI key binding system
is not efficient, okay? It's it's just
historical. It's just evolved because,
you know, for example, let me tell you
why why does VI have this command mode,
insert mode? I mean,
you know,
for a lot people it's like when you
first when when you are exposed to it
for the first time, you find it strange.
Oh, you have the command mode, then you
have the insert mode.
The reason it's like that because back
in those days, 1970s,
there is no like you cannot just like
type something and it shows up, you
know,
um
Let me show you. You know, like
you know, type something and it shows up
on the screen in real time. There's no
such thing like that. Instead,
everything is like kind of like batch.
You know, so you have to input a command
like they they used to use uh punch
cards, you know. You input you you input
to the computer.
Then you let it compute, then it output
the result. So, you you you want to
you know,
write a essay, for example, you insert a
sentence input. Then you say, "Okay, I'm
done. Now, show me the show me what I've
done." Then it it shows up on the
screen.
That is why you this this That's why you
have this insert mode uh command mode.
That was, you know, that was like that.
I don't I'm not sure
you know, it's not called that.
Then Emacs came along. Emacs is the
first editor that that has so-called
real-time display. In fact, that's what
um Emacs manual says.
Uh let's go to Emacs manual, for
example.
Emacs, yeah.
Uh okay, here. We go to Emacs manual. It
used to say, I'm not sure it still says
so today.
So, it say it says Emacs is the
extensible, customizable,
self-documenting
real-time display editor. You see,
that's the word, you see?
Real-time display editor. What the [ __ ]
does that mean? Is there an editor
that's not real-time? Yes.
Well,
back then, no editor is real-time. Emacs
is the first real-time display editor,
you know, meaning that WYSIWYG, you
know, what you see is what you get,
something like that. You know, when you
type, it shows up on the screen right
away.
Because Emacs was the first. That that
was what that that is why in Emacs
manual it says real-time display editor.
So, back to the topic of VI. So, VI key
binding, they are, you know, they are
they are historical, you know,
it's not, you know, nothing is
ergonomic, you know,
the the concept barely exist.
So, so what I'm saying is that
uh
VI's key binding is not, you know,
is historical, okay?
But still, it's much better than Emacs.
So, so I So, So, I did, you know, I want
uh Xah Xah key binding uh Xahflyy keys,
on the other hand, is
is
um is is created in invented from the
ground up based on ergonomic principles,
efficiency, and ergonomics.
So, the basic design is that, first of
all, you take statistics of all Emacs
commands, for example.
Let me show you
uh Xah um let's see what is the um
frequency show. So, you can see here
this is a list of commands statistics of
my Emacs use, you know, all the
commands, how many times they are
called, and you have a percentage. So,
it's based on these statistics, not just
my, by the way, it's it's based on, you
know, I have
You know, if if you go read the the
detail, you will see links to the
statistics
um
uh let me let me just show you then. Uh
Xah packages
uh
practically uh key binding. So, you go
to Emacs keys.
Then this page is a index of all
articles related to keys or key binding
or shortcuts.
And in here you will find
um
Here, Emacs command frequency
statistics. So, I did this study like 10
years ago, 2007, you know, when I was
doing
Ergo Emacs distribution of Emacs.
So, anyway, so
anyway, so you you can see statistics um
So, you take statistics of Emacs
commands. Then, the first 30 of them,
the most frequently used commands,
you assign them a key.
Which key assigned to what command is
based on
um the most frequently used command
have the most easy key.
Basically, that is a principle.
How evil eye keys key binding uh uh
designed.
So, let's go back to evil eye keys.
Uh
Yeah. So, you know, so that that is why
I say it's efficient. You know, I I dare
to say it is the most efficient of
anything in the universe.
That actually
um
you know,
So, let's let me So, so that's a basic
introduction of evil eye keys. Now,
so
So, let me summarize. So, if you want
to, you know, if you want to use VI or
you know, evil mod or vim, that's good.
You know, there's nothing wrong with
that.
Uh and one advantage is that you have,
you know,
you have like 10 times more users than
evil eye keys, okay?
But, if you you know,
uh really want if you have hand pain,
you or you really want the most
efficient key binding, then, you know,
go for evil eye keys.
Uh but anyway, either one of them, if
you never use them,
uh both, you know, either one of them
will take, you know, a month or two to
get used to.
Because the learning experience will
always be very frustrating uh for sure.
It's same thing with learning a Dvorak,
a new keyboard layout. You know, the
first month will be extremely painful.
But, you just have to, you know, go
through it.
So, that's the introduction. So, and if
you have further questions about that or
if you want to see some demos, you know,
you know, just post, you know, ask me
and I'll answer it.
So,
okay, so Shawn, good morning, Shawn.
That uh looks like God's terminal, okay.
What is
What a pretty machine, okay.
Uh Oscar, Oscar says, "Hello, thanks for
this live video." Thank you.
Thank you. I haven't seen you before.
Hi, Oscar.
Uh Daniel says, "Daniel Langlois, good
morning, Daniel.
So,
uh Volgoth says,
"If you don't have mods, how do you have
these key bindings without using mods?"
I do have mods.
You know, evil eye keys is is is modal,
just like vim, okay, just like evil mod.
It's modal.
Uh yeah.
Okay, so there are two parts to evil eye
keys, okay. One is that it's modal. So,
you have command mod. So, for example,
right now I'm command mod, you know, for
example, I want to delete this
paragraph, it's done, you know, just one
key. I, you know, on Dvorak keyboard,
it's I. On QWERTY, it's G, okay. I'm
using Dvorak, so I'm going to go with
Dvorak. So, if I want to undo now,
undo, one key, it's F on
um on Dvorak, okay. You see?
Undo, you know, you know, I go down. So,
if I want to go down, you know, I just
hold down the you know, this S key on
Dvorak.
You know, I and I go up. If I want to go
all the way up,
So, anyway, so you have this command mod
and insert mod. So, let's say I enter,
I go into insert mod and I'm ready to
type.
Ready to type, okay.
Now, let me switch to back to command
mod. I'm back to command mod. Then, I
can delete the whole thing. It's all one
key, one single key.
Okay, I'm I'm done with that. Save.
Okay, so um
Yeah, so you have command mod, you have
insert mod, just like VI.
Now,
after that, okay, so so that's one
thing. The other thing, there's another
thing is the leader keys
in evil eye keys.
Now, I I'm not sure leader keys is
actually part of VI originally.
I'm not sure, but in anyway, in evil
mod, there's
there's a package that does So, so what
does leader keys means? Leader keys
means, for example,
you know, Emacs by default has more than
over 1,000 commands.
And you cannot, you know, have
a key binding for every command because
Excuse me.
Uh so, anyway, so um
So, Emacs has 1,000 commands. So,
So, one of the way to bind keys, you
know,
in default Emacs, the way you bind keys
is I control X,
then control something, you know, or
control, you know, for example, to open
a file is
Let me try it, okay. Look at the left
panel. Control X,
control F. Oh, oops, I typed it wrong.
Let's try again. Control X, control F.
You know, to
to try to open the file, that's idiotic,
okay. Control X, control F.
So,
that's a key sequence, you know. But,
instead, if I want to open a file, okay,
I do that oops.
Uh I do that.
You see?
Three keys, delete C. dot.
And delete, by the way, delete because
I'm using this Kinesis delete key is
just uh one of my thumb key, a key, you
know, on my thumb.
So, I just press three keys. No no, you
know, the code combinations, control X,
control C, whatever.
You know, I just just three single key
presses, you know.
Uh yeah, so
So, this
key sequence is is
is normally called leader key sequence
because you start with the key
that begins the key sequence. In in my
case, the the leader key is space.
I can actually
uh space, so you know, you are seeing
delete because that's my customization
because
for this keyboard I'm using, I have two
leader keys. So, I can you know, use my
right thumb or left thumb, you know.
Um but in general, it's space. Space key
is leader key. So, leader keys, you
know, let me show you what the leader
key is. So, I type space, okay.
Then, I press control H.
Then, Emacs will show me all is you can
see all the leader key sequences I have
here, you know, space tab causes
commands, space return causes command,
and so on, you know,
there's like uh
200 of them.
So, leader keys, no key combination, no
code because code is one of the you
should ban code keys. Code code keys is
one of the um major
cause of RSI, okay.
Again, you know, I have like I have a I
have literally few few hundred articles
on these issues. You can see
if you
go to my Emacs Emacs blog, you go to the
Emacs keys section, you know, there are
like
yeah, 50 articles about
key bindings or, you know, uh
uh repetitive strain injury and and so
on and keyboards.
Then, if you go to my keyboard blog,
which is on xahlee.info,
you go to
uh you know, key binding, there's many
articles related to key binding. How do
you design key binding? How do you
measure which one is more efficient than
the other?
Uh you know,
you know, all all these kind of details
in a scientific way because when it
comes to key bindings, most people,
their opinions are just based on habit,
you know, they never actually sit down
and thought about things. It's just
habit. You have to always go by
scientific
you know, try to go by scientific means,
like measure. How you measure it? You
know, what kind of formula you can
measure it? You can quantify it. Then,
you you do statistics, you know, you
measure yourself or you let, you know,
uh measure other people's, you know,
that's how you actually get a good idea.
And also, of course, with
uh experience, your own
you know,
feeling of the, you know, which is
easier and so on.
So, yeah, so there's a lot of articles.
I, you know, like I have all these
written out.
Um
You guys might want
uh you know, try to read that.
Uh so, we'll go uh
Yeah, so I hope that covered the
question. Any more questions, Volkov?
Volkov.
So, Aldo, good morning, Aldo. So, Aldo,
Aldo, where you from?
Where you like come What what country is
uh
So, Daniel says I'm at a hospital cuz a
baby just got born.
Niece. Okay.
Now, the English word niece is like
like English words, I have to think
about um
Good morning, Jack.
So,
So, niece is like Okay, there's cousins,
there's niece.
I always get confused um
I don't remember what this
So, so
So,
good morning, Jack. Jack.
Uh
Jack, you know, help me out on the um
Help me out on the on the B
B chat.
So, um
Aldo is from Indonesia. Wow, that's so
interesting. It's another country I
haven't
um
you know, that's a new country
from you know,
from
from those watching my videos.
Uh
Indonesia.
Okay, Jack, I I talk to I talk to you
offline. So, we are I'm planning to go
to a you know, I'm planning to do a
Chinese talk show, you know, in Chinese
language because I have a lot followers
in China
uh and Taiwan, you know, Chinese people.
And you know, China is so they they have
you know, their own YouTube.
By the way, is Jack, do you know is is
China's B you know, their videos in
China?
Are they more popular? I mean, is this
Is it more Is it bigger than YouTube or
is it not?
No, I don't have a SIM SIM card card.
No, but let's talk about that, you know,
offline, you know, just between us.
But do you know I mean, like
B chat
So, anyways, so
back to the
um
questions. Niece is the daughter of
brother.
Oh, okay, right. Daughter of brother or
sister, but it's a brother. Okay.
Daughter of a brother. So, your
brother's daughter.
Right.
Oh, yeah, YouTube is bigger. Yeah, that
makes sense.
Because YouTube is worldwide.
Uh
Yeah, YouTube is banned in China.
Um
Anyway, so any any more questions about
keyboards?
So, if no more questions about
keyboards, then that's it for keyboards.
And maybe we talk about something else.
So, let's review, okay, this ADM, you
know, I'm just going to um
close that.
On three says, "Thanks for streams, on
behalf of the
uh TV show."
Uh you're welcome. Origins of Vim key
binding was specially interesting. Thank
you.
Uh Okay, so what what else should we
talk about?
So, let's see the X talk show. Yeah, I
wanted to show you some you know, some
Let's see.
Let's
uh let's wrap up on keys.
Uh
Okay, Jack asked me a question about
Chinese versus
um
you know, the
the tariff war
the economics war between China and the
USA.
What is my opinion about that? Actually,
I don't know much about that.
Yeah.
You know,
I don't really know much about that.
Um
So, I wanted to show you Okay, keyboard
blog.
Uh So, let me show Okay, I let me go
back to I want to show um
Emacs blog. Close. Close.
X talk show. Okay.
I want to
uh let me show you this. Go to
JavaScript blog. Okay. So, you go to my
JavaScript blog.
So, I did this. Finally, it's complete.
This is uh extreme idiocy idiocy of the
industrial
uh programming spec and protocols. Uh
you know, I've been This is one of my
common topic I
about related to programming. I talked
about
you know, often.
So, you know, in fact, I did a video on
this
few days ago, maybe last week.
Uh
the
So,
anyway, let me let me just show you
this. So, I did this.
Circle. So, you can you have this
interactive application.
You see, this one changes the center,
the X uh parameter. You can use the
mouse scroll wheel to up. And this
changes the Y parameter.
And this changes the major axis. You can
use the mouse wheel to adjust it.
Or you can type a number, you know, uh
And this changes the uh
You know, when you have a ellipse, you
have major major axis and minor axis.
And start and end radia- radi- radian.
Okay, and then you can change the
rotation.
Uh this is wrong.
Okay. Anyway, I did this.
Okay, so What is What is the point about
this? Well, you I have to explain
because otherwise it's you know, it
doesn't make sense. But I did a video a
whole video 1 hour about this.
Uh
Let's see. Should I
Should I talk about that or something
else? So, so let me know Yeah, so
what else?
Keyboards pro- you know, we Let's see.
I've been talking for
40 minutes. So, keyboard
keyboards, Emacs, programming stuff, or
JavaScript
or
uh non-technical stuff.
Non-technical stuff would be like random
stuff like today's event, current
events.
The
maybe we should not go into that because
because you know, we've been talking
about technical stuff and uh
sometimes people don't want to
Okay, no questions?
We got eight people. Come on, type
something. Let me know what to talk
about.
Okay, let me let me go talk about this
JavaScript then. So, this This is one of
the idiocy of the industry of of the
programming industry. Okay?
So, in in JavaScript, in SVG. Now, if
you don't know SVG, what SVG is a
graphics format for vector graphics,
okay? It allows you to create things
like you know, a clock or any kind of
drawing. It's like a flash, you know,
the Macromedia Adobe Flash used on the
web.
So, SVG is this technology. It basically
is just XML like that.
Uh you know, if you copy this
create a file, copy, paste this, save
it, and show in browser, it it will draw
a line.
You know, you can just copy that.
And uh
Uh let me talk let me finish this in 5
minutes then
I'll answer the question. So
So SVG is the this technology that lets
you draw all these kind of things circle
square lines and it's basically just XML
file you know just like HTML.
Um but there is this you know it's not
there is this it's
There There is this extreme idiocy you
know
okay.
So for example if you want to draw a
circle you can just type these okay
circle this is very simple.
You know just say circle then center you
know CX CY is a center coordinate then a
radius okay. However when you want to
draw a pie chart you know a pie chart is
like a quarter of a circle or half a
circle you know a pie chart.
You cannot use this
circle primitive because there's no
parameter for you know how much of a
circle you want to draw.
So how do you draw a you know an arc of
a circle? You have to use this um
You have to use this path element.
And this path element is extremely
complicated.
Uh basically what you have to do is to
you go to path
elliptic
elliptical arc. You have to use this
um
Basically
a path with like like seven numbers. The
numbers represent
um they represent the major axis the
minor axis length the rotation of the
ellipse
then there's
then two parameters called arc flag
and sweep flag.
Those are booleans like either one or
zero.
Then you have last last two point is the
end point.
You know so so you know you may not know
what I'm talking about because it is
just really extremely complicated. It is
you know so
if you want to draw an arc of a circle
the only way to do it is by using this
path element with this A command.
And it is not possible to actually
understand it unless you are unless you
are a mathematician.
You know so
uh so you know I talked about this in
last video for an hour.
So but anyway today is you know I
finally uh
uh finished writing this program.
So I so here is a JavaScript function.
This function will generate a path
element that represents
an arc of a circle.
But the function's parameters is based
on you know you just say where is the
center you know the major and minor axis
and the
the degree to begin
the circle the arc and the degree to end
the arc.
Then a rotation you know in case you
want to rotate the whole thing. So I
wrote this
uh
application JavaScript application
interactive application so you can um
So you know finally I did that.
So let me answer the question so what is
your take on reading as a hobby?
Obviously it's good for you but some
would prefer to just read documentation
or simply technical stuff.
Uh
Oh yeah reading is a as a hobby reading
is good.
Um
Let's see what I want to say about that
you know
You know when I was younger I I I I read
a lot you because I want I for example
in literature you know there are
uh
You know there are there are classic
literatures like one one you know
they they have a list you know several
organizations or publications they have
a list of the you know let's say 100
best classic literature or novel novels
in history you know.
For example you have peace war and peace
by this Russian writer war and peace
some of the classic for example
war and peace
sense and sensibility you know all these
are novels
uh
you know the
um
a tale of two cities you know Charles
Dickinson
uh you know Mo Moby Dick by American
author
the white wolf by Jack something's
American author
uh old man the sea another American
author You know so you have these
uh so many of the greatest novels.
So when when I was younger I
I wanted to read them all kind of.
Anyway one thing interesting about that
is that when I was younger I thought
that novels are not interesting because
you know my my my sense is that you know
novel is just like just a story you know
that's it but actually that's not the
case. A novel great novel such as war
and peace
you know and and many of these novel
novels including Chinese ones you know
they are
several
huge epic you know they are really
called epic you know voluminous
uh Chinese novels for example uh
uh
the dream of the red
uh chamber you know that's one of the
Chinese novel big epic one.
So not so novels they are not just they
are not just like
story or you know they they are
the great novels they represent
they they
they are many things they they they tell
the story of humanity all the
things we every day we feel you know we
we want we
For example every day in everyday life
we have to make decisions or we maybe
fall in love or sometimes we hate
someone or we don't know what we should
do you know what job should we take what
what should your career choices be.
So these questions in daily life or pain
you know or maybe your parents got sick
you don't have money or something like
that or some injustice you know you see
these rich people they do [ __ ] around
and
you know they they they lie and you know
and what can you do about that? So so
you know all the emotions you
have maybe you don't know what to do you
know so all these are you know many of
these so novels the great novels they
capture these things and they show you
uh wisdoms or they show you examples or
you know so you learn it is it's not
just like
you know I was thinking it's just a
story you know just someone made up the
story. It's not like that
they capture the many things in life you
know so called humanity that's why the
literature you know
philosophy department they are called
humanity arts and humanity you know.
That's humanity.
Uh but not you know this great novels
not not just it's about humanity but
also in many cases they capture the
history. For example war and war and
peace or the dream of the red
red chamber
um or you know they they capture the
history of the era so you can actually
see how people are like what they do you
know what's their daily life what what's
the thinking of the era. You know like
today we have current situation we have
current political things you know Trump
or whatever the social just justice
[ __ ] okay they do things.
But you know after after after 20 years
people may not know you know they don't
feel they don't see they don't feel what
we are seeing today you know or
or in the technical department you know
we have JavaScript
PHP we have Pascal you know these things
going on you know and programmer says oh
this is good that is bad. Or we have OOP
you know back then 10 years ago.
So anyway so you have a history kind of
So anyway those are novels okay.
So it's a good thing to read them you
know
I'm kind of too old you know I don't
have time to for it that those these
kind of things now I like I said you
know before
uh I give myself five five more years
after five more years I'm done for.
I don't have time to read a novel now I
hope to learn something
uh about proof systems in math. Anyway
yeah so novel you know
it's good to read them you know the
classic ones uh and also you know
there's a saying that don't read
anything that's within
the past 100 years.
I kind of agree that agree to that you
know this trash you know many of the
books
especially the popular books, the number
one best sellers
on Amazon or New York Times [ __ ] the New
New York New York Times whatever.
Usually it's not worthwhile, okay.
So for for for you guys, if you haven't
read novels, it's a good thing to do.
Well, I know a lot of you guys, you
know, because we are programmers, a lot
of you guys are into science science
fiction.
I actually haven't read much of science
fiction myself.
John Updike would like a word. So what
did he say? You know, I know he's a very
famous
guy, American writer.
But I have not read anything by him.
So yeah, so if you guys, you know,
read novel is good.
And science fiction. So science fiction
I haven't really read much about science
fiction. So let's go to let's go to Tsar
D.
Wordy blog. So Wordy blog is my blog
about writing, literature, linguistics,
grammar,
speech, all these kind of things and
logic from the haughty emotions of
lexicon, stylistic concerns,
decipherment of grammar and idioms,
linguistic quality, literature and
logicality. So this is my Tsar Wordy
blog, okay. So if you go to Wordy
English,
the lure of vocabulary, the depth of
literature, the question of style, the
logic of linguistics, the ills of
English and the cure by writing.
So some of my favorite literature I have
actually annotated. The Arabian Nights
translated by this guy Richard Sir
Burton is one of the is one of my
favorite favorite.
It's amazing, okay.
It's nothing you know, you know, the
Arabian Nights. You have to read by this
guy Richard Burton.
And then the Shakespeare.
Shakespeare
um
Where is it?
A Modest Proposal,
To Build a Fire by Jack London. This is
a short
This is great, fantastic. To Build a
Fire fire. All these, you know, all
these ones I collected here
I have actually annotated them.
You know, some of them I spent a year,
you know, for example, this Shakespeare.
This Shakespeare, The Tragedy of Titus
Andronicus.
I spent like 2 years annotating them.
Because
for example,
you know, uh
Now climbs Tamora Olympus' top.
Safe out of the safe out of fortune's
shot and sits aloft. So
This is one of my favorites, the Titus
Andronicus.
This story is about revenge and cruelty.
It's about revenge. I love it.
Anyway, so
Yeah, I kind of, you know, rambled
about, you know, so
novels, fictions.
Um
So Sean says, last 100 years he's coming
around. It's getting relevant. What do
you mean?
John Updike?
I hate hate most science fiction. Oh,
good morning, Deion.
Hey Deion, thank you for PayPal or thank
you for the Patreon.
I
you know,
like I have some Patreon, you know, some
people who support me financially,
but I do not necessarily remember them,
like who they are, you know.
Anyway, I noticed, you know, uh
you have bought my Emacs tutorials, so
thank you.
Yeah, so science fiction I haven't read
much about it. Well, the only kind of
actually the only two I've read is Time
Machine,
which is fantastic, you know, Time
Machine by H.G. Wells.
You know, actually Time Machine. So in
Time Machine you have this character she
look at
beautiful this beautiful white girl.
She
her name is Weena in the fiction.
So she you know, I'm beginning to I kind
of see today's situation society,
you know, American and otherwise, you
know, we people are becoming like like
like the
like the tragedy in Time Machine.
They they have become that today's
social social justice.
And I'm sorry, you know, all the gays
and trans. You know,
I I know a lot of my followers are trans
and gays.
Um
But anyway,
in general, you know, I think there is
kind of
today today's society it's like
um
You know, I feel like like it's like
almost
see what I want to say.
You know, that basically the question is
what is humanity? What are we becoming?
You know, that is that is the question
everyone is asking.
Meaning that in 10 years
what will what will people be doing? You
know, there are so many issues. For
example, there is
as you know, there are many political
issues, you know, people panic about,
you know, doesn't matter which group you
belong to, you know, people worry about
things may is happening and stuff.
Also there are wars going on, you know,
fortunately we are not you know, we are
in US, we don't have to you know, we can
still sip coffee at Starbucks and talk
about these things without bombs flying,
you know,
arms cutting off and stuff.
So we
you know, so there are all these things
going on and we don't know what's going
on to going to happen in the future, you
know, you know, AI is coming, we have
robotics, this space
they replace jobs, you know,
you know, lots of things. So we don't
really and also atomic bomb or global
warming.
You know, we don't really know what will
actually happen in 10 years, you know,
some people worry a lot, some people are
more optimistic.
But these questions are on our mind, you
know.
And one of the question is what will
human what will human animals become?
Let's say in five in 50 years from
today.
Now I'm
I'm probably I'm not going to be around
in 50 years, but you guys may be.
So you know, what what will
you know, the world what will people be
like, you know, 50 years from today?
So that is the question, you know.
Um
And from what I see, so you know, last
week or you know, sometimes this this
week I you know, I look at Twitter all
the anger and stuff going on
on Twitter.
I'm I'm kind of thinking, you know,
it's kind of degenerate, okay. Let me
let me
maybe I'll show some some of the stuff
on Twitter.
Uh
so
Let me let me show this beautiful girl,
okay, this Hollywood elite rich [ __ ]
Uh so go to my Twitter.
So obviously one of the big issue people
are talking about today is abortion
stuff.
Which is kind of idiotic, the American
white people [ __ ]
Like American in general like you know,
they don't know you know, they
I'm sorry to say I'm American, okay. And
most of you are, you guys.
But anyway, look at this
uh
But okay, so what I'm saying there is
like the American many of the
you know, the I thinking the they are
just
You know, it's it's a huge such a huge
topic. If I dip into I'm going to
it's going to be another few hours talk,
okay, about
the thinking of typical Americans, okay.
Anyway, look at this
this girl.
Met Gala, this this rich [ __ ]
You know, 10 years ago, 20 years ago, I
look at this, I would think this is well
wow, this is great. This is beautiful. I
mean, 20 20 years ago, this would not
happen. It's not allowed, you know,
because
you know, as as you know, we have
the sexual, you know,
the the the what is allowed and what is
not allowed becomes
you know, we have less and less rules,
you know, we have porn every day, you
know, people you know, don't talk about
it. People this white people the social
justice justice can [ __ ] and also the
programmers at Google, you know, they
avoid talking about it, but
you know, but it's reality. You know,
you look at the porn.
I don't know if you guys do it, but
you know, you look at this this is all
kind of things going on.
It's it's exponential growth, you know,
it's Anyway, just look at the
celebrities, you know, this this is a
public you know, thing and every big
stars, she's a model, okay, she's
dressed like that. I you know, I could
not this wouldn't happen 10 years
maybe 10 years ago, not 20 years ago.
So, so what I'm saying is that so what
So, what is what what is wrong? So,
because I have you know, I have
you read comics, okay? I have read
comics, you know, there's some some
adult comics, erotic comics.
And you read erotic comics back in '90s,
you sometimes you see future.
Or in some movies, let's go to some
movies, okay?
Some favorite movies, it's you know, I'm
just talking random things. Let's see,
there's a science fiction.
Sci-fi.
So, this uh Logan's Run, okay? So,
there's this
classic movie Logan's Run.
Um
and you know, it's a great movie. If you
guys have not seen it, it's great.
So, in this movie, they show, you know,
in some of the science fictions, okay?
They show a utopia
where basically, you know, they depict,
you know, look at this poster, you can
see
so, they imagine sometime in the future
the life is so good, you just have sex
all day, you know, all everyone is
beautiful.
You know, everyone is beautiful and
today we have lots of that kind of
movie, too.
You know, maybe there's a drug or maybe
there's a virtual reality, everyone just
put on a headset and everyone is
beautiful or there's a
another movie where
you know, you have a time on your wrist
similar to Logan's Run where when you
reach 30 years old, you just die. So,
every So, that means everyone in the
world is just beautiful and young, okay?
So, anyway, there's a common theme. It's
uh
in science fiction utopia where you just
have
you know, like the the perfect world of
total pleasure.
Welcome to the 23rd century, okay?
So, and I look at today, you know,
today's porn and this this celebrity
[ __ ]
Uh
you know, and I'm starting to think so,
this is kind of like, you know, the
the the the sci-fi utopia
uh
we are seeing. Yeah, particular Yeah,
let me just show you another one. Um
another one uh
it's very common stuff about this um
So, yeah, so the the the other one I
want to show you is a AI movie by
uh
So, there's a movie by by
the name of the movie is Artificial
Intelligence.
And this movie is back in
2000 something, I think.
So, so I'm still alive.
Okay, most people are gone, okay? So,
um
So, this AI movie
So, again, you have this utopia.
And this utopia is, you know, they use
there's lots of sex, you know, pleasure.
Um
And when you So, so in many of them,
they have, you know, these sex things
and
the women, they dressed like
you know, like this kind of dress just
exactly just like um
just just like her.
So, um
So, you know, that's So, I'm thinking,
you know, we are going there, we're
getting there.
And however, the society is not is not
stable, you know,
you know, so it's not So, instead of
utopia, we are you know, it's a
dystopia.
So, that's worrisome, you know.
Anyway, so I think maybe that's it for
today. So, any more comments?
1 hour and 5 minutes, okay, that's
actually not too long because in the
past week, I've been talking for
90 minutes.
So, Deion says technology and comfort is
cooking our brains. Yes. We are in a
transitional period because human beings
were not designed to handle technology.
Uh yes, just like our caveman
ancestors had to adjust to agricultural
civilization.
I see.
Uh
Yeah, so anyway, maybe we can I can
finish thoughts up about this. So, you
know, many science fictions, you have
this utopia concept and many many of
these utopia concept
uh you have this sex sex plays a major
role like in the future, you know,
everyone is just everyone looks
beautiful all the time and you just have
sex all day.
And that's that's kind of like I'm kind
of seeing you know, I feel like I'm
seeing that today, you know,
you have these movie stars, not just
her, like it's like everyone, you know,
all these movie stars or singers.
You know,
you know, almost like every one of them,
the females, you know, they they they
are dressed like that, they, you know,
and as far as as far as sex goes, you
know,
of course, we we know that it's very
open. You can
girls, you know, you have sex anytime.
You have, you know, not just sex, but
you have like, you know,
traditionally, it's called degenerate,
okay? So, you have gays
[ __ ] the ass, you know, obviously and
you have then then you have trans, okay?
Which which which is, you know, it's not
a you know, let's say it's not a
statistically, it's not a normal thing,
okay? It's not the normal biological
thing.
If you are trans, that's fine, okay?
That
you know, because this is [ __ ]
because today this social justice [ __ ]
you have these sensitive topics, so you
cannot I cannot talk about anything
without, you know, trying to maybe oh
oh, by the way, I love trans, okay, you
know, they have I have to qualify.
But anyway, so
so it's kind of degenerate, you know,
it's like, you know, people get, you
know, also Camille Paglia, one of my
favorite author, she she is truly a
scholar on
um on pop culture.
Not just pop culture, but she goes deep
into history. She studies history of all
the arts in the world, you know.
Um
You know, she has been doing that for
decades and she, you know, one of the
comments she made is that
when a civilization is about to
collapse, you know,
they they tends to become degenerate,
you know,
so I'm kind of seeing that, you know, I
don't know like nobody knows for sure,
but I I feel
there's some kind of it's kind of like
going on, okay?
It's degenerate.
You know, so I mean, it's
it's not just like she's dressed like
this. Like she's dressed like this, but
today the social justice or
it become it's a kind of a mainstream
now.
They say it's not because, you know,
they
the women's they have problem with their
images. Like they they they want to
promote fat, uh you know, fat women.
They say it's a man's fault.
But
you just look. That's not Look at them,
these rich [ __ ] They want to and
meanwhile they say they they need to
help the poor and have-nots.
And these rich [ __ ] are dressed dressed
with these
thousands of dollars uh clothing and
and, you know,
running around.
You know, so that that's that's kind of
the thing. So,
so yeah, it's kind of this dystopia. And
I also I also was thinking, you know,
perhaps, you know,
it's like the winner in the in the uh
time machine in the future.
Anyway,
uh
So, six people watching. Who who are who
are you guys? They say something. I
think I'm done today.
Deion.
Yeah, so
um
it's six of you.
So, I think I think that's it for today.
So, unless anyone has more questions,
then
type it.
In 10 seconds,
then we'll shut down.
There's usually so many things to talk
about. But anyway, yeah, but you know,
I've been talking for hours. So, usually
1 hour is good.
Uh 1 hour is good time to stop.
But, you know, but there are so many
things, you know, about the world, about
um
I wasn't actually making a coherent
uh
expression about that, you know, this
girl thing. Because actually yesterday I
did uh you mostly entire hour is about
this girl issues
uh yesterday.
Uh
Dennis Hall.
Thank you, Dennis.
Homotopy type theory. Yeah, I wish to
That's a big topic. I I wish to learn
that actually. I haven't you know, that
Yeah, so in the next 5 years I will hope
to learn that those things, homotopy
type theory.
By the way, do you know any Do you know
it?
Do you Are you
uh
Do you know
you know, this kind of subject? Are you
studying it or
something, Deion?
Okay, let's see who learns it first.
Hey, Jack. Oh, Jack, you're still here.
You may make a series of Emacs and Elisp
tutorials. Yeah, my problem right now is
is like my videos are random.
It's been like that, you know, I've been
thinking about this for a while. Um
because, you know,
because I don't have a fixed time where
I, you know, what what time I'm going to
come out. And also I don't have a fixed
topic. You know, it's almost it's
basically just like every time I come
out,
you know, it just some topics happens.
So, there's a problem with that because
then people who are interested in Emacs,
they don't know when I'm going to be on
and they don't know if I'm on, then I'm
going to talk about sex, which which
they don't want to see, okay? And some
people are interested in keyboards and
but other people are interested in, you
know,
philosophy or, you know, any thoughts
about random things.
So, I don't have a schedule, so that's a
problem. So, you know,
so I've been thinking of a fixed
schedule.
Uh fixed schedule means, you know, every
let's say for the next week every noon
I'm going to then I'm going to
I I'm going to set a list, you know,
Mondays Emacs, Tuesdays random,
Thursdays
about keyboards, you know, and so on.
Then that that would be better. But then
again, I'm not you know, I don't know
that's that is exactly what I want to
do. Um
Yeah, but
that's kind of a story. Because, you
know, because there's really there
there's a lot I can do. For example, for
Emacs,
uh I can, you know,
I could just do actually the
entire my videos will be Emacs. Emac
Lisp, Emacs today is Emacs command X,
tomorrow is Emacs command Y,
the next day is Emac command systems,
key binding system or whatever or the
next day the future of Emacs, you know.
But anyway, it's just like that. I'm
kind of just
flowing about.
Uh
No, I I I I don't know. I don't have a
time yet. I don't know. Because also
because my sleeping schedule they cycle
all the time. Because sometimes I sleep
in the daytime.
Uh what do you mean, Jack?
So, any anyway, I kind of Yeah, so today
that that's it for today. Uh cuz I'm
also after sitting, you know, I got to
go walk. Um
Yeah, I want to do uh Chinese video. I
I'm going to talk you offline, okay,
Jack? So, thank you guys for coming and
see you next time.