Good morning. Good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Son talk
show. We going to code wam language. I'm
going to show you some wam language
functions that does um that does
combinotaurics
wam language functions doing
combinotaurics. Okay. So if you are
watching this offline play at 1.5 speed
because I ramble. If you are watching
live uh say hi in the comments
how how hi to so wam language let's um
wam language tutorial so you can go
there and check out the full tutorial
for programmers and you can also
download wam language for free and uh
okay so let's begin so I want to so
let's begin so here is wufam language.
Copy the file path. Here's today's talk
show. Uh paste the link there. Uh
linkify show in browser and go there.
And what we want to do is uh uh several
functions
on list that generates combinatorial
uh things such as permutation.
You know given a list of items you want
to find all possible arrangements. So
that's one of the problem. So let's go
to there. So list data structure data
structure association
excuse me. So let's go to list list
operations.
So list operations combinatorics. So I'm
going to show you. Okay you will see in
a moment.
So first of all paste the link here. uh
paste link file. So we can go there
directly.
So there are several functions this this
is amazing fantastic you know try to do
this in Python, JavaScript or Goland or
whatever your favorite language Rust,
Hascal or camel or F you know try them.
Usually they are not built in but Wuam
language has them built in. Okay. So let
me just show you a couple because there
are several you see uh what I want to do
is I want to add the groupings and
subsequence but let me show you. So
generate tpples all possible turbos
tpples. Okay. So uh wam language for
programmers. So combinatorics update
today's state here and turppos. Okay. Uh
go to pre. So here is tpos. So you want
you know given at least one two three
you want all possible two tuples. So
that's how you do it run it.
Okay. So here's the result. It's all
possible pairs of of these three uh
items.
You see uh what one two three you see.
So so uh so that's the output. So let's
try you can also try AB uh let's say A
and B symbolic and let's say all
possible three tuples it
you see you got a a ABA
abba aa ba bba
and bbb fantastic and beautiful okay
showing browser so that's
uh what if you want this variations. You
see one um let me show you. Okay. So uh
it's also about turppos but variation.
So what if you have two list you know
the first list is 1 2 3 the second list
is ab you want all possible pairings.
Again the result are tpples. So run it
you see 1 A 1 B 2 A 2 B uh you know so
that's that's another alternative u
argument form for tpples
okay show in browser
uh so language has the property given a
function function is usually named uh
based on the result so if you have a
tole tuples a function named tpples that
means the result are tpples. Okay. Then
so one of the base the most basic usage
is a tpos of a list of items you know
then you specify how many turppos
you know two two items or three items
per tuple three tuple then you can also
have a variation you given a list of
list. So basically this does what this
does is called cartesium product. So it
forms a tuple and uh the first part is
whatever possible elements in your first
list. The second part is whatever
elements in your second list and so on.
So if you give a total of three lists
then the results are three to you see.
So both are tpples but they are
different. So but they are all named
tpples because that's what they are. So
woven language has a property applies to
all functions. The function name
indicates the result. Okay. Like
different programming language they have
different uh mechanism different u
philosophy about how they name their
functions. For for example in PowerShell
uh okay so in PowerShell
they tend to name uh
for example child. Let me show you.
Okay. So close that uh start a new
PowerShell
and uh magnify.
Okay. And child
ch I ch uh chir.
What?
What's going on?
Oh, get
get child item. You see that's a name.
You see in PowerShell all all command
names are named like that something dash
something. So the first word is a verb.
The second word describe what the uh is
a noun describe what the verb do to.
Okay. So in PowerShell all
uh commands names are named like that.
So what I'm saying is that different
programming languages they have
different way kind of uh systematic way
to name their functions or commands. So
let's go to PowerShell.
So so you can see a complete list
PowerShell tutorial. Check it out.
That's my tutorial on.info.
Okay. So download install a list of
aliases. For example, here here is a
list of all aliases. And here you can
see kind of all the possible command
names where dash object for each object
add content get content set location set
location clear content clear host clear
history clear item clear item property
and clear variable and so on and you
know move item move PS drive move item
move item property move alias move uh
module and new you know so that's the
naming of a powershell now in wuam
language so the name the function name
typically describes what is the re
result okay so here is turbo that gives
all possible tpples now that's one thing
okay the naming of the let let's write
it down okay naming of programming
language uh names okay so I was working
on the loge bump uh artificial
constructed language. So copy that. So
what are we here? These combinations. So
talk show. So we talked about um
PowerShell and naming of functions
in different programming languages.
Okay, that's a interesting thing to dive
into. So you can look at Python, C, C++,
Java, whatever your uh favorite
language. Some of the language may not
have consistent names such as the Unix
[ __ ] you know, everything in Unix.
Well, you can say they are consistent
because nothing m makes sense. you know,
they prefer the briefs, you know, they
prefer uh, you know, CD
uh, CD LS cat,
you know, nonsensical, you know, uh,
juvenile.
That's what Unix is.
Uh, by the way, something interesting,
let me tell you guys. So a friend
visited me uh with Discord. We are you
know we met on discord and so Kim Posome
Kim Posen and Ka
okay posum and Mickey Mouse.
So
so yeah we were talking about so naming
of things uh naming of functions in
different programming languages. Uh and
what what was it I wanted to say. There
is some
well
I forgot what to say. I you know I
forgot what is the thing I wanted to
mention. Anyway so a friend visit me uh
and uh so uh yeah naming
let me think okay naming a function in
different programming languages. So you
got Oh. Oh, Unix. Okay. Yeah. So, here.
So, I wanted to show you uh you know, he
went to the computer museum, which is
kind of the famous tourist spot in
Silicon Valley here, Mountain View,
where Google is at. That's where I live.
Okay. Google. Google is like 30 minutes
walk.
So, and we have a computer museum. You
can look up you know uh computer museum
in Silicon Valley. So so they show this
Unix operating system and they call it
universal operating system.
What what a what a fast what what a fake
story you know Unix why is it named Unix
like unix?
That is because it's a pun by these
hacker types. You know, we hackers love
puns and uh [ __ ] and we don't mind, you
know, saying those swearing words. Uh
sucks, [ __ ] and whatever [ __ ] So,
Unix, the name Unix, it was a pun
against Motex, M U L T I CX, which is a
operating system popular at the time,
1970s, I think. So, they why do they
name it Unix? Because it's like Unix,
you know, the the guy without
penis being cut off. Unix kind of
offensive term, you know, offensive and
ugly and juvenile juvenile joke. That is
the root of Unix. The Unix type of
people, they love that. So why is it
named Unix? Because the Unix, you know,
against, you know, making fun of Motics,
Motics.
But now in the computer museum they say
a universal operating system.
I never heard of that phrase in my 30 40
years of of reading about Unix history.
I never heard of this phrase a universal
operating system. What the [ __ ]
So this is how history become twisted.
You know, like when you read back
history 100 years ago, World War II,
certain country or whatever, they they
become all twisted, you know. So, here
is an example about computer history,
computing history from the uh computer
museum.
Okay. So, that's what I want to mention.
So, we were talking about naming of
functions in programming languages.
Okay. So some of the programming
language they do follow a consistent
naming such as Wuang language such as
PowerShell I mean you may not like their
philosophy each one is different but
they at least they are consistent okay
bash consistent no Unix it's [ __ ] it's
fa [ __ ] [ __ ] or [ __ ] up [ __ ] that's
what Unix is which became Linux
So this is an example of my deep hatred
against Unix and C. Okay. So anyway,
let's go back to the combinatorics. So
we demonstrated turppo actually just two
cases. Then there's more uh cases. So
here here's another example of turppo.
Okay, let me let me show you. Okay, so
we illustrated. So go to um wuam
language componentics.
Uh actually let me write down the naming
of functions in different languages.
Okay,
different programming languages may
have let's say uh let's may have
different
philosophy
philosophy of naming of their
functions or commands.
Some
programming languages
has a consistent
philosophy.
For example,
PowerShell,
Wuam language and emacisp and this in
general. Okay. And uh uh what and Java.
Okay. I can I can say for sure Java is
also consistently named. Doesn't matter
you like it. So whether you like their
philosophy of of naming is one thing.
Okay. But however they are consistently
named. Okay. These are some examples.
But some programming languages
do not have consistent naming scheme.
For example, bash, Unix,
uh tools and uh
does it apply to C kind of. Okay. C and
C++
the circus [ __ ] Uh they anyway. Okay.
So anyway, let's make that. So that's
about that. Okay, that's one topic. Now
let's go back to TPO. So we were doing
demonstration of TPO. Let's show another
uh another example of TPO. Okay, so
actually I need to rewrite this part.
Okay, so here's original. Now we're
going to say re uh because I was, you
know, so what what I'm doing now is
improve the writing. So right now it
says
tupo given a list and given a list of
numbers return all possible array of
dimension n1 n2 something using elements
in list. Okay, that's the current
wording, but let me reward it because uh
it would be better. Okay. Uh return or
uh
higher dimensional array
of
array.
uh
return all let's just say this n by n2
by that array.
Okay, show in browser. So the new
version says return all n1 by n2 by act
array using elements in this one. So I
think this one is more clear. So this is
about technical writing
uh you know whether you you know so I
think this one is uh clear
okay but uh I have to think about it
actually but for now let's leave it so
so let's demonstrate this one okay
comments and questions 14 people I got a
c wow a lot people saying things okay
let me read it in a bit so here we have
so we want a 2x two array okay and there
elements is A or B. So we want all
possible 2x2 array with elements A or O
or B. Okay. Let's try that.
Okay. So you know so then then you need
to format it. Um but but but basically
what you get is this. Okay. So this so
each one so let's see. So you see each
one of these is a 2x two array. A a AA a
ba a a bb a a a ab a
ba you see? So if you say three let's
try it again. Okay. So let's um 2x3
array. Okay. Now that's going to be more
huge. It's going to be it the the length
of search is going to grow
exponentially. So you got all these.
Okay. Now what what if you want to
format it?
I don't have that feature in saw wam
mod. So let's let's start wam language
then you'll format it well.
Okay, new notebook and place a notebook
here and uh and uh let's say three shift
enter to start the kernel and uh let's
magnify magnify 150. Okay, then we want
to do tles to three.
Okay, paste it. Shift enter. So you see
it looks much better. So you see
automatic formatting see on the fly
and if you want uh and you can say
matrix form and you know you can
actually format it uh by
let's say matrix form.
So it kind of make it nicer.
Uh
wait
or you can you can also say wow this is
super long
let's say table form
okay table form just okay table form is
boring and you can say tree form too
oh this this is humongous tree This this
this this this
shows a tree but it's humongous
you see. So we got a giant list and and
sub list and sub list. Okay. So anyway
so anyway that that's demonstration of
turppos. Okay. So and and you can also
have more elements you know a b and c
let's say 1 by3
uh array. Okay, run it.
Okay, so you got that and uh let's see
1x3. So 1x3 is simply a vector. So each
one of these is a you know a vector.
Okay, so that's a demonstration. So you
see so so this form turppos you know uh
you want the first argument specifies a
list of elements you want to be as the
topos elements. The second argument
specify a dimension. So here is means 1
by3
uh and here is 2x two you know then it
generates all possible search
dimensional arrays. So in this sense
this array you know n byn n m n by m
array is actually a
uh generalized version of the sense
tupo. You see normally
uh okay I need to adjust my this should
be
you see normally a tupo means just a
flat list of n items. Two tppleo is a
list of two items. Three turppo is a
list of three items, right?
But here you what you have is basically
higher dimensional turppos. So turppo is
basically an array. You know is
basically one-dimensional array or in
other words a turbo is just a vector.
Okay. So a general sense of turbo is n
byn array or n by n by n you know by a
by b by c by the you know higher
dimensional array. So what I'm saying is
that wuam language first of all they the
naming convention is that the name of a
function means the return result. It's a
noun. It's usually always a noun. It's
just what it you know what the return
value is. So those are tpples that's one
thing naming convention. The other thing
is that wra language they for each thing
each function they extend all possible
uh things about. So you can have a you
can specify a tupo of given list of
elements or you can specify several list
of elements where you generate a tuple
by taking you know element from each uh
list. cartesium product or you can have
all possible higher dimensional turppo
which is array uh you know so so that's
about tpples okay
so let's uh let's let's um yeah let's
clean up let's return the code to what I
had okay so we don't want that okay so
okay syntax clear so we talked about
tbles Then there's subsets
again just like turppo. So but different
from turbo this is talking about subset
subsets. So uh should we show let's show
one example.
Okay. So subset one two three gives you
all possible subset. You know empty set
is a subset. One by itself is a subset.
Two by itself. Okay. Three by itself. Or
you have a subset of one and two or one
and three or two and three or the whole
thing 1 2 3. You see that's subset. Of
course you can change you know the value
to whatever.
Uh so those are subsets you see and here
in term when we are talking about
subsets the order doesn't matter. So you
have a item of 1 three I mean you have a
item of one two but you do not have a
item of 2 one because they are
considered the same you know we are
talking about sets which is different
from tuples okay so here is how you
generate all possible subsets okay so
now let's return uh let's return to
to to whatever I had okay then there's
any many variations you can specify
subset of two items only. So you want um
wait maximum okay so you can specify
specify maximum length of the subset. So
in this example you don't have one two
three or you can specify the subset such
that each subset must just have exactly
two items. So then all you get is one
two 1 3 2 3. Okay. And this is still
different from turppos because if you
generate all possible tpples you would
have one two and two one right but you
don't have that here. So anyway so these
kind of problems you know generate all
possible uh things they are called
combinotaurics
that's a branch of mathematics. Okay, in
other words, it's called it's a counting
problem.
You know, technically it's trivial
because because you can actually just
count them, you know, like a like a
child, you know, you you you write down
all possible uh zero items, so possible
one item compare, you know, but it gets,
you know, quickly becomes impossible
because it's too, you know, it'll take
you one million years to finish it. So
that is why you have the mathematics of
combin combinotaurics that's kind of you
know finding efficient ways to count
things sometimes without even actually
counting and listing them you know
that's that's a it's a broad uh field of
mathematics. Okay. So for example in
graph theory lots of problem in graph
theory in um uh combin combinatorics or
the lottery you know if you buy a
lottery what are the chances you're
going to win that's probability right
but in order to do probability for this
problem you need combinotaurics because
you need to know all possible
combinations of you know six numbers out
of 49 something.
So combinotaurics is a branch. Okay. So
let's put this back. So subsets. So we
covered tpples. We covered you know some
example of subsets. There's small
variations. Then permutations is
interesting because um let me show you.
Uh so let's just do it here in wam
language. Okay. Uh let's delete this
humongous output.
Okay. So let's just
select all uh Ctrl A delete all. Okay.
Now let's just do the permutations.
So permutation of three things. So you
got ABC ACB B A C BCA CAB CBA. Okay,
that's permutations. That's another
combinatorics.
uh then you got variations then you got
groupings and sequences okay that is
what I want to do myself because I'm
writing a tutorial I don't have coverage
of that so let's let's write them and de
demonstrate okay
uh
so here is now Emacs workflow okay so
delete that so let's copy that delete uh
wait delete delete delete okay so
groupings
uh how do I want them. Okay. So, what
you have to do is do that that that
that.
Okay. Then subsequence is a function
name that that that that gives you a
list
a definition list. Okay. So, you want to
turn that to code brackets and you also
want to turn that to code bracket
refresh. That gets you that. Then of
course the references you got to move
uh remove the list. Okay. Then cut cut
cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut
cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut.
So here is a reference for sequences
subsequences all possible subsequences
and here is reference for all possible
groupings. Okay now let's demonstrate
groupings. Okay, I uh so start a wolfam
language code and uh let's just pop it
out grouping.
Okay, so let's see one two three. So
given a list it'll show you all possible
um like if you're going to put
parenthesis for example if you're going
to put parenthesis inside the list
that's one one grouping so basically you
want all possible groupings okay so
let's undo undo undo undo okay redo run
it
uh code with argument 203 expected okay
So
okay so you want let's see the
documentation groupings
okay K uh taken K at a time yeah so this
is this is actually the lottery
the chances to to compute the what
what's your chances of winning a lottery
groupings gives a list of all possible
groupings one to n taken n at a time
okay so let's let's rewrite Try that.
What? Oh god. Windows key control key
off. So that's a issue about
uh sticky keys.
Okay. So uh groupings let's say three
two. So three items taking two at a
time. Don't it?
Okay. So this three item means one two
three. So a list of one two three then
two at a time. take uh grouping two at a
time, doesn't it?
Yeah. So that's identical. So that's so
this this three is just a short hand of
generating this this list. Okay. This
list.
So
so that that is that is a basic idea. So
we just covered that and that then you
can have combination of all possible
groupings of each of the least AB taken
K at a time. So I'm not sure um what is
that? Let's try it. Okay. So comment out
comment out remove that copy that
one two three and let's say A B C. Okay.
uh taken two at a time don't it
invalid arity specification
what is that oh the first argument they
they should be together okay they should
be one list okay
it
so we got okay so we got one two then
three then a b then c and 1 2 3 and a.
So how does this work?
Uh taking two numbers. Okay. So you want
to group two elements.
So that's what these two means. group
two elements and uh
and uh
so actually this this is just equals to
you know this is actually just equals to
combination of these two I think am I
Right.
I mean combining these two results. So I
think let's see one two and three. One
and two three there. Yeah. A B and C. AB
and C. Yeah. So this is just the short
hand of these two together.
Okay. Anyway, that's um Okay. That's
some basic about grouping. Show in
browser.
So I need to permutations. So I need to
groupings. I need I need to write a
description and read read the
documentation
uh more in detail. Uh it can get fairly
complicated. Okay. So next item
next item is subsequences. That's very
interesting. So let me show you. So
subsequence. So let's wam language
subsequence
subsets no subsequence that's right and
let's say just one two three okay
you see now it's about subsequences
you see so you given a list that's a
sequence then you want all possible
subsequences.
So empty sequence is a subsequence. Now
the sequence just just of one number one
is a subsequence. So is two so is three.
Then you got one two as a subsequence.
Then two three a subsequence then one
two three. However you don't have one
three. You see you don't have one three
there. You see? So this is different
from turos and also different from
subset we showed before. So that's an
example
uh syntax color show in browser. I think
that's it for today. So when I'm offline
I'm going to you know read in detail uh
you know see all the variations and
document it here. So today this is about
list operations. Now you can try to
write any of these in Python, Golang,
JavaScript, whatever your favorite
language usually
um like all of these like except one or
two most of them are not in other
languages. So you have to write them
yourself and it's not trivial. Okay,
this is this is simple problem you know
you can you can do it in like 10 minutes
to an hour. If you are professional
coder, you can write it in five minutes
or if you are new, you can write it in 1
hour. But however,
when it comes to efficiency, you run
into problems because you you need to
write your code to generate all these
possible combinations in a efficient
manner. You know, speed and uh memory
consumption.
If you take those into account, if you
want to really write a program that's
really efficient,
then it becomes like it'll take you
several days, you know, something, you
know, something like that. And and also
if you want to create a one single
function that does all these variations,
so it's not trivial. So it's not trivial
at all.
Okay. So let me read the comments. I
think that's it for today. Uh that's 48
minutes. Uh that's about 40 minutes.
5.9 gigabyte download Wam language.
Oh, okay. It's also asking for a
license.
Well, you go to, you know, you just
follow their instructions. Don't do any
tricky stuff, you know. Don't create a
new email for whatever, you know. Then
you can you'll have it. I don't know
what, you know, it's asking. Yeah.
uh you know you can you know you can do
it. I I I don't remember exactly what's
the procedure.
Uh actually have I ever installed the
free version? I don't think I have.
ACP says, "I went to the computer museum
once and I saw Nintendo Saga display on
display." Nintendo and Sega. That's
nice.
Yeah. Well, they Yeah, they are
warranted.
Uh computer computing became popular in
last 40 years or so. So, this Linux and
Unix is just beginning. Other countries
are realizing the power of these tech
technologies. It is only a matter of
time when other people develop something
far more superior something. Uh, okay.
Seriously though, am I missing
something? If I exclusively use evil
mod, I could go back to default bindings
if that's the case.
Uh, so I I don't remember what is the
context, but Evo mod for EMAC is pretty
good. Okay. But if you want to upgrade,
you want to be more efficient, then I
recommend softly keys. Okay, which uh
pranchu you know are you the pranchu
guy? Uh who wait palash palash backup.
Um so kanfly keys I don't know if you if
you watch my video you know you know so
let me show um so kafly keys I talked
about few days ago there's episode on
latest version and lots of demo and I
have like tens of videos about keys so
it's the most efficient key binding
system for Emacs
and more efficient than vim okay more
efficient than if you actually use Vim.
God mod is no good. Okay, I can
recommend you know these are old
stories. God mod has been around since
15 years ago and I of course I know it
well. God mod is no good. Okay, I do not
recommend it at all. So ACP says most of
my professional experience has been with
web apps and big data apps. So while wam
language very powerful I am ignorant
ignorant about its application in
business world.
Uh
wuam language is business world not
much. Okay. uh
I think there are some in financial
world and in business world but they are
well there's you know wam language is
mostly for scientific programming or if
you are a hobbyist you want one
programming language that does
everything everything possible which is
actually the lisp philosophy 30 years
ago you know lisp is of the philosophy
that one language to rule them all. So
you have like all possible functions. Uh
wam language is like just one mega level
up. So you can you can do anything
physics, physics, chemistry, mechanical
engineering, electronic engineering,
anything algorithms possible. If it's
possible to build in if it's a known
algorithm, it's already built in. Okay?
If it's a known concept such as machine
learning such as statistics such as
probability, combinatorics, uh list
processing, text processing, artificial
intelligence, neuronet networks,
modeling, modeling or physics, fluid
dynamics, you know, if it's possible
possibly done by computer, it is in Wuam
language building usually by just one
function. Okay. So you can in in in some
sense you can think of it as a the god's
calculator. Okay. You don't have to oh
uh I'm going to download Python you know
you need this library that you know or
mpm you know then then what does this
library do? Oh it's got a bug. So you
have to use that library. You need to
update the version you know like a mess.
So woof language one single single
package coherent to do it all
and it is mostly used by engineers
engineers scientist mathematicians
physicist
mostly okay but they today and computer
scientist okay for example Donald
uses wuam language long time and he also
uses emacs emacs and wuam language and
and and quite a few several you know
prominent and computer scientist.
Okay, that's it for today. Bye, guys.
Uh yeah. So, so if you like my stuff,
donate to me, okay? Go to.info.
Uh go to the bottom. If you have a job,
donate to me $100, okay? Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me, PayPal me.
That's it.
Copy that. We shut down in a minute.
Okay. So, let's just paste uh stuff
here.
Bye, guys.