test so I'm going to do a recording of
my eMac stuff my Emacs in typing I
planted two Emacs some mimics demo maybe
and my workflow my workflow from having
workflow my arm is hurting here like
right here here here typing stuff typing
too much you know I'm like sitting in
front of the computer like right here
like 10 hours a day 10 or 12 hours a day
for the past you know since 2009 I would
say so for the past 10 years and doesn't
matter how fancy my keyboards are you
know spreading all that economic and
stuff like he's in everything you know I
still got problems because I you know I
don't want to say this but because
really you you know if you count the
number of people okay if you rank the
number of people who sit in a computer
the most times you know average you know
average per day statistically you know
not not you know what do you think but
actually if you have some measure on
your seat summation on your eyes staring
at a computer and and the measure of the
time you your hand is on the keyboard I
would I would rank probably the top 1000
you know let's say 1000 in USA you know
it's it's really kind of extreme because
you know I don't I don't go out I don't
work I don't you know go out basically I
sit in front of computer all day all day
and night you know all day and night
look okay I'm gonna show you you know I
don't have a camera stand so this stupid
camera no it's gonna fall down so but I
want what I want to show you is this see
happy I've been doing this since I was a
team yeah since like
13 so I can go on forever you know it's
harder if you don't have if your hand is
up is is not on the table but so
this is actually a good exercise for
your fingers like when you do it when I
do this actually I feel comfortable but
anyway so my high side repetitive strain
injury that's getting me you know one
day you know these fingers are supposed
to you know I'm going to rule the world
with these fingers that was my that's
the mode of thinking since since 1999
you know I'm going to become I'm going
to dive into the computer and become
part of the network but apparently these
fingers you know the thought didn't work
out and these fingers my well it's
almost it's always with my left hand you
know like okay since 2006 I have RSI
problems because into that I never
thought I would get it you know
especially when you know when you are
younger like I'm pretty athletic or my
almost all my life but I actually
haven't been for the past ten years you
know I'm getting old but for most of my
life up to year 45 up to age 45
I was pretty in shape to the degree that
I'm competitive Atlit you know I would
put on roller skates and you know skate
down along with cars or hold on to cars
and stuff like that yeah but that was
the last time I did that is when I was
40 age 40 around 2002
no wait no that's what when I was 30
something close to 40 anyway so what I'm
gonna show you yeah I'm gonna show you
quickly actually I'm gonna demo okay I
have a guy asking me a friend okay Wow
online friend kind of I don't know him
but he's very nice
he asked me to so one not useful what
okay he's from Russia so he's English
you know sometimes it's not chromatic oh
and and stuff what like my never never
follow grandma
so one not use useful things about
Frankie's would be bad integration with
you aaww so many keys that are okay so
basically in Emacs you have a mod called
you let's see if I can started you okay
let's type a URL let's say oh my website
sorry info okay so this is how my
website looks looks via view you aaww
that's pronounced you I suppose you know
a lot of people don't like the name but
I actually like it because you know he
rhymes with www and it's you know www
you cannot pronounce and it's you know
mouthful and you eat wwu is good some
people don't like it because I suppose
it's like you know it it doesn't Connor
Tate you know it makes people think of Q
or something puke or you that's bad you
know like what do you call that
exclamation so anyway so so you is a
browser actually it's a web browser
entirely written in emacs lisp so it's
entirely written in Emacs wait why do I
have Mathematica here
visual projection Airy it's okay
so what Dad I don't want to go there
let's forget it you see I have okay one
of my workflow is I have Auto quick you
know in in different operating system
it's is sometimes called drill so
basically what happened is is that
whenever my mouse stops moving it clicks
it makes it it makes a quick so I never
have to click my mouse let's see let's
go back to let's get the let's try this
if you can see my hand and you can see
also see my screen see well yeah I don't
I don't click you see okay look at the
Emacs screen so I moved there a clicks
here clicks you see this is supremely
convenient actually very good okay let's
put him back I need to get a camera
stand someone sent me hey you hey you
say me one OK please I could suppose
it's a donation my alarm clock my Lanka
runs now every 30 minutes it means
every 30 minutes because it helps me to
get up you know as I should
okay I'm back that you know your way
needs code you lose your temperature
temperature right and from where from
your head that's that's the place where
you lose temperature the most you know I
used to be a swimmer I was in Kappa I
was a swimmer in college on the swimming
team for two years although I was the
worst swimmer but so anyway when you
swim like into our two hours in water
you put on caps that makes a huge
difference like huge so anyway some I'm
also doing this like now I have three
balls now you know it used to be just
two you can do it so that they don't
they don't hit each other this is a
great hand exercise or you can do it so
that they are they they always touch
each other you know you know at first
you might even you might find it hard to
do but actually you have to after while
it's easy and now my roommate get me I
want the stone one because these chimes
and that's not good of course it's not
good if you are working a company where
you know today's company its Open Office
which is extremely idiotic ah you know
and because well corporations they want
to save money that's that's what they
say so that that's why it is that way so
you don't even have cubicles
so that's so this is silent you know
this chime is is mostly you can buy it
in Chinatown and that's mostly for
foreigners you know like oh this is fun
or each I'm is sunscreen you know it's
it's really cheap like five dollars or
four dollars in UK you can get in San
Francisco and today you can get it lots
of
online on Amazon but anyway I want this
I this isn't made of I think it's a
marble but they also have it made in
courts and courts and other gemstones
Jade
well maybe not what they are Jade but it
that that's gonna be very super
expensive but there is marbles in other
kind of quotes
so actually I'm so much into it so it's
looking yeah I'm gonna show you my part
of the Kibo blog Emacs blog you see this
is so super fast Emacs blog ok section
he make this know ki Emacs keys Emacs
keys that's the most critical part of
Emacs because he Emacs everything
everything you do is a command even
moving cruises like when you press arrow
key when you press the right arrow that
actually calls forward cha and when you
type a character like some you know like
something and that's actually calling
the command let's say no no type you
know that's actually called the command
self insert command so when you type
something som e thi e it's actually
calling self self insert command self
insert command you know everything
you're doing in Emacs is to command
including a mouse click like you know
when you click it for example let's show
you click and it's running
what no oh there prints the command
mouse track region actually I didn't
track but it's anyway so everything you
do is a command and vast mode for most
used for commands such as typing or
whatever it has a key binding so let me
get rid of this ok so it has the key
binding
so basically max that command is the
most important thing constant concept in
Emacs and after that it's it's the keys
because everything you do in Emacs is
command and the command up buying bound
to keys for the for the most use useful
ones so keys in command is the critical
important thing in Emacs you want to
master it so I wanted to show you yeah
the pinky Emacs Fink USA find in key
Emacs pinky that's the was a critical
topic you know it has ruined many
programmers lives you know Emacs is the
software that in the whole history of
software Emacs is the one that has
created the most hand damage in people's
that you know a lot of people actually
email me in private you know and they
from around the world and like I have
people actually from Russia not just one
and and you know they tell me that some
of their stories are pretty bad like
they visit doctors multiple times and
they have pain you know I don't actually
have pain but I have like make sure it's
always my left hand I just like like
right now I have discomfort like if I do
this it's like a massage you feel
comfortable and right now I don't know
anyway I have all these written up you
know on my website is like horror essay
so I obtained some you know essays about
my history of RSI my anyway so let's
look at the the boss why he makes my
Emacs keys are painful let's see when
your exam acts pinky there it is so you
see here
yeah simple toys you can get to help you
to help you help you avoid you know cure
you know exercise your hand and and
these things are fascinating you can
there's lots of them on Amazon and I can
I have lots of photo collections here so
you see there are many varieties some of
them you know these spherical things are
just beautiful by itself so this is
artificial tiger eye this is that's not
is it really made of jade you know so
you can be sure or sometimes and crystal
you know crystals in terms of chemical
chemical facility like if you go to
Wikipedia on Crisco crystals this
tremendous amount of pages about that so
anyway when you buy these don't don't
get those I like like this okay this one
and you know you know pretty much like
these pretty ones they are just for
laymen you know they are for people who
don't know a thing about it you want to
get and typically you want to get heavy
heavy ones you know but this this one
the black this one this kind of smaller
so now I like I do three of them
so anyway that's that I'm going to show
you a typing test okay that's what I
want
what's going to do you know random stuff
you know I'm doing random chat because
hi hi hi guys because because I'm
thinking I'm doing that I'm going to do
more videos like you know maybe one
every other day or something you know
just chat random things that would be
fun and I hope you guys enjoy
Joey me joining me for emails hang out
so we can chat you know I'm not too much
a plan type of guy so you know I if you
plan to you know let's to get together
have a good party or something more
serious you know I freaked out and you
know with that you know typically also
with recording so like oh is gonna show
us something and I you know I don't what
you might say stage fright you know I I
don't I don't want to put it that way
but you know because well let's not get
into that
so Emacs human is I want to show you oh
yeah I want to show you the keys
keyboards so it's it's let's go some
typing typing tutorials so let's go to
so I'm gonna do this test and let's
let's be it's and that would that would
be it for this video I mean I know this
video is kind of without any point I
want to try this game
and I second let me close my door
okay let's try a new game I don't know
if you can hear it well if I don't
forget one it's just start typing parts
yeah
yes oops wait what happened if you press
into oh I wasted my bomb whoa what
or inside peek rush okay if you press
enter that's your smart bomb something
like that first sick you came quit why
I wish you can hear that sound look it
but I can't I cannot switch right now to
my because I'm using my headphone that's
my also my
this needs to I'm gonna be here so you
can see
AI n logo
what
test
wait the video is frozen
okay I'm gonna stop that stupid
I'm gonna use the smart bomb just spam
them off enter for EMP so and enter
I guess I don't have smart bomb anymore
why is this frozen
okay I'm good I was going to do more
tests type in tests like there's a
typeracer but yeah that's that's it okay
so I hope you guys are doing well and
have a good new year I'll see you first
you know in you know you know a couple
of days I'll do another video bye