Good evening. Welcome to another episode
of Sand Talk Show.
We are going to code uh
cascading style sheet.
Okay, so I'm going to write my tutorial.
I'm going to work on my tutorial on
cascading style sheet, CSS.
Okay, can you guys see it? Double check.
Uh video check, audio check. Uh I'm good
to go.
Okay, so CSS, this is my tutorial on
CSS. Uh
visual CSS.
And the CSS, so let's begin, okay? So,
let's see the uh show the talk show. So,
CSS, you know, uh cascading style sheet,
they got the length. So, they got a new
like they got new things
just about every year. And I learned a
few days ago that they created several
new length units.
Uh length means like how many pixels so
and so and such. So, that is very
interesting. So, I'm going to uh add it
the new ones to my uh
my page about length units of CSS.
So, the new ones are LH for line height,
cap for capital capital letters height,
IC for the Chinese character water. So,
that is the I guess the width and all
the height because they are the same, I
believe.
RCap for root capital height,
RIC for root IC root IC Chinese
character, and RLH LH is line height
line height. So, I'm going to add this
to my tutorial. So, it's just my working
session. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed minimum.
If you are watching live, say hi, okay?
So, I think nobody is here, so I'm just
going to work on my um
So, let's add So, LH is line height uh
and
So, cap So, this Okay, so let's uh
copy them.
Cut them. Go to the CSS link unit.
Update the
um
today's date. So, updated date. So,
let's see. Where do I want to want to
add it? Relative units. Let's see.
Uh
For now,
let's just uh test them first because
test them is so important. So, in fact,
let's add
um
Let's test them here, okay?
So, you got line heights uh
So, cap is So, let's First of all, let's
look at the reference.
Mo- Mozilla CSS reference.
Line height CSS, okay? So, uh
and I want to
test it. So, you going to create a CSS
LH, let's say
Okay, so what what do you want it to be?
Line height.
Uh
How do you uh test this?
So, let's suppose
I add
a div. No.
Wait, so it's So, basically it's line
height.
So, you can specify font size. Okay, so
let's see that.
Style
font size
and let's say font size
1 LH.
Okay.
And uh
so showing browser
So, that is the one. Now, let's make it
red.
Showing browser. Okay, that applied.
Now, let's increase the line height.
Line height
and say two.
Did it work? Uh
it looks like not. Okay, so hold on a
second. So, let's
uh
two and say three.
Font size No, it didn't work.
So, is line height not supported?
Uh let's see browser supports.
Examples,
results
browser compatibility
specification
Okay, you need to turn on JavaScript.
Okay, baseline widely available. Okay,
so what So, why is that? So, the line
height CSS property sets the height of a
line
box in horizontal writing mods.
Oh, wait. This is not
Like, that's a line height um
that is the line height um
that specify the height of the line.
That's not what we want. So, what we
want is CSS units.
l h, okay? So, that is actually what we
want.
Search for it.
There it is.
l h and r h s r l h CSS tricks. That's a
popular websites for CSS, one of the
most popular websites.
Now, let's go to uh CSS values and
units.
Okay.
So, open that.
Uh
So, this is a tutorial.
We don't We don't want that. We want the
actual reference.
Do we have people here?
No. Okay.
So, let's let's see. So, I'm I'm just
going to work on my tutorial then. CSS
values and units.
Uh what day is today? Today is Friday.
All right. Friday is the day where
everyone
went to have a party.
So, what So, what are we doing? So,
we need to check the reference, but why
is this not working? Font size
3 l h. Okay, that is definitely
should work, but it is not.
So,
So, lh, is that right? CSS lh CSS unit
lh
represents the computed line height
value of the element it is used on.
So, it is the element the line height of
the current element, okay? So, that is a
unit. But, if Oh, I spelled font size
wrong. Stupid.
Font size, okay? Show me browser.
Fantastic and beautiful. So, it now it's
working. Now, let's
Uh let's make it class, okay? Class um
Uh
xlh, okay? Let's just um
make it class xlh and go here.
And uh let's add a CSS
there.
Add a style.
Uh wait.
Style.
Okay?
Then, pop it out. Then, you want to say
xlh
class.
Okay? That matches
That's the selector. It matches the xlh
value of a class.
So, whenever you have the class value is
xlh, then you say then that's pretty
formatted. Now, the pink window shows
all my command calls and uh
and keystroke on the on the left,
command name on the right. So, now I
press a key,
formatted. So, that command is CSS
format of a I'm using Emacs, the most
powerful editor, okay? So, you can see 3
LH. Now, let's magnify.
Uh
Wait.
Magnify.
Let's magnify here.
Okay. So, you can see
Okay. So, put it back. You see there
showing browser. That's right. So, if
you search that, go here. So, that is
correct. So, that is line height of the
current element, okay?
So, that is working.
Um
And there's uh something I want to do
first, okay? So, you can see if if we go
to the CSS file, that LH is not
highlighted. Normally, it is. For
example, if I say font size, you see
that REM is highlighted. If If I say,
let's say, 20 pixel, you see that PX is
highlighted. Now, not LH because
I'm using CSS mode. So, I haven't added
those new units.
Uh so, let's go to
CSS mode. Go to the source code, my
personal Emacs
uh package. You can see all these are my
packages. So, you go here and search for
PX. So, these are length units, okay?
So, you can see
Now, we need to Let's make it one line
per unit. And let's add
So, we need to add a few new ones. Let's
add them here, okay? And uh
And uh these are new ones. Copy it.
Okay, so
I see. Okay, so now let's make them add
a quotation mark
for all of them.
And uh
And uh sort it. Wait.
Uh
Okay, sort it. Cap IC LH capital capital
letter height, I believe. I believe
that's what it is.
Uh now, you also need to look at
Uh let's see CSS value units.
What is this? CSS values and units.
Learning outcome, what the
You know, the Mozilla tutorial is not
very good.
Uh Mozilla is best for
as a reference. Okay, so length
data type. Okay, so here is all
length data type. That's right. So,
that's the page you want.
So, let's let's copy IC uh let's copy IC
and IH, okay?
So, we are working on multiple things at
one time.
Uh but
Okay, new buffer.
Uh but now go back to the CSS mode, save
it.
Go to the top.
Change the version date, version number,
save it.
Make a backup, go to the directory.
Press B for byte compile. Yes, there it
is, byte compile file and no error.
Fantastic. And press capital L to load
the new code, okay? So, Emacs know
um
know the this we just added. Now, go
back to the CSS file.
Now,
refresh CSS mode, CSS mode, reload it.
There it is. You see the LH is now
colored. Fantastic, okay?
So, LH and what's the other um
ICLH
cap, okay? Let's try.
LH uh
LH IC
cap, okay? You need a number in front.
Then it becomes colored.
Fantastic, okay? Now, there's also a R
version. R stand for root. So, that is
the
root element of the line
height and uh
IC stand for capital letter.
Wait, IC stand for the Chinese
character.
And okay, anyway, it's colored, so
that's fantastic, okay?
Delete.
Pretty cool, pretty file format.
Put it back.
Show in browser.
So, anyway,
so we added
the new units to my CSS mode
in Emacs.
And now, we need to write a tutorial,
but before we do that, we need to test
all these units first, okay? So,
um
So, for clarity, why don't we just say
test LH, okay? So, let's
um
Let's do that.
XLH is test LH, okay?
So, copy that. Paste, paste, paste.
So, uh LH, IC, and uh cap.
Okay, that's the Those are new ones.
So, why don't we
Uh wait, this is wrong.
Remove that. So, we got three test
cases, 1 2 3, okay? And uh we want to
um
So, each one of them got a class. Let's
change it to Let's change P to span,
okay?
Do you want to change them to span?
Uh
wait.
No, okay. So, anyway, so let's go
through here.
Cut.
Paste, paste, test LH, test IC,
and test cap. Let's see what they are.
And uh red,
blue,
and uh pink, okay?
Let's say
uh green.
Okay, and uh here LH 3 LH, okay. Uh
IC is a Chinese character
for water.
Height or width, okay. So, that would
going to be 3 IC
something. Okay, so and this is cap.
Okay.
Let's put this back.
Now, show in browser.
Okay, we got and we seems to got
uh these three.
So,
so line height, LH is line height, IC is
Chinese character.
Okay, let's let's let's go to it.
Let's let's type a Chinese character
here.
In Emacs, you can you can type Chinese
in Emacs. So, let me show you, okay.
Um
input method, set input method.
Okay, uh
wait.
Space in
one.
Uh
Pinyin.
Yeah, what?
Chinese
Pinyin. Okay, that's the Chinese Pinyin
method. So, do it.
Now,
type
the Chinese character for water, which
is S
U I, S U I.
No, S H U I, okay. S H U I. There it is,
the first choice there. Okay, that's the
Chinese character for water.
Now,
we want to
switch the input method back to the
normal English. So, what is the key? I
don't remember.
Uh yeah, that key. Okay, let's see.
Yeah, toggle input method. Now, we will
toggle it back. Okay? So, now showing
browser. So, we got the Chinese
character for water.
So,
uh but hold on a second. So, so we So,
let me show you
guys about the Chinese input in Emacs.
So, you just search for Xah Emacs blog
on xahlee.info
http no s.
And you just search
Chinese.
So, you can see HTML Chinese character
to reference link. Convert Chinese
Japanese character full width half width
punctuations. Emacs Chinese input.
Okay, so this is a tutorial page showing
you how to
type Chinese in Emacs. You You see,
Emacs supports Chinese input itself. It
doesn't rely on the operating systems
input method. So,
you know, Emacs supports like typing
Arabics or
uh
or Russian, you know, by itself. So,
that's interesting. So, let's copy the
link. Copy the link.
And let's go back to the talk show.
Uh CSS units. Let's go back to the talk
show.
And there it is. And let's just post the
link here. So, we talked about that
topic.
And demonstrated. Okay? Now, close that.
Uh wait, don't close that. Open that. Go
back here. Close that.
Uh go back here.
Now, this is I see
l h. That's Mozilla's
ex
Cut it. Okay, close, close, close.
And let's put that
back in here. Okay, this Mozillas
explanation.
It's just
you know, we we'll just reference it for
now.
I C L H and I C
I C L H and cap. Okay, so we are missing
a cap.
You see CSS adds a new one every uh
every year or so.
I mean new CSS features. CSS in fact
became so complex like today you can do
like 3D stuff.
Uh I I haven't
I don't quite understand how exactly
that works. Like you can almost use it
like use it like uh
um
3D modeling system.
Because I have seen the Star Wars
X-Wing fighter represented in CSS.
They say it's in CSS, but I haven't
checked.
Um
So anyway, so you got these new things
cap I C L H. Okay, now let's read
about exactly what they are. Cap
represents the cap height.
Normal nominal height.
Cap height, nominal height of capital
letters of the element's font.
Okay, so
how is that different from
you know, let's look at the font section
because font you have
several heights.
Severely angry. Hi Matthew. Why is that?
Are you talking about me or you? Hi,
hi Palash back up.
So
um
So we want to look at the font, okay? So
miscellaneous examples, let's see CSS
concepts. Uh layers, animation, layout,
line wrap. Font. Font is very
fundamental, so it's on top.
Uh so you want to know
font size. So there is various things
about font, okay? So you got cap
height
x-height
cap height.
Okay?
Yeah, very idiotic.
You see, font size is very idiotic
idiotic extreme. Let me just simply
explain, okay? So for example, in CSS
you specify a font, right? For example
Uh so so for example
So you go to uh
font, you know, font size you can
specify a font. Let's say 16 pixels or
whatever.
But
what does it what does the height mean
exactly? You see, it's basically it's
not
it depends on the font. So for example,
if you look at these two characters,
they have exactly the same font size.
Okay?
The blue box is the font size. They are
exactly the same for the for these two
fonts. However you can see the right one
is actually larger the letter. Why?
Because
because the font size is just an
arbitrary box, like a designer's box
around around whatever the characters.
So,
for one font, the box can be
can be huge, but
it's still font um
I mean,
given this design box, given a fixed
design box box,
the size of the actual letter relative
to the box is arbitrary.
Like they they is not even a unit.
There's no specification.
So, given a given a font size, let's see
let's say 16 pixels,
what the actual font looks can be very
small or can be large.
It's arbitrary. There's actually there's
no
concept to actually describe the
relation of a
the design box, the font size, which we
refer to as font size, or and the actual
letter.
So, you see so that's why it's very
complex.
So, now okay, now I understand. Okay, so
now
fantastic. Okay, so today
now we have the um
let's see.
Now we have the let's close this close
this.
So, now we have this cap. That tells you
the actual
um
height of the capital letter. That Okay,
that that that makes a lot of sense.
Okay, that makes a lot of sense.
So, now with the you new unit, the cap,
the cap unit,
which is a capital letter height,
that is actually the actual
size of a font. Okay, that's fantastic.
Fantastic, great to know. So, I can demo
that
so you guys can see.
Fantastic.
Okay, so now we understand the cap. So,
let's let's put the cap uh
first because um
because that's actually the most
kind of like critical unit, okay?
So, search for the cap. So, let's put
the cap here.
So, what we want to demonstrate now,
let's see. So, show in browser, okay?
So, this is um
So,
let's see how we demonstrate it.
Okay, so we want to say let's let's copy
several now, okay?
So,
uh and uh let's
um let's change that to span.
Okay, wait.
Uh
File no exist, what?
What am I doing? So, this is size HTML
resize resize image, okay? That's not
what we want.
So, we want
I forgot what's the key.
So, we want to change
change element change current tag tab
you see, okay?
So, close that.
Tab you see
change to span.
Uh not that one. So, do it here.
Tab you see span. It'll change the
element above the cursor, okay?
So, describe key, wait.
Describe key, what?
Describe key.
Tab you see.
So, you see the command is c h t m l
change current tag.
Okay, change the tag names of the
current tag.
The current tag is the closest closest
opening tag to the left of the cursor,
right?
So, anyway, so you got that.
Uh
so
Okay, so now let's d d d d d d d d.
Okay, we want um
So, that is the font style can make
something look legible, yeah.
Especially true in web pages, yeah.
You know, this this been annoying
bugging me for a long time. Actually, I
have an article on that.
Uh
This like this is incredible. Like given
a font size, you know, 16 pixels or
whatever you specify.
But, the actual font size
is like there's no way to specify. You
don't know how large it is it is.
So, this is incredible.
Um you know, it just like you have to
just
use a specific font and check yourself.
There's no other way. There's like
there's no even the concept of the
of the actual size versus
the font size. But, now we do.
So, the actual size is called cap. Okay,
so
so we got the cap unit. Cap Cap is kind
of the actual size of the
font.
Oh, that's so so this is fantastic. So
now you know, now instead of um for
example, now in CSS
you know, instead instead of saying font
size something uh we can say
uh
one uh we can say one cap.
Okay, and say root cap. That's the
capital letter height of the root
element.
And if you specify that, okay,
then
then you can change font family. You can
change to any font family and they will
stay the same. Like the layout will stay
the same.
Do you guys see what I'm saying?
You see, before
if you just change font family, let's
say from
Times New Roman, a serif font, to to
Arial, which is sans-serif serif. If you
change your font
font uh family,
then your layout will change. You know,
things will become smaller. Your layout
will shift.
That's like that's very bad because I
didn't change font size. What do you,
you know, why why is the font become
smaller or larger?
And it and this this is why. This is
why. But now
if you set the font size to be, let's
say, one
uh cap. In fact, I can we can say one
1.1 uh cap.
Let's refresh. I think I think most of
my page will work.
Then now you can change font font
family. It doesn't uh matter. Let's
demonstrate that, okay?
Let me demonstrate that.
So um
font family, let's say
Arial.
Okay, so I believe uh what is what is
the Arial?
Common web fonts, open that.
Okay, and right now it's up
because this
uh
a r i a l, okay, so why is it
refresh it's not working.
a r i a l
refresh
Now, this is not correct because
I specified Arial. Why is it not
working?
What?
What am I exactly info? Okay.
Okay, so Arial
Now, go back here, refresh. It should be
using Arial.
Uh but it is not. Why is that? I don't
understand.
Go back here, refresh. Okay, now it's
back to Arial, but I mean to the default
sans-serif, which is Arial.
But, now if I comment that out,
that should work.
And uh
And that's not happening. Why is that?
Let's go to the inspect.
Um
Inspect the elements.
And let's say font.
Times New Roman. Why is that Times New
Roman?
Let's say computed.
No CSS property found.
Uh rules.
What?
This P element, let's say computed font
family.
Oh, serif comes first.
Wow, I didn't know that.
So, if you omit
Wow, I didn't know this.
So, if you omit uh let me show you.
Okay, so
Like if you omit a generic font font
type, then it will
take precedence.
Wait, that cannot be.
Um
Let's see.
Refresh. That works. Okay.
Now,
refresh. That still works.
But,
if you omit that,
refresh.
Wow, I did not know that. If you omit
the sans-serif part,
then it comes to the front. What? What?
So, that's something I learned new.
So, did I
talk about this?
Wait, it should work.
Uh, then strange.
Refresh.
This is incorrect because it's using
serif font.
Now,
close that.
Okay, open it. Make a backup. Close it.
Now, show this page in Brave browser.
Okay, you see in Brave browser, it
works.
Now, show this in in Firefox. It does
not. You see, they are using
serif font.
But, in Brave browser, it's using
sans-serif.
The reason, but they are they are
viewing exactly the same page.
You see, both of them using the same CSS
file, which which just says Arial.
So, this means this is a bug in Firefox.
I discovered a bug in Firefox.
Well, let's write it down, okay? Let's
go to today's talk show.
Uh
Okay, seems like we discovered
Okay, let me let me clarify.
Seems like we discovered a bug in
Firefox.
If you have CSS
If you have have a CSS
font
family
value is a specific font.
But, with
out specifying
generic font family such as serif or
sans-serif
then
For example, okay?
For example
CSS
that
Uh wait, so you need to make it well, so
you need to make it
P
uh for paragraph
let's say
Okay.
So, if you have that
then
it
behaves like
color
syntax color.
Okay, so
looks like we discovered this Firefox
bug.
Interesting.
Now, we need to test that.
Okay, so
Okay.
Can we test test that? Yeah, we can just
create a new page. So,
new page
uh new page then
so
HTML template insert uh template.
Okay. Then
save it.
x x test.html.
Okay.
Show in browser. Okay, empty page.
Now, specify CSS. Okay.
style
and uh paragraph
something
something something. Okay. Now, let's
say paragraph
anything paragraph you want it to be um
that.
Uh wait, so let's just paste that, okay?
Okay, wait. Paragraph use Arial, okay?
Something something.
You see, that's serif font. That's not
Arial.
Now, I think
the reason might be because actually
in Firefox settings, I have
defaulted with this
um
font setting.
Default proportional serif.
Might be, okay. Let's show in browser.
That's Wait, that's
Oh, okay. So, that's No, it's not serif.
Okay, so what? Wait.
Did I up things here?
Refresh.
Yeah, I think I did. You see, now it's
You see, you cannot see it. So, let's
make it larger, okay?
Font size
uh
3 REM.
Show in browser. Okay, that's serif
font.
Which is not correct because we said
Arial, which is sans-serif.
Now, the reason it is not correct is
because
because I messed something up here.
Something.
Very annoying. Serif.
So, serif is default type. I think
probably.
Okay.
And another annoying thing is that there
is no reset. Like there is no
reset. Just reset the the font part.
Uh
Oh, wait. Default Times New Roman. Okay.
Anyway.
So, that's a kind of
Okay.
S
So, are you guys having fun?
Okay. So, this is my typical work.
Everyday I do this kind of research and
and test. Okay. So,
So, now what we you going to do with
this? Okay. So, now
let's uh
Let's say this body. Okay. So, let's
just say the entire body. Then we don't
need to say the font size.
And
okay. Wait.
Font size. Let's say 2 REM. Showing
browser. Okay.
So, anyway,
cut
delete the file
and uh let's paste
HTML code.
Paste it there.
Syntax correct. Showing browser. So, we
have fully documented this thing.
Okay. Now,
go to our CSS
page and now let's
um
Oh, we got so many things to do.
So,
for safety, let's add this back, okay?
Let's see. Uh cut that. Cut that.
Cut that.
Okay? Now, switch back here.
Refresh.
That's good.
Okay. So, now we wanted to demonstrate
the font size change issue.
I mean, we want to demonstrate the
cap height unit.
Um
where
normally,
if you change the font family, it will
change your layout. However,
if you set says font size to be
uh cap height, then it won't change your
layout.
Okay, let's try that. Okay, so
um
So, what we need to do is um
Okay, let's
Let's make sure I didn't
I didn't change my um
my CSS file. Okay, so you got
that.
Okay? So,
don't touch it.
Now,
by the way, thanks for point pointing
that quirk out.
I think there is a reset
uh
I think that there's a reset about
config in Firefox.
Reset font. Oh, really?
Well, we can try that. So,
about
config. Let's try that quickly. This
This
you know, over the past 30 years,
Firefox has become
very twisted, you know, like because of
the deep state.
Anyway, so uh show only modified
preference.
What?
Okay, let's see. Let's say font.
Uh show only modified. Font display use.
Font internat- interna-
in- internal use only. Changed to true.
Font internal use only. Why is that
change?
Font language dot group.
Minimum. Okay. Font minimum Chinese.
Font minimum.
Reader font size.
Now, why why is this font internal use
only changed?
So,
very confusing.
X Western. What like what exactly does
that mean? Font language dot group.
Uh
you know? Anyway, let's not
deal with it. Very complex.
Okay, what what what what we want to do
now?
Hold on a second. Let's regroup, okay?
So, we added the this is CSS
CSS mode.
Okay, here.
CSS mode. You made a change, yes. Let's
see.
So, we made a change, yes.
New unit value, okay? So, close that.
Uh
Close that.
And what is this page? CSS unit. We
still need to write this tutorial.
Uh but before we do, we want to
demonstrate that
thing, okay? So, let's do that.
So, talk show close. Uh so, this is a
talk show.
Let's demonstrate.
Okay.
Let's do it here. So, so you got the So,
save XX test.
Okay, showing browser like before.
Now,
now what do you want to test? So, you
wanted to
Okay, that and uh you want to um
What do you want to demonstrate is that
is that you change the font family
without changing font size,
but it will change your layout.
Okay?
Even though the font size is exactly the
same, okay? For for example, let's say
pixel, okay? Let's say 30 pixel, okay?
We're going to change the font family
from
from Arial to
Times New
Roman. So,
let's see what font we want to use.
Common web fonts, okay? So, these fonts
exist everywhere.
So, Courier New and mostly Mac and
Windows as well as Linux because on
Linux you have metric compatible ones,
okay?
So, anyway, so these are like common web
fonts. So, refresh, get them back to
sans-serif.
So, what do you want is on Windows you
have these um
Let's see.
Font family.
System UI.
In Windows you have
Let's say let's just use mono space,
okay?
Yeah, let's
Let me see.
You want to demonstrate
Okay, let's use Times New Roman.
Okay? So,
then
>> Okay, so that's So, this is for the
whole body.
Uh
But, well,
you know, if you want to demonstrate,
then you need to So, you want to
demonstrate
changing font family that will change
your layout because the font actually
changed size even if you didn't change
it in CSS. So, in order to demonstrate
that clearly,
what you need to do
is to have some like
some kind of boxes, okay?
Um
that
Okay, so div one,
div one, div two.
Okay, can you um
So, div
order
Okay.
Verify.
So, you kind of got that.
Oh, god. I shouldn't do this because
it's wasting time.
Uh span
style
Yeah, style.
Font family.
Arial.
Okay, so
that
then here times
Uh
what what's other font that's simpler?
Times New Roman is like
too long. The name is too
wordy.
So, common web fonts, Arial, Courier
New.
What's another one on Windows?
Yeah,
got it. Font is the most annoying thing.
Because each operating system they have
different set of fonts.
Um you know, you have one on Microsoft
Windows, but you may not have it on Mac
or Linux. And then if you want to be
universal, then you have to use download
like go to a third party Google deep
site and download their font.
Uh that's not good.
Font is the very most annoying thing.
So,
so we want a font family that exists on
Windows and that's the shortest. Well,
one way is you go to uh you know, there
is this fonts
uh
application like on Windows that shows
you
uh
font settings. Okay, so you got this
bunch
stupid fonts. I don't want to
I don't want to like go through this.
Yeah, let let's just go let's just say
Times New Roman, okay?
Eight. So, what is that doing?
So, actually, we can just measure this
way, okay? So, let me
show you.
Show in browser, and you can see
they go up, you know, measure it against
this Google chat box.
You see, this line goes there. So, first
of all, let's
remove that.
So, now it's
it's not even Arial, because we have to
deal with the Firefox bug, okay? So,
uh
Okay, so,
uh wait, so, you need
um
Another thing annoying is that
Okay, that's
that is
Arial. You can see font Arial.
Now, measure it. You see, this box goes
there, about the same
height.
Okay. Now, if we change this
to
commenting that out and come and put
this back without changing font size.
Now, refresh. Now, look at this line.
Let's see where it go, okay?
Refresh.
It did not change.
It did not change because
Okay, well, that's because the line
height
you know, the line height um
Yeah.
It's more complicated to demo that.
Yeah, but um
Copy that. But uh let me show you, okay?
But
Let's linkify it, okay?
You can see it if I just change my um
font for my website. So, for example,
uh let's go to some page.
Uh let's go to let's say HTML, okay?
So, now if I change the font family
to be serif,
okay? Now, you
So, let's do a screenshot, okay?
So, alt
So, now we have a screenshot.
Okay.
Now,
close that.
And now,
let's change this to serif, okay? And
now, refresh. Refresh, okay? Now, do
another screenshot.
Okay. Now, open these two screenshots.
Can you see? Are they the You see?
You see they change size. You see?
First one.
Second one.
Can you see the
uh
First one. Second one. First one. Second
one. You see the table of contents box
moved up because these lines shrink.
Can you see? Before.
After.
Before. After.
So, even we didn't change
font size, we simply change the font
family, but your layout
got changed.
Now, you see especially Yeah, look at
the table of contents line. You see?
They become now two lines. So, that is
the problem. And also in general, this
serif font is just smaller. Okay.
So, this problem occur. But now, if we
change this, okay, let's let's
Okay, let's um
Let's Okay, so this
So, now if we say
app
then the effect doesn't happen. Okay, so
why is serif? So, let's try again. Okay.
So, now let's try serif. Okay. Showing
Wait.
Uh 1.1 cap. Okay, so you need to make it
larger. 1.5 cap.
Showing browser. Okay, let's say that.
Uh
So, what's the relation between the cap
capital
cap height versus the font size
for
for a specific font? We don't know. That
depends on the font. So, that's why So,
I mean, my question is what value should
I use to be equivalent to my previous
1.5 REM?
That depends on which font you are
using. So, very complex. But, anyway, so
let's leave this 1.5 cap. Okay, let's
say 1.4 cap, something similar.
Actually, we can find out by actually
compare our screenshot.
Uh did we
Oh, we shrink the window now. So,
that way
Uh this needs to be 100%.
Uh
So, you need to show this as 100%.
Yeah, okay. So, now
Interesting. So, now, let's say cap
height five, six.
Refresh.
Well, before it's much larger. So,
two cap.
Refresh.
Okay, now it's too large.
Let's say just 1.5, okay?
1.
5.
Thanks for pointing that quirk out. Uh
what quirk? The font size thing?
Slawo
Ming Grabos,
do you like this UHK60 keyboard? How
would you compare to Glove?
Yes, I like it very much.
Uh
compared to Glove 80, I like them both.
Okay, um
I cannot tell you which one is better
because that doesn't make sense.
You know, I can just tell you I like
them
both very much
and they are different. So,
you know, you if you know, your question
uh let me digress and that's it for
today. So, we explored
you know, we explored the new um
CSS
units and uh
um
you know, you guys can figure out
the rest, you know, we uh you know, I'm
just doing my work updating the page.
So, let me talk about the keyboards,
okay? So,
keyboards, ergonomic keyboards, so there
is Glove 80.
Fantastic.
And uh there is my the one I'm currently
using,
the Ultimate Hacking 80, okay? They are
just very different.
S- uh obviously, for example, the Glove
80 is curved.
Okay.
So, for you, your question about which
one you want to buy,
that's probably the question you want to
ask. That really depends on you.
Do you like have you used this
bowl-shaped
keyboard before?
And do you prefer it over the flat?
It's up to you. Also, the Glove 80 is
also linear, So, you see the keys are
all straight like forming a grid.
Okay? But meanwhile, the Glove 8
meanwhile, the Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard, then let's go there.
Meanwhile, the
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80 UHK80, the
the keys are slanted slanted like the
traditional.
So,
So, you know, so it's like up to you.
So, but I can just say both of them are
great. You know, like like I would
theoretically, I would prefer the
ortholinear, but that's a minor issue
because I'm totally fine with the Glove
80.
The most important thing
in general for keyboards is the key
switch, okay? I believe you want to go
as light
a key switch as possible.
Uh
So, the Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard 80, I have
something
called pink switch at 35 g of force.
I believe it's 35, yes.
On the Glove 80, I have even something
lighter like
uh was it 20 or 25? Anyway, I like them
both, okay? So, it depends on you.
If you know, if one of them is not so
good or if like there's a major
difference, I definitely prefer one or
the other. I'll tell you.
Okay, that's it for today. We kind of
like went all over that, you know, not
making sense.
So,
uh did we actually we made a mistake?
Let's
uh
undo. Okay, that's it for today. Bye,
guys.
So, we let's just put it back. Uh
Save.
Diff, no diff.
Thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, so, you know, check it out. Pull
the video T and all that. Good weight it
comes with a uh
very nice
carrying case.
Um so, you know, so, like you know, you
have to check yourself. Like that Like
in general, what do you What do you
prefer? Kind of things like that.
Okay, so
we shutting down in a minute.
Any more questions?
So, this uh
this is not very good today because we
went all over
many things and and discover this
weirdness. I mean, even
this Firefox
bug, even if you set your um preference,
uh it it shouldn't behave this way
because, you know, you specified Arial
and there is Arial font on my system.
It should just use Arial.
But, instead, it behaves like that.
Like Like why the it adds serif in
front of it? Like this is just wrong.
So, I believe this is Firefox bug
we discovered today. Very interesting.
So, that's very actually
very fruitful, you know, we discovered
this.
Only I can discover these kind of
things.
Because for most people,
you know, they they go read Mozilla or
or whatever. They, you know, the AI just
tell you what it is. And so, in 5
minutes, they went on with They went on
with their lives
in a job or whatever.
You know, oh, you got new units. LH, oh,
that means that. Oh, caps, you know, you
just read this here
and you are done in 10 minutes.
But me me, I got to dive into,
you know, then then you got then then
you discover this this weird um
you know, Firefox bug.
Bye.