good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of axe our talk show today is
2019 January 8th Wednesday 3 o clock in
the afternoon San Francisco time and
according to schedule the topic schedule
we are supposed to talk about goal and
today but I'm not sure what topic to
talk about Golan you see this is Mike's
a talk show homepage so today is
Wednesday and Wednesday we have it
marked down ass :
so um but I'm not sure so let's go to
topic brain ok let's go to talk show
page and let's go to topic brain where
this page is my random notes about
possible topics and let's let's search
for Golan and so let's call the command
beasts matching lines : and you can see
we have actually several topics about
Golan in fact we have ok actually we do
have some topics about Golan so let's go
there it's such for Golan so I think we
are going to do some goal and live
coding for a while then we are going to
talk about random stuff so Golan so here
are some topics about Golan go fix print
lines use Okazaki to find replace new
face go okay so that is one topic about
Golan let's do it then
Golan lots of topics and finally face
let's modify this a little bit finally
place
script
okay so refresh you can see : fix print
lines so find/replace script so this is
my goal and script it's on my website
and this is the URL you can it's under
sorry dot info you can find it and use
it so this script is for doing Find and
Replace for thousands of files single
directory and perhaps we should show a
demo of it in fact I did a demo of these
several times in my video but let's do
it again
okay let's before we do anything it's
check I'm alive yes
status Houston I'm alive and I have five
people watching
okay let's do : and after : I do have
some topics let's go let me show you
okay after : I do have some topics that
I want to tell you about which is about
arts arts and Emacs workflow okay but
let's do : first so let me show you what
is this :
script is about this is about find and
replace okay let me think of a actual be
award task that I need to do for find
and replace okay I have some idea so I'm
going to do a demo of : right now and
and let me show you what let's write
down what we are doing
okay so livestream goal and demo
and live coding and modify the
find/replace script so that it prints
the so that it prints there is something
I need to fix but let me remember what
is it
Soho now second copy the URL computer
URL back to Emacs paste it here in link
of I so that we have the URL for you
guys to look at and go back to the page
so go and find and replace find string
so we are going to demo of that and so
we need to modify it so that it prints
piece of files in separate lines okay
that is what we are doing that that is
what we are going to do so let me show
you so here it is today's first topic
and so first of all I'm going to show
you what this command do I am going to
do a real life demo so in order to do
that let me go to my JavaScript website
so yesterday we did talk show about
JavaScript where I modify my JavaScript
tutorial navigation boxes so that they
become one coherent tutorial box like
you are seeing right now so for example
you can go to eat or bone so this
section is about JavaScript eatable you
click on that you go to the JavaScript
interface page and you scroll down and
you can see the entire table of contents
there again
and you can see the green is highlighted
is the current page so we did that
yesterday but we are here today because
I want to find something I need to do do
a global find in replace for hundreds or
thousands of pages so let me look for
what I want to do you know there is some
thing I want to change here so
JavaScript basically about string
function object property object in and
inheritance okay there is something
constructor in crass
okay let's say rejects okay you see that
you see that what rejects let's change
it to regular expression yeah let's
change it to regular expression so so
the table of contents page is right here
that's what you are looking at so this
highlighted text correspond to this
navigation box so let me magnify so and
it's such for our ege okay here rejects
so that part correspond to to this part
okay and we are going to change that
copy that copy that here we are going to
okay let's so let's start the goal and
script so open a new window open a new
window we want a new window okay so new
window let's say bookmark let me show
you here so let's set background color
set background color to hunt to see
shell c shell
okay and let's use let's go to a
bookmark
open file fast then let's type replace
so you see we have a replace go so this
is my goal and script for Find and
Replace and we are going to use it so
first of all what directory we want to
work on the directory will be this
javascript directory so I go to here
copy the file path go back to the goal
and select that paste and remove the
file name so this is the directory we
want to work on and we want to work on
air or HTML files and we want right to
file true do back up true backup suffix
Chioda Chioda okay that's all good and
what what is fine end replacement we
want to do so that part is over here
this this is where you enter the find
and replace stream so the find string
will be that okay go back here so the
fine string will be that okay and that
we replace string will be let me show
you the replace string will be very
clear expression okay so here is the
replace string now if I press a key to
run this script then it will go to work
and it will change or the regular
expression to the word there so hi mr.
Yemen Yemen what are you talking about
speak English not ghost language
so okay so now let's run the script
let's change background color color
again okay gray okay set background
color gray something
gray nigh yeah that's no good
say bang background color gray 99 yeah
okay so I'm going to run the script now
let's see your expression it's just
right okay Kassadin current file and
whoops what the
syntax error unexpected expression
expecting coma this is really unexpected
did I oh okay so I made a mistake
you see I've deleted this back tic you
see the back tic is for quoting it's for
quoting string let me show you so wait
let's go through goal and page my goal
and tutorial showing browser and if you
have not earned : this is a great
tutorial to get you started so you go to
: tutorial then you go to stream then
you can see the normal syntax for stream
is double quote and then you in goal and
you have also a draw string literal and
that is done by using the back tick
quote so now let's go back to our code
you see so therefore we have the back
tick there and over here so now let's
run it again good fantastic is walking
you see we have quite a few files
hundreds about about 500 files that's
Kanha okay it's done now go back here so
you can see here are all the files that
has changed that's correct or in the
JavaScript directory now if we go to the
JavaScript file my JavaScript tutorial
if you refresh you will see this change
in let's refresh do it there it is
regular expression fantastic so that is
a demo of this : : find and replace
script so : in general is about six
times faster than any of down
Ruby JavaScript so and it's pretty
simple so I highly recommended it's
about the same speed or C or C++ : okay
so now we have done this we have
demonstrated is find and replace script
what's the next thing okay you see here
you see it says find and replace pairs
now this is the output output of that
script now let's look at the output so
the output the first line is declaration
of encoding okay and so you see this is
kind of a Emacs convention this is how
you declare the encoding of a file and
this convention is also adopted by
Python and Ruby let me show you so copy
the goal and tutorial let's go back to
let's close the JavaScript let's post
what we're doing here
so you can see this is today's topic and
now I'm going to show you and we are
talking about so this is the : hot foot
okay
and the first line is the declaration
for the encoding and this line also
includes a declaration of mod like what
made your mod to use when you see this
file this is convenient because you know
so when if Emacs opened this file and
Emacs is this line then Emacs will use
the utf-8 encoding to open this file to
decode the file and Emacs will start the
sapphire output major mod right now the
mod is is is is not what is the current
mod shell mod share output mod I think
yeah so for example if I save this file
xx today's date a random name okay save
it close it reopen it you can see you
can see how file names are highlighted
now what is causing that that is because
we are in some find out Foodmart saw
find output mod and you can see the man
named in a mini buffer I mean in the
mark line there and besides highlighting
it also allows you to jump to the file
for example I can press Enter
oh never mind that so anyway so this is
the output of the : script but meanwhile
good morning sunset sensor so this is
the output of the go line script
find/replace script and we are talking
about the first line of declaration so I
mean let me tell you something about
that okay so sorry python tutorial okay
that way it's go super sorry unicode
okay so click on the first result and we
have sorry unicode then you scroll down
all the way then you go to unicode for
programmers and here is the index of all
the articles i have related to unicode
for programmers because they talk about
technical technical details such as how
to process unicode what does utf-8 me
what does encoding me you know what does
all this unicode mean in in technical
detail what's a code point and also how
do how do you declare in coding in HTML
in Python or in Java or how do you
process unicode string in Java in Python
Ruby it's over here okay so now let's go
to python unicode tutorial in its open
it in a new tab and it's opened Ruby
Unicode tutorial open it in a new tab
then let's go to pearl Unicode tutorial
you open a new tab so basically I have
and also there is a Java Script Unicode
in Java you know I don't care about Java
so let's see Java scripts you know I
have tutorials about how to deal about
all Unicode related issues in Python in
Ruby in Perl in Java in Java Script in
Mathematica in
this but what I'm doing here is to show
you the Unicode declaration thing this
convention this convention is from Emacs
but it is also adopted by Python by Ruby
as you can see and by Perl I'm not sure
peruse peruse this convention but it
doesn't hurt if you add it so anyway so
why why do I have so many articles about
Unicode let me tell you this okay good
morning Carson so when you so what what
are the issues of unicode second what
are the technical issues you have to
know when you working a programming
language related to unicode let me tell
you okay first of all programming you
have a source code that source code any
file needs a file encoding so that is
one first issue what is a source code
what is the encoding of the source code
so we are digressing but that is good
because I'm going to tell you something
about unicode so we are in a recursive
digression so let me write down what we
are talking about so we so it's easy to
understand so first of all let me tell
you Unicode declaration file encoding
declaration
convention okay that's one thing we are
talking about the other thing is what
are the issues of unicode in a
programming language okay
what are the issues the issues are let
me tell you the encoding of the source
code now any programming language you
have a source code once you have a
source code which is a file if it's a
file it needs encoding and decoding that
is fundamental good morning
Volken good morning to you Kay so file
so so so the issues of unicode in
programming languages so that's so I'm
telling you so the one thing you need to
know is about the encoding of source
code for example what encoding is
allowed or required for programming
language X ok that's one example and how
do you declare such encoding if the
language allows allows various encoding
allows
more allows a choice of encoding then
how do you declare such encoding so
that's an example of the things we are
issue so encoding of source code that's
the thing and and what and and does it
allowed any encoding or it just allow
why encoding for example in many
languages such as Java Java allows only
one encoding that is utf-16 only that
you cannot you cannot have the firing
code editing any other encoding
JavaScript for example there is no such
requirement but however JavaScript is
actually pretty complex the encoding
depends on you know the web technology
on on server headers things like that
anyway Ruby for example allows different
encodings you can have Ruby source code
in utf-8 utf-16 and utf-32 or in your
chinese gb 16 something
encoding so Ruby allows multitudes of
encoding Python 3 for example allows
only one utf-8 encoding for the source
code nothing else ok so that's some
examples about fire encoding issues in a
programming language now for some
languages such as Ruby and JavaScript
that allows multitudes you know
different choices encoding then you have
a question about how do you declare the
encoding for example Perl also allows
many different encodings for the for the
source code so then you have the
question how do you declare it okay so
that's one example of the question about
you know coding or programming language
so I have tutorial for example
so this this this page tells you about
all the issues related to Unicode in
Python okay so let me paste it so if you
like to read it you can and actually let
me also copy this page so so so for
sorry marketing purposes makes my
website more popular so you guys can go
read it so we have Unicode Ruby Unicode
then we have Perl okay so once we
started to talk about Unicode there are
1,000 things to talk about so we
digressed okay so file source code
encoding is one of the issue related to
Unicode with a programming language
that's just one thing the second thing
let me tell you the second thing is
string string you know string is one of
the most fundamental data types in any
language in Perl Python Java will be
almost any basically all languages
string you have to deal with strings and
string when it comes through stream you
know that's the heart of Unicode you
know because you are dealing with
characters so so the question is
basically the general question is how
how does your language deal with unicode
you know emoji or math symbols or
Chinese characters in the stream how do
you how do you deal with it how do you
can you first of all for example can you
actually have an emoji in your stream
that's one question can you or can you
not you know so processing strings
unicode strings that is the question how
does your language process unicode
strings and this this subject is
actually fairly complex this subject is
actually more complex then then fire
code encoding because when comes through
strings in characters you know different
languages they have different approach
they have different meaning of the word
string for example in JavaScript string
is sequence of 16 bytes very strange
okay you know I can explain that if you
want me to explain that I can explain
that so you know the general question is
how does your language deal with strings
and different languages have very very
very different approaches in JavaScript
for example a string is a sequence of 16
bytes I mean 16 bit bytes it's it will
take half an hour to explain that okay
that's JavaScript in Python 3 a stream
is a sequence of unicode characters okay
unicode characters now what does
character mean exactly that takes
another half an hour to explain so in
Python 3 a stream is a sequence of
unicode characters in Python 2 a stream
is a sequence of bytes ok that's very
different okay in : a stream is again a
sequence of bytes but however : then
then : have bite sizes then then they
have then they have run sizes it's all
related to Unicode stream ok so so my
point here so an eMac piece for example
eMac this string is just a sequence of
unicode characters ok it's similar to
Python 3 in in JavaScript I mean in Java
for example Java a stream is again a
sequence of 16 bit 16 bits bytes very
strange so we talked about so these are
the things about so the general question
is how does programming language X deal
with strings for example and for example
example in general different languages
have completely totally different
approach on how what stream is on how to
deal with streams
okay for example for example what is a
stream okay in JavaScript and Java
string is a sequence of 16 bits values
okay in Python 3 and email is a stream
is a sequence of Unicode characters okay
and by the way what is a character
that's a interesting question you know
as human animals we know what he is a
character but you see the point about
programming languages is that you have
to defy it specifically very precisely
what exactly mean you mean what is a
character like you know this is the guy
is it a graph is it font is it what is
it so different for me languages they
have very specific specific meaning of a
character for example in : a character
is just a Unicode code point you know
it's gets complex so essentially in : a
character is just a number basically a
integer so and so in goal and a stream
in : : and Python to a stream is
a sequence of eight bits bytes okay so
that's some of the interesting issues we
are talking about again that the overall
what we are talking about overall is the
is the issues related to Unicode in a
programming language so we I'm listing
some of the issues all of the issues
actually I'm going to list all the
issues so we started to have people here
good morning Bart why such a calm voice
well my this this is melodious Ness
South Hawkshaw melodious Ness addition
for a change
good morning Kathy sweet Kathy and named
Sue
so can you name variable in Chinese
using Unicode yes that's the next issue
I'm going to talk about a fascinating
topic about all the issues of Unicode so
we talked about one file so source code
encoding that's one issue the the second
one we talked about stream the question
of stream what is it you know can you
can you have emoji in a stream can you
okay you know what does what does a
stream me let me show you an example a
good morning court cook Patrick and
thank you and Ronnie Mattie and good
morning sushi so I'm going to explain 16
bits okay in a moment remind me if I
didn't so I want to thank you court for
donations okay big donations so code
code has been donating me via patreon
patreon for for half a year or so
hormone so thank you code so okay so we
are talking about Unicode issues in your
programming language what are the issues
source coding coding
and how'd you know and how do you
declare things like that then stream
what does it mean
he's a string very complex let me show
you an example for example it's you know
this is a common example JavaScript ok
let's begin JavaScript let's say let's
it's ok magnify console.log a string T
ok length okay and equals to 1 when it
is is true you see the character a
string with a one single character is
length 1 now let's say T t1 it it's then
it's two okay so actually let's remove
that Bernette so it says 2 obviously but
let me show you this ok let me show you
let's try this ok hot you see we have a
heart here guys hot so the result is one
less expected but let's try something
yes lock it
ok so we don't have pockets so let's try
emoji oh my god oh my oh my god this
character you see this unicode character
oh my god it's magnified for the
dramatic effect so this character if you
in Emacs you call describe character you
can see so this character is that one
called point one two eight five one four
and the character name is faced with
tears of joy okay so that's that
character now we're gonna render run it
okay run it
to Jesus
so it says in JavaScript he says this
character has the length of two now do
you see do you see the weirdness the
strangeness of it so why does that
what's going on is it a bug no
technically it's not a bug with respect
to human we it is a bug but according to
technicality if you go by nerds
you know the bunch of nerds Linux no
it's JavaScript hippies you know they
tell you what to do they tell you to you
should use this idiom you should follow
this convention if you don't follow they
really they flame you those people you
if you ask them they all say oh this is
natural because technicality like the
Linux thing you know whenever you send
something doesn't work in Linux the
Linux phonetics will tell you oh that's
because the kernel because you are
missing a screw in the kernel you just
need to put that screw on me it's all
good so that's technicality of the notes
so in this case by technicality this is
actually correct why is it correct
because no it's not about type
commercial convention conversion it's
because that because Javas javascript
stream by definition the stream the
meaning of stranger script is that it is
a sequence of sixteen bits bytes okay
wait a sequence of sixteen bits okay
Oh put it put it in another way it's a
sequence of two bytes okay anyway
sixteen bits that's one unit another
sixteen bits
that's another unit that that's what it
means that's a technicality that's a
technical definition of stream in
JavaScript now to explain that okay so
hold on a second here that
and show in browser here so so if you
actually want to understand that in
detail I can show you you just go to
Saudi JavaScript stream and similarly
you can search for Saudi JavaScript
stream Saudi Python string sorry Ruby
you know you might find some articles so
JavaScript stream and to explain this in
detail actually will take you know 20
minutes something so for example in here
character code unit code point okay so
on this page I explain what's going on
you know what what does what does
JavaScript script stream means actually
let me show you maybe there is another
article
let's just go to stream okay string
overview yeah you you'll find okay so
actually let me turn JavaScript so you
go to Saudi JavaScript in-depth
JavaScript tutorial then you first page
about string is string overview
JavaScript in-depth okay you guys you
guys buy it okay sorry bye JavaScript
tutorial in depth your learn your learn
after you read this tutorial you will be
your JavaScript expert better than
better than all the hackers who tells
you what to do in JavaScript because the
information is often wrong so anyway
JavaScript tutorial then you go to
stream then you have string overview so
I on this page and tell you what is a
string in JavaScript you know stream
string is first of all a primitive type
primitive value and string is immutable
in JavaScript and string is 16 bits unit
sequence okay that's the technical
meaning
and then I talk about stream escape
sequence and Unicode escape sequence so
when you deal with strings in Unicode
you're actually things can get quite
complicated it takes some effort to
really understand them well you know
normally if you are a programmer you
don't know that you don't you don't know
that deep you know because string is
just a bunch of character sets that's
all you that's most people all you need
to know well for me too for the first 10
15 years of programming you know I code
a lot of text processing but I'd never
understood in fact it's almost like I
don't need to you know you don't need
you understand the details until you run
into some bugs such as you know such as
that you know the length of a cat head
is too thank you you go what the
then you started to read and you know
then ASCII characters in Unicode
characters the code points and sequences
and bytes and you know the name starts
then you start to learn all the details
and once you know details it does
clarify you know the whole thing for
example Python 2 versus Python 3 as you
know it's a big drama
you know Python people they want to
switch to Python 3 but actually a lot
people are not switching because these
are that you know and first of all and
why do Python wants to switch to Python
3 why is patently created in the first
place why oh why why do you why does the
Godot create such a complexity why
because strings stream exactly stream
because the Unicode they need to they
need to change they want to make the
language cleaner in dealing with Unicode
strings they and this this is the number
one the core reason Python 2 becomes
Python 3 because they need to fix they
need to make the string deal with
Unicode properly
and to this and you know so to these
days some people do not agree it's a
good change they say that if they
actually there are some expert Python
programmers who believe that Python 2 is
actually better you know all things
considered when dealing with Unicode in
Python 3 so anyway so that's an example
of how complicated these strings in
Unicode can become so anyway so in this
article JavaScript string overview so
you look at you know string is a 16-bit
Unicode sequence then you click on that
for detail then you can see an example
we just showed before and I explained
them you know in detail here you can
read so let me just pull post let me
post the link here so if you want to
know the detail of that and go back copy
and paste okay
and showing browser so we digressed a
lot and oh is good good digression good
digressions so we talked about actually
a lot about unicorn so back one level
let's summarize so we were talking about
the issues of Unicode in a programming
language what are the issues source code
encoding that's one issue how do you you
know how do you deal with unicode
strings what what does the stream mean
that's a second issue in the most
complex issue
now the third issue that's then the
third issue is for example can you have
can you have unicode in your in a
variable name or function name let's
show an example can you so the quest
can you have Unicode in a function name
why do you need that you want that
because let me show you okay so let me
talk so let me show you an example let's
say JavaScript okay
and it's JavaScript again we can
actually we can use Python or eMac based
you know we can use a lot languages
let's do eMac this okay so Emacs miss
let's show so define a function so we
have a function here now I want let say
this is a function of Pi now in
mathematics there is a function named PI
named prime pi okay I think Prime Pi
that gives you the number of primes
under in something like that oh and
prime okay I forgot which but let's look
up the web prime PI okay so prime pi is
a function in Mathematica and it is also
a common name in mathematics so prime PI
gives the number of primes you know
number of primes less than or equal to
two okay you see that
so in conventional mathematics the the
function is named just pi okay
like you know in math notation in
conventional mathematics in math books
for example number theory books you have
this function named PI and that gives
you you know the number of primes the
count of how many Prime's under X or
equal to X but in Mathematica they named
it they named it prime PI so so you see
the function name this is math
okay you you want a function name the
pie so I want I want a function named
pie okay so for example I can say that
okay hold on second to big a font it's
pie okay you see I'm defining a function
of Pi gives the number of primes equal
or less than n okay less than or equal
to n okay that's what it does
and let's just say return 3 I am NOT I'm
too lazy to code it so you see that's an
example this is a example where you want
to have a Unicode character as part of
the function name and besides that there
are many reasons okay but the my point
is that sometimes it is pertinent and
useful very useful
you do want have Unicode in your
function name or variable name so this
so we are in email based actually this
works so we run a code then I can just I
can just call it okay let me show you I
mean let me show my Emacs okay so you
can see my command Co on the left window
so I'm going to I'm going to do meta X
okay actually let me modify this
renumber
okay give a number let okay so I
actually interactive
okay this is getting more and more
complex
[Laughter]
and let's just say return three so so
this part is actually reading you know
ask user to give a number so we can
learn the program run it then I'm going
to do metal X and I'm going to type PI
okay type PI okay you see in the mini
buffer I mean see if I can magnify you
see metallics I'm giving the function
name PI enter the symbols variable is
void okay you know I need to fix the
code here but it's not to it my point
here is that in eMac this a function can
have a Unicode has its name that's my
point
okay we need to fix this code later okay
so so my point is in emag this a
function can have a unicorn name but
this is not necessarily so in other
languages in fact there are a lot of
complexities so let me show you our
cotton so you can just search for for
example this alko unicode in function
names in operator symbol this you know
Unicode in operator operator symbol is
especially useful so for example the
question we want to ask or does your
favorite programming language one
support literal unicode in stream that
is can you have a smiley in the stream
without using escape you know
incomprehensible backslash and a bunch
of numbers right so can you actually
have a Unicode in your stream that's one
thing we want and
support me to a Unicode in source code
that is for example can you have a
literal Unicode in source code such as
in comments some languages cannot allow
that then does your language allow
function names or variable names with
Unicode in it and we have an example
there you know and thus your language
allow none let her you know coding
identifier okay so what does that mean
you see in many languages they may allow
some Unicode characters in variable or
function name only some of it not all
for example in many languages in many
languages if you want a function named
like that vector circle plus you cannot
do it however if you use the Greek
letter V then it works for example this
is a case in JavaScript and this is also
the case in Python for example in emag
beasts both of them are allowed so
what's the difference the difference is
that in some languages when you have a
they have a rule about what is allowed
character in identifiers variable name
or function name and they allow Unicode
but that Unicode must be your character
they allow unicode characters but that
character must have a Unicode property
in a category of letter so if we have a
if you have a Unicode such as these
circle plus which is not a letter then
you cannot use this character in
function M over your name but however if
you have a unicode character that is for
example the Greek fee or the gamma then
you can you can use it in function name
or variable name so you see this the
issue becomes complicated you see
different languages they have diff
and ways to deal with this and this rule
where does this rule came from I mean
this rule about how a unicode character
must be must belong to the category of
love letter you know that's one of the
property of Unicode so if they belong to
the category of letter then you can use
that character in function name
otherwise you cannot this rule came from
Unicode because Unicode consortium you
know the organization that created
Unicode they have a bunch of guides you
know about what to do so they one of
their guide is about this is this this
rule so that's why Python JavaScript
they both adopted it you know it's and
actually this rule is not good why
because for example the vector you see
you see this operator you see that
circle plus that circle plus is a very
common mathematical symbol and also the
multiplication you know very common and
that character is not of the class
letter you see so so that means you
cannot use this character in function
names in many languages
which is which is pretty sad you know
it's a bad decision because this we need
this and also this you see now I'm
getting complicated complications you
see that summation you see this
summation character now this summation
character is looks the same as the Greek
Sigma character capital Sigma quick
capital Sigma but however in unicode
they are distinct two different
characters so you have so this so you
have one character that's a Greek Sigma
show you okay so first of all copy these
to my talk show page so we can read it
later then let me show you about the
Greek Sigma okay so let me show you okay
okay on a second so open a new buffer
magnify Sigma this is a Greek Sigma and
make it into a unicorn okay wait okay
Sigma okay so actually so so let's
change this to Unicode let's change it
to Unicode you see this is a lowercase
Sigma this is a capital case Sigma this
is a Greek letter but however you have
the summation sign you see these two
characters are different because this
one the Greek capital Sigma we call
describe char and you can see that is
the that is that okay let's remove this
okay core point nine nine okay
let's do that you see that that Kirk is
ko point nine three one but however this
one described cha then it is you see
you see this this character is cool
point a seven to one so they are
completely different characters but they
look the same so back to the back to our
article so if you want to name a
function you know son
some is a very common mathematical
function name son
if you want to name your function by the
summation character you can you know the
proper symbol to use is this character
is this one not this one okay because
this one is actually means summation but
that one the Greek Sigma that's just a
capital letter of Greek Sigma okay so
they are different so now
so if but you want to use this some
character but you cannot you cannot do
it in Python you cannot do in JavaScript
problem why because because this
summation symbol is not a letter you
know it's not it doesn't have the
poverty being a letter so you can you
see the complexity you know issues
problems with this design these these
these nerds this this these
standards you know we need to respect
these idiotic standards that we
are decreased with you know that's a
issue so anyway so I mean so this is
about some of the complexities of you
know and I have at least actually so you
see see zippers first go Java JavaScript
Python Perl Ruby and so on so do they
allow Unicode in name no no yes yes yes
yes no yes yes yes do they allow math
symbol no no no no no no yes Ruby yes
no no II Mac this yes Julia
yes Mathematica yes say today today
allow Unicode or say I mean today allow
the Deaf today allow you to define a new
operator so see no tsipras personal go
no Java no JavaScript no Python yes you
can define your own
operator pearl no ruby question I don't
know okay mo yes so you know then the
next question do they allow math symbols
in operator you know what if you allow
defining operator
the next question is do you allow
Unicode such as circle plus to be an
operator so you can see you can see here
you know Python allows you to define
operators but however you cannot use the
Unicode as operator so it's like one
up you know because because once
you define once a language allows you to
define operators which is extremely
useful if you are doing mathematical
scientific programming extremely useful
because you need to define plus and
multiplication for vectors for octo
nians for quaternions for different
algebraic things you know you need you
know the operators operator beats the
function notation you know operator
makes it much easier to read so so if
you do scientific programming you want
the ability to define operators and in
general mathematical oriented languages
allow that for example Julia
in Mathematica you can see in Julia and
Mathematica it's all yes you can see
here you see in Julia in Mathematica you
can define your own operators and you
can also use a Unicode for your operator
you know but you know so that's some of
the issues these are the issues about
whether you can use a unicorn name in in
your programming languages functional
variable okay that's that's about that
okay so let's delete that let's copy
that close that let's put it here so we
can have
a overview of what we talked about today
so how long have I been talking and let
me read the comments okay we have
digressed so much oh my god it's 100
already okay I guess we there's actually
a lot to talk about we haven't begin
what is this how George is posing
something well so okay we started to
talk about Golan and we digressed into
Unicode issues in programming languages
and now I guess we were supposed to
return to Golan because originally I
want to show you the thing I want to fix
but because I started to talk about the
output of Golan this is my goal and
script the first line is about Unicode
declaration for the source code the
encoding then the timestamp then other
information but anyway we digress a lot
then we saw so we digressed into about
what are the issues related to Unicode
in a programming language and I
mentioned in summary again there is a
source code encoding issue and
declaration issue then there is a stream
issue what is the stream how do you you
know can you have Unicode in string and
what is the string exactly then we have
the function name in variable name
identifier you know coding identifier
issue and I don't think that's all there
is more issues I mean let me try if I
can summarize quickly yeah and okay then
there is also Unicode escape sequence in
string
like how do you represent Unicode you
know that's okay that's that's part of
the stream issue okay yeah mostly it's
about these three issues Unicode issues
in programming language file encoding
stream the meaning of string and how do
you represent Unicode in string and
things like that do they have you know
for some languages you actually have a a
char that's a unicode character data
type and in : that is called run so
again I have a page on that I'm not
going to show it but that's okay I mean
that's it let me read a comment stand
demetri demetri makes our Happy New Year
Happy New Year to you
Dimitri join discord so we can know I
can know you better so my beautiful face
is not moving what Jesus Scott you know
oh god I talked for how long
that's a major failure 347 so I talked
for 30 minutes without kind of my video
yeah what's going on with this software
let's see if we can fail fix it
something
okay so I talked before I talked for 30
minutes without well we found my face
that's that's pretty bad that's
depressing
what is the problem the problem is I
don't know your video stuck what the
okay that's really bad okay that's it
for today
I thank you guys for watching yeah
that's it for today I guess I should
have checked the comments more often but
so I've been talking for 30 minutes
without looking in the comments so can
you name variables in Chinese using
Unicode yes you can force for some of
the languages okay I have an example
here for example I show you I show you :
you can see identifiers with Greek
characters and also a symbol oh it's
that's a syntax error because colon
doesn't allow it then you have Python 2
then you have Python 3 in Python 3 yeah
you cannot have arbitrary symbol you
that's the symbol you use for function
name must be letter type of letter type
and JavaScript is pretty much the same
but you have other more rules and yes
you can use Chinese because Chinese
characters they belong to the letter
property they have you know they belong
to the letter categorization and in Ruby
it's the same thing you know they do not
allow non letter Unicode so you cannot
have sockappellas in Perl everything is
allowed okay wait oh no it's not allowed
neither
yeah sucks you see many of them they do
not allow none later but in Emacs this
is allowed
actually well we anyway it's allowed
okay you can you can just run this code
and your run Oh camel it does not even
allow any Unicode at all in Haskell and
you can see Haskell Haskell gets fancy
you has cow allows it but however that's
a recent development in the past few
years okay yeah good good bye guys
that's it for today we so today's topic
is unicode stuff hi guys