good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
we're going to do wolam language
coding geometry okay geometry wam
language coding
Mathematica and my keyboards glove 0
glove 0 fantastic ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic newly attractable and
this is coming soon uh this is s swar
board s v a l b o a r d this is
hardwired so I press a key you know you
know so for each one of them I have a
YouTube video review so check them out
I'm going to I'm going to hop onto the
SW
board hello Mo from
aab Hello Diego so uh I'm excited for
the Asian shape what Asian shapes what
Asian shapes so okay so uh I guess we
going to start to do uh coding then uh
begin begin Shall We Begin okay
fantastic beautiful emac showing Bowser
perfect system so I'm using S likees so
uh again bear with me two minutes
introduction stuff like ke this is a key
binding system key system for emac Max
is the greatest most powerful text
editor and go to this URL showing
browser this is sfly keys and uh so
there's a video you can watch and uh
this is the key binding so you don't
have to hold control hold meta hold old
something something [ __ ] up your hands
you know cripples you so with this
system you'll no longer be a [ __ ]
fantastic if you are using emac wor
learning so uh Stu like this am I using
a Vora keyboard layout so if you don't
know this is fairly Advanced keyboarding
for those of you who work with computers
day and night and you become a [ __ ]
because your hand have pen or Mouse uh
stuff are you seeing me seeing me yeah
Mouse my mouse my keyboard my okay
so so there you see SW board beautiful
this is the advanced very Advanced uh
device so I'm using sof like is emac and
I'm using a v keyboard so for those of
you who don't know go to layout section
and you can see everything you wanted to
know about keyboard layout so you can
see this is a standard quity then you
can have vorac uh you can have corac so
you can see the circle shows the
frequency of that letter in English
language language so you just search for
ergonomic keyboard
layouts. info you'll find this page and
you can see when you switch to vorac or
the most frequently used keys are on the
home row so that's why it's efficient so
I'm using sofly keys I'm using Vora
keyboard layout and emac and uh
everything I type the all the commands
will show up on the left side this pink
window this purple pink window the
command name for example end of line or
block that's this key End of Line press
again end of block press again and a
block so so you can go you know it's
like functioning as a page up and down
you don't need page up and down anymore
and if you want to go End of Line you
just you know press end of line or
beginning of line if you do it again
then it goes to the previous block next
block so but you can see the command
names are there and if you just search
for
that search you'll find the source code
so if you are using emac you know there
it is the source code oh page moved
because the brave browser
idsc I mean the I mean the brave brave
search engine is still they don't update
so you need to go to this new link there
it is the source code so the pink window
show all my command CES as I do that
them uh for example delete that line
undo so you can see smart delete and
undo and the key stroke on the left
that's Vora keyboard layout that's okay
that finishes my
introduction uh Shall We Begin yeah so
wam language Mathematica what do you
guys want to know so this is a good time
if you want to ask me
about this wolam language okay so by now
I have like 100 videos on wolam language
so you can ask me about wolam language
mathematics geometry related questions
and the lisp you know wfam language is a
lisp it is a term rewriting system you
can ask me about this kind of questions
so new let's open a new one and uh okay
s like Keys close close show today's
talk show so you can see wolam Language
tutorial click there wolam Language
tutorial you'll find everything you need
to know and the download for free
everything is free today wolam script uh
where download okay so you can download
it for free and all your questions get
answered and uh and start to learn this
the most advanced programming language
more advanced than any of hascal closure
rust any of the fancy programming
languages you ever heard of like one
magnitude more advanced okay more high
level that
is uh okay wam language so I have like
100 videos about it already so let's
begin coding so today I want to do so
let's see the power of SAR HTML M you
see this select the whole block so this
is uh you see this is a list showing
browser you see live stream in 30
minutes 7 p.m. San Francisco time you
see what is the most efficient editing
system for HTML that would bear HTML mod
you can see right
here jump right to the source code now
so this is s tml highlight all of them
do it yellow so you can see 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 eight eight files so it's about 10,000
lines most
efficient uh you if you want it you have
to pay okay because for 10 years it's
all free nobody give a [ __ ] and instead
everyone is gonna how do you do this
please help me thank you so much I love
your
stuff but nobody give you $1 for 10
years and I've been dying of hunger and
then people are going to your code sucks
you should do this you know you're this
you know what a [ __ ] idiot are you
doing this should be this way people
comments on GitHub you know they do it
all the time you are just you know a
pawn of the open
source so it's no longer free pay to get
it but it's still open source it's a g
GPL okay so that is so uh I haven't
demoed the feature for example this list
of things showing browser this list so I
can select the
previous semantic unit which is
a li okay you can do it again again
again and do it again it become the
holist you see do it again so they go by
semantic units of the HTML you can do it
again do it again oh then it becomes the
entire main thing so if you delet it
showing browser it become empty press a
key to go back press the key to
undo uh press one more time undo you see
it's back now go to the pink window you
can see undo which is uh vorac keyboard
F so now I show in browser again so you
got that so now we start to do real work
we want I want to delete that single key
press you see why one single key press e
delete this
entire list because your cursor is here
you know so let's suppose there's uh
several blank lines above it so press
the key all the blank lines lines are G
press another key that the unit above
that is gun press another key you see
then all the blank space are gun so that
is kind of short demo of HTML mod okay
if you like it just just donate okay
donate and say you paid you can find my
donation website sad. info and uh so go
all the way to the bottom go all the way
to the
bottom mathematics and everything then
you got PayPal and Amazon gift card
click there copy paste my email make
sure it's correct $99 would be nice
thank you okay that's enough
advertisement now let's begin the coding
stuff so I want to do this um so yeah so
that's a introduction so I want to
do
uh last time we did um we you know in
past month we did
hyperbola uh there are still more things
to do okay let me read the comments
first here's some
coke Diego says in s like Keys when you
start a
search how do you jump to next
occurrence arrow keys my friend
so this is Coke and this is tea very
busy
drinking why do I drink both at the same
time because Coke is that's sweetened
sugar drink so my teeth is bad because
for 15 years I don't have money I
haven't seen a
dentist so what you do to counter that
poverty is you become very careful you
brush your teeth after every meal every
time you drink sugar drink you Rin your
mouth
or sip
tea because tea is the antithesis of
sugar a little tip for you American
Health concerned guys diet dinosaur diet
and lion diet diet Caro diet uh Diego
diet something diet you know they they
do they're doing YouTube every day like
1 million followers these
idiots life is too good life is too good
that's how you get that's how you have
this 1,000 diet Obsession
thing how do I lose weight how do I be
hey
healthy you know you can be very
healthy by stop eating basically just
eat the
minimum uh so the question about search
so let me Demo so press a key to search
now let's say I want to search curve CU
u r okay there you go you want to go
find the next occurrence right arrow you
see right arrow right arrow right arrow
previous left Arrow left Arrow left
Arrow so you can jump around you
see okay
cancel what VSS code theme is
this uh this is not vs code this is emac
uh why do people use emac is there
anything else okay uh hello is there
anything well vs code you can use VSS
code okay I want to learn how to use CVS
code shortcut okay yeah do it uh show us
doctor
scheme m is
fancier uh idiotic questions
okay uh okay we are well I'm not going
to talk about lisp you know do scheme is
a lisp which became uh Dr scheme is
scheme disp which became rocket scheme
disp racket
okay r a c k t that's basically a uh
variation of the this scheme programming
language and I talked about it a million
times in my past video m is uh well
M like like you know you don't have a
question you know you I think I don't
think you have a question you are just
like H what do you think about whatever
random
things uh uh Mo says I'm starting to
appreciate this more since treea uses a
variant of this or does it that that's
interesting yeah three C is very good
but I haven't just haven't got two uh I
think I'm too
old I'm too old for
anything the time I have I need to learn
Ling proof
system but uh Tri is something I I I'm
going to get into okay so let's just
start to do something I want to do I
need to do because I need to update this
so let's go to Parabola let's quickly do
something Parabola maybe okay showing
Parabola so you got see uh we did this
you know several videos in the past
month about you know Parabola Optical
properties we did this graph live uh
here's a
code you know you see Optical properties
of Parabola for your car lamps for radio
telescopes for uh your Dish Satellite
Dish antenna things like that this is
this is alien technology you know
whenever there's UFO alien movies they
will show this parabolic
dishes you know this
amazing so if you want to do rockets
science you got to learn this
Basics and we did this uh
evolute of okay let's let's finish
update some of these you see these tiny
little images from 30 years ago so let's
go to top search. MB open it so go to
the directory so this is a wolam
language notebook. MB okay open it you
can see let me show you some interesting
okay so you can see it's wam language um
desktop 14 let's just open it first okay
so you can see here's a notebook this is
like from 30 years ago 1995 okay last
update is 2000 uh actually we updated
many many of these uh last week so my
job let me repeat my job is to remove
some you know basically delete this
notebook remove the code and generate
new graphics move the code to the
website okay and and generate new
graphics replacing the 30 years so so
today let's do this one pedal okay so
why am I moving you know so then then
delete this notebook why because time
changed you know back 30 years ago 30
years ago you go to a website you have
you know you use desktop there's no
phone yet so you download this notebook
you have wam language installed
Mathematica you run it you do what ever
you know enjoy enjoy the
mathematics but today you know most
people don't have a notebook The Zuma
idiots you know they they don't know
what is a
notebook they don't have they just have
their phone you know little you know so
and nobody like download a package you
know well I mean if you are professional
programmer you still do but most people
you know so it's better just have C code
you know you copy the code you go to the
wfam website then you can paste the code
and you know
stuff so that's why the you know I need
to update you know I'm doing updates so
but one extra tip more if you are
watching this you know uh two days ago
we did a video about the harm of the
Unix uh concept of line truncation line
based computation pervasive harm okay
now here is a real example you see this
um you see this let me make a copy okay
so let actually so let me just make a
copy copy it new
notebook control n control V2 paste okay
now let me do it again now um control
shift I okay so you see
normally in a programming language this
is what you see you know this is
familiar to all of you right but in
wolam language for example this negative
square otk 20 okay let's magnify to see
the full Glory of this beautiful code
negative square 20 square root you know
but I want to types set it you know to
the typical Unix Linux idiots phonetics
they'll say use lat you know lat is the
best thing it's a standard
lat but if you want to do latch with the
simple square root you're going to have
like backslash braces Square something
something [ __ ] [ __ ] it doesn't work
wrong syntax [ __ ] you up you know the
Donal G idiocy that's a legacy of the
Donal gr
idiocy in wolam Language by Stephan
wolf you know this square root bracket
you know 20 if you want to type set
shift control n can you see that oh
beautiful you know you don't have to
worry about tech lch micro adjustment oh
I need to move this a little bit bigger
you know [ __ ]
idiocy okay I'm starting to get into a
rant uh that's not good
I need to just work on this okay but let
me quickly show you um
a rant about tech L because I haven't
mentioned it for a
while okay the tech pestilence why Tech
and latch
sucks by the way for you younger
generation this teex is pronounced te
okay it's not Tex it's not text it's not
Tex it's Tech that X
is pronounced
CH kind of kind of okay that's what
that's what Donald G
says okay that's what it's supposed to
be L and L okay so that you know so for
example these are the
typical uh typ set mathematics you have
Sun you have you know uh succeed uh
integral definite integral you have
infinite sum you have you know uh
definite end derivatives you have limits
then you have square roots you have the
conjugate you know you have matrices
right very common and square right you
know so this is a typical math type
setting this is basically the
fundamental okay like 19 % of math type
setting are just these things okay so if
you want to do this in Tech this is what
you have to write this this
idiocy this back slash sum
underscore uh braces n equals one
correct K back slash Frack braces one
braces n you know this this [ __ ]
complete idiocy
but if you want to write the same thing
you know so that's that's just for the
sum that's the first one
okay if you want to do it in wolam
language this is what you uh write okay
let me magnify to so you can see the
full Glory okay this is
Tech okay to do this sum the first line
sum greater than this integral okay so
this is Tech
and this is wol fr okay sum one / n and
the argument is n from 1 to
K and this is computable let me copy it
and paste let me show
you
paste okay that result is actually
harmonic number so but let me do it
again shift control n you see beautiful
summation and by the way we let's let's
do this whole okay so shift control n
you see now it's
readable okay let's undo you see this is
before this is before and this is after
okay it's like much more it become
readable it reads to you
and you have on the Fly
formatting can you see that on the F it
adjust this complicated type set
Expressions on the fly like the the the
second the microc you change the window
size it adjust on the fly it line wraps
at the appropriate places and the
indentation look at the indentation it
indents at the right
place artificial intelligence before
the CH GPT python [ __ ] was born this is
available since
1996 WFAN language version
three you know but if you're going to do
this in Python you know like return
indent indent uh return you know how
many indent you
know then then the tech
[ __ ] you know normally there's no
problem you know because Tech progresses
you know you have different people
creating different things Donald G
offered his Tech free right but but then
comes this Unix [ __ ] then the
opensource ftic
[ __ ] they insist you know they
don't just say oh I well I'm I'm used to
this so you know I don't know about
Mathematica Mathematica you have to pay
uh well I'm poor right now I'm a student
so I I you know I just use Tech that's
not what they say if that's what they
say that's okay no problem I I don't
have a problem but this Unix and Linux
and these open source
[ __ ] they will tell you insist Tech
is the best thing if you if you mention
you know wolam language they all say
like [ __ ] you they but they never seen
what this W Lang they haven't seen yet
they don't know they don't know they
tell you python is the best thing how
how dare you disagree Unix is the best
thing C is the best
language that it is that that that that
trigger triggers me
okay but anyway too bad I got into the
rent okay so you see this this is so
this is a more General this is a harm of
fanatism okay not just Unix and C or
python or Tech L it's more general
fanatism in any anything creates harm uh
including lisp you know Le people you
know there's least people they you know
I attacked it enough so you know it's
it's harmful so you don't want
fanaticism
so okay so that's about okay so let's go
back uh okay
let's relax and quit the rent mod exit
the rent mod and go back to Harmony like
this harmonic
number harmonic number by the way this
this this sum is very interesting
because uh
if you go to Wikipedia uh look at
harmonic series you know so this is 1 +
1 / 2 + 1 over three + one over four so
will it increase infinitely or will it
stop like the total is like finite
that's a question very interesting this
is like the representative of calculus
that's what you do in calculus this is
like in fact this this this series you
could say is the representative like the
calculus is entirely about this thing
you know whether you add a bunch of
number whe they increase to infinite or
will they like this is actually become a
number so the heart of calculus
and so you can see beautiful Graphics
this limits and uh there and then then
there is this thing okay this this thing
very interesting you know you you stack
of a a bunch of blocks and uh what do
you want to you want to see if it falls
or not
okay um I'm too old okay I did I studied
this like when I was young 30 years ago
30 35 you know in 1992 so I was like so
excited you know I'm studying in this in
depth why would it you know why would it
this way or that way so but no I don't
know I don't remember okay
but so that's for you young people to 30
okay so we digressed a bunch uh so let's
regroup okay so I uh this I was writing
I was coding some emac this before okay
close that close that close that go back
here close that go this page today's
talk show okay let's
do uh let's go back to what we were
doing yeah Parabola okay so let's go
back yeah so notebook so we this is wam
notebook we demonstrated Tech and L Tech
so
let's let's put the link here and uh let
me answer some questions and
maybe uh maybe that'll be today's topic
maybe uh actually I'm I'm going to do
some code okay I need to do at least one
uh tech tech I mean not I mean uh at
least
one geometry Parabola stuff
okay okay so we talked about you know so
very interesting topics harmonic
[Music]
series um and
uh okay
as a Zuma idiot I'm offended me
too me too Diego says the Unix
pestilence indeed YouTube says you use
Mouse to copy
paste no I don't use Mouse to copy paste
what are you talking about like well
sometimes but
um okay so you see my system you see the
left side is the this automate hacking
keyboard so if I want to copy I press
this key you cannot see
but okay so you can see this key is copy
when I press that it does actually
control C on vac layout this is cut this
is undo so one single key press so I put
my hand on the left you know over here
so I just operate so the mouse moves
around and my left hand can copy paste
and you know stuff like
that uh I you know you are pretty new
this you hi hi or non YouTube channel
you are pretty new because I talked
about this one million
times T is Greek letter toe e is Greek
letter Epson and X is Greek letter G yes
and more says
interesting uh properly pronounce it
yeah tech tech
I'm sure Tech lch wam equivalent has its
own notation you can probably see it in
a no books code
behind uh yes I mean so if your question
is how does wo F you know for example
this part it shows you know it it
renders it very beautifully but the
source code is actually just this okay
you know let me let me just use a simple
example
um let's see do I have something more
complex no okay let's just pick
this so if I paste that the source code
so um control L to copy previous shift
control I to turn it into the input
notation this this is actually the
source code for that okay they are
equivalent like for example I can
compute it control
enter uh wait shift enter shift enter uh
shift enter okay so that simplifies to
two over square otk of 5 so if if you
want the numerical result you say n
uh close so you say shift uh n so
bracket then percent means the previous
output okay or you can just copy it so
control L to copy the previous output so
if you want num re uh result just put a
n before shift enter so that gets you
that 0.89 something same thing here
shift n you know so if you want
numerical result
you slash slash N Post fix
notation shift and shift enter 0.8 so so
my point is that this is the actual
source
code for this types set expression okay
you can convert it either way by
pressing a button you know whichever way
you like to see it so when you code you
can just code like that when you are
ready press a button it becomes like
that if you want to print it like a
academic representation academic paper
you know then then you show it you know
you show it like that
okay
so so the the other question is how does
wam language
[Music]
actually uh kind of implement this well
yeah so there is um you can see that by
um let's go to a notebook let's just
save this okay for example this one is
simple enough let's save this Untitled
to uh let's say uh let's say XX xx2 okay
save it in desktop now let's go to
desktop okay so xx2 open it this is we
are seeing the
raw
notebook uh source code so this raw
source code is like text okay wolam
language is entirely text so in Notebook
it shows like that but in sour code is
just
text okay so so now you see this R box
you see this R box box data cell you see
the entire thing is a notebook you see
this line you know goes back you know
goes from top to bottom okay so I can
select it uh you know so this entire
thing is a notebook okay represent this
and then above that you see this this
this
parenthesis and star those are commons
okay like those are Commons in Cache you
know so you can you can delete it this
you know you can delete like like I have
in emac I have
uh you know I'm using saaan mod right
now you see that's another so I can
press a key to delete the entire comment
you see you don't need it okay so this
notebook and then if you scroll to the
bottom then you got cache okay so for
example uh go down so end of notebook
content delete that internal cach
information delete that this sell
outline this sell tag this notebook file
outline you know you can delete the
whole thing end of internal cach
information delete delete delete okay
then we got this this
thing it's a pure notebook so you see
the notebook is just this expression so
so the wolam language you know even the
notebook entire thing is is a wolam
language
then you know for example if you create
a new file let's create a new
file uh save it as xx3
NB the entire thing consist of single
this line save it go to the directory
show in in Windows browser uh wait I
already opened it okay too fast okay let
me show in Windows
browser wait wrong key so show in
Windows browser so you can see there it
is so
xx3 you can enter open it it's just
empty okay so that represent you know so
the entire notebook syntax is just text
okay so now the uh the thing about this
you see but over here we are seeing this
um Let me let me do a screenshot first
okay hold on a
second so I do a screenshot so I have a
record of what we were talking about for
my um Talk Show so uh let's go to talk
show
here and uh let's uh move the screenshot
here press press press there it is
showing browser there it is so we can
see what we talked about okay but now
let's let's just delete this delete this
um delete this so now it's more simple
okay now contrl s save it go back let's
go go back to the uh
notebook uh x x2. m has changed save
anyway no okay because we just saved it
from wam language now save it no god
let's go here okay now close this don't
save okay
close kill anyway yes okay now refresh
now you see it's much smaller now open
it uh you see it's much smaller but you
know you can see the square root there
it's still complicated so anyway my
point here is
that the underlying implementation for
this type set thing in W language is
this raw box and cell you know box data
raw box raw box so it's
it's kind of similar to math ml
okay so for example you can actually so
Ro box is actually a function so they
are like headers you know they are like
iner function but you can uh look at the
documentation so for example uh tap Edge
to see the documentation inaan mod so
there it is the documentation for this
rbox
thing so you can see Ro box is a
lowlevel box construct that represents a
row of boxes of all strings in a
notebook expression so this type set
thing are
internally represented by this this Ro
boox you know thing so for example this
Ro box this represent a plus b plus
C so it's in a sense so you can see it's
like the entire not book is just made of
the wolam language programming language
you have this Ro box they are iner
functions they are functions that
doesn't do anything they are kind of
just a markup like HTML you know H2 H3
or whatever they are kind of just mark
up iner functions but they are functions
nevertheless so but when you display
this source code in woof and notebook
this Ro box is they they become rendered
just like
HTML okay that's how you have this okay
but but again these are kind of
implementation issues you don't need to
know all you can you know all you need
to know is just type this for example
type this
sum and press the button and it becomes
like that
okay you know you don't have to know
this R box and stuff
okay that's kind of um that
um the other major problem with tech is
that they are not
computable you know so it's like what
what it's most idiotic [ __ ] you know
it's it's not just my bitching you know
like what this is a major issue design
you know Donald nth is a genius you know
I mean not exactly a genius but he's
a very high IQ one of the
most um
accomplished computer
scientist and math oriented computer
scientist so he he's one of the you know
greatest great
mathematician but but that doesn't mean
everything he creates is great you know
so in the computer you know he wanted to
do type setting you know when there's no
type setting for computers you know back
in
1970s right so he want he are designing
a system to do type setting but how I
don't you know see you know
somehow he created this language that
cannot compute I mean it's it can
compute but I mean if you want to do
let's say squar you know let's say a
number squared let's say two squared
okay so if you just want to do let's say
x x you know let's say 3 to the power of
two
right so in wam language you just copy
that you know do that type it and and
you got n but in Tech and latch how do
you how do you do a raisin number you
know so it's a same syntax right three
correct two but you cannot get n you
know it's like it's only for display
like what what the [ __ ] is he thinking I
don't
understand do does anyone know the
history like like how H how did it
happen that
g one of the you know accomplished
mathematician and comput computer
scientist creating a type setting
language but he he forgot he doesn't
know he never thought of to to make the
language like actually can compute you
know mathematics because all these sum
integral they are like they actually
represent you know computation they are
just
notations so I guess you know I guess my
guess is that back
then you know to to us today it seems
obvious right obvious but back back then
you know there's not many you know
there's no internet there's no like no
not much of anything you know there's no
python even right you got C and Pascal
you know he wrote he wrote Tech in Pas
Pascal right so he you know back so back
then his focus is to create a type
setting
system you can you know so so that is a
big task you know that's like probably a
big huge task nobody has done it before
so that that was he thinking you know
I'm gonna I I need to create a system so
that so that X squ you know this two
will be smaller you know type
setting you know so he didn't you know
he not like today he's not thinking oh
why why don't we just make it also can
compute that's that's like a you know we
are not there yet
so yeah but so that's I suppose that's
why but you know so again what pisses me
is that today you know even 10 years ago
20 years ago this this you know you go
to stack Overflow you're talking to the
Unix people the python you know like
they they say tech tech tech but they
they don't under they never thought of
this these
problems why can't you compute it
you know this Su for example I type this
let me Demo again this in wolam language
okay I type this let's say uh okay so I
copy it shift control n to make it type
set I can I can compute it okay shift
enter to compute it shift enter to
compute it okay now this
sum
is has a symbolic result called how IC
number okay but let's change the
variable so it becomes actually
something let's say one 29 one over n
sum and from one to 9 okay shift enter
can you see that now copy the input
shift control n to make it type set and
uh shift n to compute it can you see
that that's what I mean that
that's what you know you are doing
mathematics why are you writing this for
you are doing mathematics is it
important to actually not just typ set
and computer number yeah it's of course
obviously so these people you know this
like 1,000 like every time I talk to
them they don't they don't listen they
attack me they attack me like this this
this Tech pestilence article is back
from
2004 okay I wrote wrot this article 2004
then the bunch of idiots you know they
they they Tech lch Unix the [ __ ] them
they don't understand what I'm saying
they attack me is a Troll he's just
trolling every day [ __ ] that's ban him
they they did they did Lobby to ban me
for from from the news group back in 200
uh uh five also I wrote this
article this so so there's a
documentation of the fact
banar you can find it just search for
that ons.info you know so I I complain
you know I say this [ __ ]
idiots like any every time I talk about
Unix I do rent on Unix C or you know and
python or and pearl or lisp you know but
the but you got this phonetic you know
this code Unix is a code python is a
code is Cy emac is Cy very much emac
this emac okay emac is very
Cy um python Unix uh and Tech okay so
every time you mention something maybe
sensible they will attack you to no ends
if you if you are allowed like me you
know I don't say hey guys uh you know
have you thought about this maybe it's
wrong you know I mean uh can we possibly
have attack to also computation that's
not the way I talk the the way I talk to
them is you guys are [ __ ]
idiots that's you know so they ban me
they say I'm true they have no idea what
I'm talking about that you know in all
these groups what groups are not called
PHP JavaScript in the
beginning uh Pascal the programming
language Pascal SC okay like some
programming language they don't have a
code uh PHP for example everyone
beginner loves because every time you
ask question you got to answer people
will help you but in Python in lisp in
hascal every time you ask the
question everybody else is gonna you
shouldn't do it that way oh have you
thought about monad have you thought
about uh uh
iterators you shouldn't you you know
[ __ ] [ __ ]
them okay so this end upod so so so how
long have I been so I got eight more
minutes so let me actually want to do I
want to do a wam language code okay so
let me quickly let me do that so there's
one more question uh let me answer that
you are going to do a stream about wolam
language 30 uh maybe but well but you
see the the issue wam language 30 I mean
the emac version 30 okay emac version 30
came out and you can see on my blog
there is
um uh
emac 30 okay so emac 30 came out emac
version history I recently kind of
updated this page history of emac so you
go to emac 30 then you can read the
entire uh emac 30 feature list they call
it news you know that's a emac tradition
emac
news for for 40 years you know that's
how they go they don't say uh release
notes or feature list no it's it's emac
news emac news 30 so so usually every
emac major release is like 1,000 you
know pages I mean few hundred pages and
so you you know it's it's
it's 10 years ago I I sometimes I went
through and write a
nice um nice uh blog you know so you can
read and you can actually understand you
know oh this is
new um but but I haven't done that for a
long time because this is you know takes
a week to take more more than a week to
go through each one of them and they are
written usually in a
way in a way it's
not understandable okay even if you are
a emac coder or user for 30 years like
me uh I've been using emx for 20 26
years okay since
so so usually they are hard to
understand so for example you know click
on this so what is it say new value if
regular for replace argument to insert
file contents okay I know insert file
contents is one of the function uh so
new value if regular for okay so they
added a new argument to this
function okay that's one item you know
so it's kind of esoteric you know and
here for example new Hau specific
variable hu pass control tab to system I
don't even know what that is Hu is some
kind of a uh text rendering system
something so this sets whether iMac
should replace C tab control tab on the
system in instead of handling it fixing
problem problem where Windows switching
would not activate if Emax frame
something something oh on focus on the
high cool operating system [ __ ]
[ __ ] that's a
esoteric among the esoteric you see hu
is operating system so this is talking
about on that operating system then
emac has this change you know that what
the [ __ ] and like like you know so who
knows what the [ __ ] is
Hau it's like one in one in a billion
you know that like nobody uses high CO
you know so that's kind of like you know
this emac
news you know so for example this one XL
FD are no longer restricted to 255
characters what the [ __ ] is XL
FD font X lfd name now returns an X
lfde even if it is greater than 255
characters in
length font so is that a
font very esoteric you see that's the
nature so you know if I'm going to you
know
so it is hard to like summarize what's
relevant news to user relevant to the
user so you got to go through this
um yeah so I'm not
[Music]
likely going to do a Blog I mean a live
stream about emac
30 um what's new there's another guy who
is doing it you might watch I mean he I
don't think he's doing video but he's
got
the uh blog mastering emac okay this guy
is kind of my
Nemesis yeah
well okay
so so there it is okay mastering emac by
this guy so he usually after each new
emac version he actually gives you a
summary a readable summary for the user
what's new so there it is what's new in
emx
30.1 okay so okay artwork
uh then you see so this is like 50 pages
you know even even reading this his
summary is 50 pages okay but you can
check it
out okay
so yeah so you know this mastering em
guy he's a northern European uh what's
his name his name somewhere okay but he
is on video Sasha TR another very very
wellknown
[Music]
person person in emac community
Sasha She interviewed him this guy on
video so about 15 years ago so you can
watch that so anyway mastering
emx so one last thing so let me just
quickly I want to quickly code um code
uh one Parabola okay and that will be
it so what what's going on here so hold
on a
second shrink shrink okay so what I want
to do with this I want
to
um just copy this
okay okay got the image close that don't
save and uh yeah let's quickly do one of
these uh update I need to do and that's
it for today thank you guys for
watching uh where is the one I want okay
here I
suppose okay so back to the
browser am I like am I alive and kicking
is my
video what
uh
what close
that and what can I close this CL
set close
set
okay okay my
key my keyboard is not working correctly
shift
control
window okay I have sticky key on so when
you have sticky key on sometimes it's
mysteriously
stuck ah [ __ ] I don't understand what's
going on with
that
okay okay so finish this okay so yeah so
uh close close close
close uh notebook close Okay so notebook
you got to
okay uh let's copy
that actually
copy okay close close showing browser
this is today's talk show go to Parabola
yes uh yeah and go to parabola
and the graphics we want to do
is is this okay so this one so pedal
with respect to its vertex okay so um
pedal Parabola yeah okay there
more so let's copy that
copy a new
paste and
uh
copy okay make it type
Set uh kind of copy
that
so search for
pedo okay so here is the graphics uh
here's the old one very tight tiny
so the new one needs to be here so start
a wol language code
so yeah so the parabola
formula that's the code but we have uh
we can use this okay
so so the parabola is actually just that
okay so replace that by that and the
from T from 9 to 9 in increment a 0.5
yeah let's leave
it okay
then curve color function how you want
the curve uh colored leave that and uh
we need this part this is my package and
let's rename this power plot to plank
cve plot okay plot this equation
parameter
equation x = 2 T and Y = 2
t^2 ided by 4 okay uh1 to uh 9 to9 okay
pedal points uh H that's curve color
function okay automatic aspect plot
range okay that's
it so copy copy copy go here go here go
here select all paste
minute beautiful okay so we just going
to so let's just copy
this so this is the you are seeing the
pedo curve of a parabola
okay now if you want to know what is a
pedo you have to read my
website uh go here you can read
about uh ped curve there detailed
explanation and steps you know four
steps so so we got the correct formula
let's delete this part put it back then
we did a screenshot press press press
move the image here okay well that's the
other one okay let's do it
again okay that's the other image we
need to okay do it again
so that's the one we want okay rename it
Parabola
Parabola pedo okay do
it and uh update it okay now we got
these two images this should go to my
talk show copy the file path go to the
talk
show uh showing browser yeah here so
paste the true file path you can can see
make make a embed image make the embed
image so open that so that's what we
talked about from notebook raw source
code and here's a summation that's
renamed it rename it s talk show okay uh
and move move the file
to the current
directory move the file to uh what did I
do yeah wait
what yeah so move the file to the
current directory and uh rename it talk
show okay regenerate this
HTML uh and this
one talk show
regenerate show
it there it is talk show so we talked
about this things now go back to the
parabola Page open this it's gone
because we moved the image so delete
that open it it's gone because we moved
the image to a different directory
delete that so
now we got this new uh thing okay and
here's a code showing browser go
down down down down down down down down
there it is that's our new image and
here is a code we need to color syntax
color
it do it back to browser refresh
beautiful okay and this old image
deleted
uh this one tiny 30 years ago delete gun
okay so yeah remove remove the tag uh
now
um cut this line and move it to the
figure caption paste back to
browser
refresh there it is okay did we
actually anyway that's
it bye guys