hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk show today we're going to talk
random I'm going to code some wolf
language Mathematica probably and let's
talk random uh lots of updates on my
website but now let's have a drink
first let's
have brand uh whiskey what is this
Brandy oh what is the difference between
Brandy and whiskey not
sure let's have
some
s so just a little bit I'm not a drinker
so and my keyboards this is glove 8
fantastic this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard and coming up I will be doing
live on this thing it's been too long
this is sve board SV L SV a l b o a Rd
swab board data
hand it's fantastic device okay coming
up in the next few days I'm going to you
know do it live and try try
it uh so
who else is here say hi okay you guys
say hi okay so
let's let's begin okay let me show you
what I have been doing been coding
nonstop on my website you can you can
search YouTube I have reviews uh video
reviews of all of
them okay so yeah yeah so let's switch
to my screen
okay so let's do coating and stuff have
a drink first
cheers okay so huge amount of updates
let me show you so you just go to my
keyboard blck keyboard and emac and like
hu tremendous huge humongous okay so you
go to keyboard blog my keyboard s
keyboard guide you can find it so in the
past week or two I've been working a lot
on keyboard and uh on keyboard and emac
disp okay so first of all there is uh so
there's IBM keyboard history you can see
see but what's more important I mean so
this is some sum of the IBM keyboard the
most famous is the IBM model M I used
this keyboard in
1990 1990 exactly for you know for a
year that's my first time touching a
computer click clack click clack this is
the most famous you know be before the
past 15 years a mechanical keyboard this
this is the most famous
mechanical keyboard and due to this
switch but clean spring key switch
buckling spring why because there's a
spring inside and when you press the key
down the spring resist your pressure
until it cannot take it anymore it
buckles then you the key is registered
so you can see this animation butling
uh Bering spring keyboard
Tack okay so this is most famous
mechanical key switch of
IBM uh IBM model
M so let's go back let's go back to my
blog so let me show you the keyboard
history so the keyboard history so you
can see here here is the main thing so
you got keyboard history you got uh okay
let let me show you so this is you know
huge amount of keyboards in the past
some of the some of them are very famous
for example IBM electric of course this
days few people you know know it zumas
don't know but back then this is the
thing this is the most greatest one of
the greatest innovation in keyboard you
know back then it's mostly uh mechanical
type writers and electrical type writers
so you got this SP that Swift swivel
around so back in
1990 I was employed as a data entry CL
clerk so I love typing so I have to go
to um you know employment center to test
my typing speed which is 90 92 W per
minute on this electric
mechanical uh keyboard
typewriters
so so uh can you play this this IBM
electric ad so you can see the
actionable electric
typewriter the IBM
s this is what makes it difference an
element fantastic this machine
mechanical device you know there's
attraction about mechanical device
devices uh what what that's which is the
gist of
the
uh you know anyway is mechanical you
know there a strong attraction why
because it's mechanical you can visually
see how it works like gears and cams and
wheels you know it's very attract uh
attractive as opposed to electronic or
Quantum something you know like
computers you open it you can't see
nothing except the fan the fan is
holding that's
mechanical so the attraction and that is
that is also why track balls are uh
attractive oh yeah the word is steam
punk steam punk you know a a niche a sub
subfield of Science Fiction you know so
why is track for
attractive apart from you know the
mechanism how you control the cruiser
but but the other part is the mechanical
aspect of it because you can see the
ball when you row it you know how you
know so that's uh you know one of the
essential that's why essential
attraction of track ball okay so let's
go back so so you got keyboard history
you know the prestige Elite
72 very very uh amazing invention okay
and on YouTube they have you know big
you YouTube videos telling you uh you
know in detail how this ball works so
for you nuts you enjoy
it Discord hello guys hello guys if you
have questions post it now okay it's a
good time how many people watching let's
see so I'm using this this pen device
which is great cheap and you can also
see it on my keyboard blog uh at the pen
input okay everything you need to know
about pen input so anyway let's go to
back to the keyboard uh history so these
you know all these are great I mean many
of them are very notorious or famous
keyboard for example sell you know this
is a lisp keyboard the first one and you
know today you have the command key you
have the windows key do you know where
they came from they came from this
keyboard
1970 okay invented kind of invented by
John McCarthy the guy who created Lis
programming
language uh list programming language
right right right right because you know
s like ke emac if you guys watch my
video it's all lisp okay it's all it's
lisp all the
way let let's you see so this is lisp
code you
see uh you see this is Lis code so John
M Cy in the the guy who created this
code sof like Keys fantastic okay
comments and questions comments okay you
guys direct what I'm going to talk today
is random chat cheers let me finish my
whiskey brand brandy or whiskey what's
the difference
you know I heard that whiskey is
supposed to you know this is a incorrect
glass for whiskey or Brandy you're
supposed to use like um kind of like
that cup so you can smell it because
whiskey is supposed to smell it but I
don't know anything about drinking I'm
not a drinker uh usually actually I
don't like alcohol that much so I don't
know so what's the difference hey what's
your typing speed 92 did I just mention
that 92 W per minute in fact I have you
know recently I have so many update on
my website about speed typing uh like
two three videos ago uh you should check
it out speed typing okay so anyway the
first you know the the kind of the first
this is one of the one of the like
historical innovation in keyboard
okay uh cell keyboard okay uh then you
know so keyboard history so huge update
but the main thing you know so I had
this page many years uh so but the main
thing is that at the bottom you can see
history of input devices so you have
keyboard history all the famous by the
way this one is also one of the
greatest keyboard in keyboard history
Microsoft created this ergonomic
keyboard and this is the beginning this
is when ergonomic keyboard be became
popular the concept there was ergonomic
keyboard before this but people don't
know I mean but this is why Microsoft
you know usually we we just hate
Microsoft you know but actually
Microsoft had many quite a few
Innovations not comparable to Apple of
Steve Jobs however micros Microsoft did
have great many
Innovations yeah especially in the 1990s
so this keyboard is one of them you know
ergonomic and successful you know as
compared to apple you know Apple also
tried tried the ergonomic keyboard at
this about the same time 1993 but it's a
huge failure this keyboard you know
Apple's uh ergonomic it's a flop it's a
lemon it's fa it failed
miserably because it's not good okay so
Microsoft you know did you know did it
and so and also on this keyboard it's
the first time we see this menu key okay
that's a Microsoft invention although
it's not so great invention but however
however it's the first time the menu key
appeared um and uh what about the
Windows key I think it's also the first
time on on uh keyboard the Microsoft
keyboard deviced by Microsoft by zebba
Design okay although it was not the
first orgonomic keyboard it was the
first widely available sub 100 offering
the keyboard gained popularity quickly
selling over
600,000 per month oh my God Jesus at its
peak Microsoft economic okay as with
most micro Microsoft keyboards software
Microsoft intell type is bundled for
both Mac OS X and windows allowing users
to customize the function keys and so on
from Wikipedia okay so you see this is
one of the rare instance where Microsoft
made a Innovation and became hugely
successful
changed the history in other words
Microsoft Changed History but Apple
failed miserably here okay so and and my
my you know actually I didn't like this
you know before you know in the 1990s I
didn't like this weird keyboard my
favorite keyboard is just the normal the
cheapest PC you know
because you know I I don't like how they
put the six key you know it's like fancy
like who need it you know and until in
2005 I got repetitive strain injury uh
and I I my first Microsoft keepy then I
realized I got a problem seriously
because I by by then I have read a lot
about keyboards so this is the keyboard
I
bought you know in
2005 my first ergonomic keyboard and
since ever since you know then I forc
myself to get used to it usually
people's opinion are just habit you know
like key binding application Windows
versus MAC or Linux usually it's just
habit habit plays a major part on how
you like stuff so but I know I have
eyesi you know because it's feeling
weird it's tingling so I forced myself
to get used to uh I B this to get used
to this and ever since I will never I
will never use a flat rectangular you
know the normal PC keyboard
again so that's a habit you know and
another another thing is this thing you
see this this this arrangement of a home
row so I'm you I'm used to this one on
the left side right and then but on the
on this keyboard you got this weird you
know Arrangement at first it's very
annoying but after a few month you just
get used to it then when you then when
you encounter a keyboard that's a
traditional arrangement of the home home
and insert delete then you feel weird
about it you know so again
the the moral here is that habit okay so
whenever you make judgment or opinion
about keyboard of of or lots of things
or programming languages lot of it is
just simply your personal habit okay you
need to kind of remove that and make a
judgment based on you know um you know
more fair criteria like remove your
personal be personal bias or personal
[ __ ]
okay okay
comments uh listening to geek out while
going for a walk lovely lovely nostal
Nostalgia
lovely okay uh
Abdullah
mudin uh you are AR Arabic are you
judging from from your name hia what's
your typing speed 92 okay 92 it's like
all over my
blog so I recommend you guys you know
check out my keyboard blog so uh Nick
Nick
Buren says I still use that keyboard
better Keys than all subsequent versions
oh yeah that's interesting that is true
actually so you know the Microsoft since
then have many versions of the of the
ergonomic keyboard you know the they
what they call Microsoft of natural but
actually the first one actually is the
best I agree you know it's
funny like like it's funny you know then
then then they have this you know the
first one is is you know the Microsoft
natural keyboard
1994 right very good but then they come
in 1998 you have the Microsoft natural
keyboard Elite then they [ __ ] up the you
know they they they they change the home
and delet key into the tiny [ __ ] and
then they change the arrow key into this
diamond shape that's very idiotic
okay according to science okay actually
because I have an article on Arrow key
um uh okay so you know there's a lot of
things on my on my blog what is this oh
God Microsoft Internet Explorer you hit
it okay so let me show you you arrrow
key okay arrrow key science so so go
back here what is
this
and keyboard okay search for Arrow so
recently I updated this a bit so you can
see Arrow key history so you have you
know so who invented Arrow key who is
the first one who created Arrow key that
is again the sell
keyboard in ented by the lisp inventor
lisp Creator John McCarthy the first
keyboard to have some kind of Arrow but
not dedicated Arrow okay but so but this
cell keyboard s a i l that stand for
Standford artificial intelligence lab
okay so back then in the
1970s you know the artificial
intelligence is over lisp lisp
programming
language okay like I was showing I was
showing here oh did I close it lisp
programming language emx okay so so this
keyboard is uh as far as I know you know
I don't know for sure but as far as I my
study my research into keyboard is the
first one that have the some kind of
arrow on the keys then the first the
first dedicated arrow is
um is maybe this one again another list
keyboard very famous you see they got
the thumb up thumb down then pointing
[Laughter]
left this very famous keyboard called
space cadet space cadet keyboard uh
keyboard for this machine you know so
that's another history all these are
historical now obviously another famous
one is for the vi keyboard VI
VI the you know where the vi HJ KL for
Cur movement movement orated okay so
this is the ADM 3A terminal
1976 but again it's not dedicated arror
Keys okay it's just arrrow keys on some
other key Arrow key overlay and this is
how VI editor or Vim or EVO mod in emac
got their Cruiser movement with hjkl
okay so Arrow key is interesting but the
first one the first keyboard that
actually have a dedicated arrow is
actually kind of this space cadet but
not exactly because you see we are going
through the history of keyboards back
then it it you know there's no concept
you know there's no even concept where
you press the key to move Cruiser up or
down so this keyboard SP space cadet
keyboard they have some kind of Arrow as
thumb up thumb down you know left finger
but actually they do nothing okay but
they do have dedicated keys so then we
progress into um maybe this one I'm not
sure I I I don't know who is actually
the first keyboard with d dedicated
arrow keys and that actually function as
arrow keys as of today's AR keys but
maybe it's this one 1970 add DS console
880 terminal okay maybe it's this
one okay but however in any case this is
the first keyboard that has that has the
inverted T Arrow Arrangement okay that's
another history okay that's another
history so anyway I digress a lot but
but anyway you you look at the arrow
keys you know it's very interesting
interesting history you have lots of um
oh yeah the the the actually the the
first one that actually invented the
inverted T is this keyboard
okay deck
vt220 terminal
lk21 keyboard and actually they
consciously researched into
to the issue of which arrow key
Arrangement is the most efficient okay
they this keyboard the creator of this
keyboard actually went into that and
they decided they you know they came up
with the inverted T which is the most
efficient aror key of arrangement okay
which is true okay did I detail it
somewhere I have a detail somewhere
[Music]
uh okay so but anyway let's go back to
arrow keys
uh I think I uh it's somewhere let's see
which which which this
one there's someone who wrote a history
of that inverted t uh Arrow key
arrangement I forgot where but somewhere
somewhere I have a link here
okay anyway anyway uh yeah I have a link
somewhere so it must be oh God this is
huge but anyway it's all about arrow
keys you see you have so many
arrangements and
uh people just do random back then uh
and you
know so many different Arrangement and
there's a guy who did a video talk show
about all the arrows so I actually have
a lot more work to do uh but anyway so
the guy you know if you want to know
what's the most efficient Arrow key
Arrangement is the here okay so this
article arrow keys Arrangement
efficiency Vim hjkl versus I jkl I jkl
is the inverted T so here we study which
one is more efficient in summary Vim is
inferior okay the Vim HJ KL that's
inferior slightly than the inverted T
okay so you can you know here's a
JavaScript you can like uh uh you can
actually you can see you know if you
press the arrow key you can
see you can see the score
here you see as you change uh several
parameters okay so the vi keyboard the
vi Arrangement is actually slightly
inferior
okay so inverted T is the
best okay that's about you know I went
we went all over but I want to go back
to I haven't started to talk about
um yeah so I want to go back to keyboard
keyboard history
yeah uh keyboard history we talked about
lots of
things so what's what's up guys s why
does your mouse have a trail well I
turned it on so that it's easier to see
when you do live stream if you don't
know what that is let me show you okay
because you zoom us you you zoom us
don't know okay this so in Microsoft You
Can Microsoft again Microsoft is the one
who created this mouse Trail and to this
day today you can turn it on you just go
to uh you know system
settings uh uh mouse keyboard mouse and
uh go
to uh fix Mouse problems change Mouse
options change Mouse options and
you know this Microsoft user interface
is very lousy so but anyway you go to
adjust Mouse and CER size no not here
additional Mouse settings so it's buried
wait uh additional Mouse options okay
it's very [ __ ] confusing idiotic crap
but anyway so this thing so you can see
here pointer options you can see you can
you can you see you can turn it off now
I don't have any trails you can turn it
on now I got Trails you see so this is
Asian this is since
1995 so back in 1995 or you know Windows
3 or something earlier so Microsoft is
the first one who have this
option and it's fairly popular in the
1990s okay but it's still you can still
turn it on but they kind of just hide it
so it's hard to find so soas Trail is
useful when you are doing live
stream okay uh what's that se Rocks park
uh uh Francis
holder SE Rock Park that sell keyboard
no that's not c rock park okay now zumas
don't know but SE Rock Park is one of
the M very famous big
research kind of uh research uh
organization where
Apple borrowed the concept of mouse and
lot and and graphical user interface in
the 1990s so anyway let's see what uh
what what common did I
miss uh is keyboard better than okay so
do you think it's possible do you think
it's possible for a symbolic artificial
intelligence and Leist based AI to
become Bigg again as opposed to machine
learning data driven approach we have
today very interesting question oh you
are Mo I think you are
Mo moo I I oh yeah so the symbolic
artificial intelligence which is I am
very much interested you know so we we
go we going back to the history of
artificial intelligence you know so in
the 1990s I mean in the 1990s 1980s
1970s
they
are you know that's or of artificial
intelligence basically trying to get
machine to have high IQ like a
human uh so back then they focus on
symbolic AI it turns out you know
somehow they focus on symbolic AI so but
then but then today you know since about
10 years ago since about
2010 where the machine learning approach
takes over
so you know we we we can talk about this
without getting into the technical
details what they mean so
basically you know just very extremely
simplified version is that in artificial
intelligence so what what is artificial
intelligence basically they try to make
the machine be as smart as human you
know they can talk like a human they can
play chess or whatever you can ask him
questions anything right so so in the
past 50 years there's or 70 years so
there's many approaches how do you do it
nobody knows and this also ties to prove
mathematics you know if you can get
machine to do physics to prove
mathematics then it's just
fantastic theor improving right so but
anyway many approaches you know we we
like we don't know like it's not like
established like when you go to school
today you learn EST establish calculus
you know calculus linear algebra
differential equations or computer
science algorithms it's like all you
know you just read textbooks but before
but who wrote them you know
so you you need Pioneers that after 100
200 years they create those books right
so for AI is like kind of like that 50
years ago like nobody know what what the
[ __ ] to do so you have many approaches
but so in I think in a extreme
simplified way you can say so one way is
symbolic
computation
uh in so in this approach you basically
create a logical system you know if this
is true then you do this so if this
color is white you know you you first of
all you create a category of all colors
then so what color if you ask the
question what what color is this the
computer will decide you know pass the
word oh color so when you see color it
means you know you look at the database
or the colors then this color is white
black you know you have this colors and
therefore finally because of this pixel
or whatever therefore this is white you
know it just tell you this is this color
is white you know but basically logical
approach you know logic you know lot
like proof you know so that's the kind
of symbolic artificial intelligence
approach then the other approach there's
so many you know basically so today we
have machine learning and statistics uh
neuron networks that's basically
statistics based so when you ask what
color is this thing it doesn't it
doesn't do the logic thing you know it
just it just look at all the English
ever written all the English text ever
written and do statistical analysis so
whenever you see you know you have
occurrence you know the probability of
words occurring what color is this then
it looks at what what the next sentence
say so so so
that so that the AI will just come up
with a
statistical like most likely sentence
that comes what's what color is this so
you can ask AI like you know so it's
kind of like that okay but more more
knows no uh I think if you are more you
know you know more about machine
learning than I do but we can try you
know the Deep infa so let's let's see
the artificial intelligence very
interesting topic okay what color is
computer let's let's say what color is
okay computer yeah let's see what say
you know that's a that's a clever
question computers as in the as in the
physical device can come in variety of
colors depending on the manufacturer
model and design some common colors for
computers include black many laptops and
desktops have a sleek black
exterior very smart silver or
White Aluminum or metallic you know
let's
see what
uh what color is
Sky okay so this is today's machine
learning which become for reasons become
very successful it works you know it
works but the logic approach you know
the symbolic logic approach they failed
you know know there's lots of work so if
you want to see the symbolic approach
that would be um the wolam alpha okay
the wfam Mathematica which is uh what I
was trying to do today so that's a
symbolic approach but if it it doesn't
you know as as as today as of today the
result is not as spectacular as the the
neural network the L language model that
became a thing so the what color is Sky
the color of the sky can appear
differently depending on the time of the
day Atmos
atmospheric conditions and observers
location blah blah blah but in general
the color of the sky can be described as
blue light blue seruan gray or overcast
orang or red okay so let's go to wolam
Alpha so here you we will see a symbolic
approach of artificial intelligence
which the result isn't so great you know
as you know because I tried it so let's
see you know let let me let's ask it
actually we can do it in wolam language
let's ask let's do it in wolam language
so you all you have to say that type the
equal
sign what color is
computer okay let's see what it says
what color is computer
[Laughter]
oh Jesus it's taking it's taking longer
than oh there it is computer definition
computer word
definition computer now machine a
machine for performing calculations
automatically computer noun expert an
expert at calculation or operating
calculating machines okay that's not
what I want I want know what what color
is computer failed okay let's try wolm
Alpha what color is
computer using closest wam alha
interpretation computer assuming
computer is a word used as host
information or referring to Consumer
products or a general topic okay input
interpretation
computer a machine for performing
calculations
automatically and blah blah blah
pronunciation
computer it's not as it's not answering
what I wanted I want to know what color
is it so you see so so that's kind of so
you can see the result so wam alpha or
or mathematic
WF language is uh symbolic artificial
intelligence and
the chat GPT and all that today very
popular is basically
statistics um okay but it turns out you
know the you know this large language
model the neural networks the statistics
space is doing very good today but but
we don't know but you know so the
question is
will is it true can we say for sure that
the symbolic approach is just failed we
don't know yet okay you know in fact it
we we know for sure symbolic approach is
has is not failed because if you ask if
you ask all these chat Parts mathematics
like a question that has very precise
answer they they fail they fail all the
time you know they because it's
fundamentally impossible for them to get
the correct answer while the symbolic
approach can because it can determine it
will determine oh you are asking a
mathematical equation you want to know
the solution for this very precise
equation you know by Logic then then you
it will go to the equation solver and
give you correct answer but meanwhile
the statistics you know the English text
or literature based
it'll just like put out garbage you know
it'll just tell you why it is you
know uh I did a video on
this four month ago five months ago so
we actually showed the example we can
show example easily here but I got other
things to talk about so anyway uh we
digressed a lot and we already talked
for 38 minutes okay so
so what is so uh no the mouse Trail idea
they were the ones to use animations for
things like cursor motion uh
okay okay
uh my and bunch of L machines at his
house oh your old boss has a bunch of
this machines wow Francis holder you
must be a
lisper yeah it seems
like
uh
so so Abdullah say is the guy who did
scip Gerard J sisman six okay
the science and interpretations of
computer programs something like that
has an interesting idea about it they
have a model known as the for goo model
it seems to be closer to a symbolic AI
oh I didn't know uh propagator model
doesn't have much to do with AI I think
what people consider AI okay is
different depending on the time period
okay I remember Alex C Ru saying that it
does have applications for a have you
ever looked at Ur Risco cyc no I don't
know what that is
uh okay we digress into AI so I mean let
let me let me let me go back because I
want to finish what I have done I
haven't I digress so much uh so where
are we so let's see okay so I wanted to
show yeah the keyboard history so you go
to keyboard history but my main thing I
want to say is that you go to the bottom
so I worked on so you have IBM keyboard
history and then you have list machine
keyboards history so you got all the
list machine this is my favorite topic
you know I I dive deep into them you
know to look at what the keys what keys
are there you know that like the symbol
meta Super Hyper control you know the
this machine keyboard and clear input
suspend resume abort
Escape you know so this machine
keyboards then you have uh Microsoft
keyboard which is also big history
because Microsoft and also Microsoft was
was well known for their gaming
keyboards so they did kind of in
innovation in
there uh G but they stopped making
gaming keyboards and I think they they
almost they sto making keyboards I think
I mean ex uh except except this one I
think they still make this one but this
one is pretty good but this is they
stopped this Microsoft sculpt ergonomic
keyboard
2013 so anyway Microsoft history then
you have Apple keyboard history another
giant chapter in keyboards
so you know a lot of people love them
you know they Apple Fans especially but
Apple keyboard usually is no good uh
yeah Apple keyboard is usually no
good uh so you have Apple keyboard
history then you have you know B go to
the bottom Apple laptop keyboard history
so you can see laptop history back from
1989 you know this is uh 1989 laptop
laptop didn't became
popular so laptop became popular around
only 2005 beginning slightly then around
2010 it's more popular than desktop
computer so most people you know want
laptop because they are not computer
professionals but then today it's mostly
just phone you know phone in your pocket
and by the way this keyboard Apple iBook
G4 year 2003 this keyboard is the
keyboard that got me re repetitive strin
injury that made me a
quipper because I was using it
exclusively for 2 years around 2003 to
2005 you know this this computer you
know I have this one so that's that's
when I started to use Microsoft
orgonomic keyboard so the moral here is
never type on a laptop keyboard for long
okay don't do that because you know like
you younger younger people somewh say oh
why do you have problem I don't have a
problem I do it this way my way is
better you you you you're idiotic you
know you you got a problem because you
are you know because I'm superior you
know you like you you'll say that that's
not wait there's a alarm on my phone
emergency alert endangered missing
adversary oh
[ __ ] you know in
California in California you have this
emergency things
endangered missing adversary Santa Clara
County okay some kid is
missing
okay I don't know I haven't seen the kit
so
anyway are we are we are we still going
good so maybe we should finish uh pretty
soon uh let's see Escape it's
annoying okay so are we am I still going
let's
see n people watching okay so keyboards
so let me just go over so Apple keyboard
history then you have ergonomic keyboard
history you can see the first one is the
actually this type writer uh this type
writer this is
um
rainment portable ergonomic typewriter
1935 amazing you know ergonomic
mechanical typewriter
1935 with this symmetric you know just
like just like the
Microsoft ergonomic
keyboard uh yeah so so that's ergonomic
keyboard history and big part of it is
Japanese keyboard the Japanese thumb
shift keyboard
amazing uh you know Japanese TR keyboard
TR keyboard you know TR keyboard is 19
1991 uh you know lots of Japanese
keyboard and this NEC keyboard you know
they have
like six thumb Keys three for each thumb
1990 1980
T3 you know lots of them so anyway so
here is a page of ergonomic keyboards
and uh worth mentioning is you know
today with respect to the zumers the
first one that made ergonomic mechanical
keyboard popular is
2013 beginning with this truly ergonomic
keyboard mass produced that's a key
Point okay mass produced you know you
just go to to you just go to online and
buy it truly ergonomic keyboard that's
my first you know so you can see a video
of me typing on it and then also at the
same year is this ogod
do this is the beginning of do it
yourself keyboard with the 3D printers
you know the we are looking at the
history of uh technology 3D printers
became very popular
2013 okay so this two are kind of the
major milestone in keyboard history in
the in the orgonomic
keyboard Area Community and also in the
doit yourself uh keyboard community so
ever since the ogod dox then you have
like 1,000
others you can see all these doid
yourself create
creativity okay so anyway back to
keyboard history then you have okay so
there's a dedicated page for Japanese
keyboard history and then you have uh
Mouse history so this is the page I
started to work on okay so that's some
of my keyboard updates and also I want
to
uh I wanted to go over my emac update uh
so in the past week I worked a lot so
lots of uh lots of them so but one of
the major thing is this emac lisp how to
write a major mod okay so all these
about 15 pages has been Rewritten in the
past week so you can learn how to write
a emac this major mod for syntax
cling uh what is font lock for comment
you know how to color comment or how to
create a command to do commment how do
you create a command to do keybo keyword
completion uh and so on so writing a
major mod so that's a major update
okay uh and and a lot others okay so you
know and and and a lot other things I
work down
uh yeah and sof flly Keys lots of update
on sof flly keys
uh flag key tutorial and flag Keys
homepage so this is the most efficient
key binding if you are using emac uh so
I kind of update updated them okay
that's
said so n people watching so what what's
up anything
else Nostalgia says hea zoma here what
do you think of key qu Alis Q10 keyboard
I think that's a good one now if I'm not
mistaken
um I think I looked into that keyboard
maybe I have a block let's see uh oo so
you go to ergonomic keyboard
reviews uh so you have this Alice
keyboard so you have this apple maker
cedo okay this is very good I don't have
it so I can't say for sure but for my
analysis I think this is excellent and
uh it's only like $90 you know today
there so many keyboards and they are
pretty cheap okay do I have a Amazon
link no but you can oh there it is okay
buy at Amazon so go to my website if you
want to support me actually if you want
to support me just pay me okay go to my
S uh you should you know instead of
doing oh please subscribe please thumb
up please comment I want to know what
you think [ __ ] you know the the YouTube
the
[ __ ]
wait Control Alt control okay so you
know
the every video every YouTube they say
Please Subscribe and please thumb up let
me know what you think you
know actually they don't care what you
think they just want you to post
comments so so their view video gets
more views but all
this came from the Google scum you know
it's it's good to make money and to
advertise things like that but but
Google became very corrupt so they they
so that's why you know that's why today
you go to YouTube all the like Zoomer
the [ __ ] face
like you know like like drama and
clickbait no real content well a lot of
them have content but they lots of you
know grifting grifting and you know Shi
and all
that so I don't do those please comment
Please Please Subscribe and [ __ ] you
know if you like my
stuff if you appreciate it just pay me
okay so what am I doing okay so I wanted
to just show you my S keyboard page I
mean s. info okay then you go to the
bottom then you just see you know PayPal
patreon Amazon gift card PayPal okay
thank you okay so uh let's go back to
the so you are talking
about uh you are talking about that
keyang adders okay so let's see if I
have
it did I not have have
it uh let's see uh do it yourself no
more Apple maker Apple maker oh I don't
think I have it but I think I've seen it
okay
so so you just go to Amazon Alice
keyboard by the way if you guys don't
know you know why is it called Alice
keyboard very interesting okay because
you know
because the Alice keyboard layout you
know it's called Alice because of the
layout because you see normally you know
for all these keyboard they ergonomic
you know they just go with a grid you
know rectangular grid you know very very
clean and very you know makes sense
because your fingers is not
screwed you know so you know so you have
all this Grid or you
know but
then so for example this is another
example of a symmetric grid because your
hand is not you know like like one hand
bigger or whatever
symmetric and geometric and you have
different variety of designs but then
somebody somebody created this Alice by
the way also for example this one grid
you see grid rectangle tular grid that's
what you need
okay but why why our keyboard are not
like that because for example ultimate
hacking you know they they have this
weird stagger because you know why it's
like that because the keyboard back
then uh keyboard design because the
edotic uh wait where is it keyboard uh
keyboard key binding design special key
ke is design okay there because you see
this article why are keyboard keys not
aligned vertically because back then you
have mechanical devices it's not
computer we don't have computer yet so
you have mechanical
typewriters you need this you see each
key is a hammer you know it's a level
you know you you you press it it hits up
right so you need the level leveler
beneath it and you have some many keys
so each one is a hammer each key is a
hammer so you need to arrange them so
that you you know you you need space to
put all the Hammers together like that
so you can't then you cannot have them
vert vertically aligned that's why you
got this [ __ ] up stag socalled
staggered layout and to this day we
stuck with it because why habit again
habit
okay when when the first computer
keyboard came out they don't need this
you know they don't need this this
mechanical you know we don't need this
we don't have these restrictions anymore
however if you design a keyboard without
this weird stagging people don't want it
because
because you know they are used to the to
the [ __ ] weird you know that thing
that's slanting staggered layout you
know so that is why so that habit okay
idiotic habit like the C programmers
idiots C and Java you know habit
programming applies to programming
languages too and applies to lots of
things Culture Your habit your thinking
and you
know so anyway so that's how you know
the the staggered alignment but then we
have Alice keyboard okay very
interesting Alice Alice layout where did
it go okay so Alice layout okay so let's
go to uh keyboard block uh do it
yourself uh Oro keyboard then we started
to have alas layout so this is
like not exactly regular not symmetric
but no is like you know it's like we
Alice in Wonderland that alludes to
Alice in Wonderland so that's why Alice
they out you know let me tell you the
story about this Alice layout okay in
the beginning so Alice layout first came
out from the do it yourself idiots okay
because all these do it yourself you
know they are they are just you know
they they just create whatever [ __ ] they
you know because they can print it you
know they they can they can do it 3D
printing 3D printing
so I don't know who is the first one who
created this l out but they thought you
know they thought that you know maybe if
you create a you know exact
grid you know that's too too natural you
know it's too it's too regular okay so
so they they they somehow want some kind
of hybrid extremely idiotic okay this
Alice somehow somehow this weird
[ __ ] and but but but but even so this is
back in uh so the first Alice layout
came out around um what year is it 2020
no LZ this one 2017 okay I think this
this is about the first one 2017 someone
you know those St it yourself people
created this you know they somewhat
split but then you know it's it's just
weird Okay alas in
Wonderland then but
today it became good because why let me
show you this okay because you because
Alice layout is not regular okay they
are not
like H I missed all my uh yeah they are
not like they don't have to stick to
this specific staggering okay nor are
they a rectangular gits so there's
no there's no rule to to specify exactly
how you know the exact key Arrangement
but gradually over the years you see
when this when this apple maker from
China they created lless layout so if
you look at the right side there is less
staggering than the than the traditional
keyboard and also similarly for the for
the left hand so in other words you can
say that they they gradually actually
they become grid layout so it makes
those people who don't like grid layout
adapt switch to great layout so this is
secret secret methodology to get you
switch so I like it
okay so that's the evolution of Alice
because because you can look at this
clear closely okay look look at look at
this Arrangement on the right side and
also on the left side carefully you can
you can compare to uh for example a
regular grid uh let's say
normal okay for so if you compare
to you know for example if you you can
you can then
compared so they have less less stagger
okay the ls layout okay that's maybe
that's it for
today rambled a lot so I haven't U Been
coding wolam language I was going to
code a wol language
uh do I ever hang out on G no I don't
but I do check it regularly you know the
full Chan the full Chan
crowd I've never ever posted foran you
know foran is got history of its own so
in the 19 in in the 2000s for for begin
in
something it was like really you know
really something special different and
uh uh today it's like
um anyway anyway I don't I
don't I I don't uh read forchan but I do
regularly search my name on
forchan so I kind of am aware of of of
all the forun people uh talking about me
so for example they
created they created some of the images
this
one emac
emac uh and and there's more okay so
this that when then they they they
created this you know fortime people
idiotic Zoomers like teenagers like
idiot like they they they
like they go there it's just like drio
like the worst drier like you don't know
who they are nobody knows who you know
you just go there and fart what what's
the point I mean do you I guess it's
fun I mean but you don't
it's not um you waste your time you just
waste your time you know you have to
understand you see foran by now is older
than you okay foran begin let's say
2004 I mean 2004 so by now it's 20 years
so foran is older than you for you
younger people watching okay you you
have to realize that so all these years
there are people
who maybe your dad's age okay who grew
up with
fortun you have seen you know you seen
the conversations you know some of them
got tired of
forun and anyway it's there's a history
to it okay
so you know when maybe when you are 13
when you are 14 you find forun fun you
know it's just like oh [ __ ] you no you
you know just like trival like you don't
make any sense okay but then
but you know when you are 14 14 15 maybe
that's fun but then you go up a little
bit older that's no longer fun you just
waste your time
okay and but there's there is some smart
people on forun you know
anyway okay I think that's it for today
so uh did I talk about other the things
I want to talk not really actually I was
going to do some wolan language coding
so we talking about symbolic artificial
intelligence I was going to work on H
let's forget
it um so anything else I think we shut
down we shut down in 3 minutes three
minutes
okay who who who else is watching you
know I've been inspired so I only have
10 people watching not many you know
but you know I've I've been thinking you
know how
how you know the popularity you know
I've been I have been watching
chatterbate for about two or three
months now since I discovered
it uh I find it incredibly amazing and
I've have also been inspired by it you
know this girls you know uh young girls
you know 18 19 20 and also a lot olders
they go there spread their
legs daily you know some of them been
doing it for years I
guess uh and what they do exactly just
chatbate chat and masturbate like this
is completely naked and you they they do
all kind of things okay
girls and in in and specific
young girls okay they are older and they
are trans and they are guys too but gay
gay and you know but but they they go
they go live stream you know young girl
and all over the world it's not just
like oh just white girls you know the
you you have like almost basically all
girls around the world they go there you
and so that gives me inspiration about
the nature of video and where
we are going Humanity like for example I
am doing live stream so basically the
same it's just the you know I'm talking
about programming and they are doing you
know the other
things but I'm doing live stream it's
the same it's you know live
stream technology so so I mean so so so
one of the things I I I see is that they
you know they go so it's not like
like I I talked about in the in in the
past two video too there's a difference
is a change
of how live stream or video
technology their role in society so for
example 10 years
ago video is such that when you for
example if you are a professor you know
you're doing a great lecture on how do
you learn wolam language or iMac
right you think you create one you know
great lecture you know you focus you
prepare it then people watch but today
that's not the case because you have 1
million people doing live stream every
day including great
professors so you don't need it's like
you don't need you don't you don't you
don't need like carefully prepared like
one good tutorial on emac or on keyboard
or
whatever because it it it the the the
live stream technology becomes so
common so that's that you know that's
one of the inspiration I got from
chatbate you
know hello empty grocery
bag I found you by random stream in my
recommended list oh incredible
amazing enjoy the rant about
zumas fantastic thank you okay I think
that's it for
today anything else okay uh shut
down oh too bad I didn't talk about math
uh okay today but so let me just put the
link to my blog for example here's
today's talk show let me just post link
here uh so we have a record of what we
talked about oh there's already a link
to that here hyperbolic trick function
this is amazing okay so if you know
trigonometry you know you have S cosine
tangent
cotangent you know but then you have
hyperbolic hyperbolic trick functions
okay uh we have to talk about this
another another day this is
mathematics okay so land of thisp you
know look at this this these are the
things forchan people created it's and
it's quite creative too you see they
they
collage they made a collage of the of
the most famous or inFAMOUS lisp
people not necessarily the the the
people with the
greatest
accomplishment of lisp in human history
not necessarily so but but rather the
the the kind of more more famous or
notorious for example I'm included
[Laughter]
here and you know and so you know for
example I this is a this blogger this is
a emac Lis blogger Paul grham closure
creator of course Richard stowman and uh
McCarthy the creator of lisp and that
guy that guy I always forgot that's
that's oh how aberson okay then you have
guy steo guy steo is great great guy
then you have ER Eric nagam also here
he's a big Troll he's like known kind of
like known as you know he's he's known
as a
TR uh you know so quite you know it's
creative as as far as you know his
create creativity create
this uh laptop keyboard okay we didn't
talk about much about that why are
keyboard keys not aligned vertically
okay it's
a that okay close and uh this staggered
keyboard uh Alice keyboard layout we
talked about Alice keyboard
layout amazing truly ergonomic keyboard
okay well I mean by the way the trud
this one is not good okay this cleave
keyboard um yeah Alice keyboard layout
oh your question about that that
particular one
from uh from who I forgot this but I was
going to we are we were going to search
it uh Apple maker no
the this keyboard they are this one oh
yeah keyang you see the the problem is
is Kyon is very expensive you see
$200 meanwhile this this I considered
great Apple maker $90 so
$90 but the
key you know the the keyong is
like uh here
$200 but I guess the difference is that
they made it programmable I think uh
where is it
okay here so key oh you it's turn on
JavaScript I think uh so my opinion of
this is uh yeah I would you know I would
I think it's good I think it's good
okay uh slighty expensive I suppose you
know I mean I I think it they they sell
it more expensive than necessary because
you see you see this Al you see because
if you
compare
uh if you compare this apple maker the
one on my page okay I want to show the
one on my
page if you compare this apple maker
cedo you see they even have a display on
the side and it's only
$90 you got a display on the side and a
knob but then if you buy the KY kuang
which is American made but probably made
in China too but American brand you $200
you you pay twice as expensive but what
what what benefit do you get I
mean you know but I mean that's $100
more uh you know I don't I know if it's
really worth
that anyway that's uh okay bye guys