good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
[Music]
today is 2021
february 16th by the way i have
cross-eyed so that's why i put this
patch kind of oops
so it's just a piece of paper let me
show you so it's just a piece of paper
you see
so i put this on my eye cross side
you know i can get to use it for a while
but you know i feel like putting this on
for now
so today is 2015 2021 february 6
6 and san francisco time
uh two o'clock and we have a lot to talk
about fantastic uh by the way am i
alive i'm live audio check video check
and
say hi guys and we have a lot to talk
about we're going to talk about
emac lists and keyboards maybe some
and mostly i'm going to talk about
mathematica
okay fantastic mathematica so first of
all i want to ask you is my video going
okay so this is my new gaming machine
is my video going okay and is my audio
going okay
type in the chat box okay
am i on is my video
going and the
audio going okay
fantastic video audio good check thank
you guys
luis you know right now i have 10
concurrent viewers fantastic who are you
guys
and good morning break the loop thank
you break the
loop uh fantastic you know i realized pc
on a pc is fantastic it's much better
than uh
on the mac when you use obs because then
all of a sudden
the headphone or the uh logitech camera
works better of course besides i have a
better machine now
so uh i guess i'm going to start with
uh emac list a little bit let me show
you this
fantastic chopstick
ergo chopstick keyboard you know this
guy
you know he's he's an emacs user so
emacs user oh and he suffers from the
pen
of the pinky so he's a life hacker
so he devised these chopsticks
you know so that he can press using the
thumb keys
to press the modifiers the ctrl alt
shift [ __ ] band key chords
okay i have article on that just search
for
band key chords and you'll find it you
should not
you you know if you can try to avoid
using any key chords
buy a programmable uh keyboard
and so on okay so so let's start
and so this is my talk show page back to
emacs
so if i'm doing anything wrong that is
my audio went out or something you can
see my text too small or something say
it okay because
this is the first time i'm on this
machine streaming
i haven't been streaming for a month so
you see comment this
section out one key press and show in
browser so we don't see the
duplication of the image background we
already talked about that's today's
video
so uh so what have you guys
heard you heal good man hey good morning
you a good man now you a good man
you know the he is a common list coder
i i do remember and we chatted a little
bit
uh several years ago commonly skoda
right so
introduce yourself actually i last time
you told me you work for
you know a certain place i don't know if
i should say that but
um let's switch to vim
good audio good okay so so let's uh yeah
let's start to con
let me let me start to do uh things okay
uh
things so let's see uh what do i want to
do is
uh first so we have emac list
coding uh actually i have a lot i want
to talk about mostly today about
uh mathematica oh the fantastic
the wolfram research saturn stefan
wufang the certified genius
he's truly a genius certified actually
because
when he's like 19 years old he won
mcarthur
award with a monetary prize you know one
of the most press
teachers awards given to young people in
sciences you know he's
so he's by the time he's 19 he's already
got a phd
degree in physics and already published
you know
10 articles also on particle physics i
i don't like physics myself i don't know
much about physics but
and and i have some connection with
uh stefan wufang because you know in
1995 25 years ago we met
and he liked me so he always i think he
he
always liked uh he find he he think i'm
smart okay so
uh i'm grateful for uh
for that and and he's um
you know i am doing something from
him you know first of all i'm going to
be i'm going to be
a peddler for his uh stuff mathematica
but i'm going to show you but
but he is one of the guy i truly admire
among the programmer
among the computer scientists or
entrepreneurs you know for example uh
for entrepreneurs i like steve jobs that
steve jobs i have always admired
you know i couldn't say there are many
such people for example
google google's founders i don't care
much about them you know
larry and paige you know those two
people i don't
i don't give a [ __ ] i don't care about
much of them in fact many of these
uh billionaires i despise
bill gates for example i don't care too
much i don't i don't hate bill gates
like like a lot of you uh linux open
source unix people do
i don't find bill gates uh hateful i
think he's
okay person okay uh and the the you know
there
and facebook the mark zuckerberg is he's
a scum
he's a scumbag of human animals
and the traitor ceo the jack dorsey you
know these
these these people are very very rich
you know billionaires
so he is also a scum treated uh
ceo jack dorsey and for example let's
talk
let's say some other example uh you know
amazon
uh bozo you know the amazon ceo the
founder
that guy i i haven't found
you know i don't know much about him and
i don't
um i think i i don't know much about him
but i think he's okay person
and elon musk by the way elon musk you
know the founder of tesla
he's a fantastic he's another guy i
respect i highly respect
you know when when you have these people
the the super rich people
i you know my because of my personality
or my habit or whatever i look at them
you know i look at them in my own way so
i look at that what what they've done
what's their personalities like you know
uh and i judge i make a judgment you
know to see if i like them i find them a
good person so
elon musk i admire actually yes i
elements i also admire but
for example another contrast in contrast
to
jack ma you know jack ma is the china
billionaire running
alibaba and you know uh online um
social media alibaba that that guy i
think is idiotic okay
jack ma but er so elements i really
admire steve jobs i do admire
but steve jobs um and there's there are
differences between these people elon
musk is a
nerd he's a true nerd you know like me
elon musk and you know he's you know he
studied math and stuff
uh on the other hand steve jobs i also
admire but he's not
a nerd he's not you know he doesn't know
much about math or
programming actually but he do see
things you know he see you know see he
he truly see what people need
you know and he's a great uh you know
businessman a market
marketer a salesman on the uh uh
and and and stefan wufon i truly admire
as well i truly admire
us in particular because he is a you
know he's a physicist
you know since he's a t he was a teen
and
the way and he you know he created
mathematica he
he wrote it in c and c plus plus you
know mathematica
is one of the greatest programming
language i uh admire
you know it is truly the greatest
language beyond you know by a magnitude
beyond all others beyond you know
haskell
magnitude beyond it's not just oh it's
better okay
no mathematical is not just better it's
like a magnitude beyond haskell [ __ ]
okay mathematic mathematica okay so
actually so
let's let me skip emac list because if
i'm going to talk about emacs list
you know emac list coding we have done
that many times
so i'm going to skip emac this and let's
just talk about mathematica
uh wolf and research so i admire the guy
very much and he's
the way he um he view things
especially you know in general the way
he views things
i is in agreement with me
or in other words my the way i view
things uh
often uh you know in the same way as he
does and especially in
uh in computing when it comes to
programming languages the design of
programming languages
the naming of programming language you
know function names for example
uh very often i agree
with stefan wolfham the way he sees
things i've read
quite a lot of his stuff since since
1990s
on the other hand let me give you a
contrast on the other hand
donald glute you know this is the guy
donald glute there needs this guy most
of you will find
will drivel about you know you love his
stuff oh
la tech oh yeah uh literal programming
crap you know that donald glue that you
know
of course he's also a great he's a
mathematician donald trump and he's a
great
you know expert one of the top experts
in this century among programming among
computer scientists
but however donald glute you know his
writings these things i
read yeah they are valuable but they
they they are not
my type okay i don't like i don't
uh i don't admire him in particular
you know in particular but stefan wufab
very much
uh and okay so so what are we so
questions um mathematica
is free to run so let me tell you about
mathematica how do you get it for free
okay so actually it is free today so
uh yeah let's start talking about
mathematica
how long have i been talking uh
let's see where is the date here and
here let's see
average watch time playback uh chat rate
concurrent viewers okay let's see
uh where is the time okay i always
okay check check the obs so i've been
talking for 12 minutes okay so
let me talk about uh mathematica first
so
while there are 18 people here first of
all let me show you guys
how to get it for free that's the thing
everyone wants the most okay
so you go to saudi website you just
search for saudi mathematica okay go to
my programming language page
my programming blog and page down
you will see these okay so okay it's not
here you
go to click on programming language
tutorials and click on mathematica
okay so this this is the logo of
mathematica
uh version three of version two
and this this uh yeah so i started to
program in mathematica
since 1993 okay at that time it's
version two not three i made a mistake
on twitter
so anyway 1993 i started to program in
mathematica
uh that was mathematical version two and
each for each version of mathematica
they have a new
logo so this is version 2 logo and to
this day i find the version 2 logo the
most beautiful
so these are the mathematical notebooks
you know the programming
code i've written in 1990s most of them
most of them around 1995 to uh
to uh to year 2k
so i want to show you actually all i
want to show you is this
uh this page okay this is a raspberry
if you buy it mathematica comes with it
bundled free
okay and it's not [ __ ] where it's
like the full
complete version of mathematica bundled
with uh
uh raspberry pi so you go to my website
and click the link
buy it on amazon make jeff bozo
rich okay we help the people
help the world you know to be a become a
better place
you make him rich and he in turn will
make uh you know the world
the rich people will make the world a
better place for you
so that's one way to get mathematica
raspberry pi for free
and then but there's more okay so
so there is more of course uh let's go
to
let's go back to my uh
my talk show page so i want to talk yeah
so let's go to this link
launching today free wolfram engine for
developers
is actually for everyone so you go you
know
i'm going to have links on my you know
just search for it launching
you know free wolfram engine just search
for that
so you'll find the link to download it
of course you need to register you know
give your email and you know whatever
but it's free and let me show you a
and again this is this is not [ __ ]
ware okay
actually uh you cannot plot graphics or
audio
you know mathematica is mathematica it's
a programming language but it's beyond
that it's a magnitude beyond that
because it's a
you know if you read stefan wufang stuff
you know by the way stefan wufang he's a
known megalomaniac
a lot of uh top mathematicians and you
know physicists
hate him despise or hate him because
he's a magno
megalomania because you know i did
everything
he he think he's you know the best of
them all
including you know einstein or whatever
he thinks he's the best
but he's truly a genius he's a money
so anyway so so if you read his stuff
when he talk about mathematica he will
say oh yeah this is the greatest
inventions
since human human animal existed um
well i'm not sure that is true
i mean well you know it's hard to say
but i
but i truly i do agree that mathematica
is one magnitude beyond
or you know i'm not
kissing ass here it's it is a magnitude
beyond all
programming languages like haskell or
whatever whatever
crap it's a magnitude so so how do i
characterize so why is it why do i think
mathematica is the magnitude beyond okay
so in in normal programming languages
like you know let's say high school
i love to make fun of haskar because
haskell is this
cool thing every every nodes will talk
about it in every sentence
how do you like in windows 10 uh okay
that's another topic i
you know i can i'm i'm going to talk
non-stop about that topic
you know the user interface design of
metro in fact i have written quite a few
articles recently about the windows 10
interface i'm not going to go into okay
so you
i mean you can see them if you just go
to stop programming blog
and for example user interface design um
issues okay i talked about that
that x11 crap linux
thing okay then i tell you how do you
judge
user interface what is valuable what is
not
then you have you know the microsoft
metro
which is a flat
[ __ ] uh it's very bad okay
uh windows 10 metro you know these you
have these
design gurus you know clean cut boys on
stage
you know in some microsoft conference or
windows 10 conference you know they're
gonna tell you oh
we designed it this way because yeah
it's a [ __ ] crap
okay that's that's about windows 10 you
know about the interface the interface
is
really bad and windows okay anyway i'm
not going to talk about that
let's go back to talk about mathematica
so how do i characterize
mathematica as a programming language
why do i say it's a magnitude beyond
uh beyond you know haskell or lisp or
scheme
or java or php or ruby python you know
all these
magnitude beyond so first of all it's a
so you know i'm going to start to teach
you
actually about some you know
mathematical as a language
as a category of language for example
one of the characteristics
of haskell you know each language
usually
they have their personality so has got
for example
their characteristic is like pure
functional programming
where you don't have states you cannot
even assign
you know change the value of a variable
variable it's not you know the
programming language simply does not
allow that this meaning is impossible
it's impossible to change a variable
in haskell because it's a you know pure
functional language so that's
the characteristics of haskell on the
other hand let's say
uh pearl you know pearl so you can go to
my website for a tutorial pro
pro uh programming language overview i'm
an expert of pearl because i programmed
pearl in a day job in the dot-com days
for four years
writing uh you know payment gateway
that's when you swipe visa you know on
amazon or whatever
you know the uh east online store
we began it in fact you know anyway
that's history okay so i
actually i wrote part of the uh gateway
uh module you know in perl so people can
swipe
credit cards and you know get your money
so pearl
so what is the characteristic of pearl
you know of course
you might know you don't you don't know
if you are younger pearl the
characteristic
is uh you know they go by slogans there
are more than one way to do it
and the syntax is like uh crap you know
and they are proud of it you know that's
their characteristic the pro
you know that more than one way to do it
and
impossible to read syntax and they they
are part of it you know they say
there's more than one way there are 100
ways to write the same thing
pearl and the larry wall uh
anyway let's skip that uh because we i
want to talk about mathematica so
i i gave you kind of a one
sentence characteristics of haskell
then you have also seen how i described
pearl
then uh then ruby uh how do you describe
ruby
is you know according to matt's the guy
who created ruby he would say
uh he would say make programming fun
again you know what does that mean
because a lot of this language they they
all think they are actually making
programming fun
you know pearl said that uh python
uh i i'm not sure um
you know some some python people have
said that you know they
they say yeah but every language you
know almost
many of them not all you know closure
for example would also
uh claim that somewhat and anyway so
so what is the characteristics of ruby
ruby so
i would say it's uh ruby is simply a
better pearl
okay in in short ruby is just a better
pearl
you don't have this garbage syntax you
have a consistent
and actually very elegant syntax ruby
and very um you know very easy to do
stuff very easy to learn very easy to
understand
ruby is a better pearl
and python python
the the best way to characterize python
is
computer science are us uh i don't like
python
so so python you know
for example one of the most um uh
mentioned characteristic of python is uh
indentation right
um anyway python you know so how do i
characterize python python is like a
scripting language with a penchant
for formality why because the guy guido
von russom you know i did a video talk
about guido
uh yeah so because the guy he's kind of
you know kind of awesome he's a
mathematician
background but he he has kind of the
formality kind of guy
you know every time he writes he you
know you can smell it this is a certain
formality so and guy
and he he python community tends to be
uh you know they they they think
computers
they think they are computer science you
know like computer science
are skype python crap i don't like
python
and java on the other hand what's what
how do i characterize java java is
the suits java is the you know the
people with ties you know the people
with things
and java is the from the java is the
enterprise
computing you know when you are serious
about computing
financial stuff or whatever servers you
know massive server that's java
that's why google you know google is
written in java
uh most yeah google java and python is
google's
language of choice so and and java is no
fun you know
so you might heard for for from
uh pearl programmers or python
programmers or ruby programmers they
love it or you know
but few you will get few people say that
about java
because java code coders they tend to be
enterprise like the
like like the um
like the rich hickey you know the
creator of closure he is from the java
background he or you know he or he does
is enterprise programming
the most boring and he created closure
uh so how do i characterize closure
closure is basically uh
uh you might say a modern lisp okay and
the traditional the classic whispers
like common these
and schema scheme skim this they
many of them big lease fanatics
they don't consider closure to be at
least they consider closure to be the
the bastard they don't like closure
because why
because closure you know on
depending on your point of view so
closure is a lisp
but they changed some things that's
fundamental that's
that's fundamental to lisp for example
cons
you know closure in closure you don't do
cons anymore
instead of you have the interface of the
java thing
to create list or sequence or or you
know
you know you you go by interface you
don't go by
cons you know in this if you don't know
this
this is made of cards consoles you
nesting consoles that's that's a
that's a history of this so anyway i
gave i gave some characterization of
these languages and for example
javascript
javascript is javascript is a
abomination abomination from netscape
created in one week and it's still one
of the worst languages today
despite great
changes over the especially over the
past 10 years
so anyway that's the characteristics of
you know and at least
what is the characteristic of this for
yeah it's
that's easy parentheses okay first of
all all you see is parentheses
okay so let me show you uh soft like
keys
so this is so you are looking at
microsoft like keys code parentheses
parenthesis here okay so i need to go up
a lot so
so you can see the full glory of
parenthesis
except you know that's this is emac this
you are looking at
so that's one of the characteristics of
lisp but besides that this
the other thing so the uh core elements
of lisp language
you know this is a family there's many
of them so
the few core elements are parentheses
you know nested parentheses for the
syntax
and symbolic okay in this everything is
a symbol
so for example uh i don't know if i can
show you that
uh anyway it's a symbol okay
it's yeah that that's you know i talked
about that
before i have yes uh
okay nested parenthesis symbolic
and uh um
and there's also list reader okay this
is more advanced
i'm not going to explain now i did
before lisp reader
then then this macro basically these
four things i would say
and and functional programming okay
necessary parenthesis
symbolic uh reader list
reader uh lisp
marker and
and the function programming that's the
characteristics of lisp
okay now listen to what i say this is
these
hear my words okay when you read other
people these people they will tell you
crap okay i can tell you right away you
know because i've been arguing with
these people
for 20 years if you want to give the
you know like the topic comes up often
like
you know when these languages come up
they will ask
you know when ruby is hot they will say
is ruby the new list
i mean when pearl came up people you
will often hear programmers say
is is pearl the the distant right or is
pearl the modern days
you know you hear people say that
idiotic
opinions truly idiotic and then when
when ruby became very popular back in uh
2007 because the ruby on rails
then people will say we are you will
hear a lot of programmers say
oh ruby ruby is a lisp done right
or something like that that you know you
lube is ruby at least
actually if you just type search that is
ruby at least
it's pearl at least you will find a ton
of articles
uh back in the 2000s uh
so we are talking about the culture of
programming languages you know
i'm giving you a historical uh
view of it so uh so i gave the
characteristic
uh characteristics of this the language
uh and we've done that for the so so
what about mathematica so
yeah so the characteristics of
mathematica and why is it why do i think
it's a magnitude better than
other languages so first of all let me
tell you what's what what are the
characteristics of mathematic
mathematica uh that's pretty easy
mathematica is based on two
the foundation the the nature of
mathematica the programming language is
based on two
it came from two programming languages
one is
lisp okay so in fact
some people can see the mathematica a
lisp
you know so mathematical came from two
languages
one lisp one apl
okay i i do have apr code somewhere uh
star d apl if you don't know if you
haven't seen
uh i have it somewhere uh
okay so maybe we search for sardi apr
okay
so there it is there it is
open there it is open so we have three
pages
i you know so one of the thing i don't
like about
windows is that when you full screen
there are actually several mods
you know one is the f11 full screen and
you don't even see your tabs anymore
okay
the other way is windows up arrow
this is maximize window that's another
you know version of full screen it's a
problem because then you
you there's no one single key you can
toggle like i cannot
toggle it back if i want to go back
you have to say restore you know like
for you know you have to say restore
the window size or window key
down arrow so window key of arrow full
screen window key down arrow restore
if you press down arrow one more time by
mistake it
[ __ ] disappears stupid windows design
you know the design issues
so anyway back to so let me show you
okay my articles on apr
language so you are looking at this uh
you are looking at the symbols
of apr so yeah that's the
you know api is another one of the uh
programming language with lots of
fanfare and laws because it's strange
so you have you know you have lisp
keyboard with ap out
this is the original ibm apr keyboard
then you also have the list space cadet
keyboard with
apr symbols on it but however they are
the layout is different so anyway
api is another language invented by to
do math okay lisp
and ap are both invented to do math
so apl is what you call array array
based programming language which is
uh you know matlab is similar you know
anyway
i want to go back to talking about
mathematica so comments
uh ipa so what
uh so what are you guys saying am i
doing all right
so i failed to read the comments
actually there are not many comments
okay so how long have i been talking uh
i'm still talking yes and i've been
talking for
32 minutes okay not too bad
am i doing good so apr okay so
mathematica came from two languages
apl and lisp
so but not of course not not just from
of course then the other part is based
on pattern
uh uh pattern matching and term
rewriting
that's the stefan wolfe and his own id
idea
okay so mathematica so what is the
characteristic of
mathematica one it's like lisp okay
it's like lisp uh you have lots of
nested you have
what's called full form i i have
articles on it but
i don't want to show it because i want
to just uh
talk the things i want to talk about
but you know yeah you know maybe i
should show you guys since i'm talking
about that full form
anyway the focus is not about
technical details right now let me just
go on
okay so mathematica it came from lisp
and apl so it shares many of these two
languages characteristics
for example it's also full fully nested
brackets okay
the entire syntax is fully necessary
brackets
and it's also symbolic just like lisp
symbols you deal with symbols symbolic
computation that's one of the things
stephen wolfham likes to mention all the
time
oh mathematica is the greatest thing
since sliced red
because it's symbolic it's you know it
can represent anything
you know that's what stephen wolfe likes
to say so
so from lisp it borrowed the nested
syntax
purely regular more actually more
regular than this
okay and then any list you know maybe
commonly
skinned this image or racket
or the closure it's it's fewer
purely nested at least by the way
mccarthy
called m-form metaphor okay anyway
so nested syntax uh and symbolic
okay mathematica and uh it also has a
list reader in mathematica okay reader
and it also have markers in fact the
entire language is a macro
okay so many lispers they they don't
know you know
the common list for phonetics they think
oh marco is the greatest thing
but the mathematica the entire language
is the [ __ ] is is [ __ ] macro
this was don't know because mathematica
is so then it comes
pattern symbolic pattern matching okay
remember
the word symbolic pattern matching you
might have heard of pattern matching
from the haskell people you know
functional programming people they all
say oh panda magic
or camel people but
they are sim their pattern matching is
or even
even in javascript pattern matching is
coming to javascript
guys but their pattern imaging is
different because
mathematica is symbolic pattern matching
that's a significant difference
so when you have symbolic pattern
matching uh
then your the whole language becomes uh
uh at least micro the whole entire
language almost
like when you see mathematica code i'm
going to show you
i'm going to start to show you you know
i'm going to code mathematica i'm going
to show you
uh demonstrate mathematica but not today
i haven't i haven't downloaded yet
so symbolic pattern matching that that
just means the whole language
you you just like you just write marcos
all day
like more half of your code is writing
about ready
marcos that's what that's a practical
way to put it okay
the the the you know the the common
these
idiots phonetics because i've been
arguing with them for 10
for 10 years mostly in year 2000s
so pattern matching so so that's some of
the characteristics of mathematica
from the lisp side now from the ap
outside what you get is array
programming okay
now now most industrial programmers you
don't know what the [ __ ] is array
programming
like because you let's say let's say you
program in java
let's say you program in perl you you
also are expert in php
and let's say you also know python full
well
let's say you also are the inventor of
ruby
let's say you also know c and c plus
plus been coding them for
100 years and you know all these
languages
you know but you you don't know a [ __ ]
about array programming what is array
programming because that idea doesn't
exist
in all these uh industrial languages you
know including gold land
including rust gross is one of the
one of the pop thing you know everyone
wants to know what do you think of rust
because it's actually
learn rust okay so
uh so
so back to the characteristic
mathematica so so
from apr mathematica mathematica
you can't you you know borrowed or
inherited
the array programming so what what does
that mean
i can explain one sentence okay normally
when you
in many of these languages especially
today you have a map function
right you have an array or a list then
you can map
a function to all elements of the list
okay
now what if your list is nested
nested list for example a matrix you
know or a tree
yeah you can also map but they'll be
hard you know in all these languages
they don't have functions to do it
in in this they have somewhat okay
so basically array language is that you
don't even have map anymore when you
apply a function to a list
it automatically maps to every element
okay
that is what array languages means every
function or most function or operator
when their arguments are
are lists or usually almost always
they are either list or nested list
which includes
matrix or tree the function
automatically maps
you know applies to all elements in the
list or array
or tree or matrix okay that's the
essence that's the meaning of array
programming languages so mathematica is
like that
that's inherited from apl okay apr
and also matlab matlab is like that in
general
math oriented programming languages or
have that feature because you have to
deal with
matrix all the time and also let me
mention
in this math oriented language the array
always start with one
okay not zero mathematicians start their
array with what the [ __ ] stupid
programming
idiots because all the programmers see
especially
with the unix and c background they'll
say oh
because zero is you know they on one
hand they admire
mathematics meanwhile they don't know
nothing about mathematics
so when the topic about whether a race
should be
begin with zero or one comes up you know
this
not you know the industrial programs
programmers always always tend to say
oh they should start with zero because
zero is actually
more mathematical but actually
it's nothing is nothing far away
you know from a mathematician math
mathematicians languages their arrays
start with one
i have article on that just search for
you know should already start with
zero or one you know uh put my name on
it you'll find it
so i'm talking about the characteristic
of mathematic
mathematical language so so
uh so i give you you know several
elements
now besides that it also it does
mathematics you know for example
integral you know integ
integrator
you know for for example if you are a
scientist you know scientists engineers
you know you do
by biological engineering you do
industry you know you build buildings
you build bridges you build
you you do chemistry or you do drugs you
know
the chemistry you know pharmaceutical uh
pharma
pharmaceutical industry or space
industry you you know
like elon musk sending people to the to
mars
so if you are a scientist or uh or
or not you know or engineer you know in
these fields you need a lot to do a lot
of math
so for example then you will need in you
know you will need to do integration
right
yeah not this one [ __ ] this is new
so the first choice okay and not
not here so uh
yeah okay so they they change anyway so
here you can do an integral of uh
no not this page and [ __ ] i forgot
what's the url
doctor go
so anyway you you can find it you know
in in a minute
uh you can go there and oh oh you
actually you can also use woofing off of
my fire also does that you you know
intel you can integrate
you know math math expressions or
functions
so anyway what i'm saying is that
mathematica allows you to do
a huge tremendous like a thousand also
math functions
many of these functions opiodine like
unlike
industrial programming languages for
example in
in python when you need to do regular
expression you need to load a library
you know the same thing with golan same
thing with uh
uh
you know in a lot of languages because
they they partition you know
like when you need to walk in your
directory you also need to
load a library called system usually you
know in python
in ruby in golan just about every
language
but mathematica is not like that it more
has the nature of lisp
where you this you know where everything
is just
included you don't load libraries like
the
like out of the box mathematica has by
now 6 000
functions okay 6 000 functions
you know you just you just do it you
just run it you don't load the library
you don't know
you don't have to oh which library
should i load to
to traverse a directory or do regular
expression or do math or
you know do graphics you know you don't
have to it's like the full things there
so anyway i be i started to ramble uh
i haven't get to the point why is
mathematica a magnitude
uh beyond all the existing languages
well because so so mathematica does all
mathematics that's what i'm trying to
say
you know in the past five minutes you
know you can solve equations
linear algebra you know in systems of
equation or
anything anything that's possible with a
computer mathematica
does as well as current
current technology allows and
so that's one thing okay solve
math equations now when you add that
you can already see all these industrial
languages
none of that none of them do it you know
haskell
can can you can haskell do an integral
no
can can golan do that no can this do
that no
can uh per php python no not nothing
javascript no they cannot even have
they maybe you need to know let load the
library you know some third party
uh you know people wrote it but anyway
so mathematica so the ability to do math
solve equations is part of mathematica
so that by itself you know since 30
years ago
that's a that's the that's the purpose
of mathematica that's why it's called
mathematica
originally it by by you know now
after 30 years it has expanded a lot but
anyway
let's say 30 years ago mathematica is
uh is in in a way is already beyond most
industrial languages because industrial
language is not meant to do that
but that's but that's not my point okay
so
there are other tools that do that for
example
matlab does that uh mostly numerically
and you know there are a few other
competitor
competitors competing competitions you
know uh
maple for example these are in general
in general called computer
algebra systems so mathematica is one of
them but however okay
so mathematica does mathematics
are you guys still here we are we have
27 people watching
are there uh comments
comments okay let me know if i'm alive
and i'm talking
uh so i'm trying to give
the i'm trying to tell you why it's
mathematical uh magnitude beyond so it
does math okay
and other other programming language
does math too but
then mathematica is um
is kind of a knowledge base of all known
algorithms
for example when you when you have
algorithm in other languages you have to
write it you know it maybe
take you few hours or maybe a few days
but in mathematica
as you know every algorithm
if it's practical and useful
to have it mathematica has it okay
it spilled in so uh can i give you some
examples
no because right now you know i haven't
been i haven't been coding mathematica
for
for 15 to 20 years so i cannot give you
i you know and i don't have mathematica
right now i'm going to install it
and i'm going to uh demonstrate pretty
soon
okay that's i i i spent 10 minutes
trying to
tell you why mathematica is a magnitude
better than
others so now i guess
so now i guess let's see what i wanted
to talk about and
maybe i should wrap up or see what you
guys
are saying and answer some questions uh
so first of all i've been talking for
47 minutes okay that's already long long
rambling so
so you know where to get mathematica so
right so first of all
go buy a raspberry pi that is bundled
with mathematica okay
then or you go to the wolfram website
and javascript is available not
available on twitter
you go to the wolfram website
then you can download it okay wolfram
engine
search for it so that's another way to
get mathematica
free uh you know the
uh almost the full version except you
don't have graphics
uh then oh actually what you should do
is you should you should
actually simply go buy it because it's
because it's not too expensive
okay uh
what what's going on with my keyboards
what
oh okay i thought my
ultimate hacking is not working so let
me show you my
again you see
so this is my connect by the way this is
new i
i think i showed it last time this is
kinesis
you see kinesis advantage lf
this is a linear red switches cherry mx
red i bought a
new one my old one
you can see well i showed it before so
anyway so that's my
this is my ultimate hacking keyboard i
use it to
you know it's all macros
so what are we doing now so i want to
show you
some of uh what are we doing now i'm
going to read comments
and yeah uh so
in the past few you know uh two weeks a
week
yeah so wolfram
will find research okay you go to their
website
wolfram computation means uh something
something
computation means knowledge you know
that's stephen wolfram's marketing term
computation means knowledge okay so you
click
you know you go to product and services
you know they have quite a few products
now
so i would actually just recommend you
go to mathematica okay
you so you go to mathematica and you
uh then there is a pricing
so if you are a student it's very cheap
you know it's only two hundred dollars
you know 166 you know
you go buy it and download it on your
desktop
you know it's two gigabytes so it takes
a while so you know it's good
and learn it for life i mean i mean and
seriously me you learn it for life uh
is of great benefit to you i will say
though
you are not likely to get a job with
mathematica
i mean for example if you are a
programmer like many of us
are right is you know usually the
question is
which programming language should should
i learn uh because
therefore i can find a job in golan in
php in python
in c plus plus java all these are
languages popular there are a lot of
jobs
so you can eat but for woofer
so if you master wufang language you're
not likely to find a job okay
so i i want to mention that
but you know wufam language you know so
it's
um so why is that such a great language
it doesn't have job well it's actually
it's part of the tool for
scientists and and and engineers like as
i mentioned before if you
if you work for elements if you do tesla
or if you
uh go to spacex or if you do nasa you
know you if you work
for nasa if you work for a bridge you
know if you are building up
you are engineer or you are a scientist
or a biochemist
or material scientist you know then you
then you that's the people you need to
do a lot math
or even a cpu designer cpu designer
you know intel amd you know they or gpu
nvidia you know they create you know
chips there's a lot of math
how do you do it you need mathematica
that's the thing
so all these corporations you know they
they had they
they had they used they run mathematica
for example you look at
industry okay if you are google
if you are nasa if you want to buy
mathematica
three thousand dollars a pop and that's
for
this that's just for a person okay
so anyway so if you are a student or a
hobbyist
uh you know home and hobby it's only
three hundred forty
fifty uh four dollars okay so i
recommend it because when you so
so once you have mathematica you can you
know the the
easiest use is just simply just use it
as like a
a great ai
oracle you know you just ask him
questions your answer
you know or do graphs or plots or math
or you know things like that
so that that is how um that is
the you know so that's what i recommend
you go buy mathematica
and let me tell you about uh you know
reading stefan wolfham you know stephen
wolfham
the guy he's got you know a man
you know he's a successful scientist you
know he's renowned physicist
he's also renowned entrepreneur so
so that that is truly a genius by itself
because
not many people are like that you know
you have many successful
top mathematicians but they aren't all
physicists but they are not
businessmen yeah when it comes to
business or when it comes to personal
social issues they you know many of
these mathematicians
are complete idiot on the other hand
you know steve jobs he's a great you
know talker he's a great you know
salesman but he don't know a thing about
uh physics or math or programming
but so stephen stephen wolfram is you
know is
successful in both and he
is one of the very few successful
scientists who write tons of vlogs okay
stefan wufang
so you go to you know uh seven wolfham
official
website you go to latest writings
you know he's every one of his article
is
very long you know today's the these
millennial generations when you read a
blog
they tell you three minutes reading two
minutes reading
[ __ ] ridiculous
but then if you go to stephen wolfham's
you know his blog
it take usually take me three hours just
to scan scheme to have a first reading
and
you know then then you don't you know i
yeah so for example i have been in the
past
few weeks uh today uh yesterday and
today
i have been reading
he created you know in in the past few
months he created
the wolfram physics project okay
he is going to tell you the fundamental
theory
the theory for them all the theory for
everything
of fundamental physics that's his
uh you know oh there's a wikipedia
description of it
so he's telling you basically he's he's
he's
trying to he has a theory
fundamental uh for fundamental physics
that basically is a theory of everything
uh
in a sense okay and he started a project
for it so that other people can be
involved
especially younger people like like many
of you guys
so i i you know i highly recommend you
read
stefan wufang
i do recommend yeah so i have been
reading
his um in the past two days
i spent like three hours and i'm only
halfway
through uh project announcement
yeah this article
no not this one uh
here i am i have been trying to read
this article in the past
two days you know i spent three hours
three hours and it's not done so you can
see how long that is
so this is written in april 2020 or last
year
and you know pages after page
and after page you know i don't i don't
just read it because when i read i
actually
i actually check out every link almost
every link you know for example
then he says more involved with
computers i want to see what he's saying
here
so uh so i'm kind of a slow reader and
you know i read in detail and i want to
understand
the whole thing in you know uh and
you know it's tremendous stuff so
tremendous stuff i
recommend it i highly recommend it
recommend it so in this article for
example it's not just
you know backstory of the wolfram
physics project first of all he's the
megalomaniac
so when he talks when he writes he he
will often
uh say good things about himself you
know i i created this you know 20 years
ago
then what happens you know you often see
that
uh then but um but then
in this article for example he gives you
a summary you
it's it's hard to find okay he give you
a summary
of what's going on in fundamental
physics in the past
100 years okay so
and he and he can do it you know the
very few people
are capable of doing that you know there
are many
uh equally you know top phys particle
physicist or
quantum mechanics physicist you know
you know many of these people they they
are not necessarily good writers you
know they cannot write they can do
physics but they
and also they don't they don't block you
know you will rarely find
top scientists who blog you know who
talk to the common people like you
you know and explain things they usually
don't
and when they do they become this
idiotic pop
you know on youtube you know there are
some physics
physicists you know they become they
become idiots they they are you know
they do a show to the common people they
are actually not trying to
teach physics you know the advanced
physics
physics rather they are just explaining
to kids you know
make kids happy wants to go into science
things like that
so it's real so anyway so you when you
read this
you will see uh you know a history from
his point of view at least
of the past 100 years what's happening
in uh particle physics and what you know
what
are they thinking about fundamental
theory of physics
things like that i mean that's part of
this uh
long article okay that's it that's it
for that and i think
maybe that's it for today i'm just going
to read comments okay and let's close
down uh so now
my new pc gaming key uh my so i got my
new
pc you guys know i guess that most of
you
you know if you join saudi discord you
know
thank you to many of you people
who have donated and who recommended me
the gaming machine and
it's fantastic so right now i'm doing
this talk show
everything is so smooth it's truly small
smooth i don't have to worry about cpu
look at my cpu
uh gpu graph you know i have 16
gigabytes of memory
you know less than half is used
so there is my wi-fi
so this is my gpu usage
oh this is actually the first time i'm
using uh you know some
gpu power doing a video
uh memory so cpu you know
so it's great so i'm going to read the
comments and see
uh and answer then that's it for today
so i've been talking
for one hour
hello hello hello bart i haven't seen
you for a while so kovite 19 is still
going on
otherwise i might go to germany
so let's see so let's see the from the
beginning
uh video audio good
[ __ ]
hello luis bro clawfoot
hello clawfoot uh
sun doesn't play games break the loop
great to see you
break the loop introduced me yesterday
he talked about his expertise
in hi-fi audio equipment
okay i'm going to blog about it but i
haven't finished
so this this one so
apparently i do you know he went to look
at
you know to the rooms of those you know
stevia rooms high five
places that demo demonstrate ten
thousand dollars
speaker systems or hundred thousand
dollar speaker systems
so he's telling me uh how it goes you
know what's
my question was what happened to the
hi-fi audio people especially in
speakers what they
you know what happened to them is is
there a technology called breakthrough
and
things like that so anyway he talked
about it
so if you want to you know go to you
know you can go to saudi uh
you know just go to my keyboard blog
okay
go to my keyboard blog and you'll find
this article
and you go buy it
these expensive speakers uh
300 speakers and this is
not that expensive but you know it's the
highest quality
i trust i do told me of course i also
know a thing or two about
speakers because since i was a teen i've
been looking at
you know driving about all these
speakers and you know
uh so you go buy it okay
so break the loop mathematica had a free
to run yes yes yes
mc read hello mcreed how are you liking
your windows 10 great
frenzy frenzy great to see you fancy
fancy frenzy from belgium
oh guido start with guido
okay guido van russen
okay i didn't know that thank you for
the correction
[Music]
or something or maybe it's awesome
system dot out dot print line line
that's
java yeah
uh fms
says i used a program on windows a few
years back to get a pseudo
tithing window arrangement oh it could
snap window
part of the screen i don't like i don't
i don't i don't like titling
mathematics can be used for industry
non-math purposes of course
mathematica is the program you know most
of the
most most of most programmers they don't
know nothing about math oriented
programming languages
actually let me show you some articles
okay time to
time to show off some articles okay
magnify
so you go to my programming blog then
you go to you know i have 6 000
articles programming lisp
okay that's uh okay that's not where we
want
let's go back let's go to syntax soup
uh now let's go to semantic noodles wait
jargons of software industry no
syntax soup semantic noodle then magnify
why why is this
uh firefox doesn't remember my
anyway so um math oriented programming
language
search for yeah
so this article this kind of a rant okay
this
this article originally began on twitter
so it's twitter styled article where
each line each sentence is just less
than 140 characters
you know a sentence by sentence so
the title is a class of computer
languages math languages
so i began you know it's a rant by you
know
segway from another segway from another
segway eventually i arrived at the topic
of the
of the title class of computer language
math languages
you know in the beginning i was ranting
about the canvas
scum created invented by java by
apple you know the canvas technology in
javascript
a bit mapped technology is you know they
are going back
backwards the canvas is scum invented by
scum
the likes of c c plus plus open gl
etc you know those are those things
those technologies are despised you know
they those other types those kind of the
technology are the
the the likes you know they tend to be
low level
and no design and they
champion they are the champion of speed
they'll say oh we are the fastest
you know c c plus plus opengl
crap so the
canvas is gone invented by scum the
likes of c c plus
plus often gl etc
whose tenet is hi my name is speed
ever since programming is hell indeed
a vast majority of programmers 99
percent of them have no
idea of mathematical language talking to
them
in lan in language dp debates is like
talk to idiots
all these language programmers are
familiar with
for example c or c plus plus or java or
python
per ruby golan c sharp and even haskell
including haskell yeah these people you
know these are the typical
industrial programmers
all these are the math languages so in
their life
you know some of them you know they will
they are proud you know they will say
oh i've been programming for 20 years
you know each one think they are expert
they work for google for 20 years you
know they work for microsoft oh i was a
compiler writer
for 30 years so they think they know
stuff
when it comes to language debates
especially with me
because when i talk about things they
don't see what i'm talking about
so so they these people all these even
if you know these languages in the in
the other
universe is mathematica matlab apl julia
okay
julia is one of the math languages okay
so these
languages are math oriented you know you
call them math languages they are
very different in nature from all the
other c
c plus first java python per ruby golan
you know [ __ ] so you have the class of
languages
what i call math language including
wolfen language
matlab apl and judea okay julia is the
new one
but not pascal now this is important i
you know i i said
i talked about this article in previous
videos as well not haskell okay
asco is not a math language haska is
more of the tradition of the
you know the industrial you know
they are concerned about memory about
float
about int crap about pointers
no not not not haskell actually about
any anyway
so my point is you know so my point is
these most
industrial programmers you know when the
people you see online
when they when there is a language
debate you know the language war
the flame war you know the religious war
they
often you know whatever their opinion
including this
okay this is not a math language
including
yeah i would uh this is kind of in
between but
but including at least today's common
business
since year 2000 at least you know this
new generation these these programmers
they they don't know
they don't know the concept of uh math
you know math oriented programming
languages
so when you argue with them that in
debates you know they don't
they don't get your point they don't get
my points okay it's very frustrating
so basically all you see you know it
doesn't matter what language you debate
you'll see
yours you'll see basically you'll see
the point of view
from the c language see that's why i say
c is the
granddaddy of everything that's wrong in
programming industry
c and unix they [ __ ] up everything
because they are free
so anyway that's my that's my point okay
uh you know
so math languages so i recommend
mathematica you go learn it
you download it for free or you just go
buy it what happened to your eye okay so
that's a patch
for my cross side
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching donate don't
forget okay i have patreon patreon
or paypal or go buy my tutorial okay i
want to mention this
every youtubers bread and butter
you go by my uh
actually i'm gonna show you my best uh
tutorials okay
my best tutorial is actually the
regardless of the language whether i
like the language or not
the tutorial i'm most proud of
and i i think that other people would
judge to be the most
quality you know actually i think my
javascript in depth is better than any
any tutorial on javascript that exists
out there
in english language okay
possibly there are two or three
that's comparable in quality to mine
now this is my claim you don't have to
believe it but that's what i think okay
there's no better javascript tutorial
than mine
except there are many maybe two or three
uh you can say in the same
uh let's say quality okay but they are
different you know because each person
have different style and approach
in dealing with you know in document
documenting
a complex thing called programming
language
so so anyway so
so if you like my stuff go buy my
javascript tutorial
of course i have also emacs tutorial
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching a few more comments let's
see one minute
one minute also i guess
level is crazy yeah i'm crazy i'm crazy
you are crazy
uh i don't think i'll be using auto
hotkey anymore because
since about five years ago the
programmable keyboard becomes very
popular you know
so today we have quite a few of them uh
either ergonomic or not or do it
yourself
so they are all programmable keyboard
and very powerful
i'm not talking about like just gaming
you know keyboards
gaming keyboards they are programmable
but they are limited in some way
they are geared for gamers but i'm
talking about for example that kinesis
ultimate hacking
and also uh
x-files or many of the do-it-yourself
keyboard they are programmable okay they
they have memory chips built in the uh
the keyboard and they so you don't so i
try to avoid
auto hard key as much as possible
because auto hotkey
is a software uh layer on top of my uh
operating systems it does not always you
always have glitches
so i would recommend you know just go to
my keyboard website and
buy a programmable keyboard
so i don't know c i don't know c plus at
first first i don't know c sharp i don't
know any c
type of languages except java java
okay i have some i do have some
experience in java but i never actually
programmed much in java so
okay thank you guys bye that's it for
today
great great show thank you
is there anything okay that's it i'm cur
i'm shutting down in
30 seconds let's see that's how to
do youtube