Hello, good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of son talk show. We are
going to code auto hotkey. Hello
aspiring Windows composer the
combinatorics
uh student. So we are going to do auto
hotkey. Okay if you haven't seen already
yesterday I did a review of this
ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80.
So watch that yesterday. And today we
are going to code uh auto hotkey. So on
Windows Auto Hotkey is a tool that
allows you to do lots of things. Key map
you know press F8 to launch an
application of any application you want
or F3 to copy or cut and paste or um
swap old key and control key or disable
window key or caps lock or num log or
square lock.
So it's a keyboard utility. It's a best
one for Microsoft Windows. So if you are
on Microsoft Windows, this is very
useful. So we going to go over auto
hotkey
in in the first 10 minutes like intro. I
can I can give you a intro. U uh then we
going to do Emacs sessions for those of
you programmers using the Emacs text
editor.
Okay. And if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed. If you are
watching live, say hi. Okay, so we going
to start. So, uh, video check. Video
check. You can see my screen. Yes, Emacs
powerful, the most powerful editor show
today's talk show auto key. So, go
there. So, okay. So, let's begin. Okay.
So, auto key. So, let's um make sure.
Okay. So, so auto key is you know it's a
keyboard utility you can launch
application
uh for example I can show you um well
I'll show later okay so you can insert
text any text you want you know like
your company name your name or today's
date uh it's not case sensitive and
there's common syntax so it's a
scripting kind of scripting language
okay for uh coders but it's pretty
simple Okay. So if you are not a
programmer, you can also use it.
Uh and the complete key syntax and how
do you remap keys? For example, let's
see. Single key to switch to previous
window. Oh yeah, I can show you that.
For example, you know, if you have this
code, then for me, I just press this
key. So watch my window. Okay. So I can
you see actually So let's put this back
here.
So I press this key. Can you see my
keyboard? Press this key. It will uh
switch to the last window. Now look,
press.
So I don't have to press like old tab
like old tab and you know and you know
so single key press that is the ultimate
way okay to save you typing for you
professional coders or writers. So you
see so that's that's using auto hotkey.
So let me show you my auto hotkey
script.
edge key age. So here is basically my
auto hotkey script. Okay. So, you know,
I got for example this this block of
code that's copy
URL from
uh from a browser window. For example,
what it does is ctr L to put the cruiser
on the URL field then then uh Ctrl C to
copy it. Then switch switch to Emacs.
So, let me demo. Okay. So let's say this
page. Okay. Now I press this key. Now
can you see? Yes. Okay. Press. Now I'm
in EMAC. Okay. Now open a new buffer.
Paste. You got the URL. Now in Emacs I
have code to make that into a uh full
URL. So you can see.
So let's magnify. Okay. So So that's a
demo. So auto hotkey. Okay. tremendously
useful
now. So, let me just tell you guys. So,
so now they have a auto hotkey version
two which is a major upgrade because
auto hotkey began like uh some 20 years
ago. So, in the late 1990s I believe so
the syntax the you know it's very bad
meaning that you know it's very
inconsistent extremely lousy. So about
five or 10 years ago, they started to
rewrite. They have a auto hotkey version
two, which is much better. So what I'm
going to do, you know, I have my
tutorial. This is starting in 2009. So
now I need to update them to version two
because version two, the code is
incompatible with version one. So I need
to make a few updates.
So that's so that's what I'm going to do
now. Okay. So for you those of you
non-coders or not using Emacs you can
you know you can you can just go off and
download autoarchy and explore. Um today
they have very good documentation
uh not so 10 years ago. So you know
today you got AI so lots of things. So
today they you know go download and
documentation
you know. So you you want version two.
Okay, version one is basically obsolete.
Okay, go. So, click on version two. Then
you have click on tutorials. Then you
can install how to install, how to run,
you know, sample code, run programs, uh
write hard keys like remap keys or
whatever. So today they have good
tutorial. My tutorial is kind of, you
know, you don't you don't need it, you
know.
I mean, I give you some different tips.
So it's still very useful but um but in
general for most people you know they
have they have a good you know fairly
good tutorial today.
So so for those of you you know want to
use this you can you can stop watching
and go off. But now next 30 minutes what
I'm going to do is for Emacs for those
of you Emacs coders. So this is more
kind of more advanced. So I'm going to
demonstrate uh de demonstrate how I
update my tutorial like I have massive
number of tutorials for for uh complete
tutorial you know on Microsoft
keybinding another tool this is uh
Microsoft power toys it's very good then
you go you know the complete tutorial
for Linux this is also pretty old you
know like there's like 100 pages about
key map and key binding on Linux
complete tutorial on Mac
for key bindings you know uh setup
keyboard shortcuts then
then you know 1,000 articles on
keyboards and mouse and track ball and
pen input device and uh then I have like
1,000 articles on programming languages
okay emacs emac wam language HTML visual
CSS JavaScript SV VG, Goland,
PowerShell, Python, you know, each one
is like hundreds of pages. So that's
what I do. That's my obsession. Writing,
you know, writing documentation, writing
tutorial is part of it, but also explore
the, you know, lots of things about
computer. Okay. So for those of you
interested in Emacs, you can keep on
watching. So let's start to do Emac
session. Okay. So let's update my uh
PowerShell um
tutorial. You know, every every half an
hour. So this is casual now. Every half
hour about every hour I get up and walk
back and forth and read my website or
read other uh mathematics or computer
science research articles and so on. and
I take notes and so then I get you know
get back on my power station and start
to work on them. So today's date state.
Okay. So we need to add a PowerShell
about how to uh insert today state.
Actually I never done that. So meanwhile
let's also explore artificial
intelligence. Okay. In auto hard key how
to insert today's state. So what I want
to do is press a key. You'll insert
today's state anywhere. Okay. So the AI
today will help you.
So I'm using Guac. I paid Twitter to
have you know guac but guac is the
latest AI. You can just go to gr.com
uh and use it. I recommend it over all
the others. So it's better than um
chatgpt and so on. Okay.
Uh Okay. So, so here's the code. Let's
let's see if it works. So, let's just
add it to my
auto key. Uh okay. Show version. So, so
let's say F. Let's that's that's that's
a key for control.
Uh and uh what is band for band is shift
I believe. I forgot. So let's look up
the key binding.
We Okay. Uh the exclamation sign is old
is old key. Okay. So what what is trying
to do here is settl and d to insert
today's date. Okay. So
okay. So you got to use format time
current date. Okay. Let's let's just run
it. Update. So it will run when auto
hotkey runs you can see this tiny icon
on the taskbar
uh or system tray you know it was called
system tray but what actually
technically it wasn't called system tray
but it became so popular so I think
Microsoft started adopted the name
system tray but anyway that's another
thing okay now I can press let's let's
go to notepad So something simple. So
control
uh that's control alt d. So control alt
d. Fantastic and beautiful. Can you see
that? Ctrl D.
Okay, that's how you insert today's
date. So actually I need to add to my
tutorial. So let's see. Fantastic. So
uh insert text. So I have a section on
insert text. So copy the URL back to
Emacs and uh open it back to that. Copy
that. Okay. So this is my
you are watching my Emacs workflow.
Okay. So let's add a new section.
Auto hotkey. paste that code
and insert today's
date.
Okay,
do that. I'm using kasa
um
kasar html mode. That's my emac stuff.
So, okay, showing browser. There it is.
Now, you want to syntax color it. So,
press press showing browser.
Fantastic. Okay. So, insert today date.
Let's then delete it. Okay. Download
auto hotkey. 15 years ago it was not
forced https but today they want you
know most websites are
auto hotkey
https.
Okay. Go to their website. Fantastic.
Close back here.
download at fantastic then close. Okay.
New version two. Now you need to mention
new version. Okay. So um
auto hotkey
versions.
Okay.
How are you guys doing? Any people
watching? This is interesting. So, uh
let's just get this to work. Okay.
Hold on. How are the versions?
Version one. Uh version one is
very old since
year 2K. Something like that. Okay.
Actually, let's look up look up the web.
the pink window can you can see all my
command calls and keystrokes on the left
and command course on the right
okay so you can see I'm calling kasan
lookup web that's a command I have in
emacs okay so auto hotkey let's go to
Wikipedia
now what's the date originated
okay so
since
200 2003.
It uh
it is absolut.
Okay. Now version two.
Version two. When did version two start?
So this is part of the research when you
write a tutorial and stuff. Okay. So
began in 2021
it is incompatible
with version one. Okay. version one.
It is
the current version.
Okay. Showing browser. Fantastic. Now we
covered the version so people know.
Okay. So now there's another convention
about the title capitalization
conventions. There are several ways.
There's American way. You capitalize
every word except minor words like and
or in, the
United Kingdom way is you simply
capitalize the first letter of the
sentence. So typically I follow American
way, but the UK way is actually better
because American way then you have to
capitalize every word of the sentence.
It's kind of like unnecessary.
and also complicated because what
happens when the title is of two
sentences sometimes. So then you become
then whether you you you know whether
you know like typically you don't you
don't need a period after the title but
if your title happens to be like one
full sentence or two sentence then you
need a period. So the American way is
like uh more complicated anyway.
So let me move on faster. So this one is
done. Delete it. So auto hotkey. Now
there's a orthography issue. You see
auto hotkey should the K be capitalized?
Normally yes because auto hotkey each
one is supposed you know meant is
supposed to be independent auto hotkey.
But the auto hotkey convention actually
they don't they you know that they
consider it as auto hotkey like two
words. So I looked up so delete that so
you can see I looked up uh did I make a
screenshot
uh somewhere?
Yeah, there you see the official site
and Wikipedia they don't capitalize the
K. Okay. Delete. So you see when I work
on tutorial there's lots of issues to
look into if you um pay attention to the
details. It's it involves technical
writing involves writing style involves
auto hard key or hard capital A key
involves convention tradition of English
you know UK style or American style. The
capitalization of the title involves
research into you know past versions
like when did it start how it began
of course I know there's also history it
it came from auto it uh kind of open
source so you know lots of issues so
anyway let's go back to let's see
questions um hello pravin what do you
think about code editor lamb which is
configurable in common spend is a modern
similar to Emacs
Pavine. Okay. I
you know like that's a long history like
there there's been different EMACs or
EMACs based on common list or EMACs
based on scheme since like 30 years ago.
Uh and but typically they are they are
not very powerful. They are like someone
started but just never picked up speed.
Okay. They just like you know like one
one guy show
uh not many users you know 100 a few
thousand maybe at best. So
lamb have I actually wrote about it I I
don't know is that how new is that you
know so um let's see lamb editor
GitHub lamb project general purpose
whatever what do you guys think of let's
see magnify okay so now this key to
enlarging what do you guys think of
editor lamb okay general purpose okay
whatever let's open Right.
Okay. So, what is the date? Now, you
need to uh turn on JavaScript so Google
knows where you live and Microsoft
knows. And uh let's check what year this
project begin.
Install nightly build. Okay. It seems
pretty new. Do you know what's the year?
Say it. Okay.
Go whatever. Oh, quite a Okay. So, it's
uh looks like it's like newish, you
know, they come and go, you know, like
for example, 10 years ago or by now 15
years ago, there's a new Hascal editor.
Then there's also Rust, new Rust editor.
Like when they came up, it became like
hugely talked about, but after after two
three years, it just dies. Okay. So and
I have wrote a lot blogs in the past 20
years 30 years you know about them then
you know it just became history so will
this lamb editor last you don't know
okay that and I I'm not going to use it
I will use it in if it become robust and
you know you know such like that so
um so what year is it that's important
important when did this begin? I think
it's recent. Okay. So for me whenever I
look into or adopt a technology I have
to know the details. I have to know what
what year you begin who wrote it. Like
typically today it's usually harder to
find like who who the actually
wrote this and why do you do it? Like
they hide they kind of hide it starting
like even 20 years ago. the mentality
that all fairly up. Okay. So, for
example, what right now I want to know
who who wrote this?
Usually somebody like a single guy wrote
it. Who is it? Does it say no? You know
these or I call starting with
the late Malay Jen and the zoomers are
worse, you know, like they they don't
say it. They don't say author also
because partly because of the deep state
influence you know code of conduct you
know that you all up. So like the
mentality like let me ask you you guys
this is a project open source you know
so someone spend their time sweat and
blur to create it why do they not say
author it's written by you know I
started this project like usually they
don't all this all these you know like
and it's mixed in with scams because
scams if you are a scammer of course you
you don't want to say oh I started this
project something, right? So, it's all
mixed in. It's like a you know, so but
to to the zoomers, you guys like you you
guys don't know you you guys don't know
a thing. You you just lived you were
born into into this way of the internet.
You think this is normal. Who the
you know puts puts up the name and also
you are a coward. you are so-called
coward or non a non coward because you
don't want to put your name because oh
in case you know somebody dug up what
you did what you said 10 years ago then
you got you're going to be cancelled
you're going to be so the rumors
you guys yeah I you know no we don't
want the authorship so that you know all
these you know little things creates a
collapse of USA that's going on today
okay
and but you think Oh, I'm just going to
Linux. I'm just going to, you know, be a
tech hacker. I'm going to be none and do
Linux and prevent all the Google doing
things. [laughter]
You're kidding yourself.
Okay. Anyway, so this project, you don't
know who wrote it. It takes a lot of
time to dig into. Okay. Then you don't
know what year it began and what is, you
know, go vision. Uh,
yeah. So, yeah. But you know I want
personal information. I don't want like
the marketing
nice words you know like I want to know
what you when you wrote it like what
exactly why you wrote it something like
that or it can be a a corporate
sponsored it you know why you you know
like real you know authentic from people
from people like you and me I don't want
the the the the like remove all any
personal details like nice wording we
going to help uh help Africa we going to
you know I you know vision like vision
vision the who whose vision
I want to know it doesn't say go what
you know okay so you see they removed
all kind of actual you know real
information and that's the situation
with the zoomers starting with the late
Malay genen faces that's who that's
when they created created the like
button, the Jack Dorsey on Twitter, the
Mark Zuckerberg face, you know, the
Facebook face Mark Zuckerberg. So,
they created this and you zuma and look
at, you know, look at this fox. This is
Zuma fox. You know, who is this guy? Oh,
this is a bear or otter. Okay, this
guy's got a face. Good. And that's a n
or this one is a whisper. You know what
the This is the collapse of USA.
Okay. Okay. I I rambled, you know, I
digressed. Let's go back to what I want
to do. So, to answer your question, am I
interested in this one? Not really.
Until you become, you know, robust and
good, then I might use it. Okay. So,
next update image. Okay. So, let's
update that. So uh update the auto hard
key.
So version two is um okay. So in order
to do that so let's create a new um
window. Wait
create a new buffer
and uh magnify. Okay. I don't want
actually.
So windows D to hide it all. And click
on that. And now do a screenshot.
Okay, it's got the new uh now Windows D
again. That's a no very annoying thing
about Windows. Once you Windows D, then
you can't get back all the other
windows. So then you have to like click,
you know, click one by one. You you
can't just get them all back.
I want all the windows because I have
Hoover to activate because I move my my
mouse. Can you Can you guys see? Okay.
So, let me demo this again. I tal talked
about this a million times.
Hoover to activate. So, watch my hand.
Okay. Right now, I'm using this ultimate
hacking keyboard at trackpad. So, I move
here. No click. It'll pop up to the
front. I move here and with the real big
mouse it's easier. So you see I never
click because click is um
it requires muscle movement. So if
you're going to click 1,000 times you
know you every day because you are
hacker then you're going to have fingers
pain you know mouse hand problems. So I
don't click. So it's like nondestructive
way of navigating your windows. Okay. So
I So I need the windows to be like over
and have a little corner I can just move
the mouse to. So but when you do windows
windows D you know in case you want a
screenshot or something
if you do it right away again then they
come back. But if you window D then you
did something then they they you know
there's no way to get them all back you
know stupid Windows like okay I have
like 100 articles on the idiocy of
Windows okay how Windows sucks my
website you'll find it my website is um
si.info info. No https, no s. Okay, now
let's get back to what we doing. Uh,
today I'm popular. I got 17 uh viewers.
Is that right? 11. Okay. So, now let's
get back. So, I got a new screenshot.
Auto hotkey. Go here. Go here. Run
script. So, I need to update that. So,
search for PNG.
Okay. Open.
Okay. Okay, that's a version one. So,
let's add a version two.
Press, press, press, press. Uh, wait.
Show the pink window. My Emacs commands.
Press press. Okay. You see automatically
insert. Now, refresh. Now, that's uh
version two. Okay. Now, we need to
rename this image. You see? Go to the
directory. We need to rename it. many
ways but I have the most efficient way
which is press
okay now just say auto hotkey
U2 expand
uh B2 okay then a date okay do it
fantastic okay you see you you see open
open that go to the directory is you
know I I don't have to go to the windows
um for example the windows explorer
important rename you know fantastic okay
now update the the figure caption okay
so I do press press
fantastic okay show in browser
so the version two um
you know then there's other thing about
writing a tutorial uh which is about
formatting and uh lots of issues okay
So, I've been doing this for 20 years.
So, for example,
um a running auto key script icon, you
know, that's too wordy. So,
okay. So, anyway, so rem remove that.
Remove that. Okay, that's a image. Okay.
Uh let's see if this image is used
anywhere else. This is old one. Okay.
Now, call command flag command. Uh wait,
let's let me show you. Okay,
call this command which is s find text.
Okay, you pay me, you can get it. Search
for it, you'll find it. Okay, now I want
to search that to see if this is used
anywhere in saudi.info. Okay, search
HTML files over like 10,000 HTML files.
Okay, only one occurrence that means
it's safe to delete it. Normally you
can't just delete this because it might
be used in other pages. But now we know
it's only one occurrence. So open that.
Now call a command um
or command. Let's see what is the key. I
forgot. Let's say move move file to du.
Okay. So I just
tap m
old
uh not emac old. uh it's called unused
images
do it so that we'll move it to uh a
bunch of like old images I can show you.
So for example this uh so in the past 20
years of writing
uh programming languages and computer
stuff so you can see all hockey this is
like 10 years ago. So you can see a lot
of old versions Windows auto key. So
that one is regist registry editor. This
is Windows visa v Vista or something.
And back then you have Google plus
that's 20 years ago f you know it's very
popular to have these icons
uh you know old images. So now it's
moved to the old images. Okay. Because
we don't I don't use that. then delete.
Okay, so show browser. Show in browser.
Okay, we got a new one. Anyway, I need
to edit this text too. So, let me read
the comments a bit. Okay, where did the
comment go? Okay, here. And we need to
move on. Okay, so delete that. Okay. So,
let let's see.
Uh,
now if you like if you guys like my
stuff, pay me, okay? Go to my exi.info
bottom, PayPal, Patreon.
So it's coffee and uh like hi yo
important question indeed. Uh the same
like with McDonald's who is the owner.
Uh for me it's important to know who,
why, and how. Okay. Hi. Been a while
since I've seen you coffee house
philosopher. Okay.
It's basic
all zumas know GitHub contributor
insights
h
uh contributor insights okay I don't
know what you're saying exactly
so we are going to bring coffee to
everyone around the world
one can be a zoomer Do they even know
about this? Yeah, that makes sense.
Zumas know this because we don't have
jobs.
That's That's kind of true, too.
I need to stop laughing as a hacker and
uh more studying and practice. That is
true. That's important.
And by the way, lpping that's another
Zuma's jargon I learned from Allan.
Lpping, you know, they have to say lo
and gaslighting and all the all the
crap. Jesus the Zuma gin. Okay, next. So
I'm going to go on a bit 10 more minute
20 10 10 20 minutes then we're going to
go off. Okay. So this part th this this
one is about changing the link auto
hardkey mode for Emacs. If you use Emacs
you can use auto hotkey mode I wrote it
fixes some of the problems I found.
Okay. So over there but today you don't
need it because you see another thing
about writing a tutorial is that over
the decades things change writing style
change. You know today's English is
different from 100 years ago but within
every 10 years decade they also change
slightly.
So for example in fact today my entire
auto hotkey tutorial is like kind of
obsolate because today you go to AI just
ask any question you want. you can
actually ask it to write a entire
tutorial and it will be 99% correct
because I've asked so many times on
different languages. Okay. So today,
in fact, my entire auto hotkey tutorial
is like, you know, not that useful. But
it's very different 15 years ago when I
begin 2009. Okay? Because back then the
official autohockey website is like
idiotic. Sucks. There's no
tutorial. Like this, but it's like so
bad. So people go to my website or other
programmers, bloggers, you know, you go
to blogs.
So I write you know I do a lot of that.
So that's one thing. The other thing is
you know so for example this this phrase
this you know about Emacs today people
don't care you know Emacs users has
dwindled so much because the Emacs
idiots the Emacs dev the richest stolman
the you know in the past like 10 20
years is so bad so who cares like what
Emacs you you know they just going to
use VS code
so this passage
is done for. Okay. So, let me show you
how I do it. Okay. Just copy the link
there. Paste a link
and uh it became a file path. You see
now actual linkify it. Make it a list.
Then
make it a related topic box. You can see
there it's now showing browser. Go to
the bottom.
You see it was like that. Now you got
this related box. Okay. Then you just
go here delete delete
and in fact delete delete the section
tag. Okay. Showing browser
go to the bottom. So now it's just this
related articles box. So for those of
you actually using Emacs they can they
can see oh related you know they go to
my auto key. Uh yeah so and even this
page is not up you know I so I wrote
this like 15 years ago
and the code is not much updated. So I
can show you my old hotkey.
Um,
okay. So, describe function
auto ah kxr
key mode. Okay, go there. That's a file.
Uh, 400 lines of code. Still very still
good, but I really haven't updated it.
Okay, so let's go. So in fact this now I
realize so in fact remove the entire
mention of Emacs because today people
don't care things changed after 15
years.
Okay. So next. So this done. Next.
Open file or folder. Okay. Make this H3
and update. Okay. Let's show that page.
Let me show you. So this page is about
launching app. So press a key to copy
the URL and switch to Emacs and and
press press.
This will open whatever file path on the
clipboard. Okay. So we are on this page
showing browser you can see. Fantastic.
Now press a key to switch to previous
window. This key now am I doing good? Am
I still talking?
Okay. Okay. So now show in browser. Now
open file.
Now this launch app that needs to move
to the above section. Okay. So uh search
for. So first of all update the date
show in browser. You see there's a
update last update. Okay. So, press
press.
So, now you got a new date. Now, search
for Emacs. So, this actually uh Yeah.
Okay. So,
put it back. Cut that. And uh this is
launch app here. And uh this cut that
paste and launch app with parameters.
Okay, that is what this is about. and
make this H3. Okay. So,
uh press press
wait what is the key? Uh
yeah, H3. Okay. Now, syntax color or
show in browser. So, you got launch app
with parameters. Okay. So organize them
logically.
And the open file also mention open
folder. Okay. Open file or folder.
Capitalize it American style. Show in
browser. Fantastic. Okay. So that is
done. Close. And let me demo this part.
Okay. So set key to launch app. So that
is here. I want now also over the past
20 years my coding style has changed. So
let me show you here. So search for pre.
Okay. So pop it out. Uh not this one.
Okay. Search for pre.
Uh more example of different key. So you
see so now my coding style changed. So
copy all wait copy all uh so paste it
here. Now let's move. I want the comment
to be per line. I no longer like the
comment after the end of the line.
Traditionally
when the comment is short you put it
after the line. Doesn't matter. Okay.
But actually but today I want you know
let's let's let let me demonstrate emacs
marquel to make to make all the lines
per line. Okay. So, let's see.
Uh, so start recording a macro. Watch
the pink window. It will show my command
course. Okay. Now, uh,
okay. Search all that to the end. Then
cut it into the beginning of line. Paste
it and add a new line. Okay. Then search
for
semicolon. Okay. Then switch to command
mode. Then put the cursor back. Okay.
Now
stop recording Marco. You see now
call the Marco I just recorded. Do it.
Fantastic. Now do it again.
Instead of pressing three keys to
uh to call the marker, I can just call
repeat last command like this. Okay. So
now press press you see. Okay. So
actually uh we can actually do that a
little bit. Okay. So so this part this
is new
above that is old you know. So actually
we can compare which is better. Okay.
Uh, compare. Let's see.
Now put it back. Now make another pre
auto hard key. Paste it. Syntax color
them all. Show in browser. So now we can
compare which looks better to you. So
the first one is that is more compact.
The second one is like that. I prefer
the second one because again after 20
years the computer screen is different.
So now you got huge screens. So
yeah I I prefer the second one because
it got more clarity.
Uh and people became impatient, you
know, they don't want to read like a
long sentence, you know, they just you
so
okay showing browser we remove the first
one. Yeah, let's use that one. So this
part per line demo emac then delete
that.
Okay, so far so good. Now let's see
comment. Yes, I'm talking great. ACPJR.
Have you reflected on why your coding
style has changed? If so, can you share
your thought about it? Of course,
that would be another that would be huge
topic. I can talk about that for hours.
Uh, and I have 100 articles about that.
Okay? So, you just go to.info.
uh you know go to Kasadi go to parents
go to parents kasar code kasadi.info
info then you go to
you can go to uh
uh fun ntech programming language
tutorials
hacker code python documentation so this
is about coding idoms and style okay so
you can go to um
you know it's hard to organize because I
have like 10,000 articles so go just go
to hawk actually syntax soup semantic
noodle those compliment perving. Okay,
go there. Compliment perving.
When when a girl says you are a pervert,
you just show them. Yeah, I'm a
compliment perving. Okay, so syntax soup
all about syntax. Semantic semantic
noodle about semantics object array.
What does this mean? What's a exception?
Is it exception good or bad? you know
each one uh of these got hundred or more
articles. Okay. uh and on lisp
programming language. Uh so the one you
want to go to is about idioms,
programming idioms and style
and uh expressiveness which to learn
programming language hate and love where
I document why I hate this land or that
land why I love um popularity issues.
That's a social issue. You know, why is
PHP and JavaScript considered the worst
languages by the hackers, by the C
by the lisp But
JavaScript and PHP became the most
popular ever. That's it's a social
issue, okay? Popularity and Python. Why
is Python popular? Okay, so you have to
dive into. Okay, there it is.
programming idoms and coding style. What
is a EDM? Is EDM good or bad? Should you
follow it? And what's a coding style?
What you know Google has a coding style
guide. You know, every like every
programming language and factions have
one. So that's about that. Now regarding
this specific case, why should the
comma, you know, about this comment, why
should it be single line or or multiple
lines? You know why do I changed from
putting short comma after line to to
prefer um one line one uh one um
you know or comma on a line by itself
that's a minor issue okay I can go
either way but but the reason is because
when you have comment on a single line
that in general provides more clarity
clarity, you know, you see this, you
know, so you know, so it's basically
more clarity.
Um, but then you have the compactness
issue because now you takes more lines.
Um, so if you are in a real life coding,
it depends, you know, it really just
depends. But for tutorial, for this
specific tutorial, I think this way is
better for today. Okay. So that is why
for that one. Now this key set key to
launch app. Now this this section needs
to be a new page. Okay. Because on this
page is about launching app. Now
set key to launch app is related but but
in terms of auto hard key is slightly
different because auto hard key this
when you set a key to do something that
involves a separate like separate thing
because then it involves the key syntax
so kind of like separate. So let's uh
let's just make them a new page. Okay.
So I already have written emacs command.
So what I do is press press
five keys. Now show in browser. Now
that's a page by itself. Okay. Now close
that. Now show this in browser. So now
you can see now it becomes a link to
that new page. Now now I I want to
change let's make sure this um
Okay. So let's change the file name.
I want to them to be
the way I have them before. Okay.
Key to launch app.
Okay. That's all lower case. Okay. Do
it. And uh and also
you need let's see yeah you need this uh
prefix
you know you want to follow the way I
have it like I mean I need to follow the
way. So if you open that go to the you
see all these files start with auto hot
keys. So that's my
you know you want to stick with the the
way they are so it's more consistent.
Okay. And here the title you need to add
auto hard key abbreviation and uh a
colon. Okay. And you you also need to
change it here. So you I have a command
press press
do it. You see it's changed now. Show in
browser. Show in browser. Set key to
launch app. Fantastic. So now this is a
new page. You need to add this to the
panel. So let's do that. Okay. Copy
that.
Here is the panel. Here this is section
is the left panel. So you want um so
first of all you paste the file name
linkify make a list remove the URL okay
uh then you want to yeah then you want
to uh remove the prefix okay that's what
you want cut then you
and uh launch okay
should you
uh let's just do it here. Okay. So, copy
those. Now, I'm going to So, what I need
to do is for all these files in the
directory whenever these two lines
occur, change them. Okay. So, let's So,
I have a command in Emacs that allows me
to do it. Cuz find package. So, press
press
change these two lines. Okay. And what
do you want to change it to? I want to
change it to paste paste previous there.
So added this new line. So do it in this
directory. Yes. All HTML files. Yes.
There it is. So now you can see it
changed all these files. You see?
And press press a list of all the files
it changed. Okay. Good. Close. Close.
Show in browser. So you can see set key
to launch app. Launch app. File name
extension. Launch app. Set key to launch
app. Insert tech. Fantastic. You see
that's how I update this navigation
panel. Okay. So this one new page is
done. Delete it. Now there's more. Okay.
So is this interesting? Should I go on
or should I just do it offline? Why I
hate C? Why Mr. Exa wants to break my
heart? You know, C is just no good. You
know, it's Asian 40 years 40 years old.
C survives today
in part because um the momentum I mean
because the all the software is written
it you you can't just you you can't kill
it. You know the other reason why there
are new people using C is is majorly
because the C code because C like Unix
has a sense you know like it's very
difficult it's very cryptic therefore it
is the best because it makes things you
know it's for the real man because then
you you know if you know C that means
you are a real computer scientist you
know this
In fact, more actually what is more true
is that C is just so badly designed you
know so so badly designed not because
it's it's oh involves you know advanced
mathematics that's why it's hard you
need to really study hard not that's not
why why you see like hard because it's
so badly like the most worleless
from like 50 years ago Okay. But they
think, you know, the C idiots, you
computing industry idiots. They think,
"Oh, C, C is the real man's language
because, you know, you don't want to be
a JavaScript or Python kitty." They
don't know anything. You know, they
[laughter]
you know, you need to code C because
then you need 10,000 lines to do the
same thing.
Code C idiots. Okay. The the
Unix and C idiots. And what's worse is
C++.
C++. Oh, how to be popular. Okay. To be
the one way, one one tactic, one one one
tactic to be popular is just to to use
to write on the existing popularity.
Therefore, I'm going to create a C
compatible language. C++.
It's C the one you love and very
popular. But I'm gonna make it plus and
plus. That's C++. Another huge story of
um the worst worst Okay. Worst
in computer science.
Now Rust. Okay. Rust. Okay. So now we
are digressing into programming
languages which is what I talk about a
lot. Uh Rust is kind of different story.
Okay, Rust is first of all it's a new
language you know since like 15 years
ago. So in general for programming
languages if it's more than 20 years old
the the age difference the later ones
are better for sure. Okay. So Rust is
better than C? Absolutely. Is Rust
better than C++? Absolutely. There's no
question about it. ROS is just better
you know if if we can ignore the
existing code or habit you know because
older people they don't you know they
don't know rust you know they they are
used to emacs you know so just remove
them you know so if if they you don't
have old old people or old code then you
then we don't need C and C++ first okay
you can go just all rust and go land
but rust just in my opinion they got
kind of their own problem just because
it's a hot shot you know it's like the
new kid in town or the Zuma idiots you
know they don't really know nothing but
I heard my friend says Rust is much
better that's kind of that's that's kind
of the situation with rust it's also a
coat okay kind of like that so I'm you
know I don't know rust actually So I can
I cannot really say but I do have you
know decades of experience of
programming languages and Rust is kind
of like
very complex. Okay so hold on a second.
Hold on a second.
Okay, I got to go, guys.
So, thank you guys for watching. Let's
turn on back the camera and turn back my
uh system. So, I got to go. Thank you
guys for watching and bye.