Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to do review in depth of
the ultimate hacking keyboard 80. This
one. So this is known as UHK
UHK80. Okay. So let me show you. So this
is going to be in-depth review. It's
kind of heavy because I have this this
uh this tenting stand on. So that kind
of adds weight. If you if you want to
know the weight of the keyboard, check
out their website. So there are two
parts and there's a bridging cable. So
first of all, let me go over the
hardware, every aspect of the hardware.
Then I'm going to um tell you about the
software. Okay. So if you are here, say
hi. Hello. Cough M and uh if you are
watching this offline play at 1.5 speed
okay so UHK80 ultimate hacking keyboard
okay so this this so let me let me show
you so this this extra extra add-on
track ball and this is extra add-on I'll
I'll talk about them later okay so if
when you when you buy it they come like
that okay without the And now the stand
is screw down. So you can see there is
thumb screw. So I can
um so you see I you know I untwist it
and I can take it off but I'm not going
to bother. Okay. So the stand is extra
by so normally you wouldn't have the
stand. So when you buy it, it's one
single piece that can be split apart by
magnet. So you just pull it apart. Then
they um become two become a split
keyboard. Now so
and so let me just go over. So the
quality is superb. Okay. So I've been
using the ultimate hacking keyboard
since like 5 years ago. uh UHK60
version one. Then after two years or
something, UHK60
version two came out. Then after two or
three years, this is UHK 80. 80 because
it's got 80 keys. Okay, so let me just
go over the hardware. So it's highest
quality build because I've been using
them, you know, using their product for
five years. I can tell you highest
quality build. It's it's um pretty thin.
Now the palm rest is part of the
keyboard. So you cannot detach it you
know it's part of the keyboard. So let
me show you this side. Those are
magnetic
um
you know so these are magnet magnets
over there. So can you see? Yeah, these
are mag uh let's see here and here
magnets and this is the connection the
uh to the left hand side or to the
add-on mouse or track. So right now I'm
using Bluetooth. You can also use it
wired. So it's very good. Okay. So what
else I need to show you? So so something
special about this keyboard
is these thumb keys, you know. So you
got extra thumb key space. Function key
one and function key two. So you can see
uh and the mod key. Okay. So without
light it's clear. So you you you know so
this thumb keys allows you to do a lot
of combination. So you can switch to
next tab, previous tab, new tab, close
tab or move cruiser, you know. So they
also got dedicated arrow keys but you
can just press the mod and the the left
hand side the right hand side I JKL they
become couser keys and close tab and all
that. So that's the right hand side and
the left hand side is very similar.
Okay. So they they got the best key
caps. Okay. So can you see it clearly?
caps. This is P. This is doubleshot
PBS
plastic. PBT I think it's called PBT. So
I did a video about last week unboxing
of this thing. So watch that one. You
can see the entire box it came from. So
it got two USB C ports. One on the left
hand side here. Can you cannot see it
clearly? Okay. So let me just show you
in general. So again on the left hand
side you also got this uh this uh this
is like springloaded
uh connectors to the
to the add-on modules. This gives you
three extra keys plus plus you got this
uh very nice tiny track ball and the
left button, right button. So all you
have to do is just, you know, snap it
on. It's magnetic. So, so you can see
now if I press the key. So they light
up. Now the lighting you you notice they
have different color. That's because
it's the color the the the color depends
on the functionality of the key. So if
it's a special modifier, you can see
it's yellow. Okay. Normal key lights up
as white. So but the windows modifier
they become blue or blue or greenish. So
you can see so let me try it again.
Okay. So you can see so functional
lighting but you can change you know you
can program the light as well. So is
there anything I want? Uh did I miss
anything? If you have questions ask me
now. Okay. Do you find it easier on the
hands to type with tented keyboard?
Absolutely. So that depends on how much
you type. Okay. So if you don't type
that much for a normal person, you know,
your keyboard is fat. That's kind of
okay. But if you seriously type a lot,
you are a coder, you are a writer, you
write a novel, uh, or you go go online,
you talk to people all the time typing,
then then you then you want it tended
like that. So that's what this um let me
let me see if I can show that's what
this tenting stand is for.
So you see now I have it on. So let me
let me show it over here. So you can see
uh so the tenting stand I can so you
just pull it apart. You can move this
bar move this metal bar lower then then
it becomes the tinting will be high. So
you see right now it's like that but you
can make it higher in general the higher
is less convenient. So once you get very
high then then then you don't you know
then then becomes like that the maximum
is 60°. Okay. So anyway, so you can, you
know, so you have to buy this stand um
by itself. Okay. So anything else? Did I
miss anything?
So they included, you know, it's part of
the unboxing. Watch my last video. The
USBC to USBC. Then you got So
So you got two USBC here.
you know, two USBC, then you got the uh
USBC to USBA
here. Okay. So, when you buy it, the
battery is a interesting feature. The
battery is optional. So, if you want to
use it wireless,
then you have to buy the battery. Now,
if you don't need wireless, then you
just use it plugged in. So you don't buy
the battery. Whenever you need to, you
can buy buy the battery. Okay. So that's
a kind of a novel feature. And so you
know uh Okay. So uh what else? So they
include a key puller. Now I'm wondering
if I should pull out the keys to show
you guys. Uh
why don't we? Okay. So let's see. Be
care. So the key switch are
hot swappable. Okay. So let me show you
the key switches are hot swappable.
Okay. So
so there is the key cap. Let me show you
the key cap because
Okay. Finally. So it's very wellmade.
It's got, you know, this technology for
the key labeling is called double shot.
Essentially, it's two plastic. You can
see another plastic inside.
Now, can can you adjust adjust adjust?
Okay. So, you can see that white plastic
is actually the label. So, effectively
it's merging two plastics. Okay? So the
label will never wear off in 100 years,
you know, because it's part of the
plastic. Okay. So, so and uh you know,
very good. So, and here is a key switch.
When you buy, you can choose uh several
I think they got six options. Okay. For
me, my preference is linear and
lightest. So, this one is called pink
something. Okay.
the uh pink something pink pink boxed
switch I think. Okay. So that's my
choice and I recommend it if you type
you know for the next 10 20 years and
you are a coder. Okay. And then they
they got this technology called uh hot
swappable switches. So you can actually
pull this off, you know, pull this
switch off and swapping a new one if you
want to. So I never got into that. So I
don't know much about hot swappable
uh key switches. If you watch YouTube,
there's a lot of YouTubes you can watch.
Okay. So now put the caps back on. Okay.
I think I covered everything about the
hardware. So let me check. Uh
construction. Excellent.
display. Oh yeah. So they got you see
now they got actually a display here.
Oops. Which press? Okay. So you can see
it's hard to read though. Uh you see
that you can see the reflection of my
camera. But
so when when I press a FN2 key for
example, you can see it shows up. You
see FN2. You see you see X ah that's my
name. So you can program your name. You
know that line shows the current layout.
So you got like you can you can have
like 20 30 layouts and layers. So when
you press the mode mode key it shows up
mode. You see Fn2 or when you press Fn
it'll show. So anyway so anyway so so
here and here is the battery. You see
left hand side and right hand side
battery
level. Okay. So that's about
now let me tell you about the bridge
cable. Okay, the bridge cable is in fact
not necessary.
So if you if you use it wired for
example
um you don't and you don't even need a
bridge take cable because the left hand
side and right hand side they will talk
to each other wirelessly like you don't
have to do nothing about it. However, if
you want to, you can plug in the bridge
cable.
So,
so any questions, post your questions.
Okay, then I'm going to show you
software.
Okay, so you see the bridge cable is
connected. Now, it actually shows, you
know, it's small for you to see, but
anyway.
So, the bridge cable.
So why do you need it? Well, if you you
know
if you are charging the battery, you can
you know if you plug the USB here that
will charge the right hand side and if
you have the bridge cable connected it
will also charge the left hand side but
slowly like kind of very slowly. Okay.
In a similar way, if you plug in the
left hand side USB
and if you have the bridge cable on,
they will charge the right hand side
slowly or you can just plug USB to both.
Okay, so that's kind of so the bridge
cable is not really necessary, but it's
kind of useful. Okay. You know, if you
don't like the look of the, you know,
this thing, it, you know, it's kind of,
you know, this is this way without the
bridge cable is more elegant. Okay. So,
that's the bridge cable. Uh, and let me
just show you the the other extra
add-on. So, you got the touch pad,
trackpad, and you got the track point.
So, let me connect it.
That's it. That's it. So you can see now
I I got I can use my m kind of like
trackpoint mouse. This is like a little
joystick. Okay. You you cannot see my
screen. So but I will show you. So but
let me finish covering the hardware
first. So then here's a trackpad.
Okay. You see this? This goes down this
this uh
Okay. Let's show it
anyway.
Okay, that's everything about hardware.
Let's see if I miss anything. Um,
ultimate hacking keyboard. Okay, palm
rest that's attached
the part of the keyboard tenting stand.
USB port wire bridge cable show each of
the add-on I did key caps I showed you
double shot molding. Yes. pull key. I
did uh key scope design. Okay. So, one
of the design, the great design of this
keyboard, I noticed this is a detailed
design. You see, you see the key caps,
they use different shapes of the key
cap. That's very good because once you
use this keyboard, you'll notice, you
see, so normally your hand is on this uh
mode of FN. By the way, it's completely
programmable. So you can change you know
if you like this just to be space you
can okay completely programmable for
every key. So but the shape let me tell
you about the shape you see they have
different shapes. So your when you when
your thumb is normally here, right? Like
for example, so I can move to the left
and and I can feel it because it's um
okay, it's the same height. But however,
if you want to press the Windows
modifier key such as old
Windows key, super or control, they are
higher. So you can feel it you know just
like when you use a keyboard for a long
time you can you can just feel it you
don't have to see you don't have to like
oh how how much how you know did I move
too far inward things like that
similarly for the uh for the FN2 and by
default this is space I swapped them by
the way so for me this is now space the
actually this is backspace and and this
is um mode. Okay. So, there's a lot pro,
you know, huge amount of
programmatability you can do with it.
So, let me start to show you the
software. Okay. Yeah. So, let me begin
to show you the software. So, let me
plug it in. Now, I'm going to plug it
in, use it wired.
Okay. So that way I I can turn off my uh
I can turn off Bluetooth on my Windows
machine. Okay, let me switch to the
Okay, if you if you got questions, ask
me. Okay, so so now you can see you can
kind of see my keyboard. Um
are you guys seeing me? Am I doing good?
Say hi. Okay. So,
yeah. So, let me unplug this
because I like I like the track ball the
most. Okay.
And uh
and now it's plugged in. Now, let me
turn off my Bluetooth. Okay. Can you
see? Turn it off. Okay. Now check
uh uh check if I can type. Yes. Yes.
Left hand side.
Right hand side. Fantastic. Okay. So,
and can you see now I I'm going to use
my mouse. Okay. So, this track ball
track ball I have programmed it to do
cruer movement. Okay. Okay. So, let me
move to the EMAC so you can see. So, you
see my EMAC. So, let me magnify. Okay.
Magnify, magnify, magnify. Okay. So, now
if watch my hand on the track ball, I
can, you know, move the right to the
right or scroll to the left. You know,
they they can move closer or I can move
up down. Fantastic. Can you see? Because
how do you do that? Because I programmed
it. So, so let's open the
agent U HK agent
software.
Okay, a new Bluetooth device has been
paired to this UHK added to connection
so that you can switch to it because I
just, you know, set it up for for this
demo, but I don't want you usually I
don't want to use Bluetooth on my uh
main desk,
my power station. Okay, so
Oh, by the way, I didn't show you
there's a feed.
There's a four feeds. Uh, yeah. So, but
you know, you can attach, you know, the
the feet. So, you you just push it in
and push it in and twist it and it'll
it'll be on the keyboard. But I don't
need it because I'm using the stand, the
tinting stand. Okay. So, you can see,
can you see the uh Ultima Hacking
keyboard software? Can you see now my
you see my left hand? So you have
several
uh key maps. Okay. So this is for
example the default is quart for PC for
Windows you know QWER TY. So let's
magnify.
Okay. So you know then you can go to
quart
and then you also got core mac and you
got vorac by default. So you just press
a key you press fn
let me show you another feature. You see
the when I press the key uh wait this uh
here. Okay. So I program this key to be
tab. So if I press that key then I can
just press [snorts] three
and it'll say comac for PC on the
display. Can you see it? You cannot.
Okay. So let's press uh six.
Wait. Press six. Com for Mac. Press
five. Comarmac for Mac. Wait. Comac
FN7
Kasar layout. Okay. So you can see you
can define your so all the all those are
default but now I I have defined my own
key map. So it will display my name on
the keyboard display area.
So So you are looking at my key map and
in this key map you can see this left
hand side cluster I programmed it to be
left click, right click and middle
click. And for the track ball, let's go
to the track ball. Just let me just show
you a few things, okay? Because this
this software is huge. I mean you can
just program just about any aspect.
Okay. So let's go to track point.
Trackpad
touchpad. Track point. Track ball. So
you can see for my track ball the base
layer is correct.
That means when I roll the ball it
function as arrow keys. Okay. Now if I
change it to cruiser
and now click save to keyboard.
Okay, it's done. And now go. Now now
when I move the track ball, you can see
my point pointer move. Now it becomes a
mouse pointer. Can you see?
Okay. Now right now here is super slow
for some reason. Oh yeah. Okay. Now it's
working. Okay. Good. So,
so what I'm saying here is that all
these are can be configured you know you
can see for example track ball you can
change the speed acceleration
divisor speed I'm not sure what that is
scroll speed divisor correct speed
device axis locking you know kind of
uh fancy features okay so and also the
lead the lead lead backlight. So you can
see
they are colorcoded. So modifier is
green, shortcut is blue, uh yellow is
switch layer, you know you you can you
can change them, you know, you can
change because they are uh using RGB
leads. So you can change them to any
color you want. Uh and if you don't like
the functional color uh for example this
is you know they have different color
depending on the purpose of the key then
you can change it to per key back
lighting okay save to keyboard that
means when you press it will light up
okay so saved okay so press you see
the key light up yeah did it yeah it's
hard to see right now it's too Right.
But I like the function
uh function light. I want that. Okay.
And if you don't want light at all, if
you don't like it, you think it's for
gamers only, you can turn it off
completely. Like um
brightness like turn off brightness
completely if you want. Okay, I think I
pretty much covered everything, you
know. I can then for example this is my
key map my own. You can go to the mode
layer. So you can like change anyone any
part of it. For example the arrow keys
is on the right hand side when you hold
down the mode key. And uh then you also
have a mouse layer. Now that's their
special design. That's also kind of kind
of a novelty you know. So when you by
default the caps lock position is the
mouse key. When you hold it down
then your right hand side becomes kind
of mouse cruisers you know just like a
mouse cruiser. But I find this not very
good you know you you know to control
the mouse pointer using keyboard using
you know buttons is not very good. you
want, you know, you want a a mouse, a
track ball or touch pad pad or pen
input, that would be much better. Okay,
you using the buttons to control, you
know, the cruiser position is not very
good.
So, I don't use the mouse. So, then you
got the Fn
layer, which I programmed to be number
keys. When when I hold it down on the
right hand side, it become numbers. Then
you got FN2 layer and you can I think
you can yeah you can create your own
layer. Fn35
shift layer control you know uh
you know so
so what uh did I change anything? I
don't want to change anything. So close
without save. Okay. So that's the UHK
agent software. It's also open source.
Okay. But but but I think you can only
use it for the ultimate hacking
keyboard. You cannot use on other
devices.
I think I pretty much covered um all I
wanted to uh say. So if you have any
questions, ask now. Okay, that all
otherwise that's it. Hexar, great
keyboard. Hello. Uh palash backup. Hello
stabilizer. Hello. What keys are on the
thumb clusters? Okay. So,
you know, if you haven't seen before, so
you know, so
so you got space fn
mode FN2 and uh similarly for the left
hand side. Okay. Now you can you can go
to my website, you know, go to my
website. Here's today's talk show star
talk show on.info.
Remember
no HTTPS
no s okay otherwise you get error like
oh this website is not secure be careful
you cannot visit you know that's bad
because the browser started to do nasty
things so http no s okay then you'll see
my website so go to the website autoah
hacking keyboard review so I've done now
by now I've done like complete review so
you can see beautiful huge photos. Okay.
And I explain every details of it. So
for example, the thumb keys, you know,
the entire layout, you can see the
functional coloring of the key
backlight, you know, fantastic.
And you can also see the display. Okay.
So, and here is another view. embed my
bed station on a on a Mac laptop.
You know, you can compare the size
uh and uh then you you know close
detailed photo of the USB port
uh and the feed by default
uh and uh the add-on modules key cluster
which you have to buy separately. Okay.
Then you know the thing how thick is the
keyboard and the detail of the key caps
and the light. So you see many keyboards
with lighting they differ by quality.
You know some of the lighting is like
flickers or you know not not steady or
um or the key cap does not allow the
light to shine through. But on the UHK80
it's perfect. you know, they design it
very well. So, you can see how sharp
they are.
Um, okay. So, you know, and the
connection, you know, the add-on module
connection detail, the back of the
keyboard, the magnets, and I think
that's it. Okay. So,
and the stand, the
tenting prop or also known as the riser.
So you can see and okay so let me answer
the questions and that's it for today.
So now now you go to now watch you see
I've already programmed my key. So I
press this key single key it'll just
like toggle full screen. So in fact that
key does F11.
Okay so hot swap you know so all the
details. Let's go to their website so we
can you know so there's whole more
detail about the display what each
display means. Okay let's go to their
website.
uh
uh io.
Okay. So now I press this key on the
left, it will function as a mouse click.
Watch. You see? Fantastic.
So why do I do that? Because the mouse
buttons are an inducer of repetitive
strain injury. Because that takes your
muscle to click the mouse. You don't
want that. So a giant button, the
keyboard button is much easier for your
hand. Provided that if you are a
longtime typer, you know, you you sit in
front of the computer for like many
hours a day.
But if you are casual use user, you
don't care. You know, the mouse is fine.
Okay. So that's their uh website. And
you can buy the UHK60
if you prefer, you know, the small form
factor or the UX UHK 8080 keys. Now my
you know for so the UHK60
does not come with a palm rest. Wait,
did it did they actually uh I don't
think they come with a palm rest. I
think that's a add-on.
So let's check uh you know check their
website for the authorative information.
Okay, don't listen to what I say. Their
website if we disagree their website is
more authorative. So uh do I have
internet issues? Why are they not
showing
Okay, let me answer the questions. Okay,
what else? What's the difference between
FN and FN2? Okay, they they are just
different modifiers
in case you know if you already use one
of them, you know, they allow you more
flexibility.
It's like it's like what's the
difference between Windows key versus
old key versus control key. Um you know
it's for those
their difference actually they are just
the same thing but their difference is
that by tradition control is for certain
purposes. Alt is for certain shortcuts.
Windows key is more for systemwide
shortcuts. Okay, that's there by
tradition but you can change them if you
want. So in a similar way on the
ultimate hacking keyboard Fn is for
um you know it doesn't matter you can
you can change like each person is
different for you know you can change.
Okay so I think that's it. Bye guys.
Okay. So, why is the
why is the site not loading up now? Is
it because uh let's see. Okay. The UHK80
website is fantastic. Now,
now the UHK60
website
uh is not loading up for some reason.
Okay. I don't know.
But anyway, so that's it. I, you know, I
did video reviews, actually several of
them of the UHK60,
including unboxing, so you can check
them out. Okay, I think that's it. So,
bye, guys.
Oh, did you uh Okay, you uh Okay, so you
didn't see my screen. Okay, that's too
bad. Um, yeah. Anyway,
okay. I think that's it for today. Um,
yeah. Bye, guys.
How long have I been talking? 35
minutes. Okay, we shut down in 1 minute.
Okay. Is my video still going? Yeah.
Okay, we shut down in one minute.
Test test.
Uh KK
A. Okay. Go there. Go to their website
then you can check out all the details.