Hello, welcome to another episode of
talk show. So we are going to code wolf
language doing a animation of physics
simulation of bouncing balls. My
keyboards glove 80 fantastic nia track
ball fantastic Logitech 405 mouse
fantastic something like 405 or
something 46 and the ultimate hacking
keyboard. Okay. And then there is this
um sparboard. Fantastic. Okay. I'm going
to try to use it. Okay. Check watch my
videos. Uh for each one of them I have a
vid video uh on
YouTube. Okay. So let's do stop that.
Let's start to code wam language. Let me
show you what we going to do. Uh if you
are watching offline, play at 1.5 speed
because I
ramble. Now there is this fantastic
animation. Okay, let me show you
um this animation. Okay, let's go to
it. We're going to do we're going to
code
this. Let's see. We need to turn on
sound.
Start again.
[Music]
D do
fantastic. Okay, we're going to code
that. Uh I've never done this before. So
uh I'm just going to see how it you know
we are going to explore how to do it
with wam language. Meanwhile I'm going
to show you how uh about wam language
graphics programming. So if you are new
to wuam language I had I have like 100
videos in the past
uh and uh about two weeks ago we have
this one about how to introduction to
wam language programming graphics. Okay.
So watch that one uh if you don't know
yet. And uh wam language uh so I got
search for wufam language tutorial
kasali.info and you can download it for
free over here. Uh and uh you can then
you can download Jupiter extension and
there's another one that allows you to
have interactive graphics without buying
it. Okay, download free and uh then
um so uh okay so let's just code it.
Okay, so this is today's talk show. Um
yeah, so in order to do animation there
are like the most basic way is via
geometry. So that is if you want to do
an animation all you need to know is
let's say let's say we are limiting
ourself to 2D geometry but this works in
3D geometry or live action or movie
anything so all you have to do to to
know is the graphics for each frame okay
now but in 2D geometry all such as this
thing all you need to know is the uh if
you are here say hi okay if you are
watching watching live, say hi. Love to
see your comments. Now, if you are doing
animation for 2D geometry, all you have
to to know is that each object's
position with respect to time. So, if
you have an animation of let's say one
minute. So, each second you know
position, you need to know the position
of each object. Then just draw it. Then
you can create the whole frame and frame
by frame it creates animation. So in
summary, you you need to know the most
basic way is to know the position of
each geometric object. Okay, that's how
you do any animation. You can do any
animation. Now that's the most
fundamental basic way. Now a more higher
level way is that you
um let's see if I have written it out.
Yeah. So I have so yeah so one way to
create animation is to know position of
each object in any frame. Okay. Now a
higher level is to create animation is
to know an object's beginning and end
position and specify a rule to determine
their intermediate positions. Okay. So
instead of you know drawing each
position in each frame you just say the
start position end position and you give
it a function how it uh will go through
time. So as time increases the function
uh will specify the position. So that's
kind of higher level. A more higher
level way is actually to do something
like this is actually you write a
physics emulation. So that is getting
more complex but which is in many game
engines they do that. So what you have
to do is you you specify the rules. um
you know I I'm not familiar with this so
but I think basically you specify the
physics rules the ball will bounce and
stuff and so all you have to do to
create animation is to specify your
object and initial velocity so the
direction and speed it's moving that's
that's all you have to do then you just
run it and as the object moves it will
the the physics engine will detect you
know which position is that what
direction is going if there's obstacle
if so it will bounce it back it will
move the object in a different position
according to the physics uh engine's
rules okay so in this framework all you
have to do is specify object and initial
velocity that's
it so but we are going to do so I never
done this animation like this this you
know looks like a physics animation so I
never done so but we're gonna do this.
Okay.
So it turns out it's easy. You can do it
in a most fundamental geometric way
because you observe you know first of
all you in order to do this first of all
what you need to know is what exactly it
is doing.
In physics terms, you just, you know,
it's just ball bouncing. But in
geometry, you so you observe the first
ball. So you can
determine basically the balls their path
is always the same. So the first the top
ball
always always move in the same path. It
never falls down. So it's not actually
physics emulation. It just go back and
forth. So for each every ball they
traverse in the same exact path. Then
the you can you can know that by just wa
you know just watching focus on the
first ball you know the the dark
red and then you can observe the last
ball. You can also see their position
the path is always the same. Okay that's
the position of each ball. The other
thing you determine is are they have do
they have different speed? That's one
question. The other question is do they
have do the speed change? So you can
observe each ball in the animation. You
can then you
know the top ball will have faster speed
because then the last ball because when
you look at the first frame you see the
first ball traverse all the way back
here while the last ball is much slower.
So the higher the ball the speed is
faster. So that answers one question.
Um that is each ball have different
speed. Okay. Now the second question
does the speed change? If you watch the
video you'll see that the speed does not
change. So each ball have one
speed and they they they don't change
and they traverse the same path. Okay.
So so this whole thing becomes very
simple. It's just geometry. Each boat
traverse the same path.
the the first ball has higher speed than
the last. Uh and they the speed never
changes for each ball. Okay. So that's
all you need to know. So once you know
that you know I've written out you know
because I I written out. So once you
know that then you can determine each
frames object position and you can
create the animation. So we're going to
do that. uh some you know I posted this
I posted this yesterday and someone at
you know it's fascinating and someone
asked um like someone asked do this in
wuam
language and I was like I don't know how
to do that so you know because this kind
of physics emulation I've never done so
I thought about it then it turns out
pretty simple so let's begin okay so
let's begin uh let let me try to do like
kind of as fast as I
can. So that um so we start a woofam
language uh code uh because this might
take an hour because I never done this
before okay starting wam
language comments any comments nobody
okay so wam language let's start it okay
so let's say three to evaluate shift
enter to start a kernel and magn
magnify so it's easier to see. Okay, so
we got
um Okay, now let's save
it. Save
it. Animation just random name. Okay.
Okay. So, we
um start to code. So, we going to write
the animation to do this. Uh hold on a
second. Let me see.
Uh, can can you guys see
it? Okay. So, we want to uh Yeah. So, we
want to Okay.
Okay. So let's begin.
Okay. So we Okay. Let's just start.
Okay. Uh B. So B is a graphics
primitive. Okay. So do I have um Okay.
Look up the B
documentation. B is a function that
represents a
uh represents a uh a a disk. Okay. So we
want uh Okay. We don't want B. We don't
we we want
um
disk which represent you know like a
ball. Okay. So uh this radius okay so
let's say zero uh position at zero
radius uh one.
Okay. Now we want to show this in
graphics. So you have to
do is put the disk inside. Okay. Then
when
it you can see a disk. Okay. Then we can
say access true.
Okay. So, uh actually then we need to
plot
range. Plot
range. Uh let's say -1 to 1 times 10.
Then same for y axis. Okay. So copy
that. Uh copy that. Let's do this. Okay.
So copy
that. Okay. We got kind of b. So range
let's increase to uh 20
uh 30. Okay.
So we got this. Uh so that's one ball.
Okay. So that's one uh
ball. Uh so now we do so I'm coding this
in EMAC using
kasawan mod. You can download it. It's
linked on my talk show. You can download
it warm mod. Okay. On GitHub. So I do
this in Emacs because for me it's easier
to code you you can you can directly
code in the wuam notebook or Jupiter if
you
want. So we got this. So so now we just
got a static graphics. Now we want to uh
move. Okay. So let's do a move.
Okay. Manipulate. Let's look at the
documentation. I kind of already know
what that does. So manipulate I mean
takes a
expression and takes a range. So this is
going to be
time let's say x time from uh zero to
let's say uh 0 to one. Okay. So then in
this the expression with variable x time
will change. Okay. So now let's say
let's put the graphics in here.
Uh let's
see.
Okay. Let's say animation equals to
that.
Okay. Then you need a time thing. Okay.
So
wait. Okay.
So, so this animation you need the
time. So, the time will be the position.
Okay. So, let's change the X axis. Okay.
Time
there. So, so that's the animation. Then
you um Okay.
So,
so let's just do that. Let's see if that
works. Uh, so 0 to one instead of zero
to one, let's say 0 to 10. Let's say -10
to 10. Okay, copy
that. Paste. Run it. Okay, got a problem
because so uh time -10 to 10 uh this
needs to evaluate I
think. Okay, there we have it. So let's
um so can you
uh you need to drag it. Okay, so you can
see we got animation. You get back and
forth, back and forth. Okay,
fantastic.
Now, this ball, we we have to draw
several balls. Okay, so so we got an
animation of one ball. Uh, of course, we
need to color it. Uh, but
um but why why is it no auto
play? Uh, usually there's a play.
Uh, okay. So,
uh, oh yeah. Okay. So, you click on that
and say back and
forth. Okay. Then we got a ball.
Uh, so we need to change the ball path.
Then we need to draw two kind of bars.
Okay.
So okay so I need to think about it
because uh so you need so this you know
so okay let me just you know like keep
typing keep typing that's a key for live
coding because you know don't think okay
let's just keep typing so graphics disc
um dis that thing uh and uh and uh so
this time is going to be a parabola.
Okay, so it's going to be a parabola. So
parabola uh so uh the the curve for a
parabola is just
um just x squ.
Okay, for example, you can plot
that you know. So if you go negative uh
-1 to 1 uh let's say -9 to 9 shift enter
there you go okay but now it it wants a
inverted parabola so this is a basic
analytic geometry pre-calculus analytic
geometry you learn this before you do
calculus so you want to invert the axis
so it's just negative
okay so
Um okay you got something like that and
uh
then okay so this is the so the the the
path for this
um the position of the ball will be
let's say the position of the ball will
be
uh the param parameter formula okay so
which is Um let's let's write it out
here. So it's a parametric equation of
two things x and x and two. Okay. So uh
so instead of using x time let's just
say x. It's f it's simpler. Okay.
So time is just x. Okay.
So uh
so so
now
okay so now this you got a parabola
there uh and uh and uh yeah so x is
let's change x to time
tree. Okay. Because it's uh easier to
see. So So you got um let's just do it.
Okay. Keep keep typing. Keep typing is a
key for live live stream. Okay. You got
a problem. Uh oh yeah, you forgot to
evaluate. So manipulate. You got me need
to evaluate.
Okay, evaluate at add at add at add at
is a shortcut for the square bracket.
Okay, it's a prefix notation. Copy
that. Paste. Bet. Now, now how do I
play? Uh,
expand.
Play. Okay, there we have it.
Okay. So the parabola right you invert
it. You invert the parabola. Uh okay.
Now we can do something. You can
see now what is 10 squared? 10 squared
is 100. So it actually went all the way
to 100. So let's stop that.
Let's change it to 012 to
um let's say
uh change to 222.
Okay. Play back and
forth. Okay. So you kind of see where
it's going. Okay. Then let's shrink the
range. Okay. Now 22 two and shrink the
range two 22 two is four let's say
four the plot range is four and uh the
the time is from
-2 to two
okay copy that do it
here. Oh, now the the ball is
huge.
Okay, we got the ball going. Something
like that. Okay, now. Okay, stop
that. Stop
that. Delete that.
Okay, delete that. Okay, now the ball is
too big of course. Now the radius will
be uh 0.2 let's
say. Okay, and uh the plot range is
going to be
uh the yaxis is going to be
-4 to to zero. Okay, let's say 0.5. So,
so
that so that will be much better. So,
let's try
it. Paste run
it. Something like that. Okay. So,
that's one
ball. Okay.
Next, we can add a color. Okay. So,
color. So all you have to do is add a
color hue. Okay. Uh hue zero. That's a
rainbow color. Zero is red. Okay. So we
got a ball. Now we got we need several
other balls. Okay. So let's add them. So
we create a list. So this is one ball.
Uh let's put another ball here. Okay. So
copy. Now here this one let's say three.
Okay. 3 uh 0 4 is blue. Okay. 04 is
blue. Hu 04. So, and this but the the
path for the second ball if you look at
the um
animation. Okay. Can we
uh can we show the animation here?
Okay. So, the
path. Okay. So it's
actually red to blue the rainbow. It's
not the whole rainbow color. It's like
one/ird of the rainbow color. Let's
let's make our whole rainbow color.
Okay. Uh so that each ball is very
distinct color. Okay. So uh but but the
second ball Yeah. You see if you observe
that the you see you look at the second
ball like the this one. Okay.
Look at their path. It's a bit lower. So
basically a bit lower. So how do you
make the parabola lower? That's a basic
analytic geometry. So you got the
parametric curve uh lower just yaxis
minus. Okay. So you just minus uh like
minus let's let's try 0.2. Okay. So
let's see if that works.
Explore exploratory programming. Okay,
we got a error, comma, error, shift,
enter again. Okay, we got two balls.
Okay, we got green instead. Blue is
point
um 6. Okay, so there we there they go.
So they
actually, you know, they actually have
exactly the same path, but one is lower
than the other.
Okay. And increase the
speed. Fantastic. Okay. Now, you
see now one of them, you know, this this
is going to get a bit complicated. So,
so this ball uh let's just say red.
Okay. Let's just not with the
color. Let's say blue. Okay.
easier to read. So, red ball, blue ball.
Now, blue ball needs a slightly lower.
Okay. And uh it needs the path needs to
be smaller. Okay? Because so so the so
you will need to
um so you see the time is a parameter.
So t goes from
-22. Now for the blue ball the the range
must be smaller. Okay. Um so how do you
do that? The range must be smaller. You
can manually code it
by it. You see it the time varies. So
you cannot just minus something. You
need a oh yeah multiply. Okay. So again
this is fundamental of like calculus
like you know that's the first thing you
really need to master about about how
the parametric equation uh affect the
graph. So you can time 0.9. Okay. So
that time 0.9. Okay.
0.9. And uh this part
um same thing. Okay. So
uh let's put the negative outside. Okay.
Let's try it. Explore exploratory
graphics coding. Do it. Okay, we got red
and blue. Let's
see. Play it back and forth. Back and
forth. Increase
time. Doop doop doo. Fantastic.
Okay, now next we need to Hello. Hello.
Anyone here? Angan says, "Hi, I don't
know much about physics and math yet.
God recommended this. Could you tell me
what wu fam is and why are you doing it?
Okay, we're doing it to show
programming. It's a fun programming task
and it's doing animation graphics. So,
it's about graphics programming. So if
you are a student learning calculus or
mathematics or programming graphics or
you are a engineer uh or if you are a
professional scientist you want to learn
something about wufam language you heard
about it you never used it this is the
video to watch
okay and uh I've so I explained many
times in my past videos uh talk show so
there's a entire wam language tutorial
utorial where do you download it and
entire graphics tutorial I've I've done
like a 100 videos on wam language okay
uh okay so back to this so yeah did we
try this successful
fantastic
jud now we need to con connect the line
between the balls okay and actually we
can play a sound but uh yes we can Uh
well yeah you uh yeah yeah yeah you can.
So anyway so connect the line that's
easy. So you need a line
uh wait. Okay so you need the
line line takes a list of points. So one
point two point
uh or three points or more. Okay. So, so
let's let's add another ball
[Music]
actually. Okay. Now, this one is
green. Okay. Green ball. Let's say let's
this one eight. Okay. 8. And this point
uh six.
Okay. Three balls. Now, you need a line
connecting the three dots. Okay. Oh god.
So this you need to copy
that. That's the position of that one.
Then position of the second one. Then
position of the third one. Okay. So
after you done this, you can clean up
the code so that you know you don't have
to like repeat all these.
Okay. Okay. That's the
line. Now double check you got it right.
Yeah. So you got the line. Yes. And uh
make the whole
thing a bracket. Okay. So once you have
a bracket, you know, you can add colors
and stuff. Okay. But let's just try
that.
Okay. Fantastic. Are we are we
good? Increase
speed. Okay. Something is not
correct.
Wait. Okay. You forgot to lower them.
You see the green ball is too high.
So you need to um Yeah, you forgot to
lower them. Yeah. So the green ball is
uh let's say
0.3
0.6.
So back to language
here. Paste.
Now control shift
N to type set it. Now it's beautiful.
Now you see the type set automatically
formats on the fly. It's much better
than Python or Hascal or C or C++. You
know this technology has been around in
Wuam language since
1996. So you never need to worry about
tabs and space. You see there's no no
tab here. No, no indentation, but the
Wufam language you see, automatically
does it for you and on the fly, you
know, depending, you know, so as you
type, it automatically formats. So all
the, you know, industrial coders, the
Python,
Java, Goland, Hascal, this they are all
crap. They need to have this feature,
okay?
Automatic formatting on the fly. So I
talked about this in many videos in past
videos. Search for it. Uh the last one
is like three month ago. Search for you
know the Unix line truncation. You'll
find it my YouTube. Okay. So anyway, so
we got this. So shift enter to run it.
Okay. We got this animation. Let's play
it. Play it back and forth. Increase
speed. Okay.
Okay. Now you forgot to uh you see you
changed the formula here. So you forgot
to
Yeah. So
actually paste paste. Do it.
Okay. Play back and forth
faster. Okay. Now the balls needs to be
lower a lot. Okay, I think we got our
formula wrong. The green ball, look at
the green ball. They need to be much
lower. So there is something wrong in
our formula. Okay. Oh wait,
uh so the formula starts to get
complicated. Oh yeah, you forgot. So
wait, you inverted
uh you see we inverted. Oh, okay. So the
negative needs to apply to the hole. So
you got Yeah.
So
yeah. Okay. And you need to do the same
here. Copy back here. Paste. Run
it. Now it looks better. Now it looks
good. Back and forth. Increase speed.
play
Jun. Okay, that's
wrong. Okay, but similar. Okay, so you
know, so
but it's not correct. Well, the the
reason is because we need to ded with
this um this parabola. So let's think
about
it. Okay, so you shouldn't apply the
whole. So you invert it by applying a
negative then you need to move it
down.
[Music]
Uh you so you invert so parabola is like
that you invert it like that then you
move it down just minus right. So why is
our code not correct?
Um did we forget something?
You know why? Why is our code not
correct? Oh, then now you forgot the
line. Oh, yeah. For you see, did
you now? It's like the line is not
connected.
So instead of this you know now it's
getting complicated you should write a
formula so you don't have to repeat
this. So but
um so disk of
size two 0.2 into radius. And this
formula is that
uh so what is so you negative in oh that
uh wait you
negative negative the y axis you invert
it then
you move down right minus
0 three
uh but the line is not connected did
y.
So, so
the Okay. So, make sure we got this
correct.
Yeah. Need needs to be exact
copy. Okay. Yeah. So,
we missed that's why the green ball is
like not connected.
But
um but how are they different? 0.4
squared minus 0.4
Wait, how is it
different? Why is it
not? Oh. Oh yeah. So you forgot to
remove that.
Yeah. Let's try it.
play back and forth.
Increase. Okay.
So, so you need to be much lower. Okay.
So, but essentially we effectively did
this. Okay. So
0.3 is going to be one. Let's say okay
0.6 is going to
be two.
Wait two.
Okay. You know we need to figure out. So
you got a several balls and each one
their position differs slightly uh and
uh you know so you need to write a
formula so that you don't have to like
hardcode each one you can just so it's
systematic you know 0.8 0.6 6
0 4 you know uh you know but but the
basics is like this. Okay. So actually
you need
to now it's more like it you
see. Okay. So then you need to change
the range. The range will be different
for each ball. Uh that is the range.
That is the
um yeah the time this this 08 06 you
know that that changes this uh
range and you need to do some geometry
to figure out you know so given a curve
parabola
x² you know minus x^2 and plus or minus
some constant you need to figure out
when do they all align on the on the
uh you know kind of like V-shaped
axis. Once you know that the initial
initial time parameter for the parabola
then that's how you and how they relate
to two. So you want to make this -2 plus
or times or minus something. So that for
each one of them they will all start at
the uh at that. So that is some that
that part is mathematics. Uh you can
figure it out. You know you you need to
do some
plot.
Uh you know you can experimentally
figure it out how the initial
position is. You know how do you make
the initial position
align on a bar on on a diagonal bar? Or
you can solve this by mathematics
mathematically figure out you know the
square root. Yeah, you can actually
square root equals
to equal equals to a number on the x
axis and y axis. Okay. Yeah, you can
figure that out by solving a equation
very you know the most simple
uh and but basically we got this done
basically. So we got this
um we can now actually make make a
sound. Can we how do we play the
sound? Okay. Adding the sound will be a
a bit more difficult because right
now because Okay. So actually we got a
problem. Uh this is not correct
because the framework so far is not
correct
because the way we are doing it the the
order balls are just going back and
forth. They never become out of
synchronization. So you need to make
them out of synchronization. Okay.
So you know in that case you need to you
need to to start to use s and cosine
because s cosine that's how yeah we need
to do
that. Hey
Hank. So we coding this animation. So
um you know you can look at my website
talk show today on the link at the
description you can check out what we're
doing. So so
now we need to make this go back and
forth. Okay then that is okay let me let
me try to get that then that's it then
that that's basically it. So we need to
get the both. So right now the ball all
sink. Okay, that's not what we want. We
need to get the ball out of the sink. So
in order, you know, so in other words,
the
cycle is not just the beginning and end
you
see of the of the time range parameter.
So you in order to do that you need
to so between -2 and two you need to
start to get s cosine because
s is the function to repeat in
mathematics. Okay when you want a
function to
repeat basically sign is the function.
uh well sign is a smooth function. I
mean you know you could also define a
function such that you know during zero
and one is one from one to two it's
negative one things like that but then
it's not continuous stuff. So usually
sign is the best thing in math to to get
a cycle. Okay. So you want
um you want the let's just focus on one
ball. Okay. On on the on one
ball you want it to repeat this path. So
you want so so what you want is a
parametric
formula you know like this
one for x and y such
that such that doesn't matter where x is
the input the output is always back and
forth. Okay. So you want a function such
that let's say x goes from 0 to
10 but however your functions x will
will
become from 0 to one and back to zero
zero to one back to zero and so on.
Okay. So you can do that
by sign. That's right. You know, again,
let's just keep typing. Okay, let's just
keep typing and we'll see. So, you can,
you know, then you got you're gonna have
lots of fancy graphics.
Okay, so we got a sign. Let's just say
let's just say that it's going to be
like
wild. Okay, back here. Paste evaluate.
Okay. Show
uh back and forth increase
[Music]
speed. So you see they do they get out
of sync. Okay. So I don't know. Okay.
Yeah. In order for sign to work the
parameter needs to increase because sign
the period of sign is 2 pi. So the
parameter needs to be like
um like 20
pi. Okay. So something like
that. Yeah. We we can we can we can
check out what's going
on. Okay. Something happened.
increase. Okay, they went. Yeah. So, I
know. So, now let's keep doing. Okay,
before we do that, let's have a backup.
Actually, let's have a previous version
saved before we did the sign.
Okay. So this is before we do any
sign. Okay.
So okay this is
um all the balls are in sync from
beginning time param
to to end of time param. Okay that's
this version. Now we're going to start
to have them to be out of sync.
So this will be uh wait. So this need
needs Okay. So this needs to be
copy. This needs to be inside.
This needs to be inside. Okay. Now, all
we change all the parameters. Okay. So,
again, okay.
So,
copy
paste.
Copy paste. Okay.
Now,
now Yep. Now, let's try
Copy. Oh, and uh wait, let's just run
it. Uh
wait,
stop all the way to the bottom. Run
this. Uh wait, did we do
it?
Wait, this this there's no sign. Okay.
No, not that one. So,
copy, paste, run it. Okay, this is the
new
version. Play back and forth. Increase.
Okay. So they
don't wait. So this is not correct. We
are not seeing the effect of
sign. The effect of sign is should at
least have two cycles. So it should go
back. You
see if we play it just
forward you know it should automatically
come
back. Yeah because because we put the
sign there.
Uh but why is it not doing that? And see
sign. Let's make it all positive. Okay.
So sign becomes positive and negative.
Positive and negative. We want the x
axis to be
uh always positive.
Yeah.
So,
okay. Wait, did we get the error
somewhere here?
What? Paste. Okay. Do it now. Run
this. There it is. You see it started to
shrink back.
Okay. So now all you have to
do Yeah. So the x axis you see I see now
it's limited you see sign output is
always less than
one you know negative one positive one
okay cycles in between so you need to
increase
that to two okay
so god okay it's becoming more complex
X but we getting
closer.
Yeah, run it.
play. Okay.
Uh then we need to so they uh
so let's say
four. Uh now we got too many. Hold on a
second.
Copy paste run
it. Okay. Why is that 4 pi to 2
pi? It's not cycling.
I'll put
two. Okay.
So, okay.
So, so far so
good. Okay. So
um so so the input the time -4 pi * 2 pi
to 4 pi * 2 pi so the
input
is you know a huge
range 2 pi is like six * 4 is like 24
okay so we and change that to 24 you
know um 24 - 24 to 24 that's the time.
So when
-4 time s it always becomes -1 to one
you know then your absolute it's always
0ero to
one oh it needs to be
-2
so because par parabola you want to yeah
it needs to be negative so not absolute
so delete
that. Okay. Yeah. So that would be
better. So you need to be go between
okay between -2 to2. Okay. So that's
output for x axis. X- axis -2
to2 cycle them. Okay. The y axis don't
cycle. Okay. No, let's This should
do.
Um,
wait.
Paste. Evaluate
it. Run
it. Okay, it's not coming back. You see
this? Just one shot fast. Now, let's You
need to adjust the plot range.
plot range uh -4 to
4 x axis y axis is negative let's say
10 y axis -10 to uh to one okay to 0.5
okay let's say zero okay shift
enter
play. Where did they go? Okay, plot
range. It it disappears to the
uh let's look at this one.
Okay, we are not seeing cycling. Okay,
why is that?
So you go
through this is
like 24 let's say 30. Okay. So this is
like
30 30 to 30. Okay. And then t then sign
sin time
uh sine
time is always negative -1 to
one. So it will go back and forth -1 to
one. Then you multiply by
two. Uh wait you multiply when so it's
less than one. you actually shrink it.
So you want instead of divided
by two wait so this is negative one to
one let's just say zero zero to one you
* 2
uh u *
2 yeah time two is right
okay so you get um that
So, but why is that? So, plot range uh
let's say plot
range
10. Let's say pl range
20.
Copy. Paste. Evaluate
it. What is this? Hide controls. Uh,
play. There you go. So, it's kind
of
fascinating. Now, I'm not sure why.
Okay. So, it's it is doing a cycle, but
it is not doing the right
cycle. You see, it is doing
a Wait, it's not doing a cycle.
So there is something we did
wrong. Okay, we already coded for one
hour. I think maybe we should stop. Uh
So what is
wrong? So do we need to change the
yaxis the the function for
y?
No. Wait. Let's look at the x axis.
So you see if you look at the position
of the balls their xaxxis position it's
always within two and two you see right
so now we can if we inc in uh change two
to three then we got a wider thing
okay two two
three okay So then you get
wider. Now what about the y
axis? The y
axis. Why are they going up down so
much? Let's observe. Let's look at the
red ball.
Okay, let's stop.
So you go move you go. So when
it's Oh, I see. You see the yaxis they
become huge when when you range over a
large
number the y becomes very large that's
why they disappear at the bottom. So you
need to clamp them. So, so what you do
is you can you know so
again basic analytic geometry so you
need to clamp them by how much 30 squar
is 300 okay 30 squared is 300 you want
to limit it to between zero and let's
say
10 so so you need to uh yeah so you need
to
uh let's say two let's say what range we
want 10 okay so 2 * 2 is 4 3 * 3 is nine
so we let's say limited to nine we want
the y range to be within
nine okay so this
part this part should be within nine
Okay. So um and uh but you are ranging
over to 30.
So 30 times a number equals to 9. So
that means 9 / 30. So okay. So you want
to time 9 / 30 something like
that. Something like that.
which is 3 over 10. Okay. But
um Okay. But let's do it.
So Okay. Then you Yeah.
So So this is you need to do that before
you move. Okay.
So
that that
that before you move
them. That's right.
So
there,
there, there.
Okay. Let's add a
space. Copy.
Now let's see.
Fantastic.
Play.
Whoa. Okay. Stop.
Now look at the red ball. The red ball
is doing some kind of figure eight
curve. The red ball is
going. So if you look at the red ball
the x
axis it's within two and two okay it's
within three and
three but if you look at the y axis it's
going all the way to
so so this is not right if you so and
and uh let's see the look at the y axis
Look at the red ball y axis. So it's
going up and
down. It's going up and down in one
cycle.
It's going up and going
down. One cycle.
So something wrong with the
y the part for the the function for the
y. Okay, we don't want
So why is that going all the
way? So it becomes
20. So 30 squared is 300. Okay. So you
Yeah. 30 squared is 300.
Uh so
actually okay let's let's fix part range
x is 3 to
three. So let's make
um x
width equals to three. Okay let's make
it easier to understand.
Three.
Uh,
three.
Three. Uh, three.
Three. Three. Okay, that's a width of X.
[Music]
No. And
uh and uh so it's becoming more
complicated. So
y x2
So let's say time
range time range equals
to let's say 30.
Okay
20.
Okay. So then we got X range time
range.
Okay. Then you got um X range time
Uh so Y width. What about Y
width? Uh Y hat.
Why
good? Uh,
y let's say y width. Okay, y width is
should be uh just nine. Okay, negative
nine.
So if you want to
rename, so why is it Y going
up? You need to think about this. X
is X is
traversing. X is
XMath
Max. Okay. So, let's use a bit of
name. Okay.
Okay.
So x maxx time
max
xmath max
then
yax. So now
yax what should yaxx be?
So now yax should
be yax should
[Music]
be time max
squared divided
by you want Uh, let's say
five. Let's just say five. Okay, we want
it to be
five. So, we don't want it to go below
five. Okay, then. So, if you don't want
it to go below five, then the value
should be dynamic. It should be
um should be uh max
squared time something = to 5 5
/ that should be
uh something that like
that. Okay. y max divided by x * max^
squar. Yeah.
So something like that.
Okay. So this would be
five. Okay. So now you're getting
elaborate. Since you are defining
variables, you need to kind of clean
them. You see we here we use a uh double
colon equal. So that means it's computed
dynamically. Okay? Not just
static. You see here this this double
colon equal that means it's computed
dynamically. Okay. So now you yax needs
to be this.
Okay, now it's much simpler. Is it
good? It should be all
good. Okay, now copy that and it's
please make it work. Please. Oh god,
error. What
error?
Check coordinate something cell context
Y should be a pair. Okay, we got some
kind of
um some kind of syntax
error. Okay, that's the error message
there. Coordinate something sale context
Y. Okay.
So, oh wait, this wait this is this is
this is wrong. This should be five.
Yeah.
Copy.
paste it.
Fantastic. Let's
[Music]
see.
Woohoo. Now we talking. You see,
thinking does the work. You always need
to think. You cannot just like trial and
error. Okay. So, now we need to adjust
the plot range because we don't need the
whole thing blank under.
So you see because we we made it made
sure it's just five. You see that's
magic number. So let's define it
uh something like
that equals to equals to
5. So you got one more variable yax
height. Okay. So y max height equals to
five. Then you just the plot range is
just
uh negative yaxx height. And the plot
range for x is just x max
here. Fantastic.
Beautiful. Yeah. Copy. Make a backup. We
don't want to lose our code. Paste. Run
it.
Ren.
Beautiful. Slow down. Slow
down.
Fantastic. Okay, I think that's
it. Let's play this again.
[Music]
Fantastic. Beautiful. They come back to
harmony. Hi, Black. So, we so we can um
now now let's look at our
[Music]
version. Okay. So, let's speed up. Let's
see. And let's play back and forth.
Okay. So, we are very
close now. Something is not still right.
The you see just look at the red ball.
It's going up and down. It should
shouldn't go up and down. Okay. It
should stay in the same path. But we
need to fix it. Okay. But we, you know,
so that's how you do it.
Uh is there anything critical that we
are missing of trying to emulate that
thing? Is there something critical? Let
me think. So path by the way you can
change the path to any other curve. Then
it's going to be um you see the path the
path of the balls is this formula. Right
now we are using a parabola but you can
change it to like x² + minus y you know
x3 power or something you know so you're
gonna be uh it's going to be like crazy
very interesting uh effects that's what
these things are they are just visual
effects they are not actually simulating
physics visual effects so you need to
add some music. Uh now about adding
music um that can be done by um you see
the trick is to figure out when for
example when does a sound occur and
which sound. So a sound occurs when the
red
ball hits the boundary on on either
side. Okay. So when the red
ball x value is near a certain number
like -3 or and three then you play a
sound. Okay. And for each ball that's
the same thing but each ball have a
different sound. Okay. So you need to
add that. Yeah. So,
um, you can do that, but I, you know, I
don't know how to, you know, I never
done this before, but you can do that by
just um add, you know,
like when x is within three, the value
of x, which is this part, you know, the
the the value of this part is is
is near near let's say three then you
play a sound
okay like a quick sound like 0.1 second
t of certain
frequency you know you can play a sound
by uh in wam language you play a sound
by by this function
okay play just just say play okay play
uh play let's say sine
wave sine wave If
x
um x goes from uh let's say uh zero to 9
pi something like that.
Okay, that plays a pure
tone. That's too um that's too low a
tone. So you don't wait 800
hertz.
Uh I I don't think we can hear it maybe.
So let's times um 10
something. Wait times is increasing the
volume amplitude. So you need to
uh you need to
um increase the
frequency. See something like
that. Okay. No sound. Well, there's a
sound. Can you hear it?
But it's too um let's look at the
documentation for
play play function. So play that
function from t min to t max. There's a
good example here. 400. Okay. 400. Oh
yeah, you forgot the pi. So that's a
period. The natural period for sign is 2
pi. So let's add that to
uh
pi. Okay. So 10 is too low. So you need
for example they are using 400. 400 is
concert A. So that's a key in the middle
of a
piano about five semmit tones below.
Okay.
So stop. Okay, that's the pure tone
concert A. So but you can you can they
have lots of interesting sound. So
that's a s sound wave. Okay. So you can
specify how the duration where is the
duration play function sample rate
um play middle a sine wave for one
second. Oh, this uh duration is Oh,
yeah. Here actually
uh wait is it
uh yeah
so 0.1
second then it's just a beep. Shift
enter.
Fantastic. Now, if we double the
frequency, it's
the A one octave
above.
Okay. Okay. So, if we copy
that then
um then somewhere
here we add
We need a condition. Okay. So, so the
graphics. Okay. So, here is the
graphics.
Wait. Mismatch Kin. What the
Did I up
somewhere? Wait, why is my parade not
matching? Something is wrong.
I think I screwed up
somewhere. Okay, so hold on a second.
Let me make a
copy. Undo. Undo. Undo. Undo. Undo.
Undo. Undo.
and
do. Okay. Redo.
Redo. Actually, just copy that.
Copy
that. Paste. Okay. Now you need to make
a
sound. Now you need to make a sound. So
the sound is
here. Okay. Now you need to make a
sound. So you have to do back up. All
you have to do is this graphics
part. Uh yeah, the graphic the
animation. Actually, we don't need the
animation.
So the graphic spot, you just grab the
graphic spot.
Okay, leave it. So, animation add a
semicolon. So, that's evaluated
dynamically variable here. Then we don't
need evaluate anymore. Okay. So, for
example, double check. Go back here.
paste. Yeah. What is the
problem? Did we have a comma
somewhere
coordinate? Where did we up? It
works here. Shift enter.
Yeah, the code works
there.
Copy. Let's not try to uh you
know. So anyway, so that works. So
uh I don't like this format.
[Music]
Okay, let's manually fix
it. So, graphics animation. So, that is
our
animation and manually fix
it. There's one
more. Yeah, this tedious.
Uh then then there is
that. Yeah. So that's graphics. Then
then that then you want to also
do. So that's animation. And
uh then you add you want to add the
play. Okay, let's just
play. Let's play when
um if
X
time is greater
than X time
maxus min - X
max. Okay. So if if the time parameter
is near the Xmaxx boundary then we play
this sound. Okay. Play
else no. Okay. Else else
um you know we can we can remove
it. Okay. Now we added sound. Let's hope
it will
work. Paste evaluate.
Yeah. Uh you can do what's
nor manipulate is a
list.
So what is the problem?
Coordinate three signs. Something wrong
with our
coordinates.
What?
What? Yeah. Very annoying.
Oh god. What? What is our
problem? Corner three x
times. What is our problem?
Check syntax check
syntax animation that okay so you don't
need evaluate let's redo this so if x
time is if x time equals
to
max x x max minus
X. So if it's greater
than Yeah. So this is
wrong. So X maxx X maxx minus
so minus
0.2 some small
number. Okay. then play the sound and
uh and what what else? So plot range. So
let's double check everything. So
animation
uh you need declare a variable there.
So x time x
max okay x max height y max
height color
it okay uh divided by animation
red. So animation you got three balls
one ball two ball three then you got um
Then you got
uh three
lines I mean connecting the lines
connecting each ball. So one,
two, three.
Correct.
Correct. Then axis true and plot
range. That's the graphics. That's
good. Okay. Then you do
manipulate. Okay, it should be actually
should be like that. Then
manipulate of two things. The first one
is the
animation we define. The second one is
sound. Okay. So the sound
is so if it's x
time. Okay. So let's try this again.
Hopefully it will be correct. You
play do
it coordinate three sign context
something something minor is wrong.
Okay.
Something Yeah. So let's let's let's
just clean up this thing. Let's just go
full
out. Full out make this simpler. Okay.
Uh
[Music]
so function one equals
to Okay. Function one equals
to that
uh function two equals
to
that it's named B
one B one uh B
one position.
Okay. So, ball two position one, two,
three. Okay. So, you got ball one, you
got ball two, then you got ball three
position, which is that. Okay.
Then now then
um now then
then okay you got B one B two B three
then you can now simplify all
this B one position.
Okay. B2 position for
three or
two. Okay. So then here is the
same. So line now it's so simpler.
Okay. You don't need that
complicated. So now it's simpler. is P
three, P two. Okay, now
it's we needed this make it legible. So
position now. Okay, so position.
Now let's just
add let's just
clean what
the let's make it okay. So
now
yep. Okay. Now let's see what errors do
you have. So B and position depends on
the
variables T max. So time is there.
Yeah. Okay.
So don't don't give me arrow. it.
No. What the I don't
know what what if you just remove
that. Okay. Yeah, you got you got some
kind of coordinate syntax wrong
somewhere
here. Why is
it Oh, you got ball zero. So that's an
error.
Um y is zero. B two ball
three. Search for ball. One, two, three.
One, two, three. One. No, this is
two.
Okay, just copy and paste this. Abuse
the
system. Yeah, same thing. Okay,
so same
thing sine 3 0. Context
time coordinate sine
0.6 0.8. So this all
wrong. It was working
before. Xmax
uh
YAX. So where is So where is Yax used
there?
Okay.
Right. So Okay. So I don't know why is
it run
that run that okay 41
position what is the value okay it
depends on the x time that's
right so when x time is manipulate why
is it not
Okay. So somewhere the coordinate is
incorrect. So why is it the coordinate
incorrect? You know, I'm thinking it's
some short syntax
error. So this position is incorrect.
This should be two. This should be
three. So they lower. So right. So this
should be position two. This should be
three.
Okay. Position one, two, three.
Position.
Um that's right. B position two. Now if
you say both position two and
replace x
time
what we not
max
time replace by let's say x let's say mm
okay so that should work now if you
replace it by one you got a coordinate
okay now but why are so what what about
if position is ball one position
evaluate that's good now ball two ball
three evaluate you got a number Okay.
41, two, three. You got a number. I
mean, you got a coordinate when x time
is replaced to a number.
So, so you do have a uh So, you do have
a coordinate. Okay. So, this is B one, B
two, B
three. Let's change it position. Yeah.
Let's say just say P one.
Let's not rename. Okay, let's just leave
it
this. Okay. B1 B two B3 position. You
got that right. Uh and so this whole
thing. Oh Wait. So
graphics then you got the line. Okay.
You got the line of three coordinates.
One, two, three. Okay. And then the
whole
thing. Wait, how is this
work? Did
I screw up
the Okay, you don't need that. Okay,
then the graphics. That's right. Okay.
So, so something is
incorrect. Something is incorrect. Let's
try the animation there. Okay. Now,
remove the semicolon because that
suppress the
output. So,
animation, copy that. If you just run
that, you got the problem.
And the problem
is it keeps telling you the cell.
What the What
rational? Okay. So what we do is we save
this. Control S. Save it. Close it. Now
a new notebook. And we restart from
scratch.
We
uh
we evaluate quit kernel. Okay. So quit
kernel. Quit local kernel. Do you want
to quit? Yes. And we
restart. Okay. Initial. So now we paste
this. Let's let's just double check.
Okay. We got the time max. Okay.
Now time max is yellow. Okay. Xmaxx is
pink. Yes. Xmaxx
there. Yax
height. That's that's blue. Yax height
there. There. There. That's correct. Yax
is a dynamic variable
there. And X animation is this. Okay.
Now the boss comes before the
animation. Okay. Then then the
animation. Okay. So we got pause one,
two, three. Are they pairs? Yes. And we
got animation. This seems correct. I
don't see anything wrong. Backup time
max. Okay.
So,
copy paste run
it. Okay. Maybe maybe we shouldn't have
the
uh that that bracket all along. Okay.
So, so remove that brackets in the
animation
there. Yeah, I don't think it helped.
So, so it's saying it's
saying, okay, now I'm uh fairly pissed.
We basically did this 10 minutes
ago, but now I uh started to got this
kind of error.
So somewhere something is
wrong. So it says let's copy that error.
So it says the error message
says
coordinate coordinate that first
element and the second element. So we
got the rational rational -1 over 80.
Then we got the cell context
time is not a uh sale
context. Okay, this cell context this is
a
uh should be a pair of numbers. Okay, I
think I know
uh animation x time. So we yeah you need
evaluate I
think
yeah that's probably why okay we remove
that and we got all these errors
fact we tried to be more efficient we
removed the evaluate then we got this
error and that cost us like 15
minutes. Okay. So, you
always need to think you trial and
error, you waste time. Okay. If we think
about it, you know, we probably know
anyway. So, so, so this code works. Now,
remember, we need to add the the the
play. Okay. The the the sound. Okay.
Let's add a sound now.
Uh so make a list of things. Okay, this
is how you play sound and put the
animation. So the animation is the first
thing.
Then
if if
if x
time is greater
than x
time
max minus a small number let's say
0.2 then play the song. Okay. Then play
the song else do nothing. Okay. So
now we can just run this
part. Paste it. Run it. Okay.
Fantastic. Where is the
sound? And that's not too fast. Slow it
down. Okay. So, let's try again. If
greater than x time max, x time max is
uh
20. Okay. So,
wait. x time max is 20. Oh, not that.
Yeah, that's not what you want. You want
to x equals to Yeah. So you want to the
x width. So there x max. Okay. So when
it's when x time the time parameter is
greater than that then play a sound.
Okay. Let's try
again. Yeah.
And uh this no I don't want the no.
So yeah. So I don't want no. Okay.
So nothing represents nothing. Okay.
Nothing in wam language is
like like when it's inside the list and
when you nothing it automatically
disappears.
Okay. This kind of a feature you don't
see
um you don't see in other languages.
Okay. So that will remove the
new. Okay. Back here paste. Do it. So
now you don't see the no. But what about
the par You don't want the par
neither. Yeah, that's Oh, yeah. So, it's
easy. So, you should
um you just
animation.
Uh yeah. Well, let's worry about it
later. Okay. So, anyway, so now we
should have a sound. Let's
try.
No. Okay. It It play. Yeah. You see it?
It does that. That's not what we
want. You see, you want to actually play
it. So, how do you actually play it?
Well, you need to look at the
documentation for uh play. Okay. So, the
documentation for
play, how do you actually automatically
play the sound? Okay. scope at sound
audio audio play
uh in fact we can use emit sound emit
sound emits a sound when evaluated
okay let's try
[Music]
Okay. So that's one thing you can try
and
uh use image sound or you can
try let's just use image sound. Let's
let's I'm done for today.
[Music]
So
emit sound add that. Okay.
[Music]
Copy. Paste. Run
it. Expand.
Play. There it
is. Stop. Okay. Now the sound should be
uh why is it playing in so long? Should
be 0.1
second. It may
sound it should be 0.1 second. Okay.
[Music]
This is phone
tone. Okay. So 0.1 second. Uh let's say
[Music]
0.0 five second. Play the damn thing.
Okay, I don't know what's going on, but
take some time to learn about that.
That's it for today. Thank you guys for
watching. Bye, guys. If you like my
stuff, okay, go to my website, Kasi Talk
Show. Today's talk show. Uh, let's put
the code back. Okay, let's put the code
back. show in
browser and uh syntax color there is
today's
exploration and uh we go to the uh yeah
go to my website
kasali.info pay me okay kasali.info
info. Uh, go all the way to the bottom.
Patreon me, Amazon gift card, and
PayPal. Okay, thank
you. So, we end up doing two hours. Uh,
we actually kind of finished in first
hour, but we
got Thank you. Thank you, Black Automo.
Bye.