oh my god I'm such a dummy quite a few
times I have my video my audio is not on
all my video is not on something like
that [ __ ] [ __ ] I was such a dummy
that if that is why I constantly check
if I'm alive or not you know you have to
getting old okay finally my microphone
is on now I'm doing you a live talk show
and my microphone is off fantastic now
my son quality is crap okay yeah
something wrong here okay hold on a
second okay hold on a second where the
[ __ ] it's not protein that's why hold on
okay remove the audio and do it again
and see no no it's better now it's
better
finally I need new equipment I need a
new video camera I need a professional
camera actually I don't need I just need
a cheap camera that works better than
what I have here so guys put your money
in my pocket I possess PayPal and the
patreon and all that finally I know you
okay
we wasted four minutes and I wasted you
know I've been talking about all these
fantastic subjects but now it's lost so
let me repeat welcome to another episode
of saw talk show today is September 11th
Wednesday 11 o'clock a.m. San Francisco
California time the sunny state in the
great United States of
us-a the kingdom that rules the world
since since when since let's see since
1940s okay since since 1950 the
profession of Kasauli yes indeed
so so I just did a great proof of the
greatest mass theorem but that's lost
okay so it's let's see if we can be
captured
now this Arco is the there was a
difference of Russell's
not racism Huber's formalism in
axiomatic systems I wrote this back in
2007 I was totally confused now this
topic is about the foundation of
mathematics logic system formalism and
the stuff stuff and lots of stuff and we
were talking about ok this page Unicode
semantics the for all in turn a Gundam
have you guys seen that this is Japanese
anime you know turn Gundam it's a you
know I haven't watched this an anime but
however they have a epic song this is
the the last war for all you know this
is a math symbol for for the turned a
upside down a that's for all and even
reading that the the line the last war
for all makes me cry you know the now
this this is a epic song now you should
all check it out ok epic the last war
for all you know the last the last
something something the last something
the last emperor the last warrior the
last summer right you know that's a epic
title you know you're almost in every
movies the last something is dramatic
that's why we have all these the last
something by anyway this turn a Gundam
is a great song ok
great song let me post link here and let
me say oh let me say hi to all know the
turn a is now
predicates by the way the turn a
Stanfill for all if that's what you were
referring to that is a logic that's a
symbol used in mathematical logic for oh
good morning green deck and I haven't
said hi to bathroom you and Xetra
and Duncan and thank you for reminding
me about my muted microphone about my
stupidity
okay so we have great a lot topics to
talk about and I'm so busy working them
out right now and let's go to Chris our
talk show and first of all okay so let's
create a new window exhaust start
command log mod so in this window at
your servers you can see all my Emacs
commands for those of you MX phonetics
such as up arrow down arrow backward
forward so if you see any command you
don't know
check it look over there and you can
find it on my website just search for it
so now let's say Sal talk show today's
date it's a new page and make it a list
okay cut it paste it here we have it
here and now let's open that and paste
okay hold on second paste paste previous
space previous now that's it the last
condemned I want to put the link here so
that we have a record of me talking you
know even though I do just one hour talk
a day like one hour 90 minutes but it
turns out it's actually a lot work you
know one hour issue they'll take three
hours to you know everything involved
even though it's like spontaneous
impromptu extempore talking extempore
talking is my forte because
you know every time I try to focus on
something I'm trying to do do a good
presentation that doesn't work well like
yesterday I think how is yesterday's
video bathroom you you know I was trying
to teach the how to write a application
in JavaScript to plot math curves and I
wasn't sure what I was talking I'm you
know I you know I was trying to do it
it's not well so how was that yesterday
bathroom you so anyway today's topic is
going to be we digressed already but
today's topic is going to be bathroom
you okay so whether muses bathroom you
says number nine topic number nine is
programa style idioms yes indeed now two
days ago we talked about that but that
one is about how to how to do functional
programming functional programming
explained in javascript so that's that
is more of a tutorial kind of thing and
the day before that is about functional
programming concepts the history and
theoretical you know where they came
from you know we talked about that
without any code so we did a JavaScript
demo of that and today maybe we continue
of something about that programming
style related thing I think the problem
was the code itself and Nadia
explanation okay that's about
yesterday's JavaScript functional
programming oh wait wait that that was
about the plotting mass curves in
JavaScript yeah big yeah partly because
I would say I'm not being completely
myself because I was trying to do a good
presentation so you know because if I
was with myself then I would I would do
better because I wouldn't know okay this
code nobody understand then I would you
know just
you know I would know where to explain
like what like where to go how how to go
about it
usually when you know so at the
interview most of the time at interview
people think just has high school
graduate
you got this high school graduate and
who is eager to prove that he knows
programming like how to do a nested loop
they don't think I know how to do a
nested loop let's interview [ __ ] him
okay if you don't good don't if you
don't do good
[ __ ] them the [ __ ] the corporations you
know that these normal people this
normal you know help help the poor help
women help help black people help Africa
these people [ __ ] it that's excuse me
for my French okay that's okay let's
start to talk about something something
okay something important I want to be
something important you know like the
guy in matrix do you know anything about
chess scheme no I don't know anything
about chess game except it is one of the
best scheme it is the I believe it's a
fascist scheme it's written by one
single guy and it's a fastest best and
conforming scheme implementation if I
recall correctly am I correct
god I don't want to print Jesus am I
correct aside your impression greentech
let's lock up chest scheme ok chess game
so you have Wikipedia let's just go
quickly to Wikipedia chess scheme this
with the Rio de rigueur information of
the language scheme which is type of
this he uses the incremental native to
produce binary file
yes supporter since since version this
791 is free and open source oh this is
important it is free my friends it is
free and open source we should all use
it right away okay yeah so it's created
by this guy this guy is a great code
immediately what I don't wanna go now
okay so it's created by this ah what the
[ __ ] is going on back it's created by
this guy I can't type big okay
originally licenses as a proprietary oh
my god proprietary software and then
released as an open source of work on
github with version night yeah so Eve 34
years ago oh my god so it was a
proprietary and it made a name byte of
itself because it's it beats all beats
all the [ __ ] open source ones free
ones because that's how you proprietary
you know that's how you begin that's
actually how you to actually do great
things
well you know that there are a lot great
software in open source as well so I've
so green deck says I found about it cuz
racket uses it oh you are the one who
are trying to learn Lisp right was it
you who asked which Lisp to learn and
racket use it does record use it really
that's I'm not I don't know I don't
think so yeah he does okay okay maybe it
does no it's like they are powering the
engine you know because shares chess
game was the fastest you know racket
scheme is one of the slowest scheme for
educational purposes they are good for
education yeah so chess scheme you know
he's very famous very very popular so
you got my confirmation I
I you know I'm not a scheme coder so I
never actually used it so I want to get
back to programming idioms and style and
stuff so but brief but briefly let me
just close these windows and let me
mention okay this is a gray so okay
check it out
means for all and I was wondering
because when I see this you see this is
the the mind of my my mind that the the
curiosity of my mind see you see I'm
sitting on my chair and looking around
the internet and one day I saw these
phantom you know the Japanese animation
you know gun time is about do you guys
notice about Gundam maybe so maybe not I
mean if you are young guy even young guy
maybe not because condom is a old
animation okay it's a Japanese animation
so it's about all these mecca's yes
indeed so you see all these make us so
the story is about what Japanese science
fiction you know you have all these make
us you know you have all these are good
guys okay these are the good guys now I
want to show you some bad guys this this
is okay so this is a wrong word to
search it's such for last war for or
condom okay I actually should put condom
in front
you know Japanese they they make great
science fiction and also they make all
these machines so you see here are the
japanese-style spaceships and
transformers they kind of they have that
anyway these are not good pictures I
want to show you some of the mecca's you
know the bad guys oh these are you know
these are about these good guys but they
are so many okay this this is this a bad
guy I anyway I forgot so anyway so
Japanese animation you know science
fiction he and anyway so that's about
condom okay so yeah so so one day I saw
these and you you see these turned a
character so I was wondering you know
whether this decide mean do they did
they actually intentionally used the
logic symbol for all you know as a title
or was it just by by chance you know
they have a turned a you know you know
because for dramatic reasons or you know
whatever artistic you know they just
created that so I was wondering about
that question what does the turned a
actually mean you know was the was it
intentional with this logic symbol or
not so it turns out it is intentional
the title is the last war for all but
the title is usually read as turn a
Gundam
turn turn a means turned a so anyway
that's a story of the exploration into
this issue unicode semantics the for or
internet turn a Gundam okay and anyway
this this is a fantastic song okay so
that is that
and this we closed that we don't need
that why I hate see indeed why I hate
see see is worth hating okay so so
Duncan home says don't come home wait
were you from and battles battles says
they are rewriting racket in share
scheme country oh okay that's why okay
they are rewriting you know bracket
scheme has also been old it has been at
least like 30 years so I was looking at
it you know in since 1999 1998
I even tried it back then the last time
I actually the last time I used it is
like three years ago I was doing a
homework for someone paid homework for a
university student so so that's what
so that time three years ago I actually
looked into I read the entirety of the
racket scheme documentation and you know
and wrote again kind of a murder game
you know the the game that the hacker
types the programmers like you know like
or text idiotic game like you you like
oh you see you see you see your turn oh
do you enter or not you know I don't
know what what's what's the what's the
attraction with that game you know you
guys know what I'm talking about like
mud mu D game anyway that's about racket
scheme so let me catch up with the
comments then we talk about let's talk
about the programming idioms
so battles says how many browsers tabs
do you usually have open I have dozens
to hundreds of them maybe I should look
into bookmarking services do you try to
manage it somehow ok let me tell you my
solutions typically I have like 20 ok 20
to 30 opened ok
the oh this is Second Life this is
Second Life Mecca
you know they duplicate make you have
all sorts of this is american-style
Mecca
you know like American steroids like
that now this is a japanese-style Mecca
people made it you know and it can
transform this is avatar by the way so
in second life second life by the way
it's like a 3d game I talked about
several times in my videos so it's like
a 3d game and everything you see is made
by people like you and me so people have
created this avatar which you know
represent yourself you put it on and and
you see it's so fascinating so people
are so creative you can so you you wear
this avatar and you can transform
yourself into this yet right so well
this is our life you know 3d in virtual
world you know like again you know like
a 3d game so inside you are like you are
this guy you know you can talk and type
whatever then you can press some button
and you become you transform into this
this jet fighter oh yeah and you can fly
you see this is how he is flying above
this face and then you have this say
sabre tiger this is from the cartoon
Zords do you guys know about that
cartoon so it's I think it's an American
show I forgot you know it's basically
basically all this mecha in the shape of
animal forms anyway Oh Andy ok so this
is what what's fun about Second Life you
can write them so again let me say this
is avatar ok avatars are made by by
people everything you see in Second Life
in
entire thing like like my minecraft okay
like my my you know probably most of you
know about my craft you know which is
idiotic because in minecraft everything
is just a square you extremely idiotic
but anyway
minecraft shares similarity to second
life in that there is no goal
you know you're just going in you to
whatever whatever you want and
everything you see is filled by people
so that's the same for second life
except second life is not squares you
know you can create all this everything
you see you know the avatar the
buildings all these buildings you know
regions places or black people well
anyway this this page focus on Avatar
you know transformers like all these
make up transformers so you have so you
have someone build this okay you know
once you build it you can give it off up
for free but usually you sell it like in
Linden dollars which is usually like one
dollar or two dollars sometimes five or
ten dollars USD so you know you can buy
it so anyway so this is an avatar so
someone you know in Second Life you are
this mechanical cat okay but I can you
know you so this is me this was me in
second life this girl okay you can write
it so so it's tremendous fun you know
suppose this is your friend you know you
can write on his back and he can he can
go about you know take you to places so
green the excess maybe second Ivy's too
complex indeed and minecraft is
accessible even to some for small kids
yeah that's I guess that's true but I
truly despised my minecraft [ __ ] you
know in a world of technological
progress you know we are trying but then
then this guy come up with this list
[ __ ] Lego blocks leg up
squares this is the [ __ ] [ __ ] you
know and also a lot nuts they love Lego
like every day on Twitter you see Star
Wars they go oh piano made of Lego oh
the biggest Lego sculpture to [ __ ] a
bagel and despise the Lego you know Lego
is the most you know is why do why do I
do despise it because of of the word
elegance you know what the word elegance
and and you know elegance and beauty and
and then you have this lego [ __ ] you
know either
idiotic you know this bricks you know
you push them together you to create
things the [ __ ] idiots this this this
hacker whatever types of nerds with that
with there they go
idiocy Lego and and Lego and minecraft
anyway so you got all these avatars you
know this transformer transform us and
make us in second life and what I want
to emphasize here is different styles
you see you see this this one okay the
magnifier so this one is kind of like
American style makeup like Japanese they
don't do it this way and this one is you
know [ __ ] Japanese style although much
simplified you know much simplified
because Second Life Tech is actually
pretty bad so you know you know there is
tremendous hack to create to create all
these things you see including you see
this different see friend
yeah and so but it's amazing though all
these people a lot of them in Second
Life
are kind of artistic people you know
they are kinda like us okay like you
know you and me like in my [ __ ] my me
and my followers in who not not
mainstream okay so a lot of people so
very creative they create is they
created see plain you know in Second
Life that that's modeled on real see
plain you know
like 50 years old cPanel there are a lot
of them like like I have a collection of
heat pictures you know okay so I guess
are we still going to talk about because
I don't think we're gonna have time if
we continue in this road here is another
Android this is Android this is
american-style Android so created by
people and then you have these androids
you know you know you can wear them and
this this this is a famous Japanese a
iPod in in ghost in the shell it's kind
of like a comic comic characters all
these are avatars you can wear you know
you can you know you you become that and
in Second Life you walk around so for
example this is this guy's name have
iong waik that's a second life account
name so anyway so you have all these
different orbitals and you have this
math now this math is called replicator
neon Viper it's from its from a sci-fi
I'd I'm not familiar with this sci-fi
you see when I go in Second Life I saw
all these things I look them up I to
research like where is this character
came from so I I found out you know it's
a now I don't have the name here but I
forgot but it's from a size from a
sci-fi anyone knows this math okay then
you have this spider and and you and
then you have this cyborg style kind of
thing so you see this guy he's got
spider legs and so this is amazing
because you know in Second Life you got
all these amazing things in so many
aspects because first of all sci-fi
first of all this is sci-fi I mean I
like sci-fi probably you do
we like sci-fi right but then it's
amazing that people creates these you
know in Second Life you know this
tremendous creativity and hack it's not
easy it's not easy to do this okay it's
not it involves so many things it it
involves you know you have to hack well
you know second life you know the
technology building and scripting is
very bad okay so you have to find your
way to actually overcome it to actually
create you know to pio this shape you
know to be of this shape then you have
to then you see all these textures and
all those are images I mean you have to
you have to be able to follow sharp well
okay no some other software Photoshop to
create these images and map them into
the body so you create this okay I don't
have a high resolution so you have to
create you know so it involves painting
drawing skills it involves programming
skill why programming because when this
guy walks the legs walk you know the
legs actually walk like you know well
this is four legs but they are also a
leg so so you have to find a way for
example to create this you know I'm
talking but you know you'll be impressed
when you are actually in Second Life
when you actually see it so and it's so
much fun because this is your friend you
know you wonder you see your friend you
go easy to sing live and your friend
feels like that Wow
and you guys just chat you know about
things you know life or whatever you can
you know you guys chat so when you see
this walk you know so whoever did this
he the guy or she must find out you know
how does four leg you know how would for
lake creature walk you know machine like
this how oops what do you call the gate
you know the gate you know what
which leg to move to make it realistic
things like that you know so people
created that it's also from social as
like that's incredible creativity and
you teaming with it the second IV is
teaming with them so in all areas but
anyway so that then you see that this is
a cybernetic leg you know someone
created then you have the Star War
things Star Wars kind of the most boring
and you have the matrix think this
Sentinel and some I also created this
scorpion again you know the legs you see
notice the lakes they must walk they
that they must follow proper gauge so it
looks you know good it looks good
so all these avatars many of them sell
and you buy them you know so so yeah
there's for many there's an incentive
you know you created you want to make it
beautiful you get your friend you know
who are good at drawing you know artists
you know to do this for you and you sell
it and you make money and they are quite
a few millionaires who sell stuff in
second life and become millionaires in
real life but most of them are selling
sex things sex toys that's that's
another huge and deep topic that's what
makes the world go around
almost every technology poem is is
thriving Tom gets gets going and money
good morning sod so bathroom you so you
be in second life bathroom you says I
still remember flying in second life
oh yeah just that the normal of no more
flying yeah okay so and then you have
this Mecca you know this can shoot you
know just different styles of makeup so
you get you have that and you have this
one now this one is Japanese style okay
this one is clearly Japanese style Mecca
again there's another interesting
perspective
so all these
sci-fi right and almost all these are
Android or cyborgs or makeup or
machinery right humanoid in humanoid
form but now in one interesting aspect
is to look at the styles like different
you see this one is most likely American
you know it doesn't like this one you
know this doesn't like it's not Japanese
style even though it's it has you know
the L you know Japanese kind of things
like the shield you know but then but
this one is obviously champion style you
know they made that you know some
Japanese I think some Japanese made it
then you have this okay so this one is
another fantastic one
now this is very realistic this is
another American style mecha you you
know just by pictures you don't see much
but when you see it you know in the 3d
that's impressive very impressive so
like in this game oh yeah so this is a
war zone war war war zone I mean in this
is a battle area in Second Life I
remember going there fighting you know
you shoot like first-person shooter and
okay actually I have some videos so
someone recorded of me
let's see YouTube sorry
Second Life okay so are we still going
to talk about sabatham you you you you
have to say are we gonna just continue
on this road or should we start to talk
about programming style oh my god it's
already 37 minutes okay
okay I wanted to show you some of the
I wanted to show you some of the you
know I I was in a mechanic mechanic oh
steampunk
oh yeah steampunk is another thing okay
so okay so then hold on a second let me
read the comments let me take a break
read the comments
so oh okay
so we digress there's a question about
how many tabs I have okay so usually I
have like what tündi tabs okay 20 about
20 in each browser like typically right
now I'm running vide YouTube so I don't
have the other browsers but usually
Safari and brave and Firefox and he's so
open each one has like 20 20 tabs also I
keep it then I keep I try to keep them
under 20 no more and and never remember
never ever use crowd don't don't
bookmark to cloud not don't do anything
cloud okay if you are like me you are
probably a bit like me because you
followed my stuff well anyway so I you
know don't do crafts don't don't poke
much yeah bookmark but don't don't cloud
it and so likewise like today you have
YouTube right YouTube you follow people
right you follow a lot of people so it's
all in a crowd you have a list of your
followers let me stop this okay so you
have these some followers in that's all
cloud in Google today is to in
censorship and all kind of nasty things
some you know I heard but I have not
confirmed myself that Google will remove
people you follow from from your list
you know automatically like for example
on political topics they will just
remove people like and you don't know
because you have like 25 you are
following 20 or 30 people
you don't know when Google just removed
it you know so that's you know Google
and you know cow
the problem is with cloud they are doing
that you don't know so one good thing to
do is to never use cloud at least I
don't so and also specifically today
since about three or four months ago
Google search Google YouTube search in
Google search as well but in
particularly YouTube you cannot find the
videos you watched before anymore
because Google now as you know mostly
about political topics because Google
will just show all the mainstream media
results they will not show you know
individual people like like you or me
results so it's all mainstream it's like
Google it's like TV it's like TV thirty
years ago from these giant corporations
who has a agenda you know they want to
sell whatever so so yeah what can you do
so what you can do is like always when
you see a video you like book market but
book market you know either in the
browser or in a text file you know save
it for yourself
don't use crowd okay because you are you
are not be able to find it again like
today if if today I saw some video that
talks about some controversial topic and
I you know suppose it's funny for
suppose it's a rap you know you know but
next month you will not be able to find
it even with the full title keyword you
will not show up in search so you just
have to bookmark it you know yeah so
that's that's about tabs and bookmark so
I try to keep them under 20 because
because usually it tends just to pyro up
you know so I try to every time this
more than 20 I try to clean it typically
save it to my Emacs you know to read
like I have a for example let's go to I
have a kind of to read
Paige kind of you know the bunch of
links from long ago sometimes you know
kind of so yeah so the best thing to do
is to save everything on your local file
and all all the people you follow put
them into a list in in a text file
it is axel actually there's a lot work
but that's almost inevitable it's like
people want convenience and the way
YouTube and all Twitter everything the
way they are is because convenience
people just want convenience you know
they like you are a cat in a matrix you
are happy you never want to get out so
okay let me read the comments and so
that's about tabs batos what's the code
itself not your explanation okay so do
you know anything about your scheme okay
they were rewriting racket okay and
Duncan says Duncan says you probably
said you never design objects but that
means you don't get to leverage one of
the central features of go line
interfaces well I guess that's true I
mean we once you don't use
object-oriented programming you don't
you interface becomes rather useless to
you well but yeah in general that's true
because I just do functional programming
in functional programming you don't do
interface well they also a lot meaning
to the word interface okay I believe the
first one who popular popularized the
concept of interfaces is Java or was it
maybe it was C prosperous but I don't
know C purpose for tuned for to me to me
the the java popularized the concept of
interface
now however they are a lot meaning of
interface for example API applications
program application programming
interface that's an interface that has
nothing to do with opie and typically
it's all functional well sometimes it's
okay okay anyway so that's one meaning
of interface but in Java interfaces a
Smith specific technical meaning okay
now in functional foreign languages you
also have a concept of interface but you
don't call it that you usually usually
you call the functions signature okay
which in languages like Haskell it's
kind of like a type so what does the
functions signature means means what are
the parameters and they are type and
what does the function return and it's
type you know that that is a function
interface sometimes called the functions
signature I don't like that term okay
it's stupid terms of function signature
so anyway so so that's functional
programming concept of interface now in
: now in colon specifically colons
interfaces is kind of both ok so go
lines interface on one hand it's you
know like Opie interface basically means
what you know this object what method we
would have you know that's the Opie
concept of interface now but colons
interface is more than that it's also it
also functions as a type like what's you
know so you also function as the type I
cannot explain it because I you know I
am NOT expert on that goal add that
detail so yeah so that's what I'm saying
about about that Duncan so for me I
don't yeah I don't use you know the the
only the only I haven't used interface
much so far I haven't used it because
function of
I don't use it but when I do use it I
would I will if I code more goal and I
will find use of it but it will be for
interfaces as a type you know like it's
more more of that sabatham uses pattern
Mia says the attraction with mods is
that it basically doesn't didn't cause
any computing resource and yet the world
was virtually infinite and you could
have ultimate freedom okay text text
it's kind of boring way compared to
other game especially at the time where
mods were new and successful you should
watch the GDC video of the original mod
creator it is a one hour and for why
such a text-based
type game is far superior to many other
game types in many aspects okay GD g DC
video of original mud
okay let's it's just such it i watch it
later okay okay something like that this
one miss your bat oh and astonishing
contrivance okay what is GD I don't even
know I you know
okay let's next comment so green deck
size maybe second IVs too complex okay
we talked about that good morning good
morning sod path of me says I answered
your question green deck says how do you
subscribe to people RSS if so how do you
read them I don't use you know I don't I
hard to be ever read blogs I mean even
when blog did not die even when Prague
was thriving it turns out I just don't
read them much
you know other people's blogs because
I'm too busy writing my own well I mean
I mean some people like then then you
know but some people's blog I like to
read definitely but but in reality turns
out I just don't it just so happens I
don't actually read the much blogs for
example Steve Steve yags
blog I like I would read every one of
them but you know it turns out I just
never
I just never actually used RSS you know
- yeah I just don't use it and for
example but but but certainly there are
a lot of people I like to read Steve
Aoki's example Stephan Wolfen is an
example you know the creator of
Mathematica and Wolfram Alpha but I
don't subscribe to it rather I just
every month they also I you know just go
to his website and for time you know you
used when blogging was popular people
used to have another jargon block row
okay another idiotic jargon jargon I
don't like okay you know these
fashionable hackers they have block row
you know block row is basically the
proper way to say it is a list of people
I follow okay [ __ ] you block row but I
can roll a [ __ ] it's at least the people
I follow okay or at least the people
Lisa blockers bloggers I like that's
what block block row is anyway so that
was popular so I for why I thought about
creating a block row too but it did it
it's just not my thing it doesn't it's
not my thing
please especially for example in emacs
community you know we have a lot MX
bloggers and usually they have blog blog
row but I just never had well I have
something similar like you know
at least the people I follow I recommend
you know Emacs Plagas I have article but
that's ten years old and and most of the
people bloggers they come in go to you
know it's like they stopped writing
after year o to things like that unlike
me you know I don't I don't stop i I do
one thing I continue you know till one
day I'm dead so I personally read RSS oh
yeah l feed so if you like to use RSS L
feed is a Emacs package it is a RSS
aggregator that's another jargon you
know used to be popular RSS aggregator
or RSS readers so alpha'd is a great
package sabato says I'm actually
developing software in Python to add
some intervals every 30 minutes
scraps websites that are of interest to
me pass that and save in to the bat
database oh okay Duncan says the YouTube
download COI utility can be used to
easily download an archive of videos
yeah but but you need a lot hard disk
space you know you know what is
interesting is that you know they say a
picture is worth a thousand words a
video is worth ten million words and
that fact is actually reflected in file
size too because a image file is hundred
times larger then you know text file and
the video file is 1,000 times larger
than image file so you know I you know
for example I've done video like one
hour a day for for half a year already
so six times so that's 180 videos one
hour long
and I thought about you know trying to
archive them in case gogo deletes me but
that's I don't have Hadees you know you
know each one each one is like one
gigabyte now once you go by doesn't
sound much today no but in my mind my
idea of a hard disk is still 40
megabytes from 1980 to 40 megabytes hard
disk so so bathroom uses recently I
don't look sorry your channel with that
in mind
oh you did you download my channel how
many megabytes gigabytes is that so
salsa is fair enough I try to keep my
email RSS separate as I get buffer
overload I use I three window manager
okay
so green deck says okay yeah so answer
that about RSS I happens to not use it
the closest thing I do is I bookmark
actually I don't even use bookmarking
browser because if you bookmark a lot
bookmark mark what happens with me at
this is that you know browsers changes
all the time like you you switch browser
like you know II's dead or something and
bookmark and when you switch computer so
long
bookmark tends to it happens with me at
least it just lost you know I mean like
you stop using a browser you but anyway
basically what I do is I just save it to
Emacs I like for example this let's say
there's for example this article I find
very interesting I copy it then I just
put it in my Emacs let's see to read
create a new section put it there link
of five paragraph showing browser you
know that's what I do so it kind of
becomes part of my website almost so I
mean this is what I do now so yeah I
don't even bookmark then you know once
in a while after a month or two I check
the links you know and go read them you
know because as a society you know after
ten years twenty years to the past
twenty years information they are going
exponentially they are growing
exponentially you have so many things to
read and and most of the time actually
this is true most of the time reading
blogs or any any any of the social
networks is actually just a waste of
time and actually including I was going
to say including videos videos takes a
lot time to watch well it's not
absolutely true though I mean there are
so many great videos okay
not including my I mean there are so
many great videos that really teach math
you know that's really good and also
programming us where I guess but videos
takes a lot of time but what I'm saying
is that there are so many videos and you
know especially the videos like those
with my medium followers they are just
crap they are just like [ __ ] and
more vast you know yeah vast majority of
YouTube videos it's like total [ __ ]
ninety nine more than 99% 99.99% of
videos let's let's just waste of your
time and bad quality and not you know
not fun anyway and this is true for
blogging you know anything on a web -
for social media so what so you see my
point is that you know I always wanted
to be one of the greatest mathematician
okay Oh a great programmer who did
something important okay so let's say
you know let's say wrote you know like
Google search engine in a beginning you
know did something important you know to
humanity that that was that just me okay
that's that was my thought I always
wanted to do those kind of things but if
you really want to do those kind of
things
you don't read blogs okay and you don't
watch a youtube video you don't watch
movies you don't go to the go to Twitter
you don't do any of that thing you read
you know you study the subject matter
every day you work you know you just do
that you know do that for ten years now
if you are young you can do that you
know then you have then you'll be great
you know do what it if you know you
don't like it's this this is just it's
you know it's a preference it's not
everyone like you don't nobody says you
know you know it's it's not true like
like you have every you know you have to
be a great mathematician or anything
like that you know you can just do what
in your life you know okay so
so so we got this Russian guy whose name
I cannot pronounce but his name
beginning with M reverse and something
something okay so Russian M says what
are your opinion about Haskell is it
language for the future of programming
how is they compared to Mathematica well
I talked about this often you know I'll
just give two sentence similar summary I
don't like Haskell ok because I don't
like Haskell because it's pop popular is
because all the you know this is the new
kid in town Haskell is actually a old
language is thirty thirty years old or
something but it's only in the past ten
years to be it becomes popular somewhat
popular so I don't like I don't like it
because it's pop is everyone every idiot
on the Internet is talking about it you
know when you look at what they say they
they are idiots okay they don't they
don't know what they're talking about
they did but they say Oh Mona Mona is
the greatest invention Oh math Oh
category theory they don't know nothing
about math you like you read you know if
you know some math you read them they
don't know nothing so I don't like
Haskell and I don't think I'll ever
learn it the language I I'm more likely
to learn ah meta language I talked about
this often in my video so meta language
which Oh cam Oh F sharp those are you
know one family oh those are from email
meta language okay in Haskell but also
Haskell is pretty old so in terms of for
programming languages typically new ones
are better okay everyt everything use
whatever is new new after 10 years it's
better Haskell is kind of from from from
a pure functional programming language
perspective I mean if that's what you
are into I don't think has cow is one of
the good ones this is just the first one
okay I don't I so I don't like it in
many ways
but I do love functional programming
okay now how does it compare to
Mathematica oh I love Mathematica
hundred times more than any functional
any fancy functional programming
language this Haskell
Oh cam Oh F sharp idris what whatever
Mathematica is like a hundred times
better
except it's slow one one line of
Mathematica is is ten lines to 1000
lines of a Haskell okay
because Mathematica does symbolic
computation symbolic algebra you can
solve equations you know you can do
integral sub matrices solve equations
sub differential equations you know the
in one line one line of code you can
compute PI I demonstrated last time he a
few days ago PI to 1 billion places just
five characters you know one line just
five here does PI to 1 billion places
you know how many you know you more you
know your Hadees cannot store the result
so Mathematica is far superior than door
that but however Mathematica is based on
pattern matching so I did a video
talking about that you should check it
out okay this is about 10 days ago
there's a video on you know just such
folk sorry Mathematica YouTube ok
there's a one-hour on on Lisp pattern
matching and there are there are two
videos one is about these languages and
one is about Mathematica they are side
by side you know next to each you know
like today and tomorrow you know just so
check out that video okay bathroom you
know says anyway it's called mud masa
butter into that star astonishing
contrivance okay what is that
hey good morning Deon pathos says you
said you have around tiny tabs in each
browser do you find it comfortable to
switch between browsers I prefer to just
heavily customized Firefox and use that
well I the reason I use moto multiple is
like in Firefox I have cookies off
completely JavaScript off completely so
in Firefox is mostly just my my own
website and Wikipedia
so this algo is interesting most vexing
parts this is about C++ C++ idiocy
so anyway so you see all these my my my
mostly my own website you know I you
know I do in Emacs I show in browser is
Firefox so javascript off cookie off
that's that's Firefox so when I want to
visit some side web search you know some
let's say okay let's go to talk and
let's go through today so let's say
virus and I can search it it's in
Firefox you know so all these you know I
know no JavaScript so you can do nothing
to me almost nothing okay so and it's
fast okay every website is fast and I
use Chrome well anyway so Safari and I
also use brave and Safari brave is for
Twitter and mastodons and other social
networks I use Google Chrome only for
Google accounts because Google now is
extremely evil they they even have a
option for example if you go to settings
they have option they will check they
will scan your hard disk for you for
viruses like do you want do you do you
want me to scan your hard disk or
viruses yeah Google Google Chrome is
doing that now incredible [ __ ] evil
you know they want to know everything on
your hard disk yeah so the browser now
they are going to you know scan your
hard disk for viruses somewhere here
there's the option begin like two years
ago so I don't trust Google okay so I
don't the only
the reason I use Google Chrome is for
Google accounts you know and Google is
so evil that that many of Google's
websites they specifically they make
sure that this website only runs well in
Chrome
they did that you know they are proofs
they are there you know there are a lot
you know articles you know but they did
so Google is doing that so they make
sure their website only runs somewhere
in Google Chrome the [ __ ] Google and
also Google is so big and censorship and
they do every order Evo today so you are
even not sure like right right now like
if you log in to other website via
Google Chrome can you be sure they are
they are not actually you know stowing
your password in in the in their
database you never know you don't know
you know if you are open-source fan you
will say oh but chrome chromium is open
source not known you don't really know
they can do that they do that you do you
wouldn't know until one day Oh big news
you know some leaked leaked memo saying
that Oh Google did this that's too late
yeah so you cannot trust you know you
don't know what is going on you don't
even you don't know so I don't use so
that's Google Chrome and and yeah so
anyway I use different browsers for kind
so we and I don't like Firefox because
Firefox if you don't know I talked about
this a few times Firefox donate it to an
Tifa you know like you go to such you go
to the YouTube and try to search Mozilla
donate to antiva you'll find a new it's
like two years ago they you know Firefox
is you know all these are social social
justice so I don't I don't trust Firefox
either five and and not just that you
know Firefox has in the past few years
this you know they have big news they
are doing evil things like you know
so bathroom uses six 2.20 oh my god so
better of you so you got sixty two
gigabytes of my my youtube videos so one
day if google cured my account I'm gonna
ask you I'm gonna ask you for help
six two jjigae versa so you are the only
one well you have you know the archive
of my videos bathroom uses the videos
are in best quality that I could
download from YouTube directly okay
greetings Dion greetings carbon
greetings
carbon so carbon says I have just two LG
ultra wide monitors that's like four
feet of desktop and I have 237 tabs open
[Laughter]
20:37
tabs open
I still can't long divide I want what I
said what does that refer to I forgot
yeah download YouTube you know I have
sorry sorry everything sorry YouTube
down load okay I have written about that
tool Linux command to download YouTube
videos okay so that that is the the
website and that's how you use it in
fact I have a Emacs shortcut for example
YouTube u TT okay that expand to that
for example let's go to shell
okay let's we are in Asia now let's go
to III okay
i-i-i-i is a directory where when I want
to download something new new video i go
to the i directory it's a temp directory
so now we are going let's go to e shell
and now YTD
space there you go that's the only
options unix [ __ ] that's the old union
UNIX [ __ ] incomprehensible options then
you paste the URL you want to anyway
things change okay so every month or two
when you try to download a video video
it will not walk you will say oh it
doesn't work you know it cannot pass
something because YouTube and all these
treater like Twitter on Twitter I
downloaded poem yeah it sometimes you
see it I want to capture it so you know
YouTube download in the main the treated
you know that post URL so but once you
know every every month every two three
months something we are not walk then
you need to update so there's a command
so there is a command update okay so you
PDA te so you can okay so let's do main
page main page youtube download go and
this is
humongous page you know like for example
let me show you how many what one okay
wait one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven [ __ ] pages
seventeen hundred lines of man page so
this you know this this is very
extremely complicated command YouTube
download okay but anyway so what was I
saying
I forgot well YouTube Donna oh yeah so
there's update okay so you see this
option update so you can run so if I
press enter you're right okay let's just
try it so you will automatically install
the latest version then you can try to
download whatever
alright permission okay so you have to
do sudo sudo one of the UNIX [ __ ] UNIX
idiocy sudo okay password okay so you
YouTube so that's you'd so update so so
the thing I want to say is that you
gotta be careful because these days
people say are there stuff you know like
you go to so YouTube so let's go back to
the YouTube download let's go to the
home page okay on github so this guy I
don't know who is this guy but anyway he
created this right but you don't know
you don't know when he's gonna be sold
out like suppose you are some evil
company suppose you are Google ok Google
or if you are Microsoft you know or if
you are FBI you knock his door you say
hey we like we'd really love your
YouTube download you know we want to buy
it how about 20 million and what the guy
will say well how about ten thousand
dollars then the guy says oh ten
thousand
but they say a million two million you
know 10 million oh yeah oh yeah he's
open so you know he probably maybe he's
the open source of free software
phonetic but then there is the code
right there and he was just there then
the next time you download you know you
you do this you know reflectively you
know you just oh something you can now
you know you just update and bam there
it is a backdoor in on you know in your
system so that's the thing you know so
what can you do well I don't know you
know and you know most people the you
you open source or free software
phonetics you are thinking oh but the
source code is there the source code
it's okay do you ever look at the source
code no very few people do so where's
the github let's see a few more website
you do now is come and program to
download videos from youtube.com and a
few more website Python interpreter
Barbara bra donate and you can contact
channel [ __ ] I want to go to the github
how develop okay a big buttons okay so
who is this guy you know these [ __ ]
people not now they all use a generic
name like you know you so it's harder to
find out who who who is a guy you know
why did why they use a generic name
because this is the open-source code of
conduct this [ __ ] you know on a surface
it appears
what were your wire genetic name because
on the surface so it's you know it means
does this guy is humble you know it's oh
i'm open source this this is not my you
know i'm doing this for the humanity so
therefore you know it's there's no name
like that things like that typically you
know typically it usually is it's it
takes some time to actually find out who
wrote it and the history and stuff oh my
god a huge
manual copy right okay let's so good
Danielle okay
this coffee right YouTube download is
released into the public domain oh this
is good okay okay this is a good guy
public domain
the dreamy if I was originally written
by Daniel potent okay so maybe he's the
guy who created it I'm pretty sure and
Wikipedia is a maybe so I don't know who
is this guy I haven't looked into but
the thing is you know you don't know
these days like you don't you most most
people you know Oh YouTube download you
just you know especially among Linux
community like us you know you just
trust trust whatever your friend is
using you know you just download it but
actually how do I know you know I never
looked at the source code how do I know
it's not doing something evil you know
you automatically rely on you know
thinking oh but it's open source there
must be somebody oh it already looked at
the code not really
remember the bleeding-heart and all the
[ __ ] you don't know until ten years
later like ten years after ten year
after five years then oh someone leaked
big news or hacker news the [ __ ]
hacker news and read it oh oh it has
some someone actually has this a there's
a backdoor in in YouTube download you've
been using it for ten years and you
don't know [ __ ] open-source [ __ ] open
source fanatics and free software from
fanatics anyway that's about that I my
rent is you know part of my talk show is
it's it's it's so anyway so so that's we
talking up we've been talking up for
over an hour already I think for an hour
and 20 minutes for 18 minutes I think
that's about it so I'm gonna check out
continue in the comments if anything
else that will be it for today so
I'm gonna talk maybe two more minutes
then it will be shut down so if you have
any questions comments post it okay oh
my god I got 17 people watching okay so
usually yeah usually I talk randomly I
got more people watching so are you guys
all Emacs fans like you know me for my
Emacs stuff or or how did you find me so
let me continue in the comments okay
post the comments and that'll be it for
today if you want me to answer post the
comments with my name like make it
orange like that so let me read the
comments with orange first but battle
miss says check our Luna Luna Luna LAN
now Luna is is that the least thing a
Luna Luna
okay so bathroom bathroom you gave
addiction an addiction but Luna whose is
it
Luna - land dot-org let's see what is is
Luna a wysiwyg something stupid website
with this oh-oh-oh
looks fancy so animated this is this is
JavaScript my friends this is the power
of JavaScript that is why you need to
learn JavaScript ok methylome you you
need to learn JavaScript you see this
this is the power of JavaScript and it's
inevitable it's an inevitability you
have to know JavaScript look look at
this fancy thing stop stop now inspect
oh it just always inspect ok let's see
what what is this technology you know
before I read what this website I wanna
oh it's a video
ok Vimeo it's a video well but to make
the video that's done in JavaScript or
something pretty something like that so
worried what is this overview this is
this is this you know this website you
know it's fashionable ok so you have to
scroll down so it says you and data
immediate connection Luna is a data
processing and visualization environment
build on a principle that people need an
immediate connection to what they are
building it provides an ever growing
library of highly tailored
domain-specific components and an
extensible framework for building new
ones you know is a data processing and
visualization environment ok what does
what the
[ __ ] that means exactly like you know
environment okay this also is it a frame
working library and what language is it
like what Luna targets domains where
data processing is the primary focus
such as data science l OT or IOT IOT
bioinformatics graphic design and
architecture okay data flow graph
immersive okay anyway this is too fancy
for me powerful engine luminous you know
what I'm more what I am interested is
what language I mean what language is it
exactly or is it a language itself
building the future of programming Luna
the future of computing my name hi my
name is putra mosque Arad and I'm a
software developer and a member of the
Luna team Oh a member of the Luna team
does I mean you are the original creator
or you are just a nameless guy you know
this is say this is weasel words you see
this this is weasel words just say the
[ __ ] I created Luna hi my name is
this I created Luna [ __ ] you okay so we
as you see we have recently released
Luna a data processing language mean to
rebel revolutionize the way people work
together you know all you say you know
I'm the original well I think another
issue is politeness you see when it
comes to credit you see human animals
are not in many aspects are not you know
kind and you know nice people because
you can see when it comes to credit
because when it comes to credit or money
you know like how much you make hey how
much you guys make oh how do you make
your money how what do you do you know
that when this issue comes about
everyone knows you know it's nervous you
know so when it comes to credit you know
you in a team it's kind of a ish issue
so we develop we developed conventions
you know those you know those you know
ways to work around it so one of the
phenomenon is for example in scientific
papers you always see we something
something we something something even
though even if a paper is published by
one guy itself by himself you know
although it's like we something
something it's a it's kind of like a
euphemism okay I don't like that okay
you just say you know for example in
this case you you might say hi my name
is something something I am you know in
a team we developed Luna okay so he's a
member of Luna team okay so anyway so
okay oh this oh these are we so talk
this is this is marketing talk you know
this is public relations talk a data
processing language meant to
revolutionize the way people gather now
is there a thing today that's not
revolutionising that way we do things
every [ __ ] thing is revolutionizing
[ __ ] something understand and
manipulate data as open source oh there
yeah there it is open source great now I
need to use this let's take a quick look
at the problem it is trying to solve in
how it attempts to do so this post
focused more on the solutions we propose
then on the guiding philosophy behind
Luna yeah too much too much we so talk
let's just say let's just go to Luna
land wiki ok Wikipedia there it is
Luna language oh this guy Chinese kind
of guy
hey wait now this is LAN LAN this is a
pianist god Luna okay Luna land a
fictional character what
lonna land what did I type it wrong no I
just want lunar land Luna language
he's not in Wikipedia it's Luna
programming okay maybe here why is this
okay I don't
maybe it's probably not in Wikipedia but
because it's too new am I correct
bathroom you so what is the deal with
Luna I know you for your freakiness and
opinionation which is most interesting
part you are opposite of mainstream
correct I can post links so that I had
to write a weird yeah good stream thanks
thanks thank you
congratulations according to my YouTube
download you have uploaded the exactly
200 video streams now okay 200 okay
your program you program in diagramming
Luna is visual programming oh alright so
I remember bathroom you know that's your
specialty I mean you study you know you
you study this this digital media stuff
with respect to you know computer
science so that that is why you know
about Luna so is it good or I mean so
it's it's good so Luna bathroom uses
Luna is a functional programming
language that you can program with notes
as you have seen demonstrated over the
website ok did I miss anything
ok Saul says have you done a video on
creating multiple revenue streams online
and how you support yourself through
those channels no I haven't done video
like that but I can tell you right away
I make $1000 a month in total $1000 my
rent is two thousand twenty to two
thousand two hundred a month so I live
you know if you work in a McDonald's you
go mop the toilets at McDonald's you
make three thousand dollars a month so I
only make one thousand dollars a month
so I am below poverty in USA so I make
one thousand dollars for the past two or
three years like well actually before
it's less now it's like $1,000 a month
is the highest point so last year is
maybe seven hundred eighty eight hundred
before last year is like 600 a month
then before before before 2003 it's zero
zero for ten years something like that
so I don't make money so even some
people say my website is popular but you
make no money okay so so you are
wondering I mean if you are wondering
about how to
you know how to become independent like
today on YouTube in particular a lot of
people are you know they are their own
boss they make a lot of money you know
they can actually survive I cannot you
know if I move to some some other
countries you know some some podunk town
in USA then 1000 yeah you can make a
living but not in here Silicon Valley
Mountain View but anyway so if you are
thinking if your question is about you
know you are thinking maybe you will
become you will start you you become a
professional blogger forget it okay
forget it doesn't matter how good you
are it's just well if you trust my
opinion I you know I'm not gonna talk
about this for 10 minutes just forget it
now if you are thinking about maybe you
become a youtube you know video YouTube
blogger to to to make living possibly
you can okay YouTube but not for talking
about programming okay not for anything
technical so if you're gonna be YouTube
YouTube you're gonna talk about drama Oh
pop you know drama yeah drama it means
those kind of thing and even even that
maybe you have a chance you know
possibly you have a chance anyway so
yeah so you know said that's about that
if that's your question so that's it I
guess I guess okay so that's it okay
thank you guys for watching have a good
day and like my stuff subscribe
subscribe to Kesari
RSS feed everything post my links okay
and put put money in my pocket hey great
to see you Cathy bye guys bye Zee tron
bye bye everyone
you know it's amazing that Google is
censoring these things bye bye bye