hello welcome to another episode of Star
Talk Show today we are going to code
Powershell so I'm gonna code Powershell
uh the problem is to list all
directories and start Powershell so
here's the Powershell to list all files
in a directory whose name contains space
okay so space character you know a bunch
of files if the file name contains space
listed and so we are going to write a
Powershell script to do that and also to
change the file name so if it contains a
space rename it to the to the underscore
to the low line character okay so that's
what we are going to code today
Powershell so if you are interested in
learning Powershell uh watch it okay and
here is my keyboard today I'm on using
the Xposed keyboard a fantastic keyboard
okay so you can look at my uh so exposed
you know you can look at my
website so you just search for Saudi
keyboard you'll find my review and the
expose is expose night this is a great
keyboard and so are the others I did the
review on glove 80. that's wonderful I'm
going to
uh you know
uh the the group 80 is gonna be my
men when I receive the lighter switches
okay so let's start to code so what is
this page close close keyboard close so
let's start through code Powershell okay
so start a so I mean emacs start a
Powershell code and pop it out and I'm
emacs I'm using some fly keys and I'm
using a vorac keyboard layout okay and
the Ping window shows all my command
codes and
keystrokes on the pink window
okay so let's begin if you have a
comments and questions ask me okay so
Powershell let's go to my Powershell
tutorial so I have a tutorial here
already
uh let's put the link here Powershell
tutorial
and uh so we wrote we did a live stream
writing a similar command before so that
would be here so let's look at how that
is done so you have set dock theme
uh how to use that's a code to say dot
theme dark theme so here is a code to
format the code predified Powershell
code and uh here is a script to convert
Linux and windows line ending
okay so we have quite a few script and
here is a script that rename file to
Hash rename the file to the
to the hash of the file content so in
this way every file if they are if their
content is different they will have a
unique name like this 64 characters or
so especially useful for image files
when you want to determine if image
files are used uh two image files are
different so that this code is very
similar to what we are going to do today
so let's put it there okay so we are
going to rename so let's just copy this
code here and let's just modify it okay
copy it
so go back to our Powershell paste it so
here is so first of all the name of the
function will be list
file
space uh what what should be the name of
the
function list file
name contains space okay that's a bit
verbose but let's do it that way so here
is that's this is how you define a
function in Powershell and then we need
to so here is the convention from the
documentation the inline
dark stream okay so so let's say list
files of current the
whose
name
list files whose name contains space
okay so that is the
um
of current okay
so that is the documentation so version
number let's put today's date and Sample
use
um
how shall we you know so the first state
stage of writing this function is the
design of the API of the interface
um so for example you know for example
in Powershell let's go to
for example let's go to web directory
Sally
info
okay let's go to
[Music]
uh comp
uh okay let's go to company and let's
list directory so there's a log files
uh let's do it again
so lots of files
okay the phone is too large so that's
better okay
so this is how you list the file duh so
now you want to let's let's think about
how we want to design the function so
one way is typically
so you you call a command that will just
list all files of the current
and subdirectories whose file name
contains a space okay uh
so
third recurs file filter
and
now so that's not how you want to use it
so
example let's just say example just
being that
so you just you just call this function
and your list
here I'll put a collection of file
objects
where the file names contain space you
know the Powershell is different from
bash in a sense that Powershell
uh
the data Powershell deal with is always
objects using object-oriented
programming so they are actually.net
microsoft.net objects whereas in bash or
Unix shell you just output text you know
it's all text processing but in
Powershell they actually output objects
which has methods and so on
just like op you know the.net object so
okay let's just let's just begin to
write this it this way okay so here is a
link uh link we don't uh okay so
actually
oh shall
file contains space so I'm going to
create this web page later so you can
grab the code there okay so now to write
the function in Powershell there are
what you have to do is actually so
actually we can delete all that let me
just show you okay so you just say the
the is an alias to get child item and
you say because do you want because or
not let's say because
because okay that means at least don't
go through all subdirectories as well
and then you want to say
now do you want to limit to directories
only or just files or both so if you
just only want files you say Dash file
uh
so this
this should uh should so here's a design
issue should it work on uh directories
or just files I mean without directories
I think it should also work on
directories
uh okay so maybe later on we can add
option
so so if so let's just say files for now
okay so recurs files and uh that's it so
actually this is the function
so we can
you know we can do it this way we can
just copy the code
paste it here paste anyway yes okay and
now it's
evaluated so now you just copy the file
name
and do it
you see at least all files right now
there's no criteria so it's simply just
list the files hello
or so
so
from England hello hi
uh
so now
we got so we need to put some kind of
criteria
where
um filter let's see how do we do this
so there is a filter parameter that
allows you to show only
file names of a specific
wildcard pattern so if you say Wild Card
space well card would that work
don't know so let's try it
so before we try it we need to actually
create a file name with the spacing it
so why don't we do that so go up one
directory and CD took some talk show and
make a create a new directory
create a new file name now you the way
you create a new file name in Unix is
just touch something something a name
but in Powershell it's a new item okay
new item file
type file something something like that
actually is let's just say new new item
okay AI is an ads to new Dash item so
let's say XX space x x y y okay so let's
say let's say that do it
okay so we created a new file now let's
see the there it is that's the file we
just created
so that command is just that now so now
we got uh now we got a
file name with a space now let's try our
uh
let's try uh let's try this command to
see if that works good child item
because file filter
do it fantastic so simple so actually
so actually you don't actually need
um
a function you see so this is actually
that's it
this list file names list files whose
name contains the space okay
and now it's recursive okay so we
essentially get one thing done
that's what we want to do
uh
uh so we got a command so let's see
yeah that's that's all it does I mean
that's basically
these files whose name contains the
space of calendar okay so yeah so pop it
back syntax code showing browser so
today's talks your page we
that's the code so simple
uh now
we need to write another command that
delete
those files okay let's just I guess
let's just do it then
uh
so here it will be delete file name
okay delete the file whose name contains
space okay
this would be dangerous to call because
so you need some kind of
mitigation to prevent accidental core
because you might type sorry delete for
example I have quite a few
commands written you know here is the
emacs DVD Max backup so if you oh and
there's you uh delete empty the but
sometimes you didn't pay attention and
if you call this command that will
delete all file names whose name
contains space that's disaster that's
going to be a disaster
so you want to some
kind of
you want to maybe query the user let's
see how we want to do this
actually it's so simple you know once
you
you see this is a this once you do this
command all you have to do is you just
pipe it
pipe it to remove
then
that's it basically
you know that that is it
yeah so turns out actually we don't need
a command
yeah so we don't actually need this
command
so uh
go back
delete yeah we don't need it because
once you have these I mean even this one
is not necessary you can just type that
whole thing but it's usually nice when
you need to do something
repeatedly it's nice to define a
function even it's trivial you know this
is one of the design problem language
design problem
oh thank you try remove item what if
uh what if you know yeah that's right
you know it's like the Unix dash dash
try sometimes you know Unix
Xiao convention they don't have a
consistent naming so sometimes it's
called drive but in Powershell is Dash
what if but
um
that doesn't you know that doesn't solve
the problem of accidental call
so anyway I think this is what we're
gonna do so we just
you know we just have this function
because this file name contains space
which is a very simple command then once
you want you know once you decided you
you want you know once you
you know see it then you just type
pipe I am
yeah cool
uh cool yeah so
yep I think that's it for today if
that's it for today for I mean for the
purpose we are going to do because you
know I'm writing this for myself because
I need to do it sometimes you know
sometimes um because a file name
containing a space usually is
problematic you know vast majority of
file names
contains a space if you are not a
programmer you know your mom or whoever
you know because it's much easier to
you know
um that is natural to have a file name
without space this underscore is
actually kind of programmers thing
or even Dash you know most people you
don't put it you don't put the you know
you just use a space so vast majority of
files contains the space and uh
but however for programming for website
you know for any technical work in
general you don't want a spacing file
name because it makes
you know processing those files a lot
more cumbersome you know
um
so that is why
so so for me I started to you know
oftentimes I want to rename files
you know make the space to be an
underscore
and uh
now I have it
oh wait wait
oh wait we got it wrong we don't want to
drip delete we want we just want to
rename that's right
got this all wrong so let's let's do it
again
so actually we want to rename okay
um
so rename
rename file
space
to
low line okay that's what we want to do
yeah so this is actually more
interesting okay
yeah you want to rename files so now
that's right rename file
that's right so now we want to
uh
so we so what we can do is that you pipe
it to a
function you know you pipe you pipe it
to a phone to to a code block
and then you can say
you want to rename okay so let's how do
you rename in Powershell I don't I don't
remember let's let's look at
um oh yeah so we have a code here
rename item Okay so
so let's copy the code here
so this function rename to hash
now to write a function in Powershell
the
you know it's very easy but however
there are something you want to know if
you want to pipe some other collection
of things to your function
yeah so yeah so here here so here now I
got it so first of all we have this
function this file name content space
now when we want to rename it we just
pipe it to another function start rename
file
that way
that way you you won't easily
accidentally
rename all your files so you can always
call this function first then just up
Arrow then just pipe rename okay
or we can add options here but let's not
do that now so so yeah so this is this
is a design okay so yeah so that's right
rename file
so the so first of all let's write a the
documentation how how is it supposed to
work
pipe
files to
this function
to rename it okay
now this is not a proper documentation
because the proper way to say is that
you
okay so we we so there are several
things okay so several things let's
let's uh
let's go back so one thing is how do you
define a function we didn't finish
talking about that so the
so that's one thing the other thing is
what is the proper description when you
have a function that takes input from a
pipe okay that's true thing first of all
let's cover the function
how do you define a function how do you
how do you how do you write a function
such that it takes
piped output as input
okay so uh so let's look here variable
Boolean conditional data structure uh
input output function so there it is
function
so function is very easy to write you
can you know just just with the keyword
function kind of typical
then
allowed characters in function name
semicolon optional if new line okay and
named parameters okay we don't care
uh any param parameter automatically
become
these option names
so that's fairly convenient okay but the
thing is that
if you want the function to accept piped
output as input then
you have to yeah so this section then
you have two
to create this block of code process
okay so here is the
here is the
thing we want okay so comment that out
so this is how you want this function
process okay
process so that means
when this function
receives a piped output a collection of
them
it will
work on each one of them one by one in
order by whatever code you have here
okay so the current piped object is
represented by dollar sign underscore so
that's a current object so you want to
rename that okay so that's
that's how you write a function that
accepts piped output okay now let's go
back to rename okay now how do you so go
back to Powershell
help rename
okay
uh okay rename item help
the name item
and let's go to online so that will show
the documentation in the browser now
JavaScript
okay rename item and
so blah blah blah blah blah blah you
know basically rename would be
rename would be something like
old name
new name something like that okay so the
old name will just be
the old Ninja will be just dollar sign
that that's the
input object
the new name
okay so now let's look at the rename
item the new name will be wait let's
look at the
you know again
and on a second let's go to talk show
let's put the links here
Powershell tutorial
Powershell function
okay and
and let's look at rename to Hash let's
see how that is done
okay
leaf and leaf base okay so when you
rename
you have to split the file path into the
directory path
and the file name part
then you rename
let's see where is the rename okay here
rename just new name let's magnify
so
extension so you have to get the file
extension new name equals to you create
a new name
then you print it
print the message rename something
something to something then you rename
it okay
so let's copy that code okay rename file
to Hash let's go back here
so let's see
okay we also need this section
so if
the input object is normal then just
print needs argument from pipe nothing
is done okay
otherwise
otherwise continue
uh
do we need to actually split the path
what is this Leaf used for
so split the path Leaf is the file name
without the directory path
then
uh then you
okay this is renamed to hash
yeah so you check if it's the file name
is already a hash string
you know rename file to Hash if it is if
it is do nothing otherwise start to
rename okay so here is the rename part
so to rename
we
extension name
okay to rename all we have to do is take
the yeah so here is what we want to do
okay so let's say old name
oh name equals true
okay here is another problem you you
don't want to if the parent directories
some parent directories contain a space
you don't want to rename those you only
want to rename the file names itself
not not any Parent Directory
because if you do that that's disaster
so you want to so you in so you have to
split the file path oh God getting more
complex
okay so you
so you need to get the file name part
first
okay and the dollar sign underscore is
the input object you need to get the
name
so
I believe it's that or
is dot name dot dot name name is a
method
okay so let's try it
uh because I don't I'm not sure what it
is so let's try
okay let's just try the
SE two files then pipe it to
ah let's try it here
duh
file
private two
underscore dollar sign underscore dot
four name okay
so that full name is the method
okay so when you use file option you
need to say recursive okay
wait
oh yeah so pipe two you need to say for
each
yep
so but if you is there a method name
let's try that there it is fantastic
so you can just say dot name okay so
so let's define old name
okay our name is that
then
new name equals to
now you need to find replace okay now so
let's see how do you how do we do find
replace in Powershell
uh find string you're given a string you
want to find replace Space by underscore
so you can see
miscellaneous functional in depth so
string so you want to go to the string
section rejects operations string
Methods okay let's see string operators
showing string
split operator
stream match by wild cards
and rejects operators okay let's go to
we can use rejects operators for sure
but maybe there's something simpler
let's go to string Methods
okay stream method example substring
oh so there is a replace
method okay
now a string in Powershell is an object
not like bash it's just a string but in
Powershell is an object so it has up it
has methods dot replace so we can say
here
so the new name Will equals to that dot
replace
uh replace
and here is a space replaced by
underscore fantastic so that so delete
that delete that leave
and let's not be named yet let's
Okay so
fire extension we don't care okay and
here we don't care okay
so and here is the old code we don't
care
purify the code
okay so here is the
now before we rename
comment out let's just print out
Echo okay Echo
there
let me go back up
okay I think that's it so now we copy
that
back to Powershell
paste the code
paste anyway so now it's defined now all
we have to do is go back go back go back
go back this file name contains space
do it
what
wait the function is now it's incorrect
these file names contain space what
so far so good refresh let's try it
again
copy it
cancel Define it paste
okay
this file name contains space now do it
again
yeah no it's correct
okay
now that so so now we pipe these two
pipe these two
that
do it
fantastic you see it I'll put it the new
name
so
so if we come uncomment that out that
should work okay but we want to
make sure that is the case let's check
the rename
item documentation
so syntax path and new name yeah so it
takes two arguments
uh re
yeah the required there
and let's see examples
I think that's it
yeah I think that's it so
so I'll put
okay I think that's it
so we just copy this again go back here
paste it paste anyway so we Define the
function now we
call this again now make sure
in the
okay go back to the talk show page go to
the directory so you see right now we
have one file
that's that contains a
space now let's make multiple
of them okay
one two
three okay let's say
four
okay so this file contained
two places that has a space
and let's make another one
let's let's say two space okay
so we have this bunch of files that
contain space
now
if we do it that should rename
now we want to make sure our code
is not doing something unexpected
because I don't want to end up
renaming all my files
oh okay there it is incorrect okay so
this part should be old name not
uh wait but
so rename item okay it takes just a
path or yes it can take a path as a as
opposed to a fire object
okay let's hope this is good now just to
be sure
uh you know I want to make a backup of
my sound talk show directory
so
create a zip file
just in case we screwed up
or in fact we can actually do git commit
okay so anyway there's a there's a zip
backup
now let's do it
okay
check this space
okay do it
fantastic go back to your character
there it is it works fantastic so that
so refresh there it is fantastic
fantastic so we did that we did it so
close close
syntax colored showing browser
so that's yeah so that's the command
though so that's it
that's what we did today so
good anything else
so now we can actually shut down I mean
that's it for today
uh or should we continue on some other
topic I think that's it let's keep it
one Topic in per live stream
okay so one one last check if there's
anything we should uh you know make it
better or anything I don't think so
um
yeah old name
yeah that
um yeah that's it thank you guys for
watching
if you like my stuff pay me okay so you
go to my Xavi dot info website and lots
of stuff uh programming language
tutorials
uh then there's patreon or Amazon gift
card me or PayPal
okay and oh you can buy my emacs
tutorial emac lisp and emacs and you can
also buy my JavaScript in depth one of
the most um
complex programming language maybe
trimming extra space
um
yeah we can do that but I don't want to
because
yeah and then start because
because I want the command you know
that's
I think it's better to leave the command
do one thing
because if the file they begin with the
space I mean this command just simply
change space to low line
uh
so when you see when after you call the
command then space becomes visible you
know then you might find out oh maybe I
have some file name incorrect you know
they start with the space so end with
some space
after you run this the command you'll be
apparent then you might want to rename
but you may not want to because
there might be a reason you begin with
the space
okay
bye guys
so I'm gonna upload the code so you can