come on everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today's 2019 October sixth Sunday
Californian time 9 o'clock a.m. good
morning cool for school cool for school
where're you from I forgot what country
so cool for school do you have a topic I
have a bunch of topic prepared for you
guys so first of all we got a discord
now so I'm thinking of creating a forum
for my son talk show you know basically
like is you know it's almost it's like a
Saudi fanclub okay so fanclub so I have
a reddit page that is Aqsa okay so let's
go to reddit saw ok so you can see there
is this reddit snot page but however
it's a bit confusing because I created
this about few years ago maybe three
years ago four years ago 2003 2013 okay
I created this it kinds of like you know
Casa fan club and but but about three
years ago
reddit introduced a new feature that
made it very confusing because read it
introduced you see now this is my reddit
account slash saw you know user saw okay
this is my radio account so reddit
introduced the feature such that you can
follow other users now ready to
introduce this around 2016 also so
reddit introduced a feature where you
can follow users just like on Twitter on
Facebook you know they they want to
introduce features to grow their website
that's what all these
for money of course the ultimate purpose
is so that they can make money more
money so they ready to introduce this
feature so now I have a problem you see
because my user account is Casa but my
reddit are kind of room o forum is also
named ha the only difference is that you
know one is a slash capital X aah
okay capital X then the user is lower
case case so so that is kind of
confusing because sometimes you think
you are following me but you are
actually following my user account on
reddit not the staff and Club on reddit
so I'm thinking of either we name this
ox r to r slash sorry if I can rename it
do you guys know if I can rename it oh I
just create a new ostrich sorry
reddit I think that's what I out do so
this is a you know kind of like a fan
club so you guys can talk and also it's
great to for you guys to meet each other
you know because my followers we tends
to have this same interest so cool for
school say something am i alive let's
check ok let's check for
okay yes I'm alive stop that night
people watching people say hi okay
post something in the chat and also pick
a topic if you like me to talk about
that so anyway that is about my reddit
fan club and so I'm going to I will
create a new Saudi you know maybe in the
tomorrow so today so that is about that
but also I also created yesterday I
happened to run into discord so let's go
to discord so this discord will also be
sorry fanclub okay but I don't know how
to use it yet because yesterday I was
trying to use it discord discord seems
to be fantastic discord I mean we try to
sorry okay let's say Tsar - okay let's
say continue so if you want to join you
go to this this website okay let me
paste it here
now that's sorry fanclub okay so we are
on this code okay I'm not a bad stupid
I'm not about you know this this I'm not
about that net technology is very
complex
the it's a Google Chrome you know
because I've read article because they
they you know there is basically a AI
engine behind it like when you click I'm
not about how does about you know how
like it simple simply your button how
does you know the Machine note you are
not about part or not because any part
can simply click that so it turns out
you know the Google the way Google did
it you know behind Chrome I guess is
that there is actually a I engine that
it's measuring or your mouse movements
and
that and there are several articles that
keep you searched if you search for
Google I am not about there are several
articles that discuss that in detail and
apparently someone has being able to
break it you know they they study it
they dig into you know they spent days
or weeks or months they dig dig into and
dig they can't break it so anyway this
code so I started to register account on
this code and this is my first time
using it I'm not sure how to use it
exactly because now it says you know he
asked me to claim your account so
yesterday so anyway I don't want to
claim a con oh there is this guy okay so
I so this is a new information you see
it right now I'm laughing or saw too and
I'm locked in
so on this code they code you know they
you know unread that you have or
something you go to what room or
something on you know different sites
they have different names like sometimes
some codes or channel some codes room
you know like on instant messages back
then you call that room you enter a room
or exit a room all right Andre that you
have are / something how they call that
I forgot subreddit yeah so it had the
code subreddit IRC you co-ed I think you
go a channel basically it's just you all
of this is just like a room or subject
at map subject matter subject carrier
you can go e to into okay
so on this code it looks like they call
it a server you know it's kind of funny
so server or channel i'm not sure yet
because you know and I'm still trying to
learn how this code works so anyway so
what you are seeing here channel this is
supposed to be the sorry fanclub channel
okay there we have just arrived so this
is supposed to be York sorry fanclub
channel but however you see there must
be you at me so this is me
- right now I just clicked on that and I
just joined but there is a admit you see
this one this this this guy
you see this guy XRD with a with a crown
that is me I created this yesterday but
so right now I want to become me you
know how I don't know how to do that
like I don't see any logging or you know
log off so do you know do you guys know
how to do that
hola so this is fun so let's read what
it says okay so anyway so this will be
suppose we to be my you know my my place
so you guys can talk I think I'm going
to name it sorry fanclub something like
that okay
then as you know as soon as as I learned
about how to use this Corral
you know rename it things like that put
my icons put my links so this super guy
says I found discord surprised by the
way I find discord you know wherever I
join a new service like that typically I
do some research for example first first
thing is that I go to Wikipedia to read
about what what is the nature I mean
what's the history who who did who did
you know who created it you know what's
the background typically I do that so
anyway yeah so I and I posted you know
picture about this go along we Wikipedia
article about this code so this code
turns out seems interesting so you can
actually also do voice chat you can also
- voice chat and I think I will try it I
you know I haven't figured out how yet
so anyway this is this code so let's
read what this guy says super safe on
discord surprised it took you so long
yeah I think this code is pretty good
okay so the UX way is possible new now
Bartholomew is supposed to create a you
know supposed to crew create a chat room
for first but anyway you know when so
when Bartholomew has it so guys post
messages here okay so this so super says
the UX user interface user experience is
good the software kinda sucks but the
community is ultimately what matters I'm
pretty sure there are no third party
clients for this code because it doesn't
have a public API okay so it does so so
if it does in bit V I imagine you have
to have an instance running okay the
discord client is well designed but it's
electron oh my god it's written electron
Jesus reactron that's JavaScript but
it's electron if you don't know electron
is a is a JavaScript platform or
framework you know yeah actually you
should call it platform almost so you
write everything in JavaScript it's
amazing I'm starting to get into
electron actually but actually I
mentioned this before too few days ago
I'm this month October I'm going to
spend one hour a day on react.js d3.js
so you know it's already October 6th so
I've spent some time studying studying
several JavaScript modern you know we're
doing of doing things such as young such
as young react web pack so and possible
and you know I I'm going to talk about
those a little bit today so it's so
discord is written in electron that's
great any
is really bad on mobile battery which is
the worst thing about it okay so you are
using mobile phone inspect good morning
Matt so by far the most power hungry of
any app on my pixel 3 after YouTube okay
so and super says as for myself I came
from IRC and mumble on teamspeak okay I
don't know what is mumble but I know
what's teamspeak when I was in Second
Life you know I learned about teamspeak
these teenager gamers you chat and iOS
on it
IRC is the old you know typically UNIX
type of people they love that IRC so as
for myself I came from IRC and mumbo
teamspeak that I use for gaming okay for
IRC I used WeChat fancy I used WeChat
which is Chinese that's a Chinese
program is it or not the only piece of
command line and course is software I
really liked know it's kind of Emacs
seeing its approach everything is one
command away and it's very customizable
predictably the author is an Emacs user
and you can see its philosophy from
through in many ways ok I don't know
what is WeChat wait WeChat is the I
thought it's a Chinese app that does
everything okay so we chat is a free and
open source internet relay hi RC client
basically which had is a free and open
source internet relay chat client which
is designed to be light and fast ok it's
released under the term of green channel
however and has been developed since
2003 okay it's just a IRC client that's
that's not interesting at all you know
we have a thousand IRC clients today so
message do you really want climb down
the rabbit hole
like what like disco Dan what do you
mean
so super says one crap thing you should
fix this courts default server
notification settings is to send you a
notification for every message okay make
sure to change the default okay so I'm
going to you know play around with
discord and learn about it but anyway
let me repeat there's one thing I don't
know how how do I log in like how do I
get rid of the you know right now my
exes are too and become my real account
sorry like I don't see any logging or
logoff buttons so anyway I think this
discord is quite a new technology one
new message
okay this code is actually busy okay
praise the Sun praise the Sun so I mean
getting into the whole JavaScript
ecosystem oh yeah that but I'm afraid
that's something I just have to do
because you know I write websites right
I have a you know website I have several
websites with - with 6000 articles
essays and tutorials six thousands of
them not counting not counting in the me
road manuals I mean each of these six
thousand it's a five thousand five
thousand each of these five thousand
articles are written by myself manually
you know tag for tag every character I
typed you know if you know then then
with Emacs help so so I have you know so
I'm running website so JavaScript is
something I just have to know I mean
that's kind of my it becomes my job
almost so I'm you know but so like right
now I know JavaScript very well you know
I am a master of JavaScript let me
mention this again I have a JavaScript
in-depth tutorial that I would claim it
is the best in English okay in English
literature of all English literature
that teaches JavaScript may be published
as a book
printed book or online mine is the best
okay that's my cream like what do you
mean best we're like you know how do you
measure it
well there's many ways okay but you can
just trust me oh you can just take like
roughly your average okay you can you
can pick you know let's say you guys
okay pick some of your favorite
JavaScript resource maybe oh it's a
website or it's a book printed book you
know type it right now and I can give
you my criticisms about it but anyway I
just want to tell you my JavaScript so
check it out javascript in depth I spent
basically two years full time on it and
I'm still working on everyday because
this there's there's many things to do
okay so Java screaming depth then you
have a full javascript object reference
then you have the dome scripting
tutorial now my dooms scripting tutorial
is not as comprehensive because don't
doom is very complicated
just like javascript okay anyway but I
give you the quickest introduction the
most practical like you read my tutorial
you know you read my stuff you you'll be
a JavaScript master but however let me
mention okay so so I wrote this
javascript in depth and and you know in
dome okay and and SVG tutorial okay so
you can see let's go through while the
disco just keep happening so let's go
through it's not JavaScript okay sorry
JavaScript JavaScript the global object
you know I talk about the global object
anyway so you go to the JavaScript
in-depth so I wrote this javascript in
depth however I have a problem there is
a flaw because though my style of
JavaScript is is the raw technology in
depth it it
represented it can be captured by these
comics let me show you these comics
comics so you know two you know two guys
are talking well which plug-in are you
use have you used to do this thing it's
amazing and this this this who is this
guy - none none so that is my style of
JavaScript so far I don't use any
framework any library and you know so
I've shown you my JavaScript application
I've done before so I'm not going to
show it again you know in my past videos
I've shown you some of the JavaScript
application have written so no no
framework no react no vu no angular no
nothing no you know the angular and what
C angular V and none of that no
framework not even not even jQuery okay
I don't use any of them so I understand
you know the U that means you understand
JavaScript fully you know raw raw
technology and Dom okay it's all in
browser so that is that is about my
JavaScript so but there's a flaw because
today vast majority of programmers in in
the Java JavaScript field you know you
work for Google Facebook or Twitter
you don't code actually nope you know
you don't even if you know which are my
script but you don't code you always use
framework or library okay so in today's
programming Java in front end you always
use a library or framework in any
company and that is something I'm not
familiar with okay so even though I know
JavaScript well and Dom you know I don't
need to use those libraries but it's
it's a problem Monsieur you see because
because if the framework the way you use
framework electron you know it's
actually becomes net
Cerie easy becomes you know so that is
why the that I'm diving into this
technology for real you know I've done
that before but this you know I'm going
to die bit more so I'm gonna learn about
you know the react you know all these
different libraries so that's about that
so how long have I been talking let's
see Wow more people has joined here is
to kick butt but chew bubblegum enjoys
full of gum so who are you people
we are expecting you all aha yo all so
anyway so let's go back to live
dashboard so I've been talking for 20
minutes
I have several subject I want to talk
about women's bathroom you both
Bartholomew is Heidi or not here today
so so I have I heard so Matt says I
heard swept this wealth is the heart
next heart thing so or rather current
okay let's see what is that 12 GS
okay so cybernetically enhanced web elfs
cybernetically enhanced web apps so I
guess they are so new that they don't
have a Wikipedia page yet oh god it's
like I don't like it already you know
with this this font this this font in
you know this font indicates to me
anyway so let's see draft is a light
weight light weight modern JavaScript
library 4.57 cube
okay five kilobytes intended for use on
projects where legacy browser support is
not necessary okay yeah it uses modern
JavaScript who doesn't
you know query select or cross list you
know yeah who doesn't know that's old
what do you mean modern JavaScript to
help make it as lightweight as possible
and therefore only works on the latest
version of modern yeah yeah you know I
can do that without any libraries so
quick example okay yeah shut up okay
let's look at the API I don't think it's
interesting at all you do not need a
library to do any of these idiot you
know so reading the API you know I know
what they are talking about I know like
just look at the function names I know
what each one is talking about and you
do not need a library for this at all I
saw it saw peeing in DOM and JavaScript
yeah so this is I think is quite seedy
vue.js stock generated documentation
custom functions yeah yeah I think I
don't think it is yeah it's not
important you see don't use it you know
it's o dot Dave okay so so hold on let
me check that okay so cool for school
says the other day you mentioned that
Stephan Wolfram contacted you to come
work for Mathematica but you did not
respond to his message are you not
interested in working anymore I am
interesting working but I've got issues
okay you know typically my problem is as
maybe you could you know possibly it's
part of the schizoid personal
personality disorder I did a video on
that you know just search for it it's
because whenever I see something that is
that is important
I don't do it that it is a thing so
anyway so that's issue okay so
you know like with like for example when
you got the email oh god I need to reply
this and tomorrow you didn't reply yeah
you know it's called procrastination
okay now I know many of you are also
procrastinators including e-max users
now I'm gonna I'm telling you I'm the
biggest I'm the king of the
procrastinator okay I procrastinated my
whole life and I've failed okay so I'm
the king of procrastinator and I know
some of you are going to tell you oh oh
if you are a pro at it you know there's
this article that really solved it you
know this I've read them all okay I know
it the psychology I know it all
I'm the master of procrastination okay
they're finally bathroom you is here I
said Monday god I made sure I said it
clearly yesterday it's now o'clock today
but starting on Monday you know it's
it's 10 o'clock so you are here finally
so anyway procrastination so so yeah so
you know possibly you know I don't know
what you know it's up you know if I'm
you know he's great guy I could go work
for him and also like everyday and you
know every month ok you got you know you
got these head counters you know in
Silicon Valley we call them head
counters from Facebook and Google you
know busy you know human resource
department this they spam you with email
hey do you like to work for Google hey
do you like to work for Facebook yeah
and in Amazon you get that okay so I
think it's it's it's possible you know
I'm going to kind of disappear anytime
so but so I you know but it's totally
possible one day one of these days maybe
pretty so I don't know you know I just
maybe I'll start to you know try to
apply you know you know start to start
to do interviews then then over sudden
by tomorrow I'm going to tell you hi
guys there's gonna be no more talk show
now I work for Google okay now I work
for Google and I'm going to help Google
do all the evil scenes things - [ __ ] you
guys up you know but it's possibility
that's you know you know even though I'm
getting old but I'm not too old okay I
can still do coding you know I do coding
every day usually the problem with me is
with the non normal people the
interviewers and also they it's like
anyway that's another topic you know the
interview this is actually you know you
know you know the interviewing thing you
know how does company hire people that
is a very interesting subject okay
because as a company I mean you may be
one day you know you guys will be you
know open a company then that's a
problem for you you will need to hire
people so the problem is how do you do
it how do you know which people are
really good which people are bad not
just technically you know sometimes you
get you know good people but they are
lazy you know sometimes you get you know
this mini is a big issue
you know hiring people like you
interview for two hours or even
sometimes they do a photo for a week you
know for five hours you interview but
you know you might hire someone who
passed or interview so you think he's a
great guy but it turns out when once you
hire him it's no good okay a lot of
people are like that you know on the
other hand such as me sorry you
interview me you think this is a idiot
this guy don't know how to talk he don't
know how to write a nested loop [ __ ]
I can write your whole company's code
anyway that's a exaggeration but so yeah
so interview and hiring it's actually
it's actually a big problem okay so you
know but from from both the company
point of view and also from the you know
program you got
point of view like that cuz a program in
interview is also a problem for you
because you know for example take me you
know I know stuff but but when you do
interviews you know they they ask
questions you can answer or you get
nervous you know things like that you
know this many things happen you know
this this a personality issue and you
have to of course you have to dress up a
little is a little bit you have to you
know present yourself actually I can
teach you guys about how to do
interviews okay like how do you how to
get yourself accept it you know how to
make yourself how to sell yourself
that's actually important I know many of
my followers are not you know are nerd
types are not good at interviews so you
you know maybe you you know so maybe I
can talk about that I don't know so so
anyway so so interview I want what I
want to emphasize is that you know as a
most of you most for most people it's
like it's like a problem for you like
you don't know you know you oh how do
what should I do to get hired you know
you worry about it a lot but in fact
remember okay remember this is not just
a problem for you so you know people are
trying to get hired it's actually a big
problem for the corporations in fact
it's actually probably or more a larger
problem it's a significant problem for
companies because they cannot you know
they are waiting actually you know today
they are willing to pay thousand
thousands of dollars just for just to
get up for Grandma you know they and
they are competing you know so it's a
major problem for them as well so then
you have you know you have thousands of
companies they focus on trying to hire
people for you know for your company so
so it's you know so it's a big problem
so don't think you know don't think of
interview is is like these big
corporations are trying to manipulate
you are you know trying to fear to up
you out it's not like that okay they
spend a lot money you know this huge
billions you know trying to get people
and they cannot find people that you
know they have a lot problem so so first
of all don't think of it as like oh
these big companies they are all trying
to manipulate us you know who you know
trying to filter out
so something tactic it's not like that
okay so anyway that that's interview is
a problem we can talk about and how to
do the interviews how many people don't
act interview these situations call for
fake behavior okay so so if you have
actually you know if you want me to
answer on something put my name on it
you know make it orange like in a chat I
have I'm going to continue talking about
the okay's us well swathed TS okay so I
don't know what is that so me I don't
know Dave and see let's go back to
JavaScript okay so actually I do have
some things I want to talk about okay
this one I guess
okay so swell swell okay swelled
cybernetically enhanced web apps now
there it is there is a quick bait
cybernetically enhanced web apps okay
you gotta use this now because it's
cybernetically enhanced okay for example
react is not cybernetically enhanced
therefore react is bad you know this one
is cybernetically enhanced [ __ ] okay it
says write less code boilerplate free
components using language you already
know oh okay no virtual Dom oh no
virtual Dom this is this is a direct hit
on react you know react is famous for
drip virtual Dom now this swelled no
virtual Dom is they swerve compiles your
code to tiny framework
this framework less veneer Egeus your
app starts fast and stays fast ok no
virtual Dom that's interesting
truly reactive ok truly it's truly it's
not just reactive but it's truly
reactive no more complex cut no more
complex state management libraries
swelled prints reactivity to JavaScript
itself Wow ok ok and you know maybe I'll
you know I probably spend some time look
into it so anyway so let me copy that
paste it to today's talk show you know
so we have a record of what we've been
talked about ok it's swamped swelled ok
close now and also let's copy that copy
this side as well let's see you know
what what's the relation between these
two are they are they kind of the so as
I said rabbit hawk sorry
yeah JavaScript and date which do you
know the tech changes every day right I
mean not every day but every year
something new comes up ok javascript in
depth WeChat okay we child I don't care
we chat is just a ISE current Cathy good
morning Cathy great to see you so Cathy
joined XR fan club
on this code okay so let's scope let's
go to reddit closed reddit story okay
look this is my old one of my saw talk
show story of math crisis oh this one is
math okay story of math crisis math
foundation proof theory and homotopy
type theory this one's got fancy icon so
if you into math check that out
okay close now then we back to some talk
show YouTube and actually there is one
guy who posted a comment let me just
answer that this guy is my friend you
know he are you here you know he's here
frequency he was here yesterday so he
says so Lyle kado so he says because
Emacs has such a small user base its
disappearance is its disappearance would
not do much damage
how would how would it affect you it's
magnified okay that's so bad reading so
let me try it again you know sometimes
you read you know there are poetry
reading sessions like you can like if
you are into poetry or literature things
like that you know apparently they are
poetry reading sessions like you maybe
you go to the city amis in San Francisco
here oh you know whatever is your city
they are facing America okay I know it's
it's there are in New York San Francisco
or Los Angeles so you go you know you go
to a place they read poetry apparently
you know a poet you know they read
poetry it's kind of funny so I am
somewhat you know poetry and literature
I'm somewhat into you know when you talk
about poetry poetry is like this topic
that's also trauma dramatic okay like
math okay so you know like math is kind
of dramatic topic you know vast majority
of people don't know nothing about math
but however it's a good dramatic the
subject because for example Andrew Young
you know who is the presidential
candidate for Democratic Party in
America you know Andrew Young he's he's
he's you know he's one of the his theme
is math you know it like he's like
he's supposed to be the math guy you
know like you have a hat let me show you
some pictures Andrew Young math okay
he's a presidential candidate for you
know US president president 2020 you
know so you know one of his jargon you
know the slogan for his campaign is math
you know is your design math math and
the math hat
you see math you know so math is kind of
this dramatic jargon even vast majority
of people like they don't nothing about
what is math when this when when most
people think of about math they think of
arithmetic slike 1 plus 3 equals 2 for
multiplication 3 plus 5 equals 215
that's what they think let's think they
think it's math and also it's very
annoying every time you go to Twitter or
social networks you search for math it's
maybe we can try it I actually I don't
want to log into Twitter anyway you go
to Twitter or social math Network I
don't want to login ok [ __ ] Twitter you
go there you know they you type math you
know hashtag math oh you get the
movement you get the bunch of it you get
a lot of retweets you know posts half of
them will be girls like teenage girls
like there they will say oh math oh I'm
not good at math oh oh my math teachers
say something and boyfriend you know
that girls you get you know they hunt
every day every day you get that when
you type math you know the hashtag math
you know you see this thing girls you
know they talk about math and they and
and and their boyfriends everyday
they're on the other hand they have
ended then the other half is children
you know children like collaboration
game math you know your hashtag math
children you know playing in Lego or
something just a [ __ ]
you know [ __ ] the [ __ ] list so you know
so that's not math right that's that's
not math you really want to get into
math study math you know for example you
know major in math in college you know
oh you oh you can you know go to YouTube
a lot of people teach you real math you
know undergraduate level also they have
you know graduate level like PhD math
you know but it's not not but so what
I'm my point here is that math is in
society math is kind of like this has
this dramatic you know area around it
you know that you know like look at this
you know this is math so but poetry is
also kind of like that poetry there's
also a dramatic air around it you know
so anyway so poetry reading so let me
okay let's go back to answer answer Leo
Kardos question you know so he so this
is yesterday's this this is yesterday
talk show the Tarot is shameless monk
Shakespeare on drunkenness on
drunkenness on dronicus okay let me do
it again you know I need to practice
reading because reading is kind kind of
fascinates me you know it's you know
part of the poetry reading stuff so let
me try it again
and I need to get better okay I need to
get better at my articulation yeah so
you know I I do I've been doing YouTube
videos for the past half a year and when
you when I watch myself I'm going like
oh my god I'm so bad at English you know
my actually is my articulation skill is
very bad you know and I gave every
sentence I have you know you know you
know and things like that and stuttering
you know that but that's I don't want
that okay so I need to practice by the
way reading read reading I mentioned
this few times in my videos in my past
videos reading and writing a language
you know reading and writing
language such as English is entirely a
different task or subject matter then
then then speaking and listening skills
okay so you see me I don't you know I
don't speak English you know I speak you
know I speak fluently but I don't what
do you what do you say is that my
articulation skill needs improvement
okay there's another euphemism actually
what should be said is that my
articulation skill is very bad okay it's
not
but today's in today's millennial
generation you should say needs
improvements okay Oh American typically
America Americans are like that they
don't they don't directly criticize you
personally you know they don't they go
run about you know they say you need
improvement anyway so my articulate
articulation skill is pretty bad
articulation means several things but
there are two major aspect to it
one is the pronunciation you know that
you need to get it correct you know
pronunciation I'm doing kind of okay
when I pay attention to it in that you
know in the article in in the
pronunciation okay I'm doing kind of
okay
I think now if you if you have opinions
posted okay now the other part of
articulation is that is the ability or
skill to to to express yourself in real
time okay with good pronunciation you
know you have to express complex ideas
in real time you know in a succinct way
and you use the correct
you know the correct words or turn
terminology or jargons you know to
describe what you are thinking so I'm
pretty bad at that on your hand the best
person that the person with perfect
articulation is Jordan Peterson okay you
guys have you guys have you no no
Jordan Peterson right you have seen the
way he talks he is kind of but anyway
he's kind of extreme he's rather extreme
you know for example I can I can tell
you of the celebrities who's got really
great articulation skills and who is not
so great for example we okay those
people with with perfect articulation
skills are typically most of them most
of the time they are academics okay like
professors such as Jordan Pederson
okay so academics typically they have
great articulate articulation skill but
only on your hand for example a
president Trump he doesn't have great
articulation skills okay the way he
talked is like typical American make
great America again okay Trump okay that
he is not you know when we when you know
he doesn't use fancy words or tract
words structure hierarchy concept you
know the about society you know things
like that he doesn't do that and yeah
okay so for example Trump and also
president jr. Bush you know George Bush
jr. you know he he was the president
during in 2004 or something I don't like
that guy okay he said I think he's a
criminal
anyway he is also
example who does not have great
articulation skills okay and these are
Native Americans so you know you have to
make a distinction between you know
speaking speaking English fluently
versus you articulate imperfection that
those are different okay for example ice
I speak fairly fluent you know you can
say I'm you know fluent in English but I
don't have great articulation skills so
I talked about several things about
articulation and speaking but back to
you know backtrack our
also I was saying speaking and listening
skills of a natural language is entirely
different from reading and writing okay
so you know when it comes to reading and
writing I've wrote attorney and that you
know and I ripped I've read or turn you
know Shakespeare and all that that's the
entire entirely different thing anyway
I want to get better at articulation
it's actually it's one of the things I
always wanted to do because remember I
mentioned in my past talks I want to be
a superhuman superhuman means I'm
beautiful in every way I'm you know I'm
a beautiful guy I'm also you know
Superman I can run faster than you I can
you know and I can program faster than
you beat me you know like I want to be
this superhuman and I have failed you
know I've failed that you know in fact
being too ambitious is part of the
reason I fail this is that's another
thing to talk about anyway so yesterday
I was talking about this topic about
Shanley's monk Shakespeare Andronicus
poor granham and philosophy and
languages name Christel :
okay then there's this comment so he
says because Emacs has such a small user
base its disappearance would be would
not do much damage how would it affect
you well if he MX disappeared you know
I'm you know I rely on Emacs very much
but if Emacs disappeared I'll just
switch to I'm thinking right now is my
my choice would be vs code I heard you
know I probably switch to V s code and
also he says and you speak of
modernization for Emacs if the changes
were made then more people use it for
its features what would then happen like
what do you mean what would happen you
know so you've emailed
if Emacs people you know if the Emacs
death
you know those Emacs maybe you know
Emacs death if they adopt the changes I
propose you know if you search for sorry
Emacs modernization you'll find my
articles okay so if if Emacs David
adopts my changes I claim that Emacs
will at least have twice as much users
within one year within two years okay
well you know within one you that's my
claim so if they adopted what would then
happen like what do you mean what would
then happen you know there'll be more
users that's that's what will happen so
anyway that sense answers that question
okay today I meant to talk about several
topics okay
but we already talked for 15 minutes so
I don't know if I'm gonna continue with
the topics I prepared here or I'm gonna
read the comments and see what's up so
I'm going just going to read the
comments and answer questions in the
comments and continue from there okay so
josh says and I always thought I was the
champion in procrastination okay so if
you have questions comment type it now
okay with my name so rabbit hole yeah
JavaScript front-end is kind of a right
rabbit hole so DP says DP come on in DP
so DP where where are you from so DP
says if you act or lie you have to
remember those lies a lot if you are
yourself such as being truthful you can
be spontaneous and not have to remember
what not to say
exactly now I don't remember what's the
context when you made the comment but
exactly that's what I thought that's
what I'm thinking as well you know so so
that is the power behind you know behind
the
behind the recommendation sometimes you
hear about be yourself you know people
sometimes tell you you know you should
be yourself and you know I agree you
know as a nerd
sometimes you hear people say be
yourself but you think you get confused
what do you mean be yourself like if I
go to interview then I dress you know I
dress like my everyday normal dress you
know with bad hair and that you know I'm
thinking oh people say be yourself so I
just be myself
but that's not it you know so usually
this Maxim so these quotes you know you
have to apply interpretation yummy
typically these quotes are wisdoms you
know be yourself but but it's not you
cannot take it literally you know you
don't go you know for example the
interview interviewer asks you a
question you know is so so you know
sometimes they ask what's your weakness
you know sometimes they have very
idiotic questions that doesn't do
themself good okay like I said it's a
problem for you it's also a problem for
the company they don't know what to ask
you know sometimes they think you know
what's your weakness weakness so it's
you know they do sometimes they ask you
know idiotic questions that that you
know that do them bad anyway so about be
yourself you know it's usually you need
some kind of interpretation you know you
can just oh oh be myself people say be
myself so I say you know oh I don't know
you know I haven't been coding for ten
years you know I don't know what to do
but actually you could say that you know
you for example me if I do interview I
could say that but the difference is
that for example just like the way I'm
doing YouTube talks now you have to like
when you are really be yourself you know
what to say okay so if I say for example
oh yeah I haven't been coding for ten
years you know is it matters how you say
it because when your mindset is
different
it all comes out you know so for example
me for example take for example you
interviewer asked me a question you know
what's your weakness maybe I say oh I
haven't been coding for you know a long
time yeah I don't know modern
technologies I don't know yeah you know
I'm learning react today I'm starting to
react in the in the way pack and and
okay so yeah I'm trying to okay then
then okay then I'm done okay
that's no good that that becomes that's
become so bad you know on the other hand
if I'm truly you know that's one example
you know I'm thinking oh I should be
yourself you know but I said that then
that then I say that then that's bad
okay that's bad interview then the
interviewer maybe he doesn't you know
she often he's the first interview often
out the human resource they don't even
know the technology anyway the first
interview if you do that then they think
oh this guy don't know much he's a
beginner in you know he's a beginner you
don't even know react he's learning it
for the first day okay no good
close it out you know right away on the
other hand here's another take for to be
yourself okay I say exactly the same
thing oh yeah I haven't you know I'm
learning jump react yes for the first
time today so I you know I've been
trying I heard about it for a long time
but I never learned it so I'm trying to
learn it for the first time you know but
by the way you know I you know I maybe
I've showed this before you can you can
go watch my videos I know JavaScript
pretty well probably more than you know
let's say all your company's programmers
you know and I have a JavaScript
in-depth tutorial and let me show you
you know I'd we might bring out my
laptop and type it you know no it's not
to talk you know then then that's good
you know that's also be myself this so
this is kind of things like that
difference well and also it's also
easier said than done
you know because especially that you
know like I talked about this yesterday
when the stack are high like if you
don't get this job
tomorrow you'll be dead then there's a
lot pressure you don't do as well you
know anymore like a night now like right
now I can tell you what to do you know
because I don't have fresh you know I'm
not actually in an interview so I can
you know talk so well but in you know
but when if there's an actual interview
then you have pressure things like that
right so anyway that's about that's
about be yourself you know that's about
that jung-hwan soccer good morning my
Chinese Chinese friend
hyungwon Sagar trans-canada inside
Twitter so you're young vs col de la ma
[ __ ] [ __ ] is Karen Xiao de so I was
I was posting on Twitter saying that
maybe I should abandon Emacs and use the
s code it's kind of half joking okay so
DP is from Germany okay so a lot great
people from Germany so we have DP we
have Bartholomew we have Matt we have
where's where's the Z trunk razy
bottom you see trunk crazy so so George
says son do you know what text editors
are most popular around the world the
most popular that would probably be s
code today vs code or Visual Studio I
would say yeah probably visuals Visual
Studio or vs code something like that
yeah I would say so we yeah so if you
have questions guys type it okay know
how long I've been talking now
maybe that's about it for today one hour
okay so I'm thinking you know wow it's
actually a good time
lately I've been doing 90 minutes so
like questions comments posted okay
otherwise it seemed so Matt says did you
ever consider writing a book by the way
yes I have since since 1995 so let me
tell you about the my story about
writing a book since 1995 so go to Saudi
math praying curves okay I talked about
this many times so you go to my website
this is my website a visual dictionary
of special plane curves now this is
fairly it's kind of its comprehensive
you know either I did this in 1995
okay 1995 using wolfram mathematica you
know wolfen language Mathematica to
create all these animations I did a few
video on this so you know you could just
search folk sorry
thing curves so I did this in 1995 and
that you know I walk I went to I wrote
this in 1993 you know and I work I went
to work for Wolfram research for half a
year beginning as an intern he's
supposed to be interned anyway so anyway
so United so I did this so then since
since so in 1995 I learned HTML a
whuppin before that I don't really know
HTML but after that Wolfram I really
started to learn about oh you know which
you know creating you know you can
create your own website you know and and
HTML so so H so in 1996 I created a HTML
you know I put this on the website and
back then this is this is this is
cutting edge okay
I have animations you know this is the
most popular math website on the web
1996 to well depending on the year let's
say to 2005 this my website is the one
the most popular website for math
subject you know and you know thousands
of universities links to it you know
math department like University of
California Berkeley or something old you
know thousands around the world math
department website link to my website it
is this project and even back then I
thought of about writing a book so I can
write a book you know I write a book on
playing curves you know maybe you know
and but then back then there is this guy
at Wolfram research
his name is George George George pecker
Hodge Oh George Peck okay
George Peck projective geometry this is
a way I can find out his name possibly
this okay but anyway he say he's he's
his name is George Paco George Becker I
forgot but anyway he woke a wolf on
research he is still with wolf am so
he's being a Wolfram research for like
for like you know this thirty years by
now I guess George peck peck or Peck Oh
Becca something like that okay I can
find a name actually for checked let me
let me find the name okay
[ __ ] said Huxter real projective friend
okay there is a book written by this
mathematician called the real projective
plane now this is about projective
geometry this book is written in 1990 or
1998 he s I forgot what's the date of
the book anyway so he wrote you know so
so so you know oh there there there it
is music you can see his name so this is
written by coxster a very well-known
mathematician coxster okay it doesn't
okay so wait hold on a second
comments guys guys comments okay
comments so this book is written by HSM
coxster coxster okay a very well known
geometry okay this guy HSM constant
coxster he died about 10 years five five
or ten ten years ago he died ten years
ago thing but ten years ago something
like that and he's also you can read
about him on Wikipedia I talked about
him few days ago so he wrote the book
the real projective plane in 1980s or
1990s I forgot nineteen early 1980s okay
and and this book comes with a this book
comes with a disc you know a floppy disk
back then you know so it is the disc
contains some code like software to you
know kind of a health you know help
learning a stuff and that software is
with Mathematica okay so Mathematica
that software is written by George Peck
this guy so when I went to Wolfram
research I met this guy he woke at
Wolfen research yeah I didn't know
before so you know and he told me he's a
Canadian by the way George fact is
Canadian and actually no I remember now
I think he is a student of
coxster yeah I think you know maybe he's
a student of a coxster anyway George
Peck okay I made him a goof on research
and he told me don't write a book don't
write it okay you know back then I was
back then I was very young like 20 22
you know it's like hot I'm a hotshot you
know I'm going to be in the future I'm
going to be one of the great
mathematicians you know yeah you do that
you know you know when you are a PhD
student in math you kind of have that
you know thing going on you know so
anyway so so he told me don't write a
book because what's the reason for
because I forgot exactly what what's the
reason he gave but I in anyway I don't
know him too well I don't know him too
well
you know so bein you anyway I do
remember he told me don't write a book I
don't remember what's his reason what
what reason he gave me but I I do I kind
of I can i can tell you what's the
reason now typically for a caddy you
know for for professor for academics you
you know first first of all first of all
let me just say first of all books makes
zero money is almost basically zero
income okay
I've researched okay sorry how much does
author makes okay I did a research on
that and I also talked about that so you
need to find an article I need to find a
holic Oh
churches the design of the OpenBSD
homepage what okay so actually so we've
been talking to okay so let me find the
page okay they actually just go through
my home directory let me go to so go to
saudi programming block okay now go to
the diet the directory then just search
for list matching lines book okay and
and search for how okay there it is
there it is how much you'll get for
writing a programming book so I did a
research on this topic you can read the
details I'm not going to read it but
anyway basically if you write a
JavaScript book for example or
programming language or whatever
tutorial programming language
territorial let's say JavaScript because
it's one of the most popular programming
language and suppose your book is a top
seller you know among all JavaScript
programming books yours yours is the
best seller okay how much you make you
make like all go considered maybe
$10,000 that's it okay that's it ten
thousand dollars but on the other hand
if you're a programmer working for a
company in one month you'll make ten
thousand dollars okay that's how that's
how much you make for a book so that is
assuming you are the best-selling book
author
okay that's JavaScript programming book
okay
so you don't make money so you don't
make money and you know okay so that's
that that's about that okay so then
that's naming copy the URL go back to
Emacs close that close that go back to
talk show and paste paste the topic here
because it's one of the things we talked
about so later on I can put on YouTube
in the descriptions so anyway that's how
much you make a book you don't make
money and if you are writing a book for
math
for math you know mathematicians book
you know for serious mathematics such as
this one this is even less money like a
program let's say let's say you know you
you're said nobody buys because this
when you talk about when you talk about
math books for example graduate level
this is kind of graduate level math
projective geometry even undergraduate
when you read a math book you know you
have you have to realize your audience
is very very very very very very very
small almost looks like nobody okay do
you okay let me ask you guys do you guys
know what's real projective plane what
the [ __ ] is that you don't know okay I
can actually tell you what that is next
time okay just ask me again explain
what's a projective geometry so anyway
like if a program a book sales
you know JavaScript sell yeah or even
even programming books you don't sell
okay when you write a book you want to
write a book that's not technical then
you have kind of you can maybe possibly
make some money you want like novels
okay Steve Stephan Stephan King
okay novels you know or romance novels
yeah the the the bodies Reaper you know
the the you know for women they then you
make money but if you if you are lucky
becomes a Hollywood film then you become
a billionaire like like the hurry heart
Harry Potter's you know Harry Harry
Potter's and other stories Lord of the
means for example if you are lucky but
if you write technical programming books
you don't you don't you are your
audience is very few okay you don't have
money you don't make money but
mathematicians is like even less 1000
times this ten thousand times less then
programmers okay so basically forget it
okay you know but why do professors
write it you know professors write it
because they already have a job they are
writing you know in academia it's like
it's a process you know it's kind of
it's a process
you you write a book not really for
people to understand you write it so
that your co-workers your colleagues you
know other professors again to show them
you know to it's like a you know you
know it's it's like a kind of a class
you know to show them I I've written a
book it's kind of like that in academia
so you know some of the exemptions of
the course you know you know there are
exceptions of course but you know it's
kind of like that okay so that's about
writing a book
so have I thought about it yeah I have
thought about it since 1995 actually I
talked to a publisher Addison Addison
Wesley publisher I actually you know I
started to kind of go in that direction
that I went to you know I talked to the
publisher actually now a few publisher
contacted me so this is this is around
1997 1998 okay I you know and I went in
you know you talked to them who
basically then basically in the end I
didn't do it like like a lot of things
that's my life story
in the end I didn't do it it just
dropped then so that this is back in
1997 okay this is back in 1997 to 1998
you know I was kind of doing math a lot
math then then like recent you know in
the past ten years I've also thought
about you know maybe I can publish the
book you know maybe Emacs Lisp oh you
know then I did research I found out
maybe if you are the best-selling book
you only make maybe you know you only
make what programmers make in one month
but how long does it take to write a
book it's more it's like it's more
likely for time for four year full-time
eight hours a day for four year you
write a book and then you how much you
make a programmer makes the same in one
month
you know so book is not a option okay
it's not it's not something you want to
do and also once you write it this
[ __ ] programmers today's today's
society society Wikipedia internet
things should be free you know the best
means things are free the open-source
fuck-fuck heads open-source fanatism
free software fanatism pirating you know
they don't care you you write a book
order you spend one year you know dive
into javascript or email is once you've
published its pirated everywhere and
it's all the the questions the answer
from your book from your research is
over over on stackoverflow without
credit they spread and spread because
one once one one when people posted that
maybe on Stack Overflow and we keep edia
you know if just one people post
something without credit it becomes it
just copied over because they don't know
where where it came from
they don't know it's not like everyone
is so evil you know they don't even know
where it came from it just becomes
everywhere
it becomes everywhere these open-source
[ __ ] in free software [ __ ]
because these people they don't think
about you know detailed things they just
chant ideology and they work for Google
Facebook each one has one thousand
patent lawyers he these hypocritical
[ __ ] you know III I talked about these
many times in my video frame rant
so bothering me says what are you
talking about if you write a successful
book out of nowhere here you get rich
overnight the hard thing is for people
to know your book exists in other market
marking stuff what are you talking about
like what book if you are lucky and are
we talking about tech books like
programming are you talking about some
other book so okay I think that that's
it for today I'm gonna continue for
two to five minutes okay I'm just gonna
read the comments and that'll be it for
today and today's drink let me drink my
let me do my ritual of showing you today
string first of all again a cheap energy
drink this one is supposed to be pina
colada flavored and also it's sugar-free
okay
always sugar-free never drink sugared
water such as Pepsi and Coke
never they do things to your body okay
you should follow that okay if anything
you get out of watching my show is that
don't drink sugar drink try to you know
try to get rid of it now I have juice
let me get it
so I went to the Dollar Tree store and
got myself supplies tomato juice and
this one is prune juice again it's
sugar-free okay it's all juice 100%
juice
it's from concentrate or whatever you
know I don't care too much about that as
long as it's you know just juice not not
with sugar or or whatever you know they
put corn syrups things like that
so okay so let me read the comments and
that will be it for today
Cheers PG D P now how do you DP okay so
deep he I just call you DP because you
have a profile photo that's just D and P
you know look at this Google look look
at this Google censorship going on today
in the in our world today so George says
George says only a little with OpenBSD
and Google you know to go censored it
this message is helpful review what the
[ __ ] is society has become this [ __ ]
social justice forgets what way is that
sense that what does that it needs to be
reviewed because you know there are
algorithms you know trying to censor so
much you know these big you know
beginning this this sentiment begin with
the social justice people you know it's
like oh you know the hate speech in so
long they and whatnot so they did they
you know so show that so ok so read the
comments from the beginning so good
morning again we are one good morning
you I've are you from China or you in
USA or elsewhere here one so DP P P is
from Germany okay so do you know what
think say that okay so teachers German
you teach me bathroom you you actually
type something like how do you say hello
this is something like how do you say
love okay that's that's everything
that's everything everyone wants to know
how do you say how do you say love in
Germany in German
okay type it both of you okay so uh so
j-pop what do you mean Jpop je up so
ring ringin tag web surf tag okay I
don't know what they are
talk about eMac beasts talk about em can
you talk about Emacs this Josh you
should come in you know coming next time
earlier you know coming next time
earlier you know and post that then
doubt we can do that because usually
when I begin to talk about something
then it's just like a train it's just
like a bullet it's like a iron trend
there's a moment you cannot stop it now
and one thing leads to another
so if you like me yeah you know if you
like my show come in next so next week
it's going to be 10 o clock okay in the
morning San Francisco time 10 o clock
you you know coming and n-type and also
you know just say you Mac this and also
the most specific question the better
because the most specific like like if
you actually have a count question you
is it will be much better
I mean by that by that I mean I start to
talk much more you know because I got
something to talk about so you know for
example you could say you know you like
to learn you Mac this like do you know
any at all or do you or what do you
think about eMac based compared to other
languages then that's a entirely
different question because then that's
not technical question you know it's
also like like so I mean so what what is
your you know where you coming from
you know if like if so if you can ask
more more specific questions are better
but otherwise you know if you want you
know I can just talk about start to talk
about just pick a random topic about
email this I can talk about that
so DP is using vim since 1994 Wow
so bathroom is a star next to me okay
path the mule and Zee Tron crazy
damn you ode of my long for me it's
neither either vim or Emacs didn't make
a final decision so George says sigh so
you're 2020 goal in your website how
close are you to achieving them that's
that's a very bad article you run into I
posted that because I remember I I
posted that like four years ago
basically I've haven't I have made no
progress it's kind of like my life story
you know so I started to do some talk
show
you know like right now you know for
since half a year ago I started know
every day I'm doing things but it's not
focused that's that's that actually a
bad thing so anyway the thing is about
so I wrote a article that says my goal
for the next three years or five years
you know 2020 some of them for example
they are writer compiler create my new
language no pasa theory well that's so
these to me these three things are
together you know so I can create my own
language right a parcel rather compact
compared oh that's together I didn't
really do that then I need to know
JavaScript you know I need to write a
JavaScript curve you know curve parting
library you know well I didn't really do
that you know things like that and the
other major ago I want to do is I want
to know how much of he type theory or
proof theory well that I also failed I
didn't make and the other one is about
about differential geometry yeah I
didn't really do too well on that
neither so that's pretty bad
okay Bartholomew says Church the design
of OpenBSD page actually 18th second 25
should be shutting down OpenBSD you know
PST so Church the design it's really bad
it's pretty bad first of all it looks
like they are like 1999 era actually
this this is not 1999 but this is more
like you know it's kind of like 1999
style of not really bad and first of all
the texts are too small and look at this
this is so this is pretty idiotic you
know this long-running text this line
from left to right you have to read it
like that you know do they know CSS so
first of all you have to magnify I have
to make magnifying I get old I have to
magnify yeah so it's pretty bad then you
know even my website got better
well FreeBSD okay so next we are about
done okay so thank you guys for watching
I'm country in trying to install getting
basic stuff on their notebook okay don't
forget to answer my email let later okay
I'll do that today for sure you are not
worried about artificial sweeteners okay
artificial sweeteners I I'm not worried
about them yeah so I looked into I don't
think they are that bad you know I mean
I know you know for health conscious
people a lot of people you know they say
oh those are cancer genus you know they
are cancer course causing some people
always say they are quite a few types of
official sweeteners you know basically
chemistry you have several types and
usually usually each one has a marketing
marketing name like nutrasweet is one of
them the the okay some of them I can
actually name there is dextrose there is
text extras is not other visual swin
sweetener it's you know sugar this or
this subject is about chemistry
you know skirmished chemistry is a big
thing so sugar there are many types you
know they did and I don't really know
how they works I don't really know how
they works dextrose yeah circus so in in
chemistry about sugar you have circus
you have the other mistakes dextrous I
think anyway but that's that those are
not artificial sweetener you have
Zachary Zachary I think one of them is
called Zachariah the chemistry anyway I
don't think I worried up I don't worry
about them because I'm not paranoid
about that I think if you consume you
know if you don't do anything crazy
you'll be fine
I mean there's no you know they say they
cause cancer but I don't think so
possibly but but there are lots of
things in your life that's far worse
then then artificial sweetener
sweeteners such as drinking Pepsi or
coke that's ten times worse okay then
then just drinking diet okay and also
you know driving your car it's ten
hundred times increases your death
chances of death not a hundred times if
you drive cars you know things like that
you know if you don't exercise you get
too fat you know so I'm not too worried
about artificial sweeteners
okay so yeah thank you guys for coming
I almost puked when I first time saw
OpenBSD Finch Thank You Cathy
thank you guys thank you Bartholomew and
George and you know thank you guys for
coming and and you know if you have
money if you're walking you know put
some money in my in my pocket you know
my paypal and my patreon you know it's
on my website the links on my on my
website bye guys