Hello guys, good evening everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Pasad talk
show. I talk and show. We are going to
talk random randomish. Uh actually I'm
going to code wam language. Okay. My
keyboards this is UHK80 ultimate hacking
keyboard. Can you see it? Yes. And this
is Nia Trackboard. My favorite
trackboard. And that's Logitech with the
spin wheel Logitech mouse. Fantastic.
Okay, let's switch to my screen. Okay,
so we're going to uh talk randomish um
and uh but but mostly but I wanted to
code wam language. I got this uh heavy
task of wufam uh language programming.
Uh if you don't know, I'm not going to
explain but because I've been explaining
Wuam language for hundreds of times in
my videos. Today is episode 756. That
means I've done 750
videos.
Cheers. This is red wine to soothe my
soul.
You know when you read too much polit
politics when you read politics it's
very sad and you kind of like need a
drink.
We are talking about American American
politics. We are American. We are in
America and it is very sad and painful.
You know, a year ago, we thought Trump
is gonna have a chance to save USA,
so called Make America Great Again, MAGA
by the brief. But it turns out he became
the worst. And it's [laughter] it's not
MAGA [ __ ] It's like MAGA is just like a
a a skin.
Uh and so USA is very sad. It's um you
know what they say it's the collapsing
of an empire.
Okay, we're not supposed to talk about
politics but you know like and
especially this week there is the
release of the files of Jesus. The files
uh very sad thing. Okay, but let's talk
about uh computer science. Okay,
computer science. And uh so I've been
very busy. I've been super busy. Very
busy. Super busy.
So if you guys are here, say hi. Support
me. Sponsor me. One concurrent viewers.
What the [ __ ] Okay. So, uh if you are
watching this offline, pay at 1.5 speed
minimum. Okay. Okay. Nobody's here. So,
I'm just going to do a monologue
session, which is what I do, which I do
often because when you do, not you, but
me. Because to do monologue, you must
have certain personality.
Only certain type of people are suitable
to do monologue and they can do it
better. And I am such an example
monologue
analyzing stuff and stuff. Okay. So
monologue you know there are many topics
to go into but uh well I'm not sure I'm
going to like start a real important
monologue. I can but I need someone to
like tell me like if you ask me a
question to do a monologue on some
specific topic then I can do that. Hello
Desen Desen Narrowly. Hello there. Who
are you? Desen, you know, you guys
announce I assume zoomers.
When I see you guys, you know, on
YouTube, I automatically assume it's
like a non teenager like 20 or 20
something below 20 or, you know, 16
years old or something. [snorts] Hello,
Dan. Okay, so we got a few people.
Hello, Cash and everyone. Who is Cash?
Okay. I don't know who you guys are. So,
what do you guys want me to talk about?
I can talk about because I was gonna I
was gonna do you know I was gonna talk
random and I was actually I wanted to
code wam language. We I got this
problem. Oh, let's start it. Wufam
language the most amazing the most
powerful
technically we say it is the most high
level programming language on earth a
magnitude higher level than all others
such as Le Pascal F or camel camel uh
Julia Erland whatever like fancy uh name
or rust whatever fancy programming
language you can think of Wuang language
is a magnitude higher level. Okay. A
magnitude not just like oh two times two
times shorter code you know to write
this in hascal requires 100 lines to
write in wam requires uh one line you
know like 100 lines difference. Well
that's kind of like about it. Okay. So
100 lines number of lines difference
that's about like compare if you compare
wam language to python or whatever.
Okay.
So um a magnitude um so long. Oh yeah, I
was going to code because I you know I
was going to code something like rather
esoteric you know uh most of you
wouldn't understand because
I was going to code you know so the the
the problem is this
first of all find all possible symbols
in Wuang language which you can do that
by evaluate evaluating that. Okay, so
you got all possible symbols. So the so
you got like one uh basically 7,000 of
them. Okay, so these are a list of all
possible symbols in Wuam language. Now
that's
okay. Now the the the problem I want to
do is that given a symbol such as arg
max or arg or min those are related to
complex numbers or around uh but anyway
or array so array generates array. So
given one of these symbols determine
whether it is a function name or
determine whether it is a name for an
option. Option is a thing in wuam
language. Okay. So anyway so the my
problem that I want to do I need to do
this part of my job because I need to
write um
casawi mode in eacisp. Okay not complete
symbol but you can jump to kasaw wufi
mode. So here's the source code. You can
see kasaw wufam mode that's written in
eagisp that allows you to code wam
language in eagisp and which I've
demonstrated
hundred of times over 100 times in my
live stream. So this mode one of the
thing you need to do is you need to list
all symbols in the wuam language for
completion. So these are for example you
can you know so you can see that is done
by um by this okay by this um
by by the way these are special uh named
characters in wam language even before
unic code. So wuam language allows you
to have like mathematical symbols
summation integral sign plus minus sign
you know without like even before unic
code. So this is be you know before in
199 starting in 1980 uh actually
starting in 1996.
Okay. So anyway I was saying so so my
job what I need to do is one list all
symbols you can do that you know and but
the so the question is given a symbol
determine whether it's a function name
or a optional name. Okay. So I was not
able to do that. I I haven't found an
easy way. So that's kind of uh kind of a
esoteric
coding problem about Wuam language.
Okay. So I'm going to I need that's what
I need to code. So there are 7,000
symbols here because by default uh Wuang
language has 7 thou,000 building
symbols. You know all these are like
functions. Okay. So you can uh actually
if you uh I want to uh do them in like
two columns. Can you do it again? Shift
enter.
Uh okay. There's still two one column.
So make it 150 uh magnification smaller
then you will show two columns. Still
one column anyway. Anyway, so that's
what I want to do because I want to do
that because I'm writing the this wam uh
emac woof mode. I want to be able to
have completion context dependent
completion. Okay.
Okay. So, that's something I want to do.
But, um
and uh I was reading some um so some
news. Okay. So, let's go to uh let me
show you guys some news. Uh uh math
blog. Okay.
What?
Yeah, math blocks. So, so let's go to my
math blog. So, Wuam Stefan Wuam recently
wrote a new article. Okay. So, uh let's
just search for Stefan Wuam. I think
that's a fantastic. Well, I'm not sure
about that one, but anyway.
I'm not sure this one is fantastic.
Okay. But however, this uh the current
writing Oh, you need to turn on
JavaScript. So, this is a guy Stefan
Wolf. Uh
oh, wow. So, he wrote a new article. I
didn't notice
what ultimately is there metaphysics and
rule. Okay. I didn't know about this one
actually. So, this is news to me. So I
need to read it because I read aid. I
read a lot of his articles. Okay. Uh so
this one I need to read. But what I
wanted to tell you is about this one.
Okay.
P versus MP and the difficulty of
computation a rule logical approach.
Okay.
Uh I haven't read it yet but I'm
beginning to. So this is talking about P
versus MP problem. A millennial price
problem. Meaning that if you solve it,
you get $1 million, which is like
pitiful. You know, if you if you
actually are able to solve it, you are
worth more than a million. You know,
like the corporations are will like they
will be eager to give you a million
dollars to hire you. Okay? all the
universities like a petty a million
dollars anyway. So there's a million
dollar price about the P versus MP and
the problem um so you know so this is I
think this is very interesting article
to dive into because he goes by the you
know his obsession is the rulology.
What does it meanology? basically it
takes everything in consideration with
respect to computation. So in other
words, he wants to view
lots of mathematical problems and
physics problems a as as basically
systematic basically look at them as
computation
uh
uh systematic
examination of all possible computation
and uh observe what are the properties
what kind of properties we get what kind
of you know what kind of situation we
get so that is basically ludo ludology
okay that's like a term he created
okay so that so you know so anyway I
wanted to mention this article because I
think that's interesting but however I
haven't read it yet okay however what I
highly recommend uh is his other
articles that like like there are about
top five of his articles I really uh
love. Okay, that's lambda calculus and
combinators. Okay, lambda calculus the
rulology of lambdas. Okay, read that one
by Stephan Wuam. I highly recommend it.
And and this one more so combinators
combinators
centennial view by Stefan Wuam. Okay,
this is actually three articles. Each
each article is about like a thousand
pages. Okay. Uh well, not a thousand but
few hundred pages. So anyway, so these
three on combinators they they form a
book like a booklet you can actually buy
printed. Okay. So these articles I
highly recommend uh from Stefan Wu
if you are a programmer and if you have
interest in actual computer science.
These are about theoretical computer
science. So this is not your typical
like database operating systems C++
programming idiots obsession. Okay.
graphics, you know, these are real
computer science, theoretical computer
science. Okay. So, I re highly
recommended these two article by Stephan
Wu, not by others. There are other
prominent computer scientists who have
written about these topics, but but I
kind of highly uh by s significantly
recommend just Stefan Wuam's take his
approach. Okay, so check it out.
And I'm going to read them for the nth
time again because I read them several
times. Uh but I'm going to read them uh
again because I
and in combination with the latest, you
know, the P and MP problem. Now, this
one I'm I haven't read it yet, but I'm
not sure it's too interesting because he
because I read a lot of he of his
articles and he always takes, you know,
he's like doing kind of this systematic
computational
and systematic again systematic approach
uh to to to a uh issue or a problem. and
uh and often he comes up with up with
all these like diagrams like showing
their statistical distribution
the phenomenon. So you know like he look
at things from this rudology which which
is like
basically like um basically like
cellular automata but not just on grids
you know cellular automata is like you
know you got these grids and you you you
draw cells like the game of life of
conway so you observe them in evolve
right so that's one of the most
fundamental
basic
computation, you know, rules, you know,
but but it's not but but the basic the
concept of computation is not just
grids. You can have them on a number
system. You can have them on a string
system. You can have them on uh uh what
are they doing? Lambda, you know, you
can do them so or on chewing machine,
you know. So you just have some simple
rules and you observe how they behave.
Okay. So that's what he call rudiology.
The study of simple computations you
know you you simply just systematically
study all all type of the algorithms and
see how they behave. Okay. So, so in
this article he's doing that to trying
to determine trying to see, you know,
just simply by just systematically
look at all possible
uh rules of
of
algorithms for the chewing machine and
and observe just make a observation and
see which can which one can
uh result in a particular goal faster
than the other they in other words their
computational complexity okay so anyway
so I don't know how important is this
article I haven't read it yet okay but
I'm just telling you about his way of
looking at things so lots of his
articles has this you know like this
statistical
approach of looking at thousands of of
different examples of of rules and what
what they you know what's the result we
get. Okay, that's Stephan Wua
and usually his article what like each
one of his blog is like hundreds of
pages like literally hundreds of pages.
[laughter]
That's Stephan Wuam's blog. Okay. So
what uh what are you guys saying? So
hello cash and so hi no Zuma here. Okay.
So then you are not a zoomer. Fantastic.
Wuan language is always great.
Interesting. Um yeah. So you see I can
tell because of the the technology of
the YouTube and live stream
made it such that you know you can live
stream and a lot of people can watch it
you know sometimes even millions you
know uh but so it you create a
phenomenon of one
versus many relationships. So, I don't
know who you who I can tell who you guys
are, but you guys kind of know me at
least my you know my you uh live stream
um personality. Anyway, so Wuang
language is interesting. Somewhere I saw
that term very high level language is
old and was used in ' 90s.
What are you talking about? Let me
explain to you. Okay. So, high level
language it means just like high level
low level. So,
you are saying somewhere I saw the term
very high level language is old and was
used in ' 90s. What do you mean? So,
anyway, so language you can classify
them roughly by high level and low
level. Okay, you absolutely can do that
and you know because the low-level
language uh the machine language okay
which is the lowest level
machine language the code is just one
and zero. So you write what you write is
just uh literally one and zero one uh
one one 0 0 one one uh you cannot have
two okay so you you know it's just like
uh uh that that's a machine language
that's that's you know that's nobody
actually able to write that not a single
human writes that okay that's the
machine that's the CPU runs on the CPU
you
no it's even hard to understand and I
I'm not sure there's even a tutorial
about machine language
well there there is some okay so at that
level it's like very like you are inside
the CPU okay anyway and there's a micro
uh micro uh machine language
okay so that's actually like a machine
language within a machine language
machine code. Okay, machine code set of
instructions executed directly on
computer central CPU processing unit. In
computing, a machine code is data
encoded and structured to control a
computer's central processing unit or
whatever blah blah blah. Okay, so that's
low level. Then second level to that is
assembly.
Okay, assembly language looks like x =
to 3. Then um then then move X uh three
Y okay every line is like three car
three words okay assembly language okay
that's kind of the lowest human
accessible language
okay so you look at Wikipedia so you can
look at some example of assembly so
that's one so every line is about three
words basically something you know uh um
you know like uh like put this number in
that register and move that copy this
register to that register and and
increment this register by one something
like that. So that's machine language.
Actually I never had any experience.
Okay. So anyway that's machine language.
Okay.
I mean that's assembly language. Then
the next next level is kind of the C
idiots. Okay.
Okay. Okay. Then the higher level is CPP
or uh yeah CPP or you can consider
Goland or Rust. Okay. That's higher
level. Then the higher level than that
you can say uh okamel that would
functional programming f
uh has lisp okay that's kind of higher
level because well also well also uh
python
bash python the things you are familiar
with uh
okay and and then javascript and okay
javascript
and Ruby. Okay, that's higher level. So,
let's let's start to write uh write it,
shall we? Write it.
Uh talk show. Today's talk show. Go to
it and start to do some random talk
about the levelness of programming
languages. Okay.
So, go up create a new section. So you
see we've fantastic, extreme, beautiful,
most efficient keybinding system. That's
Kasafly keys. Okay. Uh that's that's the
Kasly keys. The most efficient
keybinding system you've ever seen in
your life. Here's a source code. 4,000
lines of code. You can drop it into it.
You see Kafly keys. Open it. And it is
open source. And you can see the source
code. The homepage on this website
kasali.info. my homepage, my website and
you can see it is also available on
GitHub. Uh you can download on GitHub
stuff like is the most efficient key
mining system more efficient than Vim.
So if you are a VI user,
you know, you will be defeated by people
using stuff like keys because they will
be able to do the same thing you are
typing or editing but less keystrokes.
That's what is meant by more efficient.
Okay. In a scientific way, not how I
feel. Oh, I feel Vim is better. No.
Okay. It's not I feel I feel Unix is
better. No. I feel C++ is better. No,
it's scientifically. Okay. So, less
number of keystrokes you can measure it
by doing the king vim golf game. Okay.
That's like keys and open source.
uh so that you can use keys and go back.
So what are we doing here? Uh I was just
just showing you that. Yeah. So I was
going to show you about so the level of
programming languages. Okay.
Uh so make it H2 and remove that. And
the lowest is machine language language.
Okay. It looks like this.
Okay. So,
it's just zero and one.
Okay.
Next
is uh
Okay. Next is assembly language.
It basically looks like this.
Okay. Something like that. Okay.
Something uh something I don't really
know. Okay. I actually because I don't
have experience of m uh assembly
language. Next higher
level is C idiots. Okay.
Then next higher level is CBP, Goland,
Rust. They are kind of in the same
group. Then next higher level
uh programming language is
uh bash, Python, JavaScript, Ruby they
you can consider them in the same group
and TCL and uh Lua and others. Okay.
Then you can say next higher level
programming language is uh kind of list
or camel. They kind of kind of higher
level. Okay. Now what does higher level
mean? Well there are many ways to
explain it. One way is you can say it's
higher abstraction. But a practical way
is that just it's like you write one
lines of higher level equals to 10 lines
of lower level. Okay. So one line of
Python equals to 10 lines of C++ Goland
Rust. Actually what actually one line of
Python is equals to about two lines of
Golan because I personally know that
experience you know I personally
coded uh lots of them Golan. So you can
see my code Golan. I have a full Golan
tutorial here. You can learn about it
and go back to a programming language
tutorial on.info.
So you can see Golan I also personally
coded Golan for like 10 years more than
10 years. So I can tell you Goland I was
rather disappointed because
because
for every line of Python
for every line of Python it takes about
1.5 more lines in Golan. So if you write
something in Python 100 lines in go
language it will be 150 lines. I was
kind of disappointed in that. But Goline
would be it will be it would be like
three times faster than than Python.
Okay. So that's that's a meaning the
meaning of like the higher level. What
does it mean level like higher level of
programming language? It it is a
valid concept. Okay. The level of
programming language. So what I am
claiming is that woof language. Okay.
by a magnitude is wo frame. Okay. So
next what's higher level then lisp or
camel f hascal you know one one line of
ok camel lisp equals to two line of
python python actually the this okamo f
hascal they are kind of in the same
level of
python okay I mean this is just roughly
okay it depends on specific language but
I would say f is more less is less lines
than pythons So, so F is actually higher
level than Python. Okay. So, this I mean
this gives you like a general idea of
the higher higher level of language.
Okay. But then the next one or certainty
is the Wuam language. Okay. It's like
one wam language is like 10 lines of
Python for sure. Absolutely.
And depending on how you count, if you
count mathematical um solving math
equations or doing integrals or uh you
know matrix algebra or whatever or uh
differential equations or machine
learning then one line of wim language
is equivalent to 1,000 lines of has of
Hascal or Python. Okay. So that's that
is the meaning that is the concrete
meaning of why why what I'm saying about
woofer language is a magnitude beyond
all existing programming languages
there's like nothing approaching even it
nothing even approaching it okay it's
not like just a higher level language
it's like higher level by a magnitude
okay that's what I want to Okay.
Okay, that's it. Um, so that's a
digression. So I was going to So, uh,
question, have you ever experimented
with Scala? No.
Uh, no. But I have done Closure. I have
done Closure for like um
for a year act professional programming
in closure for a year. So, so let's copy
the, you know, let's copy some of my
tutorials and copy it so that we can
link it so people can like go to it. Uh,
not Ruby. So, Python I've done a lot
Python. Okay. So, linkify so people can
later on go check out my tutorials. So,
go to programming language tutorials and
Scala. I haven't done but I've done
closure for about a year in a
professional way. I get paid like you
know few few thousand dollars. Um and uh
Scala I haven't I don't have experience
but from you know just being nearby I I
think it's not not more higher level
than than closure closure is more pure
functional scala is less pure. Scola
allows you to functional allows you to
do functional programming. It's but it's
but you can also do it in many ways but
closure is more like more pure
functional programming. Okay. So I kind
I can recommend closure. Okay. Closure
is part of lisp.
Okay. So I think I rambled a lot but my
focus mainly what I wanted to say is uh
I want to tell you guys about the
studying of this theoretical computer
science okay lambda calculus and
combinators okay uh of the Stefan Wuam's
um blog okay lambda calculus and
combinators
supremely beautiful and they are I mean
not just I mean not uh not just
beautiful but uh but they are the like
the the
they are the the heart of computer
theoretical computer science. Okay. I
think maybe I should go get some uh red
wine. Um
okay. So let me think about where we
going to do now. What we going to do? So
we talked for about 20 minutes, right?
Any questions you guys have like you
guys feel like uh I can answer 36
minutes. So we talked for 30 minutes. So
we talked about randomish. Oh yeah. So
let me tell you guys about my JavaScript
work. So
talk show go to homepage kasali.info
http nos. Okay. If the browser tells
you, oh, insecure website, the browser
is trying to censor lots of website.
That's why they do that. My website does
not ask you for your credit card because
I'm not a Amazon or whatever. So,
there's no need
to have HTTPS. Okay? HTTP nos. Don't
believe what browser is trying to tell
you. Oh, insecure website because they
are trying to censor about few million
old websites instantaneously.
They don't want you to know about the
history of the internet. you know the
the the thousands of the the millions of
website in the 1990s and 2000s year
2000s they don't have http https
but however it happened all these
internet website happened before today
you know that's the era the internet the
history of the internet so you can see
lots of information what they think
about the internet what they talk about
the internet
but today the all those website a
million about few millions of them they
got censored instantaneously by Google
and Firefox because they pretend to
think that oh those website be careful
they are insecure because they they
don't have HTTPS okay that's a that's
their way this deep state they're trying
to censor a few million website
instantaneously okay by scaring tactics
okay which includes my website so anyway
you go to my website sa.code code and
you go down. Uh what I wanted to say is
um oh yeah so I've been working on
JavaScript
huge amount of JavaScript in past weeks.
So lots of updates
um date tutorial date class date
constructor date now dateutc
um
uh methods okay uh methods and date
prototype so lots of work and uh on
JavaScript okay infinity con so you can
read about it just search go to webdev
blog okay so JavaScript and in the past
week I've done quite a few live streams
talking about JavaScript.
Uh so yeah, we did a lot.
So any anything else interesting? So
let's see. Dan says maybe it's me, but
as I get older, I'm more and more
interested in highle languages like Wuan
language. I used to be into C, but there
is a beauty to what Wuan language that C
just can provide.
Yeah, that's true. Um, you know, so each
person have different experience. For
me, I just never I never know about the
C like the low-level stuff and uh I find
myself not too interested in them
because I'm more of a math guy. I want
to know because in mathematics there's
lot like like there's a million unsolved
problems.
a million like for example this P and MP
you know this is unsolved problem
and this problem is is not hard to
understand it's like it's simple so
unsolved okay there there are a
thousands thousands of unsolved easy to
understand mathematical problems
including including computational
problems for example recently I was
reading about
knight uh tool. Okay. So, the chess. So,
it's very very interesting on a
chessboard. You you got one of the
classic
exercise is to find is it possible to
have a knight traverse a chessboard and
visit every square on the chessboard?
You know, the knight, you know. So, so
this problem is called knight's tool and
when so I so there's another problem
related that's queens eight queens
problem which I solved when I was like
30 years ago when I was starting to you
know on a calculator HP HP calculator I
programmed the code at that time I don't
know anything about programming you know
I don't know anything about programming
or computer science but I just happened
to code it by
now I know it's called backtracking
algorithm the the way you classify that
algorithm is you call it backtracking
algorithm but I did that uh 30 years ago
when I was like young like you like many
of you guys okay so HP calculator HP28s
calculator okay so I want to check out
my website let's see if they mention my
website today uh No, [ __ ] them.
So, you see they uh
my website used to be the first result
when you search for HP28s
advanced scientific calculator. I spent
like $300. Was it $250
in 1992? I remember
buying this calculator spending $280.
Uh, okay. So, kasali. So, you have to
type kali there. Okay. So, I bought this
$250 in 1992 or 1993. 1992, I think.
$250.
I bought it because I'm so excited about
mathematics. you know I really want to
uh learn and you know math or computers
you know so I bought this and and at
that time so I don't know anything about
programming languages what you know what
is internet I have no idea but however I
ran into I was told about the eight
queens problem okay so I solved it I
programmed it I wrote a program here's a
program code this code by the way this
programming language is called um
reverse polished lisp. Okay. But I
believe that's what they called
reverse polish lisp. Okay. Anyway, it's
you know so anyway I wrote this code to
solve the eight queens program. Eight
queens puzzle which is a classic problem
in programming exercise. That is the
question is if you can you place eight
queens on a chessboard so that none of
the queens check each other. Okay, there
are so there are actually quite a few
solutions. Okay, and I my program
actually there's a bug. So I missed four
solutions but anyway so it turns out
this the program is using so-called
backtracking algorithm. So like you try
you know you try and this doesn't work
then you go back then you go to the next
step you try it does it work no go back
and you know go back go back go back you
know try you know so that's a
backtracking algorithm
as far as the classification you know
one one of the uh algorithm types okay
so but I was reading so I didn't know
about nights tool I was reading about it
today actually yesterday.
So that knight's tool is that is it
possible to have a knight to traverse a
chessboard such that it
you know visits all squares
and if it if if it's possible to return
to the starting point okay that's called
knight's tool and when I was looking at
this problem I was thinking about so you
know they they mentioned it's like you
can treat it as a graph theory problem.
So in graph theory it's called
Hamiltonian path. Hamiltonian path means
that given a graph is it possible to go
visit every node of the graph
okay is it in one shot you know so
that's called Hamiltonian path I I am I
I was familiar with this you know um 30
years ago because I was reading about
graph theory but then I didn't know so I
was thinking about the nice tool so then
so the knight's tool is actually so you
can turn it into a graph. So I was
thinking about this graph and then I you
know so then I realized Wikipedia has it
all figured out. Wikipedia like just
explain the whole thing exactly the way
I was thinking it you know night's
graph. So you got this graph which is
now called nights graph and which is uh
actually happened to be a bipartate
graph. So that's uh fascinating. So
anyway this is an example of mathematics
okay uh in in in programming about you
know about programming okay so the
reason I started to mention is mention
it is I was like I was telling you guys
you know the C and C++
idiots this type of the Unix C++
idiots I despise
you know they are thinking their brain
And they are thinking about bits, about
memory, about let's hack it. Uh let's
have a bit mask. Let's have you know
like the computer graphics you know
pointers these idiots you know their
things the the the way they think about
programming about problems about
whatever they do
it seems like never interested me. So I
never got I never interested in this
low-level I mean it's it's critically
important to be sure to know about
assembly languages you know to to know
about yeah of course you know it's
critically important to have machine
language how it works how does booting
operating how does operating system
works how can you boot from a operating
system you have the like booting problem
like uh you know how do you have you
know how how how do you have assembly
languages? How do you have CPU
instructions?
How you see these are fundamentally
important
for
the electronic kind of the electronic um
hardware. On the other hand, you also
have DNA computers. You also have
quantum m machine computers. Okay, they
are entirely different computers with
entirely different bits. They are, you
know, different from your typical, you
know, the the typical C and C++
idiots [snorts]
imagination. Okay, entirely different.
So anyway, I was mentioning I was, you
know, starting to say, you know, you
typically I didn't find the C. I didn't
um for me I I'm not you know I find
myself not too interested in these bits
and buys this like typical C and C++ and
Unix programmers and operating systems
their interest. Okay. So, so what am I
interested? What you know? So, what what
are you interested in? I'm interested in
like this nice tool, graph theory,
combinatorics,
lambda calculus, you know, this this
like thousands unsolved problems. Can
you solve them?
Okay. Does does that make sense? Do I
make sense as a illustration to perhaps
most of you industrial programmers who
daily you know wallow in the C bit and
bites and things. Do you understand this
nice tool?
Right. Do do I make sense? Okay, that's
it. That's like my rant.
Uh yeah. So, have you ever experimented
with Scala? Okay. No. Is it fun to solve
a math problem if it is already have
been solved by some mega math wizards?
Okay, that's a interesting question of
course
and is is it fun? Yes, of course. And in
fact you have to do it because you know
if you
if you have the mindset that you are
just going to not waste time. You see
anytime you have must be focused on
things that don't have a solution yet.
Unsolved problem
that is actually impossible because for
each of us we have to go through the
learning process.
And this learning process actually takes
you know may likely takes 10 years five
10 and you know and it in fact it has to
it perpetuates like as long as you are
alive you have to go through this step
you can never think about you know I'm
just going to focus on solving unsolved
problems you almost like you always have
to repeat the steps going through the
motion of those in different fields of
the solved problems you have to go
through them because that's part of the
for humans that's part of the learning
process. If you are a machine maybe you
can skip that but we are humans we
cannot.
So you you kind of have like to always
have to go through the motion of solving
already solved problems so that you you
get the experience your brain gets to
you know like the neural network your
brain your brain establish the
connections about knowing them solving
them okay
I okay that's bunch of rants and
ramblings and I think that's it for
today Uh let's see. Uh okay. So how many
people watching four? Okay.
Okay. That's it. I think that's it. Any
any questions like Okay. What was I
going to do? So let's um let's just do
random nothing. Okay. So I'm going to
close that random chat and uh yeah. So
this is about random chat.
Uh
now regarding the wuam language problem,
I just have to work it offline. Okay, I
cannot. Um
yeah, so lots of walking. Okay, bye
guys.