hello welcome to another episode of
sound talk
show uh today I'm going to talk about
emac history the real history of emac
how much did Richard storman
do okay so that is one topic and the
other topic is going to I'm going to
talk about we we're going to code some
JavaScript live coding a keyboard
layout uh remap remap function okay
hello guys hello seral hello
Phillip hello uh so let's begin so my
keyboards so this is glove at Fantastic
this is Ultimate hacking keyboard to
Fantastic okay you see they have a
functional light so the color of the
keyboard changes
depending on their function and here is
the S board s v l b o a Rd data hand uh
so you can check out my videos I have a
videos for all of them especially I like
to recommend Smartboard I still I'm
still learning it okay let's start
coding emac I mean let's talk about emac
what you know what I have been doing the
emac history uh so let me show you my
screen and emac I'm using softly keys
and on the pink window oh let's move it
here the pink window shows all my
command course and uh and the keystroke
the keystroke on the left okay can you
see it yes so if you have a
questions post it now okay so I'm going
to answer hello Phillips hey man I used
s math input many years ago it's the
best thank you uh what's your thoughts
on Happy hacking keyboard okay happy
happy hacking keyboard is
[ __ ] okay if you if you want to know my
opinion I'm surp is that a troll
question or if you you know because I
was famous for flaming happy happing
happy hacking keyboard so you can see it
go to Sali keyboard blog computer
keyboards noal keyboards and here is uh
you know so they have a new version of
Happy hacking with Bluetooth came out
about uh 2019 five years ago but my
originally my original flame of happy H
happy hacking
keyboard is
here the idy of happy hacking keyboard
you know happy hacking keyboard it has a
code behind it like a lot of people
they'll just say how great it is in fact
it's one of the worst keyboard okay many
people like the toppa switch that's a
switch mechanism many people like it
okay that's that's kind of debatable
okay but but many people love it but
however the happy hacking keyboard
layout is the worst
idiotic like you useless meritless crap
happy hacking keyboard you know part of
the reason it became F famous kind of a
popular and developed a code in Western
Society okay this is kind of important
in Western Society it developed a kind
of a code is because for several reasons
one it's when it's first of all it's
from Japan okay it's from Japan you know
the Western American society kind of
have a uh Affinity with Japan not China
well partly because political reasons
because you know so Affinity with Japan
and plus Japanese anime you know all
that so anime you know that's a big part
too
so part of the reason happy happy
hacking keyboard has a kind of a code in
Western American uh societies because
it's from Japan and very expensive you
know over $200 and $300 for the latest
Bluetooth version like
um God let me let me me show it again so
happy hacking keyboard hybrid Type S
okay and let's just show it so happy
hacking keyboard uh yeah so this is a
new version it cost like over $300
350 300 okay now so it's now
300 crap $300 for keyboard that doesn't
have many
keys uh and so many reasons okay and the
left hand side and right hand side okay
now they they are asymmetric um wait did
they fix that anyway so and you know not
many you know you don't have modifier
Keys much anyway so the reason it
developed a code is because first of all
it's from Japan and very expensive okay
that's uh one reason two reasons and
also because it has this particular
layout that's somewhat you know to the
uh Unix hackers liking in uh more
specifically it's got the control key
you see right where the caps lock is
okay now many Unix
Fanatics you know part another part of
the reason happy hacking has uh code in
USA is because it's got the word hacking
you know the Unix type of people Unix
hackers you know this these type of
people they they enjoy the word hacking
or and the concept of hacking very much
so they so that's part of the reason
okay the part of the reason it's a code
and then you see the control key to the
left of a so they removed essentially
removed the cap lock which is actually a
good thing but it became you know it's a
complex issue so
whether you know what what what position
should control key B for the optimal
efficiency or hand Health you know
that's one question okay there's a lot
of details that depends on whether you
are on laptop or whether you are on full
keyboard or you can also use the pump
control method to pum press control
method okay like
that uh you search my web blog you you
search my S keyboard you'll find you
know
pal uh
uh how to press control key okay I made
this technique popular it is me I made
this popular about 15 years ago uh you
know this article is dated TW uh
2022 because I moved it for my emac
block but it was originally uh in 2013
and before so I made this technique
popular somewhat in emac community so
you use your palm to press the control
so these are photos uh some of them
people send it to me you know so for
example this one people send it to me uh
I think two of
them so anyway pump press control so
anyway back to happy hacking so happy
hacking uh so let's go back
uh okay let's go back to the Happy
hacking
keyboard okay the edsc of happy hacking
keyboard okay so from Japan
and uh has the word hacking
it and the layout so this layout is
supposed to be the Unix people's layout
for so for example they have control
lots of edsc for example they don't have
the back space key you know on a normal
keyboard can you see it uh let's let me
show
you
my can you see the picture of my
okay let me show it okay so you can see
on a normal keyboard you have the
backspace here okay I which I programmed
it to be to be the um you cannot see it
but so but now you can see I program it
to be the toggle maximize window okay so
this backspace key happy cat hacking
they don't have that key so over here I
mean so they have a delete key which is
forward delete okay okay why is that
because on Unix machines you can do
backward delete delete the previous
character by control D
okay so it's edotic all edotic all the
way you know so first of all they put
control here okay that's accept
acceptable you know it's actually better
if it the control key is on the corner
so you can pum press but now they put
the control on the on the left of a so
you have to p ke it okay it's kind of
okay okay so that's one thing but then
they remove the other control key on the
other keyboard on the other side so
there's only one control so when you
want to press control you have to
control D for example you you cran you
sprin strand your fingers into you know
into that that so you know they only
have one control key no
backspace and they instead of back space
they put a delete key which is basically
almost never used on ma on Mac operating
system on Windows operating system uh I
don't think it's actually used much in
the Unix operating system neither or
Linux but of course and and by the way
you cannot program these Keys none of
you can it's not programmable okay the
original have hacking for like 20 years
with the code the the new version the
happy hacking professional hybrid cost
$300 this one is programmable okay so
but on this on the on the classic happy
you cannot program it so lots of
problems but they have a code you know
these people they go online they'll say
oh have oh oh another thing they don't
have physical arrow keys that's most
important so if you play Pac-Man you
cannot play
you cannot play it while eating pizza
okay so you have to so how do you press
the arrow key you have to hold down
extreme idiotic okay you have to hold
down this this you see on the right
corner you have a FN key then the arrow
key is like that it's like a Loren's you
know the diamond
shape extreme
idiotic extreme but it's it's it's got a
code you know uh for the you know not so
much today I think today with the you
know so with a popularization of
ergonomic keyboard like gl8 or kesis or
lots of do it yourself mechanical
keyboards and tons of it you know so
happy hacking the code kind of died out
I would say I would claim that's my
experience but from let's say 1999 to to
2015 happy hacking is like a code you
know like every time you talk about
keyboards there are keyboard fans will
um will promote it and okay so many so
let's uh I want to talk about emac
history okay so let's talk about that
topic uh so let me let me talk about
briefly so today's video I think 40
minutes uh so it's amazing you know I've
been using emac since
1998 yeah
1998 okay so after about 26 years today
I actually seriously looked into the
history of emx what I want to know is um
what I want to know is just how much
Richard strowman did you know can he
claim you know he claim he's a creator
of emex can we accept that as reasonable
so actually today I spent like a whole
day to look into seriously in a like
historian uh way so I'll just tell you
you know I'll just tell you directly you
know get rid of the
suspense I think he deserve it okay so
we can say you you know you know history
is usually complex many inventions of
software that you know many many
inventions are created by different
people and even back then we don't know
you know this concept doesn't exist
things like that so it's fairly heavy
but overall I think you know it's
correct I mean it's acceptable to say
that Richard strowman created emac okay
let me give you a brief outline okay so
if you want to know the details uh you
can read my articles history of emac who
truly created emac okay let me show you
my emac blog so you know so that's one
article then then uh then there is um
another article a video by Gosling James
Gosling who who basically says that
Richard stowman stole his Gosling emx
and which became grx okay that's one
perspective okay that's kind of true
again you know history is fairly
complicated so that's Richard I mean uh
Gosling James Gosling the guy who
created Java you know a big guy
super super
coder and this Daniel wine R these are
the these are the people who are the you
know who are around the when at MIT lab
or you know when when in 1976
they are the people who are doing a lot
lisp and uh and kind of together created
emac okay so let me give you a brief
history so these are the Articles so
basically
emac the origin of emac is a packages a
bunch of keyboard key mark packages over
the text editor called Teo okay so let
me just go to the summary part
so so a bunch of so you know one of the
great resource if you want just a a
simplified version you can go to Jim
jimy zorinsky this is this is a another
controversial guy Jimmy zinski I have a
fight with
him he's he was the person I respected a
lot but about six seven years ago I have
a fight with him over politics you know
over the Hillary Clinton versus Trump
you know he's kind of nasty I mean not
well not nasty but he's
a you know kind of controversial so
since then I don't like him so much you
know he's like anyways I mean I mean he
he banned me on my Twitter on on the
Twitter you know he he blocked me after
one exchange you know I wasn't
aggressive but after one exchange or two
he he like um blocked me on Twitter
[ __ ] so I have a Blog about it if you
search
for Jimmy zinski jwz that's the acronym
he goes by you know back in those days
usually they these people go by acronyms
for example guy steel he's a creator of
scheme and and one of the designer of
java he's a big guy so and you know and
you know guys Ste goes by GLS Richard
strowman goes by RMS well
known uh Daniel wreb is the co-founder
of symbolics one of the first company
that creates Le machine during the AI
era of of
1976 to 1980s throughout 1980s you know
Lis a you know that's AI uh begin AI So
Daniel wine
rep David aoon he's also a giant in the
lisp community so he he's also one of
the creator of emac the
original keyboard markers you know all
these people they they part of kind of
par participated in creating the key
marker on the Techo editor which
eventually became emac kind of then
there are several versions okay I'll go
into that and add this guy don't know
much uh Charles Frank I don't know much
Ed Ed shenberg okay I don't know much
and there's uh Earl keian I don't know
much and there's Eugene cisari I don't
know much all these people created emx
okay there's uh Bob Frankston I don't
know much and there's John cop anyway
they all use acronyms a lot of them back
then so anyway my point is that okay so
let me just go to the summary so you go
to J jimy zinski he's got a one of the
earliest history blog written in 1999
okay Jimmy zorinsky you probably heard
of he is the one of the primary code of
XX which is the
first kind of free software Fork you
know in a unfriendly way so you have G
emx versus XX XX is far more Superior
than GX because I I was using it you
know I have a choice I xmx is much
better I have an article on that too so
if you search my go to Kali emx blog
search for X emac you'll find it so
Jimmy zinki you you might have heard
because he's on you know on TV you know
there's a show called uh called the
hackers or something which documents the
uh kind of the origin of the net I mean
do com days you know the the the rise of
the web website around
1999 which I was part of you know of
that move that that that
era. so Jimmy zorinsky is a well known
for creating he's a one who wrote The N
Netscape browser today is known as
Firefox ncape browser for the Unix
version okay so anyway lots of history
but anyways so he has a Blog so you can
kind of get the outline of what go
what's going on so basically in the
beginning
1976 so there was the Techo editor te O
then people write key Markos on top of
it so they are known as
TX and techm okay there are two of them
I think there's more and this maros are
created by Guy
steel Dave Moon and Richard green
greenbolt uh did he I think he spelled
the name
incorrectly but anyway let's go to his
website so you can see let me just show
his website
uh let's go to it go to it yeah okay so
here is Jimmy zin's website on the
history of
emex
so the Reon Richard greenbo guy is also
a big guy because he is a founder of the
other Le machine company okay so
anyway Techo keyboard maros these people
created it so it's a mess because you
know different people created different
Markos it's very powerful but you know
becoming a mess so they started to think
about you know merge them all together
into one single unified
system so gu steel is is a guy who began
it okay in 199
1976 then after a month or two about one
month or two basically Richard stowman
took over meaning that he wrote a lot
code and he became the main coder for it
so
1976 and also all the other people lots
of this original you know Mar creat is
They al they are also part of it you
know they contributed they debug they
you know they they all part of it so
Richard strowman that's the first thing
he did in in terms of who created emac
you know so gu Ste began you know before
that there's techmax T-Max then gu gu
still tried to unify it into one then
Richard stowman pretty much in a month
or two he he be became the main guy you
know so merge them you know so and and
this and he rich strowman is and but and
this this emac is not the emac we know
today okay you know it's not because
there's no emac list yet they are just
key markers on the Techo system Techo
editor okay okay so that's 1976 that's
one of the thing Richard stowman kind of
I mean credit to him then also
1976 Daniel wreb created I you know back
then they are into these so-called
recursive acronyms which is idiotic like
G and u g what what does it mean G is
not Unix very idiotic and this I means I
is not emac okay anyways so Daniel wire
he wrote it on MIT Lis machine in lisp
so this is the first emac written in
lisp okay then I became zy and became
zMAX on this machine on symbolics this
machine so that's a lot history but so
1976 and also
1978 the Bernie Greenberg created
multics emx on the mtic operating system
now these are history you know beyond
Beyond me so I was I was born in
so in Taiwan so I don't you know I I
started to use emac in
1998 so even 20 years before me so
multic emx running on mtic a
system so then Gosling James Gosling
created Gosling emac written in C that's
the first emac running on Unix okay 198
T1 so this Z this mtic emx this goling
emac they are not key markers on Techo
editor okay they are actual editors by
themselves okay so you have I you have
motic emx that you have Gosling emx okay
they are on different operating
systems full editor you know and and and
they all have lisp except Gosling emx
they use a he created Mark lisp which is
like lisp syntax but it's not actually
lisp there's no list in Mark lisp okay
so 198
1976 1981
1978 okay then in
1985 you know about three or four years
after all Le Richard strowman first
released publicly G
emx now at first it borrowed code from
Gosling emac basically because back then
you know copyright on
software wasn't I mean the people don't
know what that means you know because we
you know this is early days P you know
pioneering of softwares only in 1980 the
US Congress created a law that says
software
code can be copyrighted okay so anyway
in 1985 Richard strowman created GL emx
first release and borrowed code from
gosine emac removed the mark lisp which
is not real lisp and Richard sowman
created the real lisp emac lisp so he
coded everything yeah so you know it's
actual lisp from the ground of kunu emx
okay you know okay so that's basically
it so then then you know the the Gosling
emx got sold to UNI press and uni
press tell Richard stman to stop you
know stop giving out giving out our
software
free
because you know you know back then
copyright is kind of still fuzzy but you
know
so but Richard s is into the you know
the the software Freedom thing so so
rich San just removed all the code from
Gosling Emax okay so anyway that's the
outline of the
history so in the end you know if we say
can we say you know Richard stowman
created emx yeah I think it's reasonable
okay reasonable you know if you want the
whole history then you have to mention
all these people you know in the
beginning there's TECO you know there's
t-x T you know and then and then gos and
you know but if you want to just say who
created emx it's reasonable I believe
that Richard strowman did because he did
two major things one is he first merged
you know he became the main coder merged
all the Techo keyboard markers into one
coherent hole that's one thing the
second thing is after you know so after
four years or five years he he kind of
created emac from the ground up you know
you know he borrowed Gosling emx then
removed his code you know and and so in
both cases his project became very
popular you know so I think it's
reasonable if he claim you know he
created emac okay of course there are uh
significant uh contribution from all the
other people
okay okay so many so many chat uh so
that's about emac history so again you
can read my uh kind of what I wrote uh
my
articles now let's so next topic I want
to code some
JavaScript uh let's
[Music]
see okay so let let it be short today I
want to code some JavaScript or maybe
not uh let me see what's the
question stream today look fancy yeah
because I have red light on you see now
you see I have you know if I turn off my
I have one bright light over there over
there if I turn that off it's going to
be all red because red light at night is
very good for your
eye uh okay
so happy hacking
yeah I just got the professional classic
I love it what what do you love about it
why do you you know so happy hacking is
interesting is a code right I claim well
it's kind of a code so one time you know
I asked a guy what do you like about
happy hacking oh this major problems you
know and he replied well so I mean one
of the question I asked okay so there's
no arrow keys there's no you know it's a
code you know because when I say no no
arrow keys then then the happy King fans
will say you are wrong this Arrow you
just have to hold down FN first [ __ ]
idiots obviously when you say there's no
arrow keys of course you mean no
physical arrow keys
but the the the the the code you know
they just you are wrong but because you
can hold FN then there arrows idiotic so
anyway no error no physical error right
so I asked the one of the fan you know
so how what do you do if you're going to
play a game video game right he says
well I have another
keyboard extremely idiotic so in these
people so when they say the love love
Happ hacking they actually mean that
they need two keyboards you know one is
for you know coding or whatever then if
you want to play game you have to use
another keyboard extreme idiotic I don't
understand no physical arrow keys what
you going to do when you play games oh
oh I I in that case I use a different
keyboard [ __ ]
idiots uh you know so yeah
so okay you love the layout so Eric s
Raymond why are we mentioning him Oliva
hello the Kiwi
guy oh yeah so happy hacking yeah so you
know in in the back of happy hacking
they have dip
switches which is kind of Asian kind of
thing that allows you to oh allows you
to switch back to back um to the delete
to backward space oh okay yeah that's
right cheers this is a red wine with
orange
juice I think we not going to code
JavaScript because you know uh you know
since we are just talking more popular
stuff because if we code then it's going
to be technical uh which is uh different
audience
so there's a question have you
seen chario bits from the B keyboard no
what is
that so let's
see bastard
keyboard it's a name that is
not you know in the polite societies so
this is kind of a nerd website bastard
keyboard that's their company name or
something oh okay yeah it's fun I
suppose yeah I've seen that before it's
I suppose it's fun you know so there are
so many so many today
so yeah so they you know they don't have
much Keys you know they they
yeah I mean okay it's useful
you know so one of the issue about this
keyboard where they are like 60% or
50% is that of course I don't like it
okay I think all these
40% 50% are
crap okay
crap but
however now because I've been using the
kesis advantage key keyboard which do
not have the function keys it's got 70
Keys something okay so I started to get
used to no function keys no physical
function keys and what happens is that I
realized you just get a keypad you know
like like those people who like happy
hacking oh but you need another keyboard
so so when you buy a keyboard F first of
all depends on how much money you have
right you know there's 100 to 400 to
500 for example glove 80 is about 350 or
400 you know fantastic and happy hacking
I mean the ultimate hacking keyboard too
is like close to 300 250 or something so
anyway the point my point is here is
this when you buy a keyboard when you
shop for a keyboard like you decide
which one you're going to want you know
there are so many choices right so the
there's one question you're going to
just get one keyboard that's it or you
can allow to have some
peripheral okay so if you don't mind to
have a
peripheral then you could it's it's kind
of optimal to get one of these 30% or
40% or 50% then what you do is you get a
um you get a keypad programmable keypad
so I have several for example examples
so you buy one of these that'll give you
all function keys or arror keys or
number pad
keys so get you know so for example
that's what I do so I have gl8 here gl8
has lots of keys like 70 or 80 it's got
function keys but then I have the
ultimate hacking keyboard as a Marco
keypad which is 70 keys by itself so I
got 70 keyboard Mar so that's
great but for you guys you know you
don't want to spend so much money so you
can buy a keypad so you get two
keyboards one is like 40% 50% or
whatever of your choice then you have
extra keyboard okay for for the
um is it programable keyboard okay so
there are several choices
uh yeah [ __ ] where did it
go
so keypad okay so there are several
choices you know you know depending on
whether you use Photoshop or whatever
this Elgato stream deck which is very
popular don't buy it it sucks it's
like I mean it's not I wouldn't I
wouldn't buy it it looks good you know
it looks fancy because it has display
but uh I rather go with some of the
other choices okay that's about
that green blood is a correct spelling
Okay it definitely is a code but uh
topper is great okay I'm okay without
the physical error keys okay but the
layout is mainly why mainly why I love
it looks great okay why why so what you
going to do when you play video
games that's a question okay so I guess
you play um yeah I guess you can you can
use the you know W
SD yeah
well okay so maybe that's it for today
40 minutes is is there anything else
hello George you late we we we close
shop
now George you want to talk about
politics about 4D
chess that's that's your thing where's
my drink okay I think that's it for
today uh politics well it's pretty sad
you know the world what's going on in
the world there's this Ukraine war
there's a war in
Israel and today with
Iran
uh okay WD key have you tried the
consult package for emac
no uh haven't you watched enough of my
videos like today I don't use any other
people's package basically why because
I've been coding emac this for about 20
years so it's more efficient if I just
code whatever I need instead of in
instead of looking into what other
packages I need there are documentation
you know so have I used consult no I
don't know what you know and also the
other thing is I'm getting old I'm 55
okay so when
you most people you know you know most
program rammers when they are 40 they
don't talk about programming anymore you
know if you are a good programmer by the
time you are 40 you are the CEO of
something you know you you busy you too
busy to talk about coding not like me
I'm kind of the nerd so and also also
you know I'm I'm 40 years old you know I
I mean I mean I'm I'm getting old so I
haven't been paying attention to what
other packages like what's the heart
this package out
there you know I don't I don't use it I
don't so but you can use you can buy my
package okay so here is my
packages uh you know so let's delete the
backup you know all single key press can
see on the pink window so all this my
packages that's basically all I
use so let me show you my
Alpa uh
doxd Alpa so let me show you what I have
in none okay Al feed aled so the only
package I have installed other people's
is Al feed which which lets you read we
uh it's a Blog
agregator RSS you know web feed
aggregator so let's you read blocks but
I haven't I haven't used it for for you
know I don't I don't read other people
blogs not not not really I just read you
know if there's article I go read it I
don't follow blocks and I don't these
days I don't even read any other
programmers block like I talked about on
Twitter I only follow
politics I don't follow memes or any
other programmers opinion or any AI
opinion most most of the opinion on AI
you know artificial intelligence whether
they gonna take over they are [ __ ] they
are like idiotic
brandist you know like they they are
grifters grifters or like they they they
became popular because all the the
masses they don't know things I talked
about AI multiple
times okay that's I think that's it aled
is good yeah aled is very good and Chris
willan is one of the one of the coder
emac L coder in the emac L Community I
highly respect there are
few uh so he goes by the name new
program Christan Chris Wellens so I
highly respect he's a great coder not
just imagist but also C and stuff but
his style I mean he's his his his style
and you know his preferences in code is
not is different from mine okay he's I
would say the more classic typical
hacker type so he's into C
C++ memory memory dling how do you did
memory bits bits did bits how do you
play how do you program games you know
what does GPU do GPU you know that's
what that's he thing I'm not interested
in those things I'm interested in
mathematics group Theory type Theory
logic proof systems you know uh
visualization of
geometry you know he like you know so
it's different so okay so and the
programming languag is I'm interested
is application languages I'm not
interesting interested in bit ding see
memory compile crap okay so so but he is
more classic I mean the his interest you
know is more kind of what I call
industrial programmers so these are
industrial programmers these are not
Engineers not scientific programmers not
phys physics physicist not chemist you
know they are not scientists they they
they they are industrial programmers
they so most is centered around C C++
Java or business you know that type
so so our opinion will be differ on
things for for example I remember one
time we I asked him a question about
there's a change in emac about let me
show you
okay so for example you can you can
actually see it here so wait you see
there lexical B binding okay you see
that
declaration that's that that declaration
Mexico B binding came out about 10 years
ago about uh maybe
2010 okay that's new in emac disp so
with that declaration as a common
because you know it's kind of a hack to
fix it so with that common emac this
will have lexical binding so all the let
uh for example all the let uh you know
it becomes lexical binding if you don't
have that at the top then it's it's a
dynamic uh binding okay so what's a
difference you know again so this is
like
technical computer language details it's
one of the thing that this type of
people C C++ memory didas they love they
and garbage collection so-call you know
this jargon garbage collection or no
garbage collection how do you do garbage
collection Which Way rust these idiots
industrial program they are they love
they are obsessed about this thing okay
so anyway so the the the dynamic you
know scoping versus lexical scoping okay
so emac lisp created this hack to to to
have lexical
scope let let me tell you something
interesting okay from my perspective so
what is the difference okay that's a
common question right well you can look
up these people's writing for example go
to Wikipedia they'll tell you what's a
difference between lexical scoping
versus Dynamic scoping okay I can tell
you simply Dynamic scoping is the
brainless one it's the one you know
that's the most natural easy to code
like the whole story of C and C
philosophy whatever comes easiest you
just do it that's dynamic damic scoping
and what does it mean it means time
based okay so when you have a variable
it has a value then you have the same
variable if if the same variable occurs
again but at the later time that
variable's value takes over the previous
Sim variable names value time based okay
which is the easiest to to to implement
okay which is the beginning 10 or 20 or
30 years of programming languages okay
that's a dynamic
scope lexical binding lexic scope is I
think first created by scheme disp which
is what I say what I call what you see
is what you get okay so let's
see so you see you see this let block so
you see it let this let block which goes
from here to you know quite long Okay so
let's shrink it a little bit so you can
see the
hole okay so anyway it's quite long so
you can see it declares variables so
what does it mean lexicos scoping that
means what you see is what you get that
means this this this variable feeds
buffer is only valid within this block
of code
okay not anything not anywhere outside
of it what you see is what you get okay
lexical scoping which is more natural to
hum humans okay and which is actually
better okay so but what is the
difference let me tell you this
interesting thing the difference is that
there's no difference okay if you always
write your function in a functional
programming style always you function
don't have side effects okay you can
there's no difference between them no
difference do you guys understand okay
I'm talking to this C type of C++ type
of idiots there's no difference between
them so why why why these people makes a
deal of it big deal of it Dynamic
scoping versus lexical because this type
of people C C++ this type of industrial
program as
idiots they they they don't program in a
functional style they they Cod always
have like Global variables or spaghetti
code you know they they don't they don't
buy the functional programming stuff
that's why
okay I hope that's a interesting
dramatic take which is which is also
correct by the way
the question from type three
error what what error is type three
error oh that's interesting I don't I
don't recall what what kind of error is
type three
error have you ever do math in emac list
instead of
Mathematica I thought about it you
cannot you can there's no
comparison you know in EAC this you can
do you don't have to compare to mathem
you just compare emac this
to actually okay let me let me let me
try to just directly say so EAC this if
you're going to write some scientific
program you know doing some code in
scientific programming or engineer
involving a lots of
math let's not even mention solving
equation so integral so
matrices okay so um so if you want to do
any kind of math
lisp is not suitable okay you it's it's
much easier and better if you do it in
JavaScript in Python in Ruby okay in in
in in fact you need a you you kind of
need a specialized language like Matt
lab or you know if you're going to do
heavy mathematics okay so this is like
out of question if you really into doing
math for engineering and physics and
math you need a specialized math
language
okay so you know you don't even compare
to Mathematica you just you can compare
to even JavaScript or python both of
let's not say python because python do
have lots of math libraries today since
like 10 years ago because of the AI
because Google but let's say Ruby or
JavaScript they be they both beats iMac
disp if you want to do anything math
just simple math let's say linear
algebra matrices you know they beat they
beat imagist by far so what do you mean
beat well because it means much easier
much much easier to do
okay uh have you tried Maxima you know
that's one of the frequently Asked
question from the open source
phonetics Maxima Maxima is the Asian is
a
it's h ma Maxima I can tell you some
story about it okay Maxima is what
Stephan wolam used about 40 30 years ago
stepan wolam the guy who created
Mathematica he's the master of Maxima
because that you know he used it all day
he used it so much that that it it his
need went beyond what Maxima can do okay
so then he created his wolam language
his own version okay kind of that's a
history okay you can go to my website so
I have a lot so let me talk about that
okay that's about it uh three more
minutes okay because it's 1 hour
today so you just search for lisp and
wolan so you can
see uh lisp versus wam language you can
see you know I have a lot of article for
example this one this and AP are root in
WF Mathematica so you can see historical
documents that documents how wam
language are
basically similar to them you know this
is wolam stepan Wolf's own uh writing
you know documents about thisp you know
he he talk he's talking about lisp how
is it different from Mathematica or or
similar you know then there's APL he's
talking about it and then you know I
have also um my own article this versus
wam
language you know I talked about this a
few times if you guys have watched my
past video so you know everything in
this there a basically
uh analogous in wolam language
everything syntax symbols how you call
functions how you write them you know
program n PR n is same to compound
expression in language everything atoms
arithmetics you know head of the sex you
know everything um Bine so w language
okay so Maxima is Maxima was a
commercial uh package it's written in
lisp it's so-called um computer algebra
system so it's a software to do
mathematics solve equation
uh multiply matrices you know do
derivatives integrals okay very old
then you know one one of the leader is
uh F Richard Rich uh Richard fadan okay
so that's
another uh okay so let let me let me go
through that let me show you so go to
cinfo then go to search
then go to RSI
emx uh or emac pinky emx Pinky Okay how
to avoid emx pinky
no
uh famous programmers with repetitive
repetitive strain injury okay so there's
article famous programmers who got hand
pen including Richard strowman uh includ
ining jimy zinski very bad you know that
Netscape guy XX guy very bad and uh Ben
Wing very very bad
he he his hand got [ __ ] up so he quit
coding entirely for like like 10 or 20
years he basically stopped ended his
career okay bang
win uh John ort who created the TCL
language he's not a Max user he's a Vim
user VI but he also got [ __ ] he
became a [ __ ] anyway so he started to
use voice coding you know and then I
asked the question and Richard fedman
okay Richard fman is I believe the lead
for for some time the lead Cod of Maxima
okay this
guy we we talked we we you know we
exchanged a little bit uh like in the
1990s he's a big critic of Wolf's
Mathematica okay he's a big
critic uh so you know I'm getting old
they getting old he's
so yeah Rich you know Richard fedman
he's at UC Berkeley he's so he's also
one of the big
lisp you know coders
um oh yeah so he's wait I got confused
he's he worked on Maxima I think max
Maxima later become Maxima
yeah you know so I don't know what's the
story but basically
they they you you know they run out of
money or you know bankrupt or whatever
then they release their code and it
become Maxima okay so the all the open
source phonetics they don't know nothing
I don't mean you but a lot of it you
know because I this a frequently Asked
question what do you think about Maxima
why do they ask that because Maxima is
free you don't have to pay nothing and
open
source if you want to compare to WF
language it's like no comparison like
it's like [ __ ]
okay if you are a student who
occasionally you know want to do some
matrices or do a integral yeah Maxim is
great if you really if that's your
career if that's your job solving
Mathematics Two equations physics
engineering no
okay okay that's it today thank you guys
for watching pay me if you like my stuff
pay okay because money is what actually
makes all these things go around all the
history you know the all you know it's
Sil but I realize that I mean it's silly
to say but all this history you know
which language became popular why and
how it basically all came back to money
money that propeled people money comes
in many ways okay you can be us you know
it's basically money okay some of them
are like secret like lots of things
going on in politics why do we have War
why do we have war in Ukraine in is
Israel money money is talking doing all
the things behind okay why am I um doing
live
stream money well actually I get some
domination from wolam research okay
money okay so why why do you so many
people like like are Fanatics of Open
Source have you used Max have you tried
this Sage math you know all the open
source fans why don't you stop talking
about wolfan [ __ ] it's a it's a it's
a it's a proprietary [ __ ] why don't you
talk about iMac this common this money
why because this this communist idea you
know is free you don't have to pay but
then then you have a vision like you are
doing good for
Humanity you know that Vision today is
splitting you know it's getting USA USA
is
collapsing because of the social Justice
Warriors the equity you know which has a
lot to do with the open source how it
began and and and in the past few days
we have the open source
hyperland you know controversy you know
anyway good night guys okay so if you
want to pay me just go to just go to
PayPal okay PayPal is my favorite thing
Amazon gift card PayPal or uh
patreon a.info thank you guys bye guys