Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of the C Talk
Show.
Today is August 26th,
12:00 in the afternoon, 9 minutes after
San Francisco time, and today is Monday.
Oh,
dreary Monday.
It's dreary Monday to you guys, not to
me,
because every day is Sunday for me.
So,
so today's topic, let's see.
I'm thinking let's do Emacs then. I
mean, today we do Emac Emacs or Emacs
Lisp, because yesterday
uh someone, who was it? Seamus or
someone, suggested we do Emac Lisp.
And but
then we digressed into the story of GNU
Guile,
a brave
GNU world.
Bartholomew, good morning.
Seamus Slack.
Okay, do I look good?
I have to prettify.
You know, this you know, when when you
do broadcasting, you have to make up.
You know, even some YouTubers, they do
make up. They they, you know, they have
to pretty themselves, you know, for the
presentation. That's a public relations.
All important public relations.
Um
so that is, you know, this is my
schedule, but it's actually not set
um yet. I haven't published it yet.
And okay, so let's let me read the
comments and let's see what we going to
talk about. So, type the topic, okay?
Type a topic,
and let's see.
So, let me read the comments. You know,
I thought I wasn't I didn't schedule,
but actually I did yesterday, so
uh
I was late.
So, Seamus Seamus Slack says,
"About Emacs does not have syntax parser
and the PyCharm does. Couldn't you just
have the Emacs syntax highlighting
remember the word from the var and add
it to the list of
add it uh
add it a list to No, you cannot um add
it
a list to set the color. No, uh you
cannot do that because
Okay, so we were talking about Let's
show some code, okay? Let's go to um
Let me show you what
uh I mean, okay? So, let's go to uh
this. Let's go to
uh TypeScript, okay? This is
This is
and let's see, go to the bottom of the
buffer
and let's start start command log.
So, on the left window, you see all my
Emacs commands, okay? If you see what
I'm doing and you don't know what it is,
just look up the
the name, such as go to the beginning of
buffer, go to the end of buffer,
backward word, forward word, up arrow
keys, and so on.
So, this is a This is a TypeScript file,
which is 500 lines. Now, this file draw
draw draw SVG
graphics.
Math plot, like sine, cosine, and the
parametric plot, and so on.
And yeah, so we were talking about
syntax coloring. So, I Yesterday we we
we talked about how Emacs
the syntax coloring mechanism is based
based on regular expression.
Essentially, the hardware is that you
write a lot of regular expressions. You
know, you you tell Emacs when you see
this if this regular expression matches,
color this way. If that regular
expression matches, color it as a
constant name, things like that.
Uh
you know, regular expression-based
syntax coloring. And this is in fact I
would say I think vast majority of
editors
or let's say editors, you know, all
editors before let's say 2010
or you know, it's like that. Because
this is the
uh
this is uh easy way to do it.
So, anyway, so but there are problems
with this regular expression approach
because
one thing we mentioned is that uh
suppose I have a function. Let's see
let's see if we can find a function.
Okay, so here is a function.
Now, this block of code is a function.
Uh let let let me let me check out the
um
comments a little bit. So, let me finish
this topic, okay? Let's just start with
this topic. So, this is a function.
And this is a arrow function. So, you
can see
you you can see this is a function, the
whole definition of a function. We
assign to a variable constant.
Function SVG Y labels, okay? It creates
labels for the Y axis. That's what this
function do.
And so, this is a function. And this is
the parameters. You have several
parameters. Then you have this
uh
arrow. This is arrow function. The the
function body is here.
Now, in the function body, you can see
you can see we have a constant n. So, n
is a variable.
So, typically
you know, let's switch let's switch to
Emacs JavaScript mode. Right now I'm in
JavaScript TypeScript mode. Okay, let's
switch to
JS mode. Okay, JS mode, JavaScript mode.
So, this is Emacs JavaScript mode.
The default.
So, you see it colors n.
Um it colors n here.
But, it does not color Let's Let's Let's
find n.
Uh let's see where is it.
Uh
Where else is n defined?
Uh let let's I don't know where where is
n, but let's look at this one. This
defines a variable SVG texts. Okay. It's
a array. So, it it you see it's colored.
It's colored because using regular
expression you can you can say that
whenever you see a the word constant,
you know, then the next word is going to
be a variable
name.
Therefore, you can color it as a
variable.
But, however, let's search that. You see
So, however, you see that variable also
appears here, but it's not colored. It's
not because there's no way
for Emacs or any regular expression
based coloring syntax coloring system to
know to be sure that this is actually a
variable.
Uh you cannot do that, you know, so it's
not colored there. And uh
But, so the question is why can't Emacs
just, you know, once you see this, it
will just make a list like remember,
okay, this is a variable. Then, when you
see it, you color it as a variable.
You uh that won't work. It won't work,
you know, lots of time it will it will
just
be wrong because, you know, computer
languages
you really have to understand. For
example, let's see for ex-
um
It won't work because
Uh how do how do I explain? But
because the
because it's not
You see,
the way we think it's going to work
because
because whenever you see this, you know,
it's a variable. Then, what do you do is
that within this bracket, you know,
within this
curly bracket, that's the scope of the
variable. Then, you just color
everything of that word.
But that
that won't work because
because for example, in JavaScript, you
have var. You know, you can declare a
variable with var. But the
but the scope of var is not the the
outer curly
uh bracket, not the braces.
Rather, it's it it must be the the
closest outer function.
So, in this case, it's a function. Then,
then the scope of var is
inside here.
But then so that So, now the problem is
you you not only need to find the outer,
you know, nearest curly bra- brackets,
but you also need to be sure this
bracket is actually uh a function, you
know, part of a function.
This is just an example. It gets
complex, you know, because the scope of
a
a variable also
uh there are other issues. They are um
For example, what what if this variable
name, you know, this name appears in a
string uh in a string or in a regular
expression.
Uh, and uh
And what if There are other examples.
Basically, the the problem is that you
are treating this language as a textual
uh
uh uh uh as a formal language, as a
textual language. But actually, the
meaning
for vast majority of programming
languages, the meaning of a variable,
the semantics of a variable, how, you
know, its scope and where, you know, it
the semantics is actually
not textual. I mean, meaning that you
cannot
find the exact scope of a variable or
function by just looking at the text.
You actually, you know, by by just
passing the text, you cannot do that.
You actually have to
uh kind of you you you have to know the
semantics of the language. Something
like that, okay? I'm I'm probably
This is probably not the best
explanation, but something like that.
And also, it's Yeah, any anyway.
So, that was That's That was one
question. So, so let me read the
comments and keep the comments coming.
Okay, so let's see.
Uh so, yeah. So, does does that Yeah, so
I guess does that make sense? Seamus.
Uh greetings, everyone. Bartholomew. Z
Tron Crazy. Good morning. Aris Garcia.
Good morning.
Uh
Random number five. Why Go line is good?
That's simple. That's easy easy to
answer. I I actually talked about this a
few times. Go line, I love Go line. I
think it's a great language. I think you
should learn it. What depends on you,
actually. But for most people, it's a
good language to learn because one, it's
very fast. It's intent um
I Well, I talked about this many times.
Because it's very fast, you know, six
times faster than Python, Perl, Ruby,
PHP, okay? Six like six times on average
or more.
Uh because it's it's it's it's basically
almost the same speed as it is the same
speed as C++. Because Golang is is
designed to be a modern replacement for
C++.
Uh so and that's so the speed is
comparable to C. So you know, actually
for some tasks it's faster than C.
So anyway, so Golang the number one
reason it's fast. Number two, it's
uh not ordered, okay? The second reason
reason is that it's simple. Golang the
semantics the model the language model
is very simple. You can learn it in 1
week. You actually learn and understand
the whole language in 1 week. I mean if
if you are hotshot, you know, you can
say you can you can know the whole thing
in 1 day, okay?
But practically 1 week, yeah, you you
actually know the whole language the
entire how they work the entire you
understand the entire thing in 1 week.
Now, you cannot say that for Haskell.
Haskell
You understand the whole language in 1
year, okay? Uh for Clojure, no, you you
not you know, it's going to half a year
or more.
Um Java, same thing, you know. Python is
simpler. Ruby is simp more Ruby is
simpler, you know, um
but Golang is even simpler than Ruby.
Well, almost
uh
the same very simple, okay? So Golang is
very fast, that's good.
Simple. Simp The whole thing is very
simple.
Uh and it's three, it's statically
typed, okay? It's it has type inference
and it supports supports functional
programming.
Uh a function is a value. You can return
a function can return a function. A
function can also take a function as
argument. So, it supports the practical
any practical functional programming, no
problem.
Now, this is not true for Python, okay?
This is not true for Pearl. Yeah, they
you know, Python and Pearl, they support
functional programming, but actually not
not really.
We are talking about the basic
fundamental support of functional
programming, meaning that you can do
everything in functional style.
Uh
but however, not not like Haskell, you
know, Haskell is you know, as you know,
Haskell is like one level up. Haskell
and there's a lot in practical stuff
like lazy lazy evaluation, you know,
infinite list and the monad monad
and the currying and you know, those
those thing are you know, I guess good
depends on your point of view, but
anyway, they are not that practical.
Okay, so, Golang
is supports functional prac uh practical
functional programming very well.
S- and that's what I do. I I never
in in in my 20 30 years of programming,
I never coded any
uh object-oriented way, never. Well, in
a company, you follow the code, right?
Yeah, some you do follow the code.
But for my own project in 30 years, I
never code anything in OOP style and
never I will never
you know, do OOP style. It's all
function.
So, Golang is fast,
simple to learn, very simple model,
supports functional programming well,
okay? You can be practical with it.
But the most important and
okay, and also greatest documentation in
industry among all languages all man
pages, Apache, whatever technology,
Golang's documentation and the
documentation for the library and also
the documentation for the Go language
spec is the best
written. Okay, trust me on that because
I have a thing about programming
language documentations.
I have a obsession
about programming language
documentations. I I also talked about
this several times.
Okay, let's show Let me show you some of
my Go uh essays.
essays.
Uh let first of all, let's go to talk
show and uh
let's go to talk show and today What is
today? Today is this one. Open it.
Uh no, today. Okay, I don't have it
written today. So,
why Go language?
Because
uh
fast like C++.
Then,
supports
practical functional
programming well, very well. Okay.
Simple.
Can learn
whole in 1 week.
Number four.
Best documentation.
Number five, the most important reason,
number five.
The most important reason.
Go language
is indust-
industry
standard.
Meaning that you can find a job. You
know, if you you know, we all we all all
love the the language of our choice, but
for many of those choices, you will find
no job like Haskell.
Uh you know,
so but Go language, you know, if you
like it, you study it, you you can make
a living. You earn your bread, you know,
you you code in daytime, you go go code
Golang a day,
you get things to eat. At night, you do
Golang for fun,
and that's for uh relaxation.
So, that's Golang.
And this is the most This this reason is
the most important reason.
People don't usually
don't think about
about it, you know, my type of people,
the hackers, you know, the the the
language enthusiasts.
You know, because, you know, for
example, there are many great languages
people like Oh, they say, "Oh, Scheme."
Scheme is the considered, you know,
loved language by
most people throughout 1990s to up to
2010.
For 20 years. But where where is Scheme?
It's
it's tail recursion recursing in some in
some bubble, you know, in in in at Mars.
Mars. You can You can see the Scheme
people on Mars. They are talking about
things. And Haskell, they live they live
on Venus. They live on Venus. They
talking about monad and currying and
stuff. Yeah, they they they are there.
But if you want to make living, you want
to code make a living
do a language you like,
Golang, okay? Golang is it.
Not Java, the crap, and C++ crap. C++
thing C is the worst.
The worst
in the universe.
Okay, so that that is my reason for
Golang, okay? Bartholomew.
Uh is the stream going? Yes, it is going
now. Still waiting, okay. Sauce still
Sauce still is on toilet, I presume.
Giving us those big fart farts, appears.
I gave uh
Iris says I gave a suggestion to start
for today's talk some Python code
the equivalent in Emac list. Okay, um
Python code equivalent in Emac list. I
can we can do that. Um
We can do that, you know, for example,
we can do a simple programming problem
such as let's say um
let's say
print out the first 100 prime numbers. I
tried to do that a few times.
Uh shall we do that? Uh let's see.
Python, okay, let's go back.
So, Iris says that, but let me read the
comments and we'll see what we going to
talk.
Uh
one thought for each Unix ideology rant.
Oh my god, I thought schedule, okay. So,
sorry, 5 minutes. Keep the comments
coming, okay? I'm I'm reaching it.
Uh the Okay, uh
5 minutes preparation time for next Unix
philosophy rant. Plus Richard Stallman.
Uh
so, message is held for review. Don't
swear, okay?
Guys, any
Don't swear.
Uh casual look at this fact Unix
philosophy.
This fact
Why is Google
you know, uh censor that?
Okay, FACK, you know, the the
the nasty that Google and Twitter, you
know, by by by today's generation, the
millennials. Nasty. You know, like like
the you know, that's swearing word.
But typically, you see,
let me explain this. So, you you have
this swearing word, okay, right?
But
but people, you know, good people, you
know, people who you know, not like me,
okay? Good.
Some other people
they are, you know, they they know this
is sensitive, so they are good people,
so they start to write, you know, like
that.
It's
as a, you know, appeasement, you know,
it's like, you know, you want to express
something ang- anger or something, but
you understand, you know, it's
controversial, so you use this instead.
And similarly, I guess for, you know,
that alternative spelling, you know, so
it's it's a way to
almost like self-censor, you know.
But meanwhile, you you you know, you
tell people you want to say this word,
but you
you are kind.
But now they censor that, too.
[ __ ] Google, you know, they become
extremely evil and these social justice
people, okay?
Anyway,
Kash's look at
So, our Richard on Perpetual Glue
So, bathroom you says, "If you scratch
the skin of Richard, there is you know,
underneath it." Seema says,
uh
Okay, so,
I'm going to skip over the comments. I'm
not going to read out everything.
Uh now, there there is a emoji. Let's
see what that emoji is.
Magnify.
This is
This is uh
you know, it's it's it's used used to be
called rolling on the floor laughing.
Rolling on the floor.
Uh
Wait, there's an acronym. I forgot. You
know, it's a But anyway, now they have
an emoji, and the emoji is called uh
rolling on the floor laughing, okay? So,
uh
OTFL.
Yeah, right. Yeah.
Okay, so, back to the comments. Full
name actually
saw digress. The Emacs Lisp is always
welcome. Good evening. Okay, let's do
Yeah, let's do Emacs Lisp then. How long
have I been talking?
23 minutes. Okay, that's that's the
preface up to this point. It's preface.
When you read a book, you know, you have
preface.
Star Wars shirt again. Yeah, well, I
take a shower every, you know,
3 days.
You know, I'm not sweating.
But this I don't I don't like this
shirt.
You know, it it says Star Wars, but I
don't like it, you know. I I never wear
I'm a nerd, but I I never wear anything
like this. I don't like it, you know,
that's not me. I'm pure, you know, I'm
just Sali. I'm not [ __ ] Star Wars.
But But my roommate gave me this shirt,
you know, he got bunch of shirts. I just
He just gave it to me, so I just put it
on.
Uh
Star Wars. And especially, you know,
today's Star Wars, that's something
else.
Uh Elisp. Okay, so let's do Elisp then.
Uh Elisp, yeah. Good morning, Deon. We
are doing Emacs Lisp.
After the preface.
Uh Dan says, "Asian Turkish history."
You know, Turkish, they have an
interesting keyboard layout, though.
I have a story on Turkish keyboard
layout because
uh Turkish, they, you know, every
keyboard layout, typically, they are
created by one guy.
Well, well, actually, if if you look at
the international keyboard layouts,
okay, they are all
uh idiotic, okay? They are all QWERTY,
basically, all around the world are
QWERTY or AZERTY or
um
let's see. In internet QWERTY
QWERTY or QWERTZ, QWERTZ, okay, or
AZERTY.
AZERTY and QWERTZ are variations of a
QWERTY. They basically just swap two
pairs of keys. Well, like four keys,
they just swap them. And for no good
reason. After you swap, I I I've studied
them, you know, for
for for example, German, you know,
correct me I'm wrong, okay? If you
battle me or those you are in German or
whatever countries
I'm talking about.
So, anyway, so in Germany and this, you
know, your European countries, some some
of these countries use QWERTZ, QWERTZ,
Z, or AZERTY. Basically, they swap like
three pairs of, you know, characters
like these, A Q Z W M with comma.
Okay, and that's AZERTY. And for QWERTY,
I mean for QWERTZ, Z,
you swap Z and Y.
And I I look at them, it's actually
stupid, you know, I look for example,
QWERTZ is used in well, in in German and
Central Europe, okay? So, I looked at
German, you know,
frequency of characters, you know, it's
no good. You swap them,
as far as I know,
it's it's it's not really better, it's
almost
you know, it's not really better at all.
Same thing with AZERTY. So, anyway, what
I'm saying is that for international
keyboard layout, typically they are you
know, QWERTY or QWERTZ, or AZERTY, and
they are not ergonomic in in any way.
They just
I haven't, you know, one one thing
interesting is the history.
How did this happen, you know, the
history of
QWERTZ and the history of AZERTY. I
never
you You you have to look, you have to do
research. It's not
It's not on Wikipedia
the last time I checked.
You have to, you know, you have to
research for that. So, that that I never
have I don't have the answer for that. I
like to know if you know.
The history, like who actually, you
know, created aserty. Who Who the [ __ ]
created, you know, QWERTY? Yeah, I like
to know. They They They are the the bad
guys in in society, okay?
How How did they become Anyway.
So, I was saying in the in the most
world, they you you know, you just have
these you use these or variations.
And they are not ergonomic in any way.
And uh
However, there is one exception. That is
Turkish
layout.
Uh
Uh yeah, I don't have a Turkish layout
on my website. You can go to Wikipedia,
but Turkish layout is designed by a
committee.
Uh
with a focus on the Turkish language.
You know, so that is that that is
different. That's a different one. You
know, that's one standing out. Of
course, a lot programmers have created
their own, like, you know,
you know, lots of
Well, Dvorak is famous
not by program programmers, but a lot
programmers created these all these
variations. Colemak,
asset, and Neo, and Norman, and you
know, for German language, Neo, and
for Portuguese, too. Um
Anyway, the
I'm talking about the official country
countries, you know, layout. So, Turkish
one is one that stands out
because it's actually designed. It's in,
you know, it's not just uh swap a few
letters from QWERTY. It's actually
entirely designed
for Turkish language.
And by the way, the those idiotic layout
that applies to China, Japan, Russia,
too. Because
if you can look at Russia layout, it's
What is Russia layout? It's It's and
French, too. Completely inefficient. It
is worse than QWERTY.
What's Russian layout?
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Russian doesn't use English, but
yeah, but it's pretty bad. You know,
here's a heat map.
Um
And and also Japan, you know, what the
most popular layout in Japan is QWERTY.
They
I mean, exactly just like the US
American keyboards.
Uh
for inputting Japanese and very
extremely inefficient. And similarly,
you can say that for China.
Well, mostly you see, this happens most
things happens in society.
From my experience looking at all these
things, most the way they happen is just
that
um
you know, it's almost never It's never
the case. It's like someone some
inventor or something, you know, they
sit down and and think they had you
know, they're going to solve this
problem and they created some design and
and there it is. No, that's almost never
the case. It just uh
It just almost happened by happenstance.
Just by you know,
almost accidental and you know, it just
came up.
Uh
for example, that's kind of the story of
QWERTY and that's also the story of
Emacs key binding. That is also the case
for the Vim VI key, you know, the VI
model. Anyway, I talked about that
before. You You I'm not going to talk
about that.
So, today we I hope
we have 30 minutes to do Emac list and
uh okay, let me okay, so
It's what I fish out what you like to
believe. So, I
last I truly see in the for loop.
Uh
Oh god, you know, I'm not now I I need
to think about are we going to still do
Emac list because if I continue on
then the answer would be no.
Uh
because otherwise I need to start now
Emac list and maybe some Python.
Uh
I don't know what
Deon asked me this thing.
Uh why can't you keep a past three
memory? I I
don't know the details actually. You
know, the the syntax curling I learned
from Stevie X. Steve Steve X, you know,
as you know, he's very famous. He uh
it's it's
You need a parser and the parser is not
different is is different from you know,
the typical parser for
for for compiling a language. You need
a parser that's kind of for the syntax
curling. And I don't know the technical
details. So, I I'm planning to write a
parser, but
but now I'm doing start talk show.
You know,
um
Okay, well, Deon, you know, you go go
write one.
So, keep the comments, okay? That
I don't that's bad, you know, I should
do Emacs this now, but it's kind of
late.
Uh
We can associate your variables to what
on this level stack. Sorry, that makes
sense.
Uh okay, great.
Seamus, okay. Am I missing something?
You learn it in one week of non-coder.
Uh this this is a simplest is all lambda
calculus.
Uh
Sorry, if I offend anyone, but
uh
one of the worst language, Python, okay.
Um
You are offending a mass of people. You
know, you're going to be the enemy of
the people because Python is one of the
most popular language now.
Um
Python is a language that has worked
least for me.
Uh
Oh, yeah, so you you you okay, so you
code Python. Okay, great.
I don't know what have you used it for.
Uh okay, try it for Python is great. Uh
So,
All right, again, it's Richard heretics.
Uh
So, running apps written in Go
very exciting. I think it's the same
like my system breaks at least once a
month.
Python, I don't like Python. Yeah, I
don't like Python because
Well, actually, I I did a a video on
Python I on Guido van Rossum for 1 hour.
Must be 3 months ago or 4 months ago.
Uh address every application. Python is
used for
What about OpenStack, for example?
What is OpenStack? I've you know, I've
forgot. OpenS- Okay, let's magnify.
OpenStack is a free and open source
software platform for cloud computing.
Oh, cloud computing.
Whereby virtual servers and other
resources are made available to
consumers.
Uh whatever. Well, you you know, cloud
computing, the reason
part of the the part of the reason we
have cloud computing is because open
source.
Because when you have open ideology,
companies, they cannot, you know,
they have to embrace it because, you
know, that's the ideology. Otherwise,
people going to punch you.
Therefore, company went to the cloud
because, you know, well, open source,
they cannot make money, they cannot make
money, they cannot survive. Then, no
company. Therefore,
what can they do? Oh, let's do cloud.
It's a service. So, we, you know, we
It's a workaround around the open source
bug. So, now we can make money. And
let's say we help We help you humanity
advance by creating a cloud so you can,
you know, sync all your devices in one
place. That's, uh you know,
and all your photos,
in bed or outside of bed, we going to
keep it on our server.
Uh and we are going to help humanity.
You know, we can analyze the photo and
create report and help us understand
humanity. Cloud. That's right.
Thank you. Thank you so much, open
source.
What is Python for? Understand what you
are trying it uh coming back uh
Okay, so what
Let's let's see um
What is Python for? So, let's keep the
comments.
Open stack
uh
What is Python good for? Understanding
what you are trying to do coming back.
Oh god, so many comments. So So, what?
Today is just um
comment sessions, I guess.
Nobody mentioned this yet.
I mean, I don't
um
So, Bartholomew says, "Yeah, I didn't
try it myself, but Julia." I like I
think I like Julia. I just don't have
time to study yet to study it yet. But
however, the problem is, you know, like
I mentioned before, the problem is, you
know, suppose I spend time to learn
Julia, you know, there's no Julia is one
of the niche. It's great language, but
niche. Nobody use it.
You know.
And it's unfortunate, you know, nobody
uses it. You cannot find a job um
uh
you know, so you going to
Okay. Uh the first time I had touched
Python 3, I was shocked. It didn't did
not have case.
uh
functional function function
Julia rocks. Oh, Nick, is that you Nick
on the Twitter?
Is that you the Nick on Twitter?
Cuz Nick's has been telling me about
Julia all the time.
You know, I like to learn it, but today,
you know, there are so many things, you
know, it's not like
you have free time, you know. What about
math? That's a black hole. There's so
many things I really you know, I love
Math is a thing. Math is permanent, you
know, not like programming languages,
you know, here and there.
You know, you know, proof theory. Well,
of course, many of you are into category
theory from the Haskell, you know,
Haskell pop. Okay, yeah, Haskell you are
Haskell category theory, but I mean to
proof theory and math foundations. And
that, you know, I can spend 10 years and
not still not, you know, understand
that, you know.
Well, I mean, after you spend few years,
you you would have a good foundation.
You understand. But, you know, then math
then I need I need to get start to
actually start to write a parser, you
know.
Uh, then, you know,
you know, so Julia is great, but, you
know, so many so many languages today.
Uh,
I don't have time.
So, I know the feeling you end up with
lots of uh,
uh, trees.
It's a dictionary. Okay, so you guys are
chatting hash table.
Calling a spade a spade.
Uh,
I mean, easier hash table. You know,
hash table was known as hash table.
Then, in Python it becomes dictionary.
Ruby calls it hash table.
In Java, it calls it map.
And in JavaScript, it also calls map.
Well, JavaScript object is actually you
can say it's a hash table, but now since
ES 2015 they have a proper hash table
called map. So, anyway, so you see, I'm
interested in these kind of things,
terminology, because then you started to
look into etymology of hash table, you
know.
Why is it called hash table, you know,
etymology? And which one is more which
one is a better term? Is it hash hash
table or is it dictionary or is it map,
you know?
You I I need I need to find the answer,
you know? This is I I need to obsess
over this
this this critical matter.
Uh
and you know, hash table hash and
you know, hash table the reason it's
hash table is called hash table because
of the word hash function
from the
from the terminology of hash function.
And why is hash function or hash
function? Well, hash function is first
of all, hash function is a function that
takes
takes uh some string and returns a
usually a shorter much shorter a very
short string
that is unique.
Okay, that's hash function. But why is
it called hash?
Uh is it it's because I forgot actually.
What does anyone know? Why is it hash
function called hash?
I forgot. I think it's uh well,
etymology. So, let's go to
Kess Wordy English blog. Show in
browser. This is my Wordy English blog.
From the haughty emotions of lexicon,
stylistic concerns, decipherment of
grammar and idioms, linguistic-ality,
literature, and logicality.
And now we going to create a new entry
and hash and call
etymology. Kess Word etymology linkify.
Show in browser.
Etymology of hash. Now, click.
Magnify magnify hash 1650
to hack chop into small pieces. That is
it.
Yeah, so in America in America you have
the breakfast called hash browns.
That is what it means. To hack to hack
chop into small pieces.
Uh so 1650 uh from French hatcher chop
up, okay. From Old French
hatch axe, okay. So yeah hatchet. Okay.
Hash browns 1926 is a short for hashed
brown potatoes. Oh, hash browns hashed
brown potatoes 1886.
Okay, so anyway
that is the origin of hash function.
I I you know, I suppose I'm pretty sure
after you read this. So yeah. So that is
why uh you know, a list of key value
pairs is called hash table.
You know, first of all well, first of
all you have hash functions. So what why
is hash table called hash table?
Hash hash table is just a list of uh
of of pairs. Key value pairs, okay. But
why is it called hash table? Because
in order to implement that
Okay, this gets into some algorithms. In
order to implement hash you know, list
of pairs
you have to use the hash table a hash
function
to create the the keys.
So you So when when we have a list of
the key value pairs, you have a key.
You use the hash function.
The key is the input to the function. It
comes comes out something memory address
or something. Okay.
So
what So So why why you do that? So so
that when you look up any key
the computer can easily
can can find the the value of that key
in constant time.
Now, exactly how this works I don't
know. Yeah, I don't know the low-level
assembly or C. Maybe some of you guys
know. Explain okay, if you know why
if you have um
If you code in C or assembly, you know,
you know how a hash table is
implemented, you know, maybe you can
explain it. Type it.
But I I actually did did implement a
hash table back in year
year 2001.
This is a story in our e-commerce
system. Okay, let me mention that. In
our e-commerce system, we have on
Solaris operating system.
We have directories. Then we have
subdirectories. Each subdirectory
corresponds to a merchant. Now, this is
a e-commerce system like Yahoo store,
okay? So, you have a website. Merchant
can go there, open a store. So, I have a
store selling keyboards, for example.
Then
buyers can go to my store and buy
things. So, this is a e-commerce system
like Yahoo store. So, for merchants, you
can open a store. Then
uh buyers can go to your store. So, it's
a massive system.
So, a directory in on Solaris, each
directory corresponds to a merchant,
okay?
Then, of course, in in that directory,
then you have, you know,
you have uh
quantities, you have products, you know,
you have uh school number, you know, you
have data like like what keyboards, what
keyboard you have, you know, and how
much you sell, your price, things data
like that. Anyway, the point is that you
have a
you have like
lots of these directories, each one
correspond to a merchant. At one point,
uh our system crashed. Well, I'm not
sure it's it well, it it's error. It's a
crash crash, okay? Because too many
subdirectories, too many. I don't I
don't even remember exactly what's the
number. It's like tens of thousand or
hundreds of thousand. I don't remember
the number, but it's it exceeded the
maximum possible for not this space, but
a
exceeded um the number of directories
you can create.
And of you Unix guys or Linux guys, you
probably probably will say, "Oh, that's
because I not. You exceeded I not."
That's not That's not That's not why,
okay? It's more technical than that.
I don't remember the details, but
actually if you really want to search
it, you can find my name
on you know, this is back in 2001 on
newsgroup. I asked the Solaris newsgroup
about that question. You know, just
search Sadi Solaris
directory maximum
items some something like that on
newsgroup.
I don't remember what's the answer, but
there's there is some
It's not I not. There is some
maximum number of subdirectories. I
forgot exactly what.
You that uh
you cannot exceed that. So so the store
is broken because new merchants cannot
create a new merchant anymore because
when you create a directory the
directory cannot be created because it's
already full. Uh you know,
uh
So
I have to fix it. I'm I'm I'm you know,
I'm the the the hacker of the team.
So I have to you know, I first of all
find out what is the problem
uh
with the you know, that. Then you have
Then eventually I have to create I have
to implement hash
uh table.
Uh basically I need to create
you know, I basically I need to
uh
uh how you say uh partition all these
subdirectories into, you know,
basically create new sub new sub
directories and put the bunch of them
together into that. Then put, you know,
put this subset into this put subsets,
you know, create an
another hierarchy of sub directories.
So, I need to implement a hash table. I
did that.
You found it? Post the link.
Post the link.
Um
So,
So, anyway, that that's what I have to
do. As I I implemented the hash table
back then. I have to learn what is a
hash table back then. I have to um
learn it.
Okay, so
You know, just post it. Just post it.
Stop fussing. Just post the link.
We can see it then if you if it's
censored then now then, you know, uh
you know, like approved or something.
No, I don't see it.
Okay, you got the problems. You got You
got a problem, bathroom mute.
I don't even see in my, you know,
administration.
Yeah, I think Google Google says, "Okay,
you are a bad guy." Google doesn't let
you post stuff.
Wait, do I have some kind of I don't
know. I never
I never banned or anything anyone.
Yeah, I don't know why is that, you
know,
that um
But, you know, you have ways to post a
link like, you know,
separate the words. You can do it.
You know,
if you want to.
Okay, so what are we
uh hash table. So, yeah, we were talking
about hash table. And so, which uh
terminology is the best? You know, I
don't like the word map.
Uh Java and JavaScript use the word map
to mean list of pairs, uh list of
key-value pairs as hash hash table. I
don't like map because map means so many
things, you know, in math it's a map.
Map is a function. It's not a it's not a
lookup table, it's a function. Well, in
in a semantic sense, a function is a you
know, it's a map, but
but usually we you know, we we
you know, they are different meanings
and uh you know, and they are different,
you know.
I mean, from different
perspective, you can you can say a
function is also a
uh you know, it's a map. It's It's
basically just a match map between two
sets. So, you can think of it as a
key-value pairs.
But, however, another perspective is
that a function is kind of a action, you
know, action. You take something in
something output. So, there are
different aspect perspectives. And these
two different perspectives, although in
some sense are the same thing, but
however, they have different functions
in usage, you know.
The ideas are different, okay? So, they
are not the same. I mean, in practice,
they are not the same. You You use
Sometimes you want to use emphasize the
function doing things. Sometimes you
want to emphasize the
what what it is. I mean, it is actually
just a you know, key-value pairs.
So, they have different
uh meanings in in practice. So, I don't
like to use the word map because it also
means function, you know, it's
confusing. And it also it confuses with
the Google Maps, you know, the street
map. That's map. That's That's the word
most people understand, map. It's not a
function. Map is just you go to the
street, you need a map. You know, so I
don't like the word map for hash table.
I
don't Well, dictionary, Python's use of
the word dictionary, that's actually the
most intuitive because anyone who
understand, you know, we understand
what's a dictionary. Then immediately
you understand what's a
what it is, you know, look up table, you
know.
So, dictionary is a good term,
intuitive.
Now, hash table, actually I'm I'm old
school, so I'm used to the word hash
table, but
but technically I don't, you know, yeah,
but if I'm myself, I don't think that's
good. Hash table because hash table,
that term does not actually
mean
the thing because it actually means it
it it it it refers to the implementation
of the thing. You see, hash table refers
to the hash function, the
implementation, how it is implemented.
It doesn't actually directly mean, you
know, list of key-value pairs. So, hash
table is actually stupid term from the
Unix philosophy people, okay? From this
C Unix philosophy Unix people.
Idiotic people. Perl, you know, they
they they love these jar jargons.
The more opaque, the more difficult to
understand, the more they love. They
would just say, "Oh, hash table."
Uh so, hash table is no good. So, it So,
dictionaries, you know, kind of it's
actually probably the best. Um but
actually the best is just say list of
key-value pairs.
I don't like Python. Uh
Uh
Yits.
Okay, I think today is So, today is
another random chat, I guess. I remember
I'm random all so much.
And the the
um
the comments is piling up. I haven't
see it.
Uh what is this?
Uh
forum   tag exclamation
mark topic
show
Let's see if I can show show that.
Hey, good morning Justin. Justin Hayes
Jones.
So forum   tag
Uh mock topic  top
com.unix.
What is this? This is This is on Google
Google newsgroups.
bath bathroom meal
Uh let's just search for xargs Solaris
directory maximum
sub dir
Okay, so let's see if we can find that.
So I've been
digressing a whole bunch and uh so today
we are not doing number of
we are not doing Emacs Lisp then.
Uh
Okay, so you have to go Google
newsgroups. I don't like to
Why is Why is Google starting to like
Oops, did I delete it by mistake? [ __ ]
And so Nick, you posted uh something. Uh
I don't know why Google is uh
you know, uh
censored it. mistake by
I clicked delete by mistake, I think.
Because my mouse has auto click. When I
stop moving, it clicks.
Um
Google Groups
Okay, so if you have a question for me,
address with my name, okay? Then I'll
answer that. Then
Oh, okay, wait. Uh
There are so many hidden chats.
I mean, not hidden, but censored. Okay.
Oh god, so many so many comments.
Uh
Sorry. Solaris
directory
Let's search for that.
Six Solaris questions. Six? No, I didn't
What's the shell online? Okay, that's
that's that's that must be some of my
other old messages.
Six Solaris questions. Thanks to all who
helped.
Uh here's the answer to my question.
Okay, I was asking six Solaris
questions.
You know, oh my god, this is back in
Solaris days. this is year 2000
uh
two.
I was looking at Natopia and uh this is,
you know, Unix
Solaris
crap, you know, you you think Linux is
difficult, you know, the Unix before
it's it's far worse.
But anyway, there's a message for
uh
Solaris Solaris
directory maximum
number, okay.
No not found, uh
subdirectory
God.
Wait, is that part of it?
Okay, so
I'm not sure what to do here now.
Uh
Oh, there it is, show.
Let's try that.
Ah, no result, you know, Google
um
Anyway, let's
let's forget about that, maybe.
So, if you have a question for me, just
put my name, then I'll answer that. I
think maybe we
So, how long have we been talking?
Uh 1 hour, yeah. So, maybe
Yeah, I I we should limit it to 1 hour,
no more, because then
it drags on.
So, dictionary is best because it is a
thing you use to look up something up.
Yeah, so, yeah.
That's the most intuitive name.
Good morning, Justin.
Uh
Read the comments.
Read my comments.
Iris.
Type it again. What
Like
I cannot find where it which comments,
then um
Okay, that that is the
maximum number of directories inside of
the
Yeah, okay. So, that's a thread title.
So, let's
Let's find it for old times' sake.
Yep.
And I don't remember what is the
problem.
So, Xardi says in 2002, April 19th,
"What is the maximum number of
directories one can create under a
directory on our production box on
NetApp with UFS?"
You know, [ __ ] Unix jargons, you
know.
You Linux people get excited.
Oh, oh, UFS.
Net NetApp.
We have a directory that has about
38,000 first level subdirectories.
When this is tarred up and transferred
to my personal dev box Ultra 5, I tried
to untar it, I got an error saying too
many links after about 3 hours of untar.
I wrote a pearl script that creates
directories just to see what is the
maximum, and it turns out to be 32,765.
My disk has sufficient space and I not
I not see below my sig. Can anyone tell
me what is the factor that control the
number of directories one can create
immediate below a given dir?
And whether this file system config
can be dynamically updated or do I have
to create a new file system or if it
this is entirely something else, okay?
Okay, and this part this part part is
called signature. Today, if you are
young, you may not be familiar with
that. You know, like every programmer as
you put, you know, basically your
contact info. Then usually some stupid
quotes.
Uh, okay, so anyway, I have some
uh, show, you know,
Hypatia.
Uh, that's the server that's a machine
name
of my
Solaris box. So, this guy, Darren
Dunham,
so he's obviously a expert.
Uh,
something close to maxlinks three where
sysparam.h
that's that's a C file maxlink.
Each directory has a hard link in all
subdirectories. It's called each
directory has a hard link.
in
all subdirectories. So, eventually you
hit this limit.
Okay. You can't change it without
changing the UFS file system you are
using. That would require a lot of work
and would probably be incompatible with
all other file systems. So, I've never
heard of anyone doing it.
Uh
So, I'm guessing the file system simply
doesn't have Okay, so So, anyway, there
you have the answer. Some technical
esoteric detail.
It's just a magic number, 32,767
max links
in a C header file sys/param.h. [ __ ] C.
Okay.
You know, the [ __ ] [ __ ] the Linux Unix,
you know, every time like if you
mention, "Oh, our system, you know, we
cannot have number of directories." Then
the Linux Linux or Unix people, they'll
say, "Oh, oh, I know it. I know it. You
got to do this. I know it. Look at man
pages. This fuck." They think they know
stuff, you know, they think they they
get excited. They get excited about this
esoteric thing. And uh you know, they
want to tell you and stuff.
You know, back then I'm a I'm a I'm a
[ __ ] Unix master. And I know that
because I read books. I read
just man pages. I read everything, tons
of them.
And uh Solaris, there's a three volumes
Solaris manual, okay? I tried to read
them. I don't remember I did I think I
uh you know,
three volumes Solaris official manual. I
typically I like to read the official
manual. And when Mac OS came out, Mac OS
10,
you know, Mac OS X, also has official,
you know, system mean manuals, you know,
in PDF, back in 2002. I like to read
those. But by the way, back in, you
know, in in
you know, you have Solaris, right? You
know, these Unix boxes costing $40,000,
you know.
Uh and you you want to eject the CD,
okay? Now, how do you eject the CD?
Well, you press the button, right?
Usually on PC, there's a button, you
just press it.
Not so on Unix.
Well, you can you can usually you can
just press it, but that's that's
improper way to do it, okay? That's
improper.
Because then just you know, maybe you
have file accessing it, you know, things
like that. That's improper way to do it.
So, the proper I I I always like to do
things the proper way. And also, you
know, so I I take I go miles to read the
official
you know, usually I go for the official
manual, whatever documentation, to find,
you know,
instructions on how to do things, you
know.
So, I remember I spent hours
trying to find the proper way to eject
the CD. [ __ ] Solaris.
I tried to you know, you have to I don't
remember the all those commands, you
know, on Unix you have this
um
you have this command that tells you
what which process is using what which
file, okay?
Uh Linux website.
And today, you know, people, you know,
the Emacs [ __ ] you know, they look
at my website, they say, "Oh, Xah Lee
Xah Lee is this Windows Windows newbie,
Windows bee, who tries to who tries to
use Emacs."
And the [ __ ] this this fanatic
idiots, they say bad things about me all
the time.
But they don't know stuff. They don't
know this
On Reddit, you can still see it. That's
that you know, that's few weeks ago this
I once once in a while I check it, you
know, people mention my names. Let's
let's do Let's go there.
Reddit Emacs
search for Xah, okay.
Like some idiot, they they want to smear
me because they don't they don't they
don't like me criticizing
Lisp or GNU or Free Software Foundation
or Emacs, right?
You know, that that and that's normal.
Normal people, you know, they they like
to they are in a community, you know,
you don't like other people criticizing
your community.
But let's search for Emacs.
Xah, okay.
Um
Let's see relevance. No, not good not by
relevance. I want I like to search by
new, arrange by new.
People who use packages that introduce
model editing. Some advice for good
Django.
Is there a way to have which keys always
on?
Uh
I don't remember which one, but I read
one because
because now since I'm on I'm here, I can
give you a proper
retort to that guy that whoever idiot.
You know, some sometimes they are not
sometimes they just want to make fun,
you know, they you know, like today's
online life, everyone is anonymous. You
just [ __ ] posting, so-called [ __ ]
posting or whatever.
You know, you just have fun.
Not necessarily, you know, hating me,
but um
but my my reputation reputation get
damaged as a um
side effect.
As
Let's see. Um
because I remember I remember one
uh
What is that side of not um
collateral damage. Yeah, my reputation
gets
is is a collateral damage for their fun
making, for their merry making.
Okay, so so
God, I have this auto click going on.
Every time my mouse moves, it um
Uh not that. It's not like he's uh not
that.
Why Emacs leads sucks? One big rambling
rant. Uh
And not that. Wait, what?
No, not that.
Emacs hands on opening file.
Review provide feedback on state of
Emacs. No.
You know, you know, when it annoys me
like all these people
Anyway, let's not talk about that. Um
So, what is this? It is question.
Um
There it is. There it is. This by this
guy annual.
Let me Let me deconstruct this idiot,
okay?
Okay, so here is someone by Hanja Lee.
Hanja Lee is asking a question.
And uh he's posting one of my code. You
know, he has a question about it.
C- uh user-buffer-q, okay. So, he want
to make you know, he want to extend the
function. So, he wants to know how to do
it.
Uh so, I have this function c- uh c- uh
user-buffer-q means it returns true or
false. It means, you know,
whether the current buffer is a user
buffer. So, what does that mean? In
Emacs,
you have a lot buffers that begin with a
uh comma. I mean, begin with a um
with a um
uh messages, for example, messages. You
see, this messages buffer beg- begin and
ends with a asterisk star.
So, those
buffers beginning with a asterisk, those
are Emacs generated on the fly. So, like
logs, compile logs,
uh messages, you know, completion.
So, those are I what I call Emacs
buffers. Usually, you don't want
to see them. Like, when you go to the
next buffer, previous buffer, you don't
like want you don't want to see them.
Then, the others are user buffers, you
know, like your files and stuff. You you
want to see them. So, you have this
function
c- uh user-buffer-q
that returns true or false, whether it's
user buffer or not. So, that when you
call next buffer, you can you can call
this and and make sure you skip, you
know, this Emacs log and stuff you don't
want to see.
So, he want to extend it to contain
magic. Okay, yeah.
Yeah, magic is nasty magic is um
Well, that's another thing, another day.
Magic is getting annoying. Um
Okay, so then there is this Inigo guy.
He's got seven points.
It says, like everything SA does, that's
some serious weird wear. Try this
on for size.
Let me explain, okay? Let me explain how
idiotic he this guy is. The idiocy of
the Inigo guy.
You know, this is you know, unlike today
we have a society where everyone this is
this anonymous [ __ ] Use your real name,
okay? Say what you mean. Be responsible.
Well, you don't have to do that, okay?
Because it's it's it's a comment today,
but
you know, it's better if if we
you know, um
So, let's look at this guy's code, okay?
So, basically what he he is saying is
that okay,
this smart magnify
okay, shrink a bit.
Uh
Okay, so here here is here here it is.
What is his point? His point is using
or, okay? So, he has this code here. Let
me show you, okay? So, he has this code
here. So, basically we can simplify to
or AB, okay?
He's doing this, or A or B. You know,
it's like if A is not true, then do B.
Uh
do A, okay? Do B. That's the essence of
his code.
Now, I was not writing that. I was doing
What I was doing is this, if
if um
what um
What I I doing is
um
Yeah, okay. This is what I'm doing. If
Oh, wait, wait. Okay, so um
This is not about do, but it's Let me
Let me explain.
Uh
What?
Okay, we are about to finish. Let me
finish. This is getting long and longer.
Um
It's approaching 90 minute 90 minutes
now.
Um but anyway, so so do a um
Let me just go ahead and explain. So,
like normally you will see this
um
Uh you basically using or You you you
are abusing the or operator as a control
structure. That is That is the bit
That's the point, okay? You are abusing
the or control structure
uh or
uh
Boolean operator, logical operator as a
control structure. And you see this
often in in Unix
bash as well. In fact, bash is probably
the one who began it. For example, uh LS
um you know, or you know,
or if it's successful
you know, grep
uh grep something grep ABC, then is if
it's success successful, you do delete
uh remove uh file, okay? Remove
uh
remove it, something like that, okay?
So, basically what the the the the what
happens here, you are abusing the
logical Boolean or operator as a control
structure.
Why does that work? Because the way
boolean or operator work is because they
evaluate each one as soon as they see as
it see something is um
false. As soon as it's
see something is um
Well, well, as soon as it's
see something is true. If it this true,
then it stops evaluating evaluating the
second part. You know, it just stop and
return this right away because, you
know, it's true. When you know, or is,
you know, it returns true, you know.
There are several issues here, okay?
Anyway, anyway,
uh
anyway, so the
the purpose the the the the mathematical
purpose of the or logical operator is to
determine
which if any one of them is true.
Now,
but typical practical programming
language, you basically you have to
start to evaluate by order, right? You
start the first one. If it is true, you
don't need to evaluate the rest of it.
You can stop right now and, you know,
then it the whole thing is should be
true.
But however, this is not a uh this this
this kind of shortcut
will have problems as a logical operator
because, for example,
if you do this, this prevents you from
doing parallel computation, which is
critical today. For example, if you have
bunch of or's, you know, uh let's say
A B C D
uh D uh
okay, the
A
B C
D, okay? Let's say A B C D. Today you
have parallel com- computing, so you can
if you have a compiler, you can write
them They you know, evaluate A B D
together at the same time on four
different CPUs.
You know, but
but this is different from you know,
this if if your language is using the
sequential evaluation, that's a problem.
You can never do the What if you have 1
million items?
You know, that What if you have 1
million items? That's a bad. That's bad.
But for practical purposes, especially
before let's say before year 2000, we
all do we every almost basically every
programming language, you just do
sequential evaluation, okay? That's just
practical. That's just just a You can
say it's a side effect of kind of a
practicality.
But it's not a logical
It's not you know, supposedly the proper
way
to to to have such evaluation strategy
for all and the end operator, the
logical operator.
Now, but anyway, we have so-called idiom
in many programming languages. That is
for example, in in in JavaScript, you
also have
for example, let um
let
x equals to color
uh color or
um
red.
You see that? This is common. This is
common in JavaScript, in Python, in
Perl, okay? Like like the these
[ __ ] they tell you what to do.
They tell you to use this, you know,
when when these hacker types these any
Unix philosophy [ __ ] These hacker, you
know,
you know, Lisp people, they they they
they they they will tell you like use
this. If you don't use this, they say
you they think you are stupid. They
think you know, oh that that Sally is
you know, he's trying to teach something
wrong, you know, you should do this.
This is wrong. Okay.
Because if you understand what I'm
talking about about the logical
operators, you know,
for example, one of the limitation of
the problem with this evaluation
strategy is that you
you can no longer do parallel
parallelism. Okay.
You know, and also also, let me tell you
another thing. This is this is called
abuse of the abuse of the semantics.
That that is
you know, each programming language you
have lots of what's. Okay, you can abuse
them. You can abuse them and to create,
you know, clever ways to do tricks.
That's, you know, that's where that's
how you have a obfuscation.
C obfuscation
competition. Pearl golf, you know, Pearl
golf the golf the [ __ ] I [ __ ] I [ __ ]
hate those these type of people, you
know, the golf, you know, obs
obfuscation. Clever, you know, hacker
grok great you know,
grok, you know, I grok this
idiots. Okay.
Okay, so you I hope, you know, you I
hope I get my idea across, you know, why
this is, you know, a problem. And you
might think, "Well, that's your just
opinion, you know, nobody actually
believe what you say." Not so. Let me
tell you a famous computer scientist.
Let's go to
show. Let's go to programming blog.
Okay. Then let's go to semantic noodle.
And let's search for all.
Uh
I'm a confused you are you are you
kidding?
Wait, I I I cannot keep up with the uh
comments.
Okay.
Uh
I have a article here.
This article, logic, okay, this section,
programming idioms and style, logic
operator as control flow.
I gave I gave some examples, basically
like what I explained. Uh you know, and
you know, these idioms tell you to do
that. And including Emacs Lisp, that
like that Eon New idiot.
You know, this Eon New idiot.
He you know, to him he's like he's like
you know, he thinks like he's made a
great point, you know, oh. And and and
look at you know, this seven votes up.
Seven votes up. When I see that, you
know, it makes my blood boil, you know,
then
like some idiot say something then ooh,
seven, you know, everyone is like oh
yeah, you are right. Oh my god,
Sally is so bad.
And okay, let's go back to let's show
the computer scientist. Who is he?
Edsger W. Dijkstra. This you know, he's
he has actually a name of it of this
thing.
Uh wait, okay. Anyway, let me just read
out what he says.
So EWD says
you know, he's a well-known computer
scientist. Uh he's he's he's you know,
he talks a lot. He criticized a lot of
other computer
science stuff. So he says the
conditional connectives
C and and C or for short
are
less innocent than they might seem at
first sight. For instance, C or does not
distribute over C and. Compare Okay,
he's using uh math jargons, you know,
the distributive law, you know, anyway.
He shows some code. Then he says in the
case in the case of the Okay, he he's
using logical symbols not A and C, okay?
The second expression requires B to be
defined. The first one does not because
the conditional connectives does
complicates the formal reasoning about
programs. They are better avoided.
Uh Okay, are they Is he say Is he
talking about the same thing I'm talking
about?
Anyway, I'm not going to go into you
know, maybe someone will say cuz he the
other cuz
actually he says something else. But
anyway, that
the
I'm pretty sure the idea is similar,
okay?
Actually, I I should look into, you
know,
um
Well, anyway,
I don't remember. I wrote this in um
in 2015. I need I need to double-check
what he's he's saying, uh
and uh
Yeah, and the racket even has the old
map. Anyway, so that's I think that's it
today. So this
um
This is Thank you for watching Sat Talk
Show.
And today we talked about 90 minutes.
And people are getting tired. I'm
getting tired. You getting tired. And
I'm getting confused.
I'm confused. Dion says I'm confused. Um
so Dion says I'm confused about what it
what is wrong with the old construct.
Surely a buffer check predicate isn't a
candidate for parallelization.
Okay, so let's let's go back to Emacs.
Well,
let's check what I um Okay, that's about
Emac Lisp. Let me Let me Let me show my
original code, okay?
Um, where is it?
Uh
Okay, so actually
uh
back
um
Uh [ __ ] Anyway, so let's go to let's I
can find the code. Let's go to Emacs
list uh buffer.
So
Xonotic user buffer Xah user buffer
queue. Let's search the function.
Uh and here is the function.
Uh Xah user buffer queue. Copy it, close
it, and
paste it at the top. So here is what I
wrote.
Um
So I use a condition, you know, so what
What is his
code here? What is this guy complaining?
Yeah, okay, so
Anyway, so
but anyway, I mean in general, you know,
I I never I don't use these, okay? Don't
do these. I mean well
This is kind of
kind of nitpicking because in practice
like who cares? I mean I mean this is
not Emacs this is not logic, okay? It's
not formal logic. And it's not you know,
people understand what it means, you
know, it's not like um
you know, but you have to understand,
you know, there is you know, there is
this issue. There I mean I mean you you
have seen even that guy talked about it.
It it
I mean
there is this issue, okay? So anyway, in
general, I never use or
a b c d to do that. The only time I use
or
is when I want to know which one is
true.
I do not try I do not use the side
effect of or, you know, like dropping
evaluations. You know, don't I don't do
that. I don't like that. Unless in
shell. In shell, you almost you have no
choice. That's just the way, you know,
the shell is so bad. The Unix [ __ ]
That's why.
So, in general, I always I always do if.
You know, I don't care what. I always
write if.
And you know, if something then I
typically always, you know, just if.
In any language, in in in Pearl, in
Java,
you know, in in Pearl, JavaScript, in Go
land, I never do this. Okay, you never
see you in my code you'll never see this
this thing. This is very common. This is
like in every JavaScript code they they
they all do it and they'll tell you to
do it. These idiots.
Okay, so
So, that's that's that's it for today.
So, yeah, you so you let's
30 minutes then you have last comments.
Okay, I'm going just going to go
check if the any comments addressed to
me.
Uh
Yeah, so Seema says with the
with the or abuse, why does it matter if
you are only using two cases? Yeah, I
mean
I'm because I have a math background and
I like formal logic and stuff. So, I'm
kind of into these kind of things.
In practice, I mean practically
speaking,
it's fine. I mean this is fine. I mean
again, this is a matter of style. Okay,
so like you have people telling you you
should follow this style, that style.
That's their your
So, my opinion, I have my own style. I
don't like this. Never do this. I use
if.
Now, which one is actually exactly
better? I mean, this is like doesn't
matter. It really
You know, you know, we are not doing
formal logic. It doesn't matter. You can
go either way, okay? So, I'm kind of
when I talk, I I exaggerate and you
know, I make it dramatic, of course. I
swear these people.
Let's just Let's Okay, let's say that's
a show, okay? That's Xah Talk Show.
That's a show. That's a show part of Xah
Talk and my my rant.
It doesn't really matter, but but the
but I like to complain. The other thing
is these people these people never
thought they don't they haven't seen
this idea I just presented that formula,
you know, about the logic consequences.
They haven't seen. They don't know. And
also, when you don't know these things
and you keep I mean, the thing about
this I hate is that they they don't just
use it.
I mean, if it's your style, that's fine.
You like what you do, you know? You You
do your style, I do my style, okay? But
these type of people these type of
people these idioms style guide, you
know, every Python language has style
guide, you know, Python priests, you
know, Unix faster people, Unix people.
They [ __ ] they [ __ ] with you if you
don't follow their advice. They
they they start to say, "Oh, you are
stupid. You should do it this way." That
is the problem. That is that what that's
what gets me all this rant this [ __ ]
heads this Unix philosophy and idiom
Python idioms, you know,
you know, the Python standard style
guide and all that.
They don't know they don't know things.
And you know, programmers in general,
they are ignorant like completely
ignorant of
of math or formal logic like like they
never studied, you know, maybe they
studied calculus, which is actually not
math, okay? Calculus is kind of like
engineering. The real math is when you
started to learn abstract algebra and
analysis, so-called analysis, but
which basically is a calculus, but in
mathematicians' way, okay? When you if
you have studied abstract algebra like
group, field, rings, okay? Or analysis
like
infimum and supremum, you know, the the
the the or topology, okay? That's That's
when you under when you understand, you
know,
what math is about. And I talked about
this whole video 1 hour in
you know, last month also. You guys can
check it out. I discussed what are the
courses you study in math, you know,
what does mathematician do? What does
What are the things they study?
So, in general, in general, the
programmers in the industrial
programmers, they they don't know math,
okay? Like they have no idea, but they
idolize math typically. They idolize
math and they tell you these these idiom
things, you know, they they they think
they are hotshots, you know? Like even
in Emacs community, I can tell you right
away. I can name them, you know, I
rather I know it's not a good It's not
good thing to
to name them.
Like uh on Twitter's group, you know, on
Twitter I know several, you know, I can
name them. Several, you know, big shots,
you know, Emacs package writers. Huge
very popular package, tens of thousands
downloads. They are like huge, you know,
they are hotshots, you know? I'm the you
know, I'm the
the package writer. Oh, he's a weird
guy. He's He's package only got 100
users, you know? Mine's got 10,000
users, you know, but they don't say it.
Those These kind of people, they are not
like me, okay? They they don't say these
kind of things. They are They always
nice. They They are here to help
humanity to make a better world.
But they some of them I know, I can name
they they they like this, you know, they
like this they and if you don't do that
they think they are they are you are
stupid. That's what they do. That's
That's what they think.
They ignorant you know, just like the
this example this Reddit you know, we've
seen that's a you know, actual real life
example. It happened just 2 weeks ago, 3
weeks ago.
Was ellipse or intended to be analog to
the FOL or I'm I'm not sure what FOL.
Anyway, we should shut down. So
uh
So I'm just looking at comments
addressed to me and answer that. So
thank you guys for watching.
Put money in my pocket. Okay, so
Yeah, some some of you you know, if you
like my stuff um
you know
and if you have a job, you know, put
some money in my PayPal and uh
Patreon and stuff.
uh
Okay, so that's it for today. Thank you
guys for coming.
And tomorrow tomorrow is going to be
uh Okay, to tomorrow 12:00 again. So 12
12:00 noon.
San Francisco time.
Bye guys.