okay guys are you see are you guys still
here
apparently I talked for one hour
apparently I talked for one hour with
something went wrong oh my [ __ ] I feel
very bad
Jesus so this is so bad I actually
talked for one hour over an hour now you
know I thought you know I thought
something went wrong but meanwhile I
also thought there was a prank going on
but anyway I talked for one hour and
nothing happened happened
I answered actually quite a lot
questions and also j-team donated $100 I
spent half an hour answering that
question but no I think I'm going to
stop so sorry about that today
I just talked you know I talked one hour
to myself basically
I feel very bad
yeah so Alan Alan was trying to alert me
but when I saw that I was saying you
know I was talking I was saying I'm not
sure I'm going to read private messages
while I am streaming so apparently Alan
is trying to tell me something is wrong
or something like that
I saw the messages here and I felt
strange but I was wondering if it's a
prank
okay anyway so that's it that's it this
is a major [ __ ] you know like it I can
yeah and this happened to me my saw TV
my livestream before this happened to me
before
I talked for you know 20 minutes without
audio or without video but today I
actually talked for [ __ ] one hour and
I answered all those a lot questions
here and also on discord without
realizing something went wrong but you
see but I noticed the comments you know
it's I noticed the comment it's being
strange but I was thinking it's a prank
or something because I checked you know
it says I'm alive you know but
apparently not something went wrong but
anyway thank you that's it for today
I'll see what actually happened and Jade
jteem the guy who donated okay go to
maybe go to this code okay I'll talk
I'll do a next do a video on your
question next time
hi guys