hello hello hello hello welcome to
another episode of kar talk show
fantastic today we're going to do emac
list coding and some random chat about
type
Theory okay and this is my keyboard
kesis
360 and uh this one is Ultimate hacking
keyboard too both of them are fantastic
they are super light switches 35 G
activation Force if you are uh you know
if you don't have a mechanical keyboard
go run by it now okay uh you know get a
Chinese Cheapo at uh at by the linear
switch okay so let me begin to uh talk
on today's topic uh you go to Kali
keyboard blog and you can find uh
you can find all you want to know all
you need to know about mechanical
keyboards and the ergonomic keyboards I
recommend this glove 80 I recommend
kesis 360 I no longer recommend Kinesis
advantage to okay so glove 80 and kesis
360 and I recommend expose night and uh
this apple maker fer LS 80 is actually
pretty good although I don't have it so
I haven't I don't actually have
experience and ultimate hacking keyboard
okay I recommend these keyboards and
this kesis freestyle is actually pretty
good too so run and get
one you know if you don't have you know
this some of these cost 200 100 100 2002
200 $300 so if you don't have that much
you know you are a student if you are a
programmer you should buy it you know
you know you know programmer because
this is this you know keyword is your
life okay you don't want to see a doctor
for your hands problems but if you are a
student or you don't type that much you
know but so first of all go get a normal
mechanical keyboard
so uh you know just go to Amazon buy a
cheapo Chinese Cheo but the the ones
here are very you know buy this one for
example this one is like $60 or
something thing Optical switch very good
too but the looks is the gamma look The
Zuma gamma idiocy you know they have
they have to name their keyword bloody
like oh bloody this must be good because
te Gamers you know they want
shoot [ __ ]
idiots uh but the gamers you know they
they they created they basically created
the whole industry about mechanical
keyboard in the past about 10 years it
made mechanical key switch is popular so
anyway
so yeah okay so that's that's enough
about keyboard let's go back to uh let's
put a link here and uh go to S Talk Show
today okay so today we're going to talk
about type Theory and emag this coding
okay if you have comment and questions
and any thoughts say it now okay I I you
direct what my talk show okay I see your
questions I answer or start to talk in
that direction okay
so so jman hello jman I know you
jman zuu hello
uh reu XD I saw you in the last couple
of my videos okay so type Theory okay
I've been reading a lot so should I you
know so two topics today we're going to
do emac this coding
and uh so what is the topic for emac dis
coding the emac dis coding topic is uh
close that close that okay so we have
several image you know we're going to C
something about processing images in
within emac okay so which topic do you
guys want me to go let let me just go
because every time I ask there's a delay
and you know I don't get the answer so
emac this coding and uh type Theory let
me just talk random okay type Theory so
I've been spending like 30 hours in the
past few days reading type Theory this
time seriously so this is as you
know let's put it into you know I and
you know this is my uh New Year's
resolution so I really want to
understand type Theory which is part of
logic you know the type Theory proof
Theory category Theory they are all kind
of part of logic mathematical logic and
they are has to do with the foundation
of
mathematics this is very interesting
Foundation of mathematics logic type
Theory what you know you might ask why
do you need it for example most of my
followers followers you guys are
programmers right so programmers you
know you code cc++ Java you know you
have compilers you know the machine
don't lie you know machine just
manipulate bits you know logically they
they not not like humans you get tired
you got Slappy they are always precise
so if we have all this Java you know
Java C++ why can't they just
automatically prove everything prove
everything in the world because they
just follow logic
right that's a issue why why can't they
you know like sometimes I say you know C
C++
um python they actually don't have a
spec okay so what does that mean you
know some people will say oh they do
look Java virtual machine specification
but so as you know even hascar don't
have a spec so I mean the question is
the question is you know they are so
precise then why can't you just solve
you can just you know use all the Google
machines solve all the world's problems
prove everything in mathematics because
you have like so powerful
machine that's a problem you cannot do
it you we can't do it you know because
this why why can we not do it because
that's that's when all this logic and
type Theory and category Theory and
proof Theory and model Theory comes into
play so you wanted to know why can't you
do it
um
God I lo I lost my train of thought I'm
going into a direction
that you know
you so you cannot do it let me let me
let me give you a example okay so let me
okay this this is not a good way to go
because I'm going to get myself into a
hole so why can't you just prove
everything in the world with you know
C++ for example for examp example can
you prove um let's you know uh some
simple
thing uh we know we know already because
uh for example some simple thing can you
prove that
um I'm writing a program okay so let's
see I'm writing a program so for example
given a file path let's say this tra
okay copy the file path you know I'm
using emac this but you can do this in
cc+ plus Java python right so I'm
writing a program I press a key then it
becomes a link okay so let me show you
so show in uh show in talk show so you
can see right now I got this Twitter
link I want to make it a click B link so
I write the emac function I already did
press the key it becomes that and
showing browser okay so it becomes link
so question how can you prove that your
command this function is
correct right so we have a question that
you know computers are based on C you
know CPU complicated GPU they are bits
they almost they never wrong you know
one in a billion a thousand billion
times maybe there's some error bug but
usually they are never never wrong right
the machine don't lie so but yeah so so
we want to we have the question about
why can't it just prove all the human
problems you know like who is correct
who is
wrong you know in the world in among
politicians you just run a program and
the program will say no you are wrong or
he's wrong why can't we do that well a
simple example so I have this command
that does turn a link to
a turn a URL like that into a HTML link
like that how but then how do we how can
we prove that this command is always
correct you see that's a very simple
question practical you can understand
what it means how can we prove it you
know the computer so powerful you know
so how can we prove this command always
work let's try something this is not URL
but if we do it okay we got
error okay we started to get into you
know the detail so oh okay so this you L
must
be we know that it must be a particular
form okay so what if so what if it's uh
that okay is that a valid URL you know
that's a question you can look up but
anyway let's try our Command what's what
it does oh it
works it works it works let's make a
link showing browser so you click there
of course it's it's not a valid URL so
you know having trouble finding a side
so you started to get into issues so
first so for example we know first of
all you know this URL cannot just be any
string it got to
be like in a URL form so but what is
exactly is a URL valid URL form well
that's that's getting more complicated
so that's the first thing
then now if we assume this URL is always
correct correct okay a valid URL form
then can you prove my the command I just
wrote always
works you know for example let's say you
know some URL have things like that for
example Google
search something let's search Google
okay so you search some in Google let's
so copy the URL paste the URL there so
this will work let's try it oh it seems
to work but
some some for example some
um uh let's show you okay let's go to my
Unicode blog okay so Unicode the mark of
human
animals comments okay so the you know
you go to unical search then let's say
search
for mlns Monster okay so you got that
monster emoji copy the URL back
to talk show paste the link here that's
a link so let's call our Command
oh
error error something 85 file not
exist but this is a Val URL so what's
going on so you see you started to get
into complications you start to you know
what what is a valid URL what is an and
and
then what is the valid form that your
program supposed to Output is here is
there a
specification so so this is why this is
one of the simple the the most basic
reason you can see why you know the even
the computer is powerful they don't like
they cannot prove things okay you know
the most practical issue for for
programmers how can you prove your
function is correct so you get into
specification and what form is a spe
specification for example we run into
the question of about what is a valid
URL that simple question is very
complicated because you know for for
example let me show you the Unix idy URL
with their the Unix idsy with their
request for comment really [ __ ]
common okay so there's
URL so this is Wikipedia trying to
explain what that is then you go to the
living standard there is a you know what
the [ __ ] group created by Google and uh
Google and Opera scums and apple because
they want
money you know the what the [ __ ] group
so you go to leaving standard and you go
to RFC okay wait let's go there RFC
there RFC
1738 RFC
3986 oh my God RFC
4248 what the
[ __ ] I just want a simple URL
specification what the [ __ ] IC
4266 you see so let's look at this RC so
now so the UR living standard oh my God
how many pages this 1 million
pages
URL specification so for this simple
thing you got you got this
problems okay then then request for
comment idy that's a Unix idy RFC okay
the Unix people love to site this for
like 30 years not so much today because
the Unix hacker generation died
out replaced by malen zumas which is
don't know not nothing and don't care
about
nothing even worse so anyway you see the
you know RFC RFC
1738 Network working group request for
comments [ __ ] the [ __ ] their ass uniform
resource locator okay status of this
memo abstract introduction this this 1
million pages of it okay for the simple
the most simple issue and references
Jesus you know a
youl it's just just it's just a format
of certain strings with you know certain
where can can you play certain
characters but they this but they have
like 1,000 pages and this is not it then
so okay so IC 1738 then RFC Unice
uniform resource identifier you are I oh
this is different from URL this is
URI request for comment
3986 okay and uh this is million a a
million pages of it okay
next request for common 4248 the Tet URI
scheme oh so you you have UI but you
have specialize
URI then this the goer URI scheme the
male to U scheme moving M server URI
scheme to
Historic oh they change there's also
change
happening okay so this is this explain
the complication so you you know
machines are powerful but you cannot
prove a
[ __ ] actually that's the right way to
put put it you know C++ Java so powerful
but you can't prove [ __ ] okay you can't
you you can't even prove prove when + 1
= to 2 let me explain about that case 1
+ 1 equal to 2 you know you are a
college student or you are a you know
professional programmer Hot Shot working
at Google you you you you hear what do
you mean you are you know you cannot
prove one plus one and two for example
you are a python coder very popular
python let's see
print 1 + 1 run it oh it says two so you
are wrong look python python says one +
Oneal two but this is this does not
constitute a valid proof
because proof goes by Logic you know so
1 + 1 equals two so simple question what
is one what is you know what do you mean
by one what do you mean by one what is
the
number is there is there infinite number
of numbers you know all these are
relevant
questions because if you say this proves
1 + 1 equal to two then we can just
invent anything we can invent from now
on WE invent t+
T equals to mm okay let's just invent
that then you can code this in Python
and t plus T OS equals to mm but the
problem with that is not useful so when
you want something useful like real
numbers then you have one you know
decimals and fractions you run into lots
of issues so this is all this is comes
to the foundation of mathematics this is
when you
get uh formalization logic systems type
theories and category theories things
like that okay this is kind of a simple
and practical
explanation okay let's go back to act
actually I digressed so much that I uh
did
not talk much about uh you know what I
wanted you know you know I I was reading
about type Theory so let's go back to
type Theory
okay school and Bon says found you from
your s love your techn knowledge man
keep up the stream thank you
money okay money makes the world go
around all the nice things you know uh
doesn't do me much if you donate that
does does
something okay
so the foundation of mathematics this
this is the most funny and the the the
most accurate meme I've seen about logic
you know so mathematicians for the past
300 400 years since uh 1600 since since
let's say 1700s they started to see
seriously actually the history you know
the foundation of math goes way back
2,000 years ago from Greeks the ukian
the ukde
elements anyway so this picture
summarize summarize kind of summarize
the funny thing about the foundations of
mathematics because you you chase you
know logic you know
know Plateau says this you know all
men's are
male all men are male I'm a man
therefore I'm a male okay you know
that's the classic propositional logic
so you begin with that some like 2,000
years ago then you started to find
problems you know you can do this or
that you know there are issues logical
issues then you improve it then but then
in the past 100 years you started to
have different
um you have you started to have symbolic
logic that is instead of using English
words you know you just replace them by
symbols so you just like almost it's
like string replacement
so
so so logic what is this
oh my God the Zuma [ __ ] this guy known
professionally as logic insulting a
rapper you know the
rapper so here's Wikipedia on logic so
you replace symbolic logic or
mathematical logic known in the past 200
200 or 100 years invented so you replace
words by symbols so you capture just the
essence of the mechanism of logic so if
P then P implies Q therefore Q okay so
you know you don't have to say oh man
male I'm a male therefore something
something you just p a
proposition and uh if P implies Q then Q
okay therefore so you symbolic logic
okay so then then you got problems you
got you know it's not you know it cannot
capture certain things we we want to
know is true such as 1+ 1 equals two or
it Compass something then you replace
something
something okay then then you
have well anyway I'm not going to go
into you know I so but basically that's
how you know in the past 100 years you
have basically tail
Chas like this okay endless tail chasing
it's almost like going a circle but
actually it's not going a circle because
then you real I mean because actually
what happens you you started with this
logic then you realize oh but there's a
paradox for example the most famous is
rosos paradox you know let this be a set
that is the set of all
sets Okay it defines a set what is a set
a set is a you know a set of things
a finite or infinite you know I forgot
which anyway a set so this set we Define
a set X let's say it's defined by this
set is a set of all thing all sets Okay
but is X
itself a
member
of is X
itself a set of all sets you know things
like that Russ r Russell's Paradox okay
so you run into that problem so Russell
you know he's writing principia
Mathematica about 100 years ago you know
he got this Paradox so in order to avoid
that contradiction Paradox so he created
type Theory so what he says is that you
cannot Define something by referring to
itself okay you know this set is the set
of all set you can you know that's
referring to itself so you cannot do
that so you classify sets into types so
you have hierarchy of types so this
level level
one you know you have sets then level
two you can talk about level one stuff
okay then level three you can talk about
level two or level one stuff but you
cannot talk about you cannot Define
something in terms of itself something
else in this in its own level so you
started started to have this type
hierarchy very complex because you logic
you know you go into it then you know he
found that this doesn't work or you have
to amend it or you know then you know
then getting very cumbersome and
elaborate and also you made mistakes
things like that so it's like going
around circles but actually what
actually happens you know you disc
discover some problem you went onto the
next level you know you Tred to fix it
then you got something else then that
has some other problems so you started
to fix that and can you know reconsider
and come up with a new thing category
Theory type Theory you know okay type
Theory you know you you started to have
Lambda calculus okay oh yeah but it's
you know you got this problem so we have
typed Lambda calculus yeah but that got
issues too that so we
have you have um you
have what's interesting is the
um then you
have these variations of type systems so
you know you look up Lambda Cube on the
lower left is the Lambda calculus then
you have typed Lambda calculus then you
have uh anyway
so yeah I you know
I not I'm not an expert of this but I
been studying logic like casually for
the past 30
years but anyway I'm I'm kind of going
uh
nowhere
uh so what's your thoughts about how
long have I been already already 30
minutes [ __ ] I
wasted is it
um I'm wasting like I'm going
nowhere uh okay so what uh what what do
I want to
say
K what's your thoughts about logical
languages you you mean like prog you
know because essentially that's the only
thing almost Prue and
Mercury okay that's a logical language
okay uh and what's my opinion about it I
don't know much about it I
mean okay so let's see logic programming
so what are
the other uh logic programming languages
so anyway so logic programming
that's you know all this logic proof
Theory so they of course
they they went into programming
languages and then of course today we
have H
SC and a bunch of others or camel and
they are all they all kind of came out
of uh you know
the math Foundation studies including TR
machines and Lambda calculus but
anyway what I want to say about let's
let's go back to type Theory okay maybe
that's it I'm just random stuff okay so
type Theory so what I can say is
that okay let me give
you guys some uh recommendation yeah
Mercury uh so if you you know if you are
young students you don't know anything
about what I'm talking about you can
learn type Theory okay there is also
category Theory which is very like
popular because of hascal
but I don't recommend it okay type
Theory you should go to into type Theory
and uh in type Theory there are quite a
few you know there are quite a few
variations like I showed that like that
uh Lambda Lambda Cube you know there are
quite a few and there are quite a few
programming languages modeled based on
the different models of type Theory okay
so you can so so if you want to study
type Theory you
can start to read
Wikipedia that's what I do the Wikipedia
is my preferred material as over over
textbooks uh there are a lot
textbooks
about okay let me show you a few
textbooks these are three math textbooks
I've collected number Theory calculus
linear algebra real analysis complex
analysis differential geometry topology
logic and proof Theory so you can read a
few of course in universal algebra you
know universal algebra is another kind
of branch
that that that kind of deal with
Foundation of mathematics so you have
set theory you have type Theory then you
have Lambda calculus of course then of
course then you have the universal
algebra approach then you have model
Theory fairly complicated you know
you it is fairly complicated to really
understand them all like yeah so anyway
these these are some of the books I have
not read them though uh but so there's
also a foundation of mathem let let's
let's open them okay let's
show uh then the
latest is homotopy type Theory that's
what I like I recommend okay so you can
see Foundation of math um all these are
free books as
in like no copyright I mean they allow
you to
uh uh
use okay so anyway I'm I'm going nowhere
now so let's go back to
um
let's go back to what I want to say
let's let's go back
to yeah so let's start to do emx
okay so about logic languages no I don't
recommend it uh I rather so if you ask
me I recommend okamo I recommend
FSH okay I do not recommend hascal
because it's filled with this pop
idiots okay okamo F shop then actually I
discovered yesterday there's fstar very
interesting uh uh let me show you let's
go to my Twitter okay so
I found very interesting
things so this by the way so this
article type Theory this this one is
from the Stanford
Encyclopedia of
philosophy and uh they have article on
type Theory and it's updated in
2022 by this guy Theory
conad this guy is a guy who
created calculus of
constructions which is a branch of type
Theory okay so they have so many
branches calculus of constructions and
this branch of type Theory uh there's a
programming language to go with it proof
system actual programming language that
mathematical proofs very popular in fact
it's most popular the name is cogg okay
so anyway he wrote this article uh and
anyway so I want so there's a new
language this
fstar interesting so this is looks like
a from Russia you know this originated
from Microsoft research
FSH fshp is
a a branch of okamo okamo is a branch of
camo camo is a branch of ml ML stand for
meta language that's one of the language
original language functional language to
do trying to do mathematical proofs
based on type Theory typed Lambda
calculus okay so you have meta
language
then you have standard meta
language or SML or called New Jersey ml
okay so then you
have then you have camel okay which
stand for category something
category something meta language then
you have or
camo object category something
ml then you have FSH by
Microsoft okay then now you have
fstar uh FSH is a functional programming
language but all this ml SML camo camo
they they begin like 40 30 40 years
ago trying to model type systems you
know they they they their purpose was to
do some proofs
but but you know as we learn more about
proof Theory they are mostly just progr
functional programming languages but uh
so F shop is you know Microsoft's
version of functional programing
languages then what's interesting is
fstar now fstar is actually a
language designed to do
proofs in fact it's specialized in uh
program
verification okay so this fstar I just
discovered very
interesting and among these proof
languages you know uh okay so let me
just talk
random uh okay let let's go to Wikipedia
there's a page called proof assistance
okay so what's a proof assistant it's
basically a programming language that is
designed to do proofs okay so there are
quite a few now there is you know C we
mentioned before it's the most
famous uh and there's whole high order
logic which is type Theory you know
there's Idis there's Isabel you know and
one of the most interesting I find I'm
going to start to learn one of them this
year so that's my goal I I'm going to
try to get you know serious
with proof systems and homotopy type
Theory you know I've been reading them
like so much in the past
years
the a in camel is abstract okay so some
people know what you know I'm talking
you know they they know things I don't
know okay object so category
abstract metal
land category abstract metal land ah
object
category abstract met
metal you know so anyway so among this
very very complex you see all these all
these programming languages they are
designed to do proofs but what but so
many so many plus their model you know
we were talking about type Theory and
different different uh type
of models you know different branches of
type Theory right so it's captured by
this Lambda Cube
Cube then the more General case is the
pure type Theory you know all these
names may not make sense when you first
read it
but just like every jogger in
programming or mathematics but once you
study after a while you know so pure
type system is basically the most
General the way they differ you see the
way all these different type systems
they differ is that let me explain you
know I'm not expert you know I'm a
comedian okay I'm a comedian on type
Theory so all this diff the difference
between them is that in type Theory you
have you know like we talked before you
know Russo Russell's Paradox the set of
all sets right so he resign it by
creating types A type hierarchy so at
level one you have this bunch of things
and level two you can talk about level
one things but you cannot talk about
itself okay so if you want talk about
level two things you need to go to level
three in level three you can talk about
talk talk about level two and level one
things kind of like that okay so you
have this hierarchy of
types now you know so it get complex you
know how many levels do you need or is
it infinite anyway so back to type
Theory so so the difference between them
is that is that okay so you have level
one of things you know it's you know
it's called individuals depending on
what year you know 50 years ago or 100
years ago today or today but anyway
level one things you
have things right
uh usually called terms okay now in type
Theory so level two you have types okay
so you group the terms at level one into
different types you
know type is just like English word you
know different class of them okay so
level two you have different types
then then level three let's say level
three you have type of types so you can
you can talk about what you know the the
different types so you can talk about
type of types okay so so the difference
between this this Lambda you know this
so-call Lambda Cube which captures
different different type systems is that
is
about can the system Define can the
system allow you to talk about type of
types
okay so kind of like level three we are
talking about or do they they do not
allow for example the the the lamb the
Lambda calculus is not typed so you
don't have level two three you know and
so on you just have terms okay but it
turns out you know Lambda calculus is
kind of
weak so you have so anyway so you you
can you can talk about you can define a
type in terms of terms or whether it
allows you to define a new type based on
other types called dependent you
know called dependent type Theory you
define a type based on what the argument
the type of the term okay so anyway
so anyway the the the essence is that
defining a type based on a term or
defining that's one thing or another
thing is is defining a
type based on a type okay type of type
then you can also have defining a term
based on what type it
is so that's essentially that's what
this gets you all this different so you
can see the Wikipedia says you know this
x- axis types that can bind terms
corresponding to depend dependent types
okay
then another way is terms that can bind
types corresponding to polymorphism
that's a computer jargon that's like
when you define a function what the
function return depends on what type is
the argument okay polymorphism you know
then you have types that can Bine types
you know like we were talking about
level two you know you you can define a
type
by by another argument of a type
so so you have all these different type
type systems and they have like
different powers and different flaws and
it relates
to whether they terminate things like
that for um you
know like there there's uh pros and cons
for for many of them because otherwise
you can just go to the highest level why
do you have to bother with all the you
know different ones you just pick the
one that's the best but turns out it's
just it's not like that so that is
why that is why you know when you study
logic is kind of like this you going
around
circles so so you have all these
different models of uh
of of the Lambda Cube you have all these
different models of type systems so the
most General is is SOC called Pure type
system that that allows you define that
allows all of the above you know type by
type type by ter turn by type so you can
see this
s symbolic Expressions I love them okay
I love this this this symbolic
Expressions now the C and C++ and Java
and python idiots you know try try to
get the load of them of
this okay unic code so this un this is
related to Unicode so we can go into uh
you know you can unical symbols for this
you know
logic systems you know for all and exist
therefore because therefore and proof
not and or and so on not and implies
assert true not
true love them okay then there's uh
binary operations and there's inary
operations and or for a bunch of things
not just two things so there is that
then then you also have you know in type
Theory one of the symbol you know so
while I was studying type Theory I was
also looking at you know the symbols
they use uh which is very important you
see this vertical vertical line and the
horizontal line that's called a Tac t k
okay and that is used
um that that these tax and turn
Styles okay very interesting okay so and
another thing I learned is that in type
Theory you have this B let's go here
okay you have this you know normally we
are familiar if you are into mathematics
you are fam familiar with this double
stroke Z for integer double stroke n for
natural numbers which depending on the
author may include zero or may not
include zero so that's a ambiguity the
meaning of natural numbers some author
includes zero some not then P for Prime
Q for rational R for real C for complex
numbers double stroke
found and you have H for Quan which is
like um four-dimensional complex
numbers then you have sardinians
sardinians is a dimensional complex
numbers okay these Quan and sardinians
are less use you know so they they are
the theories about complex numbers Quan
sardinians They can they are part of
algebra okay they you know
algebra okay then in type Theory you
have this P they stand for bulling okay
so this is this is new I mean this is
new to me because this is rarely seen in
typical math textbooks you know they
they don't talk about bulling type but
in type Theory you have this B for
bulling that's very that's
interesting okay I rambled a lot about
type Theory uh let's go to code emac dis
it's almost already on hour so now let's
go yeah I want to code emac dis I want
to
because you know this is uh what I need
to do you know to for my work so Rambo
about type Theory oh yeah so we talked
about you know
different type theories you know very
many different type theories the Lambda
Cube then
then you have proof assistance okay
proof
assistance so these are programming
languages that does proofs so there are
many of them and they are based on
different type theories you know
different type theories so you can
see [ __ ] for example the most famous one
they are based
on dependent types okay uh yes dependent
types higher higher old logic uh okay
they are not very specific specific here
but Co is you know for example I know I
read it's based
on uh Co calculus of what's the
term sequin calculus okay let's let's
just open it sequent
calculus or calculus of con
constructions
okay and calculus of inductive
constructions which is a higher level up
okay so you
have calculus of constructions is which
is one of the model of type Theory then
you have calculus of inductive
constructions you know I don't know
exactly uh the the you know I don't I
don't know the details okay so I'm just
starting to learn it so different proof
so this so one of the question is which
one you're going to choose if you want
to study them so that's the question
that's the question I'm facing you know
because I want to start to get into and
some of these you know you know one of
the thing I despise is
hascal you know in the past 10 years
because the hascar coders they don't
know nothing they you know they are
programmers
driveling about Monet every day they
don't know not a thing about what is a
foundation of mathematics but they just
Dil so and and you know so among that
Community you know what you might have
heard online is adaa okay you know is
one of the proof assistant and uh
another one is address these two are
probably you might have heard address
and ABD and and ACTA but actually they
are not good they don't seems to be good
you know because when you are looking
into a you know proof assistant
so-called proof assistant they are just
programming languages for doing proofs
okay they you have to look
into the context for mathematicians not
for programmers you know the programmers
will tell you oh you should use hascal
oh you should use atda or you should use
address but you you look at you know the
article they they they haven't really
proved anything you want to look at what
professional mathematicians accepted in
the math
word you
know which which have been most used to
prove you know difficult mathematical
theorems so that would be [ __ ] okay
there are some example here
so uh you know so they they have article
on which one have been actually have
done nonrival proofs okay so [ __ ] is the
most old and most famous uh then what I
discovered another one is link okay so
that's also from Microsoft
link okay and I think Ling wait wait wa
where is it Ling so this this
this okay it's also from Microsoft
research so I think this is the one I'll
try to look first this and [ __ ] so
they uh they have apparently been used
for by
uh you know by a few notable
mathematician for example the Thomas
hell I've came to know he has you know
he he used he work at Intel okay like
designing CPUs things like that Thomas
hell a mathematician he's very
into doing mathematics by computer so so
I know so you know here says he's using
it and also this Kevin Buzzard I was
looking up yesterday who is that
guy uh so he did you know this these are
mathematicians okay not from the typical
you know you know my audience you are
programmers you hear about hasar mon
[ __ ] you know so for example this
Buzzard guy he has done pure math math
pure mathematics specialized in
arithmetic geometry and landland program
okay that's that's deep
mathematics so what is he doing
apparently he's uh lead in
the is his he's
um you know he's using Lan
[Music]
to for the zena project one of the zena
Project's goal is to rewrite every
theorem and proof in the undergraduate
math curriculum of Imperial College
London okay in Ling so that that seems a
good you know a good
uh
uh good thing happened for link you know
good recommendation good uh
advertisement for link and also link was
used to formalize a new proof by this
guy Peter Schwarz in the area of
condensed mathematics okay I didn't even
know what that is but it is a
new branch of kind of geometry that
tries
to create a single foundation for
topology complex geometry and algebraic
geometry okay typically they are in
different fields they have different
foundations different axioms so this
condensed mathematics apparently is you
know started by this guy Dustin Cen and
Peter
shes who tries to bring this
field into one unified found Foundation
something like that
okay algebraic geometry very difficult
topics okay
so so you know if you ask the has our
people you know what the are these they
don't know they don't know what [ __ ] but
they Babble about no proof correctness
has go [ __ ]
them you know why because it's
misleading information it's fad fad
fashion uh and I I I truly despise that
like the C and CPP and C++ in Java you
know o o is going to solve everything
you know this this this misleading
information fake news
essentially so anyway so condensed
mathematics by this guy by by no by by
by the shorts
Sky you know so he's also using link and
uh the one of the most popular
mathematicians ter style is also using
link to prove
polom frame and Rosa conjecture okay
very I don't know what that is very
difficult that I know so anyway so it
seem Ling is great you know I'm I'm
going to try to study them okay that's
about I think that's about type
Theory uh what's
up okay anything any comments let's
let's start to do uh emac LP okay so I
want to do emac L okay so let's see what
am I talking about so yeah so let me
show you what I'm
doing what I want to do okay so I have
so this this is just my random notes on
on stuff
so okay let's go to the type Theory page
let's go to the PNG what is this logic
chasing okay so what I want to do is for
example I have this is emac okay let's
talk about emac
now okay say something guys if you're
watching now emac so I'm using emac of
course uh I'm using sofly keys
so here's a source code here's a URL you
can read about it soft keys it's a model
editing keys for emac okay and on the
pink window you can see all my command
course as I call them for example move
Cruiser you can see that's uh this
command
okay and I'm using a keyboard okay so
what what is the problem so I have this
image let's say you know so for example
I show in
browser you know I'm a I'm I'm a blogger
right I write the block so I want to I
want the icon version of this image so I
can press a
key okay it ask me width okay 250 Okay
so it gives me it creates a new image
and it inserted the path here so you can
see the command I just called is
um where is
it oh it doesn't show it doesn't show
because I called the command by key
anyway let's open it okay so you can see
your iconized uh
image okay the command I call let's
let's do it again okay open it delete it
remove that
now let's see the command I call to
create a icon image is this HTML resize
image okay let's do it again C it paste
that do
it okay and uh it says width 250 250 yes
okay okay so it
creates uh icon okay so now I want to
modify the the command so that instead
of just pasting the path here it will
actually paste a
link like that okay so now if I go to
the browser refresh you see I want I
want it to do
that uh
should I do that actually I'm not
sure now when when it comes
yeah you know I want to do that is
because it makes my you know writing
blog easier but I'm not sure actually I
want to do that
because you know when you create a icon
you don't necessarily want want to use
the icon in the same page you know for
example I go
to uh okay let me for example I go to my
math
blog okay so that's the page about type
Theory now go back now I go to the type
Theory section which is here now I can
paste the iconized image path open it
you see now I I want to extract the path
for this link okay press the key so you
can see the command is there then go
here paste it so that's a path all right
now show showing browser so you got that
now I press a
key it becomes that okay the command
is icon linkify okay now I show in
browser you see now I got this you you
have this
nice iconized
link
so so let's so what do I want to do do I
want to
um yeah so now actually I'm not sure I
want to change
it okay so
there is another thing I want to
do okay maybe that's it for today
uh yeah let's forget about Emax so today
is just random random talk about type
Theory okay anything else anything else
guys that's
it
bye
guys uh jman says what will you like to
see added to new version of the wolam
language do you think the compiler will
have an important impact oh yeah this
it's going to be a huge impact by the
way jman are you a wolfan language coder
so w language they just came out with uh
wolam language
14 and and you read stepan Wolf's blog
it's like Jesus 100 Pages like each one
of his blog takes
you five hours to read it to to actually
have some you know
reasonable
detailed reading you know so each one of
his blog is like 50
pages so this one he's talking about
announcing version 14 just came out
yesterday and so I'm using 13 you know
version 13 and uh you know so version 13
is like a year or two years ago
so you know each version they apparently
in the
past 20 or 30 years they started to add
a huge amount of things it just keep
keep adding it so anyway this blog I
haven't read entirely
yet uh you know you can do so much
machine learning like like machine
learning right I I learned a lot about
machine learning so machine learning in
wuan language you have one single
function to do whatever you want you
know
the prediction or what
whatnot so you can do machine learning
visualization image computation ation
calculus in algebra that's that's old
optimization
fem okay I'm not even sure what is fem
geometric computation and so on okay
um and you know one of the big thing in
WF language is that you know and also
you can do crypto like every every
every
algorithm every
format every
algorithm every every equation every any
problem that's known to
humanity is in wam language you know the
algorithm may be stream processing the
shortest distance of changing one string
to another the venan distance or
whatever
everything as long as it's a known
algorithm and useful it's it's it's part
of wolam language so stepan wolam says
that even
him doesn't know like right away which
one does
what so it's you know tremendous and so
you know reading his blog I haven't I
started to read it
but but so this article is not just
about news of ofam 14 but he goes
over like kind of give you a overview of
the history not well kind of you know
the development why are they adding
things what kind of things they add you
know
rmm become a big
thing uh last year
2023 and you have prompt
repository prompt engineering so wam has
ProMed repository you know I haven't
looked into the machine learning
features of wolam
language
but it's very interesting let me show
you a simple one okay let me show you
like like let me show you a simple
machine learning thing build in in wam
language okay because I tried it so
anyway a lot of things in the past
decade they they build in uh image
processing and video processing you can
see
so it's like you don't have to be a
programmer you it's for technical people
you know a lot of people today they work
with videos or images or games you know
they know technical detail but they are
not necessarily programmers like they
are not professional programmers they
they
don't deal with algorithms and all that
but they know specification you know
so wam language is what wam calls a
technical Computing platform so for you
don't you know you don't need to solve
equations you don't need to program o or
functions or whatnot but you need
to do a lot things you know processing
images export input various formats or
transformation whatever
so that is what wam language has become
useful to to many of
these uh type of people so for example
here is
a animation it can generate animation
and it can you see it can do the edge
detect filter you know in in in image
processing they call that
filter
so and one of the and this this is also
interesting random tree you know to
generate uh generate the random
tree it's a building function okay it's
not so trivial you know it's kind of
trivial in python or whatever language
to generate a random tree but if you
want to
control the depth you know how random is
your random tree that becomes more
difficult because there's a depth issue
and there's a number of children issue
at each knot so you want to create a
random tree that is actually random you
know with respect to some criteria so if
you want to do that then that's not so
easy and then W language actually just
also renders the tree and that's even
that that's not that's you know trivial
so uh so when uh so let me just do some
of
that so what is the question would you
like to see added so what do I like to
see added in wolan language nothing it's
it's big enough for me okay but but the
aspect about compiling
it that would be nice okay I mean like
you can compile it so you create an
object just like C and CPP and and Java
and that you can pass that
to uh to other people and they can run
it without having W from language
installed that has been a that has been
you know this idea has been thought
about since 30 years ago 1995 when I was
at
wufan uh
so but there is you know anyway I don't
know what's the story with that in
general it is this this is this is a
issue with lisp languages because for
lisp you got the same problem because
for the c or CPP or Java people they can
just create a program that can be run on
other machines but for
lisp usually that you cannot do that you
have to go through something something
you know it's
not usually done
so that's the issue
anyway uh let's see if I can you know
you need to turn on JavaScript in order
to copy
this okay so I mean there's so many
things I was going to trying to show a
machine learning stuff okay so it didn't
copy yeah there's a problems with the
you know I think if you have cookies off
the copy doesn't
work so you need to use a browser where
you have cookie
on so let's
magnify and
uh oh yeah that actually they show the
machine learning here you see create a
plot that looks similar to
that this is a wolam language plugin for
chat GPT so then it it generates a code
here uh I haven't tried it I don't trust
this CH chat GPT thing uh but anyway I
wanted to
show resource function that's not we
want
what what is this can we actually do it
uh yes but you need what is this tool
video new inversion
14 tools 3D
geometry animation video is based on
Computing each frame in a video by
evaluating an expression another class
of video generators take an existing
visual instruct and simply tool it oh
okay so you just pass this function a
video you know that that's
another uh thing no other programming
language does you see most programming
languages they deal with
text you can't like you can't paste in a
a graphics you know but wolf language
can you you actually paste you know
visually you are seeing
a image as the input to this function
but actually that
image is actually a structured you know
input um of of of a
video but in a wolan front end you you
see it like that so anyway that's not
what I want we want the yeah let's copy
that oh God we need to turn on
JavaScript
[ __ ] okay
copy yeah got this this copy copy
okay H never
worked let's see if that works
here
no
no it didn't work I'm not going to
actually we can just type it
directly
okay let's just run it or you need some
argument random tree code with zero
argument you need one argument or two so
let's let's see what is
argument okay I don't want that you want
random
tree random tree n give a sudo random
tree with n knots okay that's what we
want let's
say
fantastic let's get the output
no uh but anyway so that that's that's
that so we were going to try to show a
machine
learning feature okay so yeah let me
show that and that's
it oh random tree is actually
experimental okay it's interesting
so here let's go to
oh random tree is what version is it
random tree came from version
12 I don't have it in my
wolf uh Wolf
mod why why is
experimental but anyway so I want to
show
uh so let's go to
documentation let's go to machine
learning uh machine learning over view
okay let's go to
overview uh predict
classify find
cluster feature
extraction there's some interesting let
me just quickly show okay feature
extraction you know in JavaScript you
sometimes you see this you
see you know this happens on Twitter and
other websites is stupid
JavaScript uh predict so what is a find
cluster feature
extraction is it not feuture
extraction find clusters okay no not F
clusters
classify
no oh yeah I was trying to do this okay
let's try this
so it creates a bunch of images each one
of these uh so let me show you what that
this means okay alphabet is
just returns a string a list of strings
okay then
rasterize it so this syntax
means
um it means turns a string into a image
okay uh
what okay so let's say
B okay so this B
is a
image okay it turns a string into image
let's
say
something okay so you can
see so now you map this rasterize
into a list of alphabet strings okay
that's what that means so image is a
list of images
okay so what you do with
this this uh this machine learning
command feature space plot is that it
automatically arrange the
images
into Cate categorize the images so that
the similar ones are grouped together
okay so you have a bunch of
alphabet you know they they
automatically group them by their
features so we can see n and H are close
B and P are
close Y is by itself so why is kind of
unique in English alphabet in terms of
shape lower case so that's that's what
what's interesting okay so let's try
this
again for
example you know we so right now we are
trying some of the examples they gave
right you know so for these examples
obviously that they tried it and it
shows it works so what's interesting is
that you want
to we we need to do this in another
video you want to use this feature space
plot but you want to give it one bunch
of let's say your
photos and see how they arrange
it in order to do that I need to get you
know a bunch of photos so you know for
example you
can yeah so so you know you you you have
to get a bunch of photos uh but let's
try let's try if we can do this quickly
okay yeah let's try uh let's try Unicode
okay okay so let's try
[Music]
some some Unicode let's let's see
okay uh letters so we want mathematics
okay so we let's go to mathematics
or let's let's get okay let's try a
bunch of these
okay Korean characters let's get the
Korean characters
and let's get a bunch of emoji
characters okay copy
that and let's get a bunch
of cres okay interesting
coures okay and let's get bunch
[Music]
of Latin characters
okay let's let's grab
them this is going to be interesting
we're going to turn each of these into a
string then turn the string each of the
string into a image and then we're going
to use the feature space
plot machine learning to see how it
groups
them so we want we also let's try okay
let's try some Japanese okay let's grab
just this
okay then we and uh
we this a shavan finition okay I think
that's enough okay let's do
this
so I want to turn them all into what is
this so
tab uh qu replace tab
by space
okay
uh tab by space
okay and uh turn them into a line
so
now so we
got now
change double empty line by a single
empty line
okay okay then we have okay let's
magnify so each character is on a line
by itself you can see let's remove those
okay anyway so now we do this so we put
a double quote and put a comma so each
one becomes like that and then we
combine them
all so we got this okay then we just add
a
list okay so we want to remove some of
these
copy that paste in wolam language see if
we got the syntax
correct correct okay so we got a list
here
um yeah we got syntax copy make sure we
got it right okay uh well
God let's try it
again yeah okay so we got a list now we
want to
say
map
rasterize
okay
rasterize function apply
to images equals
to yeah
wait chars okay chars is a bunch of
characters and uh
Rize chars so
images equals to that okay copy that oh
then we just
say uh what is the
plot feature space
plot okay feature space plot images copy
or actually copy
that
run
it oh we got the extra comma
here it worked okay
so wait even extra Karma it worked
because yeah it's new okay so that's
special okay so
anyway then let's just plot it
let's see what it
come wow look so it puts all the Emoji
colored ones
together then it
puts okay some CR and Japanese together
then you see all the Latin A
variation here they put them together so
it's pretty
good then here's a lowercase a group
together so feature so machine learning
function feature plot in one you know
here that's what it
is fantastic okay bye
guys