morning guys welcome to another episode
of Santa's Show today is 2019 2019
November 16th Saturday and 1 o clock
p.m. in the afternoon hello beautiful
people hello Bart
how are you guys so how many people do I
have six people not many I'm actually
tired you know I like I slept 4 hours
yesterday so ok concurrent viewers now
dropped to 4 I'm kind of tired so today
Alan is Alan here we are supposed to do
JavaScript in mathematics in my life yes
I am like okay so hold on a second I
need to turn off my laptop over there
my junk so what you guys up to hello
beautiful people hello beautiful people
so what are we talking about you know
I'm thinking you wanna the plan was to
do mathematics to continue yesterday's
polyhedra we were drawing polyhedron so
let's show it showing Chrome but but I'm
kind of tired so I don't know if I old I
can do well when talking about technical
stuff today so I'm thinking maybe that's
just too random like random chat hello
beautiful people so how are you doing so
Bart had some questions I don't know
what I don't know what you're doing but
I don't know you know if you have a
question you really need to solve
you know just post question you know
post the error messages you know get it
solved like like like do you want like
what is your intention like you want you
you got a problem you need help you want
it soft or not or you just want to you
know it's a topic to talk about to joke
about
hey come on easy trunk crazy so I mean
so so bad so you you have you are trying
to install this patch show okay I didn't
know what that is okay so before I
thought you mean bash then after you
know a few days ago when you guys were
mentioning that I thought you guys means
bash okay then then good morning Kathy
okay I started to have people coming in
now I need to now I need to do a good
show oh god now it becomes a
responsibility
so there is this I guess new new tool
okay called batch which which is idiotic
so people you know people but and other
people has been talking about it a few
days ago I didn't get it I thought they
mean bash you know I thought there's a
joke somewhere and then after the video
I thought it means bad [ __ ] like bash
like bash is bad [ __ ] okay I didn't get
it but today bodies you know this he's
saying he's got a problem he's you know
he's got a problem so so apparently
apparently so there is this tool okay
called batch now what it does is it's a
it's a kind of a new language the
purpose of these languages that you can
read in in this language is language so
that it will compile into both bash and
windows batch script because both bash
and batch are very problematic because
they are very old 20 years of baggage so
apparently this bat shell is is meant to
solve that problem so you write shell
script intended for Linux or or Windows
patch so you you write in path shell
then you can compare it to both that
seems to be the intention of this
scripting language this show and it is
written in this wondrous language okay
mo functional programming language which
is also meta language which is also F
sharp which is also camel which is also
you know and Haskell borrowed basically
Haskell is somewhat a derivative of it
so okay moe
and it's practical it's used it's very
widely it's very it's much more popular
than Haskell even before Haskell was
known ten years ago so it's written you
okay mo okay so in order to install this
patch you'd apparently you need to
install this Oh Pam you know the ochem
Oh some some towing or camo and install
camo and okay so I don't know let's look
at the syntax okay I think this is crap
you don't need it but I can tell you
right away you don't need it you just
you know unless unless you are working
you know this is my guest like I don't
know much about you but my guess is
pretty much you are yak shaving that's
what you are doing that way and yeah I
don't know okay I don't know what you
are saying I don't know what's your
situation but that's my guess from what
I you know of seeing of you you don't
need it but anyway unless okay unless
you are working your company like a tune
you know a two-five like you know you're
working a company and your company has
ten ten hundred thousands of lights you
need to be oh the system you know that
needs to have the script working both
windows and bash on Linux and even in
that case I don't think you know you
don't need they will not use it okay I
can tell you for my experience I don't
know for sure because I haven't actually
worked in such a company with such a
need but I've but for my experience I
can tell you right away those companies
you know who has maybe millions of lines
or some critical system where they need
to deploy on both Windows and Linux you
know they need a shell script that works
on both they will not use this bad [ __ ]
okay okay I can tell you right away
so I don't know what is your reason but
why are you doing this okay I don't know
but maybe you find this language
interesting awesome
okay so I don't know
but even so Kathy Kathy do we have a
topic Kathy and Xetra okay let me ask
you some other guys because right now
I'm just rambling and hello beautiful
people I'm because I'm kind of tired
today but do you guys have a topic so
anyway back to the batch so you know I
don't think people are using this okay
it's somewhat popular 3.9 thousand stars
oh okay
when is this created oh six years ago
it's pretty old
I guess it's I mean it's 66 years old
some way out
good morning somewhere where are you
from so if nobody has really any
specific interest I think I'll just talk
random okay so so this patch so who is
using it let's see is there any actual
company who is using it and and are they
actually like what's their background
okay yeah yeah I think you need nobody
you know nobody will need it that is my
guess okay I don't know how they got
three point nine thousand stars and folk
181 folks so so anyway so I so that's
you know we need to find find out about
that but I don't think I have interest
too big so some way out says the
wonderful [ __ ] known as Flo Rida
okay Flo Rida is hot Miami Vice Z Tran
says I don't know exactly but can you
talk a little about math for example
fractals or the interesting math yeah oh
yeah let's let's do that then then
technical talk okay let me finish about
the Bosch not bash but a bad shell bath
show let's just go ahead bath show
stupid name okay well it's it's it's a
mix from bash and batch okay so I
question the utility of this tool
because in real life in general
this is just my experience in general
when you write when you need to compile
to both windows Spach you and in linux
you you don't do this kind of thing okay
you don't do this intermediate like Oh
convenient want to solves your problem
that doesn't work in real life this
doesn't work unless you have actual some
other stories but okay it test tell me
posted
this doesn't work okay this nobody
nobody uses this this is maybe for small
companies you know some some some people
they maybe they think they say save them
some time or maybe it's used by one
single company but you know anyway
because when in real life there are so
many technical details you cannot have
this this one installed you know you
know script that compiles to both and
expect it
so we're on Windows and Linux it doesn't
it's like it's kind of like today you
have so many almost all languages
compiles to JavaScript okay and vast
majority of them are just idiocy okay
they don't they don't work in real life
they don't work if you want to work in
JavaScript you you dive into JavaScript
you know didn't develop you know
JavaScript applications use electron or
whatever you don't you know you don't
use a generalized language that because
you love oh I love : therefore I'm gonna
code everything cold and then compared
to JavaScript this doesn't work okay
doesn't work because you you then you
will run into tremendous number of
issues in particular with stomp because
javis you know okay so the only
exception is that if the tool is
designed from the beginning to work as a
part of the web such as email okay it's
a good to mention email now wait not a
re reason ml let me show you reason
email now reason ml is a version of meta
language which is okama okay let me talk
about the history I thought I told this
story many times so in the beginning you
have meta language ml then you have
kammo you have you know different
variations kammo standard ml then you
have okay moe from kammo then you have F
sharp from cap formal camera okay so all
these are the same but pretty much the
same language the same family so then
you have reason ml so what is reason ml
reason Mao is basically okay moe but in
JavaScript syntax Facebook created this
okay so that that is about that and I
think I think it's a great language but
it's not very
up here right now so you can you know
here's recent email and so I was talking
about tools that tries to you know that
tries to compare to multiple platforms
things like that like the bat bat shell
thing okay
and I was saying it's similar in
JavaScript land where you have so many
languages each one of them or trying to
compile to JavaScript like you go to
their website you'll see they say you
know as a marketing oh we also have this
version that compared to JavaScript you
know that's [ __ ] when but however
what I was saying is that there are some
exceptions so what are the exceptions if
the language is designed from the ground
up to to be to work on the web then that
is good such as reason email for example
reason email react.js you know react yes
and angular okay we I also count angular
or they are quite a few Oh Alyssa Elm
okay I don't know if you guys heard of
that that sorry for liberation of
computer languages so I'm kind of tired
today so I'm just going to do easy
ranting today like because when you do
rent you don't have to think too you
know yet you don't have to think so I'm
just gonna do easy ranting giving you
guys my opinions
okay so opinions guys opinions posted
okay and rest what what rest okay but
was saying something okay let me finish
my thoughts so UCF shop ml family so ml
family you have F sharp
you have camel you have Alice you have
Oh camel and you have F F sharp and by
the way you see the
theory improving systems ho-ho light
isabell [ __ ] they are all written in oak
mo okay so okay mo is very practical
industrial language far more widely used
beef before Haskell becomes somewhat
popular ten years ago the ASCO idiocy
okay so so what I was saying was I
saying so then you have concurrent cream
that's another functional language
today's people they don't know they
don't know nothing people today's people
you know Haskell people they talk about
Eskimo not every day you know [ __ ] then
then you have mercury you have Q you
have asked these these are different
languages logic languages and so on but
anyway let's get back to I was giving
use and get back to the previous topic I
was talking about how almost all
language today they have a version that
you know they say they compared to
JavaScript and I was telling you they
are [ __ ] okay they don't walk don't use
them and I was saying but I was saying
unless unless they are specifically
designed from the ground up to be part
of you know the web ecosystem what are
some such examples that like I mentioned
reason reason ml typescript react.js
angular okay those are examples and dot
okay dot dot is from Google now you can
see pictures of them and in CoffeeScript
yeah so these are these are examples
this is these are tools that I would
approve if you are a front-end developer
you guys I approve these tools
CoffeeScript all those of course I may
not like them because some some of them
are old and stuff like that so you have
typescript
reason ml react.js angular you know you
have dot you have typescript you have
ASM and today you have web assembly and
you have you have weight let's go
you have Elm weight dot typescript web
assembly then you have Elm which is also
designed for the web specifically so
those are good ok not hacks hacks this
hex is the opposite example like where
they try to like compared to every
language like you just writing in this
language it compares for everything [ __ ]
so so let me give you some other
examples elixir elixir is a good example
- a good one for Java for compared to
JavaScript because it is the it is
designed you know from the ground up to
be to be for as a web language you know
for as a JavaScript you know either's
replacement or compatible you know like
tag typescript elixir is is based on
olan okay so so you have these things
and pure scripts okay I can accept pure
script you know and then you have cake
ml which is another branch of meta
language okay mo you know so you have so
let me summarize okay let me summarize
what I'm trying to say so
today almost all languages they want
they they have a version that compiles
to JavaScript
okay now of them most of them are just
[ __ ] no good some of them are good those
good ones are those that that that are
designed to work as a web programming
language almost the young
go like you cannot use it for anything
else the only purpose for their
existence is to use it as a you know
JavaScript compatible we pray old
replacement you know for the for the web
those are good and and the examples of
those are recent reason ml CoffeeScript
typescript dot um
elixir elixir and pure script I guess
and okay these are the examples so so
you if you want to do web dev you you
know those are I would think good
choices okay now now all the other
languages they all have a version to
compare to JavaScript okay that those
are all [ __ ] examples are I will say
closure script basically all languages
colon has a version to compare to
JavaScript almost all of them okay rust
I don't know if Ross has a version for
JavaScript compared to Java is good :
has a you know kind of a project to
compare to JavaScript and you know those
are oh crap
okay don't use them no good you know so
so that is my point about that now so
now back to the so what so what I'm
saying so why why is that why do I say
some of these for JavaScript are good
well all the others are no good because
because you know you have to look at
their arrange you know design their
purpose many of them for example there's
a closure script okay or goal and you
know Julia also have a version I believe
I've seen julia has a project was you
know either some of the these are
official some of these are not official
like just by someone so they because
they
exist because because the goal and let's
say goal and for example or scheme list
there are so many such examples in
scheme or common or this community they
compare to JavaScript they are all crap
okay now the reason this type this group
exists is because you know the the
programmers you know the fanatics they
love the language so they think oh yeah
I just I love goal and therefore I want
to write everything you know I want to
also write JavaScript Nichola that's
what they are thinking that and you know
that's that's the reason all these
others exist okay and that is also why
they are no good because when you
actually work on big projects serious
project all these fail or this will fail
on a meanwhile on on the other hand the
those languages that's designed
specifically for the JavaScript platform
you know for the web platform those will
be good you know things you know I
mentioned many examples typescript dot
angular react react yes you know those
are so those are good okay so that is my
opinion about that and why and so on
okay I'm kind of tired so I'm gonna go
just rambling and rambling and I guess
you you guys have to suffer so MC we do
pony that there [ __ ] is good and there
is sorry good okay so but what are you
doing with this patch this patch [ __ ]
what are you doing with it like okay
excuse me I'm sorry for my intrusion of
your private space and opinions what
what are you doing with it
okay ho now second part but answered
something above I think let's see
z CH from crazy great to see you oh oh
yeah so we see strong crazy said we
should talk about math but okay so what
how long have been talking 25 minutes
maybe another 20 minutes
so let's seize each one crazy so bar
says okay yeah so okay so waiting for no
I want to i only solved my threat is not
approved yet but because okay mo
[ __ ] did not approve it that they did
they did not approve it because you did
something wrong you know but I think I
know you a little bit I can kind of
guess because you will you know because
you know like so you ask you know so if
you are trying to if you have a whole
camel question you know you have a
question in some languages you want it
to be answered so you join their group
forum mailing list or whatever you post
a question usually it will be you know
you'll just be posted and people will
help you know but you are complaining
you know I can kind I can I think I can
tell you know even from your style even
from the way you are you know as talking
to me about these things you are not
really serious about it you know you are
not serious about the question it's not
like you know if you if you don't get
answer you will lose let's say $10,000
tomorrow let's say by next week then
then you know what to do you don't know
what to do right now because this is not
actually serious to you you are just
[ __ ] around
yes that is why because if by next week
you lose $10,000 then I don't have to
tell you what - you know what to do you
you will get your question answered on
their forum you will show up it's not
showing up because you are [ __ ]
around I can tell like okay okay you
know they're like
prove it why do they not approve it
because you have some garbage in your
post probably or something else you know
this is something something
Tsubasa's is oak ammo needed nowadays
right now I'm tempted to call it worse
then see what garbage experienced Oh
camel okay I don't I don't I haven't
coded Oh camel
okay so I can't say for sure but I I
studied it for like a month or two so I
have kind of you know I have kind of a
beginner's tutorial you know if you are
interested you know if anyone of you are
interesting or camo you might you know
it's a good for beginners you might try
for the first let's say three hours then
you move on so but so I don't know
really I don't I was planning or camo I
was you know I was planning for it to be
my my you know main main language this
is about ten years ago this you see this
is written in 2009 but I just never you
know things happens you know I just
never actually did much so I spent one
month in your camo and that's it so I
don't really know whatever okay more
questions but however I was thinking you
know I want to okay mo to be my miss my
main language to go to is because
because I've read you know all the
opinions and it's very good now remember
this is back in 2009 where Haskell is
just beginning to become popular by the
way has cow is old okay
Haskell is like 30 years old 30 years
old I'm not sure it's older than your
camera or not probably not okay but
anyway Haskell is pretty old MMA I was
older Mao is like 10 years older or
something they asked but Haskell itself
is begin as Mao is like 1970s okay
Haskell is like 1980s
and Hesketh didn't become popular until
2009 or something
so in but by that time in 2009 Oh camo
is already
Oh camo is like it's rather quiet okay
it's a night
unlike Haskell where every [ __ ] you know
young [ __ ] stupid people
programmers every every day you ask our
people Oh Mona
oh man Oh monad oh you you need to use
Haskell oh this is pure okay it's not
like that
Oh camera is rather quiet you don't hear
it however in fact in 2009 there are
lots of industrial-strength applications
for example the what's the application
for downloading peer-to-peer software
that you know download movies you know
the most popular one that's written
yokomo okay
unison is also written yokomo the UNIX -
for wow it's so extremely popular ok ok
we started to get into a history unison
now if you don't know what unison is
unison is like a sink except it's
two-way ok both ways so here's their
logo but however they didn't get you
know they didn't continue they so they
kind of a few people know about it today
but back then like in 2000 it was very
popular it's a two-way sync he saw it so
it's a command-line tool like a sink the
you know Unix Linux a sink but unison
does both ways you can update whatever
is more current so unison I used it you
know for many years for 10 years and
it's very good and unison is written you
know camera ok so if you want to look at
you know so they are quite a lot things
retain your camo you know I'm not going
to go into you can I think Wikipedia
yeah software we turn your camera okay
so you can see [ __ ] yeah
[ __ ] me oh ma almost all the math proof
systems [ __ ] ho light theorem proving
systems they are all reading okay mo
okay now those are serious stuff and
reason Mao is a version of Oh camel in
JavaScript syntax okay so that's why I
have always been interested in oh camel
just for some reason I never actually
you know get on with it
so camel I recommend yes I approve you
have my proof oh so okay mo so what are
we saying so unison so what is written
your camo so you have facebook messenger
okay that's kind of recent like in the
hacks the hack C programming language
compiler okay
hack C as we mentioned before hacks is
the language that compares to multiple
other languages and that is also written
your camo I didn't know
so whereas this one has hacks okay this
is this is written your camo and quite a
few so whole light we mentioned Mirage
OPA tinsel unison 10 cloud platform web
assembly the reference interpreter for
web assembly is written in your camo
okay so camo is solid okay okay
Oh camo is you know truly solid and in
far before Haskell came into life and
actually I'm trying to find the
peer-to-peer system called what is it
called you know what's a peer-to-peer
systems for example they say in mm you
have many of them
okay so so this is each round crazy and
hello beautiful people so it's just part
talking but in parting so what's the
peer-to-peer system for example a donkey
exactly thank you Matt a donkey that's
the one I'm thinking so a donkey okay
now they have a mere donkey to a donkey
yeah so a donkey is also a donkey is
owed the number what the most the most
popular peer-to-peer system okay
it's software that's written your camera
so you know I so I was you know okay mo
him in my opinion is very good solid
industrial language however it's you
know okay mo is like you know it's like
PHP and JavaScript its it was quiet
you know you don't it's because of the
culture you know you don't go there and
you start to talk about Oh Mona Mona
Mona everyone oh you need to do Mona did
you do one after you know understand do
you not understand monad like the
Haskell [ __ ]
okay so camo is by the culture community
it's kind of just quiet they just you
know two things that is good so why are
we talking about our camo because well
oh yeah so body's asking me it's asking
me my opinion about it okay so I do my
homework and I'm not so sure
oh okay z trom crazy and okay so so what
what does what did Bart say let's see
what did bar say so you are right that's
why I mean you know
I want it solved okay so you know camo
he's okay mo needed nowadays right now
I'm tempted to go it was then see ok ok
mo is good pretty good ok now as far as
needed
well nobody needs anything these days I
mean there are so many languages so it's
up to you to choose I mean oak an oak
ammo is one of the option in my opinion
so yeah so for those of you who
constantly asked me which language to to
learn ok ok mo is one of them I would
say so you can study : o camel
JavaScript Python these languages I
would approve okay I would say yeah go
ahead that I would like it you know okay
mo s :
Oh camel JavaScript Python
I don't like Python but you know it's
very popular and useful industry
especially if you need to get a job ruby
is also good okay you know it's just
some choice oh okay mo I yeah it's very
good okay so so so what about so let's
see okay mo needed okay so you say bad
Chou is bad but what about bad rather
learn bad show them bad so what what is
bad but but you know stats yeah I just
what is what is bad so what is bad bad
like Batman bad yeah I don't know what
that so so zoom way out some whales is
from Florida so maybe we can talk about
math a little bit so yeah so I'm just
random talk and we're gonna shut down in
15 minutes I think so how are you doing
so today's Saturday I guess Saturday is
kind of relaxation day so far says I was
about to use it for a deployment thing
at work but then we dipped Windows
support we dipped Windows support and I
don't need it anymore but I'm still
interested in the language oh okay you
know so so you walk in a company so you
know my opinion is just opinion okay so
I mean you can you can you know so if
you you you you you know your needs
better than me so you know if you so I
don't actually know anything about this
patch so but maybe it's actually a good
choice so I don't know
and I haven't so you know because I'm
thinking if I'm in a company and you
know like a small company let's say
startup and they you know then then we
need to write some simple shell script
installation script for both Windows and
bash then it's possible you know I might
say oh that you know let's use bash bash
shell you know maybe because you know I
can then but actually I don't think that
I'll do how do that
yeah today you know if you want a
universal installer just go with Python
Python Ruby okay just just tell your
users to install Python Ruby yeah that
doesn't work because typically the
installer scripts you don't want to tell
people to install another system
to install your system so that is the
reason why Bash is the most popular
you know script for installing programs
on Linux and on Windows on Windows you
don't you don't use shell script to
install things you use the Windows
installer they have a framework you use
that you know you have to do that so
anyway that that's it about bad show
okay
I don't recommend it it's it's a CV
small language and in today's world you
have so many other far more better and
powerful and interesting languages then
then this you know bad shell okay that's
about that bad show rent
what's wrong with rust again no nothing
I don't like it because I don't like low
level stuff hello beautiful people yes
so Kathy asked asked about your key
mouse key mouse device so okay so boy
six-six-six says hello have a nice day
hello and a nice day can you talk about
the math of non-repetitive tiling
Penrose tiling okay let's talk about
math let's start there so I don't know
much about that subject so I just you
know your rents random run today
I mean not rent but random chat
yeah so but you need to post the error
messages anyway Matt met you you know
Matt Matt can help you ditched ku not
always bad what do you think about
electron-electron well they all you know
electron is just it's very complex you
know I'm trying to learn it ignore about
those scar [ __ ] rants on the web okay
that's that's what I think I haven't
read it you know I it a link and that's
a medium so someone blogged about you
know why electron is bad I can guess I
don't know I don't read I don't need to
read it because I know what they gonna
say you know they're just some nerds
they electron yeah it's bad but it's
it's it's it's it's kind of necessary
almost you know if you want to talk
about what's bad or what's not bad don't
use bad
don't use javascript in the first face
and in fact don't do phone and dev don't
do web at all that's that's the best
okay don't do any don't write any web
application that's the best if you
really yeah in these nerds they did you
know opinions okay it's just different
opinions if you want you know you if you
want really great things stop you know
don't do it don't don't do anything that
you know don't create any web
applications because that entirety of it
sucks donkey ass not just sketch of a
script but the whole Tom the whole
system is worst crap and intern speaking
of that now you know if we are actually
get serious you know we want we don't
want garbage garbage things then well if
we are talking about you know you
shouldn't write anything for the web
then you shouldn't write anything for
UNIX neither kill the entire unit
say Linux [ __ ] ok because well in fact
if you ask my opinion if you actually
want to compare which is was the UNIX
ecosystem the Linux you know UNIX
ecosystem every software they a culture
entire thing all things considered
versus the web you know the JavaScript
complexity the package the Dom extreme
fact complexity the Dom then all this
this entire group of languages web
assembly and reactant you know the whole
entire garbage if you want to compare
this to I I think UNIX is worse ok ok
tidings ok I don't know much about
tidings so I'm kind of tired so so today
random rent
let's see tidings let's say let's say
something interesting about tidings I
didn't talk about tidings before and you
are asking about non-periodic tilings
so the non-periodic tilings ok reading
notes
okay let's I'm just gonna talk some
random things about tiling okay I did
write a lot about it but I haven't been
you know as doing it seriously for the
past 20 years basically
why is your problem with her scowl my
problem with the Haskell is the ignorant
Haskell youngsters you know that's my
problem not Haskell itself but the
people I mean like today like in the
past ten years this idiot yeah you know
I don't need it's not specific to
Haskell
it's rather it's about this thinking
trend following fashion full fashion pop
crowd type across programmers these
people are despised okay
so 20 years ago they are they are
chanting Perl every day pearl Oh pearl
this in there every day and you know 20
years ago this pearl pearl [ __ ]
then you have then you have then you
have Python well you know then you have
many many okay but so Haskell is like is
one of them in the past ten years it
become you know this young see there are
a lot on Twitter okay
like they'll tell you what to do they
think they know better okay they think
they know functional programming this
and they they're gonna tell you oh ma at
Haskell and they you see what usually
happening is that you know they will get
they will go technical okay it's like
they don't know nothing about the world
you see so here is the universe okay
here this years we have the universe
let's say it's this big can I see myself
let's see this big okay this this peak
okay the big universe okay now for
average people you're you know you live
in this circle fold for basically all
people you can't because you know the
you the you know that the world is truly
much bigger the history and everything
else so you live in the
little bubble every every everyone lives
in here we live here okay this is our
galaxy this is Earth okay we live here
well the unit universe is this big so
what I was saying what was I saying so
this so but we have these hotshots you
know from camp College typically or
almost always young people you know you
know this almost always happens with
young people and and logically too
because they are young you know you know
college student or the smart you know
like when I was young me when I was
twenty twenty something I know
everything okay so these people young
people so and they you know they read
stuff and they learn oh has cow is
better because it's pure it's you know
referential transparency Oh monad Oh
curbing or you got curry or functionals
no side effect oh it's based on
mathematics oh it's algebraic types
these [ __ ]
okay these idiots but but so they you
know they are studious and they read a
lot okay they are smart you know young
young you know uprising young people so
they so but they don't know how big is
the universe they don't know and they
don't know they are you know obedience
of people before them who are older who
have passed by you know you know like me
thirty years ago they don't know because
because they are young you know they
just you know they just they just woke
up they don't know they don't know they
but they think they know because they
read a lot and they are smart and you
know they are harsh Island and they are
young you know so so they they gonna
tell you they're gonna tell you you know
everyone what's good or what what's bad
that okay that's the thing mostly and
many of them are actually ignorant
because and you know husk out what what
a idea see the husk are people you know
these young people
they know they know nothing about math
like nothing nothing they know nothing
about you know first-order logic
you know this seriously not just oh I
heard I heard first-order logic
oh I took a class first-order logic in
college these [ __ ] idiots they know
not nothing about it okay this has got
people but they chant about category
theory every day that's what happening
you know and before he was you know then
there's also Python people then these
people then before his Perl people so
that is what I despise okay not because
has cow there's any technicality of
Haskell the language itself in fact
fifteen years about twenty years ago I
was I was a fan I was a phonetic of
Haskell because it's a pure functional
programming language you know I'm not
going to show my old Arcos but you know
that's my opinion I never actually
picked up Haskell actually okay yeah so
I'm kind of tired so it's just rambling
so about tithing as Titian's tidings and
patterns okay there is this there is
these periodic tilings and there is this
the most wonderful okay this is the most
wonderful book you should buy I go out
and buy it right away
tidings and patterns this is considered
the the one and only the biggest
reference on the subject matter tidings
and patterns the mathematical treatments
of tidings there are many aspects of it
this geometric aspect there's a symmetry
aspect there is a topology aspect then
there's you know the study the math
study of tidings so this book was
published in 1986 this is the
to this day today I'm pretty sure this
is the the only and biggest reference so
anyone who is serious about studying
tilings you should get this book now
this book is out of print so there's a
new version you know the Deauville
republish it so and they change the
cover to these trashy cover now this is
original cover classic you know by Guam
bum and Shepherd so I talked to the
authors those are mathematicians those
are they are very old like probably 80s
80 something 70 or 80 today but 20 years
ago I you know I wrote to them the Guam
bond guy I think he is in University of
Washington and in fact he is so nice
he's so kind to send me several of his
GCC he sent me a stack of his
publications let me try to get it for
the show since I'm doing a video talk
show
there we have it so in 1996 to 1998 I
was heavily I was diving into tiny sand
and patterns you know I'm writing a lot
programs so these are all my websites I
I created them back then and I was
studying symmetry and tidings and stuff
toggle contrast taco contrast random so
you have so I wrote I wrote this and let
me show you some web sites so yeah so
remind me to show you the articles he
sent me so I was reading his book and so
here is my program written in
Mathematica for doing tidings this is
the best of out there okay they are
computer scientists who has also written
related stuff programmers I mean
mathematicians you know professors and
my is better than theirs
you know they I can tell you this brain
tiling and Mathematica package so I
wrote this in 1997 so I was studying and
I was reading this book I still have
this book I sure I did a video talking
about that book actually actually now I
need to show it ok let me show it might
need to show the articles these authors
sent me this mathematician okay hold on
a second
okay it's so oh very dusty you see this
yeah I don't know if you can see it's
it's all dust you know actually I can't
I cannot touch this book because it's so
much dust the last time I talked about
this book is I think four months ago on
video so this you know I still have this
book ah God now I need to read it I need
to clean it for some reason my room is
very dusty you know I don't know where
they came from this just so-so in 1997 I
was studying this guy stuff and and I
wrote him an email
I forgot what question I had I forgot
but then so he sent me these will show
you okay so oh these are publications of
that guy in math journals you know he
has his own copy oh my god is this is
fake you know this is actually 20 pages
20 pages so this is Saturn and drills an
introduction to the geometry of fabrics
okay in a mathematical investigation
into patterns of weaving we really
reveal in subtle stupid camera revealing
sort of problems in combinatorics and
geometry so bye-bye Bronco go home so
it's all math you know if you can see it
you see it's all patterns math study
your patterns
okay very interesting actually I haven't
read it but this is long ago so he sent
it to me you know I wasn't asking for it
think I was asking him some question I
forgot but then he sent me to me like a
collection of his papers in these math
journals I don't know if you can see it
ok let me try to so this one is
interlaced patterns in Islamic movie
shot oh yeah so I think I asked him the
question I asked him is about the
relations between between tidings and
weaving I think you see this many anyway
he sent me several of his fabrications
you know a copy of it so now that was
when I was younger
and now I end up being homeless and
nothing what the [ __ ]
the sad story okay so anyway so you know
now I end up a YouTube I'm a YouTube
Kamini con comedian guys that's why I'm
teaching I'm teaching teaching
trigonometry anyway so so yeah tiny is a
very interesting subject okay I think
that's it for today that's that's
closing down notes so let's figure and
and random now you would you know
there's so so there is a very
interesting thing about this there is a
tithing code
Penrose tiles okay let's go there so you
go you go to you know I don't you know I
don't know I I cannot teach you anything
about it I have some pictures but let's
go to Wikipedia Penrose tiles there's
tremendous interesting thing going on
okay so let let me leave you guys with
one puzzle in math yeah let me teach you
something about math
okay so any questions so I'm also young
and I feel stupid because all these the
information I didn't found I just
learned from school books or Internet
what aren't hirings and patent use in
for that's good
we've seen some of those tiles in Arab
countries yes they are famous for that
because they the Islamic religion for
some reason forbid depiction of animals
that is why in Islamic churches you will
see no animals and also no human figure
because they don't allow it so that's
that is why in Islamic you know how they
call their church you know how they go
ahead Mars or something is you have all
these tires
so Penrose tire is invented by this guy
Penrose is a mathematician physicist
mathematical physicist and Penrose tile
okay the the the the reason peristyle is
is interesting because it's a it's a
periodic tiling okay what does I mean
let me explain that and I'll be here
today okay so this and in fact and
Penrose tiling is one of the greatest
discovery in math one of the greatest
you know is fairly important because the
discovery of Penrose studying kind of
surprised everyone is so it's kind of a
evolution revolution not evolution but
rather revolution is it has it made a
wave in math community and because it's
like the relativity you know he changed
how people think about so it's you know
so you know it's a big theory it's a big
discovery so a periodic tiding so let
let me let me talk about let me tell you
what that is okay again I'm tired so I'm
now
you know I cannot do you know I cannot
think you know talk about math poverty
but let me just let's try to show you
random things why do you why is there
two copy of this page okay close one so
I'm going to tell you about okay so here
is my notes
it's very incomplete okay I mean it's
not even beginning about the math of
tithing so we're we're how shall we is
begin so first of all yeah let me tell
you okay so let me so tidy so let's go
to Wikipedia so because Wikipedia
actually has the most information so I'm
going to tell you what is a periodic
tiling then they'll be here today
what the [ __ ] is this biology computing
people and what tessellations okay
stupid name tessellations and i don't
like the you know the phone version of
Wikipedia [ __ ] the phone version it's
gorgeousness go to the full version I
don't want the phone version okay that's
better so I'm going to tell you about
periodic tilings and periodic tilings
okay let's show some
okay so here is the tithing
so this one is created by so you see you
have this shape and you just repeat it
you know like a tire you have a tire
like a bathroom you know the tire you
just repeat it okay right right guys
right so what time is it so I've been
talking oh it's one over one now so okay
so let me finish that five more five
five more minutes so let's go back to so
you have a tire you repeat it and you
can tire the plane now this this tithing
is made by just one single shape you see
this one single shape you just rotate it
and you can tire the plane okay and when
you have a tithing when you use a tire
to tire plane you call that tithing okay
so it's so tidy so when you have a
tithing you can consider one of the
question to consider is whether it's
periodic a periodic tiling means that
the whole thing can be repeated by by
moving it you know so like imagine if
you have a transparency of this picture
let's see if I am showing you my screen
yes
if imagine you have a transparency of
this picture you move you just move it
up or to the side or in any direction
you will become itself okay so
mathematically we call when you move we
call that translation so we so the the
tithing is a translation of say of
itself in other words you can repeat the
pattern by just moving it by moving it
straight lines okay not rotation
rotation is a different thing okay so
that's so when you can do that that's
called periodic tiding because it's like
good
period you know it'd be Pete's but not
rotation okay remember that's the
rotation is different so now so now you
understand what's a periodic tithing and
remember this whole tire is made by one
shape okay that's another thing
important let me talk let me show you
let me talk about that now here is
another tithing now this one is also
periodic because you can just move the
whole thing in a direction and it will
repeat the whole thing will repeat okay
so it's periodic tiling however now this
tithing is made of two shapes you see
this large square and smaller Square two
shapes to create this hiding now those
shapes is called the prototype okay
remember that's a technical term when
you talk about tithing in math for math
okay so the shape that creates a tithing
is called the prototype proto tire so
the in this hiding it requires you need
to prototiles you know you have two
different shapes to create this one so
let me let me just show you some other
examples okay so you've seen prototiles
and let's look at this one okay this one
how many prototiles are there can you
say can you tell it this this one
requires one prototype you know just
this one you know so it requires just
one shape then you know you then you
rotate it and you can tell the pain now
the question is is this tiling periodic
now try to answer it okay you guys try
to think about that and type your answer
okay so you know you have to think about
it because you just listen that that
doesn't do nothing you have to actually
think about it so
that is that one periodic or not type
your answer let me show you some other
prototiles okay okay they don't have
okay so let me show you so this one this
one okay so wait so let's look at some
beautiful tidings okay yes
boy is correct so that one that tire we
seen before it's periodic that's correct
thank you for the answer it's periodic
because you can move it no it's actually
periodic guys so you see this is so
that's why you have to think about it
you have to work out homework okay
because if you don't do you don't you
just listen you don't you don't you
don't you forget and you know so this
one is actually periodic now it's a bit
tricky but actually if you look at in
detail you know if you actually try to
think about it
you know because fundamentally it's
basically based on a triangular grid
okay let me show you
you know triangular grid once you see
triangular grid you as you understand
why it's periodic I lost my glasses
but what
so we have a triangular grid here you
know imagine this right
so is this periodic obviously this this
triangular grid is periodic because you
can just move the whole thing you know
it they repeat itself now this this is
also tied in so it's also triangle you
know it's made of triangles now if you
go back to look at that one we were
talking about this one you can kind of
see it's actually based on the
triangular grid so you can actually move
the whole thing and it will repeat
yourself yes overlapping when
translating yes so I think the first
shape what
yes em seaweed yeah you are right so you
know so this one is periodic
okay now let's let's talk about let me
show you this okay now this one this one
is also periodic you know you can you
can kind of easily see now but this one
is got to prototiles one is the hexagon
and the other one is the triangle now if
you don't count different colors as
different you know you ignore the colors
for now
now colors are interesting because they
they change many other aspect but
however we ignore the colors for now so
this tile is periodic and it is made of
two Paulo tiles one big hexagon and one
small triangle so you use these two
shapes to create one okay and let me
show let's show another example now this
one this one is also periodic it's like
a triangular grid you know it's periodic
and it's it has one prototype because
you use one shape too tired so now
remember two things okay let me
summarize the concept of when when is at
hiding periodic now you have to remember
to give a definition when is a tiling
periodic okay the other concept is the
prototype which is the shape or or more
than one you know the shape that is used
to tire the plane okay okay that's a two
thing I hope you will remember that
because you that because that's part of
the important concept if you want to
study the math of tidings now let's look
at this one now this one is very
interesting because this one actually oh
it's so big
let's shrink this one actually also
tires the plane because you can see this
thing two things we've heat and your
tire the pet but is this one periodic
now answer okay try try to type that in
the okay yeah you are right boys but
anyway let's think about this one this
one is this is this one periodic or not
and this and this one but this this way
you're tired tired of the plane because
you can see it goes outside and this one
has only one prototype if you ignore the
color so one follow tile to tile the
plane okay anyone anyone answer the
question is this one periodic or not
so Bowie says no you are right it's it's
not periodic because you cannot move it
by a straight line to have it repeat by
itself you cannot however it can repeat
myself by itself if you rotate it but
that's that's not the definition of PV
Odyssey you know that's symmetry that's
rotational symmetry which is important
but that's not periodic
okay so periodic means it repeats by you
know by moving by like like you know
period okay
so periodic or not and proto tile
remember these two things okay so now
let's go to now we are going to talk
about a periodic tiling now who asks the
question you know I you know I'm
probably talking to basics to basic
about because whoever asked about
Penrose tiling he you know the person
already know so
so now now remember
okay periodic tilings and and proto tell
okay so that's the two things you want
to remember now let's go back let's talk
about periodic tiling okay let's just go
to Wikipedia because because they have
the most good information okay this is
beautiful now this is instance of
Penrose style Penrose siding it's
beautiful now remember the question you
know we talked about the concept concept
of hold on a second so let me go to
remember we talked about the concept of
weather tiling is periodic and the
prototiles of tithing okay now let's
look at some examples okay okay here's a
question the math met mathematician
wants to answer and to this day it's not
still not completely solved okay the
question is is it possible to have a
prototype you know a shape or a set of
shapes let's say just a shape okay is it
possible to have a shape a photo tile
such that the shape can tile the plane
however it can only do it in a way such
that the result is not periodic does
that make sense anyone
okay oh yeah boy so boys about asking
about about the parallel of symmetry
groups in Penrose tiling the yeah so I
don't know that answer you know that's
that's advanced question I don't know
the answer I'd you know that I studied
this actually I never studied much about
Penrose tilings so yeah I don't know
answer to your question so so anyway
back to the general ed okay general
education so the mathematician wants to
know is it possible to have a shape or a
set of shapes such that they will tire
the plane but they can only do it in a
way that the result is not periodic and
the answer is yes and in fact we have
seen the answer and that answer is that
ends wait is this though is this also
count as yes I don't know
anyway let's so so the anyway the
Penrose style is one such solution so it
uses two shapes you know one one is like
that one is like to rhombus like shape
to tile the pen however the only way you
can do it is by creating a pattern
that's not periodic now there are some
complexities in this because this is not
actually the shape you use the actual
shape is actually you know that requires
some explanation
Penrose type Penrose tiling because
the actual shape for Penrose tiling is
actually you know the the shape is
actually more complicated it's not just
rhombuses
however you can like a jigsaw puzzle you
can carve holes into it so that they
only fit in one way you know that's so
that's a real shape but however we we
kind of ignore that because I don't know
if you guys know what I'm saying talking
about anyway that I think I think that's
it for today so you can now you know you
can read Wikipedia okay so here is an
example okay here is a real pain rose
tiles so with these two shapes or you
call them prototiles with these two
shape you can tile the plane you know
meaning Theo the plane to infinity
however it's it's not possible to do it
in a way that the result is periodic
okay so that is a solution this is one
of the solution to the question and this
is not the only one you see before
Penrose style
mathematicians has come up with other
solutions for example let me show you
we've seen it here but I just scored off
anyway we've seen that it's called Wang
Wang tiles okay let me show you one tire
and this subject connects to formal
logic connects with very deep connects
to formal logic and the heart of
computer science theoretical computer
science so this this one tiles in the
beginning it's like hundreds of tiles so
100 you need these hundreds of shapes to
tie a plane and they can only do it such
that the result is not pure periodic I
think
that's the okay I think that's that's
that's what it is
you know don't quote me for it I don't
remember I'd you know you I'm no expert
anyway so so so the answer to the
mathematicians question is yes it is
possible to have a set of shapes you
know one or more such that finite number
you know tiles such that they can tire
the plane however they can only do it in
a non periodic way okay that is possible
because for example here's one example
and then we have Penrose tiles that's
another example okay and but however is
it possible to do it with one only one
single shape single one single photo
tile I think that question is not solved
okay I think that question is not solved
I think also there's another requirement
is that they require that the tie line
be not symmetric okay so this one
doesn't count
you know they required because this one
the result is symmetric meaning that
there's a rotational symmetry you rotate
it it becomes itself anyway that that is
about that for today thank you guys so
boy says I'm called the Einstein problem
it's called the Einstein problem for now
it can only be solved by mirroring the
tile or by using a disconnected time
okay so let's see what is the instant
problem
is some problem let's look this will be
interesting in plane geometry the
Iceland problem asks about the existence
of a single photo tile that by itself
forms on a periodic set of volatiles
okay forms on a periodic set of
volatiles okay okay so that is shape
that can-can tessellate the space but
only in a non periodic way okay yeah
okay so the problem the question I just
talked about is called Einstein problem
so so boy you know a lot math you are
you a mathematician no because my
followers they are very diverse many are
young people but some are mathematicians
some are about the same age as me so I'm
talking it's a test you know the subject
is too simple so anyway so let's see
such a shape is called instant not to be
confused with Einstein okay
play on German word Einstein okay one
time
okay stupid name the problem the
Einstein problem can be seen as natural
extension of the second part of Hubert
eighteenth problem okay yeah I haven't
heard of this name interesting I should
have okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye guys
study math as a hobby that okay that's
great
me too and in fact you know when you
study tidings there are quite a few
mathematicians you know hobbyist without
even knowing calculus they have created
theorems in tiding you know just by you
know because tiding you know the the
math of tithing is a subject it's not
mainstream okay if you go to university
you want to become a mathematician so
you took you go to college you study
calculus linear algebra differential
equations complex analysis analysis
complex analysis topology differential
geometry you know you go on you get a
PhD and algebra you know group Theory
field theory you know you become
mathematician after you got a PhD but
you may not have studied tiding you we
all know nothing about this subject this
tidying thing is not mainstream okay
well if you are a good mathematician and
if we are curious of course you you will
have learned it by your own
in your journal journey of studying math
you know but anyway so this is not you
know the main stream math one you know
you know like combinatorics graph theory
projective geometry those are not
mainstream including the tiding stuff so
and tiny tiny thing is very appealing to
the mathematicians because you don't
need to know calculus you don't need to
study two years of calculus just to
understand you know what this is about
you don't need to because I just
explained to you in the past 30 minutes
what pv Odyssey you know means you know
so so you might start to you know do
something you know you it's fun oh yeah
here is an example what Robinson tire
here's an example of non-periodic tiding
it's called a periodic because you know
when a set of tiles they they can tie a
pin but only in on a periodic way you
call those tiles a periodic a periodic
tiling so here's the example so anyway
so they are it turns out they are quite
a few no mathematicians like they don't
even like that they are housewife they
don't have a college degree and they
have found new theories entirely for
example let me let me show you here okay
in 1990s okay when I was studying math
this happened in 1990s so the question
is here the question is you want to okay
so you see this bunch of Pentagon's
they are a shape of five side you want
to create or tiding using this shape so
tied in by Pentagon's okay that that is
the problem but the problem is actually
to list all possible such tidings so you
want you want to have a complete list of
Pentagon's that can tie all the plan you
want to have a complete list so this is
the problem and you know they are the
mathematician her name is you know you
read this article you will find it but
you know I have to okay 1975 rice okay
this this housewife much mature advice
in 1977 she discovered four of them
never studied you know never known
before she did she discover four of them
then you know later other people showed
more then by 2015 2015 just four years
ago they
discovered another one and today I think
it's proven that we have the complete
list of them yeah so yeah so this
problem is now solved anyways in tithing
there are quite a lot and soft problems
it's easy to understand now look at
these some of these are just beautiful
you see another interesting thing is
that when you have a tile sometimes a
set of prototiles you can tile the thing
in more than one way you know do you see
what I'm saying like you arrange it this
way that's one configuration but you can
arrange another way using the same tile
and it looks different so you know this
extremely beautiful okay bye guys