good morning everyone welcome to another
episode exotic show today's 2019
October 13th Sunday 10 o'clock a.m.
California time greetings
but greetings Matt let's see how many
people are here ok 0 let's refresh that
so what is today's topic yes but I
missed you yesterday
so yesterday I was going I was talking
about the keyboard you showed me that
SteelSeries a peck a peck keyboard and
that turned out to be a great keyboard
so I was talking a little bit about that
yesterday and there is another topic you
mentioned that I didn't understand when
I another topic you mentioned I didn't
understand at the time
you mentioned twice about how Microsoft
something about repairable hardware - I
have no idea what you're talking about
until yesterday while the day before I
read the I read the comments in detail
then so you are saying so Microsoft
apparently let's let's see if we can
look that article so today's talk show I
got several topics prepared but let's go
to talk show homepage and let's go to
the actual topic spring and there is a
let's see repair ok it's not here ok so
back to excel talk show go to yesterday
must be here
SteelSeries keyboard no this one
yesterday oh yeah so there is this
article from Microsoft okay hold on a
second let's change this to live chat so
so your links will show up so let's see
Microsoft so let's show that article
let's see what it is okay so I get the
idea basically so I think they are
singing nice move Microsoft that article
says nice move Microsoft Microsoft says
they value repairability they value
repairability design small repairable
product okay that's a title I didn't
watch the video I didn't read the
article neither but but my impression
okay
do they have actually any detail my
impression of this title is just it's
[ __ ] it's marketing [ __ ] yeah
right they're gonna make repairable
hardware it's I don't trust it maybe
it's true but you know if we support I
mean the intention I mean what they are
saying is that Microsoft decided from
today on they are going to create
Hardware you know Microsoft notebook
surface book for example so that it's
more repairable like we you can replace
memory chips something bad parts you can
replace parts of it hottest things like
that you know in the past 10 years we
have moved Apple especially led by Apple
we moved into a situation where they
made it so that everything is not
repairable we'd not repairable not
replaceable I mean even if you take your
Apple laptop if something broke you go
to Apple Apple's store they will not be
able to repair it almost like the only
way is for you to buy a new one or get a
replacement things like that you cannot
take it apart repair repair change the
battery
things like that it's that way because
Apple makes more money that way they
designed specifically design their
product to be that way so I think that's
a I think that also applies to Microsoft
products like their service book their
laptops and there are YouTube channels
YouTube video channels that ok close
that there are YouTube channels that
talks about that you know there are some
very popular YouTube channels so there's
this guy I don't know his name I so you
go to youtube youtube Apple repair ok
and there is also another very popular
hugely popular a few million followers
YouTube channel by this guy called
Lena's okay not not the same guy as
Lena's towboats the guy who created
Linux but another guy whose name is
Venus and he also did a video that
discussed that shows you you know Apple
products Apple laptops you cannot be
fixed and many bad things evil things
done by Apple and I remember also so
he's one of the popular video channel
that does that okay hold on a second
so so bottom you says did I hear querida
you change your mind yes so that affects
keyboard that keyboard has the best key
switches ever basically you know
practically speaking that keyboard has
the best key switch ever so actually
let's go there and let's go to keyboard
so I actually wrote a keyboard block so
thanks to you for bringing my attention
to that keyboard let's see let's get
this window okay in this way so if we go
to my keyboard block and and you know
this keyboard turns out to have the best
basically in practice the best key
switches ever today well not not the
best of because they are several they
are also two other horse which affect
keyboards so let's say this keyboard has
the best key switches a man came in
keyboards okay
but however they do not have have the
gas pedal ability you know they didn't I
mean I think it's a software issue like
you mentioned but they didn't do it but
anyway this higher sound 22 he made a
video talking about it if you go to my
website you will see it okay let's let's
let's go to the website
okay so actually I do have some topics
prepared but let's just go to this
website now oh wait a second so great
opening him brave so he did a video wait
oh yeah oh yeah you have to turn on
JavaScript turn on JavaScript and
refresh yeah so this guy he's a keyboard
switch expert he did a video on that I
watched it so it's a one it's a best key
switch and but but it's worth mentioning
that there are they are two others
that's also using whole switch and also
I'm not big a fan of key switches III
think maybe I talked about it yesterday
a bit I'm not - yeah I mean oh as long
as you have a some kind of mechanical
switch that's almost good enough of
course I like better switches like
optical for example optical switch such
as this keyboard is also contactless
meaning that you don't have electric you
don't have electronic metals like copper
you know contact when you are when you
have contact based switches that
improves the key switch much better
because because usually it's a
electronic contact that makes a
mechanical switch you have constraints
about how you design the key switches
tactile sensation so once you go
contactless such as the optical like
this one showing here and then then you
have much freedom to to create better
tactile sensations but anyway so so yeah
so that's about that keyboard so little
so let me read the comments so back to
Microsoft repairability so they are
these leanness channel who talks about
that and i think there is a
the guy I think this is the guy Lewis
Rossman okay let's see no it's not this
guy okay but anyway you go to youtube I
think you'll find that you just search
for Apple Apple lab laptop repair sucks
things like that you'll find it very
popular channel so they discuss you know
they have the the Lewis guy is the
expert on fixing hardware so you know he
he almost a shop you know fixing Apple's
products so he knows we need details so
anyway so what I'm saying is that
there's a trend since the past ten years
they make the hard way or not repairable
intentionally so like advil for example
memory they are all soldiered into the
laptop motherboard you cannot even
repair it yourself it's basically
impossible so once it's broke in some
way you have to throw it away and buy a
new one that's that's what society Apple
you know that's that's that's the way
they did it you know so who do you blame
you know this is not a good you know
Apple on one hand they say oh we are
recycle you know we are for green planet
you know they market there in their ads
they say they say they are the company
that makes the more recycle recycling
things they have solar panels in their
headquarters you know so on and it's all
marketing [ __ ] but meanwhile they
are doing this you know they are doing
they they make you to buy a new Apple
product every few years they force you
kind of and whenever there's a new
iPhone came out they have software on
the iPhone that makes it slower you know
secretly and they they've been being
sued they are being sued for now for
that I think so when you throw away your
laptop that's kind of that's a
tremendous waste you know as far as
recycling green planet goes so Apple is
doing that so so who do you blame you
know like a lot people will will just
blame it Oh
that's capitalism I don't think I don't
that I don't think that way okay so the
way the way I see it it's basically
corruption okay not capitalism
capitalism or free free market actually
in my opinion it is the most fundamental
it's the it's the most natural and the
best system
sowhat's but in USA for example you have
a lot you see all our problems you
cannot you know corporations manipulate
you there's nothing you can do or that
you know the politicians they taking
bribes I blame it on corruption you know
they its corruption and it's also I
blame it on people's ignorance of how
things work for example a lot people
today including many the hacker types
and social justice people you want you
know they push they they tell Twitter's
they say oh I need a pen but you know I
we need Twitter too I think eyelash gets
into my eyes you know a lot of people
they today's young people they have the
sentiment they want the government to
help them they want the corporation's to
help them so for example on Twitter they
tell Twitter oh we need we need you to
ban this this this those kind of people
or offensive things you know they and
they tell Google to do that they tell
Google so since about 15 years ago
almost every website you have this
report button you know this this was not
there it began about ten years ago let's
say ten years ago almost every website
including this court you have now a beep
or button this code is great ok this
girl is this code is great we have a lot
you know when you started to chat on
it's not like Twitter we don't on
Twitter no information flows like when
you just get into argument debates and
also when you debate there's no new
information it's just the same old you
know there's no opinion but on this code
you see all sort of opinions you know
flight and it's also fast like real time
you see all sort of opinions from
different people that's important
diversity you know from different actual
different people different opinions and
I learned things you know I learned you
know I think you talk to people actually
this this is acne you know this is not
necessarily just discord is this is true
for other social networks like the one
you mentioned about mass something I
haven't looked into it but you mentioned
about parts mentioned something about
alternative so anyway so yeah we talked
so Apple you know Apple so Microsoft
says they are going to create repairable
hardware okay you know let's see I don't
I don't I wouldn't trust it so what so
what is the next topic let's see X our
talk show some talk show close that okay
close that PC keyboards so let me write
down the top topics we just talked about
I have some topics today so keyboard
Microsoft repairable ie Pai are ye
microsoft says they they'll make more
repairable Hardware okay that's that
that's what they say evil even magnify
showed the command lock evil Apple group
making laptops
that's not repairable
okay now spell check repair case spell
check in Emacs Emacs spell checking is
utterly idiotic you know like for
example you have a wrong word for
example here wrong word you you call the
command fly spell buffer so it's
incorrect now it's right there
so you correct it it doesn't auto check
of course you have to spellcheck the
hope of a year and it and the spell
checker in Emacs is about five or ten
times slower than paying web browser
editor that's just the way he max are
you know this is a problem with Emacs
this this is a flaw weakness of Emacs
for for the past 20 years so if I am
making up laptops that's not repairable
and slow down your iPhone when there is
a new version
so that's Apple steed okay and ok so we
talked about that why I love gonna go
like why I love Cola and that's the next
topic so now let's look at the comments
Allen W says Kassar you can mass you can
mash your keyboard in the chat so we can
see what nonsense looks like on go rack
mash like what do you mean mesh well my
left hand is just that ok my right hand
is that
another moderator just handled this
Google started to be tell me that what I
think I'm the only moderator why is
Google telling me that okay anyway let's
read the comments from the beginning
I've been talking for 18 minutes good
I'm is so far in control have not lost
my mind yet like some of the geniuses
you know in history some of the geniuses
they went crazy
c'mon is it wrong crazy
there you have it wrong crazy so but
Bart says I don't trust any company but
I prefer baby steps in the right
direction over big steps in the wrong
one okay so do you actually trust what
Microsoft says Microsoft yeah I'm gonna
show about that so Bart Bart says by the
way I don't know if you knew but Lewis
Rosman the creator of this video is a
professional Mac repair guy okay so
that's him yeah I because okay so maybe
that's that is the guy tsubasa it's not
being able to fix a product is one thing
but making it very fragile and purposely
make it unrepairable is just immoral yes
yes Inbar says do you speak about
theoretical free market because I don't
see a single country on earth with free
market as described in theory code well
I um theoretical I mean I don't know
about you know so what how do I respond
to that I see what you are saying okay I
do see what you are saying because I
believe you are you are again is
capitalism I think okay I think you you
you you think that you know once you
have capital you know free market it's
I mean when we when you talk about these
kind of things there's lots of detail
there's you know there's you know in the
you know philosophical context in
economics context in political context
they all mean slightly different things
when you I mean and also this is a
political subject people have a strong
opinions okay so they say oh you know
you are doing oh no you are wrong but
you are wrong no but that means other
things you are wrong you know so and
also the very concept this topic you
know it basically we need the proper
context should be economy okay when you
talk about well yeah you call me freak
free-market capitalism when you talk
about that you know truly today modern
society nobody understand economy nobody
you know unless you study for years you
know you have a you know you have a
degree in economics then you understand
some you know just just some you know
there are a lot economics professors do
I do I trust them no do I believe what
they say is correct no you know so there
are several experts in economy called
economists economists in general I don't
trust them because because in academia
what you know especially in political
topics you have these experts but they
are not they are they cease to be honest
people you know even though they are
expert in this subject they become like
politicians they they get bought out by
politicians you know politicians or
corporations say oh I'm gonna give you a
you know a few million dollars a year
you gonna you know say it's things that
that that's favorable to my company
known to to to the system I want things
like that so economics you know experts
especially those you see on mainstream
news you know mainstream news the
journalists journalists idiots they
often say you know Oh a professor you
know something something economists at
however they do and you know say is you
know with this way or that way that's
that's all typically fake news okay so
so in summary modern economics nobody
really understand it any like again you
cannot even talk about you you know
forget all the internet people saying
about economics is they don't know
nothing about it okay that's not that's
my opinion
including me you know including Mia you
know you know very few people know
unless you study for years you have a
major in economics then you know
something about it okay something about
how money stock stock market you know so
it's very complex subject as you know in
modern society nobody understand it then
the other thing is you know also because
it's a very highly political topic so
you tend to whatever your opinion is is
is not is often not not not honest or
you are just biased because because you
know when it comes to politics you are
biased from person to person I'm biased
towards whatever view that's benefit to
me family to family I'm biased towards
you know whatever it's good for family
same thing for race my skin color so I'm
biased towards when it comes to Chinese
for example Chinese people this is true
for you know this is just general the
true for everyone so when when you study
when you study even if you have
economics degree you tend to be bias
towards towards your country towards you
know your country system or whatever so
so this is how to think to say anything
valid about about economics okay but
this but I do have opinions of course
so I mean given the situation then then
then what opinion can you trust you know
so this okay you know I'd so I to me
free market is basically so what why do
I say why do I love free market what do
I think it's the best system essentially
because in my opinion you throw away all
the theories and you know throw them all
away throw them all away then basically
what you have is free market you know
freedom basically I do whatever I want I
create I create my Emacs tutorial if you
like it you buy it if you don't like it
don't buy it I can say how much ever oh
how much ever I want this is a free
society so no force remember no no force
no government incentives no no you no
subsidies you know that free absolute
free market so if you want to pay me
three dollars you know let's say you you
want to hire me to write some tutorial
or something you're gonna pay me 50
cents 50 cents per hour it should be
allowed okay do I want to do it if I
want to do it I do it for you if I do
not want to do it I don't do it
my choice is free market okay so and so
under this is this is so what what I'm
saying is that this is the most natural
system okay this is the most without
government without tribes you know this
is the most natural you know you you
want sex I can give you sex you pay you
pay me okay $1,000 an hour for girls
it's cheaper okay
by the way I'm not gay okay so so that's
free market you know that's that's
that's prostitution is free market well
when it comes to prostitution they
always other issues social issues
because certain things for example you
don't want to people you don't want
people to allow to sell bombs
for example god I shouldn't mention that
word because then the Google censorship
is gonna
you know so so yeah so so free market
forget about you know you you know about
weapons insects that's that's that that
involves other things well anyway so I
think free market is the most natural so
it's freedom you know individual that's
one thing the most natural okay without
government you know but also I believe
in my opinion that is also the best
system because that is the system in
general okay that that makes the society
thrive people will be richer but why do
I say that
but you know because if you ask me my
work in generally that's just true you
know look at America look at China China
become it became a capitalist country
since 1970 1976 also so we you know us a
very you know extremely prosperous China
extremely prosperous today so so so that
that is why I think free market is the
best thing okay now about you know okay
so bath about says you know free market
would be the best system if there were
no [ __ ] on earth well I get what
you're saying you know I can guess what
you're saying but however there is no
alternatives I mean doesn't matter is
like economics or not you have [ __ ]
anywhere okay on any thing you always
have you have rubbers you have you know
you have bad guys you have murderers you
have you know gangs gangsters mafia you
always have that you know so
so guys be careful with the words okay
google censorship I don't want that so
yeah so you always have [ __ ] so it
is not because you know you always have
[ __ ] then you know in many
capitalist countries such as USA you we
see a lot bad things you know bribery
those are corruption so what we want is
legal you know we want a system so
called democracy or you know we want law
you know no justice judges you know to
solve these issues not not just because
they are [ __ ] therefore we throw
away you know we so I mean there is no
alternative
basically so free market if you don't
want that what you're gonna do
communism when it comes to come you know
let's not use that word
okay communism because the day needs it
becomes anything else everything every
person have their own fixed attachment
about what it means because in your mind
you see bad things you think that's
communism in other people in China you
know you actually if you ask Chinese
people you know they they hate communism
you know they don't want it because
they've they've tasted what it is like
yeah and also in in Russia I think in
whole Russia in many of the communist
people countries so anyway what a bug
okay there's a moth so what is so so so
so what is alternative so communism is
kind of communism so what is this I mean
in a large-scale it's basically
government control system it's a
centralized I mean the idea back then
when when communism began you know at
least the economic part of it the
economic aspect of communism is that you
you know you want a central system you
know centralized design so that the you
can't you know so you have a centralized
you know cover
and experts all the experts in a country
on Earth you know they they so they
decide how much how much iron you should
make how much ships you should make how
much bread you should make you know
because they think they are expert they
see everything they control it so it
should be in theory okay it should be
most efficient but you got lots of
problems because because first of all in
fact all the people the experts
so-called experts they are not they are
typically just academic experts they
don't actually know things in local
regions like I know I know things about
my neighborhood how many people you know
what are my neighbors how much is an
apple here how much is a banana here how
much does it cost to go to a movie I
went to watch Batman the other day
yesterday two days ago I haven't went to
a movie theater for like 15 years I've
been to watch Batman the Joker the Joker
movie so you know so this so it so first
first first problem with the you know
the centralized communist economic
system is that these experts gathered
together they actually don't know things
you know of all the country they don't
know they don't have information and
their expertise is typically the
academic type they are not from
practicality from person like if you are
businessman you you know you try to open
store you know all problems you you know
once you you know like I say about like
I said about open source you know try to
open a company then you know all the
actual problems what things you're
actually what are the truth you will
know because then you you're gonna shut
down you close because you know it's not
like what do you think ideology open
source you know you're gonna shut down
you know money so so so when you are
actually you know you if you open my
business you know and also you have
experience throughout your life once you
open a business next year you know how
to do better next year you know how to
do better
so after ten years you you as a
businessman home urchin you know you
know what's the problem you know where
to do things how to you know that's
knowledge but this knowledge is not
expert you know that is not the academic
type all for example if you open a
restaurant you know what's what to do
you know maybe the first year you fail
the second year you know better where to
get food you know what to do
you you know what customers how do you
attract Christmas you know so so when
you have free market kind of thing each
person have control they know locally
near they max is maximize profit to
themselves you need that you know and
they make people happy because if I
don't like your food oh if I go to your
restaurant the service is bad I don't go
there anymore there are other psycho
there you know you fail so so so free
market so again you may in my point of
view that's the best system you know so
but back to the centralized communism
economic system you know you have you
know these academic experts they don't
know things so they fail they you know
they create they actually create the
most inefficient system then you have
company you know you have communication
problem you know that you you trying to
control the whole country like ten
thousand miles away from you you cannot
do that in a huge amount of inefficiency
and also you have the problem a
bureaucracy because you try to you you
you you as an expert you see the country
needs more bread for example or more
cartons for example but you have your
you know your boss your officers you
know you need to tell them all you need
to tell the factories to do things but
then it's so it is a lot of problems
that's one thing yeah so the so the
first problem is that this academic
expert state they don't really it's not
it's that they have a lot of problems of
their own they are not experts of local
you know local
since they actually didn't have the
experience of running a car but you know
running a factories things like that
they don't know their expertise is only
like academic in theory you know
economic production system that's one
thing the other thing I think that
actually was about communist communist
systems is is about bureaucracy like
once you have communist system who who
is the boss that that becomes
immediately the question who is the boss
who tells you what to do then it becomes
basically a Polock political struggle
this is why you see in China in Russia
you have dictators you have dictators
like Keo people you know it happens it
happens in lots of you know communist
countries you have you know because once
you have the ideology of communism
commune it's like oh that is exactly
basically the idea of communism in
principle is exactly the same as free
software foundation okay basically
exactly the same come commune you
establish a group you know who is
everyone you suppose everyone is good
people everyone is in it for the good of
the whole you know but but who is in who
is controlling who is you know decide
who gets how much food to eat you know
in in free software you know you the
past is vicious Tolman he doesn't do
anything he just he just say oh we need
to have free software you know you know
and did he get money but not every
everybody else not me I've been doing
free open-source which software free
software because of the I use the GPL
license for plus ten plus years I don't
get food so that so that is my opinion
about communism you run into this power
struggle issue because once you don't
have you know once you you believe me in
this kind of ideology good society then
you have the power struggle
who is a boss you know in in free market
system you yeah again it's complicated
it's complicated topic okay so in
general I don't believe in I believe I
believe in free market is the best thing
okay so so that's a major digression and
that makes up basically today's topic so
let me write why I think free market is
the best system why I think communism is
the is bad okay I mean besides communism
what else system you're gonna use I mean
you you know maybe you know then we get
into philosophical theory or history of
the world or history of the world or you
know maybe we have feudal system maybe
maybe we have oligarchy you know maybe
we have family controlled system or
maybe we have cancer control system
mafia you know so what what is the old
alternative you know all you could have
you know then some people you know I
know many of the free software type of
people open source they want energy you
know anarchy it's that's another thing
so anyway these political systems and
philosophies is very very complex you
cannot you cannot really make sense just
by talking you know talking which is the
best that doesn't make sense at all
first of all you don't have you have to
you have to have four years study to
know what you're talking about secondary
four-year study that's nothing you don't
you don't have the actual experience and
things so
so what what is the better in my opinion
the better system is that we need to go
through a more scientific based study so
when we say for example when I say free
market is better okay oh when I say
communist is was you look at you know
you look at history you know there are
countries or regions that have practiced
those Oh for example one of the hot
topics is minimum wage minimum wage you
know like how much you know should we
have a minimum pay to you know like $10
an hour or something for people who work
at McDonald's for example you look at in
practice you know many history in
different countries we in many of these
theories we have done that and you can
study them you know by statistics that's
controversial but by many means they
just so many means scientific means you
can look at them then actually you you
can actually do you to find out which is
in general or better so if for example
minimum wage that's another hot topics
related to free market or you know or
socialism or get in general when you
have a minimum wage when government says
that basically then you lose jobs you
know like if I'm a restaurant owner I
had a higher ten people for example
cooks you know waitresses but photos but
laws you know dishwashers hey I was
washing dishes for like two years about
four years ago that's how I made my
roommates you know wash dishes then then
so before minimum wage I can pay
whatever I want whatever I want you know
and if you like to work for me you you
get a job if you don't like it if you
think the pay is too small you don't you
don't take the job free market you know
so suppose our hire you're ten people
now with minimum wage it says I have to
pay a minimum of certain money an hour
then you know typically is high right
because you know the minimum wage the
purpose is supposed to that you you know
the the labor you know the pool people
can think more money you know so now
with minimum wage
I cannot hire ten people anymore because
then it's gonna double or you know it's
double what I have money to pay the
people I don't make enough money so
naturally I have to reduce my the people
are higher so before I have a higher 10
people maybe I hire 8 you know two of
them will be fired nothing I can do
because yeah I you know remember a lot
of people who you know who don't
experience that young people they think
oh you know you are owner you are a land
owner you are apartment you know you own
apartment you know they think you are
rich you know that's not that that's not
that's not generally true you know you
try to open my business it's not like
you can you have a Dollar Tree
you can say whatever you can you it
becomes a super rich boss that's not
like that okay you you look at
restaurant owners you know you open your
company yourself you will see I know you
for example universe right I have I when
I was washing dishes I have a boss
Chinese in minimum wage they have a lot
problems you know in Chinese restaurant
they don't they don't [ __ ] paid
minimum wage you know even if you have
law there are a lot of people they they
pay cash it's popular it's common I mean
if you have any sense of reality you
know as opposed to you being an academic
you know oh I'm a I'm an economics I'm a
professor or something it's there for
this or that you know it's a [ __ ]
crap you just got you think you know you
try to you go go wash dishes yourself
you'll see what how it works you meet
people you will know how actual poor
people thinks what's your life is like
like me okay the [ __ ] [ __ ] the white
people the social justice
you know white people the the minimum
wage or that they create all the
problems they create all the problems so
anyway so ever saying so I I know the
boss you know he's not like oh he's
super rich he can just do whatever he
want it's not like that so when you know
you have minimum wage you cannot hire
this many people anymore so people you
know I'm a restaurant before I hire ten
people now I can only hire eight or even
less you know so they don't have jobs
anymore that end and when you to study
do you look at you know countries with
minimum wage and so on this is actually
a fact I mean oh by the way this is a
fact okay anywhere even economics
anywhere you go this is a fact
once you have minimum wage jobs
decreased then who is a victim you know
I tell you I I you know the the victim
are the people basically young people
just out of fish out of school they
don't have money they own they have lots
of loans you know from the corporation's
from the white people social justice can
they are pushing for minimum wage
minimum wage they they own universities
you know they are the means and they
they have loans you know they know they
they benefit they benefit anyway so if
you are student young you just graduate
you owe a lot of money you know student
loans and all that you don't have job
anymore because the restaurant they want
experienced people now they have to do
they need to pay the minimum wage they
of course then they want experience
people you know you are not experienced
you are young guy you from you know you
don't have any smears you don't know how
to wash dishes before I can hire you
oh yeah well you are new ok I hire you
for five dollars you want it you are
iike usually you know if you want it you
take the job you have make you make some
money you know but now with minimum wage
I'm sorry you know I don't think you
know I don't think you are worth $15 I'm
sorry and I don't I have you know I have
a business I have to pay I have to pay
my employees you know it's not like I
have a money tree so
I cannot nothing I can do other either I
have two choices I hire you minimum wage
and I shut down by by next year my
business is gone then I go wash dishes
you know it's like that reality so
that's the situation so so what I'm so
what I'm saying so you look at there are
so many scientific ways you can study
country's system so what happens but
instead what we have today for example
in in America you have you have you know
supposedly we we live in democracy you
know American the white people they
especially when it comes to China they
want to say Oh China is evil but
basically in America what what we have
is we have this as we know this all
these corporations Google Facebook
Twitter they control information they
control what you say especially in the
past four years it has become that way
you know they control information they
forbid using things about you know
minimum wage you know they ban you they
forbid you from saying women and men are
different they fire you you know then
you have the oil companies then you have
you know all your companies you know the
bank our cooperation speedy ins of
dollars then you have the abstinent
then you have you know Clinton family
they have donation they have tax-exempt
you know all these you have thousands of
these tax-exempt you know how they call
it you know this this these
organizations charities charity
organizations they eat they just eat
money you know you don't do not ever
donate okay not do not ever donate to
anything if you have money you give it
to people people you know you know you
poor people you know you give it to them
do not ever donate to any organized
organization you know you give it to me
hey power to me do not ever donate but
then so you have this cooperation all
your companies
tech companies the giant you know this
mega billion they have you know they are
CEO they make billions like my million a
day they make 1 1 million a day and they
it is they they want minimum wage they
want you know they push for it they have
money they give it you know they want
minimum wage so that for them they feel
better and also you have these
programmers white people [ __ ] the
white people programmers at Google the
social justice part programmers at
Google Facebook they live they make
$2,000 mm that $20,000 a month you know
almost like 1000 a day so they they have
comfortable lives you know and then they
feel they don't they don't know nothing
about economics nothing these
programmers they don't know nothing
about history society the complex issues
they don't know nothing what what they
know is that they have the utopian
vision like the free software foundation
like the open source and help the poor
help women help Africa that they have
that they have a lot so they make cities
much money they have so much money but
they you know they gonna donate like
0.1% to some organization like the and
they feel so good oh man
I'm such a moral person I donated look I
donated $1000 to to these nonprofit oh
you know and they go on Twitter they say
oh I'm going to donate today to some
some minimum wage organization the some
Green Planet organization typically
that's like 0.1% of whatever they make
they feel better they feel they are a
good person and if you have a pinion
that says you know they shouldn't only
think you are evil and they do all they
can to wipe you out they pan you you
know like if you say bad things about
open source they pan you that's that's
what society in USA are like this this
this you know affluent the social
justice to be typically
white people you know another thing
interesting about social justice their
leaders are all white people rich white
people so that's my opinion about free
market and stuff so what so what are
your counter so but but I know you are
pro you are kind of I'm guessing okay I
don't know you to twelve so I'm guessing
you are like and kind of for communism
and or something like that and I know a
lot of people I know because on Twitter
sometimes I see my followers you know
they say they tell me things they say oh
no you are wrong so what what's your
counter - why are you for you know
communism in stuff and we can talk about
that because then today the table is
gonna be you know that's gonna be that
that is the main topic for today so
let's let me read the comments so do you
speak about the theoretical free-market
okay so we talked about that disco D is
great so disco D and disease has gotten
you to what allows you it's just it's
just useful I mean so what what is your
suggestion you you didn't you you know
you should have suggested you know like
like to say something that I can do or
something you know and you know I you
know and you know sometimes I think
there's a misunderstanding because for
me I'm talking so I can talk you know I
can talk ten times faster than you can
right so there is a misunderstanding but
because you to date you know like you
know past three days like you were
saying you cannot post links but there
is one thing you said that is just force
you you kept saying few a few times you
know that you never sing live
you are posted and that that is just not
true so so I didn't you know so I don't
know you know
like what are you saying but if you said
instead you know if you didn't say that
then maybe maybe I would have looked
earlier because right because I mean to
me I didn't I mean the technology gets
complicated today so I didn't notice the
live chat stuff so discord to me I find
it ok because why because because I have
not been into these chat rooms you know
I know there's a lot like I mentioned
you know the exponential technology
growth there are so many new things not
like not like 10 years ago
you only have you know hacker news
reddit and maybe you have IRC do you
have new schools and that's it today
it's like there's so many you can't even
keep up and I haven't been you know keep
you know even if I try to Cuba you
cannot so there are so many Israel you
know there's another guy who follows you
know Israel he also knows you know many
others but I you know you cannot keep up
keep up anyway and yet you know it's not
like in H each time you go to one of
these you have to spend time to learn it
you have to for example at least for me
I have to read Wikipedia about their
nature typically that's what I do I look
at who created it you know I want to
know the background typically then you
try to use it then you have to register
another password to remember then you
have to learn how to use it you know
what you know what like you have to
learn either user interface so it's not
you know it takes a lot of time so if if
you I think you suggested something I
mean you mentioned alternative but but
the okay so that's that's one thing you
know it is just take tremendous time to
look into the other thing is that
the other thing I know so I mean from
your perspective I know what you're
thinking I mean you you are going for
those open source type of once right but
typically they don't have users you know
they like master then for example you
you know I've been there for like five
years now for four or five years by now
it's sucking every way is you know this
open source sucks the the features the
the user interface sucks in every way
and it breaks down every every week you
know every week this instance cannot
post oh you know and every time you make
a complaint you have an army of open
source people they attack you they say
oh you should then you know it's open
source where is your code then you know
they like you cannot even criticize
something broke you know they you get
attacked you know this ideology this
happens so the product is lousy it's
very bad then you have the open source
ideology people people are thinking you
know I'm a master then they are thinking
they are going to replace Twitter this
this brainless completely lost
you know the brainlessly they not renas
like they they are out of touch with
reality because you have people are
master than them
you know I don't know if you believe me
or not you guys okay you have people a
master then when whenever there's a new
new wave of news about master that you
have people open source phonetics
typically they literally now you know
they try to compose you know hey hey
new people who join master then here is
some tips that can help you to you know
to avoid Twitter or something like that
you have a lot of that people they
genuinely you know they think they are
you know they think master day is going
to has the potential to replace peep
Twitter this complete idiots [ __ ]
unbelievable you know unbelievable just
like some of the Emacs users you know
unix/linux phonetics you know and
complete idiocy then why I mentioned
some some technical actual problems for
example instance going down you know
some you use an interface that's totally
idiotic then then they don't see that
they then their reaction totally like
they don't see that as a problem then
their response is like where's your coat
my god this is open source you should
contribute like they totally ignore the
actual problems of getting mastered and
to become popular like they don't see it
they this open source [ __ ] fanatics
they don't they are brain you know it
doesn't work they don't see it instead
they're all their response is that oh
this is open source you should you
should support it you should fire you
should where's your bugs report you
should this or that this or that and
your actual valid criticism nobody
actually smug to it it gets buried ok
it's like that now I know what you're
thinking you guys may say oh yeah but
that's Matt that's Matt that's master
then that's not whatever you you want to
push you know it's this is true of
course of course all these open source
kind of products it's all cost so you
know today I try on the other thing and
another problem is ok so I try whatever
you guys say ok whatever
open source chant forum ok I tried then
next year next year Microsoft bought it
you're gonna do mix your Microsoft
palate then the cycle start over again
Nick you know next year Microsoft
bothered like github then everyone is
like oh let's switch let's what what's
the best one now Microsoft water what's
the next one you forever like I said
before for every in this niche idiotic
niche group go nowhere
what meanwhile 99% of society is is
going you know the corporate crazy crazy
you know Karaka rock corruption Google
Facebook that's right it's like that ok
so do I make any sense at all
so so I would like you know you'd be
great if if we I need so I mean I I
didn't mean to start a flame about open
source but I was just talking about
discord you know for to me I mean you
know me right I being open source for 30
years but to me discord is just
something walks you know it's just this
just use it I mean that's it's that's
that's that's kind of that's what you
know that's what I'm doing because good
morning la cacica so how long we have we
been talking for one hour so what is the
next topic so today today we just been
talking about a little bit about
keyboard then okay close you know one
problem with brave you know right now
I'm temporarily set brave browser to be
my main browser but one problem is that
whenever you open a new tab of the same
of the same page it does not you know it
does not automatically show just one
page so you will have duplicate so
that's a problem because I show in in
browser it opens the same page then
Emacs are showing browser game opens the
same page again so pretty soon I have
like 10 duplicates of I have hundred
duplicates of the same page of different
pages so in Firefox I have a extension
that close to bucket tabs and in Safari
they also have that feature
automatically without installing
extensions so so in great browser but I
think you actually you can actually
install extensions
I think the brave browser they created
few months ago they
they have a way to for you to use
install Google Chrome extensions but but
I haven't looked into but anyway so
today we talked about a little bit about
keyboard the whole switch the whole
effect switch and we talked about the
repair ability of hardware of Microsoft
and Apple the evo apple then we talked
about free market versus communism stuff
like that then we yeah so basically
that's we've been talking about so Alan
says do you make much of paper books no
any opinion on analog stuff film cameras
record players yeah I do have a lot
opinions on that heaven heard you flame
hipsters hipsters before like what do
you mean hipsters hip hips hippies okay
like what do you mean by hipsters
so anyway paper books I haven't actually
I haven't actually read books for like
15 years ten years like beginning in
2002 basically I stopped buying any
paper books it's all digital beginning
around 2002 because I'm kind of you know
when it comes to tech when I was very
progressive progressive innocent not
political sense but very progressive in
the sense that like like you guys say
you know like for example today you have
fish our new show you know I was you
know I was I was I was very progressive
choosing you know the best technology
the latest that's better in computer
languages like that so so since about
2002 I stopped buying any paper books
but then it's basically about the same
time I stopped working you know you know
company so gradually I become poor and
poor and after five years
yes I don't have money to buy books even
so I haven't read paper books in fact if
I read paper books today it's usually
strange you know and this and also we
and mostly I just been reading Wikipedia
Wikipedia as being better in but better
so there's any question addressed to me
when you get different players nations
are varying by different rules so about
digital versus analog I always you know
I'm always like pro digital because
digital is simply simply the better
technology technology wise it's simply
better okay but however it's you know
it's digital versus analog it's really
it really has a lot consequences it's
not just about technology because you do
have a lot political and social
consequences for example with digital
books then you begin to have this
situation where corporations can erase
your hard disk you know if they can
erase the books you bought digital books
or digital movies you know they can
control you have digital you know
management controls things like that
when while on the other hand if you go
analog you have less of that you cube
you also have that but much less big you
know it's it's harder so that's
associated problem with digital so on
one hand digital is truly really just
it's just better it's just I mean I know
for example there are some people CD
players when CD came out it's all
digital digital music but however you
have this high five you know high five
the classic high five people they have
phonorecords they insist that the phone
record has actually higher quality okay
I think that's that's all [ __ ]
maybe back then when two CD came out
that's true but digital is simply better
is it will become better it will become
better and better you can sample you
know you can have quantification oh you
know did you know basically there's no
question about it this teaches digital
is always better than analog always okay
doesn't matter I mean so in in audio you
have this old high file a claim
otherwise but but not today
you know then you have synthesizers
people they say Oh analog synthesizers
is warmer and so on but actually that's
also push it it may be true today but
but digital technology fundamentally is
speaking there is no way for analog to
beat it okay so yeah but so but but but
but again but socially that you you have
kind of lots of baggages with digital
because then people started to have you
know corporations they can control your
movie you movies or books you bought and
also for example monitors you know back
then 20 years ago in 1990s you have this
an analog plug interface from your
computer to your screen its analog
signal for your monitor okay
then teach it how became popular okay
then you started to have digital so
let's look at digital monitor interface
so I think it there's an interface
called dpi that's our list
yeah ditch DVI okay this is the earliest
interface between your computer and your
monitor DVI interface this is this began
around yet 1999 so this is the first one
so this is you know you can see it's
actual plug so when it came out you know
back then I was working
at companies so I have money you know
I'm a yuppie and I'm a program you know
yeah you know so I was like the king of
the era that that that there was the
dot-com days so I was you know so I
started to buy monitors I want these you
know digital so back then you have this
this
I don't remember what's code now this
plug this what was it called this god
you know after so many so after 10 20
years you forgot the name yeah that's
actually that will happen to you too
what is that frog name code VGA right
VGA cut obviously VGA [ __ ] VGA stand
for visual graphic video graphic
something I forgot anyway so this is a
first digital interface digital visual
okay it's the with this interface you do
not have the what's called you know
digital rights management thing you
don't have that at least when it came
out it you don't have that okay so you
just plug in you get pure digital
interface fantastic you know because
with analog you have to do lock a lot of
conversion like back and forth you lose
quality and so on but then then Apple
created their own ok Apple created their
own but after a few years then the HDMI
came up this nasty HDMI and in fact
today is the standard like actually we
can click directly here DMI okay DMI is
basically the standard today for TV for
your computers DMA and it looks like
let's see
okay it looks like that wait wait is
there a new 100 am I like to outdated
HDMI I think it's HDMI yeah yeah it
looks like that okay yeah but uh it does
this is this yeah this is TV I to TMI
but the plug looks like that right so it
looks like this okay right this very
port is another thing that's apples I
think that's another that's another
thing that's Apple thing but D th d H
HDMI is is the standard it's like use
everywhere between PC Thunder board is
and another thing Apple Apple keeps
creating over the head anyway HDMI is is
common standard between high-definition
TVs or your computer or any monitor you
buy but this this has building like
digital management control basically
basically it's nasty okay I don't know
too much technical details but what I
can tell you is that the signals
transmitted in this cable is not it's
not an actual digital signal anymore
it went through encryption and all that
so you cannot for example if you are a
if you are into if you are a electronics
expert you know you rec tronics nerd
you cannot just cut a wire and get it
get the get the video signal because
there's there's lots of encryption you
know the protocol is going on so that's
nasty so in order to use this like you
have you need a distich decryption chips
things like that so so you see this
happens because this happens with
digital things you know with when you
have digital then you get you started to
have these things
you know so that's my opinion about
digital and stuff
Apple Apple has their own you know Apple
create this DisplayPort and thunder
board and things like that
in general Apple you know their stuff
it's actually technical better
technically better but they of course
they have lots of their you know they
they have their proprietary stuff and
they have tight control things like that
they sell you know they they say oh they
are dongles you know about that Apple
down goes let me show you
fo down goes you go to my keyboard block
you go to design you go to Apple dongles
you know the same tongue go you buy from
Apple it's like you know they make a lot
money with these tangos they sell you
know the same tango if it's ten dollars
but if you want apples they sell for $30
that's generally true for everything
about us like two times or three times
surprised but well but if you are a
programmer typically you work for
companies especially in the Bay Area
here in Google Facebook Twitter you know
you have money you you just buy Apple
you know you you want you want you want
an apple logo on your stuff you know
it's like a show of like like you don't
you know you know it's like a show of
you know you you do that and meanwhile
your mouth is like talking about open
source yeah I'm the open source
proponent oh yeah I could get github or
get revenue but meanwhile you you are a
scumbag you work for Google and you own
Apple you open laptop you go to stop
Starbucks you know you you show off
that's what people do that's and that's
how you get girls to actually this is
actually true this is so this is
actually fundamental part of sexual
attraction
you know females they look for they
choose their mate and typically they
look for they they look for mate that
that in short reach okay you sure just
just like the common saying in rap you
know in rap songs you can you can hear
it and sometimes you don't believe it
because oh and that's not true because a
lot of girls they actually look for you
know high quality you know the love and
so on actually actually the number one
thing females look for is money you know
isn't it's not necessarily the way you
think okay but but it's like implicit
like like if you don't have money for
example let me put it this way then you
understand if you have if you don't have
money like me okay or think of some some
homeless people on the street okay
and suppose you are a girl a white girl
whatever you know or whatever you know
if you are younger you will not think
about
oh that homeless guy maybe I should talk
to him
okay never okay it's like that
okay money so when you see a guy you
know you know the young guy at Starbucks
you know opening laptop so my app Apple
stuff in Drive driving you know driving
driving Tesla and stuff you know then
you maybe you'll say hi hey hey hey I
think you know you know you start to say
hi
do you want to see my Emacs config money
so I think that's it for today
so DP says I discovered that and read
your website back in 2005 or 2006 oh my
god
Flatwood then Alice in Wonderland great
reads Wow so you have been you are you
have been reading my stuff since long
time what motivated you to put these
texts online
do you have more well because I it oh
let me comment something else so you
know you guys know me but I don't know
you guys that's one of the issue with
being being popular you know I'm not
exactly too popular but you know I'm
somewhat well-known among some
communities like Emacs you know so so I
so so you guys know me but I have no
idea who guys who you guys are so like
like DP I don't know so now I know okay
so you've been reading my stuff for a
long time but all of you like I have no
idea at all so so sometimes that's a
that's an issue you know so anyway so
thank you for checking out my website
and about about okay so about that now
it's on my wordy blog okay so why do I
put up for example if you go through you
know such folk Saudi wordy English then
you'll find my literature linguistics
writing related blogs so this blog says
the duo of vocabulary the depth of
literature the question of style the
logic of linguistics the years of
English and the cue by writing so that's
my tagline so in this you see a
collection of classic literature you
have Arabian Nights your flatlands you
have time machine these are basically
world literature's you know
very popular so do you have a modest
proposal eating children that's been
talked about on social media in the past
weeks
oh my god today you can't believe what's
coming up Jonathan Swift eating children
then you have little right Little Red
Riding Hood which is basically a sexual
story you have by the way if you read
The Little Red Riding Hood you want to
read original okay not not the later
versions you wonder you want to read
kind of the original by the way so I
everytime I you know I I put this up
because I I read them and I'm interested
in them so I wrote about them and I also
looked into them for example what is the
background of this story where does it
came from Little Red Riding Hood who
wrote it you know things like that so in
this case a the Little Red Riding Hood
he began I mean it's not like one author
wrote it it's not like a rather it came
from folklore folklore you know then
then a writer collected kind of like
that and edited and made a version so
this version Charles Perrault wrote from
1697 you kind of consider it as original
there's no I mean we could you know it's
it came from folklore so there's not
know one author but this this one is
kind of like the original that began to
spread so you so when you read them you
usually you want the original version so
anyway so so what's what's about this
story this this Little Red Riding Hood
is very much sexual and when you read it
so this is 1697 you read it you
also learn history okay so so you can
see how you know like this is 300 years
ago what people are thinking oh what is
it like if you have a movie that's 300
years ago what people want to see you
know things like that you study you read
you know you read it not just for the
story but you also read it between the
lines no because when you read a story
300 years ago you can learn you know you
can you can you can see kind of what
people are thinking you know things like
that so anyway that's about that story
Little Red Riding Riding Hood and also
this artwork this artwork is also kind
of original so this artwork is by this
very popular woodcutter or artist
Gustave doré okay so I have a little
collection of his stuff by the way today
it's all on Wikipedia
so you can read a lot about it on
Wikipedia so discuss stuff though from
1832 to 1883 he'd you know he's a very
famous popular artist back then he drew
you know this classic oh these are very
you know very classic stories for
example these stories about Andromeda so
today you have a lot novel science
fiction's that's all named on dromeda
you know you have game games or game
game companies that says named Andromeda
you know so that many of them came from
Greek 2,000 years old stories on dromeda
so it's very interesting to look into
that's how you learn that's how I
learned about society history communism
capitalism that's how I learn about
these things you don't you know
typically like today today's people you
know you think oh I want to learn about
it
makes so usko study you read a book
about economics okay that's okay that's
not bad but typically the book authors
they have they have their own bias and
opinions you know and some and and often
half of the time the books you read they
are just they are typically are just
propaganda okay they are just propaganda
you know they are just authors who wants
their spread to who wants to read to
spread his views or he got paid by
corporations you know he's an economics
professor he got paid by by by Exxon you
know your company about you know by
Google by whatever you know about then
he talks about green planet he gives his
opinions about whether solar panels who
is gonna save the world or not you know
he's gonna talk about theories and he's
you know jog and say no that you know so
that that happens about so you so so
another way to learn about all these
things is you you studied you know just
different things like you know you you
look at you know this quick mythology
this author this artist painter and this
you know story written 300 years ago
not just this way and from different
authors from different countries you
know and quick mythology 200 years ago
you start to get a picture of humanity
as also what is a general situation you
know it's like that so that's that's
kind of how I learn things because I
don't have a college degree I went to
Community College over here back in 2000
by kin year 19 1991 1991 to 1993
Community College
basically means it's very cheap and
basically that's equivalent to the first
two years of university you know so I so
I did that I don't have a degree so but
then for the past you know 20 30 years
for the past 30 years I learned things
including math programming on my own and
also about kind of history and human
humanity philosophy literature writing
on my own I started to read for example
these kind of literature things starting
around 2002 that is when you know I I I
read them I also annotated oh these okay
all these on my website for example let
me continue to build a fire
this is a short fiction by Jack London
American author very popular American
author Jack London to build a fire which
is a great great story short story you
can you can finish it in in 20 in 20
minutes
great story to build a fire then you
know in many other famous stories so and
I annotated them cool of us travels this
this is actually very boring eyes you
know I made them I also annotated them
they takes tremendous time so let's see
so you can see my annotations in these
boxes these fresher so let's turn on
okay so you cannot turn on JavaScript
anyway good Ava's cool Ava's travels I
find it super boring but what I also
learned is that in good OVAs travel you
know this is written in 1726 okay so
it's like 300 years ago when you read it
you can see you know again that like I
said you want to read or the original
version not not not the children's
version or the watertown version okay
those are or those those are all kind of
they are not they are not cool averse
travels anymore they
they are complete different completely
different in nature to the original work
complete completely different they are
not not about what you know what the
author is trying to say so vote for
example Disney Disney Disney will have
lots of stories like about guru verse
travels about about Mulan about you know
the ACM rule and about ponta hoon you
know Punta hometown you know the Indian
you know it's a fairy tale it's all it's
like oh he has nothing to do with our
original story whatsoever in fact it's
like it's basically like American
propaganda basically all the stories you
know the about same bird about Aladdin
the Disney stories like they are they
are they are kind of like Americanized
very much Americanized things like they
removed anything from the original
culture disliked totally removed me
recognized you know it's like so if you
watch Mulan oh you know whatever Chinese
story Mulan I can tell because I'm
Chinese or if you watch Aladdin which we
which is about kind of Middle East
culture you know the Disney's version
version are added what you see what you
see is American heroes American story
American culture American ideals like
like the democracy good versus bad what
is good what is bad everything is
American except except the characters
you know the moon and we were dressed in
Chinese you know Chinese whatever the
Chinese sword or Chinese you know and we
say in the American see it you know say
oh that's Chinese culture then when they
see Aladdin
everything is American except their you
know you know they have they wear - you
know turbans or whatever you know oh
that's that's Islamic culture Oh multi
culture we need to support multi culture
it's just pure pure white [ __ ]
American okay that's all the Disney
thing
so anyway back to back to Jonathan so I
have actually so you can see I have you
want to read this if you want to read
Aladin you know you have to read this
this one by Sir Richard Burton I did a
video talking about this so anyway back
to the bull goola goola verse travels so
this story 300 years ago I read it I
find it actually boring okay over I will
not read it again but however you tilden
you do learn some things you know one
thing I learned is that this is very
offensive
okay very offensive now you know they
were talking about this sky
okay this so so he's a giant okay he
went to different places so you have
some places that small people you know a
little people like you know a few inches
okay so one so he so in one of the story
one of the thing I don't remember where
so you know the cream you know in this
small people country the Queen's castle
or whatever the Queen's palace is
spurning so this guy he's a giant
you know he's gonna help the small
people so he just take out his penis
okay he just piece piece into the
Queen's quarters to Taos House the file
so it's you know and this is now
remember you have to remember the
historical context so this is packing
300 years ago
17:26 in England now you know back then
if you say anything like that you get be
hated you know something like that I
don't know I don't actually
you know I don't know the UK history
that much okay but I kind I can kind of
feel you know you don't you cannot say
those things back then you know you say
it you get killed
yo your head get chopped off but he
wrote that so he wrote you know this guy
Jonathan Swift
you know seven
20:26 zero this supposedly fantasy you
know so the Queen's quota is burning he
pissed off he just pissed it off you
know he takes his penis out and just
piss it and then quite a lot you know
it's a curse another you know so you
know you can go to Wikipedia then you
can read about you know the context you
know the then you'll see what you know
the author's intentions things like that
you can read that okay that's you know
that's kind of the academic take oh you
can read it you know just just read this
story yourself then think about you know
give your own impressions then after
that then you can go read Wikipedia
about what you know suppose these
scholars say about this work and you
know things like that you form your own
judgement first so that that is why I
created this so beginning in 2002 I
started to spend years you know many of
these takes a year the for example this
one takes a year to two years I you know
I did this you know throughout several
years but if you do it full-time it
takes a year to annotate things like
that so I spent you know this years
reading about this and annotate them
Gulliver's Travels in the trader tragedy
of Titus Andronicus this one by
Shakespeare so that is why I did them
because I like I enjoyed the stories
that that is like that
so I think that's it for today anything
else I think I've been talking for 19
minutes I guess yep so that's it for
today
one more minute any questions I'm gonna
shut down thank you for putting stuff
online thank you okay so this is the
right time to mention if you like my
work paper okay PayPal
patreon you know the stuff Amazon
giftcard you go tuck sorry dot info I
have you know patreon links things like
things like that you don't have to but
you know if you walk you know then you
be good okay so what else so did I miss
any comments you should read up on a
difference between digital and analog
music what do you mean you know my take
about that is basically digital digital
will just feet analog always you know
like back in twenty years ago you maybe
you have quibbles about digital you know
this sample nada did they were there
just may actually be better as we you
know if not it's for music I think it's
already better it's already maybe not CD
okay but yeah because because if you
study these issues mathematically
there's no way
analog will be better no way because you
know yeah okay that's it for today thank
you guys for coming so what about part
says the point is that there is a
physical difference between analog and
digital ways no no because for example
in digital music you always you can
always actually it is true today when it
comes to headphones when you come to
speakers you're you have to always
convert it back to analog so then you
got analog I mean in the end it's analog
there is no way to create digital wave I
mean yeah because the sound you know the
the molecule you know the sound of the
OTL sound is is from from basically
shaking of the molecules kind of
so in the end you converted to analog so
but there is no way to convert from
digital to analog well I think you are
true and you God you know you mean you
might be right I mean what so what I'm
saying so if you are if you are a expert
on these audio suppose you you being a
audio engineer for years and also you
are a hardware engineer so suppose you
have a master you know you know about
your running you've been running a audio
studio for recording music and also you
happens to be a audio nerd you happens
to be a electronics nerd so you know
actual those resistors the ohms the you
know the the electronic circuit you know
all that suppose I mean there are people
like that they are quite a lot you know
so you are you are a audio engineer
suppose you are that person and I can
you know I I think I can see that some
of that people some of those people will
say audio is better in some way okay but
I would say not all you know because
when it comes down to with fundamental
principles there's no way to beat no to
beat digital there is no way to be
digital because in some because even in
some sense if you study the whole
universe in some theory you could say
it's all digital you know because for
example if you study cellular automata
they you know you go look up salute our
mantra you know digital you look up in
the world digital universe or theories
theory of digital universe USC Holocaust
but you so you in my my tech is kind of
that if you go by principle there's no
way to be to beat kind of the digital
way of thinking because
because once you have digital it allows
huge amount of possibilities that's
otherwise not possible
yeah there's a physical disk difference
yeah but okay that's it for today thank
you guys for coming
so when one teachers a wave always we're
down to one sends Eero analog waves are
always gradual yeah but the problem with
analog you see bah but the problem an
ERG is that we cannot it's not precise
you know we have lots of problems we you
know when you have electrons flowing
through the circuit or wherever it's not
digital you lose quality you lose
quality you have lots of problems if you
want to put you know if you want to
boost the signal if you want to you know
anything you do or even if you it
travels a long distance it loose crowd
quality you lose you know you have a lot
of problems and also yeah you kind of
like that we are talking about no we are
we yeah so so yeah also depends on what
kind of product are you talking about
okay that's it that's it for today okay
I think yeah 40 minutes I'm getting
tired - what 1 hour and 40 minutes thank
you guys for coming thank you guys for
coming that's it for today bye guys that
yeah digital versus analog that's the
interesting so maybe we talked about
that whoa
because then these are the things
interesting about piano about things the
sizes hi guys