hello welcome to another episode of EX
talk show today we are going to code
wolam language on PL tilings mathematics
geometry topic so you see this is a
wolam language mathematica
notebook that creates Tidings you know
the Decor Decora patterns you know there
are many uh aspect of Tidings you can
think of it as de the mathematical
aspect of decorative Tidings for example
this Islamic
styled uh you know tiing kind of Windows
pattern or ceilings pattern Islamic
Church pattern so and they are you know
these other symmetry graphics and these
graphics for example you will often see
in uh Christian
church so mathematics as mathematical
aspect of tilings and patterns okay so
this is a package I wrote back in
1997 and I'm going to work on it going
to update it you know after 20 years
lots of changes in wfam language um so
mathematic mathematical Tidings and
geometry I'm gonna code today so it's
probably just going to be boring for you
and let me so for example here is uh
another my website where I
um you know so these Tiding patterns
okay let me show you some example
chicken
wire okay this Tiding patterns okay some
examples of Tidings and patterns
beautiful can you see me if you are here
say hi Okay so so I'm just going to code
it and it's probably be boring but I'm
just I'm going to explain the things
what I do uh what I'm going to do so if
you are interested in mathematics in
geometry in the tiing subjects or
patterns Symmetry and if you are
interested in mostly wolam language
Mathematica um you know uh you might
learn find it interesting learn a thing
or two so some more Tidings this is this
is cido uh scope uh I don't know if you
guys younger people have seen it cido
scope is a toy you can twist and you can
see this kind of fourfold symmetry
patterns okay made out of mirrors three
mirrors like arranged in a triangle
fashion so you can twist it and you can
see
Kaleidoscope okay in fact I haven't seen
a
kaleidoscope um for a while you know
when when I was a kid 30 years ago 40
years
ago this is uh juice and wine juice and
red
wine so this is uh Tiding and patterns
again this is kind of like Israel
star and the more Islamic kind of
patterns and this is a a modern one
Islamic
patterns okay and another Israel star P
pattern and here is uh there's a name to
this pattern actually um actually let me
let me show that okay
so uh tidy in some patterns and here is
all the others you can see so let me
show you a picture about that uh oh okay
so here is also
interesting uh this I got somewhere but
anyway let's go back I want to focus on
the code okay so this this book I highly
recommend this is the best book on
Tidings and patterns uh very rigorous
mathematics based okay uh this is like
the the book okay the tiing and patterns
by the mathematician G Gan and Shepard
you know when I was younger in the '90s
I actually emailed them oh I think maybe
right email I think I email them and
they sent me a bunch of Publications
their Publications in mathematical
journals because I had some questions so
you know when I was younger so you guys
younger people you know go out and do
whatever you want to do okay make your
life Rich be a mathematician or be a
professor or whatever is your goal uh be
a great programmers or whatever don't
waste time don't you know do memes and
you know stuff social network so anyway
Tidings and patterns this is the best
book I recommend you buy it it's out of
print but the do publication published
it again so it's on Amazon now I believe
let's see yeah so uh 34 fairly expensive
let's see hard
cover Tidings and patterns yeah okay so
this is somebody else sending their copy
uh
anyway so I highly recommend this book
okay you go out and buy
it uh okay let me post my website if you
are here say hi okay I love to see hear
you uh Tidings and pattern book let me
post to the chat hello
o okay so Tidings and patterns I
recommend this book and let's see what
else uh yeah so I wanted to show
you so I wanted to show you uh uh that
particular okay so let me show you some
of these things related to Tidings and
patterns okay so okay so open that I
already showed that um open that open
that so you know it's been 30 years and
I've been now working a lot on
Mathematica on wolam language uh some of
the these are extremely beautiful okay
so let me just go over and introduce you
some of these Tidings and pattern the
mathematical aspect of it
okay so let's see uh yeah so this this
is one of uh this is more serious
mathematics I wrote in
1997 on discontinuous groups of rotation
and translation in the plane this page
actually got cited by lots of academic
Publications or academic Publications
journals or in workshops you know back
then so this is about 1997 I wrote this
article so uh theorum on rotation and
translation so this this the the the
subject of this page is about groups so
group Theory that's part of uh abstract
algebra okay so yeah I recommend that
you read this so it shows you it gives
you a taste of what is abstract algebra
if you haven't encountered it yet
typically group Theory abstract
algebra if you are an engineer or
physicist you are not likely learn it
you know but if you are a math major if
you are studying math to become a
mathematician or math major in
University you typically study group
theory in your third year of college
which is usually after calculus after
multivariable calculus after
um multivariable calculus after
introduction to differential equations
and after linear algebra so you usually
after you have linear algebra then you
have a course on Modern algebra also
known as abstract algebra or simply
algebra as opposed to high school
algebra you know high school algebra is
like you solve equations
x² equals to 3 what is X you know that's
high school algebra
but which belongs to the proper you know
algebra but anyway abstract algebra
which is what what you study when you um
after you study linear algebra linear
algebra is like a part of
it so anyway so let me show you some so
this this um so this for example why is
it related to tilings you can see in
this picture in these pictures this this
is a classification of symmetry of any
possible wallpaper patterns okay so you
classify you know for example you see
this this pattern is reflection so you
can see the red lines are reflection
lines and this pattern is
reflection both horizontal and vertical
and you also have rotational pattern
like right here so you rotate fourfold
rotation so every time you rotate this
wallpaper 90 degrees it becomes uh
180° it becomes itself so you have
twofold
rotation so then you know so there are
several others so I mean these are all
possible
symmetries and this in mathematics we
call this wallpaper
symmetries so and uh you know the more
beautiful ones are
sixfold sixfold rotational patterns like
this okay so for example we uh we
actually encountered several of these
you know
so you you go to a random one so this is
sixfold rotation one this is fourfold
rotation so
anyway
so all in all there are like 17 possible
uh of them 17
possibilities okay so anyway so these
are some of the you know
examples yeah so let me show you then
let me show you the um um okay so this
uh and and then we have wallpaper
Gallery okay so this page shows each one
of these 17 possible symmetries
wallpaper symmetries using only one
single Motif that is one single pattern
the star the Pentagon pentagonal the
five pointed star okay so you can see
the background image is a w paper and
this embedded image shows you the
Symmetry illustrate the symmetry of this
wallpaper so in this example you can see
you have vertical symmetry of lines
that's called mirror symmetry or
reflection meaning that if you reflect
the line in any of this one you know any
of this line the wallpaper becomes
itself so you have reflection symmetry
any vertical line you also have that for
horizontal lines and then you have a
fourfold symmetry like like like right
here like in the center so meaning that
every time you rotate around that point
90° the whole wallpaper become itself
rotate again 90° the whole paper becomes
itself so fourfold rotational symmetry
then some other point you can see over
let's see uh let's say where is
that over here okay for example over
here you have a two-fold rotational
symmetry meaning that at that point you
can rotate the whole paper around that
point
180° then it becomes itself but not 90
Dees okay so you see some of these
points are fourfold symmetry some other
points are two-fold symmetry so that
makes it you know quite
interesting so let's see uh you know
let's let's go to the next
one this this is a bit more complex
example and uh you have fourfold
symmetry and two-fold Symmetry and uh
the most beautiful one begin with
threefold symmetry like this one so you
can see at each point many points you
know here here here you have threefold
symmetry that means you rotate 1/3 of a
circle the pattern becomes itself okay
so this is again wallpaper symmetry so
you can
see this wallpaper is kind of simple so
at any of these triangle points you have
threefold
symmetry however you do not have
rotational symmet I mean you do not have
like the mirror symmetry like there's no
line anywhere on this wallpaper that you
reflect it it you mirror it it become
itself there's no search so this is
purely
threefold symmetry you know so that's
you know and and using the star as as
The Motif very interesting so let's look
at next one
uh can you press AR or no okay so again
so this this this is like before you
have many threefold symmetries like over
here over here over here you know many
three-fold symmetry but but this one you
also have reflectional symmetry for
example along this vertical line you can
reflect it it become itself and then you
have also kind of you have several such
lines okay so very interesting pattern
so this again these are about
wallpaper so if you want to look up
Wikipedia search for
wpaper groups
okay wallpaper groups you see Wikipedia
you know back then they you know there's
no Wikipedia when I wrote it so but
Wikipedia has become you know over the
past 20 years uh literally 20 years
Wikipedia began in 2003 so Wikipedia
become very rich so you can learn what
is this wallpaper group you know what is
it about why is this like like a simple
you know carpet pattern have so much
mathematics this is about group Theory
okay there's so much mathematics in
it uh and you know group theory is one
of the foundational very uh important
mathematics one of the most important
every mathematician doesn't matter what
field you have to know group Theory okay
and uh the wallpaper groups is one of
the best example to to learn about about
this uh group Theory okay they used to
site my website I don't know if they
still do uh they don't anymore uh but I
think they used to you know site you
know
but but Wikipedia you know after so many
edit they copied your information and
they replaced and your the citation is
good but anyway they did a good job so
you
know so okay so that's about wallpaper
let's go back to what we uh what other
things uh let's go through this and then
I'm going to start to talk okay yeah
let's finish this a few
more so
anyway okay that's okay so you can check
it out so
next uh this these are about uh plots of
trigonometry equations okay very
interesting but but it really doesn't
have anything to do with today's subject
about Tidings and and patterns okay but
anyway so for example this plot is this
equation tangent times tangent and
tangent sign x / by X time tangent and
argument is tangent time y so you know
very interesting
okay uh let's see next so we were
talking about this package which is
which I'm going to work on
today uh let's see yeah so some features
yeah so next uh this is another
interesting thing but okay this has
somewhat have something to do with our
topic today which is patterns okay so
this pattern is got a rotational
symmetry at the center somewhere in the
center it's like a Tai G but
hexagonal
okay anyway yeah so yeah okay yeah so
for example this pattern you kind of get
the wave pattern you know you can see
kind of wave going out okay that's
interesting and this this is a fish ey
pattern so what happens to how do you
generate them so you start with a
symmetric pattern you know a carpy
pattern then you apply a function that
makes it like a wave going
out and similarly for the fish eye so
you begin with a picture or photo or
whatever your face then you apply a
function which is this function okay in
W from language you apply that function
then it becomes a fish ey lens okay so
that's uh geometric is all these are
geometry geometric transformation yeah
so you typically you know when you learn
mathematics it's very boring because
if you have if you have a good teacher
then it's not boring but usually they
don't talk about but usually the teacher
is not too half of the time you know the
teacher is not too good so you don't get
you don't really learn about this
beautiful uh interesting things about
mathematics in
Geometry okay next uh so we talked about
this before so here is another
interesting this is about transformation
so this this picture for example you
begin with a grid just rectangular grid
then you apply the transformation a
rotation but this rotation transform
transformation is such that you know
when you given a point so when it's near
the center it rotate a bit but when the
points are far away
the the more further away from the
center you do more rotation so this is
kind of you know so then you get this
picture okay and the function to do that
is here okay and this okay yeah so and
here is another transformation this is
almost like a black hole sometimes you
see you know scientific educational
program they'll show photos they'll show
you know images something like that
kind of illustrate a black hole so how
is this one done this one is
um similar but reverse kind of opposite
of that so the more close to the center
the more rotation you do okay so if the
point is further away you don't do
rotation if the point is
further outside of a limit of a radius
then you don't do any transformation at
all so within this circle you know in in
physics usually is called
um uh what Horizon something Event
Horizon something so within this circle
once you pass the circle par uh
parameter then you get sucked in so so
geometrically what you do is that if the
point is out outside of the circle don't
do nothing but if inside if it's inside
the circle then the closer it is to the
center you do more rotation to it okay
so that's how you generate this um
picture uh and you know that's a
description in English but the
interesting thing if you are into math
is actually trying to do this trying to
draw this then you get into coordinate
and formulas that gets you you really
start to learn things okay so I
recommend so
um you do it you know you can do in your
favorite language python or whatever
with the graphical
environment uh
or I can recommend of course my own
tutorial just search for S wolam
tutorial you can do it in wolam language
here is how you can download it for free
okay uh okay so let's go back to
um to what we want to talk about let me
finish then we're going to start to code
okay some of these you know interesting
Graphics okay now this is the wave
transformation like we talked about you
can see it clearly when it's a grid you
begin with a grid then you apply the
transformation and here is another one
which this is like the fish lens thing
this is is like the fish lens
transformation okay and the different
one both of them are like fish
lens uh and this is a complex number
complex inversion very interesting okay
so
anyway so now let me uh so yeah let's go
on to the next topic any
comments uh smart guy
hello the dude uh this would be equal to
implement in a game engine for go dot or
un real engine yes exactly and I hope
someone does
that uh exactly they would be beautiful
in
games you know with some creativity you
can create lot you know games you know
one of the trick about uh let me digress
digress a bit one about one one of the
thing about creating 3D games with these
ideas is that
usually you don't want to directly just
focus on the image you know if you just
show the image in a game like what does
it do like people are not interested in
this yeah okay that's that's pretty and
I mean that's what does it do so what
you want to do in a game is that you you
design the game the game play or the map
you know where you can run into or you
know with this ideas for example this
black hole idea so certain area certain
area if you enter it then you you
there's some kind of gravity that sucks
you in that's how you implement this
kind of idea you don't want to just like
show this picture you know that what
does it do so you design a personel you
don't even show you don't even show okay
this is a circle if you enter it
something you don't do that you but you
do have that you you just don't say what
it is then you have the all all kind of
interesting things can
happen it's about game design okay so
let's go
next um now this one is interesting this
I got somewhere from the web this side
let's see if it's okay it's a
Twitter um
what so anyway this is a this is just
like a
tiling this is just like a tiling we
showed before you know like one of the
two-dimensional Tiding but it's
threedimensional that's what happened
here you see threedimensional Tiding uni
this this one is
called uh uniform honey com I'm not sure
that's the technical name it looks like
it is so anyway in mathematics you study
this kind of thing you study the
Symmetry you study how they repeat and
in fact this is actually Applied
Mathematics
is it's called cryst graphy
okay Crystal graphy so we can see okay
you got xray x-ray Crystal graphy so you
see molecules are arranged you know you
have seen snowflakes you know very
common molecules are arranged in a
pattern
um let's see if they show any
interesting ones
so this very much applied you have to
study you have to you know if you are a
chemist or if you study Material Science
how you can make all sort of materials
and you know today we
have for example
bulletproof vest or nonstick cookwar you
know how do you make them and you know
all this sort of thing uh
actually this page is not at let me show
you a more appropriate page Crystal um
Crystal graphic
disorder Crystal structures
okay so yeah Crystal graphic disorder
okay Crystal structures okay so this is
like the three-dimensional symmetric
pattern this is what how
molecules crystals are bound so you have
to for example if you are chemist uh you
know chemist you need to know what are
the all possible mathematical ways for
points and lines to arrange themel in
three-dimensional space in a symmetric
way you know because that's required to
know I mean you know once you know
mathematically what is possible it helps
you a lot in figure in figuring out how
how the crystals actually the molecules
actually arrange itself you know things
like
that so so this is mathematics you know
in particular geometry you see lots of
math very
interesting uh so if you want to study
this kind of thing for example like
today the Tiding and stuff I'm talking
about usually you don't study that in
college I mean usually there's no like
one course teach you about this subject
okay so this subject belongs to Geometry
group Theory and Symmetry and tidings
and patterns okay so mostly belongs to
abstract algebra but if you are a math
students if you are a uh PhD student
usually you don't even you know you
don't encounter you don't there's no
course that actually teach you this you
see because University they they can
only teach you so much things you know
and typically the mainstream fundamental
topics they don't you know so even if
you have a math degree you may not you
may not have heard of uh this this kind
of thing you know if you are not doing
you know chemistry engineering and
Crystal uh studying crystals things like
that
okay so yeah okay so that's I think
that's it about these uh various things
Tidings and wallpapers Okay and this
image is a a Tiding on a sphere you know
another variation so this is a Islamic
pattern uh and this mathematician I kind
of know him a bit you know I talk to a
Canadian what's his name uh Craig Craig
s
kapan now he's a mathematician H got
dead
link uh okay that link let's just search
for his
name you know he's a mathematician who
specialize in this in this uh Tiding and
symmetry okay he actually that's his
specialization so if we search I mean so
he's an expert in this topic so let's
see if we can go to his website
um yeah so this guy this photo this
photo is old this photo is like 20 years
old anyway he's a Canadian mathematician
okay very
interesting uh and apparent yeah he's a
professor now yeah
so let's see what else uh
so download language okay uh not found
close close uh yeah patterns on a
sphere uh and here is another
interesting variation of tiing and
patterns now this one is interesting
because for two reasons one is it's fral
okay so it's recursively nested in in
some sense okay so you have a pattern
but unlike a you know unlike a ordinary
pattern uh oh God we have so lots
of you know unlike these just ordinary
cpet patterns or wallpaper patterns
they they are unusual in a sense that
you never seen it before before let's
say before 1990s you never seen a fral
pattern in human history you know
meanwhile the other patterns you have
seen you know you might have seen you
know it's possible you know um you know
this pattern is possible but but facto
is kind of like a
new it's very interesting in a sense
that it's it's a new idea like human
animals don't know this thing before
before 1990s say so it's a factal but
also the other thing interesting about
this one is that it it actually show you
the Clockwork mechanism beautiful okay
and there's another one this is done by
now I don't know who did that one uh but
this one is done by this
Sky okay so you know
yeah very
interesting uh so let me show you okay
so the most popular
guy about creating artworks that
illustrates the beauty of mathematics is
this guy a Dutch guy MC Asia you know
you probably have heard of it um and
these are some of the my favorite of all
his work you know I have a collection of
his work a thick a thick coffee book you
know it's somewhere I forgot but anyway
I have you know so this three I would
say probably is my favorite artwork of
MC aser out of all
his um artwork
okay and one one of my favorite planner
one is this one but fly so this one the
pattern itself also shows another
interesting variation so you
see you can see it's a symmetric
rotational symmetry fourfold rotational
symmetric pattern but however as it a
things gets near the center it it become
it shrink into it you know it kind gets
smaller and another and this so This has
something to do with uh um you you might
model it with um hyperbolic geometry
okay hyperbolic geometry you can look up
Wikipedia you can find lots of other
pictures um anyway that's so that's a
math topics you can uh get into deeply
for you know you can get a PhD in
hyperbolic geometry and so on so anyway
but so this picture is interesting in in
in
that one it's um um it's this kind of
hyperbolic thing the closer to the
center Things become smaller that's one
thing now the second thing very
interesting uh and unusual about this
one this artwork is that if you look at
the pattern if you study the pattern
closely okay so let's open it you know
if you study the pattern
closely you can see that
they
you know the the circle you see this
four red circles then you have these
four yellow circles you you can kind of
see a some sort of
symmetry how these colors are arranged
you can you see there's a blue circle
here out out of all these butterflies
you see yellow circle red circle yellow
red then on the Outer Outer one you have
green circle
then you have blue circle then you have
red circle oh wait green blue so is
Cycles green green circle blue circle
Green Circle Blue Circle then if you go
outer you have red
circle let's see red here and yellow
here okay and red and yellow and red and
yellow again two two
cycles so that's you know so it's quite
amazing how you know they col part of
the butterfly to create this kind of
color patterns uh very
interesting so MC okay so then let's see
next uh there's didc okay so there's
another one uh this is also kind of
interesting also in a different way it's
actually this is a plot of a complex
function okay but they render it with
marbles so you got you know this very
interesting by this guy Doo okay they
call it doyo spiral plus mobus
transformation okay then another thing
is tiing and patterns is very much tied
to uh braid Theory knots and braids so
you can see this is a weaving of your
clothing you know you know actually I've
been looking into clothing and textiles
you know like to a modern man like us
you know we wear clothes every day right
underwear or whatever but have you ever
looked at how how is it made how what
kind of thing can make this right you
have cotton you have silk you have you
know or blue jeans you know how do they
cotton is kind of a plant right H how
how do you get the pattern into this
this thing right so textiles that's a
tremendous deep topic the history of
textiles then you get into nighting
night uh nighting and weaving you know
and and this kind of beautiful cable KN
this is called cable how do they
pronounce this word knit or
night I always say it night so anyway
beautiful so amazing in mathematical
thing you see and then then you have
this thing how do how is it possible you
can see how intricate and uh delicate
delicate and intricate it is these
patterns and then you have this Chinese
knots you know uh patterns and tidings
okay all these are Tidings and patterns
related to and then you have this CTIC
Celtic knots which is
a uh kind of Northern Europe CTIC
tradition you know they they draw these
kind of
things and then you have this modern
rendition okay now this this one is
interesting worth commenting on so this
one so on the on the overall on the
whole you can see a pentagonal star
pattern
right that's on the whole but if you
magnify right you can
see it's made of links and weaves it's
made of weaves you see this this thread
trting going
around very complex very interesting you
see and then you know how are they how
how is it made what is the structure of
this
weaving I don't know so uh and yeah so
weaving okay so very interesting
mathematical pattern that's why I find
them fantastic
amazing okay then we have this one this
one like we've seen before this is
pretty common you can you can create
random
ones uh and then you can this animation
shows you how it's done you know you
just have a bunch of squares on each
Square you can have you can draw a
pattern you know connecting the to the
sides
then depending on how you Orient Square
you got this you know different patterns
this this thing is called trenet tiles
okay it's got a
name and then you have a
threedimensional
version now that was my girlfriend
sleeves in Second Life about 10 years
ago 14 years ago so we went in Second
Life and we build this you know and then
you have threedimensional
version uh created by her in Second Life
second life is like a virtual
reality okay I think I think I covered
all of these now it's 47 minutes
actually I was going to code the the
paining pad and you know I was going to
code my package but uh let me show you
let's start wolam language but now we
already talked about Tiding ins and
patterns for 1550 minutes I think I'm
not going to code it
anymore okay anyone
uh can you start solving Millennial
price problem on the stream are you
kidding you know to some of you who you
know I suppose many of you are going to
YouTube watching shows you know you
don't uh you are not a mathematician or
maybe you are a math student okay so
anyway for most people watching online
online stuff uh they they watch YouTube
mostly for entertainment right most of
most people so when you see mathematics
there's quite a lot mathematics YouTube
channels they talk about interesting
mathematical things you have no idea
what they actually are I mean to you it
seems oh my God these people are so
smart it makes sense they're talking
about these things it makes very smart
threedimensional space time travel oh
Jesus this or that space black hole what
happened to Black this that Wormhole you
know as a
Entertainer I mean as a as as someone
going for entertainment you know going
to YouTube you know you find them
amazing and smart people but you don't
really know what they talking about like
you have no idea um unless unless you
are a math college student or physics
you know study phys Physics physics you
know in a college then you have some
idea this one is good uh tutorial on on
on the nature black hole that one is
okay then you can start to tell
this one is just pure drama no content
black hole this black hole time
travel okay but you can tell if you
actually studied some Physics even even
a beginner then you can tell this is a
good video it actually teach you what
what is you know the black hole or
chemistry or you know so I mean the
point is that if you don't really have
haven't studied any of these let's say
let's say calculus okay if you haven't
really studied calculus or group Theory
you you you have no idea what I'm
talking about you just think oh this guy
must be smart beautiful Graphics right
but you don't actually
know so you are asking about manial
price Millennial price yeah I hope I
hope I can even understand the problem
okay that's how that's that's the
difference
between what I know and millennial price
problems okay there are about 10
Millennial price problems you guys some
of you may not know let me
introduce Millennial uh
price okay there's a Wikipedia okay
there there's about uh 10 problems I
think each one if you solved it you get
1 million1 million US dollar okay
actually that's pretty small because if
you are the someone who can actually
solve this problem you are wor you are
worth more than 1 million okay people
want you more than 1 million easily okay
but anyway anyone of this problem you
got 1 million problem okay now let me
tell you how I understand so you can see
you can get some kind of
context okay you know this level of
mathematics this level of programming
you know you know if you don't know
anything about it you think it's all
over your head but if you read actually
just know a little bit you can tell
these different levels okay so the
millennial price I can tell you of all
these 10 problems let's just say 10 I
don't I don't understand eight of them
like I don't even know what they are
asking okay and if you want to
understand just just simply understand
what is what it is that they are
asking takes you
like four years okay four years uh to
understand them okay like okay let me
explain Point CL conjecture okay that's
one of them uh Birch and S conjecture I
have no idea about that Nava stroke
existence and smoothness okay go solve
it you you get one million P versus MP
now as a programmer I'm a programmer I'm
more of a professional programmer okay
now a lot of people have might have
heard of this P versus MP and it's kind
of
dramatic
but most people have some idea what it
is about but it act for so for for me
for example I
don't you know you you have some idea
what it is about but it it's it but it
comes to the question of do you really
understand what it is
asking most people
don't uh no I okay I I'll
say I kind of know but not not really
okay so I understand kind of what this
problem is
asking but if you push me I cannot give
you I cannot be precise okay all all
these all of these problems are very
precise okay you can like you can you
can you can you can write a mathematical
equation like that that says that can
show you what you understand like give a
concrete example so this one p versus MP
I kind of understand if you push me
within a month I can truly understand it
within you know a
week okay like I spend three hours a day
you know I can truly I can start to tell
you and I can teach you what this is
problem exactly what it is about okay
not just with vague idea oh P just means
polyal time NP means non polyal so some
problem polom can you use it then you
know like hand
waving most programmer 99 out of you
know let's say one in
10,000 I would say one in 10 one one in
100,000 actually understand this you won
unless you actually you know read it
anyway so next problem WR Raymond
hypothesis again again I understand the
problem the problem is find the zero um
let's
see prove that all zeros of this
function lies on a line something like
that the r zeta function is a function
whose arguments may be any complex
number other than one and whose values
are also complex okay its analytical
continuation has zeros at the negative
even integers Okay negative even
integers -2 -4 -6 when you give these
numbers to this function the result is
zero okay that's what it means these are
called its trivial
zeros however the negative even integers
are not the only values for which the
zeta function is zero the other ones are
called nontrivial zeros okay now the
rment
hypothesis is concerned with the
locations of these non-trivial zeros
okay so in other words you are given
this
function you want to find you know this
function we know if you give it
-24 -6 the answer is zero okay but
however there are some other numbers POS
you know like shown in this graph there
are some other numbers that the output
is also
zero the problem is prove the real part
of every nontrivial zero of the r zeta
function is one over five uh one over
two okay so the real
part uh let's see the real part
um
Yeah so basically saying it's saying
that you have to prove that every one
over four I mean every one over
two of a complex number whose real part
is 1 /
two maybe I
mean okay it's a bit complex to phrase
it it's it's saying that that all these
other zeros that makes this function
zero the input for the for the function
that makes it zero is such that the real
part is always one/ two okay so you have
to prove
that now the the r yeah so I kind of
understand the problem but you know you
look at you you take a deeper look into
you know what what is this function you
can't even fathom okay this function is
you know a zeta function the input is s
okay s what is the output the output is
that so you sum these numbers so 1/ one
raised to S power + 1 / 2 ra to S power
+ 1 / 3 ra to S power to Infinity okay
that's not too hard yeah but so so you
have to sum this infinite sum
then whatever you know you input as then
whatever output is a result okay of this
zeta function so this Zeta hypothesis
Raymond hypothesis is saying
that you want to find all the zeros of
this function okay so you know so if you
have studied complex
analysis uh even a basic one then you
understand this problem rayon hypo
hypthesis for example another this one y
me's existence and mass Gap okay I don't
understand it you know I don't even try
because that's a physics related to
physics okay I I'm not I don't know too
much about
physics okay R hypothesis I know I know
a bit m p versus MP I know a bit Navia
Strokes that's another physics thing I
have no idea what it's about us usually
differential equations okay H uh H
conjecture I I believe that's uh a break
variety very deep topic it's mathematics
pure mathematics but I have no idea like
you take me few month to just just
vaguely understand what what what's it's
asking okay that's what I'm saying
so so when you look at things you don't
know usually you have a impression oh
that's for example juggling okay let's
random let's talk
random
uh and that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching juggling okay I have a page on
juggling let me tell you something about
it
um okay uh here's my favorite juggling
balls now so Ball Juggling um I have
collected many videos about juggling
because I was into juggling so these are
many of these are the great you know uh
juggling uh I have seen I've seen a lot
I've seen basically all possible uh so
anyway some of these are great so do you
juggle okay so if you never are in the
juggling Community you don't know
anything about juggling so all you see
most frequently question is how many
balls can you juggle right you don't
know I mean that that's like the common
question how many balls how many balls
can you do oh you know five six six this
is better because it's got more you know
six right then but yeah yeah the then
then you this this three Ball Juggling
okay this three Ball Juggling is far
more difficult than six balls okay this
guy uh this guy um Victor key is a one
of the top jugg okay he works for S used
to I I don't know about now juggling is
like uh Sports when you get old you are
kind of
done um usually you know and I mean it's
a age you know very much related to age
you know beyond certain age you get
older you can do it so anyway so
juggling so when you watch juggling in
you know when you watch circus you have
Unity cycle you have juggling some
juggling balls some juggling clubs some
do a Cheno that's the most idiotic you
know Cheno and the apple and bowling
ball okay but you have no idea it's more
difficult than the other you have no
idea to you when you see a chance so
that oh my God that is most difficult
but you have no idea you don't
know only when you actually spend time a
week a month to juggle to get into the
commity then you can you then then you
know right away which one is actually
the difficult okay which one is just
drama for sure okay gets the most
Applause you know the most dramatic the
chaino and apple you know the tic
same thing for mathematics okay
that's what I'm saying same thing for
mathematics same thing actually same
thing for programmer programming like
many of you are programmers right you
get people asking you can you fix my
windows my windows got this problem can
you fix
it that's it for today thank you guys
for watching uh okay so yeah so let me
show you the package so this is the
source code for the package um that's it
for today
no let's show the gallery okay so this
is a wolam language
code okay
so oh wait uh no this is not the package
I'm talking
[Laughter]
about oh yeah so tiing and patterns Okay
so so we actually we got
a so PL
Tidings uh what the
okay let me show it and that's it
for
today okay so so this is this is the
tying package I was going to code today
but we already talked for an hour so
that's it so let me just show it so that
at least that we get something to
run uh I need to do a backup
first
okay any
comments
okay so I need to load the package so
here is the source code for the
package
uh open it in wam
language so here it
is so here's a code those are
documentation
and OBS Studio connected okay got a
little
problem okay uh but that's it for today
thank you guys for watching if you like
my stuff PayPal me okay go to
kali.
info
s. info you can see my
website
then all the way down there's my patreon
Amazon gift card PayPal or you can buy
my emac
tutorials uh I had some delay in sending
out Emax tutorials few people about it I
but I did send out so my emac tutorials
or my um JavaScript in depth okay thank
you guys uh for watching
bye
fantastic after 20
years still
works let's see there some some these
here some beautiful
ones okay that's a illustration of
symmetry
groups okay then this is a illustration
of the kollider scope fundamental region
this region is called fundamental region
because by having this region you can
create a whole pattern by just
symmetry okay so let's run it let's see
if that
works oh it does okay the graph is a bit
more
different let's see
magnify
fantastic and here is some random
pattern oh oh it
works random pattern so that pattern and
uh this pattern has this
symmetry okay but why is it black and
white it's supposed to be color that
means I need to fix it
something I think it's supposed to be
color okay let's see what's more
interesting
so here is a hexagonal Grid or
triangular grid here is a square grid
but with a pattern a certain symmetry on
the coloring of the
dots uh and here is
another he is a a hexagonal Grid it's
like a triangular grid but very
variation okay here's some patch weaving
so we started to do some weaving some
Islamic patterns let's run
it uh kind of snowflake patterns okay
honey comp then a very interesting Arrow
uh
thing here is a
code uh let's see we can make it code
into mathematical type
set
and then okay that's it
bye