good morning guys good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today's 2019 October 22nd Tuesday
11 o'clock a.m.
San Francisco time good morning guys and
what are the questions Nybo says what is
the best Chinese food is North American
better than Chinese food North American
no I don't have actually I don't know
what is the best Chinese food they are
Chinese food I'm not very picky about
food so I eat anything and anything
cooking restaurant I love it
from any region China Middle East
Italian almost anything Indian I'll eat
it greedily so I'm not very picky about
food and I love restaurant food
hamburgers pizza too but about Chinese
food you know most food Chinese
restaurant in USA they are Americanized
Chinese food just like Miss Mexican you
know that so because if you have real
Chinese traditional food if if you have
the real thing Americans don't like it
basically that's why you have to sell so
you have this Americanized Chinese food
actually just like everything else
almost yeah so-so and I love it too yeah
you know the Americanized Chinese I
loved you know I love it I love them but
however if they are some restaurant in
USA for example in California in here in
San Francisco in Mountain View where
Google is that there are a lot a turn
of Chinese restaurants and some of them
maybe 1% 2% vo kind of Chinese cuisines
by Rio I mean that's what Chinese people
eat in China
Oh in Taiwan there's also time when once
and they you know some of them are and
actually in general I don't really care
for them I actually prefer the
Americanized Chinese food but I do like
them as well and and yeah you know so
China is pretty big
you have several lots of regions am i
alive check ok I'm good
so China is pretty big you have lots of
regions and you know over the past
thousands 2000 years they have different
kind of tastes different kind of food
developed and I don't really actually
know the details because I've never been
to China so some region for example
suchan okay you in English you coach see
trend you know so Tron so that's that's
a province that's known for very hard
things anyway there's many details I
don't I don't know about them and Oh
food is good for me even dry bread dry
bread and milk you know I have I have
obsession on eating just plain food
without taste so good morning guys what
would the example be North American food
P what North American food is North
American let's see what American eats
salad salad is one of the main thing
well hamburgers hamburger is the main
thing they well Americans they eat
various different things
I guess mostly European hamburgers stick
sausages bread and bread is also very
common
and by the way sewing in North America
you don't eat rice okay
well occasionally like once a month
maybe you eat rice that's considered
exotic or something you know advice but
in China every day is like you eat rice
every day every single day that's your
stable in America you know America
sometimes you also eat potatoes fish and
chips UK the UK cuisine so in China they
they you know Chinese in Taiwan and in
China they eat rice every day you have
to eat it and many Chinese came from
China or Taiwan they cannot live you
know it's a habit like like you you you
migrate to USA such so for example of me
how much wealth you would consider me
your first generation like Mike migrant
but many of them other people they take
they cannot they cannot just leave you
know it eat American food like they
cannot they'd rather go back to China so
they have to they eat rice every day in
America as well that you know you go to
Chinese market and get rice buy rice and
you have to cook you cook Chinese food
you know you cook yourself most Chinese
people I would say most to that because
you cannot you know most people they
cannot just eat they cannot change adapt
the the tired unless you came here very
young to the degree that you rather you
know they did move back to China and
okay so that's about that good morning
Kathy pine tea I never heard of pine tea
so Freddie Freeman says good morning to
Germany I've been
wandering about seven goofin spoke a new
kind of science did you read it and and
do you think that it's worth reading yes
I talked about that topics for one hour
for 19 minutes the other day so YouTube
go to youtube sorry
oh go to Saudi talk page okay go to my
website sorry that info talk show and
you have a page full of full of article
titles and indexes you know I've been
doing this for half a year now every day
so lots of topic I already talked about
so search for new kind of science okay
so this is 2019 August 28th let's have a
look
math languages scientific programming a
new kind of science what is random and
cellular automata August 28 so there it
is this is you go to youtube and you're
you know you can watch that that's
that's one hour and talking about that
book but that book is so much you know
it's over 1,000 pages we can actually do
it again some of the day because
covering you know for example I can
teach you so in that video I talked
about new kinds of science and many
other things related to that but one for
example one day we can do a technical
introduction to cellular automata and
that will be fantastic because cellular
automata it's one of the most fantastic
subject especially you know for
programmers you guys are interested in
in cellular automata you would be I
would say and also artificial life it's
you know back then in 1990s I've studied
a turn of this cellular automata thing
and also called back then you there's
another term called artificial life okay
I don't know if they still use that term
so let's look at Wikipedia Wikipedia our
official life
by the way I'm used using a new keyboard
setup let's see if you can see that a
new gig
you
in randomly and any topic can go and
sometimes I start to talk about one
thing that just meant stop so artificial
life okay so they still call that
artificial life insect in Wikipedia you
can see this article artificial life
okay so what is artificial life or a
life well it's it's basically like a
cellular automata it's it's like it's
like chewing machine okay so anyway so
you create so what's the examples do
they have a pictures they don't have
pictures okay
there it is there's a animation this is
a bad animation because they kind of use
ASCII so anyway you know if you're a
programmer you would be very highly
interested in this because it's visual
and so let me show actually show you
another another thing in in 1990s I
tried I looked at all programs through
our 1990s I'm on a Mac so I've looked at
all possible programs out there that
does artificial life and I wrote a
review I use them for month I was you
know into it's so fun and I read reviews
about them for example let's go to saw
math some ass okay there you go
so many math topics fascinating topics
and you go to math software keep the
comments coming okay you go to math
software great math software and now
they have categories so cellular
automata would be you have factors you
have dynamical systems you have cellular
automata and this is fascinating this
this this one is written in JavaScript
let me show you that so let me show you
this one this week this is written this
is recent 2016 written by a computer
science student yeah and she okay turn
on JavaScript oh it's already JavaScript
this is Google Chrome
it takes some time to load to load
because because I'm running video so
there it is you see that is an example
of cellular automata okay she has also
written game of life but on a hexagonal
grid and here's some other variation
variations so it's fascinating you know
you just see how they evolve so let me
give you an introduction to cellular
automata then do you guys know cellular
automata
so is it like game of life yes it's like
game of life let's see how should should
we do kind of explanation yeah I should
you know but but look at her it's
beautiful you know I must I need to
write that this is my forte but but I'm
getting old I you know it's a fact that
many things I wanted to do in particular
programming projects you know I
procrastinate for years 1 year 2 years
all Langdon's and that's actually one of
the thing I wanted to show you and she
happens to have it but however she is
doing it doing it on a hexagonal grid so
this is not original lanterns and so
let's see she point to Wikipedia right
she points to Wikipedia so this is
fascinating you know so let me try let
me try to explain the lanterns and LEL
what does I mean yes beautiful Kathy
says we are actually a movie my text
workflow into Emacs day by day
excellent regardless of the criticism of
skis and skis and skepticism
for my code appears so Freddie says I'll
check it out yet then I have another
question when do you think art is art
okay is computer-generated are the same
word as art by humans oh my god I have I
need one hour to talk about that art and
the as in particular the idiocy of of
what Saturn let's see the idiocy of
generative art have you guys heard of
the term generative art again I'm
starting to digress I need to shoot
generative art by programmer idiots they
have this thing about generative art let
me show you an example what they had
look like this this this okay is the
computer the many of the programmer
idiots they love this gen generative art
it's this is no art okay this is not art
this is just this is just random to do
to do tutoring by by programming this is
like this the equivalent in real life
would be like you splash a packet of
piss onto the wall and that would be odd
this is the same thing except it's done
by probe computer by programming
generative art you know many programmers
idiots they love they they do this and
they say oh my god this is odd look at
my creation that that is my opinion
about that and and on that topic what is
art we we were we can also let me just
finish that topic quickly so for example
you have photography you have
calligraphy you have typography those
others are not art okay they they are
kind of semi quasi art photography
calligraphy and typography those those
are cabbage
and so okay what what is art art is
there's no definition okay you could you
could call any of these art there's no
actual there's no scientific
scientifically precise definition what
he thought okay anything human do is art
you you take you know you take a [ __ ]
your [ __ ] comes out hit on the ground
its shape is art okay you could say that
and in fact I'm pretty sure some artists
it did exactly that you know so there is
no actual definition of art art is the
thing art is the thing human animals too
so how do you qualify how do you define
it
art is first of all art is something
human animals to such that has no
definite purpose okay that that would be
my definition something something like
that I need to refine it art is
something human animals do that without
definite purpose and and usually well
this is something like that okay along
the line so so there is no precise
definition what is odd
what is not odd because once you defy it
it kind of ceases to be art that's
that's that's the point so this kind of
thing for example the generative Genet
generative art so iiii i don't consider
name art because so first of all so my
definition of art is like art is just
something human animals do without
specific purpose but however so why is
this not not art for example that's the
same thing when you take a piss you you
use your piss to paint some words that's
also art but so how do you distinguish
so art you know it's hard to define I
have to like I'm going to I'm doing this
often I'm going to start walking you
know go outside and take a walk and
talking to myself in a monologue about
about how do you define art what is art
come up with the definition talking to
myself then I will have the answer I can
give you more precisely what I think is
the definition a good definition of art
but alternatively you could look
Wikipedia you know there's you know
human history it's big so many great
thinkers have have tried at least to
give a definition anyway so I don't
think this this this out garbage okay
same same thing with photography clock
calligraphy and typography those are
those are belong out of proportions also
graffiti graffiti is one of the idiot
donkey ass thing loved by many hacker
type of people I mean okay among hackers
many of them are the Indus sub culture
subculture underground thing they love
that I know many of my followers are so
you know that that's when these people
for example they love honor ki they love
you know this this underground thing
Bitcoin
and all that and many of them we all
love graffiti they they get excited okay
Fiji's crap so what I can tell you okay
I can tell you right off what do I think
is great art art a good art piece of the
great good piece of artwork is one that
requires skill okay second let's go back
to generate generative art let's see if
we can go back to that okay I don't want
YouTube close it so for example that
generative so a great art in my
is one that requires years of skill to
develop in order to create it for
example scope classic sculpture okay
painting painting sculpture drawing even
illustration like Japanese comics books
or American comics book those are called
illustrations you know the typical in
art community they don't consider those
art they they like they did they are
dismissive towards illustration kind of
artwork you know like comics books
anyway so what I consider great art is
that require a serious of mastery skill
to master it and you can do it the for
example classical sculpture painting
especially realistic ones and require a
walk and also programming is kind of you
know some some people consider it art
like the download news and many the
hacker types they love to think Oh
program is art you know for example
Donald Knuth wrote he spoke the art and
science of computer programming right he
said the title you know there's art and
so in fact I have articles about that
sorry what is art
what is science this is one of my post
to new scoops it's it's a flame okay
it's a it's one of the my ode articles
that what is art what is science I don't
think you know it's you don't see it
because it's not a popular article it's
just me ranting so anyway so with
have I digressed enough Oh
Ahri's for ganda okay so let's go to San
talk show
let's go through my sock code let's go
to programming then on the left panel
you will see anti hacker year 2k most of
these articles are written in early
2000s around 2000 to 2010 so let's
search for art there it is is
programming art Oh science
dear friends you mentioned the title of
Donald Knuth's magnum opus art of
programming in a context of discussion
that fringes whether programming is
science or art I am quite pissed off at
work at the moment so let me take the
time to give some guide on this matter
to the daily programmers at the bottom
runner programmers there is no question
about where the programming science or
art because monkey coders could not care
less these folks and be reading this
post for they heart B we all have heard
of Lisp now this is post this is posted
to complan Lisp so among the list
programmers to year 2002 so so then I
continue this this leaves us with this
leaves us with elite programmers who
have a smattering of interest on
cogitation and philosophical conundrums
so is programming a science or art ok so
this is my 2000 year 2002 kind of flame
you know the you know people say it's
true
ok well no it's not true ok this piece
of essay is art okay so is programming
out of science so let's so that's that's
that and what did we talk about today
cellular automata okay let's lanterns
and okay let's magnify okay let's get
back to the hold on second Genet
generative art in fact I have argue
about that what is odd what is not odd
and I mentioned photography calligraphy
typography okay and I have a article
about that so let's talk about that
let's let's just talk about in this
direction today how artists propaganda
what is the opinion of Donald Knuth
do you ever did you ever met a guy yeah
well I didn't meet him but I saw him
three years four years ago at the
history of computing Museum down here
it's a kind of well known Museum in
Mountain View so if you come here you
might visit but it's kind of boring and
sorry I saw him for you know yeah I saw
him I didn't go talk to him he's very
old you know he's like 80 something he
can barely talk coherency but back in
the 90s I would be so eager to meet him
you know he is in Stanford over here
Stanford University which is 10 minutes
drive perspective drawing okay so what
what are we talking about so we are
talking about art what is art generative
art okay so let's see if I have let's
see if we can find the Arco
paste enter
okay I have a article on that but you
cannot find it by search because because
because it's a you know it's a random
essay nobody actually look for it you
know the the the things that's popular
on the web are the things everyone wants
to know things like how do you do
something in Python how do you you know
like a tutorial but when you write
essays about you know philosophy
nobody's search for it nobody look so so
let us go to goal and find go
so this : script is 180 lines and
basically the functionality of this
script is grab you know find text in all
files or directory so let's type
generate generate let's type generative
art and that's such for it the net will
get the results let's see if I can find
my article so back to so we were talking
we need to talk about cellular automata
heart and let's see Donald knows I
talked about this in my past videos
I don't download news and his walk input
you know in computing in programming and
computer science is not my type so
whenever he has opinions I don't like
his opinions I don't see eye-to-eye with
him he the the way he write books his
style I don't like the things here he is
interested I'm not interested okay
that's Donald Knuth
so you know there are quite a few other
well-known computer science I liked I
talked about this before for example a
Stefan Wolfram the the least inventor
McCarthy the quite a few you know I
gotta like I don't like Donald Knuth
you know I need not is not my type he's
he's walk you know his work I don't know
how he is as a person but however he's
writing his writing style he's you know
his jokes I don't find funny like yeah I
like his stuff
okay so we have generate generative art
here and let's have a look let's see
it's done okay so sapphire output mod so
it's colored so there it is generative
art so indeed open the file show in
browser so this is programming blog 2018
much let's search for GE and e ra okay
okay I don't have much articles about it
just online so so generic generative art
equals two piece please smash Plus
programming here's history of processing
ok processing processing is the language
it's a programming language that does
generate generative art okay basically
it's a language that focus on drawing
visual drawing processing and they are
kind of you about those languages so
processing is somewhat popular you know
it's there is a community processing and
it's also it has been ported to
JavaScript so you can actually code
processing in JavaScript as well
so here's history of processing the
generative art programming language for
non-programmers non-programmers yes
it's Java anyway so here is the article
by by this guy I don't know who is this
guy okay Mac max sorry
so it says okay the title is like
research essay research essay the
history processing it's crap okay so you
know you can read the article I don't
recommend it actually you don't
recommend this this is generated
generative art it's garbage actually
this one is not bad actually this this
one yeah you know this one to me
it's garbage but it does have some sort
of aesthetic to it but you know so the
you you know in art this you would
classify this as a abstract Modern Art
you know in those basically in my
opinion my you know in my opinion those
abstract modern art or garbage you know
like a bunch of lines and different
colors red blue squares that's crap
you know why why they rise up art art
what are the community community just
like every other community just like in
a corporation in in politicians you know
in government you have a power struggle
you know who is gonna get more bread who
is gonna be you know get more money who
is gonna get more pay who is gonna be
more popular and you gonna you know for
example in politics you have ABCD efg
politicians you know each has different
viewpoints and you're gonna support for
example today you have social justice
you have chomped you have you know this
or China you know China you have Russia
you know different political parties
different opinions about different
things certain you know typically it's a
case you like this guy but some of his
things you other things you don't like
and that guy
you don't like but there's one thing
he's opinion you really like you know
things like that very complicated and so
so our community community just like
pilot you know politics or corporations
in your corporation you struggle to get
a raise you know to get to become a
manager you fight fight with your
colleagues things like that you know
backstabbing and all that same thing in
the math community you know
mathematicians I don't like your math
you don't like my math we fight you know
I get I try to get you fired from from
being the head of a publication of
University you know they do that in
science is to and you have different
personalities different characters some
are greedy some are a slime some are you
know as kinky as kissing how do you say
that you know as kissing to climb the
ladder they you know they are career
career lists you know they do anything
to give themselves ahead then when they
are top they you know they they do they
do things you know so so then you know
there are some characters who are just
like Richard Stallman inflexible and you
know you know and you know doesn't give
a [ __ ] about any other thing so anyway
so in science you have different
personalities you know all these
different communities same thing without
community there's power struggle so in
my opinion okay this is this is just my
opinion I don't have solid research into
it in my opinion this modern abstract
art let me show you some examples of
modern abstract art usually they say
abstract modern art okay
let's look at the pictures oh yeah
garbage you know for for this garbage
crap abstract Modern Art it hurts my
eyes okay this is some of them are part
of famous like they are a few of them
like a super famous you know they sell
for example the same some of the old
paintings they sell 400 millions of
dollars you know that's actually I have
article on that but so so so so so there
are some famous cases okay there are a
few people who become extremely famous
for like like you would call them you
call them the father of modern abstract
art there is Wikipedia article we can
find yeah okay so let's go to Wikipedia
and Jesus is this this [ __ ]
Robert de Lune II the loonie Robert the
loonie this [ __ ] you know it is
these kind of things know every way okay
so they hold on a second I mean he not
said too much random things let's try
you know I still want to be what what
are they doing this this is crap okay
this is Wikipedia doing propaganda you
know they started to put in a Chinese
painting in in the article abstract art
okay they didn't say modern but they put
into the article abstract art so as us
to solidify as to you know
prove that abstract art has long history
even in China this is this is false the
garbage Wikipedia this is example of
Wikipedia doing propaganda okay if you
actually know Chinese in you know
there's no such in Chinese culture okay
there's no abstract art okay they put
these two you know the actually this is
this looks like a mountain this is the
guy I'm not 100% sure about this but I
can read you know like they put a title
abstraction in early art in many
cultures my ass abstract art is a
creation of Western society not in many
culture earlier in in early art and many
hit culture my ass propaganda from
Wikipedia and what is this you know they
so they they they put this into abstract
art to insidiously this is not abstract
art at all you know another thing about
art is that in in the art world you know
each one is an artist you know if you
are an artist there's nothing you can do
okay these these are abstract art you
know abstract art arose from 20th
century it didn't [ __ ] you you it's
it's fair to say didn't [ __ ] exist
before okay so here you are seeing
Wikipedia are doing propaganda you know
they try to come up with some some early
abstract art so anyway so this 20th
century yeah those this is abstract art
and then that and that yes indeed this
this crap these are abstract art indeed
it is [ __ ] idiots and and oh yeah
this one is the is the one I had in mind
this this you see this guy this guy a
very famous you probably have seen so
what's his name
Mondrian tota the composition
number ten responding feet above his
cameras fainting by by the artist Theo
van osburgh [ __ ] idiot okay so so
that's modern abstract God so what what
was I saying I wanted to say oh yeah so
so why did you know there are some of
them okay so Wikipedia shows some of the
famous ones for example you can see the
names here they you know sometimes they
are called the father of modern abstract
art or or you know the pioneer you know
like like this guy this this Theo von d
osburgh DOS book so so in my opinion now
I'm not sure about this but it's it is
my guess okay yeah I mean the question
is how did they become popular how did
they you know like this this guy you
know some of the founders they would be
considered gods you know in the art
community like they everyone they become
idols so how did that happen the
question is how did this garbage become
you know like sacred sacred you know how
did this garbage become sacred in our
world it becomes like a movement becomes
you know meanwhile it's purely garbage I
have theories about that okay again this
is my opinion so I think this happened
is because it's a power struggle you
know just like in sciences in
politicians in corporations among Europe
you know you among your brothers
you fight for power you know you fight
for who gets more pay who gets you know
who become rich things like that so the
reason these are like this became a
thing and the people become idols in my
opinion is because power struggle you
know nothing to do with art it just they
are able to with the help of luck okay
they are by chance you know he's
events nobody can predict so they happen
to become powerful and they made you
know made they made just you know they
are almost like crackpots okay
just like in Scientology in Scientology
you know the codes many codes you have a
leader they created a they created a
thought you know they created
Scientology you know what you
Scientology Falun Gong and you know many
many coats you know around the world
they typically create you know Larry war
for example in programming in
programming community we have Larry wall
we who created Perl and who have lots of
slogans and jargon who says laziness is
one of the great vote virtue of
programmers and and you know and there
are more than one way to do it you know
lots of jargon slogans this [ __ ] so it's
the same way in my opinion it's the same
way these people became popular it's
from just by political struggle there is
actually nothing that qualify their
workers you know waiting anyway that is
my opinion about this thing and you know
just like in history and lots of other
things you have you know doing certain
years you have some Sun some movement
for example in history of science you
have phonology you know phonology have
you guys thought about that phonology
okay there's a Wikipedia article about
that but let's look at the images you
know so phrenology is that you you know
this is a pseudoscience today it's known
as pseudoscience so the back then it's a
big thing it's like everyone believed it
like what's their belief I forgot what's
their belief in any you guys know so
let's read Wikipedia article
so phonology is a pseudoscience which
involves the measurement of bumps on a
school to predict mental traits okay
yeah that's that's it basically so but
you know so in 1982 eighteen twenty okay
so what what is is the discipling okay
so developed by german physician Franz
Joseph gall in 1796 the discipline was
influential in the nineteenth century
especially from about 1810 until 1840
the principal British Center for
phonology was Edinburgh where the
Edinburgh phonology called Society was
established in 1820 okay so it's a big
thing back then in the 1800 1800 s you
see it so in a sense oh you see this is
a piece of history this is a piece of
history of science you know where you
have this scientific thing phonology
everyone believes you know you have you
have Edinburgh phonology called society
you know like like the British has you
know the philosophy philosophical
society you know basically the greatest
greatest scientists gather together in
there so you know so here is a piece of
history of science and in my opinion and
we you know you can see this is the
total garbage you know history in my
opinion this this is the same phenomenon
abstract art you know some some the the
movement the abstract art school it's
the same thing same way okay suddenly
you know the political situation is
right then suddenly you arose some code
or movement like like today's social
justice scan okay
so that is my opinion about modern
abstract art and about art and about you
know the generate generative art you
know this generative art garbage you
know this idiocy history of processing
okay so that is about that now shall we
go back to you know so regarding odd I
have actually a lot of things to say I
have you know articles about typography
calligraphy and we can talk about
calligraphy and for hog Rafi that's you
know anyway it's a the basic my opinion
about it basically I just talked about
that's like that same you know this
apprised typography and calligraphy and
photography they are not arts okay
photography for example for how goofy
it's just so why why did photography
became art you know maybe not today but
in the 1990s for example it used to be
considered you know one of the art you
know photography photography basically
it's rich people who has money to buy
cameras and they do things and they want
to you know they want to think of it as
odd okay photography and also journalism
Journal you know the journal
photographic journalism you know you
have a turn photographic journalism you
know so so so they are how did they
arise what they are they are just power
struggle just like the just like the
phonology and you know the of modern
abstract art in my opinion it's a mix of
power struggle and movement and
pseudoscience you know coat it's a mix
of those
so you then you become the photography
as art and also in the 1990s you you
know pong we don't have as much phone
back then so photography make - so when
you have pong you call it photography
okay it's a one way it's one of the way
that photography
the world photography grew was odd you
know basically people just want to work
to look at naked girls okay they are not
interested in the art of photography my
ass but many people you know they do
photography art you know that's part of
the way to you know chalk chalk up
photography there's a history you know
is and also yeah photography is not odd
okay because back there back then for
how goofy equipment expensive you know
you have to be rich to do it you know
not like today everyone you know you
have a phone everyone has a phone you
take you know you can take a thousand
photos a day you know 100 of them is
gonna be greatest art walk in
photography but photography back then is
what was the it's you know you have to
buy those you know only rich people
Playboy's can do that kind of oh you oh
you buy photography equipment and you
you profess to be a journalist like you
know oh crap
so you know it also you know these kind
of things movements also needs to be had
to be in the right time because you know
for example in let's say in in early
nineteen hundred's you don't really have
journalism needed you know you cannot
travel around the world because you
don't have airplanes yet well not
popular yet you know you can't just
travel you know so so you don't even
have journalism yet so you know things
dangerous time got progress as you know
technology technology is the thing that
for
everything technology progresses use you
have airplanes you know airplane becomes
common what travel becomes common you
can go to Shanghai you can go to Tokyo
you can go to London you can go to New
York Big Apple you know so so that
becomes common then then you start to
have journalism you know you you start
to go to places to write about things
you know you report then journalism
becomes a thing you not journalism
itself is also crap okay the proper term
is just called reporter you know brain
less reporter not not journalism Oh
democracy democracy needs journalism
know the [ __ ] go [ __ ] yourself
journalism are just reporters brainless
reporters and we need them that's true
but not not the way Americans see it or
we need German journalism ok this so two
things journalism they are like they are
you know the what journalists to they as
far as job intellectuality goes they
they are the brainless brenes low okay
low like you mop the toilet at
McDonald's you go wash dishes in your
Chinese restaurant ok getting paid less
than minimum wage okay by cash that's me
that's that's that's the same class with
Journal journalism ok you like today you
have Harvard you go to Harvard to study
journalism communication crap these are
people reach people you know why did
this happen why did why did Harvard you
know this this this I've every tower you
know I read how Ivy League colleges has
this communication you know it's a study
major communication generally journalism
because that's that's the way that's
money like I said like I like I kind of
my opinion my train of thought about
abstract art about phonology you know
the way these things happen is because
power power struggle and you know it is
like actually it's like cellular
automata you know it's just like you
have certain basic rules and things just
happen you know you never know what will
be the shape over here you never know it
just happens you know this is humanity
so anyway so how about you know
journalism yeah so I don't regard them
as great or important what what is
important for democracy well you need
general education you need a good
education for every citizen you need
honesty yeah for mastered majority of
people you have good moral moral or
ethical principles for most people and
that's that's it you don't you know
that's that's about that's what you need
for democracy or rather for a good
country and you know so okay okay so
let's see let's read the comments and
see where are we where am I going
and and whether should I talk about
cellular automata again you know we
haven't we digressed and we haven't
talked about cellular automata so
actually some of these other was
articles I have talked about in the past
I don't know if Bart has seen it before
about have using it before you you may
or may not because some of these are in
my early videos this this math art is
fantastic we need to talk about it some
some some time so okay let me read the
comments and let's see where we go in C
transferred is awesome C Tran really see
transferred is heart you know I like
super heart III cannot eat very hard
food
how long have you been a okay this guy
we got a TRO poison again we have
another troll the other day who kept
telling me to do the some JavaScript
thing I banned him in this group so how
is Emacs coming along wasted watched
some of us older Emacs videos nibel so
Nybo so what do you use vim so okay
thanks are you muted Jesus I've been
talking all this way I hope I'm not
muted
okay I'm not muted right
so I'll check out then I have another
question when do you think all these art
is computer generated on the same worth
as art by humans oh okay
actually so this article this article
these I consider art okay this article I
have met algorithmic mathematical art
that's what I consider well mathematical
art yes art hold on a second
so let me just post that that okay so we
are I guess we are not going to talk
about keyboards yeah so methanol so
these these I would consider art okay
but these are a specific type of art
math art now now if you know if you do
math you know you're know today on the
web there are a lot of art you know
that's called math art oh you know this
often you will see math and art mixed
together you know over the place you
search the web you know you are seeing
conferences in exhibit you know there's
actually a dedicated conference for math
art I which I despise okay because most
of the time they are they are just like
this this brainless generative art for
example this this some people will you
know in the early 1990s this will become
a math art okay this this or some of
these for example you'll become math art
this is you know crap anyway so so some
of these I would consider this these I
would consider heart in math art for
example these because they there is
creativity and there is a essence of
mathematical structure embedded in art
okay so in this piece of walk in this
showing they are not just they showcase
I mean they are first of all they are
visually pleasing okay they are visually
pleasing then each one of these in my
page okay not elsewhere I mean I will
need to explain in detail what I mean by
math art but anyway just for now just
look at the examples in my page in this
article so each one of these first of
all they are visually appealing but the
second set the others important thing is
that each one of them they illustrate
and embody an essence of certain
mathematical principles or theory or
equation for example this one I call it
I call it a Borg cube but this one is
actually a part of this equation so you
see these it embodies the solution to
this equation it looks like that okay so
so it's not you know it's not random
like like generative art okay it's it it
actually if you are studying math you
know it actually happens in real life
you want to know what this equation you
know the solution looks like it looks
like that and from this you can learn
many things you know you can learn how
for example if you have a line
intersecting it you can learn it
intersects at multiple places and you
can also form a topology point of view
for example this is a great puzzle out
of the blue you can for example let me
ask your question how does this surface
partition the 3d space you see when you
have a surface let's say when you have a
surface let's say a plane okay let's say
a plane infinite in length so it
partitions the 3d space you cried in
space into two parts right now however
if you look at this one this Riemann
surface now by the way this should be
extended all the ways out okay you can
you have to kind of put multiple
multiple pieces of them together you
know it's drawn like this don't just
because software is not good enough but
anyway you can see these surfers the it
extends all the way out and also to the
top in bottom two so you can see these
also partitions this the 3d space into
how many parts that that is a puzzle so
think of this as a if you love math
think of this as a person if given this
surface yeah I mean it's just fun to
think about how many how does it does it
partition the space into two parts or
infinite infinite many parts you know
you can think about that question and
same way same thing with this how many
parts of space it partitions the 3d
space too so anyway so my so back to my
previous point I'm talking I'm saying
this math art vo mathematical art in my
opinion because the way I define math
math art is that each one of these
embodies a specific math theory or
process okay now Raymond Raymond surface
is kind of advanced it's this one is
actually this one is a minimal surface
minimal surface is that means that
locally they have minimal area but
anyway that's another topic so so this
is also math art why because you can see
first of all it's you know it's it's the
it's the octahedron okay octahedron is a
solid such that it's a regular solid
solid meaning that each face is made of
the same shape a a octagon and octagon
itself is a regular Sol regular shape
because each a
is of the same length and each angle is
the same so you know it's one of the
Platonic solids so there's a math theory
and in this very shape you know then
they change the this guy this guy
Michael chart he is a fist
he's a mathematical feces he woke at
wolfin research i met him you know back
in 1985 and he is into creating these
things so anyway so in this picture you
can see first of all it's visually
appealing
okay that's odd then it has certain
significance in math and creativity well
math because it's you know it's a you
know linked it's a linked octahedron and
also why is it interesting because just
like you know when you when you look at
this other picture we talked about we
can think about how many parts does it
partition the space into meanwhile on
the other hand when you look at this
picture you can think about you can
think about how is it linked the link
structure you see you see the you can
you can cut you can look you can start
to think about how are they linked and
then then you can think about how would
you extend it to you know can you extend
this to the whole 3d space and how would
you link them how would you do that so
that's that's math you know that's math
that gets you to be if you actually
think about this you would get into I
suppose you would get to you can get
into a graph theory you know you start
to have issue you know yeah many
interesting you can think of many
interesting problems just from looking
at this so this is math art okay so
that's another example and okay here is
some real warding example of using
polyhedrons
and here is also H this is kind of
ancient example you know polyhedron
based your lamp you know you can
truncate it you can start
did you know it's these for example
these are all my math arts but even
though they are very common today you
see them everywhere and these are
different examples they are plots of you
know curves and it's art because first
of all it's visually appealing secondly
because they are actually they represent
the solution of equations so it's not
random it's it's there's a very precise
every pixel every pixel is precisely
defined by this equation okay so those
are art and this is also another example
of math art why because the first of all
visually appealing
very beautiful secondly they embody the
mathematical process of inversion now I
did a video talking about
I think inversion and geometric
inversion and complex analysis you might
check it out you know my math tutorial
is not so great there are so many great
math tutorials on the YouTube anyway
so this is so nested inversion of
circles okay it's a it's an exact wait a
second it's an exact mathematical
process in order to do that actually I
have article and here's another example
of nested inversion and here is another
example of nested inversion and actually
I have out of article explaining that so
if you want to know what is an inversion
you know use you study this page
geometric inversion okay I show you how
each points are generated what does it
mean inversion of a circle and you know
I mean you know and here is proofs and
things like that
so inversion of circle so this is art
art art you know this math art and this
is also art this
why is this odd first of all it's
visually appealing okay
secondly this embody your process what
you might call fish can okay
fish can you know you know it's you know
you it's a camera
but behind fish fit behind fish can it's
a mathematical process of transformation
you call a transformation
oh you simply a function a function that
map's the plane to itself okay so you
start with you start with a normal you
know non warped star stars pattern then
after the transformation it becomes that
fish lens so actually I have a formula
for that too you can see over here I
think you know you read my article
you'll see the exact formula so the
formula here is this this one so the
fish and so you so this is mathematical
notation so basically you have a vector
x and y u divided by vector by their
length okay
then plus five right so that's how you
that's a function that does these fish
wings
fish fish lens but actually actually I'm
not sure I think fish lens has a very
specific definition I'm not sure this is
it but it's kind of similar similar okay
similar effect then you have this one
l-systems turtle graphics this is also
art because it's visually appealing and
it embodies a mathematical process of
recursion okay these are examples now
this this is called our systems you can
call with read Wikipedia okay so I did
you know I did most of this page in 2000
in 1990s
you know 1990s in 2000 this was from I
did it in 2004 and another one this one
is called because if tiding this one is
called pink white pee
we are tithing think we are tithing and
you can see it's actually a building in
Australia no boom
okay pink we are hiding and pink we are
hiding is this specific tithing but also
it is one example of what's called
recursive tithing okay because you can
you know it's like a nested because if
tidy so that's art because you know it's
it's visually appealing and it embodies
a mathematical process recursion very
specific and and actually so I got quite
a lot many different examples that I
consider them to be mathematical art
okay now okay so I so so I titled this
page actually I call them algorithmic
mathematical art now I want to contrast
it with contrasted if so what is not
mathematical art okay let me show you
some example which I consider that's not
odd no is it math at all but how long
have I been talking okay so maybe a few
moments and let me read a comments so
let's look at images
okay so these I would consider
mathematical art yes this yes this yes
this yes but it's not means you know
it's not very good though I mean some of
them are just simple this no this is not
math mathematical art okay it's well I
would say it's smart okay it's but it's
nothing but my point let me get to the
point okay they are something that's not
mathematical this one for example you
know a lot of people start to do this
[ __ ] okay a lot of people start to do
this you know they are trying to mix
math with some kind of you know the face
or you know especially the hippies you
know they they like to do that this this
is this is well it's pretty actually
this one is pretty but it's is kind its
art okay it's art but it's not
mathematical art okay so this is not
math art okay I want to show you some of
the examples that actually this and I
want to show you some examples that
shows my point many okay many of these
are code these images are for my website
this is for my website so this is so
most of these so far I've seen these are
math art okay these are great and god I
hate children stuff
so this this is not math art okay well
it's fun but it's not math art and also
this is idiotic
you know my point is that you start to
see many people start to mix in
photograph you know photos or joins or
some kind of like none no mathematical
things mixing with fractals you see that
often you know they you know they trying
to use factor techniques but they try to
do you know random things with you know
human face so those are crap okay why
how come I don't see usually you see a
lot of those examples but now I'm not
seeing much here you know I on twitter
you'll see you'll see them often you
know it's like you know it's like yeah
so pins sierpinski triangle is also it
so images with factor generally are art
in your opinion no wait wait it needs to
be okay so let me show you some of them
that's not okay I know a website so this
professor is a friend and who has helped
helped me a lot
richard palace he's got a wikipedia
article but he's got a home page so let
me show you each a palace i three years
ago he gave me in the mac okay so
richard palace you can see Wikipedia he
is one of the great differential
geometry okay so that is him and that's
his wife his wife is a Chinese from
Taiwan and she is also a differential
geometry I think there's also a theorem
named
and also him as well like you know a
theory so which Apple a is I you know he
gave me he gave me the Mac and they and
he's got a home page so let's go to his
home page so if you go to his home page
and you have this software website
called 3d explore math I you know I I
helped to create this website so
basically I I did this website so you go
to visual math museum then you go to
math art okay now now this is his
website so you know it's not me no it's
not all written by me so I I cannot I
mean I'm just helping him create it so
he he tells me what he liked or what you
know I have some influence on how it's
done but engine but it's his website
okay so anyway he he has you know
created this is like 15 years ago this
page was created 15 or 20 years 2015 15
years ago in 2006 or so so he's got a
collection of other people art okay
many of these I do not consider art at
all okay so what's some examples so this
for example this you know I you know
like when you criticize you know
sometimes they stay here you they don't
like you okay so it's kind of fishy to
criticize okay this I like this okay I
like inverted trust trust said tiding
okay so this is a trust a tiling you
inverted like geometric inversion we
talked about that's that that I like
okay
this I would consider math art okay
let's go back but some of them are not
okay now this guy actually this guy is a
acquaintance but I really do not like
the things he is doing okay so he would
call this so he created this and you
know he consider them art not to me okay
they are not art nor are they math so so
I would put them almost in a category of
that abstract modern abstract art thing
you know these kind of things so but you
know it's kind of like somewhat so it's
like easy so the way he is doing it it's
kind of like somewhat you mixing
abstract modern abstract art with some
ideas of math then you get this kind of
thing I don't I don't like them at all
okay so so not my thing and poop okay
probably we talked about and Louis lost
keys okay so in general and you know I
don't like so this you know I don't like
this I mean yeah it's like yeah this one
okay so this one is a stereotypical
thing I don't like you see they are
trying to they are mixing part of the
computer graphics technology you see
that repo that's from computer graphics
technology you know Wayne's when people
can start to do be able to do that you
consider it very cool you know computer
graphics technology they also they try
to mix in kind of factors you know for
math that's how you get these kind of
thing then they also try to mix in some
of the abstract modern abstract art
concept so you kind of have this random
you know whatever they are so it's like
odd to
this is garbage okay this is the this is
the great example of what I would call
garbage and okay this is okay so in
that's a movie so anyway so that's so
that's about it today I think I've
talked about for one hour and 20 minutes
and opinion Jesus okay so any any
comments so I think that's it for today
so today's juice is this cranberry and
stuff cranberry and raspberry oh and
apple and then you know they typically
mixing apple juice because apple juice
is cheap and I need my energy drink and
I read comments and that will be it
we shut down in 20 in two more minutes I
think unless you have comments type it
it's the right time Freddie guys Nybo
tablet okay
[Music]
what music do you like and do you like
to do music Mia do you like to listen to
music while coding III decent mostly 80%
would be classical piano music actually
I did a talk about that I think for 20
minutes or something I don't know if I
can find it let's see if I can so go to
a talk show search for music yes I think
so
so 2019 June 24th classical music park
beast dance frenzy keyboard layout input
methods shortcut later they are
repetitive strain jury so I thought I
talked about music what I like in that
video basically I mostly I listened to
classical piano music for 80% of time so
the other 20% is pop you know pop and
English dance music like dance music a
lot you know like brainless dance music
frenzy you know thank how they call
house house music and stuff and yes it
was if I code
it must be classical music you know I
don't I haven't been listening to music
while coding much she haven't been
actually coding much as I get older you
know actual coding is supposed to you
know just reading about writing
tutorials but actual coding heaven you
know it's like getting less invest now
one hour a day old in in the past two
month
it's not even one hour a day I feel sad
that yeah I need two sets I need to get
back to coding
but the other problem is that you know
I've been sitting in this chair too long
I have to walk so you know League of
noobs not League of news you just came
on okay let me read the comments and
they'll be it so good morning Kathy good
morning Freddy Freddy is from Germany
nibel neighbor way from again either
from Germany or the UK UK boy song in
gran ok don't know why you have trolls
here Kathy has Emacs okay so check
though what are you running hackintosh
no I'm not running hacking - so game of
life is fascinating ok so we we need to
talk about game of life in the cellular
automata look at this person's thing I
really you know I really like her app
truly a lot I like her apple Abelard
it's beautiful this cellular automata in
artificial life ok so guys if you
haven't seen you know if you are
programmer go read about go read about
you know go check out her app and go
read about cellular automata or go read
about artificial life ok so go through
Wikipedia read artificial life and also
read cellular automata beat cellular
automata first ok then you read
artificial life and also read about game
of life gamma of life is one of the
cellular or cellular automata okay so
you do that Wikipedia then you go you
know you can go to my web
at least several of the great cellular
automata and artificial programs
actually I don't have much here but
actually if you have to go to old math
software because many of these in the
1990s they died
you know the software is no longer there
you know people get old so it's like 20
years many of these programs are 20 or
30 years old people no longer program
people get cut married you know they
have a kid they got busy they are no
longer programmers they or some of them
died I'm pretty sure that happens to
some of them so so so for example here
simulations
this is poit this is 3d simulations
basically this is very popular in the
1990s where you want to emulate a flock
of birds you know their formation how
they change things like that so you have
a software for it so actually this guy
in Japan is still awful yeah so yeah so
you know I when I look back at my old
pages I start to do some you know so I
discovered no it's gone yeah you know
you don't know what happened to him many
of them I've talked to like back then in
1990s I we talked email via email you
know when you that's what you do when
you are younger you know you you are
still doing things like me three things
today I'm just seeing here doing
commentary commentary Terry and
historical comments but but you guys are
you know maybe I don't know how you all
are you you guys are full of chances
so you find things interesting you can
do you can code you can learn you can
actually talk to them you actually you
know you email them and maybe start
collaboration or maybe you know things
like that
so here is several you know very
interesting this
tired tired cellular automata okay like
I said you know most of the links on
this particular page are dead because
this page is named owed math software so
in 2018 I kind of cleaned up I try to
clean up my list of software and I moved
all the dead links to this page so you
can see so these are there they are many
interesting things you know do you have
magic cube 4d by the way this guy who
created this is very interesting
he Melina Queen Melinda green okay but
Melinda green was a guy but she he she
became a trans okay now this is before
the social justice a age okay before you
know before the past ten years she
became a trance packing
I think 2000s but we were free we were
friends okay we were talking about you
know we exchanged emails a few times and
she's also in fact in Wikipedia this her
name is mentioning one of the fractal
thing anyway but you know however there
is a glitch between us because back in
2017 okay you know when the trance when
the social justice scan was up you know
with because the Trump election so the
social justice sky is talking about you
know why all things every day trans
trans every day so my opinion about that
I'm negative
you know I'm negative about social
justice so I started to criticize you
knows some of the issues and some of
them involves trends you know
transgender and she is transgender and
apparently she didn't die captain so she
unfollowed me yeah the death that's all
so and so I think you know she you know
she you know it's too bad
so anyway so that these are the old
programs and I wanted to show that you
the actually there's a lot more and what
I want to show you is some of the
programs that does artificial life so I
think over the over the past thirty
years I've actually deleted them you
know because I did this spring up in
2018 but however I've done coming up you
know five five or ten years before so
the old programs I I might have just
deleted them so is you don't see them
here anyway
so artificial yeah cellular automata is
very interesting now artificial
artificial let me tell you what
artificial life is artificial life is
almost the same thing as Lu automata
except when you have a cellular automata
remember it's squid that's why you call
cellular because you have lots of cells
then you generate each generation you
know game of life or many other for
example these girls this this this
ladies walk you know it's fascinating
it's beautiful but you have cells you
involve cells in a plane lots of cells
you know they you have rules you have
basic rules that tells you what happens
in the next generation that's how you
get this evolution you know changes now
in artificial life it's almost it's
exactly the same thing each generation
you follow rules except except it's not
sales you know you don't start just with
a bunch of you know chessboard and you
know you have cells you know you have
feel it or don't feel it it's not like
that rather you it's more creative it's
it's it's more free okay so you can so
basically what basically it's just
simple programs a program you you define
at the beginning what what it is okay a
car whatever Oh birds okay actually so
let me read it let's read it because
Wikipedia usually have a good definition
under visual life is a field of study
wherein researchers exam systems related
to natural life its processes and its
evolution through the use of simulations
with computer models robotics and
biochemistry okay that's that's that's
not a good definition that's kind of to
academic to abstract too philosophical
you know they are trained that's not
good
but anyway other visual life is just
just like sailu automata in each you
read
program it's a program okay yeah it's a
computer program typically you can call
it emulation or something you write a
program that in the beginning you define
what's a state then you define what's a
rule to go to the next next step
typically visual like you know this
visual then what then according to the
same you know you just keep generating
the next generation following some very
typically very extremely simple rules
and see what happens so one of the
example is Lang Lang Lang turns and okay
so you begin with and okay the end can
face in any direction north east west
south so you have certain rules that
says say that says if the square in
front of him is black then the and
should turn right if the square in front
of him is is white the aunt then should
turn left something like that simple
rules so then you just you just let it
go and see see how the aunt race is a
pattern you know following in this
specific rule so this is one example of
artificial life and actually this length
length this is called lengthens and okay
but it's unsolved there's there are many
unsolved questions in it like you know
anyway you can read that okay so thank
you guys for coming if you like my stuff
go to my website go to the top you can
see my web paypal and patreon pages okay
donate and support me like my videos
subscribe bye guys