good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show today's is mm
19th October it Evans Friday 10 o'clock
a.m. San Francisco time thank you for
coming
good morning teepee good morning Koufos
school yeah because I noticed something
is wrong with the oh yeah so good
because yesterday yesterday I remember I
said uh scheduled for today but but just
now I you know I went to YouTube and
that stream is gone I didn't see it so I
started a new one so I don't know what's
going on with YouTube so let's go and
have a look
so I'm afraid you know the bad thing is
that if people went to the other one
and they wait there and they don't see
nothing how long second so let's see
what's going on so 3 waiting hello chat
hello ok so I myself apparently wait
Abdo so I'm not seeing app though here
what's going on
can you can you guys you can you guys
see my chat this one on this window
apparently I have another chat with deep
content okay
so Charlie's girls time to find another
stream okay so this chat is dead
so this chat is new okay and okay god
this is so bad
so let's go to edit videos the good why
do I have this window up geez
okay sorry about that so I'm here I need
to click on this live control room and
wait for it
live dashboard and there we are
so this is the new chat okay so let's
pop out chat okay so anyway this seems
to be working
good morning Abdul Abdul is from Egypt
can you answer my questions what
questions both of you I don't see it
this chat is new here we go yeah okay so
what happened why was another chat for
well yeah I don't know what's going on
it's a YouTube you know night watching
okay good
so today and discord okay guys remember
discord did something happen to the
scheduled livestream yes
sorry go to my channel and try it from
there apparently the livestream code
changed or something okay so that's
discord and you can find some talk show
topic Franco took some talk show and you
can find disk or join the discord Club
okay
sorry you are not there bathroom you
told me both of you I learned yesterday
on on discord someone told me that
bathroom you is apparently your name
from Bible and the short for it is spot
so can I call you but so I didn't know
that but you know it's like Bart
Simpson's you know you know Simpsons
cartoon good morning Matt good morning
is each from crazy okay so today I have
some topics I prepared and if you have
questions just
okay just type it okay so talk show
brain that's not what we want we want to
go to San talk show and show him browser
and okay let me close this window so on
the left window you seem all my Emacs
commands and let's go to exhaust our
talk show and show it in browser I don't
have it okay so I'm planning to do some
:
so part means beard in Germany in German
okay so exotic so I have some topics
which is over here
I'm the logo tool so let's talk about
something about Mouse okay and we could
not do some go line okay today okay so
now I'm like feeling pressure I'm not
doing so well in the talk wasted five
minutes okay so there is this keyboard
okay this one I showed I think I may or
may not have showed yesterday so this is
a keyboard that with a giant ctrl key at
the corner the lower right corner or
left left lower corner so you have a
giant ctrl key what is the purpose of
the giant this is a key cap okay so you
can buy and put on your keyboard and
what's the purpose of giant ctrl key is
for using the palm to press the ctrl
keys for Emacs pinkies so let me show
you some pictures here you see one of
the tip about buying a keyboard is that
you want the modifier keys to your
finger position to the index finger
position to be symmetric on the left
side and right side so for example this
Apple keyboard the command key to F the
distance between command to F and the
distance between right command to J is
is very different you know so the right
set of modifier keys are much more to
the right so it's not good so that means
you have to curve in your thumb much
more so you want something symmetric
like that also prefer preferably with
giant modifier keys so anyway we were
talking about the control key so one
technique of pressing control keys with
your palm okay these are by different
people
these aren't this is not me and this is
not me this is another technique where
you press by your pinkies knuckle okay
like like that or sometimes you just use
a fist you sit on it that's what I do
so people have created this and this is
alternative I think I think I talked
about this yesterday so bottoming says I
asked your opinion about we
repairability in general and
repairability regarding Microsoft
yesterday I I talked about that for 10
minutes yesterday the Borg repairable
Hardware do you remember I talked about
that and I don't know what's you know
and I also showed the github software
repairable like you know you can check
out a fire when you delete it by mistake
but and I don't know what do you mean by
repairability in general and
repairability regarding Microsoft well
in general I mentioned you know the poke
technology where we have material
science that fix fix things itself right
so I'm not not sure what you talking
about both of you
it looks like you've been lost a bit
like you cannot post links it's very
strange
there is also bad part
Elmen a prominent New Statesman State
New Testament Bible scholar part
Elmen airmen airmen part Airmen I don't
know what exactly do you mean with
repairability yeah exactly what what do
you mean by that part of you but sobota
is being precise says you general
time in the long run same for talking
tops take your time before you speak you
will save half an hour ok ok bar says I
saw a video explaining that Microsoft
tries to make their product repairable
which is again is the mainstream that
tries to make everything is hard to
repair as possible what what is the
article I mean but you know that's you
know let's fix your posting link problem
you know I think you've been kind of
lost I lost you since yesterday like now
today you telling me about talking about
repairability we did talk about that
yesterday for like 20 minutes and then
you talking about not able to post links
and you said you said yesterday actually
you said you you have never seen anyone
post links that's false
what now you think you know what that's
forced you being watching my video
almost every day we have seen people
posting links right like guys you know
post link right now
for example programming block ok people
could go here post this link see if you
can do it ok let's fix
patthamas problem of posting a link you
have seen people post links so maybe
something on your client maybe something
on your client that deletes you know
that does prevents you from seeing
things we have seen Binks and even even
if it does not show you on your chat
screen you will sometimes see it in my
talk shows screen because you know the
chat is right here you know you have
seen a link I'm sure you know Ike we can
go through the you know all the text
files and actually I can show you links
for example let's do it right now
so let's search for htdp ok
htdp something and such for this
directory search for or text files okay
there it is
this is san talk show 2019 April 15th
George says George posted this link you
know there's one two three it is so many
you know and you are here right here
this one okay this one okay I post the
link okay that's all my link we are not
counting me because maybe because I'm
the show host because so maybe there is
something special do you think I have a
self censoring extension in your browser
in my browser I don't know I don't know
what's that about that but people people
but but you have said something strange
you see whether you have self censoring
extension whether you have something we
are going on I don't know but you said
you'd never sing Binks in my talk show
that's that's force in quite several
ways because first of all we have links
in the talk chat okay that that is one
thing we have we you know you for
example I showed I showed the one posted
by George okay there is also I showed
one okay most yeah most links are post
by me but but but we have seen this one
by George okay and but also so you know
it's possible maybe you don't see it
because something on your browser that
just removes link maybe but you have you
know since you watched almost every you
know of my videos my videos you know my
talk show you can see on the screen
where I have the chats yes so you must
have seen some my postings you know once
so well unless you are not paying
attention so I don't know what and owes
so so so far you see
so so far you see it's it's it's hard
for me to see what what is your issue
but also the the other thing is links
you know links it's impossible not to be
able to post links because you can
always change things you know it should
be it's not too difficult so so I'm
going to read ok so but but guys post a
link ok let's do this let's get this
let's get this going let's post a link
ok I want you guys okay help me out help
me out you're gonna post this link ok
post this link ok just actually just
post this text I cannot see past I
cannot possibly see that this is
impossible guys can you copy these lines
and post it can you copy can you guys
copy that line and post it there it is
cool for school see I am calm
so battle me like I you know there is a
problem I don't know what you talking
about like add you know you know what do
you mean you can you can always easily
post links and ok so big by not why is
that censored it is censored so we are
exploring the you know the issues ok let
me show that ok you see you got guys
look at this one okay this one is
censored for some reason okay so past
perhaps its stop saying that stop saying
nonsense you know both of you you just
sync okay let me read the chat okay let
me read a host chat let's get this set
out today since since bottom you know he
is watching every my video so let's get
this settled so question I've never
behaved okay so hello and so dig of says
great name okay League of noobs let's
magnify okay magnify magnified and okay
let's move it here
so that you can see it well my window is
too small okay so actually it means
shrink it let me shrink it and just put
it here then okay so let me go back here
and let's see how many I got seventeen
people have been talking for 16 minutes
okay and let's see okay so let me read
all the comments so what do you think
about okay new what do you think about
brand new Apex protti KL by steel series
okay we can look at that
I think it's crap SteelSeries it's it's
for gamers that that keyboard I think
it's pretty much it's crap and when you
go to this gamers website oh my god the
JavaScript doing everything is so busy
you know they eat your CPUs and all that
is $79 app this one crap you can you can
get a cheap cheap mechanical keyboard
for fifty dollars or thirty thirty
dollars if you really want to go cheap
but 50 dollars gets you a solid one
solid okay
nuclear will not break you know your V
you can use it for years so a pixpro TK
what is it in the next sleeping
mechanical keyboards first of its kind
of just well adjustable mechanical
switches for customizable perky
sensitivity oh okay that's something new
but exactly what is there switch a time
faster response crap five times ever has
to actuation crap crap oh oh LED smart
display delete delivers information crap
series 5000 aircraft grade aluminum
aluminum my ass aircrafts aircraft grade
my ass detachable soft touch yeah yeah
yeah yeah my ass
so the $180 price tag is primarily for
this reason for this first-of-its-kind
adjustable mechanical switches so
exactly what is it okay here is a key
switch the next beep in mechanical
keyboards the is a biggest leaf
invention of the mechanical that each
key can be adjusted to meet your
preferred sensitivity okay no technical
detail adjusted to your preferred
sensitivity so from the wording you know
they are trying to market you know they
are using the marketing's talk market
marketing talk you know but so they try
to sway me into certain direction but
instead I can see through instead I see
so from their wording you can tell right
away this is not a analog switch meaning
you know these days you have analog
switch let me let me tell you about that
about the link we're gonna solve that ok
so let me tell you about analog
mechanical switch so now you have this
keyboard routing very famous in this key
stone is also becoming very famous
routing is made by someone in northern
Europe I think okay so this is wooden
keyboard and this is Keystone keyboard
this just came out like three months
three months or so ago
okay and they what what's so special
about them they are mechanical
mechanical analog switches you know
effectively to the user what it means is
that the the key switch depending on how
much you press down there is a
difference different register you know
you can so for for example you can use
one single key any one of the key as a
gas pedal you know last as a gas pedal
because it measures levels so that these
are analog they go
analog mechanical switch but they are
not necessarily analog you know they it
may be actually digital but the the
point about them is that they can each
key with this switch can measure
different levels of pressure I mean how
much you press down so you can actually
use it use it like a gas pedal you know
so that's that that's why so you have
these two things new this this is new
kind of new technology okay they
actually I think they existed existed
before but nowadays you know this is a
modern one analog mechanical switch okay
you have these two choices you can buy
one from America went from the northern
Europe okay it's highly recommended by
this guy this key switch expert choir
sound 2022 okay he's a he's a keys
keyboard switch expert
sorry keyboard okay I want to let me
show you my stuff then do I know Kyra
song yeah well no I had never talked to
him and he's on Twitter so I have
occasionally treated he's you know we
have excreted his posts
I have reposted we shared his posts and
maybe once or twice I've talked to him
on Twitter that's all but anyway so he
is an expert in key switch remember just
key switch not layout not economics not
you know keyboard design but key switch
exactly okay he in fact his idiotic it
he is extreme idiotic when it comes to
keyboard ergonomics like you know he's
not the touch type I first of all he
doesn't touch type and he doesn't like
any organ AMA keyboard he you know the
OAuth he all the things he ever like is
like this in fact he doesn't like this
mini version he doesn't like this
compact he like he prefers the
I think you know the IBM the IBM
keyboard is his favorite keyboard like
that you know that I be I be a model F
you know we are known the most popular
IBM keyboard is model in but actually
there is a model called model F that
comes before M and and model M is
actually trying to make it cost less to
produce the keyboard so so model M is
actually less in quality model F is
better so you can see a model F here
because I I have a I have I don't have
JavaScript on there so anyway so let's
okay so here is another link okay so go
there and buy my keyboard okay so let's
go to open linking chrome okay he opens
a new tab and it's not what I want
[ __ ] I'm kind of like in a hurry because
sometimes I do video I feel like there's
a pressure I need to do it well but
anyway let me pop this in okay so
mechanical keyboard so we were talking
about that so we were talking about
analog mechanical keyboards okay so
choir song disk i/o song guy his real
name is I forgot yeah I cannot remember
names so so anyway so you have analog
mechanical keyboard
okay now you so so from this one this
SteelSeries they make idiotic keyboards
you know they actually they just they
just market to cameras that SteelSeries
is a chemist brand so anyway they say
each key can be adjusted to meet your
preferred sensitivity level so they you
see they didn't say each key is you know
have different you know 100 levels of
measure so it's
analog you know so it's just adjusted to
meet your preferred sensitivity level I
kind of get what they are saying so you
can adjust the resistance it's crap crap
okay this keyboard is crap okay now what
are these lists are interesting oh these
are Devils yeah so if if you ask my
opinion about this keyboard it's crap
okay let's copy that close that it's
because that let's go - let's paste it
okay so we have a record now
next topic now shall we get back to the
what is this close and stop this okay
stop this and kibo log general okay
discord
okay join this code and what why do I
have these two of these oh yeah this one
is dead
okay close okay
other switches crap well I did you you
see I don't think it's you don't need it
because you know okay I don't fully
understand what exactly they mean but I
guess what they are is that they you
cannot just you know the much how much
resistance each keys are so if that is
true I think it's crap I mean it's not a
very useful feature it definitely not
you know not a very useful feature you
don't want adjustable resistance rather
you buy a key switch that with the
resist resistance you like you know you
just use that you know you don't spend
hundred eighty dollars to buy adjustable
resistance then you are thinking maybe
you gonna as we adjust it every day it's
City you are just like once and it's
it's sitting there instead
it's useless so that's why I don't think
it's a good keyboard okay so let's see
the comments about posting Binks let's
figure out why you cannot post things no
no this so let's backtrack to that
question so I personally think to steer
series again I did no I don't see it so
let's fix it so not a link but but the
hint you know I'm the second year of
computer science do you think they are
interesting project that i okay so
League of noob stays I'm a I'm at the
second year of computer science okay do
you think there are interesting project
that I should pursue yes absolutely I
know some Java assembly and algorithms
yeah sure I mean that's very broad
question I mean at school they must have
lots of homeworks and projects right so
I I need to know what's your background
what's your what's the context you are
asking the question because because even
in your home book there's lots of
computer science
I'm sure you are using there are lots of
homeworks and projects right so so what
do you mean you want an interesting
project you know this is like that you
know tell me like what what are you
looking for something because they are
so meaning for exactly like you know I
can random name one like you know write
a program to write a function you know
the depends on what you you you want to
do you know web dev or what or
algorithms you know this you know so let
me know
wait saw I posted a link I see it in
chat but not on your chat okay
my roommates they are talking weeks aw I
posted a link I see it in chat but not
on your chat
okay so I'm waiting for my roommates to
go to come they are they are leaving I
think so yeah so let's get the chat fig
the link problem figured figured out
okay so so TP says can't cannot post
links can't use emoji just tried what
why is that I see it on my chat too but
you will never see it
okay listen to DP DP but Petri to make
sure it works what BTW you spit three to
make sure it works
yeah links cannot be posted okay so is
it because I have something set up so
kisara
so max the reader says I'll read the
chat okay so seems like you all owe me
huh okay possibly possibly you are right
but we but we have seen links you know
it so it's not exactly alright we have
seen links you know at least for example
we have seen you know let's do it again
so in this directory so let's search for
let me magnify okay so search for HTTP
okay in my talkshow directory and all
files that ends in txt okay
now these are the comments I pasted I
copied and pasted it to my Emacs you
know for my comments so you can see this
one you know George this is a link this
so you know if you go to youtube star
talk show 2019 April 15th it will show
up there I'm pretty sure you you know
you play you play the video and at some
point they will be that link that you
know this so this is
April 15th well so April to today they
are you know quite a lot of things
happen maybe so yeah and and Google is
trying to do censorship you know they
have new rules so maybe some some times
in between something changed so I don't
know yet as I'm not the only one okay so
can post links message redacted p3 just
works guys just use it for posting
things you cannot post things directly
you have to dissect it okay trying to
post the link to this hangout yeah yeah
remember the other thing is posting
usually gets sensors so but you can
always dissect it you know you know make
it you know things like that that is a
point on this a space left read the damn
chat okay so means actual URL you can
post this reason we will prevail reason
that Kibo is only high quality new one
that has whole switches that's horse
switches okay so bottom you say is
that's a whole switch okay so that's
let's have a look close that SteelSeries
hose hose whole switch now if it's whole
switch that's interesting yeah okay so
that that makes sense
horse which is a switch that does not
require contact it uses some kind of
principle I forgot what but let's see if
we if we go to Mike sorry web keyboard
block you go to keyboard design then you
go to key switches okay over here then
this page talks about several order
different type of key switches at the
bottom you will see whole switch
and you have optical switch actually i
optical switch is is good I like it you
know I think it's good
infrared up optical switch anyway you go
to the bottom your seahorse which hor
effects switch okay now how effect
switch that refers to electronic switch
now I talked about this before when you
talk about switch one aspect is how the
electronics makes contact
you know how the electronic tronics
makes a register that's one thing so you
have host Ojo effects which you have you
know just the most common is metal metal
contact switch that is used in or MX
switches you know metal contact you have
two pieces metal they contact oh you
have roberto robot dome also have you
know electronic conduct conducting
material when they contact they they
turn it on you know when the key is on
so that's about electronic switch but
the other part the other aspect is how
it feels so when we talk about MX switch
that usually refers to the tactile
mechanism which you know the MX which
uses a spring the anyway affects which
is a electronic refers to the electronic
switches but however you know the
mechanism how they how they actually the
mechanic nism for the key feel could be
anything else but typically when you
have a switch that's using whole horse
which effect you know there's a
technical term hole or something like
electromagnet magnetic of you know
theory when you have a switch that uses
that theory to connect the electron flow
typically those switch are expensive
therefore they're tactile sensation the
mechanism for the tactile sensation also
uses some
good so when you say host which so
usually you also included as part of the
mechanical switch where anyway if you
like hole switch by this one okay I
recommend this one this is this came
from a guy his name is I met him one
time at keyboard meetup in San Francisco
Soho effects which is the most expensive
to make and most reliable each switch is
rated at billions of presses in context
Cherry MX switches are rated 50 million
so you know so it's like few times more
reliable than Cherry MX
so you can buy this keyboard from this
guy there's also a wooden version at
least I don't know what's the current
state but you know just go to this his
website this guy this guy is known as
mix2 guy that's his online handle okay
so you go to his website so it's on drop
mash drop I don't like my strong so
anyway you can buy it okay and it's not
expensive it's under $100 so it's very
good it's quite amazing under $100 for
hole effects switch now about a pecs
did they say ho effect you know this
marketing you know they don't okay and
oh wait wait switch type a name Omni
point adjustable mechanical switch
analog hoe effect magnetic sensor okay
so it's horri fact and it says analog
hoe effect Micmac magnetic sensor but
can register different levels like like
can use can you use a key as a can you
use a key as a gas pedal they didn't say
that
because if it doesn't do that then yeah
I don't think yeah yeah I don't think I
wouldn't buy it you know you you buy
from this MIT guy okay
this can mean basically this came in
brand they are just there to grab your
money okay so I wouldn't recommend it
a pecs
you know a pecs I mean the the
SteelSeries they came out with a
keyboard where the spacebar is a space
pad okay like you know space bar is
usually long right about but very very
thing you know
however they have a version from C or
series where they increase the the hate
you know of the space bar so they become
space pad so I don't know what they are
thinking they are complete idiotic
Amazon let's go to Amazon okay I am a
CEO and calm complete idiotic thus this
camera things and the worst is the worst
is the the the keyboard you you never
want to buy is form the scheming brand
let's see what he what is it PC keyboard
I cannot remember names
okay razor yeah razor
what can I find it here [ __ ] search for
Raz okay I guess I removed it okay so
yeah so never buy razor ok never buy
razor you can go there and and see why
so anyway so SteelSeries let's look at
st de ser IES okay keyboard
so I guess they they don't make that
model anymore I mean it's a keyboard
with a huge space pad okay let's go
through some talk show page I mean cause
our keyboard K page and such full ste el
ser okay enter such in this directory
and HTML file let me show you that
keyboard okay this mouse is the worst
the the worst possible I bought it recon
so you have where is it SteelSeries
since I'm a this is okay
there it is this this apex cable this
girl is fantastic there it is this one
this idiotic big-ass space bar you see
they created this keyboard it's like you
have no idea what are these people are
thinking okay that's that's that that's
that
so I I feel like today we I lost track
you know I wanted to talk about
something but
change topped chat to live chat sorry's
goofing on the picture thank you know
what tough chat what tough chat little
chat where vehicle keyboards are nice no
fluff yeah but via KHOU I don't
recommend either they are like two
hundred three hundred dollars these
other proportions Raisa
yes razor is bad you leave ok let's
let's let's let's finish the keyboard so
I don't know what what we are doing
today I wanted to talk about something
something but SteelSeries this this
keyboard ok this idiotic keyboard it's
just post the link here curse that curse
that Keystone keyboard we talked about
ok
close that ok reopen reopen go here PC
keyboard and we also talked about wooden
keyboard ok those are great keywords now
now we still haven't finished the link
problem the post endings problem you can
do it ok bottom you dissect the link we
still have not solved that issue dissect
the link I don't understand why Cannot
you do that it's impossible to you know
it is impossible to not to say it's it's
not possible you know you you you just
remove the HTTP part you know remove
that HTTP or HTTPS dot dot slash slash
you know and you know and then post that
you know cnn.com just type CNN space
type do t space then type come right
that's a link it's impossible you know
it's impossible not to able to post a
link
okay so let me get back to so I'm kind
of like today is kind of confused I
talked about 45 minutes he's so he's so
it's like random chat you know no no Co
no purpose that's that's good kind of
for a chat but yeah
so and and I'm confused about this chat
box
going back and forth you know two parts
I've already read okay so so bothering
me says I use the first generation of
Logitech G 15 because of three times
sixteen custom programmable keys okay
the switches will survive you and your
son in terms of durability okay so read
on how these switches work okay so what
about two ports which is tapas which is
the circus tapas which is is you know
one of the switch many the keyboard
nerds keyboard you know nerds they love
but I think it's the worst I don't like
it at all and the happy hacking keyboard
is the most famous for using tocqueville
switch and the happy hacking happy
hacking keyboard is the worst possible
keyboard I have a full review here and
it's constantly posted we posted to
Reddit and hacker news every three years
the idiocy of having a king keyboards
okay you can read that so many choices
of periphery even on Linux server
keyboard today why are you a fan of
sticky are you part of me are you truly
do do you actually love you know so you
you you think steelseries keyboard are
the best among all the others I mean
better than Logitech for example or
razor or you know the bunch of these
gamers think cooler masters you know
like you know this skimmer keyboard they
don't make sense to me okay that not so
I don't had yeah I mean not just make
sense I think they are idiotic or the
skin came in brand
you know the these keyboard makers they
they market to the gamers so for example
SteelSeries well Logitech to
Coolermaster razors in particular razor
the most extreme idiotic and you know
they market to chemists who don't know
nothing you know they put on colors and
all that and make they they double
triple the price and they intentionally
remove the memory chips on the keyboard
so instead instead if they make it so
that they connect to the crowd rely on
the internet connection and you also
have to you is required you use their
you know software the code you know they
have a name like some cyber something
you know required to download their
software run some windows only I think
you know and when you have the keyboard
you require the the software is running
in a background and you also require to
register account to they are you know
they are crowd so these all these nasty
things without the software or the
programmability doesn't walk so you
cannot bring your keyboard to work you
know plugging on a Mac or Linux doesn't
work you order your custom keys doesn't
work you have to on that machine you
bring a keyboard to that machine then on
that machine you install their new
software then you connect to your their
cloud account then then you know that's
you know this this this camera idiot
keyboards of the gaming brand the only
one I trust is Logitech okay Logitech
I've I have quite a few Logitech devices
I had their keyboards yeah symbol of
their Mouse this is great Logitech okay
loud she take the other gaming brand I
don't you know I had one Coolermaster
Mouse that's the software is disaster
and also when you buy a keyboard you
know like to me okay like wait when it
comes to keyboard many
people and also especially these
keyboard makers especially for gaming in
the industry because remember for each
one programmer you have 1,000 gamers so
when if you are a keyboard maker you
want to market to the gamers because
that's that's you know you have lots
more audience want 1,000 times more
literally in the same way if you are a
virus writer or a more way a writer you
want to write for the Microsoft Windows
operating system not Linux because for
each Linux user desktop user you have
1,000 Microsoft users that is why not
because you know that's why our
Microsoft Windows you have lots of
viruses not because MINIX or unix is
secure secure my ass so so so these
keyboard makers they market to gamers
right and and when but so so they
created this this this this perception
that you have some mouse or chemi Mouse
okay like you you have like this this
kind of muddies are chemi Mouse those
are not gaming mouse okay and this
keyboard is this these are gaming
keyboards those are not gaming keyboard
that okay big they created this concept
okay because they advertise everyday
they use the word gaming keyboard Gaming
Mouse they created they embedded this
concept into your brain just like the
word democracy you know USA we are
democracy okay you when you hear the
democracy anything that's not democracy
that's bad okay in the same way okay so
but to to me when I see well you know I
study things you know I look at these
keyboards there is no such thing as
gaming keyboard no such thing okay
but however it is true in this so-called
Kimmy mouse or gaming keyboard they do
have certain features that is somewhat
you could say it's somewhat more
customized for gamers
spoke for gamers needs okay actually you
know first of all I would say there's no
difference Gaming Mouse none gave me
Mouse same doesn't matter what you use
for gaming or not it's a device that
that that that is a pointer device okay
Mouse the same there's not no such thing
as Gaming Mouse okay same same thing
with keyboard there's no such thing as
gaming keyboard but however now that is
first secondarily it is true some gaming
mouse has certain features that is you
know somewhat better for for gaming
different game different type of game
depending on our games so again so it's
just a very minor it is not important
okay for example most gaming mouse you
know have at least five buttons you know
not that's not even true because when
you would do first-person shooter games
you don't you don't even need fight post
fight but a mouse three button standard
three button is enough some people never
ever use them you know the thumb bonus
you don't need it okay
so actually so the concept of gaming
this is Kimi mas that is not it's
idiotic it's a it's created by these
corporations in bed embedded to your
brain
same thing with keyboards no now what I
wanted to say is that when I look at
people I study you know I study so so to
me it's all the same just keyboard but
however different keyboard have
different features different different
features and it's quite varied okay for
example key switches is one part
economic design whether it's you know
split into two parts
whether you can't end it programmability
that's another issue about keyboards
okay about the device human device
keyboard programmability how it is
programmable because there's some some
things you cannot program for example
for example if you are a programmer but
you are not really a gamer many of this
keyboard Kim you know so-called gaming
gamers keyboard from this Logitech razor
you know they cannot program the
keyboard to
for example for example I want for
example I want to press a key then it's
for AK I press another kid Scotty many
of the keyboard the gaming you know the
so called gaming keyboard do not have
that feature even even they say oh we
have 5 profiles we have like
programmability markers so this that
cybernetics things bloody things you
know battlefields things [ __ ] they don't
have that feature ok because you just
don't and so so in fact many of the
programmer you know so I don't look at
you know as a gaming or not my point the
point I want to say is that keyboard
device or Mouse do you have many
features and often it is the case you
know some people may not know about this
you know often it so case some features
you want are not actually not in the
gaming keyboards okay did you throw up
the bathroom you okay so so I've been
talking for our Nets ever drink and see
so one of the reason I found it so bad
is because naturally when you have a
display attached to your face the
effective resolution of the display is
reduced dramatically you're talking
about some kind of virtual cargo
okay so God so many comments zero as a
joke look up zero zero series okay huh
on top of the chat on top of the chat
look at your display okay on top of the
chat here
Oh top chat Oh live chat [ __ ] Google
no it's not alcohol it's just it's a
it's kind of it's a energy energy energy
drink and apple juice in futures usually
oh that is why ok bathroom you know so I
know I know
so the reason ok so the reason you and
many of you your links do not show you
see now it shows up now that's why okay
so that is why now I don't know that so
this so the reason is because I clicked
on the top chat some messages such as
potential spam may not be visible live
chat all messages are visible oh so I
guess this this has this effects not
just my screen but it affects every
everyone else who can see he's i right
so that must be reason so i maybe it's
at some point i switched to that thing
could be
the YouTube you know this kind of
censorship and hidden censorship you
know that how they call it where you
don't see you can see your own messages
but other people don't see it this this
begin with again I'll just say the open
source UNIX philosophy people about 15
years ago and I know because the Amanda
Emacs community communities these white
people they opinions I don't disagree
with the opinions but they say yo use
must be this way or that way and and
not-safe-for-work [ __ ] they created they
originated these ideas then it becomes
you know how they called shadow band
yeah they may becomes all these things
social justice the you know the shadow
band and it becomes because they because
they say oh that's offensive
not-safe-for-work [ __ ] begin with that
time about twenty years ago from this
open source help people people free
software foundation have a look at your
child I'm waiting for the first review
on the Microsoft keyboard you talked
about yesterday okay maybe I'll go by
that okay you really think I'm stupid if
you think I did never try that you are
being stupid
the in this sentence I mean if you try
that I mean what anyways I don't know
what you're talking about I see assume a
few station being able to post URLs okay
so anyways yeah so I you know that's
something I guess it's my my fault you
could say so but anyway I think that
soft the link that missed the middling
problem mysterious link problem yes
it's some adjudged electron-electron
stuff is so stupid maybe when we get
quantum computers we could use this code
and we vs code at the same time okay
apparently your table chatter was it for
that yeah okay you are right you are
right
are you drinking alcohol yeah three
particles of the soul in your sentence
that does not I can't emphasize okay so
okay so today's chat next episode inks a
factor another cold case closed
okay we are still in a software crisis
they talk about in the 1980s we are
seeing a soft sofa yeah you know
software crisis League of News says well
I was searching for cool algorithms to
implement like path finding suggestions
they are a lot I mean okay so what work
would I suggest I mean I couldn't I
couldn't think of it's like sometimes
when there are so many things you know
you can't think of one example but I
mean depends on what you do want to do I
mean for example if you are you know you
can learn I was trying to learn passes
you know passes where you create your
own language and write a parser you know
I don't know you know you might look
into that for example you can search
website for how to write a parser
tutorial then when you get into that you
have a lot algorithms about passes you
need to write a parser and they are
quite a lot different algorithms so for
example that's one thing you can do well
path finding is also very interesting or
you can do maze creation for example
they are there's a book sorry maze
creation main spoke
I think it's this one no personal number
Macy's no there is a book I don't know
who I this guy these are not me
so if we go back to Amazon let's search
for maze programming this book I didn't
read it but I just noticed this book so
for example you can so so what this book
do is it teaches you how to program how
to generate mazes so they have all
different kind of may mays so it's you
know that's interesting
so the I mean there's a lot like a lot
algorithm like okay so let me let me
talk about that okay so here's a book
maze book
okay so so when you talk about you want
the project you know for example when
you draw a maze like this when you when
you write a program to talk to create a
maze like that there are two aspects one
is the algorithm how do you you know how
do you what what is the algorithm to
create a maze like that okay you can use
any language almost any language to do
it
now the second part is almost the more
practical and more important and also
offered and also more difficult because
so this part is 90% of you actually do
this part is about the technology to do
it for example what programming language
do you use you can use Java you can use
Mathematica you can use goal and then if
you use you know in then then the second
question what technology do you use to
create images for example in Java maybe
you use SVG or canvas they are two
entirely different you know you know one
you may not know the other you spend one
year doing one you may not be but you
cannot write SVG like vice versa so even
if you know JavaScript you may not know
neither canvas or SVG you know it's
about generating a graphics so that's
about technology JavaScript oh you use
JavaScript then you use the d3.js
library that's another entirely
different thing you know even if you are
expert at JavaScript plus canvas or
JavaScript plus SVG but if you use the
d3.js library your knowledge is not much
useful because that's a thing by itself
but on the other hand if you use
Mathematica then it's simpler because
everything is in it you can generate
graphics but but for example if you use
:
how you gonna generate the graphics then
that's an entire open question you can
go low level OpenGL oh I don't know what
: they use they they have you know links
to API to other graphics libraries I
don't know so so the tech the act the
actual technology part is actually the
most important and it's very complex so
depending on what language you want to
do and also are you doing for example if
you are you is using javascript you have
a choice of making this a desktop app or
a web app the two are the code for the
two are entirely different if you are
doing this just for a desktop app well
you could use electron okay but if you
use that to the web then then you don't
use electrons then Dane's you know it's
very different that's that's the case if
you use JavaScript but if you use for
example scheme you know scheme disp
you know that like you have the question
of how do you generate graphics or or
let's say another way you can you you
can call this you know game game
platform unity I have heard I have never
tried unity I'm pretty sure you can use
it to create this maze and in fact
actually interactive you know but I
don't
but that's entire entirely different
technology so you could you know you
could use JavaScript with different
graphics you know to : odo Julia or you
know Mathematica or unity so to you so
the question is what is your you know
what's your what is it you are trying to
learn or trying to do what is your call
big of noobs so that that is my answer
to your question about you know
suggesting a coup arboretum written
there's you know so many for example
what I do what I'd love to do is
visualization
for example let's see write a program
that creates surfaces like this you know
these are maths not you don't have to
you know let's not go complicate it
let's say Justice feel can you can you
write a program that generates a sphere
like that can you
so and what language are you gonna use
what graphics system are you gonna use
so once you choose that then then it's
about algorithms what are the ways to
generate a sphere and you wanted to be
able to rotate it in real time do you
want that feature so what argue rhythm
so and then also we can draw a maze on a
sphere we can actually start to draw a
maze for example we can see one one way
is by simply removing some of the edges
of the sphere you see though there these
are edges this sphere is made of kind of
rectangular patches you start to remove
edges so so you have to write a program
remove you know the first try might be
just remove some random randomly so so
first of all you want to find a
algorithm that kind of given 10,000
edges you want to have a random remove
random edges
you don't want you you want to yeah to
be somewhat distributed well then then
you can see a picture what is a result
then you might find that the result
doesn't look like a maze at all because
because sometimes you've removed all the
edges of a square right so then you have
to narrow down okay you know that's
things like that that's one way to do it
of course then then if you read the maze
book you probably learned quite a few
ways but also the difficulty here is
that the difficulty here you have is
that you want to draw the maze onto the
sphere you see I think this book is
mostly talking about maze on my plane
you know you draw it on the plane but
almost fear it's kind of its entire
different thing then then drop approach
so what one approach for example you can
begin by drawing a maze on the plane
then you use a stereographic projection
you use a stereographic projection let
me show you where like this okay I did a
video talking about this so you draw a
maze on the plane and you use the serial
graphic projection to project onto a
sphere then you got a main Sonisphere
that's one way okay that's just one way
oh you did that
they are quite you know so so what I'm
saying here is that I'm trying to give
some kind of my experience about how do
you approach your problem and what
possible potential algorithms you will
have to face you see when you study when
you study algorithms in school typically
typically that those are those are
classic fundamental common tasks
therefore we have those algorithms you
know people have studied them for
hundreds of years we already you know
know what's the best solution best
algorithm for doing this or that or that
that but typically in the real world
yours you are not dealing with those
because those are rhythms already in the
programming languages you know for
example you in Python : in any language
you can create a list you know you can
append element you can you know know
that those are you can sort you can so
the list just by Konya function they are
like 10 algorithms for sorting but it's
already building in language in the
language but typically in real world
like we were talking about drawing a
maze on a sphere you run into lots of
things that's you don't have you don't
you cannot just go to a book and find a
solution ok so you have to kind of find
a way yourself so so so if you are I
mean you are a computer science student
so you can
see I hope this is useful idea you know
you can see how how it gets complex how
the different aspects about tools versus
the algorithm part the algorithm part is
kind of computer science you know ways
to do something but the tools is
actually what you deal with you have to
learn the different libraries usually
involving several libraries you know
each language
each library front-end back-end you know
things like that and the graphics system
you have to then and also when you do
this for example when you want to draw a
sphere you start to need to learn quite
a few things you need you need to learn
linear algebra okay you need to learn
stereographic projection this is
typically part of complex analysis you
know you you learn that in the math
subject complex analysis and you know
you can get these pictures so you learn
you know you don't linear so so you
learn about this in complex analysis but
however they don't actually teach you
how to write a program you know the
algorithm to actually draw these they
don't teach you that you know complex
analysis teaches you about the some math
aspect about this complex frame but
anyway you don't they don't teach you
actual algorithms to draw these
they don't teach you algorithms you know
so you also learn linear algebra in
order to draw things like that sphere or
things like like that these lines and
stuff you need to have the knowledge of
linear algebra now if you take a course
of linear algebra in university they
don't actually teach you how to write a
program to do this they don't not at all
it's like that you don't learn it at all
you only learn the math concept about
projection about how how you can use
matrix to do projection okay but you
don't actually learn how to draw this
graph you cannot you know you ask most
people who have linear algebra you know
who know linear algebra and programmers
you
getting immature it you know to tour
this you have to learn like I said the
the which language which library then
then you have to actually start to get
into projection you know you you you
write a program to do projections
you know then you know in order to do
that you have to have the math knowledge
of linear algebra and and at least some
basics of the studio graphic projection
this is called stevia guava project
rejection so anyway so yeah i my point
is about you know how you know some
different aspects when you do actual
programming about you know interesting
things about algorithms about the actual
technology you need to know and and you
know and in this case linear algebra
some some math you need to know things
like that so League of noobs I hope
that's useful gotta go have a nice day
good good good night Matt implement
implemented layman trying algorithm in
Ruby oh I don't know what is that
so I think I'd been talking over an hour
now so that's it for today kind of
that's it for today
do you have github enabled home male
cats there we are male cats
plug it right in I mean thanks said
Julia have used Ruby GL glue glut4
graphics and Ruby STL for rendering JPEG
into Windows 30 so sphere in Ruby GL in
20 lines Ruby + GL and 1 means my logo
not geek stuff serious tactics
discussion do you use oak mud I don't
use oak mud I talked about this before
for half an hour in several of my videos
so if you know if just such my youtube
search for shoddy Oakmont sorry HTML vs.
oak Nybo so so do that ok yeah I talked
about oak mud it's one of the frequently
asked question and stevia graphic
projection stereographic projection is
not like a Hubert space math in school
is so boring
school is so boring
I think mostly because yeah people get
that impression but because I think
usually because the math teachers are
not good yeah I don't know what's your
case but at but are you are you like in
calculus like being beginner calculus or
precalculus zis from crazy yeah yeah it
depends on the teacher a lot you know
whether math will be interesting or not
it's hard to get 1% teacher that
actually teaches it well yes but they
are also the tasks Rob Pike has some
statements about language design yeah he
sure does he is opinionated but back
then my teacher was seeing as pedo bio
pupils
Guga
where are we okay he says Google
programmers are not researchers so land
design has to be simple to understand
yeah yeah Rob Pike Rob Pike said that
yeah there's an interesting thing about
foreign language I mentioned this before
because in our mind we want we are
thinking there must be one design that's
the best general-purpose language but
that's actually not not true because one
decision you have to make is that
typically for us hackers follow Haskell
or least pakodas we want a language
that's very flexible you know you can
put things in different places you can
you know you flip very flexible but
however such languages
examples are JavaScript Lisp Mathematica
for example in such in this very
extremely flexible languages you it's
they are not good for a team because
when you have a team of a hundred people
working on the same project everyone
writes in their own style I mean we are
not talking about line formatting you
know things like that
we are talking about the actual code can
be so many different kind of styles
there is no way no automated way to mix
them all the same no way just like
there's no way to to change one
algorithm to anyway so so the point is
each person will start to write a
different style to do exactly the same
thing so that is a problem when your
language is flexible
then we hacker types love it but then in
your team it's actually a problem
because everyone's code will be very
different then you will start to rely
heavily rely on you know some sort of
programming style guide you know
everyone need to stick to this and
that's a problem too
because because different people they
came from different Brack background
they learned this language they only use
the style they liked for example me I
could : I only do functional programming
I don't use interface you know almost
never
I just therefore I don't you have any ol
P I don't have all P structures so you
know but now you have different people
coming to work in the folk for the same
company so each one is used to their own
style of coding so so now you have to
learn about you know so it's it's kind
of a problem so in this case the better
language in a team of a large team the
better language is is those that does
not allow too much flexibility example
of such languages are Java C Java C and
Golan okay yeah :
so that is why Rob hikes made this
comment you know we you know when you
have a language there is this issue you
don't want you know if you want the
language to be a industrial language
used in big corporations then you want
it you don't want it to be very flexible
that is a kind of thing of course the
problem with that then you know we then
then you have to code lots of lines
lines then you start to have template
codes lots of templates to repeat the
same thing you know so so the point here
I am saying sighs so the concept about
one best generic purpose language is
kind of not valid you know really it
really depends on what what's exactly is
your call
okay so how many people was still
watching me I think that's it for today
16 minutes one hour and twenty one hour
in 20 seconds so anyway so today we
talked about this link thing that's kind
of annoying me so I guess I you could I
guess you are right bathroom you okay
anyway I'm glad we you know we focus on
that and that solved one thing at least
you know that's soft one thing DP will
you get on github okay so that that I
think that's it
and also I'm thinking of you know
switching time so for next week so this
week tomorrow Sunday tomorrow Saturday
and Sunday will be the same time ten o
clock okay but I'm thinking next week I
need to change to some other time
because I noticed you know like oh I
used to have a lot of strallan good
morning Kathy I used to have a lot of
strategy and people watching from Perth
but now they are gone like I don't
remember seeing them for the past you
know month because you know someone
wrote to me they told me you know 10 o
clock in Australia it's 3 o clock in the
morning so yeah I think I need to kind
of switch time I'm not sure what to do
yet because so maybe I'll have two
videos a day 30 hours each
okay so that's it for today I guess what
else I want to say it there I was going
to talk about this there is something
anyway okay so great quick chat that's
it for day thank you guys for coming by
guys Tito may be excited she uh saw to
your tomorrow yes tell me
tell them to wake up in three in the
morning yeah you need to try racket I
did try I wrote I did do racket European
time okay bye guys