the following is a conversation with
Sali the artificial intelligence machine
chat GPT describes Kali as a great
computer scientist and
essayist he is known by the programming
Community as the biggest Internet
troll he is a master of emac LP
programming language and wolam
language this is K Talk Show podcast
supported by you and now dear friends
here is
Kali [ __ ] Lex
fredman welcome to another episode of
sound talk
show so how how are you guys if you are
here say hi if you are not here skip
around play at 1 Point 1.5 speed okay
here's my keyboard glove 0 fantastic
glove 0 keyboard buy it buy it for
yourself buy it for your
friends buy it for your mom buy it for
your dad buy it for your
girlfriend glove 80 fantastic I have
reviews um on my website just search for
Kali keyboard block and it's Bluetooth
but you can also use it wired and this
is Ultimate hacking keyboard also
fantastic and this is newly ATT
trackable and uh I'm sorry my friends I
have this thing this is one of the
greatest input device but I just haven't
uh started to use it but again I will be
uh you know because there's a lot to do
with this I will be okay
so you know don't wait for it don't wait
for me you know but will be getting onto
it because my work is
usually like I I got lots of things to
do you know mathematics programming
proof Theory and my website and then on
politics and you know I got lots of
things to do so hello Louis hello Louis
from uh Germany and you are in Africa am
I right are you the Louis I
know I believe you are in wait Spain or
is it Africa something
uh what's up why are you going there so
today is random okay random talk show
and uh my keyboards okay let's go back
to my live uh
screenshot uh you know we were talking
about Lex fredman which is
a kind of like a career careerist career
careerist
careerist you know in other words in
Zuma's Jon he's a grifter okay is a kind
of you know gri okay so anyway so c talk
show we're going to talk about emac yeah
let's talk about emac emac and emac lisp
the greatest lisp programming
language and the wolam language wolam
language in fact is the greatest
lisp uh and okay so so Random is so okay
so Random is chat am I alive alive and
kicking audio check video check and say
hi chat checking hello oo hello Dan V
from Spain oh hi
Ola uh yeah so yeah so Random if you
have any questions just ask me okay
today's like random is talk show any
questions ask me uh okay where am I
where do we start okay so I want to talk
I want to show about some e you know as
so ask me questions okay so let me type
it uh because later people don't know
ask me any questions you ask I talk
today is
randomish topic you know that is there
is redundant because random topic is
sufficient so in English writing you
want generally to remove redundancy
randomish topic and by the way random is
the is is informal English you don't
actually have that is
word uh but anyway so Rand random like
like the reded scum the reded you know
be who which became a scum red website
you know they sell por since like 10
years ago like massive you know once a
website allow pong it becomes 90% pong
you know all the traffic is p red it
[ __ ] you know it's not just Reddit and
you can't blame just the Reddit people
is because since about 2006 there's a
massive deep
State s censorship complex you know
massive they infiltrate they they they
kind of push you force you to all the
tech companies that's why Reddit Google
even Hacker News they
become I support the current thing you
I I support the current thing
yes
whatever
hello oh oh
Switzerland Louis from Switzerland
really wait are you oh yeah oh yeah
Switzerland
right good morning
coffee US Army be all you can be by the
way this is a very very quality cup for
my neighbor heavy and uh you see this is
carved in you see this this um these
decorations they are actually carved
into
it it's not just printed so I mean so
this is a high quality cup
okay uh okay pay me pay me so I buy
those fancy cameras you know I looked
into webcams because my webcam is lousy
like for example when I do a lot
keyboard reviews right you know for this
setting is clear but but you can't get
close you know when you look watch other
people's YouTubers there are like
millions of them reviews on keyboard on
microphone on anything on computers on
iPad iPhone or C you know they they are
the they are kind of the grifter because
everyone sees oh there's money you know
they they try trying to be a star but if
you watch their video they they you know
their videos is you know like very high
quality right and professional almost
professional quality and you
see and they have sharp pictures but for
me you see it's not really good so I
need a camera you know so I looked into
you know how to buy a camera and by the
way chatter bait oh my God amazing I
discovered chat B this year 1 million
girls the most beautiful girls 1 million
and they are just spreading their legs
and talking and they they all have high
quality cameras okay so I looked into
how to buy a camera like oh for a
beginner blogger you need to this Sony
or or Sony or or Canon something $600
beginning for beginning
blogger $600
my camera is like the Logitech $40 okay
this one from five years ago from
actually by
now 10 years ago and the other one is
chi China Cheapo
$30
so so this one you are seeing you are
watching me vi are the China chipo
camera okay I have a I have a I have a
Blog about it it's called SPO but China
chipo they don't have a brand name like
they change every every every few month
you know they don't really have a brand
name you just you just buy it okay and
it's usable so you are watching me via
this spto China chipo camera $30 or
something and the other one over here is
the Logitech you know the the the not
log Tech 92 or something the most
common um but it's got focusing issues
okay so so again today's random you ask
questions I answer okay because once I
started to talk about something it's
going to be nonstop okay I want to talk
about we haven't talked about emac for a
while for for a month or two so I I've
been busy you know I've been coding on
my website so for example you should you
know again you guys check out my website
yeah buy me buy me a pay me donate okay
PayPal patreon or you can use the you
know the Google the
YouTube uh what they call it you know
the Super Chat you know Ching super chat
but but Google takes half of
it um yeah so pay me PayPal okay PayPal
is the best or Amazon gift card onadi
website right so you go to kadi
website kadi doino
and you see H how chat GPD says I'm
beautiful and then at the bottom you got
the links to PayPal or Amazon gift card
okay or or patreon me and let me thanks
to
Dion and Allan who in the past few years
have paid me like $2,000 each or more so
Dion and Allan they are my biggest
supporters um
yeah anyway so I want you know I'm going
to start to talk about emac just post
your questions I'll read it and I'll get
to it okay the you know so I've been
busy you know like so you go to my
website s
code. info and you see I got I got like
10 blogs so I've been writing about them
keyboard BL blog which I haven't done
much in by the way there's a news on
keyboard there's this one com upcoming
this is superb okay I believe this from
kesis this is combines combines the best
of Microsoft natural because the
Microsoft natural keyboard people love
it people really love it you know the
foam Factor the design the shape however
they don't you know their key switch is
Rober doome is very
bad and you know so people really want
can we get you know we want a Microsoft
natural keyboard you know what they call
Microsoft natural that's their marketing
term for their ergonomic keyboard but
they want the mechanical switch and and
now kis seems to have done it kesis
mwave keyboard so this is coming in
2025 Merry Christmas and happy New Years
guys uh so I work on you know tons of
keyboard emac blog programming blog web
dev blog and uh math blog which I
haven't done for for for two month or so
and by the way this this this one is
from Notch the guy who created
the the Minecraft you know kind of
edotic game you know 3D with blocks
blocky 3D in today's technology you know
like technology you're supposed to have
realistic computer Graphics right but
the the NCH created like oh let's do 3D
but let's just use like to Illegal idiot
but anyway he's a very smart guy and he
started to do this and he he's actually
genuine you know this Notch guy is a
genuine genuine person okay he's very
rich of course million multi-millions
right because he created Minecraft which
became the most popular game some 10
years ago I never played it though
but so I don't know who he is you know
I'm not into m craft at all at all
because that that game is insulting to
me you know so but but in the past five
years since about 2008 19
2018 I started to know a bit about oh
there's this Notch guy oh he created
Minecraft and then this social justice
Warrior controversy you know during the
social justice uh Warrior era from about
2016 to let's say to today is kind of
dead you know social then then they they
they complain about the notch guy oh
he's this or that but
he as far as I observed on Twitter or
Ellen X he's a very good guy okay he's
very good integral
person and he and and super smart okay
he once wrote a JavaScript I still don't
understand
okay okay I'm starting to ramble ramble
all over
he created a
um let me show you quickly okay so I
kind of digressed into the notch so he's
a great person okay because I interacted
with him on Twitter a few times like
he's got the million you know Millions
followers normally when when you when
you talk or reply to any of these very
popular guys on
Twitter they don't see your message they
they ignore you and they know they don't
they don't they don't care especially
the Zoomers you know the you know these
gri grifters you know but not he
actually replied to to my
post like
twice uh yeah like one you know one time
about four years ago or
something like one like he he usually
post you know he doesn't make
a complete comprehensible post he just
post whatever you know whatever he's
thinking like at the moment so often
times you don't know what he's saying
like he post a lot like this one
sentence or two sentence random things
okay so usually some people are like
that so you read his you follow him you
don't know what he's talking
about so one time about four or five
years ago actually I also have a Blog
about it I I think so
wait uh yeah I think I have a Blog about
it about five years ago so one time I I
I complained I replied to his post I say
this guy you know what the [ __ ] is he
saying you know he's like he just like I
complain about the fact that he doesn't
make he he doesn't make his post like
something understandable to the public
then he actually replied he actually
replied genuinely oh because you know
yeah well you know he says I was saying
this and that you know so that shows me
he's a he's a genuine guy okay you want
you want to follow genuine people you
don't want to follow like many of these
politicians bden for example and and
lots of these YouTube grifters they post
things their goal is to become a
influencer to make money okay they don't
they don't actually talk or or to talk
what they actually think you know they
they whatever their behavior online is
just to what's the way to make my post
go viral you know
that I would say at least half half all
all all of this popular you know with
million followers on Twitter are like
that okay they are like scums I don't
follow those you know usually I don't
follow anyone who is like got have a
million followers I don't follow unless
I have very very specific reason I
follow very I don't follow you know I
I'm very careful who I follow for
example this few
people I follow okay I know exactly who
they are what they do what's their
nature uh you know you know that like I
know exactly so I don't follow random
especially especially those you know
grifted like part popular you know they
like [ __ ] [ __ ] they they they are all
kinds you know grifting about drama
about social justice about women
feminism or dead rape or that the
[ __ ] the American white man thing or
pedal you know that like the white man
is into those
things I don't understand then there's
MAA grifters Pro Trump grifters then of
course there are like 10,000 you know
Democratic Liars they just lie every day
um you know so so anyway back to uh
Notch so he's genuine and and then few
weeks ago he posted about this you know
he he's he's you know playing he's still
code he still code so he he created this
hyperbolic structure
okay so I you know I you know I just
made a comment you know I wish there's a
game engine that allow n nukan and
higher Dimensions you know because I
wrote an article about 10 years ago that
about what do we need for in a game
engine in the next 10 years you know I
want a game engine that's just not ukian
3D geometry I wanted it to be able to
handle higher Dimensions projected into
3D and or and also uh aot
hyperbolic geometry you know so you
don't have to act Cod it yourself you
can use the game engine you know so he
actually replied you know I feel like a
hyperbolic 4D space would probably be
too big so yes I I I'd also like to play
around with it so genuine you know you
you get
genuine thoughts interaction with people
so I like you know I I think the notch
guy is great but I don't really know uh
too much about him so but let me uh let
me regroup okay keep questions coming
okay let me regroup to there's a few
things I wanted to
say so today's talk show uh about
notch game engine that's one topic we uh
we talked about and
then not 3D JavaScript okay he created
that I'm going to show you in a minute
uh then am I going live say hi where is
Tiffany
do
Jesus okay so
actually
uh okay so Notch and 3D JavaScript
engine okay so let me show you that that
that 3D JavaScript engine where is
it uh
okay so it's not here then
um search for 3D search for Notch no
it's not there okay let's go to
uh uh
Dev C web dev blog SVG no uh we want to
just search
Okay
3D oh yeah there JavaScript 3D MineCraft
demo
amazing you see this became very popular
about 10 years ago uh
2012 Notch wrote it and here's a code
you know here is a code um let me show
you so go to talk
show yeah so here is the link then go to
the page show in
browser and then um here's a
code okay so it's just uh 200 lines of
code
JavaScript you know no libraries no
nothing just pure JavaScript 200 lines
of code uh you can see
this is old JavaScript still using V
actually I I I'm going to you know
convert it to uh new Javascript app you
know JavaScript 2016 so you don't have
this V thing so anyway this so this is
amazing I still don't understand
it okay let me read the comments okay no
comments what are you guys doing 17
people watching no comments where where
you guys came from you guys can know me
from my emist coding or from my wolf
language coding or you guys know me from
my keyboard blog or my Unicode stuff or
you guys know me from forchan like you
know say
it you ask me questions I talk okay then
uh if no questions I going to talk about
Emil and
EAC so then V says you won't believe
this but the government here launched
proposal to limit the amount of home you
could consume each month you have to
register and then spend some kind of
tokens what what where is
that the government there uh spend in
wow oh yeah Louis hi Louis Louise know
me from emac yes so okay that's about
notch you know that's JavaScript stuff
okay so um let's drink it back you know
it's quite quite incredible but I I mean
it's I you know I don't think it's too
deep but this kind of thing is what you
know by heart if you write you know if
if you do game coding
um so there are some things I don't get
you know you can see it's a loop okay so
but how does he yeah I don't something I
don't get you see if you ask me to do
this it's going to be more than 200
lines of code you know you you need to
create lots of Cubes okay they
coordinates then you can of course
reposition them in in l of places and
you have to position them in a random
way but also in a way such that such
that you can see a hole and but then you
have to um you have to write projection
because in pure JavaScript you don't
have like 3D engine so you you need to
project all the coordinates in 3D space
XYZ into a plan okay then you have to do
the then you have to do the
the the bit map you know you see the
cube the textures on the cube I I I
don't even know how to do that so I
suppose it's you know it's randomly
generated and then if you do that then
you project then that's going to be too
slow you know so I I don't know how this
is done a lot of people have like
commented on Hacker News explained it
but haven't I just haven't gone through
them uh and if I want if I you know I'm
I'm I have to uh understand this myself
I don't want read some someone else's
okay hold on a second let me get out of
the sticky key
control
okay okay so
okay so that's about that Minecraft
let's
see uh Spain
yeah you know so I don't know much about
what's going on in Spain but in UK it
became so so much worse UK and Canada
and Australia they become even worse
than USA so much censorship
you know like if you if you are a
grandma and you posted oh I don't like
the you know I don't like
Arabs they're gonna the police gonna
come knock your door and put you in jail
in UK that's happening in UK right now
so it's so bad but you know why are they
doing it it's not is it because the UK
no it's it's because the USA the USA is
is actually calling the shots
that's you know that's a deep politics
you know like most people what the
[ __ ] oh God this guy uh you know so most
people uh so what was I going to say
yeah most people you know including
me like especially programmers you know
us we don't read politics much you know
for most of my life I'm just into math
and programming like I just need to code
and math and programming learn math and
geometry and hyperbolic geometry what
they are they what exactly how you know
how they
work and programming languages right so
but usually when you get older you
started to have some pay some attention
to
politics but so anyway I I kind of
started to you know read a lot about
politics since 2006
16 uh and it so
happens that that is almost exactly the
date that the something you know
something you know something went on
with the USA deep state so they started
this huge machiner it's by intention
it's by purpose okay starting in 2016
actually it began in be it began in
Ukraine you know it's kind of Sil you
know it Act actually did you know so
because by now you know because I've
been reading so much politics since
2016 2016 is the beginning of the social
justice War years you know you begin to
have this patriarchy how uh men are evil
men are evil from from even from 2,000
years ago men men are the [ __ ] face you
know men are the scum of
everything you begin to hear that and
all the people all the [ __ ] like
college students are saying that what
the [ __ ] is going on like actually
basically happen overnight all of a
sudden then you have the safe space then
you have lots of you know lots of you
know one bunch of jargons then you have
CIS sex you know like the gender is
constructed you have like oh you are you
are
CIS CIS yeah like oh oh oh now I'm CIS
like meaning heterosexual
heterosexual the [ __ ] white man's
Obsession about this Jons to describe
you know your sexualy and whatever but
then then oh I got a new name I'm a CIS
then you know starting in 2016 all all
this you know beginning you know so
that's a social justice Warriors what I
call so I I'm surprised you know I
started to look look into what's going
on then after like four years then the
covid happened oh my God covid is
massive scale you know it's
death uh what how many million you know
few million people
died then you know the V and we don't
know what's going on back then you know
and there's heavy censorship we kind of
live in fear remember do you remember
during the covid years you know that's
about four five years
ago literally people are dying you know
I know mathematicians for example Conway
John Horton Conway one of the greatest
mathematician one of my favorite let's
let's say top three favorite
mathematician he died why because covid
okay so we live in in fear you know like
from China you got this virus over you
know people are dying with you know a
lot then you got the Alex Jones Co man
who is like oh we need to like start to
like apocalypse you know another white
man thing Christianity they are obsessed
with the end of the day you know
something apocalypse then then you got
these gun Tarts American white man you
you you you need to start to stock up
food and you know you know this this
this that then you know so then Italy
and you see the map you know dying and
and some videos you know people dying
Millions
dead Co you know and it turns out now I
know now we know you know it's a fact Co
is a USA United States of America deep
State bioweapon research went
wrong but it came from China right yeah
USA funded it because USA because
there's a law by Obama you cannot do
bioweapon research in USA so the fory do
it in you know let's do it in Ukraine in
China you
know and it turns out it's bioweapon gun
wrong that's not you know bi you know
you guys know what is
bioweapon that's like oh I want all
China men dead you know you can create
the virus that just kill China men or or
Jew or white men or black people or or
or Indian or whatever you know you can
like that's what that's the meaning
that's the that's the that's the
ultimate you know go bioweapons you know
you can create a v virus the you know
the it will it can check your DNA like
who you are and determine it's skill or
not biow weapon you know it's not
allowed it's internationally banned but
USA is like the you know the Deep state
is doing it and they they have like 20
by weapon research in
Ukraine So Co million died and they
tried and the drug companies they for
sale push the VX on you they make
billions of dollars you
know okay you know so 2016 social
justice Warriors you know patriarchy you
know men are evil then covid happened
then the trans okay the r rise of the
trans
trans is the god king of everything you
must
respect if you dare to say on Twitter
for example during the Jack dorsy
scumbag he should go to jail okay Jack
doy before Alam musk you know if you say
oh men and women are actually different
you get cancelled your account get
cancelled if you are too loud your bank
get cancelled you know that's what
happen that's what
happening so I started to read you know
about politics since 2016 then you know
like you you have to read you know like
there lots of sensors I got I got
censored myself one day I posted you
something about this girl this rightwing
you know pretty face you know I think I
I said something you are you are like
a brainless blonde you know then then
then
Twitter says your account is going to be
cancelled unless you
apologize delete that message and
apologize then your account will come
back I have I have log of it I have a
Blog of it okay I don't I'm not sure I
want to show it you just if you really
know me you can find it okay s Twitter
Twitter band you know I have a
screenshot of it
you know and they sensored they cancel
Jordan Peterson on Twitter lots of
people you know like lots of people and
the covid the doctor you know the the
doctor who who who who think it's fake
news about covid and you know you if you
say anything against what the the top is
pushing you get banned or cancelled so
it's very bad so then okay so after Co
so social justice War years
2016 Co
and then all they are then the black Liv
matters massive burning of buildings you
know and and you know all over USA and
the Mayors kneel down to this
antifa yeah you guys remember the
pictures the videos like the you know
all over USA you know the black life
matters then then Co then then then
Ukraine war you know over said that oh
you Russia invaded Ukraine Ukraine war
Ukraine
war and you know I didn't know what is
Ukraine before like where is Ukraine
what is Ukraine I didn't know so I start
to read and what is Russia what you know
I thought Moscow you know I thought
Moscow is above China you know on the
east side like near
Japan I didn't I didn't know you know so
what's the what's the difference what
what's Ukraine what what is Russian
what's the difference between Russian
you know white russian girls versus the
northern European girls you know I don't
know but I find you know the white girls
so attractive to me the blond blonde and
blue
eyes now I know you know now now I know
the
difference so I did you know Ukraine war
happened what's going on so I started to
read and you I spent you know like an
hour a day for the past
uh 10 years basically on Twitter and
elsewhere you know so I learned now I
know I know lots of this stuff you may
not know if you don't care and you know
so so you can what happened I I started
to read about it every day on on T
Twitter and also telegram you started to
see
real real movies of killing okay like
the Americans we used to love oh war war
movies you know massive big giant screen
blood tank oh so so horrible you know we
enjoy
it you know like
the you know the saving P Private Ryan
you see and several others platoon and
you know lots of but now you see actual
real footage of War
yeah people die you know you you see in
live videos how people die how they are
arm got blown off or head got blown off
or you or just dying on some other way
you
see you can see them if you actually try
to see it I I I see I see them almost
every day since the Ukraine war on
February late February 20 um 22 was it
Ukraine war okay I started to look into
what's going on who who is doing this
you
know I I started to look into and of
course then then there's lots of fake
news you can talk on Twitter you know
then a bunch of you know people will get
angry even including sometimes including
your friends you know on this
sensitive issues related to war or race
or religion you know even even your
friend you can see some of your friend
is supporting Ukraine or supporting the
social justice Warriors or telling you
how you should VX and you know Co you
know and so
on so created lots of problem so UK can
walk you know I I see the videos and
they say oh they are Nazi I actually I
see the you know if you if you don't
actually seek the info you will not know
okay if you are just passive you know
reading whatever come to your Twitter
you know then you wouldn't know nothing
all you know is just fake news you know
you have to look into and El the
character too so you have to dive into
they are truthful in you don't know if
it's truth truthful or not you just have
to read and read a lot okay and even
eventually you'll know what's you know
what kind of poster or info is this or
that so I I read you know and you know
so you can so you see live video footage
and I can tell you the difference
between real war and killing videos
versus the movie version you see in
movie version Hollywood you know Saving
Private Private Ryan it's pretty
realistic right you know because the
technology even though it's a movie but
you you know you see giant tanks or or
or sort of guns or grenade and they go
off and people die and the horror on
their face and so on
and the picture are crystal clear you
know very sharp you can have like giant
screen like America oh I buy a giant
TV you know you can that's that's
the that's a movie version of War okay
you can also see the real version today
what why you can see it because
technology the cell phone you know like
today's war everywhere on Earth you can
almost like see it real footage a lot of
them are fake of course because of the
info War you know the fake news million
BS from this faction million other BS
from that faction they sometimes they
fake videos there are lots of tons of it
okay but you will also see real ones so
what's the difference between the
Hollywood war video footages well the
real ones first of all you don't get a
clear picture it's not crispy like you
know like oh bloody and giant tanks and
you know you don't get get that but you
see like fuzzy sometimes you don't know
what's going on fuzzy
pictures I mean it's it's not crispy and
detailed but but you but so you don't
know what's going on you don't you don't
see a giant tank coming in and then
another tank they fight you know you
don't see things like
that so you but you see tanks you know
but all all people get killed you know
but it's like it's like you don't know
what's going on
you know so lots of that okay lots of
that and uh then the real torture you
know what it means you know torture re
like real like not in the movies like
taking your eyes out this footage of
like that that like that and and and and
fairly a lot okay oh uh and
uh and of course there beheading from
Middle East lots of it you can see today
so anyway Ukraine war so I looked into
you know so I now now I know a lot you
know I know a lot what's going on if you
if you want to know you know from the
top you know people you can trust today
it's very easy es especially become
because of the Trump you know Trump W
the election the American people
actually they know what's going on they
they you know American people they voted
for Trump which I voted for Trump too
right um so so if you want to know
what's going on in Ukraine watch this
one tur Carson okay tur Caron he
interviewed this guy is know Great
American this guy is Jeffrey saxs
okay and uh then watch another one by
Mike Ben okay also on tuer and and uh
also on Joe Rogan Joe Rogan interview
Mike Ben
okay
so so if you have no idea what's going
on you can you can watch this video I
mean whether you're going to believe it
or you think it's I'm just like posting
fake news it's up to you but you but you
but today you can you know I can
recommend you know if you don't know
nothing what's going on you can watch
these videos
okay so social justice Warriors
2016 black life matters okay after that
Co after that then Ukraine then Ukraine
war happened okay then of out of the
blue the Gaza thing happened that's
that's that's the most that's another
very sensitive the the actually maybe
the most sensitive of all this okay the
Gaza happened
okay I don't know what is Gaza I never
heard of it I don't know exactly what's
Jews you know I thought you know all the
Jews are just white people you know I
just you know I've been living in
America for for since
1989 so you know it's been 40 years yeah
I hear about Jews I know it's a race but
I don't exactly know what they you know
exactly what they are it it just to me
America is just white people okay white
people black people then then the red
skin American Indians then then Indian
Indians then then then Asians you
know I don't know you know that's my
picture of of Jew before it's just white
man so Gaza happened of course that's a
very deep complex topic right there is
lots of fake news there's lots of pro
this or Pro that you know or again is
this that but again you read you start
to read you just read read this this
this you read then you get then you you
have an idea what's going
on another you know so it's pretty sad
picture so actually we went into
politics you know politics you know non
technical topic lots of people
watching always the case when you do
programming you know one two people
watching when you talk non technical
lots of people watching okay so what is
going on here let's
see so yeah let me summarize you know so
this all these happenings right then you
got uh let me show you some my of my
website
okay yeah yeah uh so you know so let me
show you some of some of my worksite you
know
um so this is my art blog Kar art blog
go to Kar art blog it's
on.org
and uh let's go to this section Chan art
Index this is the
Zuma melen and Zuma art
you know you are familiar with this you
know Pepe and this one is a great video
one of the greatest artwor okay in my
judgment this one so very
funny you know this memes you know memes
they
capture phenomenon from people's
perspective you know from average
people's P perspective you know so this
this depict
basically Fair fairly well what's going
on in the past 10 years you know the
social justice War years online drama
clickbait and you know and angry people
shouting Pro this or anti that uh you
know yeah so that's you know
then then that's that's marking the
Kardashian
Kardashian a woman who became famous
because of her sex tape doing
sex and and selling her ass and tits
every day
uh she went on into the New York Times
what is it Time Magazine You Know cover
showing her ass that's what this image
depicts you know you are not seeing the
bottom
but
that's you know that's the you know the
Kardashian okay so what I want to show
this is also a great art I love it Pepe
got a good girlfriend you know you know
so people who is the artist you know
they they it's a great art okay okay you
also got the you have to have a sense of
what's going on to capture to you you
know you need the
skill the drawing skill but you also
need
the create creative skill and understand
socially what is going on in order to
create a very good memes and artwork
like like these okay so for example this
one it captures you know the
relationships between male and female
this one for example why because you can
see you know you know you can see this
is kind of a common you know the girls
they smile and
they you know if you if they are your
girlfriend you know they hug you but the
guys usually are you know not smiling
and you know just sitting there so it
captures you know this kind
of phenomenon okay but what I want to
show is this we were talking about you
know then people
see you know the the social justice
Warriors the trans the BL
BLM you know then the Ukraine war then
Haller I support her I I stand with
Ukraine I stand with her you know I
stand with you know
whatever so people see it they created
this meme I support the current thing
you know I'm not into memes so when I
first saw
this uh this this came about you know
before 20
2022 so when I so when I first saw this
you know I I thought well you know the
Zuma idiots you know they are creating
you know they are trying to make fun of
things but actually this meme captures
the the feeling of you know a lot of a
lot people what what is going on oh yeah
and I want to show you this you know for
example what's going on uh for example
this is what is going on
okay you
see this is what going on okay let let
me show it uh this
one you see a photo someone with the
Ukraine flag and black life
matters and then inductor fory We
Trust how do they relate you
see why are people you know like suppose
you are a black person right you support
black life
matters but would you care about Ukraine
or the or the you know the doctor fory
the medical issues usually not you know
I mean usually I mean you you wouldn't
be passionate about the other things you
if you are Ukraine Ukrainian or Russian
do you care about black life matters
usually not and if you are really
concerned you you know you if you are
American citizen you are very concerned
about health you think that we should
take the V vaccine to prevent you know
spread of the you know the mysterious
you know natural disease or
whatever you you you are usually not you
know why do you push for the black life
matters and you can so so you got this
photo you know you got this kind of
thing and by the
way we we don't know for sure this photo
is real okay A lot of times you know
tremendous fake news someone can just
put this together right so you have to
know
that but in any
case we know this kind of personing
because you know like like like why why
you have this you know like like the
patriarchy and then
trans okay so
patriarchy men all males are evil then
you got trans trans is the best thing
the most moral and women is you know
women shouldn't be called women they
just they should be called the person
who can you know who's got a [ __ ] you
know something something like that you
know they don't call it women anymore
why do this you know so Mike Ben
captured this very very well you know
mik Ben you should
follow literally the only thing these
things have in common is that they are
backed by the state okay that's what
really going on so so then we have this
meme I support the current thing you
know this really captures the sentiment
the mentality of you know of seeing this
these things in the past 10
years um okay that's about it I think uh
maybe right been one hour
already
almost okay so no emac disp no EAC disp
today
cheers what are you guys seeing me yeah
okay so cheers and maybe that's it for
today
so let's see the
questions
uh second
do you know the elom huge track B of
course I do uh so let me show you
my keyboard blog uh so you can just go
to SAR keyboard blog and uh let's see
hold on a second so s keyboard
log yeah
[ __ ] what I want to know
is okay
so so there's a track ball section so
you can see all kind of track
balls basically almost every track B
that exist on Earth well not every
but yeah so the you know elom huge uh
which I don't think is the best but a
lot of people like it my friend and
Emily showed this
video uh and uh then you have track boo
history so I'm
just showing my site for those of you
who don't know I talked about this all
the time has like 100 videos in the past
four years talk show about it
so let me just quickly answer the
um the comments so what about
um keyboard layouts oh yeah fantastic
that's another thing why don't you have
soy Jack I do juang
okay okay from juang
one is a longtime customer one is into
the the the meme crab the mean idiots
you know the the most
um so Jack you want to see sorry Jack
there it is okay so where is it yeah
Chan art there it is sorry
Jack wait sry Jack uh well it's kind of
related to that but
no se well there's a so
Jack by the way so we were talking about
this you know so all these things why
did all these thing
happen patriarchy social justice
Warriors
BLM
Co bioweapon went
wrong then then then the Ukraine war and
the Gaza you know they all actually have
to do with one thing this United States
step
State
[Music]
um okay
so they started around 2014 I learned
from Mike B and
others basically all this
[ __ ]
is designed and planned beginning in
2014 now who designed it why are they
doing it it be it actually it's kind of
surprising or maybe not surprising it
started with NATO
na which is the military organization of
United States of America in Europe okay
a military organization NATO that begin
at all the social justice Warriors the
black life matters and and all that
okay uh it's it's kind of sad so if you
want to know you know politics at least
my opinion I I tell you okay I tell you
in kind of in a sum in in in a summary
uh
way and why they are they doing it
because
because there's there's billions and
billions
dollars that's
involved and this money goes to the bank
to the bosses of the bank to the bosses
of the bankers the O makers you know the
the the politicians in USA okay most of
this money they sprad to these thousands
of people Mega rich people that's why
this is
happening okay that's it for today so
let's
see shaders on Shader toy are crazy is
it like those Shader
Snippets yeah those technology of
computer Graphics I don't really know
shaders not uh not that
guy
something
uh thank you start your own gold M let's
go back to emac oh yeah wow it's too
late
I just chime in in since looking at your
Website Layout okay sorry Jack
understand Asian people like these cute
pictures so much oh yeah
that so about
Asian that's another story you see
because as Asians um well we you know
it's it's it's funny in America they say
they just say as Asian they don't you
know they you know most Asian in America
is Chinese okay but they don't want to
say Chinese because you know Chinese is
like the enemy of
USA so they say Asian you know whenever
Chi Chinese people
get robbed or beaten by black people in
the past few years happening a lot they
just say oh Asian
Asian uh but anyway Asian you see and
well and speaking of Asian this Japanese
okay Japanese and
Chinese these two are the big
ones now mostly the white people well
the all the America they know about
Japanese because
why it's not because for some reason the
white culture prefer the Japanese
culture more than Chinese no it's
because politics because USA and and
Japan they are so-called friends
made the decision is made by the top
people like those people who began
Ukraine war Iraq war or the Gaza thing
okay those people determines who are
friends so the Japan Japan
is friends with USA you know not China
because China oh my God how can you it's
communist they are not Christians they
you know they should die so Japan is
friendly so the Japanese culture the
anime the girl the under the te the
pedal the te girl you know the little
girls with panties showing that's in
Japanese anime It's All Over America you
familiar with it right not China you
know you you know you you don't even
know what's the difference but anyway
but but the anime they they they they
came from Japan Japan is actually the
best
you know they started
the the illustration that
Japan you know is the best doing that
so uh so that's a good reason anime is
popular but anyway
so so most white Americans they would
know something
about [ __ ] Japan or [ __ ] Japanese Zen you
know Zen Dojo the game of
Go what what the [ __ ] does the go me
that's a Japanese word not the Chinese
word the Chinese word for that go game
in English is literally called surround
game you surround the pieces you know
it's in Chinese it's called
Wei uh but Japanese learned it you know
long ago like a thousand years ago the
original Chinese word is G or something
you know language evolves so anyway the
the name in English is co called go and
that came from the Japanese name from it
you know I I I every time I read about
it I I get annoyed because I I I was
born in Taiwan I'm a Chinese right so I
grew up with this
game and then in English what why are
they calling It Go I mean and and not
just go but there's a lot of things you
know like origami origami lots of things
they use a Japanese name but the
Japanese name I don't know I'm not
familiar with it you know how come you
so there's lots of
that well because [ __ ] Japan and USA are
friends and China is enemy to to this
you know this this this Elite Americans
so that's why so you don't know you know
for example in Buddhism you know about
you hear Japanese zen zen o Dojo you
know a lot programming stuff oh learn
the dojo of Ruby or whatever whatever or
or or or the Sensei Sensei you know like
Japanese terminologies
but you know but the Japanese culture
actually most of it is borrowed from
China but today because China became
became so prosperous so powerful you
know you started to hear people use the
Chinese terms for ex for example Sensei
for teacher is um suu right okay in ch
in Chinese suu and and and anyway lots
of
things so what I'm saying is that in
America most white people whenever you
know something about
Asian you you typically think about CH
uh
Japanese but a lot of that is actually
just Shar shared across
Chinese Japanese and Korean because they
and they are actually all rooted from
China uh because you know just because
historically China is this big you know
country so so why do Asian people like
those cute pics so you see the reason so
the Asian culture or Far East you know
Chinese Japanese Korean they don't you
know we are not not white people
basically you know to put it
bluntly different people have
different cultures have different per
perspectives so to the white men you
know I'm bitching about this all the
time the white people they are concerned
about justice justice uh rape uh pedal
you know they are concerned about this
every day their brains like you know
like you need Justice and and and logic
you need argument Precision you you know
you
you know and precision like Jordan
Peterson oh you know top seven things
you need to do learn to be precise you
know learn your oration skills Western
philosophy right you know logic and
Justice and and and you know and what
you know you know and you know the you
know respect and individuality and
freedom yeah that's that's Western
culture you know
uh but Asian Chinese Japanese Korean
they don't think that way it's not like
that okay and they don't have the your
your sense of pedal you know the white
sensitive thing like everything is pedal
pedal oh my God
pedal so that's why you see in Japanese
you got you know you know you got this
you know like how is she you know you
got these kind of things and Japanese
are fine and I am Chinese I'm fine with
it I don't have a problem
okay so in simply the Japanese you know
the Chinese Japanese Korean they don't
we are not white people so you guys have
your culture and thinking and P
perceptions which is different from from
from our from us
okay that's it bye guys sorry I didn't
capture all your questions but it's
been uh
over an hour
now how did you find that keyboard block
so fast I must show you later my system
H you should play the original Dukes X
okay I don't know what is that game
Chinese are friends of me not
enemy uh different culture okay okay bye
guys yeah so Random politics
today thanks for watching
don't forget if you like my stuff put
money in my pocket okay just go to
cinfo go to the bottom you'll see my
Amazon and PayPal and
patreon that's the most important okay
pay for whatever you use you know like
forget about the open source each which
you know once you pay
everything tends to go correctly