good morning guys
welcome to another episode of SCI talk
show and today's topic is going to be
non tech none technical introduction to
JavaScript okay so let me put the title
here and I'm waiting for people to come
in and then take intro to JavaScript
JavaScript land and other things okay
so when I'm working for people to coming
so what I mean by non techie intro I
don't know I'm just going to talk some
you know random topic so yesterday I did
a YouTube video livestream why
email is sucks and there was a big one
and I end up wanting for like 90 minutes
and you know when you do video you you
actually learn a lot of things about
yourself you know I've been doing videos
for the past thirty minutes thirty half
a year hi guys and you know you learn
things about yourself so I learned that
that I don't communicate well I mean
most specifically I don't my English
articulation is pretty bad but I have
been doing videos you know forth for
half a year now and you know you improve
like you you know I'm for example you
know I'm okay for example I'm improving
my English articulation articulation
meaning the pronunciation and you know
and and other things like not being
sloppy you know sometimes my in a rush
to talk about things I get sloppy and
when I get sloppy you know your your
pronoun SHhhh my pronunciation gets bad
you know you you start to hear more
typical Chinese accents you know just
and also I learned you know when you do
video also I learned that for example
usually you know I'm socially socially
inept that is in social situations you
know I'm a nerd in social situations I
don't I don't talk much and when I do
you know
it's it's not well expressed like
whatever opinions it's not well
expressed so anyway so I learned that
when I do start to do videos and and you
watch yourself and so you know there's
articulation and there is so I don't I
don't express myself well but I learned
that so you you start to actually you
know like like when you want to like
sometimes when I want to say some ideas
especially around people I don't know
you know or you know let's say meetings
you know the you know accompanying a
meetings like you I feel like you don't
you know you know you you think maybe
everyone knows yeah and you don't say it
when anyway I learned that you know you
just have to say it like a lot people
don't know and okay anyway so but yeah
okay let me finish my thought
you see that's an example you know
that's a that's not a thing you want you
want to do you want to you know when you
have some idea just express it
completely and people will like it you
know not necessarily everyone but you
know anyway so today I'm going to talk
about I don't have a focused topic but
I'm thinking I'm going to focus so I'm
going to talk about JavaScript the
language so but anyway but Mandy I want
you guys to type ok type here type here
you know let me know what you want is
you know ask questions comment whatever
I said you know you have your opinions
coming and you know keep the
conversation going
you know that's what what they say you
know I learned this from Tim for Tim for
there's a guy on YouTube named Tim for
or think Tim cast
if you can search his name like team
team for sometimes he goes by team cast
and at at the end of every video he will
say you know let me know what you think
first you post your comments below you
know keep the conversation going so you
know yeah so type things you know keep
the conversation going because you know
I don't know what to talk about you know
I'd like I you know my my video is not
scripted so you know it's you know I
like it to be like a conversation like
when you go out with the friends you
know whatever topics come to mind and
you you you say it you know you talk
about your opinions anyway so I was
going to I I think I was going to talk
something about JavaScript
you know something about JavaScript you
know if you guys don't comment now if
you guys don't comment anything you know
usually that will end up you know my
video will just end up me you know
telling you to read my websites so let's
see Java JavaScript in depth but if you
comment you know say anything you want
you know when you come and then I you
know I have a topic to talk about
for example JavaScript you know you know
right now I'm just talking to myself you
know keep keep the comment coming you
know to just type so for example
JavaScript so I wrote this tutorial I I
spent like two years full-time basically
writing this tutorial and this is the
most in-depth tutorial of all of my
tutorials
so you go to Casali dot info and you go
to let's say programming blog and you go
to on top there's a link to tutorials
actually you can find
on the homepage you know all these
languages you know I have written
tutorials of the best ones the best ones
is this one this this this is the
JavaScript in depth is actually the best
best of them oh by far okay but you know
when you judge something you have to
give a criteria so by what means it's
the best okay so this javascript in
depth is actually the most in depth and
the most in depth that i've spent the
most time concentrated you know focused
concentrated like i want to write this
tutorial i want to dive into the
JavaScript language in depth you know i
want to read the javascript Specht you
know across script so I read the ACMA
script specification you know almost
cover to cover you know two versions of
it you know there's two xmas script 2015
and 2016 and 2017 you know you read them
in detail it's very it's very hard to
read by the way of all the language
specs I've read the JavaScript one is
one of the I would say one of the worst
you know JavaScript language so
JavaScript language is pretty bad I mean
even okay so already I have several you
know I have several topics to talk about
you know let's type it out here
javascript es2015
okay and so on keep the comments coming
okay I'm going to check the comments
every five minutes so javascript ACMA
script 15 and so on and javascript is
really a bad language
it's a confit Newland
so JavaScript 15 ACMA script - well
maybe I can talk about JavaScript
history okay but back to the hot topic I
was talking about you know I'm giving
you a introduction to my programming
tutorials so all of these the JavaScript
in-depth is the one I spent the most
time concentrated and trying to be also
professional you know by that I mean you
know just not my random my random rant
about things for example my Emacs
tutorial there's lots of rant there I
mean my Emacs website is beside besides
the tutorial you know the Emacs
practical tutorial and practical Emacs
Lisp tutorial oh these are rather
focused but besides that I have lots of
rant but anyway it's so I'm saying let's
go back to so I'm saying so this one is
the most in-depth and professional so if
you if you want to learn JavaScript this
is a good one to beat now the the other
good ones rather the other one good ones
are Python examples Python by example so
this is also you know lots of material
but but however it's it's rather it's
not it's it's best for beginners it's
rather best for beginners no this is a
no nonsense tutorial on Python but if
you already have let's say two years of
programming in Python this my tutorial
is probably now gonna do you much
so python is good and go is also good
but but this my golden tutorial is also
for beginners by the way : is now my
favorite language my favorite language
among industrial languages but if
without qualification my favorite
language is Mathematica this this
Mathematica by far so anyway so
javascript is good
the so colon is my favorite language and
my golden tutorial is great for
beginners also ok so let me finish one
thing at a time because every time I
talk about something there's so many
other things I want to talk about so
Thomas curry is good : you know you go
read it go learn it if you don't have
any goal and experience in Python it's
good and as SVG to Dario is also good
you know SVG is SVG is basically XML
it's very it's quite simple you know for
example for example you which if you
just copy this in file save it in a file
and you show in browser and you'll see
your line so it's it's just like HTML or
XML weight the syntax colouring is wrong
here so let me show you this you see all
these are written in Emacs so I open the
page so here's SPG example in browser
now you see the syntax crowing is wrong
here this SVG should be blue so I press
a key and it's return return nine of
them so let's see if it's ok it's not
corrected anyway
so it's VG tutorial a so let's go back
so SVG you know SVG is very useful if
you won't want to have any sort of graph
graphics in on a web javascript so
anyway javascript SVG goal and SVG is
part of JavaScript of course you use
JavaScript to script it the practical
Linux is also pretty good if you are new
to Linux I give you basically the my
tutorial is pretty yeah anyway anyway so
I give you all the command lines you use
the the most frequently used practical
command command lines for linear Linux
so let me check the how you do our SS on
your side I'm kind of new to the channel
but I enjoy the most video so far ok no
ninja no Z no joke yeah yeah let me talk
about both of these so is s ok let me
talk about that but let me finish the
topic here so I have these tutorials
javascript is really good go read it let
me turn off the auto click ok JavaScript
this this is the in-depth go is good for
beginner that's my favorite language
when you love something you you do good
with it so go is very good
Python is very good this is also very
good SVG introduction the the rest and
practical practical in exists also good
and eMac list my Emacs Lisp tutorial is
also very good in fact you know you
wouldn't find any ok so if you consider
all the resources on the web that are
you know that teaches eMac
you will find none that comes close so
basically this is the best in the world
period you know you know always search
for yourself you know don't don't take
my word for it but from what I have seen
you know basically email is tutorials
online doesn't exist
you know they are like you know they are
like a lot that just like one page you
know one page tutorial like one page
condensed intro you know but you know
but my is like a small book you know you
have over 100 pages and covers basically
covers you know I would it not
everything he emag this but it's a
comprehensive introduction to eMac list
and and I would also say I mean this is
my claim I would say of all printed
resources are emag list my is best okay
well partly because you know there's not
much out there this may be one this may
be to two books you know teaching eMac
this we are not counting the official
eMac this manual the the emag list
manual is like 1000 pages and it's it's
very dry and very hard to read I mean
you you know honestly if you've never
studied
eMac this before and you try to learn
eMac this from the eMac this manual
that's not going to work I mean you
that's gonna be extremely inefficient
you cannot you know spend hours in right
but you know hours reading that and you
you won't get out out of it you know
much things out of it and by the way
there is also another eMac list tutorial
that is written for beginners for
example if you are in Emacs you go to
control H I and you'll see early
subtopic
this is info Emacs info and
you so you can see there's this one
email is intro now this is written by
you know it's it's very annoying like
they don't they don't show the author
right here so you have to go let's go
down this is written by I forgot his
name but he he died about five years ago
but anyway so so this is this is this is
also on my introduction to eMac
programming English it's let's look at
it so there you have it
quick magnify so it's written by yeah
it's it's very annoying this you know
you know Richard storm and they don't
they don't list the author name at the
top I should remember you know about the
author here yeah Robert J chasse oh so
he died about maybe five years ago so
anyway I'm talking about this book so
this book is also available in printed
versions but it's pretty bad I mean well
it's not bad but it's a it's for
beginner programmers that is you never
programmed before you don't know what a
variable means you don't know what a
function means you know you don't know
what a subroutine means you know it's
for people who never programmed before
so if if that applies to you then this
is a good book but if you have maybe one
year experience programming in any
language this is not suitable because
when when I started to learn him at
least back in 2006 I try to read this
book you know it's great you know
there's a book you know well you know
comprehensive you know well I mean
introduction a great book so I think you
know I'll just skip you know parts I
already know
I know what the variable is I know
what's the function you know but that
doesn't work like you have to skip 10
pages to learn you know a tiny little
bit about email is you know you're like
so it you know you so it just doesn't
work so I read like - you know I read
five pages and I quit but on reddit you
will see people you know post a link to
this tutorial all the time if you
actually read it read it you know a lot
of people I mean that's the situation
with online stuff online postings a lot
of people will tell you that that that
they will tell you to read Emax manual
eMac this manual but very few actually
read it and because why because it's no
good you know because you know you know
try it like you know you go to eMac this
manual you tried you know try to read it
you want you know you won't last for
like a few hours okay so I'm talking
about my tutorials so JavaScript go is
good SVG Python practical Linux is good
and eMac this is very good the rest get
is also good my kid tutorial practical
get it's practical so if you haven't
used get before is it's good but the
others on they are they are not they are
still good for for beginners like you
never touched java before and you want
the basic intro you can read that same
thing for PHP closure pearl you will be
you know you'll be nice if I you know
complete them you know like finish them
but it's not worth it because you know
each of these like even one page for
example this is closure function Chinese
like some of these articles are really
great in depth
but but you know writing tutorial is not
that easy you know really because it's
different from writing blogs like if you
write a blog you know you whatever in
your mind you just write it you know you
could you know for example you if you
are programming JavaScript and if you
are you know you know working on
something at work or something and you
find some problems and you read some
website you finally discover the
solution and you plug it you know so you
know that's your blog
however it's entirely different if you
actually try to you know cover the
subject of let's say create or delete
properties in JavaScript it's gonna be
ten you know you're gonna spend ten more
you know because you cannot spend like
ten you know you cannot spend many days
just for one single topic because
because when you are blogging something
you know something come your mind you're
just trying to solve one specific
problem and also you assume your
audience already you know no you know
JavaScript and you know it's just like a
problem you want to solve so you want to
tell other people other JavaScript
programmers you know this particular
issue you know they they understand it
you know they can read your blog 8'o
this is how you do it and and then
that's it but if you are writing a
tutorial they you know there's no
context like people you know they are
not here to read your particular
thoughts you know about solving
something you know they they are trying
to learn you know the concept of
properties you know the concept of
properties and how you can read them in
and stuff you know it's like the whole
thing
you know by the way keep the comments
coming okay I'm gonna check it more
often because I don't want to like
sometimes I just start to you know
became a monologue you know like maybe
rip it you know being repetitive and and
so on so anyway let me let me cover the
question so like so this question I kind
of wondered how you do RSS on your site
okay so it's pretty it's easy so for
example let's see so this is my
programming blog so you can see let me
turn the auto click back on so this is
my programming block this is HTML page
so so the RSS is just this is the RSS
you know right now right now this is my
local local file you can see my my local
disk but let's go to for example
programming blog so if you click the RSS
that's a web feed RSS is just an XML
file so on my local disk the file is
this one blog dot XML let me magnify so
this is the file and I'm using the atom
format you know the RSS there are two
formats there's the you know there's the
RSS format and another format is called
atom let me just show you
okay I have a cup of holocaust you can
read
oh yeah Adam web feed tutorial
so this article discuss a bug in the
atom RSS readers so this article command
to update rss/atom web feed so this is
how I this is actually how I do how I
update my RSS you know the atom file
basically I have written a command in
Emacs is so it's a Emacs command and I
just call it and it will update it I'm
going to show you and on this page is an
atom web feed tutorial it shows you the
format you know the format of atom where
feed so is RSS if you don't know it
stands for web syndicated something but
anyway basically people can click it and
subscribe so whenever I have a new
article you will notify you I'm not sure
what what's the RSS readers today what
do you guys use type it type it come and
keep the comment going so so anyway so
let me show you so for example I so this
is my blog I create a new new entry
section this is just my own format I
created this
you know so new entry okay let's say
that's it
so I'm done so if I show in browser you
can see your new entry magnify new entry
now it's not in our RSS yet so I want to
put in in RSS so let's okay first of all
I'm in turn saw start command log now
this is the command log mod I've talked
about a few times before in my videos so
you can see all the Emacs command I'm
gonna call so okay back to my blog so
this is the new entry now I want to add
this entry to my RSS file so if I do it
manually it's gonna be like these so I
copied this line I
open the XML file which is this one I
open it and I have to well I have to
create like copy dad so so I have to
create a entry here for example create a
entry so this is the new entry
dddd and I have to ok switch back so new
entry put it here so title is going to
be that and I have to update this part I
have to update the date and so it's
tedious you know it's it's it's quite
tedious so so this is the part I want to
add and also I need to update the
updated date here so it's very tedious
so so I just have I have written a
command so here's how I do it
look at the left panel so I just first
three keys and that's it that's done so
the cursor is on this here that's the
title you know whatever I do I want to
say so let's just say new entry ok and
let's just close it I mean it's that's
that's done basically has let's done
close it then I go to each ow then just
a sink and just upload to my server
and if you go to so if I if I go back to
my website you know I'm sorry come and
refresh you'll see a new entry here and
if I click on the subscribe feed you
will see here you see so that's how I do
that okay
but however I don't want that so let's
remove it
okay so no ninja knows a no joke
yeah you know um lots of tutorials let's
go to for example a job you know are
lots of tutorials like you be you know
they have like a ninja thing like the
nude you know JavaScript ninja you know
there's such a book you know JavaScript
ninja or Ruby Zen or you know or
something something you know dojo you
know it's I don't like those styles and
also yeah so how long I've been talking
32 minutes so you know yeah let me talk
about that so in a cuter you know
tutorial writing styles so for example
if you go to Ruby there's lots of you
know mini tutorials it okay let me start
to show some topics so eloquent
JavaScript that's one of the book by the
way I also want to mention you know I I
know all the JavaScript book out there
so well yeah because I write JavaScript
tutorial you know in depth so I've seen
and read many basically I know basically
all JavaScript that you can find online
and also have I have surveyed most what
many of the popular books but let's not
talk about books for the moment it's
about online you know so I'd look at
them also okay so this is so you know
this is this would be biased for me to
say but I would say my JavaScript my
JavaScript in depth is better than them
all
possibly except one or two okay yeah
possibly except Wow so if you compare
Mozilla you know the Firefox you know
Mozilla let's say
the dead stuck for JavaScript poverty's
okay javascript
poverty's yeah w3 school is the worst I
mean they are they cater to beginners
okay so this is the Mozilla Firefox
JavaScript reference they they have also
have a tutorial but anyway you know what
I'm trying to say is that yeah I'm you
know I've really seen you know some some
some okay here's a point my tutorial you
know they have a tutorial here
JavaScript JavaScript dear friends
Mozilla is JavaScript tutorial it's not
good okay Mozilla in Party you know the
Mozilla JavaScript tutorial is no good
and okay so anyway let's get back to so
this one for example I mean this guy is
very capable guy but but however you
know in many books like they they are
writing style I mean there are many
writing styles for writing or tutorial
for example this one is like story
oriented you know a story like he took
you know this lots of words you know
very verbose and he tells the story like
introduction first of all you know you
know introduction so let's see you know
he he does some you know funny quotes or
some you know wisdom inducing quotes and
he showed screwdriver you know he you
know too many words but I mean this is
just his style okay yeah I mean that
that's perfect you know some people like
that style you know that's fine for you
but I don't like this style you know he
is like too many words and also by the
way this is for beginners this book is
good it's a good book
well written and he's he this this guy
is an expert in JavaScript he has
written JavaScript passes in JavaScript
and by the way he's also Emacs Lisp code
he he has rewritten the turn
you know JavaScript IDE that's written
by him so you know so this is a good
book for for beginners but anyway the
the writing style is one of those I
really don't like and if you go to Ruby
you know then you start to see these can
and Kong and ninja and stuff I haven't
really coded in juvie I just learned it
for like three months so so you can see
some of that you see you know the Ruby
Ruby cons like what what the Ruby
cons and there is there and this guy is
very famous
I learned wise pointment guide to be
it's a it's actually a comics but anyway
so he was very apparently you know I
don't know much about juvies community
because I I haven't actually caught it
very much but but there there is this
guy he who is named online name is just
why okay that's it like for time be you
know for quite a while it's a mystery
nobody know who he is but however he is
very enthusiastic about Ruby so he has
written a lot tutorials and helpful
things you know and he has written this
okay open the book comics you know
teaching Ruby you know via comics so he
is immensely popular in the Ruby
community however he became more popular
when one day he disappeared from
Internet like you guys we are you guys
Ruby code us do we have Ruby code us if
you are Ruby code erssime probably know
the story
so anyway one guy one day he just
disappeared from the internet you know
like they are quite a few cases where
famous people famous programmers they
just disappeared from internet like they
deleted their edit they deleted the
github they deleted every every presence
on the internet and so this guy did that
you know for whatever reasons so anyway
some I'm talking about back to the
tutorial writing styles so you see this
you know Kong you know the you know like
it's stupid I don't like them okay so
you know you have you know and Ruby
essentials learn to program and learn
Ruby the hard way okay this guy is very
interesting this Scott this guy learn
Ruby the hard way and he he has also
written learn Python the hard way and
several others yeah and also he he began
to write learn JavaScript the hard way I
hate it because it's crying is it's my
competitor oh it's not done yet but
anyway this guy is interesting remember
this site I'm I'm not going to read that
loud but but you might have seen this
this is done by him he this guy is quite
interesting he sway a lot what's his
name any anyone remember his name
but anyway he and also he's a very
capable programmer he wrote yeah he's
one of the big contributor to Ruby and
to Python as well he he wrote web server
that's included in I forgot which Python
or Ruby or JavaScript I forgot which but
yeah but but anyway so what so I was
talking about javis tutorial writing
styles yeah so anyways so okay let me
get back to there's one thing I want to
talk about you know okay besides you
know so for right writing styles of
tutorials let me show you another web
page so if you go top you'd go to my
programming block and on the side you'll
see dark for dummies so so this is index
to a collection I have written about
documentation I'm I have obsession about
documentation so I've read object I've
read programming documentation more than
anyone essentially yeah I can safely say
more than more than anyone who works at
Google let's say well partly because my
age I'm 50 years old you know but yeah
but so I have a session I mean it began
since I was a teen since I began to
learn English you know I would read the
book from you know my habit was that any
manual like not just tutorial about
programming but any manual any any any
comics book or any menu I will I will
read cover to cover literally like from
you know from covered you know not just
first page cover
you know preface type of content and so
on - epilogue and you know and end of a
cover and whatever bluffing you know
cover to cover page by page and word by
word every word I have to like read
every word and every word I don't
understand I have to look up so I have
looked up you know when I was learning
English back then 30 40 years ago 30
years ago every word every what I did if
I don't know that word I read it down
and I look up dictionary so I've looked
up this dictionary more than anyone you
know more than most people you know so I
mean that's a habit in fact that's not a
good habit that's not how you want to
read a book actually yeah you if you
really want to read a book you you you
want to skip and scan scan get the point
you know quickly scan you know but
anyway I was I was talking how I became
you know one of my habit back then you
know I don't I don't do that these days
but anyway back then when I was a teen
you know first I first I learn English
so I have the and well it's not just
English I mean even for Chinese the way
I grew up you know for my dad's
influence but anyway so I have the habit
the mindset of when you read a book
especially manuals like everything
before you do anything you have to read
the manual like then you read the manual
and yeah it has to be like cover to
cover and and actually carefully read
every word you know so you so I spot or
arrows climatic arrows come missing come
as you know you have to do that you know
that's that that's how I was there was
my habit so anyway so I've read you know
turn of programming documentation and I
have I obsession okay okay that's one
thing you know that was my habit about
reading you know and also part part of
my history of learning English you know
that's how I learned English by the way
which is extremely inefficient don't do
that okay if you are going to learn a
new language let's say I don't know
Italian Spanish don't you know open any
book you know like newspaper like God
you know we'd pick up a Spanish
newspaper and start to read every work
word and start to look up dictionary
that's extremely inefficient you know
but back then my mind mind said you know
it's still somewhat with me is that is
captured by the word brute force
you know I like the word brute force you
know I don't care how other you know if
if other people do something you know
that they maintain timaeus I'm going to
run hundred miles you know that says
there was my mentality so you know I
just brute force you know like trying to
learn a new language this way you know
because I was thinking you know to learn
a new language you know basically you
just know other vocabulary vocabularies
and that's it you know you just you know
maybe there's more efficient way but you
know I don't care I didn't care that was
in the past
I want to do is just know every word you
know so I know words Nate I can
understand language understand the
language but that way is extremely
inefficient you don't want to that do
that for the same amount of time you can
study hard and you are too much better
and also you know also you know for my
you know studying English by vocabulary
that you know I learned quite a few
things for example vocabularies they are
actually quite several categories you
know for example if you don't know
English for example and you pick up
Shakespeare's book you know Shakespeare
you read the entirety of Shakespeare you
look up every word you understand every
one of them for example your English we
are you won't be able to read anything
you won't be able to read newspapers
like when you open a newspaper but like
half of the world more than half you
don't understand that's a situation so
you know because the words they are
actually you know very much categorized
you know this novel novelists you know
words their particular poetry words this
particular set you know everyday
conversation conversation words they
this particular said you know speech
words you know
journalism so-called journalism like in
newspapers or Time magazine you know
that they have a particular set of
vocabulary so it's very you cannot think
you know I'm just going to you know be
you know no other words starting let's
say Shakespeare you know if you pick the
wrong book then you can allow you waste
like food you know you waste your two
years you know studying a language so
that was it so okay so back to the
documentation topic so so anyway that
was my learning English experience so
but still to this day I still have
obsession about reading documentation
you know I read a lot you know
eunuchs and also I have a obsession
about writing like writing style you
know all like all aspects of writing you
know for example some of the popular
topics are how to be a good writer you
know or how to be a good technical
writer writing styles what kind of
writing styles are there I mean not
necessarily just technical writing I
mean including journalism anything you
know what what styles are there you know
if you are reading a book or whatever
and linguistic issues I mean if you know
linguistics you know how does that
affect you know how they affect or
relate to writing style and also
literature you know how you know so I'm
kind of like I have interest in these
kind of things but anyway back to the
programming documentation so I have this
page I collected lots of my essays you
know opinions about documentation that
you know as many aspects about about it
and most programming programming
documentation it's really bad I mean
they dislike me I have no idea what they
you know they like the writings the okay
the quality the writing quality is
extremely poor for many reasons for many
reasons I mean for example first of all
programmers they don't you know first of
all documentation is not really part of
the program like when you you know if
you work for Google whatever software
you write software that
imitation or inline documentation they
does it doesn't affect the software at
all so you know it's like you know you
don't pay higher attention you know you
don't get it doesn't get much attention
yes said so thank you very Lou that says
oh that show is the guy who who created
this page yeah he's a very interesting
guy and he sware all the time and also
you can see he has been given talks on
YouTube you can see and he's also yeah
he's very interesting and and also very
controversial and and some of his ideas
I liked very much for example he has we
at one time I don't remember if it's a
lecture you know a talk you know in real
time or is it was it one of his Alec oh
I forgot I think it's a talk where he
talked about programming idioms which I
am with him you know I don't like many
of these you know Python you know the
the code you know they are like a coat
and he attack he attacks them very much
too you know for example this phage
become a programmer you know anyway so
back to the documentation I was okay let
me let me get let me get out of my
nested topics I was talking about so
documentation programming documentation
I was saying yeah so you know
programmers you know for many reasons
multiple reasons the documentation
programming languages is extremely bad
okay for several reasons you know I can
talk about reasons but for one of the
reason is that you know documentation is
not really part of the software so it
gets neglect neglect it and second
secondary programmers in general they
are not writers I mean that they have
less interest in writing you know most
programmers you know maybe you are very
enthusiastic about algorithms or
algorithms you know
Oh Python idioms you know how you do
that Oh object-oriented programming Oh
functional programming how you do it
that but when it comes to documentation
you don't have that interest you don't
see that you know usually they don't do
well and you know anyways there are many
reasons the several reasons I can talk
about that for four whole hours so maybe
next another day next livestream but so
you say something I want to say actually
I forgot what's the topic so we were
actually okay so I was going to
originally talked about Yama's giving
depth but that you know we even didn't
begin so anyway so let me answer the
questions keep the questions coming guys
so you know let me know how am i doing
or what topics you want to I mean like
maybe some people actually come here to
really hear about me talk about
JavaScript but instead of I'd rambled on
and on you know there's so many things
interesting about JavaScript in depth
yeah because also if you don't you know
if you don't post comments and usually I
just end up just promoting my own
website so ok back to the I forgot
what's the reference to for sandwich
okay nice we were looking to that this
stream okay I forgot that one that is
hello you so hi guys thank you
what do I think what do i what do you
think about raising in Ag dismiss Java
scale is edit row' because yesterday for
those of you don't know yesterday I did
a big huge rant about how eMac this
sucks in yesterday's livestream so I
didn't you know I know it's going to be
a rant
yeah yeah okay anyway so yesterday I
knew I'm going to rant about it
but I didn't expect actually you know
just you know keep going and on about
that actually that's a you know I don't
know if I you know if my people who
watching that video didn't like it or if
they liked it I'm not sure what's the
audience response but however you know
like I'm not sure like at one hand you
know I was when I swear a lot and I
curse at many of the Emacs community and
as well as Python community and
programmers in general so you know I'm
kind of like you can say I'm attacking
you know them attacking the programmer
communities and this opinion is not very
popular in general so for you know if if
any average programmer you know you know
maybe from Google or whatever they they
watch it they probably not gonna like it
so they're gonna vote it down but on the
other hand you know for people who maybe
know me a little bit and for you know
non mainstream programmers I think that
video is actually quite interesting for
them because I actually I honestly you
know spewed out over like ten years ten
years my frustration with these elite
programmers you know and I felt good you
know although I wasn't you know I didn't
intend to do it that way but you know I
just flow it out and so I think you know
a lot of people might like it so I
wasn't sure overall it was it good or
bad you know and also I like to know
because you know I don't want to you
know make videos that just like about
myself you know I you know and hoping to
do something people like
so anyway so let let me ask answered the
other questions do you have any advice
about key for switch to command modding
stuff like is why not escape keys yeah I
actually have written a tutorial I mean
I have written an article about the
reasons so let's go to keyboard bug okay
well let's go to sally keyboard so that
article will address this question
exactly
excuse me
so yeah the question is about yeah so
the question is about being soft like
keys why do I choose envy more VI you
have escape key that switches to command
mod but however in soft like keys which
is a package for Emacs a key binding
system it does not use case escape key
to switch mods so why is that
okay so odd keyboard blog you'll find
the answer at design layout key binding
so go to key binding here design of the
mod activation key so you know you can
read this you know if offline but
basically the reason is okay the short
the short one reason is that the escape
key are normal PC keyboard is not you
know it's not a good key to press
because it's on a corner and you have to
move your hand all the way that's on a
typical laptop keyboard or typical PC
keyboard so I don't want people to do
that so because you know yeah you can
you can remap the keys you know most
people we map the escape to the caps
lock key which is very good position but
to realize that a lot of people they
don't bother you know actually that's
the fact because for you or for me you
know we we are you know obsessed about
these to us it's obvious you know it's
things we think that could they possibly
possible that nobody knows this you know
we think everyone knows but actually you
know out there a lot beam users actually
you know they never bothered you know
it's put escape here on the cap lock
they just never bothered most I would
say probably the majority of them users
out there you know it's interesting
because of the vim community on Io Emacs
or Python or whatever you know online
people they are actually like a very
small group of the actual users like
let's talk let's say Emacs you know I
write Emacs tutorial right so I and I
read you know Emacs Prague I know the
Emacs people you know I go to Emacs
Meetup
so and so does you guys most of you I
suppose so you know to us it seems like
this is you know the everyone knows
about this this is the email community
but actually that's a you know the
online Emacs community is actually a
very small fraction like 1% or less than
1% that's I you know I think that's
reality same thing applies to the Python
community or the you know Java community
you know vast majority people
programmers you know for example they
they don't you know they don't go online
and read blogs and you know you know
talk about things you know they they go
home and they you know go to their wife
or whatever you know they have a life
they have alive
he has gotta be better so I got a scowl
so the best key to change me in state
yeah JK so so JK key is good for change
command mod as well but the problem with
that is you know the JK DB the problem
with that is a hack
so well you know what what I mean by
hack well basically it means it doesn't
always walk well that's what I mean so
like sometimes you press it it doesn't
work who knows you know things like that
happens a lot so it's annoying you know
annoying so usually I avoid any kind of
that but however if you you know what I
mean by hack for example you know the
keyboard you know keyboard let's say
versus piano on a keyboard you know we
have what's called key code right you
know you press ctrl then something
control option you know control codes in
something we call it a code but actually
the the key press needs to be in
specific order for example if you want
to copy ctrl C right you have to hold on
press control first hold it down press C
you have to really see then release
control it must be in that order
specific I mean very specifically even
we call it code but it's actually not
called
because if you press C first then you've
you know that doesn't work so it's but
compared to a piano that's actual I
don't know if you can I don't know if
it's a good analogy but anyway the piano
is actually designed I mean that
physical keys are actually designed for
you to press motor co multiple keys at
once and easily like you know you don't
have to go into hand contortions to
press you know more than five keys on a
piano you know you it's designed that
way but the keyboard
you know the computer keyboard is not so
this so this is a huge that that the
difference is huge and you know there
are a lot of people you know they want
to they started a project where they use
a computer keyboard to try to make it to
be a steno so they are thinking you know
they want to use computer keyboard as a
steno machine it doesn't really work
well in fact I think it's it induces
with repetitive strain injury let me
show you for example it's miscellaneous
for example here is a state steno type
steno machine so this machine is for
typing it's for typing very fast at at
the speed of speech level it's used by
you know in code for example you know
this stenographer they code the people
who use this machine to type is called
stenographer
you know they in code they type you know
people speak and they type record it
down and the reason it's fast mostly due
to two things one is this particular
physical keyboard you know it allows you
to this is actually a code keyboard it
allows you to press multiple keys at the
same time that's one thing the other
reason is that the system it uses to to
to to type is actually a coded system so
it's an input system in other words it's
not you know typing one letter by letter
in fact it's actually phone eight
phonetic based so it's based on sound so
for example sound is one word sound they
just type to like kind of two keys like
sound is is one thing T is the other
thing sound you know - it's instead of
sou and D so that's why it's extremely
fast and but now there are people
who let me show you yeah she her her she
started a project that but anyway there
are people who there's a project called
plover yeah you can look up over they
try to use the steno system on a
standard normal PC keyboard you know
that's very bad you know I mean you know
just for yourself always Church you for
yourself but in my opinion it's it's no
good the idea is that you know their
idea is that on a PC you know the steno
system is great you know because it's
abbreviations you know phonetic based so
it allows you to type very fast
however the steno machine because of you
know because it's a rare market you know
very few people use it so it's very
expensive it's like $1000 you know and
very bad you know because there's no
competition you know it just likes so
much
some small company makes it and just
sells it $1,000 or something so she has
idea you know she was a stenographer yet
you know this is a c-note stenograph you
know the machine it's like thousand
dollars or two thousand something but
she so she began idea that you know you
know $2000 it's no good so she wanted to
she's not the idea that she wants to
create her own steno machine or
something like that
eventually it becomes a project where
you use a normal keyboard there's this
keyboard let me show you if she's a
do-it-yourself there
this keyboard is very popular on the
hacker types you know so so so you use
this keyboard to to input the steno
system and it's no good you know in my
opinion it's very bad it's going to
increase your risk for repetitive strain
injury yeah
so anyway so yeah I rambled I cried a
lot I think already okay one hour and
ten minutes seventy minutes I think
that's it you know so anyway I was going
to talk about JavaScript but turns out
we didn't cover that at all JavaScript
maybe yeah this okay maybe I'll talk
about that
[Music]
okay javascript ACMA 2015 and so on and
it's a completely new language
JavaScript history in JavaScript is a
bad line actually maybe we'll talk about
that some other time so in any any any
other questions
last chance questions last chance
ten seconds so if I think you know yeah
so let's see what else
steno machine become a programmer
JavaScript JavaScript eloquent
JavaScript JavaScript this this guy this
guy why
Ruby why silly who would you know who
would read a programming tutorial buy
comics
well actually Japanese do that you know
in Japan
everything is let me show you in Japan
everything is done by comics actually
yeah you know if you visit Japan you see
it everywhere I mean the comics is there
foam there what it's almost like they're
one of the primary form of communication
you know besides text no Japanese so you
see it in metros in public science you
always sees you know drawings you know
in Japan so for example let me show you
this this funny where is it
ah I can't find it now
yeah if you go to Japan you'll see lots
of comics everything is done by comics
yeah I cannot find it right now so thank
you guys for coming I'll see you next
time and by the way so so when when the
live stream ends you know then after
about thirty minutes it will show up VG
a YouTube video and so if you miss any
come you know questions you can comment
on my videos you know and I like I like
to get comments you know partly because
you know the YouTube you know everything
you see on the web today you know its
commercialization you know they they
push they push and push because they
want to make money I mean Google I'm
talking about Google Twitter you know
they push you to use their platform and
on YouTube for example every video you
will see everyone you know start to do a
video and they they start with a some
logo do you know the Tech Talk
you know what just like TV
you know the end at the end they'll say
please stump up and and and please leave
a comment you know there's many styles
of doing that and you know for example
girls you know thank you for you know
coming in and you know
please stump up if you liked it many
styles of doing that it's nothing wrong
with that but but when everyone becomes
it becomes mechanical like every
everyone does that and why does everyone
do that because actually Google or
YouTube is trying to tell you to because
you know for example if you do a video
straight stream if you do it yourself
you know maybe you you had a turn before
you know YouTube will tell you and you
know how to do it how to how to get more
people they show you statistics you know
who is watching you know which of your
video has more views you know at what
time you know so they they they do all
they can to increase
you know people using YouTube so they
make more money so that in turn any
video creative such as myself also want
to push that I mean there's I mean
there's nothing wrong with of course you
when you and when I do something or any
anyone else you know you want to people
watch it but it it becomes you know
these corporate mechanical things so you
know I'm not sure what to do about that
if if you don't actually try to market
or push it you tends to be buried so you
know it's like it's like this the choice
falls down to me you know you know if I
don't tell people to comment nobody you
know there will be less people
commenting because you know obviously
then you know your video get less
watched then you know that's that's no
good right so anyway so I don't know
what to do about that so anyway thank
you guys for watching see you next time
bye