Good morning guys. Welcome to another
episode of Kar Talk Show. We are going
to code JavaScript. Today JavaScript
advanced JavaScript functional
programming.
Okay. My keyboard. This is ultimate
hacking keyboard 80 UHK.
This is Nia trackable. This is um this
is you know my pen device. But let me
show you my screen so you can see them.
Go to screen. Okay, you can see my
screen. Stop that. So, Sun talk show
January 26th
and episode 750 JavaScript functional
programming style. That's we're going to
explore casually.
Okay, if you are here say hi. If you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5 speed
minimum. Okay. So, you can see my
keyboard ultimate hacking keyboard 80.
You'll find it on my website kasali.info
http nos.
So, I have video reviews of them. One
hour each. Lots of video reviews of all
sort of ergonomic keyboards. Glove 80,
Kinesis 360, Kinesis Advantage 2,
Moltron. I don't have a review for Mron.
I don't have that. But I do have Glove
80, which is fantastic. I've been using
for three years on my live stream every
day. Uh and uh you know, so anyway, so I
got reviews, so you can see all of them.
Uh lots of reviews. Okay, that's my
that's my keyboard. Let's go back. So,
and the L Nia track ball. That's the
track ball there. You can see you can't
see it, but okay. Nia track ball. This
is Nia505M50
and Huang uh tablet drawing pad. That's
what I'm using right now. Huang H640P.
Okay, let's let's uh start to code
JavaScript. Okay. So, JavaScript uh so I
have a page if you search for JavaScript
style guide for functional programmers
up here. New uh tab search for it in
browser you'll find it. Let's see. Let's
see if it shows my website. It indeed
savas script style guide for functional
programmers. So, you can see Oh [ __ ]
Okay. So it um
you see it showed
it funny you see if you do brave search
on JavaScript style for functional
programmers it gives a summary of my
page. Okay. So, there's a link. So,
let's see. Um, yeah. So, it does show a
link. That's my website.
But then the result is some other page.
The W3 school is the worst [ __ ] on
earth.
They they are very old. They became
hugely popular. They are uh since like
around year 2000 or 2003 something very
early. They are they are like for the
most very beginners like programming for
dummies and uh lots of errors. But
however they succeed they became very
popular because vast majority of
programming tutorials are written by
these elite programmer [ __ ]
They don't write for beginner. They
write for to show other coders how
elite, how hacker they are. So the
typical programming language tutorials
are or blogs are full of like either
jarens or in you know like
incomprehensible
you know things. So so you want to write
a tutorial that is uh very friendly for
beginner. You don't want to pretend they
are dummies,
okay? But you, you know, but you do want
to write them, you know, you don't you
don't want to be pretentious like lots
of these programming language tutorials
are, especially in the past, not not so
much today. Because today, since about
10 years ago, this vast mega uh movement
of corporate sponsored tutorial website
usually created in India, you know, they
trying to make money, cheap way to make
money. Anyway, so so in the 1990s and
and up to even 2010, vast majority of
programmer programming tutorials are
very bad, lousy, pretentious um because
they are all written by elite, you know,
they are they are written, you know,
and and a lot of them don't know how to
write such as the Unix and C programmer
class of people. They don't even know
how to write properly.
And and some of them, you know, harbor
the thought that, you know, I'm a I'm a
hacker. I'm a great programmer. Writing
documentation is beneath me. These
[ __ ] Very common among the Unix
and C people. Okay.
Do I have an audience? If you are here,
say hi. Okay. Seven concurrent viewers.
Okay. If you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed. Okay. So anyway we we
I started to digress on how programming
tutorial scene were were like in the
past 30 years. So in the 1990s and the
year 2000 you know there are not many
programming language tutorials and even
if you ask the question you don't get
the right answer because everyone is
going to tell you why why are you doing
that you should do it this way you know
did you try Monad you know these
[ __ ] like the Hascar people will
tell you that monad did you try monad
you shouldn't do it that way you know
all you want to do you know how do I
sort this thing you know then they're
going to try to tell you you their fancy
ideals like the Monat from Cascal the
Lispers they're going to tell you
something about something something you
know the the Python [ __ ] typically
okay so these people but the the most
uh lousy language like JavaScript back
then JavaScript and PHP they don't have
this situation so when you ask the
question people actually try to give you
answer so that's why part of the reason
PHP and JavaScript became the most
popular programming language on earth.
Okay. Anyway, so so and also because of
lots of you know the lack of good
tutorials for programming languages or
even documentation back then it's very
common in the 1990s very common for
software or API that do not have any
documentation at all
very common back then much less today
you know almost like it doesn't exist
you know this the situation where you
have the software or API that does not
have any documentation at all is almost
non-existent today.
Uh you know so this is like a progress
of the programming community evolution.
Okay. So anyway so so also this reason
lack of good tutorials is part of the
reason how Stack Overflow became very
popular.
You see stack overflow they have rules
that if people ask a question you must
answer that question you are not
supposed to going to tell you your story
oh but I think that language is better
why are you doing this way you shouldn't
you know this way whether or that [ __ ]
this programming [ __ ] programmers
okay so stack overflow saw the problem
you know people want to you know when
you program you have a lot of questions
but when you ask you know you don't get
the answer because each person going to
tell you something else. So, stock
overflow they created a rule that you
must answer the question. So, they
became hugely successful. Okay. But of
course, they died since like three years
ago due to AI. So, AI is another chapter
in the progress of programming language
documentation.
Okay. Am I like losing uh viewers, you
know? So anyway um so programmy language
documentation okay so when you search
brave any they showed my they basically
they give a summary of my page this is
my page let's see if I can
uh where is my page yeah okay so they
they showed my page a summary of my page
but then you got this um okay W3 schools
which pretty bad JavaScript style guide.
Okay, Google's got JavaScript style
guide.
Then JavaScript.info. This is another
like this this is one of the this is a
good example of a none who are trying to
squeeze money. You know, you got
JavaScript info dedicated domain and you
don't know who they are. Okay, but I I I
presume most most of the time these are
just random Indian.
Okay, let's see if I can open that. Uh,
open that.
I made some change to my keys. Um, so do
I still have a Yeah.
So that button is middle click. Okay. So
let's look at this JavaScript.info.
Like who the [ __ ] are they? Okay. So Oh.
Oh, you got this diagram. Let's see.
syntax. Here is a cheat sheet with some
suggested rules. See below for more
details. Space between parameters.
Okay. So, okay. Also, coding style
guide. Okay. So, [laughter]
Okay. So, this is coding style guide for
dummies.
There are no humorous rules. Curly
braces. Okay. Let's let's have a look.
Let's see like who they who are they.
Okay.
So, indentation, nest level, and who who
you know who they borrow the style from.
Okay. Style guides. Google JavaScript
style guide. A or B and B's JavaScript
style guide. Idiomatic.js.
Okay. Another
Okay. Then standardJS. That's a scum.
Standard JS is from a Malay scum. Okay.
This scumbag
standard JS one you know from the Malay
gen MPM scum idiot. Okay.
Uh very popular you know the million
millions of download MPM something
something million 100 million something.
[ __ ] them.
You see they you see why they exist.
They exist. You know it's not you know
it's it's it's not that they are
necessarily bad. They exist for the
simple reason to
to either monetize to you know make
themsel rich or to become famous which
is in turn make themsel rich. You know
if you ever thought about
you know rich and famous these are two
terms often related. Why are they
related? Because one is like helping the
other. They are uh very much affiliated
rich and famous. Because if you are f if
you are famous,
it significantly make you rich, you
know, doesn't matter who you are. If you
are like if all of a sudden a million or
a billion people knows about you,
they're going to give you money. They,
you know, you're going to benefit
tremendously.
So with this open source they cannot
make money directly but they can like
have a corporation like MPM you know
they they they make money indirectly by
you know ads and all or all different
ways.
So this standard JS is like offensive to
my eyes you know look at look at them
sponsored by socket what does it mean
that means money sponsored you know like
this these people are giving them money
either you know you you might think oh
that's because donation because the
JavaScript standard style guy is doing
so great to the community so these good
people you know this also other
corporations they donate you
But actually
not necessarily. It's more like
advertisement. Okay. You want
advertisement, you want to advertise
here, you know, so contact them, you
know. So you got, you know, your name
there. Of course, you have to pay.
So I don't know if that's true, but
that's, you know, but you can never
tell, you know. That's the kind of the
situation in the past 10 or 15 years.
You know the standard Java standard JS
[ __ ] scum. What gives them the right to
call it standard? Look at the authors.
Okay. It's a good thing they have
authors. Okay. I think this I think this
is a guy who started Feros. Okay. The
[ __ ] skun.
By the way, this is all my opinion. This
is opinion only. Okay. Nothing. Uh this
is just opinion. Okay. But Russ uh I
think that's the guy who began it
standard JS bucking offensive.
And who are these people? You know these
people are like um you know a lot of
Chinese there. You can see a lot quite a
few these people are like they they are
like young people. They are zoomers.
They don't know anything. you know they
grew up in this uh late you know Malay
genian situation so they grew up with
the idea or idea you know of open source
of uh pull request uh you know so they
so so they in turn they want to be part
of you know like part of the game like
so you know they can say oh look I
contributed to this very popular
open-source project standardjs because
you and see my PO pull request that's
what they are doing most most of them
you know so that's why you know like
like so and also to benefit them benefit
this this guy whoever created this to
list all these names because when you
see your name there are you happy oh
look you know my name is mentioned
especially when you are younger vast
majority of these people are young you
know teenagers that's what you know that
is my Yes.
So what is exactly is wrong with them?
You know the So it's not a crime. Okay.
Standard JS for example.
Why do I hate them?
Is it a crime? No, not really. Is it So
is it is it like unethical or
misleading?
Not really. But it's um it's what how do
you you know it's it's a it's a a social
phenomenon that's not doing good. Okay.
That's like um
kind of you know you can you you might
think of it as like some bad movement in
society or some bad habit or some for
example let's let's say graffiti
you know there there are c certain
subgroups they love graffiti you know
like graffiti you just like damage
buildings you know you paint whatever
and they and some of them they think
it's doing good because it's uh
providing you know peaceful protest
complaint to the corporate corporation
you know some of them say that but
actually actually you are just doing
[ __ ] to society okay you pretend it's a
good thing you know that's some of these
graffiti artists they are
they pretend they are doing good things
but they are actually just for
themselves
so so some so in society you have these
some kind of bad notions of movements
Okay. And that's what I think that's why
my despise of this standard JS is like.
Okay. And also also also look at you
know what exactly they recommend
standard JS. I don't recommend it. Okay.
For example, you can look into details.
I you know I've seen this like 10 years
ago.
Uh, you know what? What do you uh what
do you what do you might do if you are
clever?
[ __ ] some what a [ __ ] idea. What
what the [ __ ] are you trying to say? You
know the way they they they they
um
you know like when you read something it
washes your brain. It colors your brain.
Okay. So that you you know you can look
at the the when you look at this Zuma or
Malay Malayian things you kind of get
into their mind mindset how they think
about things
anyway.
So anyway so um
what you might do if you are clever what
the what the [ __ ] are you trying to say?
Okay, let's let's see usage after you've
installed standard
offensive insulting [ __ ] Who gives you
a right to call yourself a standard? Or
is this like a Zuma jargon like a
marketing play? You are proud of this
fact that you abuse the word standard.
It's like why not? Because there's lots
of memes today. You know, we love memes.
So we you know I just use the word
standard you know standard JS like why
not is that
what is the guy is thinking you know so
JavaScript style guide llinter another
very offensive jargon from C idiots okay
and formatter okay
table of contents install usage what you
might do if you are clever what the [ __ ]
FAQ what why should I use JavaScript
standard style. Standard style. Who the
[ __ ] are you? Who use JavaScript
standard style? You know this question
you can you'll know right away. It's
lots of sponsor corporations. Facebook.
Oh, Facebook, Microsoft, you know, lots
of them. Abn you know.
Are there text editor plugins? Is there
a read me badge?
I disagree with rule X. Can you change
it? But this isn't a real web standard.
Okay, let's let's let's see. Um,
okay, we are I'm supposed to um show you
some JavaScript functional programming
code, but I we digressed into this. Um,
let's continue with this documentation
thing. Okay, so install. So, by the way,
so this is just not a style guide, but
it's actually it's a tool that make your
reformat your JavaScript. Okay, that's
reformatter and they also call lint
which is a very stupid term from C
community. So let's see uh let's see. So
install usage after you install standard
you should be able to use the standard
program. The simplest use case would be
checking the style of all JavaScript
files in the current working directory.
Okay. So you just type uh standard error
use JavaScript standard styles except
except expect expect that and that you
install standard locally run MPX
instead. Okay. So MPX okay so D by
default standard will look for all files
matching the patterns JS okay and JSX
what you might do if you are clever add
it to package.json JSON okay style is
checked automatically when you run npm
test okay okay so why should I use
JavaScript standard style the beauty of
JavaScript standard style is that it's
simple no one wants to maintain multiple
100 line style configuration files for
every module blah blah blah uh no config
automatically format code Okay.
Okay. Digression. I don't recommend the
standard JS. Okay. I don't recommend it.
I think it's [ __ ] Okay.
I re Now what I recommend is Deno. Okay.
What I can recommend is uh Deno. You I
have a I have
D N O. Okay. I don't have I don't have a
great uh Deno tutorial, but but anyway,
this is Deno. Okay, by the way, by the
way, uh interesting digression. Deno
changed their logo two years ago. So, in
the beginning, you know, uh before they
change, Deno has had this logo. It's
cute, a cute dinosaur. Okay, but now it
looks like that. Okay, it looks like a
penis basically.
So when did this change happen? This
change happened in this new logo came
about in 2024
October. So two years ago. Okay. In the
release of Deno2
and so I looked into so why do they
change what they say? Basically
they have a
blog that is corporate speak. They don't
actually say anything. They don't
actually say why they really change it
because someone wanted to or why is the
old one not good? Why you do you need
you know they didn't really say
anything. It's a corporate you know
corporate speak. So you don't really
know why they changed. Well because they
you know they got a new version.
Therefore they need a new logo something
like that. But this new logo looks like
a penis. Does it? Does it?
And uh interesting I I looked you know
on Twitter and elsewhere I think nobody
these days nobody comment much on the
logo change nobody like made some
comment and like used to be like 10 uh
20 years ago when you have a software
popular software logo change a lot of
people will talk about it they will give
you opinion you know I like it better or
not sometimes arguments
but I don't you know, but I think time
has changed. So, you don't see much
comment on this new logo at all.
But, however, I did see a a few like two
or three. They say they don't like the
new logo. It's like, what the [ __ ]
It's like a penis. Okay, let's just, you
know, just let's just say it's like
looks like a penis. like particularly as
if like it's like specifically designed
to be
um
you know kind of ah kind of uh you know
so there there is a there's a story so
anyway Deno I think it's a great great
software I think it's great so you can
use um I don't have much demo tutorial
but you can use Deno to format Java
script code which is what I use. I
recommend demo. Okay. Not NodeJS, no
mpm, no NodeJS and no the standard JS.
[ __ ]
[ __ ] the standard JS.
Okay, that's a lot digression.
Ideado says new new deno logo and fun
looks a little bit more professional.
Wow.
That's what you think. More
professional.
Um
where is it? Um general logo there.
I don't think it's more professional.
Okay. So, I think we I rambled all over.
And now, let's go back to some uh to do
some JavaScript I was going to do. So,
as you know or if you don't know, I've
done huge amount of JavaScript work in
the past month. Like huge. So just
search for
just for uh just search for JavaScript
in depth. Okay, search for it. You'll
find it. You'll find my website.
JavaScript in-depth refers to a
comprehensive understanding of the
language internals beyond syntax and
usage. Okay. No, that's not
okay. So no, they no longer shows my
website looks like. Okay, my website now
is on the third JavaScript in depth.
Now it's after this egg egghehead.io
in-depth JavaScript tutorial for 2025
and after this um the modern JavaScript
tutorial. Another [ __ ] JavaScript.info.
Now who who runs the JavaScript.info?
info
buy. Oh, okay. So, they are like buy so
you can make money. GitHub one two
25,000.
How is it done now? From the basics to
advanced topic with simple but detailed
explanations. Okay. Okay. So, by PDF so
you can buy it.
Okay. So, Okay. So, this is by someone.
So this is not a random Joe. This is by
because you can see Elia I think
let's see part one the JavaScript
language part two browser document
events interface part three various
topics networks regular expressions part
one and two together okay 1,00 pages
okay full tutorial all three parts
1300 pages is
okay. Specify your email. So, who are
you about the project? Let's see.
The modern JavaScript tutorial was
created in 2007
by Ela Caner.
Okay.
Okay. It's not
some random joke. Okay. Uh and regularly
updated since then. New chapters were
added out outdated ones removed to stay
fresh. The PDF version is about 1,300
pages starting from the beginning and
then to advanced topics. It's a book not
a video as for many people reading is
faster. Also, books are easier to
update. Keep modern.
The content of this tutorial is open
source and everyone is welcome to
contribute. Okay, it's open source.
Let's look at
uh the open source. Okay.
Okay. 25,000
stars.
Translations. Okay. Uh
Okay, not bad. I think this is not bad.
Okay. So, this is Ela Caner.
Okay. They are from
I believe they are from like Eastern
Europe, right? I mean they did they
mention the country
uh
okay not bad about the project
Armenia. Okay they are from Armenia.
Okay.
H.
Okay, not bad. So, JavaScript.info. I
think it's pretty good. But wait, but we
haven't actually read anything by them.
So, let's see. Hello world. Okay, that's
bad. Uh,
modern the modern mode use strict
fundamentals data types. Okay, let's
look at data types. So I'm doing a insta
review
example of this JavaScript.info book.
Okay, let's see. JavaScript fundamental
data types. A value in JavaScript is
always of a certain type. For example, a
string or a number. There are eight
basic types in JavaScript. Here we'll
cover them in general and in the next
chapters we'll talk about each of them
in detail. Okay, fairly verbose. So you
got number, you got the infinity and
none all part of number. And what are
these um gray boxes? Let's see.
Turn on JavaScript.
Oh. Oh, you can what? Play and edit.
Okay. So you got [laughter]
Oh god.
So you So they have like a buin
JavaScript. um
clunker. Okay, they they allow you to
evaluate.
Okay, stop. You know, just use browser
uh console. Okay, if you are a real
JavaScript coder, you need to learn
about browser console, not rely on
websites JavaScript, you know, editor
engine, you know, use the browser
console. Okay, like you can you can you
can type whatever
You know let's say con okay here here
console
log three okay there it is
okay so this is um
data types number
big int. Okay. So, it's great they
included a big int. This is essential.
This is a new feature from just a few
years ago. Uh I believe it's just few
years ago. Big big int. That's a very
huge feature.
Oh, but we don't cover them here. You
see this here is a part. You see this
big int is a very complicated
and very interesting feature new in
JavaScript. just like for for just a few
years I I think I forgot. Um so if you
search my uh JavaScript tutorial big int
okay okay big int um so let's see big
int uh created in 2020 five years ago
okay so it's very complex so I don't
have the details yet you know but nor do
they you know but devoted them uh a
separate chapter beginning read it when
you need such big number oh they do have
it covered [ __ ] a recent edition. Okay.
So, they do have a chapter covering it,
but how complete is it?
Uh does not seems too much. Not much.
Okay.
So, anyway, so big int and string. Okay.
Now, very interesting about string. Now
string in JavaScript is very [ __ ] up
because string is the index of a string
is made of of
uh so-called code unit.
Okay, which is very [ __ ] up if you
have emojis. Okay, let's see. Do they
talk about that
string is in JavaScript must be
surrounded by quotes? Yeah, uh of
course. Uh let's see. Do you ever talk
about
uh
code unit?
We'll cover things more thoroughly in a
chapter. Strings. Okay, let's go to
chapter strings.
Strings quotes. Okay, let's see. Special
characters. Okay, that's escape
sequence. Okay, uh you got this. That's
incomplete escape sequence. And you
didn't cover what is whites space
exactly I think. And the next alert. Why
are you using alert? You should be using
console log my friend. You know alert is
like nobody should ever use alert. Alert
is from 1990s.
Uh you you you're talking about modern
JavaScript and you showing alert.
Okay. Then string length. Okay. Here is
tricky. You see length when if you have
a emoji of a single emoji length will
return two because in JavaScript strings
are made of not characters but so-called
code units which is how a character is
encoded in UTF-16. So in other words,
the string in JavaScript is a byproduct
of technology. Okay, it's a byproduct of
engineering. So a character is not a
character but it's like half a character
sometimes.
So then it says okay let's see if you
talk about that you see note that
backslash n is a single special
character. Yeah that's called um that's
called uh that's a new line character
that's a you know
form feed. So length is a property
people with a background in some other
languages sometimes mistype by calling
length parenthesis. Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Accessing characters. Okay. They didn't
mention
string are immutable. Okay. Now changing
in case. Okay. Uppercase lower case
searching for substring. Now the
question is did they did you ever talk
about this code unit and how did you how
do you talk about it that is the key if
you are anything about JavaScript in
depth
getting a substring okay so uh getting a
substring and uh which one to choose
comparing strings okay let's just search
for unit
Did I did I found any phrase not found?
So um search for code unic code value
beside these special characters there is
also a special notation for uni code sl
back back slashu. Okay it's rarely used
and is covered in the optional chapter
about unic code. Okay rarely used
advanced knowledge. Okay. So they
mentioned the escape sequence for unic
code but did they talk about okay ser
they did okay here server got pairs okay
[laughter]
but um unicore string internals okay so
that so they they they phrase it as
string internals
advanced knowledge
um
based on uni code okay a bite sequence
one to four bytes Okay. Uh, JavaScript
allows us to have unic code in that and
that and that. So, good pays. Okay. Uh,
that that that that that.
So the method string from code point and
string code point at we will add it in
JavaScript to deal with surrogate pairs.
That's correct. Okay. So anyway take
away splitting string at an arbitrary
point arbitrary point is dangerous.
Okay. So basically
they are aware of this situation code
unit. Okay. But did did did they ever
mention code unit? Because that's the
technical word. That's the definition of
string index. Code unit. Okay. They
didn't mention it. No, no, no, not found
when you search it. Phrase not found.
Okay. But however, they know about the
issue and they mention it in a kind of a
miscellaneous,
you know, add-on chapter. Unicode string
internals.
which
it's not internals because when you do a
length string length of a string that
contains a unic code such as emoji a
smiley you know you get length two and
basically every function every method
that works on string if there's a unic
code in it it's [ __ ] okay now I talked
about this many times so let me just
quick quickly do a demo one more app
uh where are we? Let's just add it here.
Okay, so JavaScript. Okay, now console
log and uh uh string and let's say
butterfly. So we have a butterfly and
length. Okay, now run it.
You can see the result is true.
Now let's say you we want to uh purify
the code. Let's say we want to take a
slice slice uh or substring. Okay,
substring. Okay, so we want to take a
substring of this uh a butterfly
a butterfly b. Okay, so we want to start
from position zero to um let's say we
want to take the butterfly from position
one to uh two. Okay.
Now
run it.
So you got that. Okay. Run it. And you
see that's incorrect
because that FF can you see it? Uh
you see this FFD
that is half a character of the
butterfly. Okay.
In other words, that thing that this
thing is invalid. Okay. It's not a
character. It's like have it's like a
it's a code unit of the UTF16
encoding for this butterfly emoji. Okay.
So this is invalid. So when you take a
substring you you thought you're going
to take the butterfly but no you you
actually so if you actually want to take
the butterfly you have to say three.
Okay, you see and this length is two.
You see it's a [ __ ] up. Okay, this is a
the the the fundamental JavaScript [ __ ]
up
to this day. Every string you method
will [ __ ] up. We'll trip. will get
tripped if you if your string contains a
emoji.
Or more technically, if your string
contains any character that's not in the
so-called basic multilingual plane or
another way to say it is that if your
string contains any unic code character
whose code point is greater than 16
bits, greater than uh 2 raised to 16
power. Okay. So you can see the
butterfly code point is 129 419. In
other words, if the the code point code
point just means the ID for the
character. If the ID for the character
is
in in hexadimal is more than four
characters. Okay, that means that
character is outside of the basic
multilingual plane. It cannot the the
the the the character's id cannot be
expressed in four hexa decimals. Okay,
it's more than 16 bits and whenever you
have such a character in a string any
string method will get tripped will get
[ __ ] Okay. So this is how fundamental
it is. It is not it is not for example
the way you know this JavaScript
info would say it's like string
internals it's not it's not internals it
affect how if affect it affect your code
okay you're doing code you don't need to
understand internals but your code [ __ ]
get [ __ ]
so it's not like
you know this uh uh oh unic code string
internals
according to javascript.info. Okay.
So anyway, but they do they they did
address that and they put it this in you
know like additional chapter um like
advanced additional chapter. You don't
have to know like it's rarely used. Is
emoji rarely used? No. Emoji is like
everywhere
you know. Look at the way besides these
special characters there's also a
special notation for unic code back
slashu is rarely used and is covered in
the optional chapter optional chapter
about unic code. Okay. Then over there
then you started to you don't even see
code unit. You started they talk about
like ser pairs you know they they talk
about this issue but they there's no
they don't even mention the technical
word the the technically correct word
for string index that's called unit.
They didn't mention it. So this is my
review, spontaneous review of this
JavaScript.info
uh you know like the modern JavaScript
that's very insulting you know modern
JavaScript tutorial. [laughter]
Okay. So, so, so I would conclude of my
10 minutes, was it 10 minutes review or
20 minutes review? This not bad. Okay.
Not bad. But,
but I would have to say my tutorial is
better. Okay. So, you go to my tutorial.
Well, actually, you know, I do miss some
things they do cover. Okay. Better. So I
mentioned you know I miss proxy
promise
big int. Okay. But on the other hand,
let me tell you about my JavaScript
tutorial about strings for example.
All right. Uh let's see value strings
string overview. So you can go there
quote string uh quoting strings. So
several different ways you you have
template string with grave accent
apostrophe
uh string or quotation mark. Okay. Then
you can uh string operation string type.
String is one of the JavaScript value
type and it's a primitive value. String
is immutable. Okay. And string is 16
bits unit sequence. Okay. That is the
meaning of string index. Okay.
Okay. So here is the you know about the
the emoji issue the when when when your
string contains unic code emoji or any
other rarely used unic code characters
or Chinese characters some some rare
Chinese characters okay so that that's
the um so this is in full detail about
what what this code unit mean that's the
the word code unit is standard jargon a
standard terminology in uni code UTF-16
and also in JavaScript specification.
Okay, this thing is called code called
code code unit and and basically it's
just two bytes of the UTF16 encoding.
Okay, that's a value and that's the
meaning of the index of a string. Okay.
So I uh
so I'm you know I'm presenting my
tutorial covered that part. Okay. I
think that's it. But let's go back to
the you know I'm curious about this
JavaScript.info how good they are. Okay.
So we looked at strings. Not not too bad
because well because it really is
esoteric. You know most JavaScript
programmers they don't understand. Uh
but how do they explain another big
issue in JavaScript is array. Okay, so
you got array like thing. You got this
array like magic thing. Then you got
this sparse array magic thing. Okay,
those are like crippled things from due
to JavaScript design. Those are the
watts the cancer of JavaScript. Okay,
array like object and the sparse array.
It's a pure headache. Okay, and let's
see how they um covered let's see how
they did they how they did they how they
how did they talk about it. Okay,
JavaScript fundamentals data type number
uh big int. Okay, string. Okay, boolean.
Okay, logical type. Okay, uh new value.
Okay, so let's see how you address new
value. The special new value does not
belong to any of the types described
above.
It forms a separate type of its own
which contains only the new value. Okay,
this is incorrect.
This is partially correct because when
you say type of new, it returns object.
Okay.
So you see uh so can we do this? Uh okay
also log means print type of
new what does it return? It return
object. Can you see that?
So but but you say new is a special
type. No it's not. Okay. So what what
actually happens is that
by the intention of the designer
new is a special type of itself. Okay,
it's just new. There's only one value in
this type the literal value new. It just
means like nothing. Okay, just that's
the the intention of the
of the JavaScript creator Brenda Ike.
However, that's not what actually
happened
because back then 30 years ago in 1995
when he wrote the compiler, he made a
mistake. So when you say type of new it
becomes object. Okay. So type the new
type in JavaScript is actually an
object. it you know technically so it
depends on your mindset like depends on
you know whether according to the
intention of the creator or according to
actual practice because in actual
programming the JavaScript programming
language type of new is object okay it's
not like oh
type by itself so this is you know so
this so I'm looking at you know how they
cover the new issue
Okay. So, let me
show you my uh JavaScript uh on that
topic. Okay. So, uh string overview. So,
let's open a new new uh tab and you can
find you can find it either by the
search or you can just go to um new I
know where it is. No new. Okay. So
actually
so new is actually um
so okay let me show you where to find it
like in a natural way. So JavaScript
in-depth intro. So you go to So first of
all you got types. Okay. So that's a
basics print quote string number math
operations common print assign
assignment number comparison operators
boolean. Those are the basics test
equality. Okay. Then value types. Okay.
This is the beginning to cover the
technical details of JavaScript. Okay.
So you got types. value types. Let's
click on that. You got undefined.
No new. Okay. Actually, he's right. No
is the only type. [laughter]
Uh yeah. So, no is the type by itself,
but it also type of return object that
is because of the bug. Okay. And that
bug is described in in depth by this guy
Axel Ramos. Okay. very um in-depth guy
and you can also find the source code.
So that's a error. Okay. So the new
Yeah. So that's about the new type.
Okay. So that was like
uh JavaScript style. Wait. Um
uh so let's see
data type. Yeah. Okay. So I wanted to
talk I wanted to see how I deal with a
array. Okay.
So, review extle got to go. Okay. So,
let's see. Uh, do they talk about array?
So,
summary. Okay. So, they didn't talk
about
array. So, you got Okay. So, and one
primitive type objects. Okay. So the
type of operator object and symbols.
Okay. So okay then you have to go to the
chapter object. Okay. So go to object.
Uh so okay illustration with that
literal and properties. Okay. The okay
when are they going to mention array?
Uh
okay. Anyway, so my Okay, so let me give
a summary of my extle review of this um
of this JavaScript.info. I think it's
pretty good. Okay, so I think it's
pretty good. Um
pretty good JavaScript uh
inepth kind of tutorial. Okay. Of
course, I would also [snorts]
uh recommend if you check out my
JavaScript in depth. Okay. So, let's
see. Let's see some of the uh other
chapters. Code quality. Okay. JavaScript
fundamentals
then uh code quality debugging in a
browser
comments.
Why why is this why is there a chapter
called code called code code quality
like uh
this chapter explains coding practices
that we'll use further in the
development okay
ninja this like bunch of meen idiots
jargon started to show ninja mocha
polyfield transpilers this nonsensical
[ __ ] This late Malay gen and Zuma idiot
things like ninja code. Mocha
automated testing with Mocha. Does Mocha
is like does Mocha still exist?
Behavdriven development. What a [ __ ]
dil behavd driven development. [ __ ]
them.
Oh god. It's it's it's disappointing to
see this page started to talk about
these things. Okay.
Mocha. Okay. So this mocha chai sen.
Okay. The mocha the core framework. It
provides a common testing function. What
the [ __ ] The mocha.
Is it is it still alive? Like okay. So
the the new documentation site, hello,
welcome to the newly revamped mocha
js.org.
I don't think I heard them like for like
10 or 15 years, right?
Monkai is a featurerich JavaScript test
framework running on NJS and in browser.
Okay.
Okay, I think I talked for too long and
that's it for today. Bye guys.
So my summary
I need to give a summary poly feel.
Okay, I need to give a summary of this
site. I think I think it's not bad. I
think it's not bad. Object basics.
Constructors operator new. Okay, that's
very complex there.
Uh
getters and setters. That's also very
complex. You know, it'll be interesting
to see how they go about it. uh and
whether they cover the full complexity,
the technical details,
getters and setters. Okay.
And uh Okay. Anyway, so yeah. So anyway,
this a lot a lot, but my impression is
my impression is just it's pretty good.
Uh okay, bye guys. I think that's it. So
today,
so today we kind of we just randed over
um JavaScript community
uh basically about JavaScript
community of the JavaScript tutorials.
We talked about um the JavaScript
standardJS. We flamed it very badly, you
know, standardJS
and we then we went into talking about
the
um this javascript.info info website
which turns out is a JavaScript book and
turns out it's written by this um this
uh ar people in Armenia
and uh so we I we started I started to
look into like do a a review of it and
uh so it's a full book 1300 pages but so
far I think it's pretty good you know I
only look at you know I looked at it for
20 minutes. I think it's not too bad.
Okay, so bye guys.
Uh if you like my stuff, okay, you can,
you know, just go to my website uh pay
me. Okay, so
so go to Casan JavaScript in depth and
uh check out my book. If you like it,
you can get the entire thing in a zip
file
by pay PayPal me 35 bucks. Okay, you can
get the whole thing or Amazon gift card
me. Okay, so you can get the whole
thing, pay me because you are beautiful.
Uh and you know just donate to me or you
know then you go up through my website
go up you can uh my tutorials and my
si.info info my website homepage. Okay,
so you go all the way down then you can
donate to me fully PayPal, Patreon, gift
card me. Okay, bye guys.
test.