welcome to another episode of the xl
talk show today is 2020
september 10th thursday 10 o'clock in
the morning
san francisco time and today we don't
have a topic
the topic is going to be either
i'm going to code some emac lists
or i'm going to do some javascript
i'm going to look into the demo platform
and to run some typescript and check out
its libraries
uh i think i would like to do that or
we're gonna talk about keyboards random
keyboards keyboard stuff
so of you here pick a topic okay what do
you like to listen
pick a topic sergio and bot
and today you know there's a california
fire going on all over the place and the
sky is red
it's very dreary it's very dreary and
depressing oh so today the background
image so let me show you the background
image the background image
is this one uh the math
graphics gallery okay so you go there
let me talk about mathematics that's
fantastic topic now this
is this is called stereographic
projection and the picture in the
background is
the one at the bottom you see you begin
with this
image then you do the stereographic
projection
then project them onto a ball then you
get this
that's a background image so how does it
work it works like that
so imagine a sphere sitting on a floor
then at the top of the sphere is a point
let's say the light source then you
so so any picture
on the floor can be can have a one two
one map
map to the sphere by projecting a line
from the top of the sphere
to a point on the floor and vice versa
any point on a sphere
corresponds to one point on the floor
so this way if you have an image let's
say a photo
of yourself or a picture anything you
can
project it onto the sphere
and vice versa if you have a ball a
beach ball
whatever pattern on the ball you can
project it
onto the floor so this is a
stereographic projection that's
part of the math topic and this topic is
very important it's
it's basically the core of what's called
complex analysis complex numbers okay
uh you know so it's rather it's quite
interesting how
you know if you you know most of you
know
a bit about complex numbers you have
imaginary
numbers you know it's part of algebra
you have this square root of negative
one but however it then
then it's tight it's very interesting to
see that it is actually tied to this
this uh geometry thing projective
geometry i mean not
projective stereographic projection
now the word stereographic projection is
a bad
jargon because you know what what the
[ __ ] does it mean stereographic it's not
you know when you see the word
stereographic you imagine it do
it being three-dimensional you know uh
like realistic that's not
so the jargon is pretty bad jargon it's
it would be better it would be better to
call it spherical projection or
something like that
but however you cannot do that because
uh math has its own history you cannot
just
change your word arbitrarily or change
some concept to a new jargon
because then it creates whole tons of
more confusion
but anyway so this is known as
stereographic projection
you basically just project you know a
sphere onto
a plane so we got some pretty pictures
these all these graphics are done in
mathematica
in what year 2006 okay i did them in
2006.
mathematica you can do them in
javascript today
it would not be too difficult
shall we shall we try to do that in
javascript
uh actually if we do this i cannot
finish it in one hour it will be
two hours or so i haven't done this for
a while
so beautiful a stereographic projection
part of complex analysis good morning
cortes
uh so bob says i think you need a
low pass filter when recording
uh low pass filter you mean filtering
out the electric hum
you know so i have you know i'm looking
for the answer
i have electric hum in my live stream
you know
in the background uh i'm but
it does not happen it does not happen
with the same equipment
when i was at my old apartment
like three months ago you know if you
watch my old videos
you don't have the hum problem but um
problem
uh i have a home problem here so i don't
know how to fix that
does anyone know anyone know any one of
you who are
electric nerds electronic nerds
you know resistors and capacitors and
ohms and amperes you know so
any of you know that answer i will i
would appreciate how do you fix the hum
okay i don't want the generic answer
okay it's like you know
supposedly it's a it's called ground
loop huh
so anyway i'm talking random so today
the topic
let me repeat the topic should be me
coding emacs list
live or me exploring
javascript the deno platform looking for
its libraries i'm gonna
you know do it live or we're gonna talk
about keywords
uh random topic topics about keywords
or i'll just go on okay so
so if you have something you like to um
you know type it okay
michael edwards good morning and uh
elder rio so we were talking about
electric
electronic home in my background it's
called
ground loop uh
what what ground loop what um ground
loophole
so yeah i i heard it's ground loop hum
but if you try to read it it's like
you're gonna spend hours
so i want someone who has experience
with you know doing live streams and who
has experienced
this who can just tell me oh you need a
new
speaker you you need a new microphone or
you need to unplug these and plug it
somewhere something like that
okay don't just tell me oh ground loop
go on loop huh
okay so so what are we going to talk
about
let me talk about random math then since
since
uh i guess hey good morning justine
scarfie
now justin scofie he is here now
that's scary because he he is
a professional mathematician at
at a university so now
he puts a check on my on my uh
go on my 2b discussion of math because
someone is watching he would know the
right answer
okay so okay let me
let me talk about math okay some general
educational uh beautiful mathematics
for those of you guys programmers you
know programmers are typically ignorant
of math
so bob says your opinion on using many
different random libraries
instead of writing your own uh own one
for your
app my opinion
okay i can tell i can talk about that uh
okay libraries
you know the it
all has to do it you know it started to
um go
down here beginning with the millennial
generation
[ __ ] the millennial generation
that includes you but
so let me tell you about libraries
programming you know programming and
libraries
so let's say before year 2000
okay before year 2000s now we are
programmers right
we do we program and they are libraries
so basically every programmer knows
about libraries you know libraries is a
you know someone wrote a package you
know
as some set of functions that to do
something useful
and you know not everyone has time to do
you know to write everything from
scratch
so that so there exists libraries you
know someone
someone has already wrote that for
example
a library for matrix computation
a library for stream manipulation a
library to process
html to pass html and so on a library to
do
cryptography and so on you know terms of
libraries
you know because there are thousands of
tasks in programming
so libraries are very useful and you
know someone wrote it so
so i'm saying in let's say at least
before year 2000 every program you know
you don't have to you know so they are
libraries you know what they are so you
use them you don't necessarily know how
to write them but at least you
understand
you understand the entire context why
are you using it
you know that this this library is
you know is designed to do this
particular
task so if you are working in a company
or for yourself
you have many tasks a b c d e f g
so you know you know you code some and
you know okay
for the task b you know you might know
that maybe there's already a library
written by someone that will speed so
you just you you download it
install it and you use it this is a
normal situation i would call i would
say you know this
is uh you know it's that's a situation
but
let me talk about today's situation
today this
millennial generation especially
javascript programmers these
these [ __ ] idiots
these people they have no idea what is
the library anymore
okay a library to them is just something
on the web you just
type this line and you just download and
and and your code will work
they have no idea what's what is going
on that's
that's today's javascript programmers
and ruby programmers you know
starting around i would claim let's say
okay starting around 2010 that's the
situation
so let me let me uh go into details
what's
what's the problem so
so like today in javascript you have a
library
library that just finds five five
lines of code one two three four five
five lines of code
that does stream string you know like
left pad
you know five lines of a code what the
[ __ ]
who the [ __ ] doesn't know how to write
that i mean you
you see library the purpose of library
is to save your time
usually it's a task someone has
dedicated their life
their time to write it you know take it
takes a week takes several days or a
month to write a library
so you are a programmer you know it's
useful you you separate things into
packages you have libraries you can use
but today it's it's it's
it's quite different okay today there
are libraries
especially in javascript land that
exists that's just five lines of code
now if you are a programmer if you don't
know how to write that
i mean you are you would be a [ __ ]
idiot you don't
you know you you should not do it be
doing programming
but okay the thing here the major thing
is that
you download the library that's five
lines of code let's let's trivial
so the actual the
the time to uh maintain that library to
keep you know keep that library around
is actually uh it takes more time you
waste your more time than actually
writing that code yourself
you know just five lines of code this
happens in the javascript land
npm the the mpm the the boss of
npm isaac i think he's not a good human
animal
you know he basically he created this
situation
for the purpose of benefiting benefiting
you know making himself more popular
that is my opinion okay
so you know it's today the library you
know
the programmers they don't know much
about programming anymore
you know so they just they don't even
know
like they don't know what is the library
they like they they lost
the general sense of things
why does that happen well part of the
reason is you know programming
uh us technology progresses programming
uh becomes
more you know we have lots more
technology and these companies
they need people they need to keep they
need people to code it so
it would benefit these companies you
when
if they are you know huge number of
people programmers
so they don't have to pay uh high
salaries for very few
you know nerd you know programmers so
they
companies they create the situation with
they create a situation basically they
want everyone to be programmers
and they want you to be replaceable they
don't want someone who
like knows a lot or has a lot of
opinions about something
they want you to be [ __ ] wheels so they
can you know
they can pick cheaply pick pick you and
kick you out and replace you with
someone else
like you you you don't matter you don't
matter to
these corporations that's that's the
condition that's what
generally what corporations want you
know that because that
benefits them that way so
because of that and because the
tremendous progress of software you know
technology because everything becomes
computer because the computer becomes
becomes more and more important and ai
technology and so on
um so you need more programmers and
then the programmers that you know their
knowledge and their ability kind of
degraded
in general okay generally speaking
and so libraries uh i would say that
that is
the situation okay i think that's that's
about that for that that for that topic
uh someone says especially in the
javascript so many random libraries are
used even for the synthesis tasks
that's right but each library has their
own risk of breaking the project that
imports the library that's right
and this situation is specifically
particularly
severe in the javascript community
and in particular the npm
ecosystem you if you like my codec you
know the mpm system
it's why is it that way in part it's
because
it's created that way because these
corporations or this
npm leader they they want it that way so
that
they benefit you know they can you know
they can become more rich
okay that's part of the reason okay
there there are other reasons there are
other more um they are less
there are other reasons that's not as
dramatic
you know you know because you know we
you know there's more and more computers
and technology um
progresses
so good morning center good morning
freddie
uh good morning to germany cam she came
just
right on time for a rent okay so
okay that's about that's about that i
don't know what um
you know i have article on that actually
so if you just search for
okay so let's uh e-max the
start command log mod
oh wait [ __ ] okay so back to
so here you can see all my commands in a
pink window
and let's type for xally library
okay there are some there are some some
articles about
that but i don't think i'm
um seeing the one i want actually i want
to talk about
but anyway there are some generic there
are some other articles about libraries
so this one this one is actually quite
popular this one is not written by me
this one is written by david barr and
this one
is the title is why ld library path is
add
you know that's one of the technical
environment variable in
unix and linux and
and this article is written around year
so you know i talked about this before
so back then i was working at utopia
and we write server software e-commerce
server software one of
you know one of the first or the first
and i was
responsible for
uh for i'm part of dev
team and i'm also part of the devops
you know what today what you would call
it devops
but devops back then doesn't exist that
word doesn't exist
you are just called sysadmin so i'm
doing both
and one time when installing and testing
our software in a staging
server you got this bug and
finally i traced it to the ld library
path
so i found this article written written
around
2000 okay written around 2001
so so i but but the article is dead you
cannot find it on the web anymore so i
copied
it and put on my website and since
since then this page has been very
popular
you know you'll see this if you just
search this title you you'll find it
linked
in quite quite a lot places on stack
overflow
on database forums you know lots of
places
so so this is this is part of the unix
problem you know the unix linux people
you know the
[ __ ] heads they don't they don't they
don't unders you know so this
so this is a major problem this is a
major
technical problem of unix
in particular the concept of
environmental
environment variables environment
variables
should be banned they create small
problems and
then they solve they should be entirely
banned
so never ever use environment variables
okay
if you um that's my advice if you like
what i do you know if you like my style
of thinking
never ever use environment variables in
your system
so like for example if you are
linux or bsd or whatever you know or mac
os you know you're doing something you
know you
it's it's it tells you oh for ruby or
python or
you know alternatively you can use this
environment variable don't do it
you know avoid avoid environment
variable as much as possible
it's it's not entirely possible because
this is part of you know what we have
the technology you cannot just throw it
away
but you know try to avoid environment
variables
as much as possible uh
you know is so so why is environment
variables bad because
they are basically they are essentially
the essence
of environment variables is that they
are global
variables okay global i mean if you are
a programmer then you already
know how bad is global variables
that's what environment variables are
and then then you you have you know a
bunch of dot files
anyway
so i recommend don't use environment
variables okay
now if you have to use the file the dot
file is even
you know better than like config files
use
use config files uh to avoid
environment variables and even better
than that is just
invo avoid that at all like no no
variables
so every time you call a library or
something
let's say every time you call some kind
of bash command
you just make it make sure that you put
every argument
i mean every parameter in the line okay
don't use the
environment variables
yeah i know some some of you will say oh
yeah but that's too many
uh you know
arguments you know to well you can do it
so okay bob says it's hard to follow
that advice
from a kubernetes perspective
it is based a lot on environment
variables and
even if you don't use them then you
still depends on constructs very similar
to environment variables okay
that that's a that's a point you know
what you mean by depends on
constructs very similar to environment
environment variables that's the thing
what do you mean by similar but
you know essentially you you don't want
global variables
so what says if you work with kubernetes
okay i don't know what's kubernetes okay
let's look up
kubernetes kubernetes let's see
wikipedia
yeah [ __ ] never ever donate to wikipedia
okay they are the guy is a scum they are
a millionaire never ever donate to
wikipedia
in fact never ever donate to anything
open source
today now 10 years ago 20 years ago
that's a different story but today open
source
it's uh it's extremely evil and also
wikipedia never don't
do not donate it okay do not donate to
wikipedia if you got money
keep it keep it to yourself and spend it
you know do you know
buy stuff whatever you know don't don't
donate thinking oh i'm going to be a
good person no you have you are [ __ ]
[ __ ]
you are doing that just to uh so you
feel happier
meanwhile you contribute to the
to the mystery of other people who are
poor
okay uh kubernetes kubernetes uh
kubernetes how do you pronounce it
kubernetes common commonly
styles that at k8 s is an open source
container orchestration system
for automating computer application
deployments okay
scaling and management it was originally
designed by google
okay and it's not maintained by cloud
native computing foundation
crap you know this gun
you know uh usually all these
nonprofit organizations basically in my
opinion regard all non-profit
organizations as scumbags
have you ever looked into you know all
these donations like you you might want
to donate
you know it's good you know it's a
common uh good
thing for programmers to do especially
if you work at google you have
you know quite a few money to donate you
know you feel you you feel better you
know you feel you are contributing to
society to some
non-profit organization this or that you
know there are
quite a lot of them but have you ever
looked
where did your money actually go oh you
know some organizations they donate to
africa africa children so
americans love these concepts you know
donate donate
where does you know have you ever looked
where does your money actually go
uh i bet well most of you have not you
know you just uh you doing donation
because
you know it makes you feel happy and
that's usually all that
that's about it and you are donating
only
like less than 0.1 of your money
you know if you're a programmer now if
you donate the big time
that would be a different story okay if
you donate for example let's say
let's just say even one percent of your
income
one just just one percent if you donate
one percent of your
yearly income then that's you know
that's actually something
but that's not what all these most
people donate um
anyway let's go back to the article so
it's it was originally
designed by google and it's maintained
by this org foundation
it aims to provide a platform for
automating deployment scanning and
operations of applications con
containers across clusters of hosts
okay uh this is a new technology of
course oh it's written in go
fantastic you know this is beyond me
i'm too old for this this is six years
six
years ago so this is a new generation
thing so i don't have
experience uh
kubernetes okay so you know your cloud
cloud and uh and
uh you know parts replica
sets services volumes name space
config maps and secrets stateful
sets demon you know they are okay
quite a few jargons well i i don't know
are you so are you working on this kind
of thing part
so kubernetes so body is saying if
you're going to use that
you are going to have lots of problems
if you want to avoid using environment
variables okay that may be true
yeah okay that may be true yeah so you
know
okay what's uh we're gonna let's talk
about something else
uh how long have i been talking
i've been talking for 30 minutes uh
korean lynch uh kinder lynch good
good day for from faint michigan
all hi joseph search good day from
ecuador hey ecuador
and freddie i have an article yeah let's
go back to my article so
we rambled about this uh unix
lb library path okay they are they are
you know
i have an article that um okay i know
where to find it
okay let's go to one let's go to my
programming blog
so this one is closure instant insta
pass pasta tutorial you know i worked i
worked on two
uh closure about five years ago and
you know 2014 and studied
this parser in detail and wrote a
detailed tutorial of it
better better than its documentation so
i wrote the entire manual
of this uh closure parser
instaparse parser okay is are they still
around let's check
so it's written by this guy eaglebug
okay so it's
it's very good faster but
the documentation is not
as good as i hoped that's why i
rewrote it
but okay so anyway
so you see it's popular it's got 2 000
stars and 128 folks
okay let's go back so you go to my
programming blog
okay closer closure tutorial so
well i have lots of tutorials on many
languages
you go buy it okay
you know you can buy my entire saudi
website or you can buy
um
you know for example i have javascript
you know some some of these are
very good okay javascript tutorial
get linux in python
okay so i want to show yeah okay so
let's go to my coding um
programming blog okay so go to
programming
then go to
yeah technology
there it is technology past and future
so this guy says you promised me moss
colonies
instead i got facebook
now if you are oh oh the generation like
me you understand what this guy is
saying you know but if you are
younger you don't know
you know you don't know so anyway here i
think i have an
article here let's search for libraries
on the question of too many programming
libraries
exponential growth of programming
language libraries
now this is written in 2016
when i was a poor sub
i was living below poverty below
the poverty's poverty
so 2000 you know you know exponential
growth of programming language libraries
so i'm right i i this article is written
with respect to
from a philosophical point of view
you look at humanities you know one
aspect
one in doing endeavor
endeavor of human animals
that is programming you know the
programming activity and
there exists this thing called libraries
right
you know the libraries existed long ago
like 40 years ago
so you know program means activity of
human animals and
and you know it's part of technology and
you have this concept of libraries
which is part of the programming um
you know activity activity so i want to
look you know as
typical of me i want to look at this
situation from a
from the from a entire human animal
perspective you know uh worldwide
uh and and uh income passing
from you know from the moment it existed
to today not fat okay as
in contrast to today's you know most
people
the the fats you know they don't know
nothing they just look oh this library
oh this is a new language i need to use
this so
did you did you know this new library or
that that's about the [ __ ]
okay so so i have always been doesn't
matter what topic i always i've always
been
interested you know you want to look at
the whole
history and humanity humanities point of
view
so i'm so i'm looking so i noticed you
know in 2016
wow so you know there are so many
libraries like you cannot even keep up
you know like this is different from 20
years ago
like in year in 1990s or even
even year 2000s if you are doing
particular language let's say c or perl
then you know that you know basically
there's a set of libraries
you know part of them bundled with the
language part of them
outside of the language okay but
basically they are just
said that that every programmer
of this language at least the good ones
will know
you know this is just these or maybe uh
next year there's a new one then okay
then everyone you know we know about it
if you are a good programmer of that
language
so that's a situation back then but not
today i mean even doesn't matter
what language even even if you study
hard
even if you didn't care your type yeah i
mean you cannot keep up you cannot
you don't even know what what's out
there it's like it it grows
exponentially beyond
beyond the possibility of your
comprehension
now that is the case of course in
javascript
and that's the case probably in python
in ruby and if you
you know if you sleep for one year next
year there's
10 000 things you don't know so that's
you know that's so this is a
from from a overall historical
phenomenon point of view this is a
phenomenon
this is new this happened in in humans
world this is a new thing
you know this all of a sudden you know
libraries you know like
ten thousands of them that to the point
that
even in a particular language you you
don't know you can you can
it's not it's impossible to be aware of
them
anymore even if you tried
so this is so there is this new
phenomenon and
so i you know i'm a blogger i'm a you
know blogger kind of a guy you know i
observe the you know situation so i i
i try to think about what
what is what what what is the
significance of this happening what is
the significance of this phenomenon you
know
of all things all things like how does
it
impact humanity how does it impact
programmers life how did how did this
happen
what are the causes that made this
happen you know you think about all
these kind of things like it's
it's not like given you know it's not
like school work
you know you go to school you got a
homework and today's homework is to
solve this problem
you know and if you don't know the
solution you look at
you know that you know the answer or you
look up wikipedia so it's not like that
this is open
it's this is this is this is philosophy
okay many people don't know
you know we have people talking about
philosophy but actually they don't know
[ __ ] about philosophy this is philosophy
okay
this what i'm talking about is about the
question on the question of too many
programming libraries
this is philosophy but it's not
but this one is it's not a you know it's
not a giant um
a major thing you know but anyway
i'm illustrating you know what is
philosophy this this is a philosophy
this is what philosophers do
um okay so anyway so on a question of to
me foreign libraries so so
so what what is the cost when did it
happen why does it happen
what is the impact what's the
consequence you know you want to study
you want to look think you want to think
think is the major thing
think the definition of philosophy
is think you not just think okay
it's not like you think about one minute
and and that's philosophy no
you put your life to something and just
think about it you think
for one hour today two hours three hours
five hours a day you think about it
every day you think you keep thinking
about this
for one year for two years for three
years but for ten years
then you are a philosopher of this
particular topic okay
so you can do that with this topic
exactly you know what
on the question of too many programming
libraries so
and you will you know that's what
philosophy is
then you'll discover you know this is
not just about programming anymore
because
once you dive deep it relates you know
for example
it touches uh human habit social
structure you know what kind of what
kind of society what
kind of for example economic system
in a society will create this situation
and maybe some other we are not and you
know so so it's open question there's no
end to it
and also often it involves uh
history so you can type you know so for
example
when you study this question on the
question of too many programming
libraries
you could you know one of the questions
you is is when
when did library begin when did the
concept of
a library begin in programming you know
try to find it try to
you know some people you know today's
you know the malaysian [ __ ] and
idiots they want they they they like to
say oh academics they say
oh where's your citation i need citation
okay citation try you know so try to
find
the first citation you know in academia
or somewhere
or maybe it's etched in stone you know
maybe you'll find
on the greeks someone's grave you know
2000 years ago
when did the concept of library begin
and does that qualify as programming you
know maybe there's
library concept before the you know
programming of course then there's
linguistic aspects
for example when we say library what you
know where does the
word came from what do you mean library
library is a place you go to
and borrow books right so what the [ __ ]
is a programming language library like
like you know it's not you know it's not
a place i can go and borrow books so why
why do you call it library
well that that's etymology okay so of
course
then you understand you know it it's
it's borrowed from the concept of
physical library
via analogy
analogy is in fact how most words are
invented
okay so anyways let's go back to this
topic on the you know so i was you know
uh so i don't remember what i said here
but let's see
so many so many libraries so um
yeah so among the question is how does
it affect you
you know so this is a new phenomenon so
you know
this too many so so many libraries this
is a new phenomenon
in society it somehow just happened uh
it happened around let's say 2010. i
mean it doesn't happen just one day but
it's kind of like
you know he's historians usually you put
a specific
date as a milestone or you know some
kind of
to mark that day as you know as
something happens so you could you could
say let's say this
began i would say late 2000s
okay or we can just say make it easier
2010. we can say okay that
that's the time when libraries goes
exponential
uh and you know so one of the question
is i mean
like how does it how does it impact you
you know you as a programmer do you is
this something you like
does it benefit you or does it uh
is it good or bad what do you think you
know so there are
all sorts of questions to ask
so okay so you know in turn uh we
realized
it's not just libraries it's exponential
growth of everything today because of
technology
you know it's uh we you know we
you know we we i'm i might call myself a
technologist and you guys
too because we are interested in
technology you know
also the programming languages and uh
you know computers
cpus or intel or what what's the latest
gpu you know from nvidia you know we are
interested in our latest monitor display
inc
technology you know we are excited about
that
so so many and ai of course artificial
intelligence and machine learning
so in quantum computing of course
um so there are many things going on and
so it's not just libraries so so we do
know that
this is exponential growth of
almost everything so human animals
we begin as far as i you know my
perception is that
human animals we know nothing we know
less and less
and basically we know nothing each one
of you
and me we know nothing
that is the correct answer you know
nothing
now if you believe that then you are
correct
if you don't believe that then you are
[ __ ] idiot you are just another
another you know warm crawling on earth
okay i think that's it for today
oh my god i got 19 people talking about
philosophy
uh okay so but
all the comments is from bot how long
have i been talking i've been talking
for
45 minutes
we we should shut down uh since we
talked about
on this topic of philosophy that makes
it
nice uh you know just one topic
and we shut down maybe five minutes in
five minutes so
let's see
okay close that close that let's see
let's go to my
video check audio check
sally monologue famous sally monologue
i know nothing
so derek says derrick rods says
the the impetus of libraries
is what we call what was called code
reuse
back in the day too many libraries
fracture
effort is a trade-off too many libraries
too much fracture not enough libraries
okay
okay i think maybe that's it for today
um
okay so what the so that's you know
that's the question
you know that's the thing that's the
article i was trying to
you know since spot asked about
libraries so
i have an article on that
uh okay mathematics my
true love you know this you know you
know these
are the these are functions you see
these pretty pictures
now this is the beauty of mathematics
and you know when you learn math
at school mostly it's boring right oh
trigonometry or calculus or algebra
oh x y you know how to solve you know
that's boring
uh it's boring because mostly because
the teachers are not
interested in it you want someone
who are enthusiastic who love the
subject when some you know when
when your teacher when when you love the
subject
you know it may be programming or math
or chemistry or whatever
you know you do when you love the
subject
you you and when you talk about it your
your
show you know you know in your emotion
and you will
you will automatically do a spectacular
job
so at school you know
most most math teachers uh i guess
many of them i guess most majority of
them are not
that great they because they they you
know they
they don't love the subject that much
uh on the other hand great
mathematicians
almost always love the subject okay for
example the greatest mathematicians
oh i mean it doesn't have to be math
teach mathematician
it can be programmer the pianist you
know pianist musicians
the great you know usually the greatest
ones they they truly love the subject
so so math okay so you know
you you learn in school you know the
boring stuff but here is the actual
beauty okay
today we showed we showed
you know today we have seen the
stereographic projection now this is
about complex analysis okay
why well i can go i can i can i can
i can i can actually do a tutorial i
think i did one
but it's pretty lousy you know i'm not i
i need to practice
uh teaching teaching math and also i
haven't been doing math for a long time
so so but you know for example this
a stereographic projection i can
wait what happened so you can i can go
into detail so you can so you can
understand
how how does this you know what why does
this have to do with complex numbers how
is it
so interesting and similarly okay
similarly
what uh for all these you know
for example this okay this mathematica
i wrote in 2 in 19 1997
this this is what mathematical language
looks like
okay now if you ask our fans and then
scheme at least you know get out
because mathematica is like 10 times
more advanced than
than whatever your huskar or whatever
so i wrote this in 1997. this one is
doing plain tiding
plain tiling and
patterns and symmetry there's you know
there's huge amount of math
of it today you know i can write this
in javascript uh of course there will be
more lines and it will be harder
but it's it's it's doable and
actually quite a few people have already
done that for example you look at the
javascript
3d.js library that guy's
you know done lots of these and many
other people have done you know using
javascript
i'm kind of getting old you know i i
want to write
for example i want to rewrite this in
javascript
but it just delays and delays i'm
getting oh that's really what
you know what is happening that that
that does happen
i mean on the surface i don't see
any reason like i why not you know but
it just it's just not happening
uh anyway so all these are in
mathematica
these are these are the plots of sine
cosine
in functions
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
uh if you like my stuff donate
patreon paypal amazon gift card
go to my keyboard website buy stuff or
buy
buy my emacs and javascript tutorial
okay
paint rules titling yeah abstract
algebra plus plus
uh penrose tithing yeah good morning
informatic
penrose tidying you know i actually so i
so maybe next time we're gonna talk
about math because this
there is quite a lot okay let me show
you where to go to okay you go to
xr math you'll find this page
then there are some spectacular things
here
uh that's a plot this one this is a what
i call
borg cube and this is actually a plot of
a
equation involving sine and cosine
this is a minimal surface this
is a polyhedron you know rinse
for decorative purposes
this you know this one is dark cohesion
and you have more of that
this this kind of images are fairly
popular
uh cyan cosine plots and
again this is inversion this is called
inversion
okay i need to talk about it some other
day but i anyway so
and this one uh this one is also very
interesting
because in part because let me show you
so
you see the whole image is made of one
single line
okay now this this this image
you know so you can you know you know
today's generation the male engine with
their you know idiotic
[ __ ] you know they they also have
graphics by the way so malenchen they
have got
what they call um what gen genet
uh genet generative you know generative
art what what is it called what's what's
the proper word
generative art what the [ __ ] they
they [ __ ] create scrap you know like
like you
you you splash piss on on your screen
then that's artwork
that's those uh generative uh that
those are like that you just splash
paste
or spit on your screen that that's art
uh instead of using your mouth you use
you know you use the programming
language to do that you know just
garbage
you know it's like art that's today's
generation beginning
beginning with the malay generation so
the
millennial generation you actually they
constitute a
a huge chapter in human history
you know about the change of people
change of
norms change of society so you know
like you know we know each generation
is a bit different than you know even
back to 2000 years ago it also depends
on the region
you know in china in in usa
you know in different regions you have
different culture different norms and
they change
and so the millennial generation is uh
you know i i think you know it's uh it's
it's a big uh
kind of change in human uh culture
so anyway so these are you know part of
them is a
fractal snowflake okay so recursive yeah
this
this one a single line it's called it's
done by recursive
line replacement and you have also
recursive thailand pinwheel thailand
very famous very popular
uh this is a building using that as a
theme uh pink wheel titling
as a theme in australia melbourne
federation square and then you have
fractals
then you have um okay you have quite a
lot okay so the
the all these are i'm talking about this
on this page
it's algorithmic mathematical art
actually so this this is actually one of
my big
i would consider one of the more um
if i may say so among my
thousands of articles this one is more
important valuable
algorithmic mathematical art so first of
all i give you a survey
of all different types of what's called
mathematical art
you you will see these if you are into
math
you know for example there are
competitions you know
visualization of maths math
so i give you a survey of all the
different
math arts and their techniques how they
are generated
then then i give you and at the bottom
near you know bottom of the page these
are celtic knots you know
celtic nuts uh traditional uh decorative
art
in northern europe you know scandinavia
countries
uh but this one is uh something else
though
uh this this one is more islamic you
know different different culture they
have different styles
and then you have uh islamic patterns
then you have penrose titans
penrose titans is one of the great it's
not just
uh decorative art but it's uh it's one
of the
greatest discovery discovery or theory
in mathematics in fact penrose tidings
so anyway at the bottom then there's
there is hyperbolic geometry okay
then the typical factors then
then you know four-dimensional things
five-dimensional
things the shape of space
then evolutionary programming cellular
automata
then you have the you know this azure
symmetry group theory okay
symmetry and group theory this
this one is is i i would say
the my favorite artwork of asia
of all mc asher's artwork this one is my
favorite
okay then more mcsha this is about
transformation of
tidy so anyway at the bottom of the page
i
try to give a definition of what is
algorithmic mathematical art
okay in short it must be
mathematical uh well it's hard to define
you
you can read it yeah and you know it
you know it's mathematical and then by
mathematical
essentially it means it must illustrate
certain mathematical structure or the
artwork
must have certain systematic
mathematical structure
okay on in contrast
computer generated graphics such as
these
that's not okay that's that's crap this
is
crap you know these computer programmers
you know you guys
love this you know you know like if you
are in programming community
every day you'll see oh great tracing
you know let's do a retracing
the [ __ ] idiots computer programmers
they
they love this topic but they don't but
they know nothing about the
you see all these uh other things i
talked about they like they
they never see that you know they they
might have seen a few polyhedron or mc
asia right
but they have no idea what what's what
what are they made of how
you know what's the structure you know
why they don't know but they
however every [ __ ] you know these
programming nerds you know unix
philosophy these [ __ ] they will love
that you know ray trace
ray trace is one of the big thing you
know if for computer programmers c
c plus plus coders they love this
so so this so that this this
is inco this is not an example of
mathematical art
okay nor is it algorithmic
art okay i i defined what is algorithmic
artwork here you know
if you read the detail so this is not
okay so some drawing some image
created algorithmically is
not by definition not by my definition
not my definition okay
that would not qualify as algorithmic
art okay but literally yeah it's
algorithmic because it's done by a
computer so
you know computer can do lots of things
you can do you know especially today
machine learning
ai they start to paint you know they
start to
generate pictures you know uh and so
you might say oh are they algorithmic
not really
well in some sense literally they are
they are created
entirely by a computer by uh by
algorithms
but those algorithms especially the ai
you know the machine
learning the neural networks they are
not
um how shall we say they are not uh
they are not they are
they are i think it's called statistical
algorithms
they are not um
how do you say predictive there's a word
i forgot you know deterministic okay
they are not deterministic algorithms
in other words what they come up will be
different each time you know you don't
know what's gonna happen
that's that's those machine learning and
ai
and neural network stuff
so so so first of all i give a
definition of what's mathematical art it
must
in short it must contain a certain meth
must contain embed or illustrate certain
mathematical structure
such as this one symmetry so what is
symmetry
you know if you study math you know it's
like it's actually isometry it's a group
theory and isometry there's a
very technical definitions okay
and this transformation you know they
embed they embed
mathematics in other words these are
mathematical arts they embed mathematics
for example this one this one you know
double score
of fishes you know so they are spirals
but
but what about spirals spirals i can
show you um
okay you know spiral is one of the curve
this one is called
this spiral is called uh
this one is called equal angular spiral
or
logarithmic spiral that
meaning that they have a specific
property for them to be
world this way not bigger not smaller
you know every line every point must be
exact
to qualify as this spiral so so
so this again it's called uh equal
angular spiral okay you can look at my
website
okay so i need to switch to um
equal angular spiral okay so we
rambled onto math but what the hell we
have nothing to do
we have the okay so these are equal
angular spirals you know these
are this all all of these the top two
rows are all from my website
so equal angular spiral why is it equal
angular because they have a specific
property you see all the angles from a
read
from the array from the center to
a tangent on the spiral is
always the same angle doesn't matter
which rate
that's that is why they are called equal
angular spirals okay let's go to the
page
and okay so that's you know there's diff
there are many properties and then you
started you started to see equations
okay
sine cosine and equations that that's
that's the beauty
of math and you have to prove you know
why why is it equal anger you know
show a proof you know then there's proof
and curvature you know all these
fantastic things
this is math okay then it shows in
nature you see this often you know in
in those um in those uh math
you know exhibit or you know in science
magazines
so anyway equal angular spiral so back
to the
uh you know so
so so that's why this one is a
mathematical art
i claim because it embodies this
mathematical structure in this case
equal angular spiral or logarithmic
spiral
is the alternative name and this one too
it embeds symmetry there's you know
and you know and cellular autonomous
automata this one
it doesn't well it this one it
demonstrates the nature of
this statement this this illustration
cellular automata
from stefan wolfram a new kind of
science demonstrates
demonstrates the theory that
deterministic systems may not be
predictable
okay that's one of the great things you
learn when you study
cellular automata so the system is very
simple deterministic just like
atoms in the universe uh well
if you don't count quantum computing
anyway deterministic okay
but however it's not predictable why
because
in order to predict it you have to do
the computation
and do the computation it's so huge it's
impossible it doesn't matter what kind
of computer you have
the only way is to actually leave it
leave it
so for example you know one one thing
interesting about super computers like
you studies you know you go to wikipedia
you look up
super computers you know every year or
two
they have like top 10 the world's
fastest fastest
super computer you know usa china japan
they take turns on the top and one of
those
you know so what what do they uh what
what does those super computers do every
day you'll find you'll notice that one
thing they do
is that they they they they
compute weather like they learn
simulations
to model weather like they they try to
predict the weather
imagine using super computers to not
solve you know difficult math problems
or computer problems or nuclear physics
or
or you know thermal chemistry or
whatever but they
they use those supercomputers to predict
weather
why because well actually because
weather is actually
one of the most important thing in
society you have to know the weather
like if tomorrow is raining you know
whether you can go to your friend's
house
it actually turns out to be one of the
most important thing
and the other thing about it is that
whether
it's you know extremely computational
intensive
and you know like you can predict next
minute but in order to predict
two minutes after that it the
the computational power is exponential
you know exponential growth
so the further away the harder
it becomes impossible like very quickly
it's impossible to
to predict you know five days you know
like today
with our current technology we can
you know we can look at weather like
apple you know apple and you know every
computer has this weather
um in five days you know you go to web
you know where the five days you know
but after a month you know it becomes
impossible to predict
so that's you know so so that ties into
cellular automata you know that
if if you study this uh you are no
cellular automata
it you you you understand why that that
is the case
determine you know even if you know
deterministic
systems may not be predictable
and and generally just it's just
unpredicted
you know not predictable so anyway so
then you have you know four dimensional
things like this these things
four-dimensional thing five-dimensional
and this is uh
you know and different shapes different
uh shape of space
topology okay so all these images
they i i call them basically all images
on my page
the all these are mathematical uh
artwork
why because they embed or illustrate
certain structure
of mathematics of mathematical beauty
pure you know you will not see an animal
face you will not see a pretty bird
you will not see you know some you know
some
some pretty girls okay
it's all pure abstract
uh images they there is
you know there is immense beauty a
structure embedded in them
for example knots for example you look
at these knots
how are they you know how are they
connected how are they weaved
you know that's a that's the structure
info informatics okay information
okay so anyway so that's a definition i
give you
some kind of definition of what's what
what constitute
an artwork to be called mathematical
okay
then i also define i tell you what
how i should i by you know
when's the when is the when when's the
computer
computer generated artwork qualifiers
algorithmic
okay now i'll give you the short version
of it
in order for it to be algorithmic you
know what i call algorithmic it must
your code your source code must must
must correspond to
it must your source code your algorithm
you know
the way you create the picture must
correspond to the structure
of the image then if that's the case
then
your code is you know what i would call
algorithmic uh
art you know program you know the a
program
uh that that that that qualifies as
you know the program generating
algorithmic mathematical art
there are details you know this anyway
so that's i think
so okay that's that's that's it for
today
thank you guys for watching lots of
rambling
uh kinah protein folding like curry can
models
yeah uh
okay bye guys
so today we talked for
one hour and 10 minutes okay
have a good day