good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is August 3rd 2019
7 o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time and today we are
going to do Emacs Lisp I'm going to live
code email is so and I'm going to call
email is live and meanwhile I also teach
you you know explain Emacs Lisp that's
one of the topic the other topic is I'm
going to talk about JavaScript
there is a insult incident happening in
JavaScript where I was talking with
brain Brendan Eich the guy who created
created JavaScript on Twitter and so it
was you know something unpleasant I
turned it turned out so so so so
nobody's here yet let me see let's see
let me typed out Emacs sleeps live
coding and JavaScript wait
okay
so so that is the topic and let's see
what why am i okay wait something's I
mean Chinese mod no I don't want Chinese
mod ok and saw start command log mod ok
and in this window you will see every
Emacs commands I call on the top left
and let me pop pop the chat out so if
you have any comments questions just
type it ok so the today's topic is going
to be Emacs live coding Emacs Lisp and
JavaScript let me get the I'm kind of
late a little bit so let me prepare the
windows so move the windows here so you
can see that should be fine
okay so let's do Chavez that's to Emacs
Lisp Emacs okay so let's see
emacs least what I'm going to do okay I
know what I want to do so let's go to my
Emacs blog so you see this is my Emacs
Prague and a few days ago I talked about
there's a Sun talk-show episode I talked
about Emacs conference 2019 and Emacs
Meetup and light coding so that was
another email is tutorial so if you are
interested you might check it out now
this is my local version of my website
just search for saw the Emacs you'll
find it my blog Emacs blog then you'll
see the video I don't have it here
because javascript is off so what we are
going to do today okay I know what to do
do so as suppose so
you see this is the file showing browser
you know this is my Emacs blog on my
local computer so I'm gonna create a new
section one second so let me move this
here so that we you can see my you can
see this window okay
all my Emacs commands over there so I'm
going to start something okay let's say
something X okay
showing browser you can see it's there
something X now I need to add to my RSS
feed
now ISS feed is is it's basically a XML
file so people can subscribe to it you
know then you'll get whenever I update
my blog you'll also get it so how that
is done is basically so if you go to the
directory here you see the block dot
HTML is my Emacs block and this block
dot XML is the web feed RSS file now
there are several format you know
protocol of that the one I'm using is
called atom so if you are not I talked
about this before if you are not
familiar let me show you sorry Adam web
feed so I have a tutorial on the atom
web feed so this is what the file looks
like here over here so it's basically a
HTML file and each entry you know you
have the header there you have the
footer at the bottom feed then each
entry this is part of the header here
and each entry so this is what one entry
looks like you know so today if you
wrote a block it's gonna be you know
like that
so this is what atom web feed look looks
like it's a XML file which is you know
over here so this is my atom web feed
you can see you can see here's one entry
August 1st and here is another entry
this is July 29th and here
another entry and so on so close the
file close it so I need to add entry for
today's blog you know I just wrote I
just wrote something X I want to add
entry so I have a command the command is
called stomach atom entry that is on my
website you can search that name you'll
find a code so you can see it created a
new entry here you know with the title
HHH those three triple edge are just
template so you have title you have ID
you have updated date this is supposed
to be a date ID ID is supposed to be
unique across the universe okay so so
guys say say hi okay say hi here today
we are going to I'm going to I'm doing a
live coding of Emacs at least and also
talk about JavaScript a bit so anyway so
here is the atom entry and you have the
ID supposed to be unique across the
universe then you have the updated date
it suppose vo date then you have the
content you see here from here to here
is the content you know the the meet of
whatever you want to say then after that
you have a link you know it's like a
aute link you know so if people want to
read this in detail you know you can go
to this link so that's the end of the
entry so that that is basically what a
atom RSS seen dug in a atom web feed
looks like also known as RSS so so so I
just created this entry you know I save
it you know then I close it then I I
split the window go to each shell and I
say update my website or sync okay so
it's uploaded to my website you can see
there's two files gets updated and now
if you go to my blog sorry
Emacs you'll see you'll see the entry
you see something X then if you click
the subscribe feed you can see that
there are something X C so it's updated
so that is web feed but what what am i
doing I mean what what is it that we
want to do what we want to do is okay so
I said you know here I say something X
but after an hour I want to edit it so I
want to say actually you know something
Y and so on okay you know when you write
a blog sometimes you want to modify or
add stuff so once you do that you want
to modify the the web you know the web
feed file as well you want to update it
so so I copy this I copy it okay then I
go to my web feed file open it this is
the entry I need to modify it so
remember we changed something x2 select
that paste it you know it becomes
something Y and so on so that is a new
entry but there's one more thing we
should do that is we should update the
updated tag the date you know we need to
give it a date so guys comments okay
comments opinions questions say hi say
where you came from you know
you know type just type it the more
typing the more better is the talk show
so something so we we modified the atom
web feed file we saved it then we need
to update the date so how do you do that
so let me show you I have a command so
let me copy that okay copy this line
paste it over here and let me show you
what I'm gonna so I'm gonna call command
okay I'm gonna press control you then
meta X then saw insert date okay so that
that is my own command so insert a enter
so it asks me several options you know
what format you want the date to be you
see style you know style of the date do
you want it to be you know including
weekday like Tuesday Thursday or just
sequence of digits digits or American
style like you know you you know the
date format has different styles across
the world so it asks you to pick a
format now in the case of atom web feed
the format required is is this number
three let me just press the key number
three okay three that one okay so you
see the date is here let me let's do it
again it's put the cursor here so I'm
going to you know normally I just go cuz
I insert date like if I just call it you
know just insert date in this format you
know year year year year four digits
year two digits month then two digits
date so so now it's 2019 - 0 8 - 0
three let's do it again so so select
that deleted coke assigns a date enter
so you got a date but however if you
want a different format you can press
ctrl you first and pressing control you
then you coca silencer date then you ask
you to pick a format so we pick three
enter you see now that is the updated
date you know current date first time
date time stamp so this is fantastic so
what we need to do is delete the old
date you know use the new date and save
it then close it then go to issue then
call or sync again our sync to my web
server you see main sub uploaded to my
website and now if you go to my MX blog
again click on the RSS you can see you
know it's updated something why you know
that's what we want okay so so what is
the problem so the problem is you know
so every time I make a edit I need to go
to the XML file open it find the entry
then they'd manually you know put a
cursor on the updated location then code
an inserted command which is tedious
what I want is when you know where my
cursor is in your entry I can just press
a button it will automatically update
the updated date there so that's what we
want to do before we do that let me show
you the let me show you the code folks
our insert date
so here's the code and it's also on my
website here you know so go let's go
have a look you can copy it and use it
it's you know for yourself it's very
convenient okay that's you know that's
about update date but today we so what
we are going to do is to write a new
Emacs list command that automatically
find a location for the date tag and
insert a new date that is what we are
going to do right now so open a new
buffer so let me check you know so so
far so good to people so far so good
okay so let me get some drink then so
I've been talking for 60 minutes let's
let's let's continue let's continue it
okay so we we want to write that a new
Emacs Lisp command so we're gonna you
know learn some email is okay so it's
close this XML file close it so back to
my Emacs blog so what we're gonna do is
split the buffer open the new window I
mean a new buffer then save this buffer
as X X date dot DL okay yeah is the
filename extension for Emacs Lisp okay
so now we have a new file now when you
when you open the file in 30 L Emacs we
operate in Emacs Lisp mod you know which
is a mod for Lisp but I'm using my own
I'm using solace mod you know you can
check it out so let me show you
sorry list mod you know this is the mod
I'm using
let's go to the code so here's the
source code a three thousand six hundred
lines of code and go to the my wife my
website for it viewing in browser and
you can see you know it's it's pretty
good you know yeah it's my code so if
you like it if you like nice stuff try
it you know it has many features anyway
so let's go get back to coding the new
function so I so we have a file here now
we need to define different is how you
define a function okay so we have we got
the abbreviation the template so if we
want to define a function but first of
all let's think about what is it exactly
that we want to do so let's write it out
you know typically my style coding is to
write out the kind of sketch out a
documentation first you know then then
sketch out you know how I'm going to do
it like our line of algorithm then I
code it so so what what so what is it
that we want to do we want to
when kusa is in a anthem XML file okay
let's open atom XML file here so what we
want to do when cruise so basically
overall update the date time stamp of
atom RSS file okay that's the that's
what we want to do what's the what's did
what this command is supposed to do now
here's a details when cruiser is in a
atom entry
find the okay then move closer to the
updated tag we face the date time by
current date time okay that that is it
that's what we want to do okay so now we
know what we want to do we can start to
write a code so let's say the name the
file name will be saw update atom date
atom entry date okay that is the
function name okay doc string doc string
version version okay let's say doc
string is this it's just you know since
that's our dog string yeah so actually
call it we're gonna copy that here you
know we're gonna edit this and make it
nice late later but for now let's just
start to code and and so so so okay so
so how do you do that so let me show you
how for so we're going to is this is
what you do so okay so let you know in
Emacs let is how you define local
variables so you have a let and you have
variables here X Y for example then
whatever here you know it's your code
you know you can use X Y are the local
variables so we don't care about that we
don't need variables for now so what
we're gonna do is search backward okay
basically that moves Clues
backwards so what we want to search is
this stream updated so that's the string
we want to search then you have a bunch
of optional arguments which we don't
care about optional arguments so move to
remove them okay
such backward update it now what that is
going to do is going to it's going to
put the cursor here okay so yeah so then
okay here now we are going just to code
this as a prototype I mean quickly we
let's not worry about details oh look or
you know the fine point you know the
most elegant weight you know it's just
to this as a tutorial so now we now Cuza
is over here now we want to move it over
here so how many characters are there so
let's see let's use the Emacs command
count words so they are night characters
okay so now now let's move the cursor
forward nine characters because we want
to move it here so actually let's
declare two local variables p1 and p2
meaning position you know we want two
variables for for crucifies a position
and for short we just name it p1 p2 so
set set key one
so p1 we are equals two we want the
location now remember we want the
location here to here that's the
location we want because in Emacs when
you want to delete part of the text or
things like that you need the position
the beginning position and end position
then you can say you know deleted or
insert somewhere you know things like
that so set position one equals two
point first one actually we can say one
for us
it's the same thing let's just say point
1 so some point returns the an integer
that is the current kusa position okay
and now first one actually we don't want
to press one we want to press 9 remember
because because they are nine characters
here so so what we actually want is we
want the cursor position we want the
kusa position over here so we want to
know what what number that is so this
will give us that save it to key one
then what we do is then we what we do is
search for word again
such forward okay
now this time we want to search for the
less than sign so that the cursor will
end up here you know when you in acts
when you use such forward then you give
the string the cursor will end up at the
end of the string so if you are
searching for word the cursor will end
up here on the other hand if your cursor
is here and use such backward for the
for the less than sign then the cursor
will end up in front of the string you
see so we're so so whether the Kusa
ends up after the string or before the
string depends on whether you are using
such forward or backward you know that's
that's how it is so now now remember our
cruiser is here actually
okay let's do this such forward such
backward okay such backward then let's
do this we don't need options let's make
it simple so such forward so that then
this way it's simple okay then such
forward Demi I'm going to explain how
they walk so first of all such backward
updated so so when we you know that's
gonna put the cursor here then such
forward greater sign the cosa is going
to be here then we save it you know to
p1 that's the point
the Chrissa position then we search
forward oh then then we actually just
let's just search forward such forward a
less than sign then cosa is going to end
up here then one character before that
is the position we want okay so so here
we can say set p2 equals two point
actually - one point minus one okay so
this bunch of code we have p1 and p2
that that is the position of that now we
just want to say delete region DV region
takes two positions p1 and p2 that we
are delete like that so now we just say
insert sorry insert you know date that
command so
on a second okay so let's look at the
command let's look at the command saw
insert date okay we want to insert date
of this format so how do we do that we
there are two ways one way is that we
just sign is a date which is the
other way is to you know to have the
code that insert this state directly
let's do that because that way it's
simpler because the science' date is
designed to use interactively you know
it's not designed to be used to be
called in Emacs Lisp code so so this is
the format we want to insert number
three so let's see the code for number
three so here it is okay so let's copy
the code close it paste the code here
something like that so we need to insert
the date here okay so how do we do that
formal string this we don't need
compact format format timestream okay so
actually the code is a bit more
complicated than let's so so far so good
okay one guy watching
okay so let's so let's figure out what's
going on with the code so we have the
format code let's format it so contact
means join stream
okay concatenation now contact here we
have two arguments to contact one is
format stream format M string and the
other one is that now what does format
time string do let's call describe
function to find out okay so format time
stream - final time it just returns a
timestamp I think it's just run it Evo
it you see okay so let's see
okay so format time string insert this
string you see but then what do you need
to you know so what is this part about
that part is that this that part is
actually let's try it
oh yeah so that part is actually adding
the local time difference you know the
time offset to the universal time
Greenwich Mean Time
oh you know Universal UTC universal time
code and you know the UTC or gm's GMT
you know you know because I'm in
California so it's usually seven hours
later you know eight hours later
depending on you know similar time and
stuff so okay so we know what these code
is doing so we are using contact which
is join string and enjoying string we
have two arguments the first one insert
basic insert a time stamp time and date
date time stamp we including time you
know you have the date here then you
have the time here including seconds the
second part actually insert the you know
the time offset to Greenwich Mean Time
now so so why is this time difference
part so complicated let's see yeah
because I remember it is complicated
because because Emacs doesn't have you
know the format M string it doesn't have
an option for you to actually add that
you know I looked into this when I was
coding this several years ago must be
five old you know seven years ago I
checked in detail so MX doesn't have
that option so that's why you have to do
it yourself
oh yeah so you see what emag does have
is this let's see what it runs so let's
run that oh you see it is easy you see
the here is what it was it returns it
returns - zero seven zero zero without
the semicolon without the colon in
between but the format required by the
atom actually need the the colon in
between so actually this code is a bit
more complicated than it needs to be
because we can actually just insert you
know we could yeah we could but let's
not worry about elegance now so let's
let's let's keep going with this so okay
so so we have the so this this code
insert this code
insert the date/time we want it that's
right so all we have to do is say insert
there okay I think that is basically it
so let's let's check again so we don't
need the date anymore so we such so look
let's look at so we search back for
updated date then we such forward ok
then we set the point then
such forward for that ok then set the
point then delete region let's do it
this way ok let's search for what such
backward
search for would such backward that okay
that is our code then okay search for
word so we search for word and we
searched backward and we set the point P
to then delete region p1 p2 then is that
that that should be it so now we
evaluate the buffer okay now let's test
it okay let's see let's put a date here
let's put yesterday's date so so let's
put August first here you see August
first
today's August 3rd so okay let's put the
cursor here and let's call the command
we just have written so what what's the
name of the command cuz I update atom
entry date okay so update atom entry
hantum and entry date okay it's co-ed
yay
so it worked you see that the date is
got updated correctly okay so that that
is the code that's what we want that I
think that concludes the topic we want
for this topic today let me let's copy
the fight the code and let's go back to
my Emacs tutorial insert emag list code
paste it here then color Fayed show in
browser you see so that that is the
fruit of our effort
okay so that that kind of concludes the
topic now let us delete these we don't
need it anymore
close that so you know this is the we
did that so any questions so guys say hi
okay say hi I feel lonely here so that
finish that concludes the topic now so
now it's 38 minutes we saw we talked for
38 minutes what else so I was thinking
to talk about another another topic
which is about JavaScript but I'm
thinking maybe let's do it another time
well I mean let's talk about that topic
another time because that JavaScript
topic you know I have it's rather it's
somewhat unpleasant okay is this
incident so it's not exactly you know
it's related to design of JavaScript but
it's not you know it's not related to
you know learning JavaScript oh it's you
know it's not a tech tutorial related
which is what I'm doing now so maybe
let's keep this video you know let it be
just tutorial because that way it's
better for people you know who watch the
YouTube so any any other questions among
our Emacs or Emacs Lisp any other
question any any questions tab it guys
type type check check okay yeah yeah as
a type can UK you know so if there's no
more let's see I mean what else is there
to talk up talk about so that's about
Emacs so let me um clean up the
so yeah okay so that's that's about
Emacs what what else okay so so one more
minutes okay let's you know sit for one
more minutes and if there's normal
questions and that'll be it for today
this is my drink Rockstar sugar-free
energy drink which is basically it means
concentrated coffee and as usual this is
my orange juice and pineapple juice 100%
juice and I drink these every day for
like the past 10 or 20 years the juice
that is the the energy drink I started
to drink about five years ago every day
comment post your comments what were you
up to where you came from and what what
interesting things about ya
okay so you know I I realized you know
when I did the video you cannot rely on
people to tell you you know you cannot
keep asking people to tell you topics
stuff you have to just do it then
if people find it interesting they will
comment things like that so about Emax
you know so there's a lot of things you
know about Emacs let's go through you
know so Emacs is the great the greatest
editor editor something it's let's
update that so that we let's see so let
me just you know let me show you I'm
going to write go to update Adam Adam
RSS web feed entry now that's what most
mouthful you know like originally it was
known as RSS now RSS stands for RSS
stand for something syndicate oh yeah
it's the the it actually doesn't have a
real kind of a name so is sometimes
means RTF site summary then it becomes
you know rich site summary then it
becomes really simple syndication you
know this is back in the days this is
around 2001 when iOS RSS was first
created now it was invented by this guy
David what wine I think David wine are
listed search for his name
huh dave winer wait what so such dave
yeah dave winer now dave winer is kind
of a crackpot kind of guy I don't think
he's a good person okay yeah he's kind
of a crackpot you know kind of like
labrie war and and he's kind of into new
ageism or a coat kind of stuff and you
know I don't I don't like him I don't
think he's a good person but anyway he
he created that and he like he's like
hugging on you know he's like you know
as a programmer we programmers are often
you know we programmers are often you
know guys you know we make males
typically very contentious you know
competitive contentious or even some you
know some some form any aggressive or
being an you know that that's
that you know that's basically
male-male nature you know and if you are
like that women like said you know that
said that's why you have this aggression
emails you know so so I'm programmers we
we kind of all competitive and stuff but
Dave Winer is one of the you know
so he created RSS you know on
one hand he you know a lot of people
likes to say oh I'm I'm kind you know
you know so this is you know not
patented it's open source everyone can
use the meanwhile usually there's a
conflict you know so on one hand
typically you want you know you say oh
it's free you know let you know everyone
can use but the other on the other hand
often you you kind of want to control it
you know not not just for the good of
the society you could have a whole but
rather you want
you know you there is an element of like
this is my thing okay I wanted this way
not not really because that way is the
best but rather just because I want that
you know I like it this way this is my
opinion therefore I created it is
therefore it should be this way you know
this this kind of thing and also there's
this kind of you know so you know on one
hand usually on github you know people
avoid mentioning names like you know
they avoid mentioning I created this you
know because then people will say oh you
are so you know such an you are
rude oh you are not humble you know
today the white people programmers they
tends to you know humbleness is like a
good thing to have because if you say oh
I created this you know people tend to
not like that they prefer humble but
actually the whole thing is kind of a
fake because on the other hand you can
see these people you know you know they
actually do want their name attached to
things you know like this is my thing
you know so anyway so dave winer with a
story of RSS that's that's that's a
illustration of that situation you know
he you know like other people create you
know ISS is not very good standard
because in the beginning there's no even
not there's no standard I mean it's not
well specified he's simply basically
just here's a code here's my website I
created RSS and you know just show it to
the world open source there is no
specification then people started to
criticize and and to come up with a spec
then there's you know fight you know
Dave Winer says oh no I don't want that
all you know this is a fight lots of
this has been going on for several you
know for several years and different
versions of RSS but eventually there's a
Adam you know some someone else oh yeah
Adam is created by this guy who now he
killed himself Aaron
we can find a name okay Adam okay
RSS compared to Adam now Adam is the
technology that does exactly the same
thing as ISS but but it's an entire it's
kind of like a different format it's
more way of specified and you know it's
actually it's just better it's a better
one an atom but Adam is created by this
guy you know so we are going into the
history of computing you know many
colorful stories
Adam is created by these these guys used
to be known as a prodigy something like
a prodigy okay let's knit let's find his
name Aaron Schwartz okay he oh yeah and
Mark pilgrim oh my god a lot history
there
so other notable supporting a time
including so who is a guy oh so who is a
guy who actually created Adam Sam Ruby
so I don't know exactly the history of
Adam okay Brad pissed Brad Fitzpatrick
who created that livejournal you know
made many of these well-known names
anyway so you know the people who
support is according to Wikipedia the
people the programmers who support
notable supporting Adam includes Mark
pilgrim daybreak mock pilgrim timbre
Aaron Schwartz Joey I taught his Jack
Park I don't know who that is also and
also dave winer the key figure behind is
s2 gave tentative support to the new in
diva you see tentative support that's
kind of like a polite word for you know
you don't like it you don't want it you
know he want his own is s like I created
you know what a web feed you know
anybody assails shouldn't be successful
this is basically that's a polite polite
way of saying it saying you know Kate so
why they wanna gave tentative support
why would you want you know tentative
support you know you either support it
or not
so anyway Aaron Schwartz you know he is
a he's an
okay he's actually on the kind
of a guy and very bright but sadly he
killed himself you know as most of you
know he because of because you know
suicide in 2013 you know and that's like
four years ago five five six years ago
Aaron shots so when when Adam is going
around this is around 2000 102 or to
2002 or so Aaron draws is like 15
something like that 15 years old
so anyway Mark Pilgrim is also
interesting guy
mark Phil Graham he is known for he is
known for a few things but you know the
last thing he is most well known for is
like he disappeared you know he
disappeared from the internet like when
like you know typically a especially a
famous programmer you know you have
github you have you're on Twitter you
are on Google person you know all the
social networks you have a lot websites
presence you know you have your own own
website and domain and one day like all
of them disappeared like you know
Twitter account every one of his
messages disappeared he just said idiot
that this is last thing he is well-known
for and people got worried you know
where did he go you know then it turns
out you know he's you know he is fine
you know he's doing fine and he just you
know disappeared from the web because
here you know wikipedia talked about it
so this is 2011 yeah he has several
websites and he has wrote many tutorials
dive into Python dive into html5 dive
into accessibility okay dive into grease
monkey now grease monkey is a history
one big chapter of the history of
JavaScript on the browser side you know
because grease monkey is a way for you
to use JavaScript to customize your
browser you know back then you know in
the early 2000s
that it that is a large part of
JavaScript everyone you know he's
talking about that he's using that but
that that greasemonkey the whole thing
disappeared including his tutorial so
anyway he did he disappeared and also
another guy disappeared is this why the
lucky stiff guy he is very famous in a
ruby community very famous and also he
disappeared in in in 2009 so so I guess
they called in for suicide just so you
know this happened you know so they one
day they decided internet is harmful and
they completely severed their online
presences you know I've been thinking of
doing that you know sometimes I've been
thinking maybe I'll do that but I don't
think so I don't think that's something
I'll do so so comments no comments
that's about it today and because I'm
just random ranting mark pilgrim Aaron
Schwartz so anyway that's a story of
Adam you know the web feed and also
there's a linguistic interest you know
Adam so you have all these names you
know atom syndication you know RDF site
summary Really Simple Syndication you
know then
oh the you know all these names is
around 2000 then in let's say 2010
basically people start to use simply use
the phrase web feed you know that's
truly simple you know not web
syndication like because syndication is
the word it's rather more advanced word
you know if you look at the free
in jargons you know people use some
online or elsewhere you know like the
evolution of languages often at least
for some of the programming terms often
often the phrase people eventually end
up using is the one that is that uses
the most basic words you know for
example web feed you know because if you
look at web feed you know web is just
website you know website web can be you
know even a child knows what web means
you know because it's spider web it's
very fundamental two thousand years ago
ten thousand years ago people would
understand what spider web is you know
that's web that so so that's how
primitive the word is you know web and
feed is also very primitive you know
feed feeding eat you know you need to
you know use circle on teats that's
feeding you know you have to be alive
that's so so you know web feed is the
people commonly adopted what okay but as
you know then then Google cured blogging
basically Google cured you know blogging
Beados then basically the entire prog in
community kind of went away then instead
the social you know the the social
websites you know so social networks
so-called social network sites like
Facebook Twitter they took over and you
know blogging is kind of dead killed by
Google mostly when Google cured Google
web reader blogging is already kind of
dead because of the social networks
because so so why this social network
kill blogging because social network
websites like Facebook and Twitter they
they use psychology and and any devious
means to get people hooked into and they
you know to get people to post an
including vast amount of useless you
know information which gave into quick
bait which eventually became quick baked
click bait and fake news
you know this the way that the things
they do is very powerful you know the
the way they they they shaped their
servers so it's so powerful it's more
powerful than good content you know
because when people see good content and
bad content in general everything being
equal people will love the good content
you know good content meaning you know
you spend time on it you know let's say
you spend three hours to write it
instead of one minute let's say you
researched you know you have you know
you spend one day to research something
or it's written by a professor who had
20 years of experience on the subject
you know that's what makes good content
bad content is just some anyone can
write any anything just you know
opinions typing anything so in general
people like good content and people will
thump up like you know spread the good
content now this is how good content you
know spread by word of mouth which is a
primitive way we humans you know support
bubble up the good things we want by
word of mouth but in a digital age the
social media and that or that they
started the whole thing
so today because Twitter because they
use psychology and you know cell phone
you know all kind of tactics so that
when so that today in general the bad
content thrive now not exactly bad
content
it's not like here's a good content
here's bad content and people love the
bad content it's not like a like that
but rather it's not exactly bad content
but rather content that's more dramatic
content that is you know anger emotional
that those stripes and you know dramatic
like you know you know accidents blood
crying girls pretty girls pretty girl
crying you know those kind of thing or
injustice someone died someone got
killed someone killed himself you know
things like that political like intrigue
some you know some people did so you
know big thing bad things those kind of
content thrive normally they thrive to
you know without technology normally
those content thrive too because because
often they invoke some sort of emergency
because no mori like every day if I
suddenly quiet very loud you know that
means something happened you know
something happened my neighbors or my
you know my roommate will come it what's
what's up are you okay you know that
that is a natural way you know it's like
a siren it's a natural siren so you
including emotion you know emotion like
if you hear some girl is crying on the
street you will go check it out you know
see hey you know what's up are you okay
or something yo or something you know
that's natural way for us to focus our
attention on you know certain things so
but now in digital age you know that
became because of the Facebook and
Twitter push for it so that becomes so
widespread and that basically wipe out
all the good contents
you know because today you if you write
something good the problem is it's not
you know people don't even see it
because you write something you spend
one day to you know write something
that's really quality content
any subject you know but when you post
that there are 1000s you know literally
tens of thousands posts all over that's
Brandis you know you know the people
just shout cry you know I owe this
something something something you know
your post gets buried plus this social
digit you know media Facebook Twitter
you know they have likes you know so
that people tends to like the most
stupid you know the common thing like
cat pictures memes that's why you have
means memes you know you have go viral
you know the phrase go very well
something go you know everyone is trying
to do something very well usually and
and our viral you know you might think
oh maybe because the viral content is
came from you know someone who spent ten
years studying something and finally
write wrote one essay that's that's how
good it is that's why I go viral know
the things that go viral if you look at
them they are basically orc you know cat
pictures you know the most van you know
in a sense value valueless to the
prosperity of humanity you know they are
the garbage so that you know those so
you have these things go viral means cat
pictures you know kind of filthy you
know quotes you know you know empty
empty things that's so that's a
situation of so that is why the social
media kind of took over blogs then
Google killed Brock you know Google
Reader that you know basically that's
the last nail in the coffin for blogs
and that so today where do you find good
information when you try to search you
know they then you know you see besides
the like and all the stuff then Google
Facebook and Twitter then they start to
use algorithms to control they actually
control information
so why they control it so that they
wanted to you know they want only to
show you information that you find
pleasing you know if you like something
they tend to show that to you not
anything you don't like or disagree
because so that way they get more
traffic they make more money more ad
money people you know then but yeah so
then then they start to control
algorithmic information then what you
get is the bubbles then there's a
political bubbles then you know and it
become so bad today you know then people
got angry you know politicians and you
know then then you start to have
censorship you know this is almost a
description of the past ten years old
you know 10 to 20 years of the history
of social media you know communication
on a weapon you know well I didn't you
know since you have blogs but there's
another period when you don't have
praxis and anyway that's a story so
that's it for today greetings yelling
Lyon studio yelling Lyon studio great
name so are you from so so you guys came
so late like I was so in the first 40
minutes I did live coding and tutorial
of Emacs Lisp you know I wrote this code
so that's the first 40 minutes then you
know I was about to oh this is I'm in
Northern California near San Francisco
greetings to Sydney
so the first first 40 minutes is about
Emacs with coding then I started to
ramble about RSS web feed technology and
atom technology
and in turn I mentioned their creators
and the history you know a bit of a
story of their create creators because
that's a interesting because you know
mark pilgrim and Aaron Schwartz who
killed himself and you know then we
started to talk about the history kind
of the history of the blogging how
Google Reader killed blogging well his
social media actually did in the in
Facebook then the like button how
information becomes hard to good
information becomes how to get then you
know today we have political chaos you
know online and censorship and all the
anger what language do I know okay so
you must be new so well I code a lot
languages so so I can you know so I have
I have a bunch of programming language
tutorials JavaScript colon Python Ruby
PHP Java enclosure and and you know so
actually I love languages you know I
have been coding for like twenty first
you know thirty years now
Matthew was Sosa is a textured eye
coding languages I think that's it for
today so oh you just you just found my
channel thank you yeah I yeah you know
YouTube is interesting I started to do
YouTube videos like every day for four
months now and I noticed like a lot
people new people you know start to you
know they finally via my YouTube videos
not via my website because I was
thinking you know because I'm an
old-timer you know because I've been
reading blogs
for like 20 years so and I have you know
Emacs people follow us so I tend to
think you know then they say you know my
Emacs people follow us they say oh you
are making starting to make videos then
they go to my video but it seems like
there are a lot of people who probably
buy on my videos only so that's very
interesting and and the thing
interesting is thing about that is like
you see that is the power that is the
power of YouTube I mean YouTube the
video format is really extremely
powerful I mean we mentioned this before
because the YouTube because talking and
seeing is the primary way humans
communicate writing comes later you know
and in writing also takes more takes
takes education you know to be able to
write and and to be able to read but
most people can go by you know visual
communication so so the video so that is
why I think you know YouTube became you
know it blew ups became so popular and
you know you can't like today you can
find every topic on YouTube it may be
programming math sciences you know a lot
of people do sciences why this happens
or why or space you know then you also
have you know gamers of course then you
have girls makeup then courses there
celebrity like almost everything I cause
you know cause everything you can find
on YouTube now on my discord if you want
to geek out a bit I have about 14 years
of experience oh okay so discord well
okay I am Master than if you I think
this code is connected to master than is
it
like I'm not on this code so you know
I'm a master then but but yeah so so
okay so so thank you guys for coming at
that's it for today yep bye guys