good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show today we are
going to do emac this let's get on get
on to it right away
so today's uh topic um
today you know we are going to code
emaclis so toggle
doc theme so let's make the browser
um
not dark theme so it's easier to see so
what we are going to do is we are going
to write a emac this command
that allows you to
swap
block of text for example i want this
block of text
to
to be swapped with this block of text
text so i can uh
so again
you know after i have this command i
just press a key and this block becomes
comes down here so you don't have to do
select the block
cut it
and
and paste it in front of the other one
so it just swaps okay so emax has a
bunch of search commands it's called
transpose i never used it okay so but
let's see
transpose okay so let's look at the emax
command so you have transpose characters
which swaps the current character with
the one
before it
um
[Music]
let's see transpose characters transpose
lines transpo post paragraph
okay transpose region oh there's already
transpose region okay that's great
transpose sex okay that's those are
great so let's copy that so let's put it
here so we can um
so we can see
uh
okay transpose commands these are built
in in emac list okay
so
let me let me make them
into one line and make a list out of it
okay so emacs already have these
transport transpose characters so
transpose characters
transpose lines that we're gonna use uh
transpose paragraph we are not going to
use uh because the e max paragraph emax
has a weird kind of sensor paragraph it
depends on the major mod and
uh usually it's unpredictable
so if you just have english writings for
example if you just have english
writings for example this paragraph and
another paragraph then you do transpose
paragraph that work in a plain
text fundamental mod or text mod but if
you have html or pro i mean called
python ruby or javascript whatever the
transpose paragraph
doesn't work because
the meaning of paragraph depends on
emacs concept of
chart table okay uh child class so
basically unpredictable so in a
programming language mod you cannot
predict what is a paragraph so it's kind
of weird so
so that's why so we are going to write
uh let me show you okay so hold on a
second so transpose sex is also good let
me make them colored so you can see
easier
so
transpose paragraph is essentially what
we are going to write today you know uh
where a paragraph is defined
precisely
as a text block separated by empty lines
okay so universal it doesn't matter in
what major modeling this code in python
code in
c programming language whatever
programming which is just transpose i
mean swap
block the current block uh to the
previous so okay so let's let's let's
begin to write it okay so uh e uh and oh
there's another one transpose words okay
uh make it color the wood and make it
that and back to browser
refresh okay transpose words okay and
transpose 6
s e x p
means a
symbolic expression that basically means
uh
let me show you okay so you go to some
emac list code
ah let's go let's go up okay so emac
this code if you
say transpose sex you know this so this
is one sex
symbolic expression basically means
means a
text
enclosed in a bracket okay so that's one
sixth
then if you call this command transpose
say sex it's gonna swap this one with
the previous one the previous one is
this one
you know so let's try it so
so i put the cursor here and let's call
transpose
okay six
do it
okay what it did let's see what it did
yeah it's not so good
okay so what happened is that it
transfers this parenthesis with this uh
this
um
text block yeah that's correct okay so
let's try again so if i put a cursor
here
okay let's do something simple okay make
a backup let's do something okay so
because this way we can see so this is
uh
magnify this is b this is a and now we
put a cursor in between them so now i
call transpose six
okay do it you see a and b and swapped
that's what transpose sex is
it's useful so
so now we're gonna write one single
command that depends on who's the
position you'll call any one of these
but first of all let's write transpose
block
you know
if you are already
if you know emac this already if you are
you know uh already code e magnus you
might you might think that
what i'm going to do is cd because
you know you might think oh you should
do it this way because
anyway uh i'm going to do this for from
uh ground up kind of for the
for those of you who are new to emac
beast
so
so don't worry about the you know not um
don't complain okay if you already know
this
i'm gonna do it my way so okay let's
begin write the code so
uh create this code okay so here is our
template uh i mean so
exactly smart cause i imagine smart i'm
using my own mod so d for different
expand to a function name
then let's call xr
transpose
block okay so that's our function name
the documentation is swap the current
text
block with the previous okay
and
version keeper today's date so let's
start to write it
so first of all transpose so first of
all you want to determine what's the
current uh
current
the beginning position and end position
of the block okay so a block
a block is defined by separation of
empty lines essentially let me show the
white space
okay so essentially you can see it's
separated by essentially two
end of line characters
so for example this this would be one
block and this would be one block right
now so if you remove that end of line
empty line then this is one block okay
so in soft light keys for example i can
press a key to select the block you know
number six to select the block i go here
press number six that's one block okay
so
this okay so first of all
get the beginning position of the block
and
end position because we need those
positions to tell e max
to swap this region okay so
so i i already have uh you know
i talked i wrote this
many times in my past videos so if you
watch my videos you probably have seen
it so today we are just going to call a
command we have already written
and the easiest way is just look my look
at my existing code okay
for example
press number six select the current
block so now let's call
the pink window you can see all my
command codes and keystrokes okay i'm
using soft light keys and voila keyboard
so for example i press six you can see
the command
select block you see that's one block
so now
i call describe
key
then i press the key 6
then you get the documentation for
select block okay
then you just jump to the code so here
is the source code for xr select block
you can see it defines the block here
okay but um
okay let's let's do it quickly so i
don't want to waste time
so let's just copy that then
uh select block um
you know so um
yeah so okay so
let's go to my emacs tutorial okay so
you search for emacs tutorial
then
practical emac list okay then you have a
section that tells you how to select
the beginning
position and end position of a block
okay so let's go here let's see get user
input
uh
thing endpoint get text block okay
so here is a code
for
getting the position of the block okay
so actually so let's copy that
copy it
close that
what are we doing select block i want i
want to do this quickly
yeah
so anyway so that's my tutorial okay you
like my stuff if you like my stuff buy
it okay so for now let's just copy this
thing close that okay paste it here
uh
remove the white space to do that this
is the part we want okay
paste it here this different we don't
need any more purify shrink
okay so if region is active okay so
forget about region active uh
well we'll do that later okay so
what if the region is active do we
okay let's push on uh let's worry about
things later so okay so here's a code
that you know you skip character
forward
to find
you know the new line and
and
and the tab in space so you want to move
the cursor to the
end of the
block okay then
you re you search backward this is
yeah so so what it it's doing is that
you search forward to the
end of the end of a sequence of empty
lines
then you have to move backward to there
because that's the end of the block you
don't want the position to be that there
so
so that's why you research
backward
okay
now this this code is not
yeah this is better okay so actually
it's a it's they are pretty much the
same but
let me just do it quickly
so
paste
so that
okay there
so let p1 and p2 are local variables
save excursion uh search backward search
backward by
two or more empty lines
and maybe a space or tab inside it
then
you go to the
end of the match and
set the p1 that's the beginning
position of the
block okay
okay yeah that's right
so
if the search is not successful you know
if you cannot find a you know so what
this code search backward you know like
search backward here
so you have empty lines there right if
you so this line will search backward up
and put the cursor there
then
then you move the character there
and set the end position of the match
so you
you know you search
oh god i'm getting i'm getting kind of
uh
confused
good morning guys
so
so you search
you search backward
by empty lines
two or more empty lines so that means
when you do that when you call this
command that will move your cursor there
then you want to
go to the character match end match n0
means the whole
matched
text and uh that's what z in match and
zero means the whole matched
the position the end position of the
whole match stream so
that means
it's gonna be here because we are
searching a bunch of empty
lines so
the match n0 is
over there okay or over here
then you you also move the cursor there
go to char then you set the position
point is the current cruiser position
okay it's a number
so
that's how you set the beginning
position of the block okay
but however if you
if you search backward is failed you
know
this commands research backward it will
return true if it found if it's found if
otherwise it returns near so if it
failed then you simply set the position
one beginning of the block to be the
current cursor position
so when does when would this happen this
would happen if you your current block
at is the beginning of a buffer because
you don't have empty lines above it so
when you don't have empty lines above it
you just um
you know search backward will move the
cursor to
to the maximal previous position that it
cannot search anymore and
it still returns zero because no empty
line is found
okay so i'm getting it is you know this
is getting um
take too too much time to expand this so
anyway so once you found the beginning
position of the block then you do it
again you search the end you know you
search forward to search the end
position of the block okay so
so that's how we set p1 and p2 okay so
so then the message is we don't care a
vector we don't care okay
i i talked about this
uh in my previous videos many times
okay so now we got a beginning position
and end position what's the next thing
to do
the next thing to do
is that we need to find the beginning
position and end position of the
previous block okay
yeah we took a lot of time to explain
this one um
then we gonna do it again so
let me write it quickly so go to char
go to char p1
okay
so we gonna declare more variables p1 p2
p3
p4 p3 and p4 will be the beginning and
end position of the previous
block okay
so go to chart p1 then then do the whole
thing again
now we are doing inefficient code but
this is
because i'm doing a video i need to get
moving moving on
non-stop some action so you know i need
to show some action
so we go to the beginning of the
beginning position of the current block
then we do the whole thing again we you
know just like before we do the whole
thing again
that's right then then then you
set
this is gonna be p3
p3
and p4
p4 okay
okay let's just do it quickly then we
gonna call this command
trans
uh we're gonna call command
so there is a building there it is
transpose regions okay
so we're gonna call this command
now let's
describe function to see what that
command does okay the documentation for
this command
okay so here is the syntax transpose
regions
start position okay so
we are almost done so start position is
gonna be p1
n position is gonna be p2
and p2 okay p1 p2 p3 p4 that's
so we swap
p1p2 region 2 p3 and p4
and the
optional leave markers no okay
okay that's i think that's it for our
command it should work
transpose block yep
okay so now
evaluate the buffer okay you can see the
the command i call there
so now let's just try it okay so
okay so let's copy
this and create a new buffer paste it
there magnify so you can see
we have
something
here
and some else okay so each one of these
is a paragraph i mean it's a block okay
so first of all let's put so we're gonna
call the command it should swap these
two okay
so
transpose block
please
what
did it work this function
okay this function
then normally okay so it did not work
let's do it again exact transpose block
do it
symbols values variable is void p1 okay
we gotta we got error so you can see
that's the errors in messages buffers
symbols value as variable is void okay
let's fix it
oh yeah so you need to put the transpose
code inside the let that's why
there it is okay
comment it out so
okay so
evolve the buffer again back to the test
code
now call our command transpose block
do it
yeah
okay it says transpose regions overlap
so that means
we didn't get our position correctly
because
the region overlapped okay so
so let's go back here to fix our code
so first of all
don't save excursion okay so you you see
that saves excursion that means
whenever you move cruiser in when you
code emac this when you are moving
closer such as we are doing you know go
to chat and so on usually usually when
your command finishes you want the
cursor to be
at wherever you know before the command
begin
so that user don't confuse you know user
calls your command then
the cursor goes to somewhere else you
know so
in that situation you want to call save
excursion
what it what you'll do is that
you can look at the documentation save
excursion what you'll do is that you'll
run
whatever the code and when it's done
you'll return the cursor to the
original position
so in here in our case we don't need it
okay so
so let's just replace it by program n
that's just a
group okay
okay so what is what is going on so so
we are doing so
go to char okay then go to chart p1
go to chart p1
okay so we don't want to go to chart p1
we want to
so p1 is the beginning of the block okay
so
p1 is the beginning position of the
current block
so we got p1 and p2 is the beginning and
end position of the current block
now you want
to okay the easiest way is just um
okay once you do once you've done that
then you go to
p1 then you search backward again to
to the
to this is essentially the end of
previous block okay so set
p4 okay
point okay so actually we don't need
this
then you do it again search backward
actually uh
you know
yeah this should work okay so but the
problem is
okay so this should work okay
you know you go to the p1 is the
beginning position of the current block
then you search backward for empty lines
that will move the cursor to there then
you said p2 so this is this is
i mean you said p4 so p4 is
means the end position of the previous
block okay then you do backward search
again
for the
empty lines
then you want to set um
then you want to set match end okay so
actually i'm not i don't think i'm not
sure i'm doing a good explanation
said p3 to match n yeah so this code
will work but
it's not robust let me explain why okay
because this code will not work when you
have
a situation like this when you have a
block that doesn't have empty lines
above it
uh for example when your text is
at the beginning of buffer or when your
text is at the end of buffer where
there's no empty lines below it or above
it
so this code we need to fix
okay so go back here let's try it okay
first of all evaluate it go here now we
call the command now it should work
do it yeah it worked okay now undo
but you see if i remove if i remove the
empty lines at the beginning you know so
there's no empty lines before this block
then it will not work for example let's
try it do it
transpose block yeah it worked but you
see it got screwed up it you know the
two
paragraphs become merged
so
so let's
go back and fix this command okay
actually in order to do this we have to
think you know we cannot just like push
on and code you know give you guys
activity all the time we need to think
about it
so
uh two people watching okay so let's fix
this
transpose so let's fix this we need to
think about this okay p1 and p2
and p3 and p4 okay uh
so let's name them
instead of p1 and p2 let's then name
them name them something to be
more intuitive
current block end okay
p uh
current block p2
let's just say begin
end okay
then
previous block begin previous block end
okay that's much more readable
now
now we want to find
let's
let's remove the redundant
okay remove that okay
so current block begin current blocking
so first of all search backward search
backwards search empty lines
okay
so we have the
so then
so if it's found then
match beginning
is
set
previous block end
previous block end let's match beginning
zero yes
then
set
current block begin
that's match end
zero that's right
so that is if it's found okay so then
let's remove that
remove set point okay
so
if you found
the empty lines before the cursor
then
the beginning of empty lines
is the previous block end
the end of empty lines is current block
begin that's right
but
if
there is no empty lines above the
cruiser then
and then basically you just error out
because you you don't have the previous
block to swap too okay
so
you're gonna say
hero
no no previous block
okay
so that
is that is that okay
now
now you go to char move the cursor to
now you
you move the cursor to
current block begin
okay
then
then you search forward okay
then you
not search backwards search forward okay
then you search forward for empty lines
okay
so you move the cursor to the current
block begin then you search forward for
empty lines
okay let's add a
conclusive position okay
okay
so current
you go to
conclusive position
then you search forward
you want to find the current the the
position
the end position of the current block so
you do that by search empty lines
now if you found it
okay now if you found it then
then that's the current block end
position okay so you want to say region
match begin
zero okay
so that is the current
block end
now if you did not find it
then it's just the max position okay if
you did not find it then
point okay
so let's let's clean out the code so
let's um yeah let's let's remove this
uh clean out the code here
okay so
so we got now current block end and
yeah we set the current block in okay so
now we got
block begin we got current block end and
now we also have previous blocking now
so now we just go to
previous block end
then
we search backward
so copy
basically copy this
okay so we
now we move the cursor to the previous
block end
okay
then we search backward for empty lines
okay we search backward backward for
empty lines
now if you found empty lines
that's great then you set
previous block begin
to match end
zero
that's right
okay then you don't need this okay so if
you found empty lines
in the previous block
then
the end position of the match of is the
previous block begin that's right
however if you did not find it
then
then you just set the previous block
begin to be
current point position conclusive
position okay
that's it that's uh that's that's it for
the code eva eval buffer
so now we evaluate the buffer so that
should work okay
okay
let's go back to the test okay
so now
if there is a let's remove the empties
so let's call the command
transpose vlog
do it
symbols value is
void p1 okay yeah
where is p1 oh yeah
p1 p2 we need to change that
okay let's rename the let's rename
let's rename this
okay current block begin let's rename it
to bp1 okay so because it's shorter
okay
current block end let's let's name it
so p1
is
okay
current block n will be named rename p2
and previous block begin
is p3 okay
okay
and previous block end is p4
predefine the code
okay
that's good
evaluate it
back to the test
page
move the cursor here
call it transpose block
do it
fantastic it works
undo
now let's remove the empty lines
now let's do it again call it
transpose block
it worked
it worked except that it
kind of moved the buffer i mean let's
try it again
you know actually let's just say a and
bbb okay so now it's
simpler okay
call it
do it
okay it move the cruiser you see it
let's put something
do it go ahead do it it worked
move the cursor here call it
it works
but when you don't have empty lines
above it
call it
do it
it
it worked but however it moved the
cruiser i mean it moved the
it moved the
[Music]
let's see what's going on so
let's
call it
do it
it worked
but it puts the
it scrolls the buffer so that your
cruiser position is at the top we
uh
i don't know what's going on right well
i mean
let's do it over here okay
do it
yeah you see
okay that's kind of worked so now let's
go back okay so let's
let's
do it
okay so after it transpose
it moves the cursor
it's
let's try this okay so this way
so we call it
what
we call it
it moves the cruiser all the way to the
top now why is that
okay so yeah so we need to save
excursion to save to save cursor so save
excursion okay
not
start moving cursor okay
you are region
back here
let's call it again do it
fantastic
do it
fantastic now do it again
you should swap with that
do it again
fantastic now it's now it's fantastic
it's complete our
code is working correctly and good great
let's try it over here
without empty lines
below okay
it should you know swap with that okay
do it
uh i failed
what
now if there's empty lines to it
it okay so
it failed because
okay so here's what happens it will fail
when
when there's more than two empty lines
okay let's see
call it
do it yeah it fails when there's more
more than two empty lines to it
yeah so now let's go back to the code
and fix
it failed it fails when there's more
than two empty lines
oh yeah so you need to yes that's right
uh
empty line empty line slap backslash n
you need to put a plus uh wait
yeah you need to put a z zero or more
that's right
zero or more which is uh asterisk sign
to make it zero or more
that's right
okay and over here it's the same
evaluate the code back to our test test
page
put more empty lines there
move the cursor here
try it
what
no it didn't work uh
so any questions
caught you live for the first time or
flamie or hey
why do you not use emacs as the front
and two of them language when you use it
for every other language i do
i do i i do often
except that when you um
when you want to plot something graphics
yeah let me let me digress for a minute
okay so
plus 3d
uh
plus 3d psi x y x
0 to 6
y from 0 to 6
you see you are plotting a you know
graphics
but
you don't have that feature when you use
emacs as front end you know because it
cannot display graphics that's why
you know when you do if you are using
woofing language for solving equations
that's fine i use the you know e max
from then
language mod okay but if you are
plotting something uh i go to the
wolfram language
notebook phone name okay that's that
answers that i think
what's the second best language to use
for cellular automata
that depends okay if you want to do um
okay i'm i'm about to digress you know
yeah okay let's talk uh let's talk about
that a little bit serious automata
so you go to my website okay so
sorry info let me show you okay so you
go to my website
you go down you go down
you go down uh you know there is
programming language tutorials
hacker code about programming languages
and stuff
then you there's a math section
then you go to
exci math
okay then you see
all things related to math
then you go down
and there's my notes about a cellular
automata
my notes on reading this book
this heavy book
then
so that's all about cellular automata so
that your question is
what's the best language to do cellular
automata besides language
uh let me put a plug for wufang language
okay because they are donna they donate
to me okay so
i would you know
my honest opinion just useful foreign
language you know
it's free you know that you know just
search focus on wufab i talked about
this all the time in my video just
search for wolfram engine you can
download it for free and follow my many
of my tutorials let's go to it
so let me show you okay so some math
so you go actually you go to my website
xrd.info
then you show javascript
then you go to there it is wufang
language
so here i did several videos of it you
know tutorials on wufang language and uh
from language tutorial you can download
it i mean the wolfram language is free
now since two years ago
and this page explains the differences
of wolfen language
versus mathematica what's the difference
from engine or from script
and so on and then you have the wolfram
language complete tutorial for beginners
okay
uh
you know i
i recommend you know of course i
recommend that i've been coding wolfen
language since 1990s okay
so wolfen you know so you can just use
fulfillment language
probably the best okay but now
it depends on okay it depends now
now if you are going to code cellular
you know there's thousands
varieties you know you have 3d cellular
tomtom you have one dimensional cellular
tamdah you have two dimensional cellular
automata you have all sorts you have and
scrolling you have all sorts of graphics
you know this is infinite
in
essentially infinite types even of
cellular automata
for example game of life very popular
you know that's also cellular automata
so
cellular automata is about pure
computation so you you just even you
have super computers you know
you cannot finish it you know this is
infinite so
so if you want to study so
so to answer that question you know what
what other language to use for celu
automata depends on your goal
now if your goal is to look at you know
some of you know to study cellular tanda
you know just
yeah
to study cellular automata is also the
manners you know then wolfen language is
the easiest it's the best okay but if
you
here's a particular
if your goal is to study a specific like
you are a researcher you know you
already know about cellular automata but
you are studying a specific type of
cellular template such as scheme of life
you know each one of them there's
infinite almost infinite like
infinite exploration so you can spend
your even if you have a super computer
it's endless okay but if you are
studying a specific type of cellular
automata you want to find a particular
pattern meaning that you need the most
efficient
way to compute you know the mediant the
billionth generation possible
that's when that's when
i would say
you might want to use other languages
like c or
usually c go land c plus first you know
this or or maybe even fortran fortran is
actually faster in number crunching than
c
so that's when
you want to use some other language and
and and i would just recommend go let
okay
so that that answers your question
so let's go back to my boring emac list
so um
[Music]
so right now we have a bug
and the bug is
uh yeah the bug is it's not
let's say evaluated evaluate the region
call the command
do it it doesn't trans it doesn't swap
when there is more than one
empty lines in between the blocks okay
so
why is that
so we have to go back to our code and
look at them in detail
so
we search backward
and
actually we should search forward
okay then and let's just stick with this
search backward
we've we tried to find
two or more empty lines
right
two or more empty lines if we found it
then
[Music]
if we found it then
block end
and
current block beginning okay
if we did not find it then we do that
then we go to
closer position
then we search for what you know the
order is not optimal you know so i need
to rewrite this
and the order is not optimal anyway so
we go to the current cursor position
then we search
forward
for one or more empty lines if we found
it
we set to
p1 to be that
otherwise p
is the maximum okay
then we go to
[Music]
p1 then we go to the previous now
so i don't understand why is it
not working
okay so
so what is your interest so are you
studying cellular automata
oh so you already have wolverine engine
you know
so cellular automatic
yeah let me digress i'm stuck with this
for a while so say to automata you know
[Music]
you cannot do everything in wufang
language well i mean you can but i mean
ufam language has built in cellular
automata so it's
but because cellular automata there's so
many you know there's thousands of types
so you cannot really
so it's not just a function
i mean okay so so let me try to rephrase
wolfram language has built in cellular
automata okay so let's try
so cellular automation so you can see a
list of functions about cellular
automation
okay
generates a list of representing the
evolution of the cellular automation
with the specified rule from initial
condition okay so
now
my question is
is this general or not
for example can we use the building
function cellular automation to run game
of life
okay no
so you see
wufang language provides this building
function that does cellular automation
of
one very specific type
that is this
this type this one-dimensional cellular
automation
so if you're gonna so if you are
studying this type of cellular automata
ufam language is obviously the most
easy and useful you know
but however if you are doing game of
life which is two-dimensional or if you
want to do three-dimensional or you want
to do some something else then
then
you don't have the convenience of a
building function so that means you have
to write the code okay you have to code
wufang language
so at this point you can either code it
in language or code it in other language
now of course
so now this becomes a general generic
programming problem which language
should you use
and the wolfram language is of course
much more high level one line of wolfram
language equals to you know hundred or
thousand golden or c or whatever
so
but it's slower you know that's the
thing that's the thing
it's slower so it allows you to in you
know in one hour you can create your 2d
cellular automata you know
but it's slow
you know maybe 100 generations per
second or something
but if you so but you can do it in one
hour and you can see all the graphics
you can see you know you can you can
easily see you know you can do it in a
day you can see your cellular automata
of specific specific type
but if you do it in another language
it's gonna take you days it's gonna take
you yeah
weeks or days just to
to to to make it work then you don't
have graphics you know then you need the
library for graphics that you know
easily takes you a month
but
if you are a professional programmer you
know what you are doing
then after a month your program is very
fast it's usually 10 times 10 times
10 times or even 100 times faster than
your one day prototyping movement
language so that is the
full answer that's a full
detail
so yeah you want to do computer
experiments outside of academy okay
yeah okay that's about that
uh
okay let's back to emacs so
but we are stuck why is this
not working we already talked for one
hour already
okay so
we have a bug
that
you know i'm inclined just to rewrite
this
let's say current block
c1 c2
p1
p2 okay
that one that way is more intuitive
so yeah i'm gonna rewrite this okay so
yeah
can block begin current block in
previous vlog begin previous block end
okay
so
composition
so you start by search forward okay so
so i'm gonna i'm just going to rewrite
this
search forward
search for what that
if it's found then
c2
current block end
okay
otherwise
okay otherwise the maximum
so that's the
current block end so we start at the end
so then
then you go to
closer position
then
you search backward
for that okay
if it's found
then
and c1 is match and
current because the beginning and
set
p2
match beginning okay
that's right
if it's found if it's not found
then that
okay
so we got
c2
then
we work from
below to upwards
this order is more efficient so c2
c1
p2
then we go to
go to
p2 okay then we go to p2
then
then we search backward
if it's found
then p1 will be
match end that's right
then but if it's not found
if it's not found
then it's just a maximum point
okay
evolve the buffer
do it
symbols value is void p3 oh yeah okay
so p1p2
okay
give out the buffer
go back here
call the command
do it
same problem same problem
and it's even worse than before because
now
search forward
oh
oh i know yeah instead of the asterisk
we need plus one or more not zero or
more
idiotic error
so asterisk we need a plus
there
there yeah
evaluate the region okay back here
call it
what evaluate region
plus right m plus evaluate the region
evaluate
buffer
oh god i think i thought
this is much easier
tastes right it was a stage to render
okay so
do it
it worked okay
do it it didn't work
do it so you have when you have multiple
empty lines it does not work
and straight
when you have multiple empty lines it
did not work
and
do it
you it any error
now
stuck
i'm going to
you know i think i'm going to delete
this
ddd stream because
it's
it's going nowhere
where i'm done
uh so
because i've done much better emac these
tutorials before you know you can watch
my previous video
what do you use to mine the web right
now i don't mind the web
putting a group maybe
what group
so double check
double check
it
should be right
so i have to think about this the coding
the coding is like that it's like that
so search forward search for word for
for at least two empty lines
okay
and uh
and this neo means
this new means not bound okay
and this move
means if it's not found move the cursor
to the maximum position okay
so you search forward to the end
search forward for empty two or more
empty lines
that's correct
then if it's found
then
[Music]
when if it's found you say
the match beginning okay the beginning
position
of the
match text
okay
and you set it to
[Music]
c2 that's right the end of current block
because we are searching forward okay so
if you found these empty lines
below cursor
you set the beginning match position to
be the
to be the position of the current block
the you know the end
of the current block
okay i'm just gonna
put a parenthesis around things that you
want to find then oh
oh you mean regular expression group
no you don't you shouldn't need it
because we
yeah you can do that but you shouldn't
you know you shouldn't need it
i'm pretty sure so
rejects rejects group right
okay so
[Music]
we can try but
right so
so okay let's look into the regular
expression so we have an empty line then
we have either space or tab
zero or more zero or more space tab okay
then another empty line at least one of
it so that means empty line
oh you know what
i know what's the problem yeah i know
what's the problem the problem is with
the problem is the emacs technical
details emac these technical details
because
i've been into that before
you see when you search backward
yeah i think i know what's the problem
instead of using search bar code you
want to use skip chart
yeah that's right
yeah that's that's pretty
you know the problem is when you search
backward you know like here when you are
searching backward you know we are
searching an empty line
then spacer tabs zero or more then
another empty line at least one of it
so when you search backward when you
search backward with this regular
expression
it does not
it does not work exactly like when you
search forward even though the regular
expression are exactly the same
so
you know this is hard to explain i mean
it
emax does not move the cursor all the
way basically
you know i you know so
we can fix this by
okay
saying make a backup and we can fix this
by
okay so yeah let's fix this spine
so now go to char
go subscription
then skip chart
so search backward
yeah this i think this is pretty much
the problem
yeah that is why so i think okay
i'm pretty sure so um
but what are we going to do now
so
[Music]
search char backwards
so the problem is it doesn't move the
cursor or the way of the matched
expression
so that means
so that means this part the p1 the
previous
block
end is going to be wrong
yeah so
so what we can do to fix that is comment
this out
then we say
skip char
skip
chart backward okay
we want to skip any of
empty space or t
tab okay empty line
or space or tab
and no limit okay
so
so you skip chart then
you set point
p2
okay so instead of that line we replace
it with these two
like we force we kind of force e max to
move the cursor
backward and skipping skipping those
empty
white spaces
i think that that's it
and
probably similar things happen here
no this this is fine i mean the problem
only happens when you want to
you see when you search backward with a
regular expression and if the regular
expression involves some kind of
white space you know continuation it
doesn't emax does not move it all the
way
this is a bit tricky and
complex you know i
i cannot give you an example right now
uh actually we can we can actually so
for example
let's run this code okay
run it you see
you see that's a problem you see
our cursor is here
you know you look at you know this is
our cursor so we're gonna call the
command
uh
eval s6
so we're gonna run this line of emac
this right now if we run it
this says you know research backward
empty line
followed by spatial tab
zero more
followed by
one or more empty lines so intuitively
you might think you know
let's show white space you know we're
gonna skip those those so the cruiser
should be here
so if we evaluate this line
when the cursor is at the end
the result is it should move the cursor
there but it doesn't you see let's try
it okay run the code you see
that is the problem
that so you see
there is a asymmetry between the search
for word and search backward
you know even though your regular
expression is exactly the same you know
if your cruiser is here
then you do the
the same code you know but you search
forward
it will move your cruiser to
here
okay
but if your cursor is here you do the
same code it doesn't doesn't move all
the way back there it stops there
so this problem
i haven't looked into detail why
why does that occur uh but i mean that's
that's that's the behavior of emac lisp
and the documentation doesn't really say
you know the documentation doesn't
really
you see there it is okay search backward
from point
for regular expression
okay it's search backward okay this
function is almost identical to research
forward except that by default it
searches backward instead of forward
and the sign of count also indicates
exactly the opposite search and
direction
you see there there okay there it is
note you see this is a
very tricky technical detail
note
note that searching backward may give a
shorter match
than expected
because regular expression is still
match in the forward direction
yeah you know it's it's a bit um
oh now now they have a reference they
have a link
now they have a link to the emac list
manual let's see
god this is this is one of my bug report
10 years ago 15 years ago nowadays
now they actually did it
you see now they have a link
to the
documentation for this function at the
emacs this manual you know i suggested
that 15 some some like 11 years ago and
finally
you know i it's funny okay they talk
random you know it's funny that
let's go to e my emacs blog you know
the gnu bug report you know i reported
some bug
in
2008 and after 10 years
you know they say not email oh this one
is gonna we're not gonna we are not
going to fix it or it's fixed you know
in 10 years
fixed after 13 years that's that's one
example but
but right now this is another example
you know i can search for the bug report
to find my original report i have i
probably have it
on my blog somewhere but anyway
so
this emacs manual talks about regular
expressions okay so anyway so that's
that's a problem okay so
so we now know the problem
so what is the most efficient way to
solve this you know we already have a
solution you know let's evaluate let's
try it i think it will work
you see it worked
you know
it worked
now let's say if there's no
no empty lines there do it
it worked
do it okay now let's say there's no
empty lines at the bottom
do it
it works okay
fantastic now our code works
now
remove this okay now
we want to add a key to repeat it
because
for example
d is it okay so
you see once you
call the command
usually you want put the cursor at
at the
position yeah you want to cr
there okay so let's let's
let's try to move this inside
oops
let's put it inside save excursion okay
this transpose okay eval the region
evolve the buffer back here
do it
yeah so you want the cruiser to stick
with the paragraph
you are on so that you can call it again
and you'll move that block up you see
this is very convenient way to move a
block you know like up
do it do it do it okay now we are going
to add a key
to this okay
so let's say
f11 what is eleven
yeah okay let's say f11 okay
global set key
and let's see what is ctrl t
ctrl t
hit expand okay
control n yeah
control m
control w
control
d okay let's see
d
okay let's give it a key
transpose block okay evaluate it
ctrl d do it do it do it fantastic do it
do it
oh okay
so when let's see do it
do it
do it do it okay so there's another
problem
when
when the current block does not have
ending
uh
empty lines
then when you call the command
it does not move your cursor up
okay i think that's it for today
storm story
this episode is worth keeping oh okay
it's nice to know that people are
listening what
i think that's it for today thank you
guys for coming
evil mod for keystrokes okay even much
evil much sure well wait hold on a
second you know you
you're gonna mention evil mod
in in front of some fly keys i challenge
you
you so you say four key strokes right no
ink some fly keys it's the same okay
watch okay so first of all let's let's
make them in the right order okay so
abcd right so i want to move this block
up okay
watch my key count okay without without
using the command we just wrote today
okay
one key stroke
another keystroke one two three four
five six okay
six okay let's try it again okay let's
okay
do it
one two
three
four five
okay
five and you you got um
let's do it like okay let's start let's
not start from this okay
one
two three four four key strokes okay
let's see let's let's swap the first two
okay
one
two three four
okay that's stuff like keys and you are
you what you are saying
evil mod
except like he's is more efficient than
evil mod even without this command but
today
after this talk show i'm going to add
this to sapphire keys so it's even more
efficient than than evo model v
okay so
um
yeah so i've been talking for one and a
half hours okay that's it bye guys bye
my emacs tutorial okay
bye my emacs tutorial and emac this
tutorial
bye
hey diocado
okay we shut down in one minute so you
know
so fantastic
actually should we just go on you know
dragon why not you know live
live stream coding
so i'm going to so this actually a lot
to do so you know we kind of stuck today
and spend 90 minutes on this
so once you have transpose block
you know there's a lot to do let me tell
you okay so now we have the command
right we can just like transpose easily
you know except we need to fix the
problem when
when
when you are at the end
when your current block is here at the
end of a buffer when there is no empty
lines below it
then when you do the transpose block
it does not move your cruiser it works
but it does not you move cursor to
to with the block
how do you fix that so that's one thing
we need to fix
um
why is that
know basically save excursion got
confused save excursion got confused
yeah
save excursion got confused
so the end of block can block in c2 so
something about c2 there
c2 so where is c2 c2 is here
so
you search forward
and if you found it
then c2 is good otherwise
otherwise you set c2 to
the point
but but why would that not work i don't
understand so anyway
so once you have the transpose block
written right
you what you want to do is that
you know sometimes we don't want
transpose block you know sometimes we
want to actually
transpose lines
so
so the design is that if your cursor is
at the beginning of a line
then it will transpose lines so you can
call for example transpose line okay
you see if your cursor is at beginning
of the line then you want to call
transpose lines but if your cursor is at
end of line you want to
call transpose block you know like
like that
yeah okay so this still
why is it not
ah god
okay so there is an issue when basically
the issue is that when there is no empty
lines
it
it's not satisfactory because when you
transpose
then emax scrolls the buffer yeah
you don't want emacs to scroll the
buffer because it's confusing because
where did my other line go well it's
above the you know it's you know it um
wait no no it does now it works
right
so why is that sometimes it doesn't
i don't know when is the condition it
does is it scrolls above over there okay
so when your cursor is here then you
call the command oh okay so maybe when
when there is more than one
empty lines between
then you call the command
okay that works
that works
there
that doesn't work okay so
you see if your cursor is at the end
of the current block then you call the
command
it works but however it
it's scrolled up
or scroll down your cruise your your
your buffer okay do it you see scroll up
do it scroll up
do it scroll up yeah
so when your cruiser is in in a block
anyway
i need to fix this so this is a tdm of
real-life coding you know like in theory
we solved it but this is just like a
bunch of minor you know issues edge
cases edge cases
uh
so you have to figure out you know
before we had that little problem
then now but now we have to figure out
why is this doing this so anyway
when this is fixed what i want is that
depending on your cruiser location
it may swap the current line or it may
swap
current block
and if your cruiser position is on a
bracket for example
like right here
then it should swap the six you know
swap like
like that
you know so
you will have just one single command
depends on where your cursor position is
then saves you a lot
uh tdm when you do editing okay that's
it for today
so
put this back here
color it show showing browser
so that's today's talk show and that's
today's code kind of
bye
uh