good morning everyone fantastic this is
Sarah talk show
uh ends episode I've been doing this for
three years and today we are going to
talk about some emacs 29 features
uh you guys we love that some of the
emacs 29 features fantastic okay let me
show my screen and first of all let me
introduce my keyboard This is glove 80
keyboard it's I search for Sally glove
80 review you don't need this this is uh
charging this is a wireless okay so
glove 80 keyboard fantastic it's got
colors and over here is Ultimate hacking
keyboard too I also have a video review
okay let me show you my screen and this
is a mouse with fantastic spin wheel it
spins for 30 seconds uh great for uh
scrolling so I also have a review on my
website now let me show my screen
okay so Emax 29 is today's main topic
okay say hi guys hello
hello hello guys immortality and uh
Huang and track the guitar
okay emacs 29 is today's main thing so
let me start uh yeah so excited search
just go to kasari.info
keyboard so you can start to go to my
keyboard website okay not this one
best keyboard for emacs keyboard
keyboard keyboard let's just say search
for glove 80.
okay there are so many pages on glove 80
keyboard create a custom layout yeah so
let me go to
why why is this page found Okay so
so anyway so this is my sorry keyboard
review website go to my blog so you can
see Club 80 they came out with a new
case you can buy so this is glove 80 I'm
using check video check audio good okay
yeah good okay so this is glove 80 and
you go to the ergonomic keyboard and you
can see my review for the ultimate
hacking keyboard okay it's another
fantastic keyboard I have a video review
okay check it out and buy them I support
them
okay so that's two of my best keyboards
I can see the best keyboard the other
one is
exposed night okay I also highly
recommend this one this three of the top
keyboard and also Kinesis advantage
I haven't done review for the 360 yet
you know because delays okay so that's
about keyboard now let's talk about uh
emacs then
okay so show keyboard talk about my
podcast okay so you just go to XA talk
show on saudi.info and recently I did
some podcast mini podcast each one is
about seven minutes they begin
they stir from
chat you know someone posted my opinion
about artificial intelligence about how
useful or how bad how brand Rod it is
Twitter then I started to rent you know
and I discovered podcast so I record you
know because typing is too slow being a
podcast I can talk a lot so
so you just go you can find it search
study search you'll find it podcast mini
podcast so there's a series of
artificial intelligence
AI alignment Ai and morality and
sentient Ai and chat gbt and AGI or
sentence sentient AI or strong AI you
know I have opinions on it strong
opinions
evolution of Internet uh how to use
Twitter and where the Twitter is brain
rot or it is not okay so I have my
opinion so several
and something about Elon Musk you know
that's a big popular topic everyone
loves to love LMS or hate Elon Musk
uh and uh
okay so so that's about my podcast so
you can
search it find it and listen okay now
let's talk about emacs
and emacs 29 and after that if we have
time within one hour we're gonna do some
coding of emac beasts I'm gonna write
some of these commands Okay
so if you have questions post it okay
do you like Club more than expose uh
kind of yes yes certainly because Club
80 you have uh you have tainting you
know by default you have tinting and you
can raise it but expose does not but
Expo is fantastic you know it's good for
the go it's one piece solid you can you
know
um
yeah you know different you know
depending on your purpose your goal do
you uh you know lots of things do you
already have RSI and things like that
okay let's talk about emacs 29 features
so let's go over so okay one more thing
uh on my emacs blog so you can just say
search for Sally emacs okay so you can
find my emacs blog okay this is old
website so go to sally.info is my new
website I have a new index page
you can just search for
controversy okay
so
oh I forgot to update the index so I
need to run that actually I can run that
right now so you see I did the live
stream about how to create a search
engine
about a few months ago so that one is a
good one so it teaches you about
JavaScript and about I think we used
Golan or python I forgot which but
JavaScript is the front end so you
create the index space so you can search
my website thousands of pages so that
that one for you programmers go watch
that one okay so right now I need to
index uh for example let me show you
uh Emax block there's a lot to cover
about emacs 29 fantastic
emacs in the past
four years or five I would say has
the emacs new Emax development has
increased so they have improved a lot
improvements on the core features on
emacs lisp so that's very powerful you
know it's kind of surprising you know I
was surprised you know glue emacs is
like going nowhere anytime you know 14
years 10 years but in the past five
years there is huge amount of
improvements the way I like you know the
the core features so emacs 29 in
particular and 28 also fantastic I'm
gonna cover them okay in a bit
um so right now I want to talk about uh
create updating my index page for my
study search but let's forget about that
because we have a lot of other things to
talk about
okay keep your comments coming okay pay
me okay you guys watch me the most
important thing is not thank you for
your work okay for its money you know
for the past 10 years I don't get money
dying of hunger so if you guys like my
work go to PayPal you know I have lots
of links you can find on my website
you'll find a link
for example or you can buy my emacs
tutorial patreon me Amazon gift card
PayPal or you can buy my emacs tutorial
and JavaScript in depth okay
let's go to let me show you uh uh um
controversy page okay
emacs controversy so I created a new
index so this page is about all the
controversies surrounding emacs in the
past about 15 years so a lot about
Richard Stoneman uh you know Richard
Stoneman did this or that
2009 2018
2017 2014 many of these not just
spectacular you know it's incredible he
is doing these things uh you know and
other controversies in emacs so this
part is technical controversies like
some features some people like you know
one group of emacs phonetics love them
one other group of Fanatics hate them
you know a big uh
big fight big flame War you know so
these are emacs controversy of course if
you talk about controversy I am included
you know lots of people don't like me
because I talk about you know I talk
negatively criticism about Richard
strowman and lots of emacs community and
stuff okay so this page I just want to
show you so you can read it so new index
page
okay so let's see next topic uh so close
emacs blog go back to talk show uh
controversy so talk about Adam McKenzie
guy this this idiot okay
okay I'm starting to Flame let's start
so this is part
um let's talk let's talk about this
issue this item
so in
okay so let's
um
so in order to talk about that let me
show you uh this first okay so
hold on a second so emacs version and
emacs 29 features so we're gonna talk
about that then we're gonna talk about
Adam McKenzie guy who uh he's an emacs
developer and he introduced one of the
biggest up in emacs and that showed
up in Emax 29 very bad extremely bad for
the next who knows 10 years it's gonna
be it's part of emacs this idiot
so anyway so I want to show you you can
just go to my emacs website and you'll
find this page XA emacs version so let
me show you okay so
so you type version so you can see uh
emacs Version Control emacs version
history so you go to that page this is
uh uh this page tells you when is what
which emacs version is released released
when so today we have end summary of
features so today we have emacs 29 emac
28 here and emacs 27 so you go to emacs
so I want to show you this page okay so
you can check out emacs past versions
you know like often when you install you
want to know oh this feature is emacs 28
yeah but when is it released you know
maybe 10 years ago or five years ago so
this page is helpful and you go to so
this page I want to show you and and
then another thing is that you click on
any one of them
so today we have emacs 29 released last
month okay so you click on this link
each version has this emacs news file
so in emacs you type Ctrl H and uh hold
on say you type Ctrl H and N
okay so you can you can see this is the
Emax news file and it's just endless you
know like how many how many lines uh
four thousand lines emacs 29 features
four thousand nice four thousand lines
of description so it's huge I haven't
gone completely over yet but almost so
as I go over I'm updating my website
emacs tutorial and taking notes and you
know tell you what's new on this page so
emacs29 so you have each emacs version
you so so here's what I want to say each
emacs version has a emacs news feature
so let me show you so you control h n so
you can see this is for emacs 29
and you see uh here emacs 29 and then
you you call tired jump
to go to the directory so let me show
you so you can see you go to the
directory so that command is Tire jump
now this pink window shows all my
command cores and the keystrokes so you
can see
you know as I type it shows the
keystrokes there and the command core so
I'm using soft light keys and I'm using
a vol rank keyboard not quality Okay so
so you jump into the directory so you
can see all the past emacs versions
uh release updates I mean feature
descriptions so there's Emax 29 is the
latest then you have emacs 28 so all
these are so called emacs news files
that's a Emax tradition so you can
search you know which feature was added
when
and you know in it comes with emacs okay
so that's a news file and it's also on
my website but so you click on that so
you have the HTML version and
particularly interesting I did is that
you have this
uh pop-up you know feature showing the
inline documentation for each of the
function so you can so it's very
convenient for streamlines so
streamlines so there's a new change
string lines handle trading new lines
differently so you can
you know either click on that for the
detail or you can move the mouse over to
see the inline documentation okay so
that's a feature on my website so you
can you can start to browse you know
make it easier to see what what some
commands do you know this emacs news is
usually esoteric if you haven't used
emacs for five years so you know even me
I've been using emacs for 20 years you
know some of these um
you don't understand you know like you
have to dive into detail but because
emacs is essentially a emac lisp
environment
okay so that's a that's the pop-up
that's uh that's what I want to tell you
about okay so you can check out the or
this version and click on any version
emacs 25 and you can see
uh you know these pop-up documentation
okay that's one thing uh what's the next
thing so
pop-up feature and also this pop-up has
been updated throughout my emacs website
for example if you are learning emac
bisp uh go to let's say testy quality so
you can see you know you have pop-up for
all functions even inside code so it
makes easier for you to learn okay so
that's what I want to mention
okay now next what's the next thing I
want to talk about
yeah so let's talk about emacs 29 some
of the features in emacs 29. okay one of
the features is Emoji now you can see
emacs supports inserting Emoji many
commands very convenient uh let's try
one of them so Emoji insert okay so
Emoji insert for example
and it's open a new file
let's metax Emoji insert okay the
shortcut is Ctrl x 8 e i you know
shortcut is fairly complex so
do that
okay so you can see
oh wow what am I doing so wait why is it
so big oh you type a letter to pick so V
let's say
this one B okay we got a car we got a
taxi
so that's a new feature Emoji insert and
Emoji search you can search Emoji by
name
uh Emoji list you can list emojis let's
try some of them but another feature
that's old let me tell you is you call
describe chart okay so I'm gonna call it
now
okay then it will show you all
information about this character this uh
taxi car so expand the window so you can
see the code point the Unicode code
point in hexadecimal or decimal and
uh the utf-8 encoding and the name
oncoming taxi the name of the character
okay so that's some of the useful
features so again that feature is called
describe chart
you can see somewhere here there it is
describe chart okay very useful so Emoji
so let's try another Emoji command so
Emoji uh let's see Emoji list okay
meta X Emoji Beast that's what I want
okay so it gives you a list of emojis
then you can just copy and paste in
emacs
you know these are the some of the more
common emojis fantastic
grouped by name
pretty good
so IMAX 29 great feature Emoji okay so
close that close that
so next let's see what we talk about
next so Emoji is a feature
then
now I'm gonna not cover everything here
because that's taking a lot of time
uh let's see what's next any comments
is on YouTube a great platform hello
a Chinese guy from China I think I don't
know who you are but thank you for
following me uh
so let's see what we what you guys are
saying here
uh do you like government okay so keep
the comments going okay you can ask
questions I'll get to them
okay so let's see next thing I want to
show you some features describe mod
okay so the command describe mod so I
can show you okay so metax let's show
the pink window
uh let's close this window okay So Meta
X describe mod okay
Ctrl H N so you do it so that will show
you this panel so this panel is
basically the documentation for the
current buffers major mod so if you are
coding python JavaScript CC plus plus
Java or whatever go land roast
or any any anything or in text you know
doing text or email you can just
describe mod that will tell you
the features and the keys for the
current
you know mod so all these so I'm using
my own so
uh HTML mod
so here's the keys here's the functions
and you can go to any one of them and
you can see the documentation for them
so remember
this described mod is one of the most
uh useful thing you want to do you know
to look up the documentation of the
current buffers major mods you know so
how do you for example in Python how do
you indent a whole bunch of lines or you
know things like that so it doesn't
matter what HTML mod whatever mod you
can see so this is describe mod okay
documentation for it
okay I'm gonna skip some of the minor
changes you know they they made a minor
change so that the minor mods are now
listed at the bottom before you know
before emacs 29 you'll see this you'll
see this thing
you'll see this irrelevant one you know
like one bunch of you know the this part
at the top
you know if you are a typical you know
for me I'm using all my emacs mod I
rarely use any other people's code these
days but for you you got you may have
more lines and you'll show at the top
like very confusing you know
this bug I've been telling the Emax
people since like 15 years ago they
refuse to listen like the emac step
usually after 10 years then they make
the change you know in IMAX 29 there are
so many features in Emax 29 that I
either fire filed a bug report to the
new Emax people or I bitched about it a
lot a lot of features after 10 years
finally they did it
uh that's a situation with the emac step
but anyway that you know it's pretty
good today I mean there's a lot
improvements in images okay describe mod
is useful
um
now another thing about describe mod or
describe function uh let's let's try
um let's say describe function
find file find file is a command you
call to open a file okay most of you are
familiar so you can call describe
function
there that's the command to show the
documentation of a function and in
emacs29 you see these these you see
these key strokes
blocks diff color differently that's new
okay before you just got plain text so
so now it's better it's rendered like a
key
uh so that's one of the emacs 29 feature
okay now but there's a problem in
if you are running emacs on Windows the
default font for this Keys is very ugly
it's a big mapped font so you want to
change that and I show you how to change
that okay so you you know you go to my
website emacs29 really features and
click on modify default face
basically you just put this
in your emacs init file
then you can have you know now it's
using a great
font okay so just copy this code and put
in your
um emacs in it okay so let's talk about
next thing default major mod okay so
there's another thing useful
now let's let me talk about Let me give
the rant about the Alamo Kenzie guy
okay so okay okay let's do that so let's
go to emacs blog first
okay and uh
search for Allen let's see
search for
okay so it actually
um go to emacs 29 features okay
so go to Emax 29 features this uh
mentioned here somewhere
am I doing good
what do I think about Transformers what
do I think about it
I uh I have some
political things to show about that one
Transformers but maybe not today
uh let's see what's next by default
Microsoft uh yeah let's talk about Adam
McKenzie guy okay a rant
so that will be
yeah here a major problem
it's a damage into Emax for the next 10
years who knows what
so let's see how do I start okay so
here's a story it began in 2025 2015
okay you just search for this emac B
stock string curly quote controversy
2015. this is the problem begin okay so
the problem is in emacs
you have you know emacs documentation
you have this uh let's let me show you
some of that okay so you have this very
um
very ugly notation you see this search
forward so you want to quote you you
want to mark up search for what is a
command Okay so actually let me show you
um
let me show you find fire okay describe
function find file okay so you can let
me see if it's there so it's there you
see so we are look describe function we
are looking at the documentation for the
find file function and you see some of
these are clickable links so when they
whenever they mention another command or
function it's highlighted so you can
click on it it'll jump to
that functions documentation okay and
you can go back
by clicking here or press L okay so this
is great feature you know it's a markup
so in order to do this in in the in the
emacs documentation you have to use this
grave access grave
accent character to begin markup then
end with a single
straight quote character so that's a
markup to tell emacs that this is a
function okay now this is ugly because
you know they are using you know that's
before the era of Unicode before you
have Kodi matching quotes anyway that's
the way it is the emacs tradition you
know since 1970s
okay so they started because
I I would say because of me I wrote an
article about it so some of the great
one of the great guy uh
his name is Paul Eggert he started to
implement the curly quote so that
instead of writing you know this ugly
ASCII
to emulate a matching quote you would
use you know an actual
proper matching pairs such as curly
crops single curly or double curly or
lots of emacs
uh
parenthesis okay let me show you
so you just search for Unicode Saudi
Unicode you can find and search for
bracket so let's search for bracket
okay so all these are Unicode brackets
yeah you have so many different types uh
and uh so this page I recommend this is
one of my page so show hexadecimal no
show ID no show name no so you can see
here is a bunch of Unicode brackets
fantastic matching pairs actual matching
pairs no hack
you know like like the markup
you know dark the markup uh the markdown
system you have lots of you know ASCII
hacks
so anyway matching brackets so let me
show you my page okay
so Saudi code
info Unicode bracket okay so this page
you can see all Unicode brackets
many of them this is a proper
brackets
so you know people started to you know
the poor Eggert poor Eggert he started
to implement so that in emacs
documentation let's go back to find file
so you jump to the source code at find
file so you can see here is the
fine file function source code and you
can see you can see the markup you see
here
you see
this
grave accent markup so that indicates
the function so with if you want to use
the proper matching bracket so you can
you know create a new convention so
instead of using that character hack you
use the proper some kind of some you
know new Unicode proper brackets for
these right so that's a good idea so he
implemented this
okay and this is 2015. he he you know he
talked with the emac state Then There
came out this Alum McKenzie
okay an idiot Dimitri gutter you know
he's also one of the one of the core
emacs Dev I I don't know actually what
he did but he
but anyway the the main guy is the Adam
McKenzie okay so you know
so let me show you
so search for Alan
Alan McKenzie
you know he he he uh he let me let me
show okay
so anyway he object
you know he says oh so scrub should not
contain Unicode because we don't know we
can type it you know this white Western
idiots you know the west Western people
they have a Obsession of sticking
sticking to ASCII characters and what
what's asking character
uh
you know you guys probably know or maybe
you some of you don't know okay so I
have a article on ASCII characters I
have lots of Articles so as the
characters are basically the characters
you see on your keyboard
so Western people especially America the
pure English speakers they love ASCII
they have a they have a thought
mentality that every source code must be
ASCII only because anything else such as
curly quote or any other Emoji they
think that's that's a problem because
you cannot type them directly on your
keyboard this is American monolingual
mindset
why do I say that because you know if
you think about it over the world you
know Japan Chinese arabics
they don't they don't have that mindset
because in Chinese for example you have
33 000 characters commonly used
characters you can type directly on your
keyboard you use the input system just
like the way you input Emoji you know
you don't directly press a button to
insert the Emoji you have a input system
okay so that's true for Japan
Chinese Korean Vietnamese and lots of
others and in Europe in European
language you know German France
uh Spanish they have also some special
characters so you need a special
keyboard with you know dead keys and old
graph keys right but in America
the English speaker the Americans you
know they don't know that like that is
far into them so that's why I say so
this has to do with culture if you grew
up as American you never went anywhere
you know you just know English only so
it's your mindset it's your thinking
it's part of your brand that everything
must be asking only you insist about it
when you see code you know that's you
know when you see some of the
Emoji or the curly quote or this you
know you think that's that's weird okay
but two Chinese Japanese any anywhere
else which is who is not just English
they don't see it that way because the
you have two type you know there
are three you know there's no character
you type directly on the keyboard every
character you have to use the input
system so it doesn't matter if you have
a you know Cody quote or whatever it's
natural
so this is a this is a cultural
difference that's why I say okay so
that's why so this so came out this Adam
McKenzie
he insisted
no we cannot have Curry quote in in you
know in other convention in
documentation because that's hard to
type
so anyway so this became a flame War
flame war in the emac step mailing list
you know fourth
several thousand messages you know
Arguments for four months
okay this this guy uh told the tale you
know I also I'm you know I I also read
it
so anyway if So eventually
eventually Richard Stoneman the
Richard Solomon came in and says this
please stop inserting curly quotes into
dark streams in emac sources the
face Richard Stoneman okay because he
posted that then
it killed the entire conversation and
it's decided implicitly that we are not
going to have curly girls in a document
you know we don't have we are going to
stick with pure SC code in the emacs
documentation
okay that's decided so but what is the
problem the problem is
let me show you what is the problem okay
the element McKenzie okay
so let me show you the what is the
problem
so we are right now in a list source
code of emacs29 so um so let's do a
search using so you know I have my
you know let me just search it okay
backslash
uh
equal okay search for that search for
all emacs these files okay let me show
you what is the problem this Allen
McKenzie cost
and it's gonna be with us for the next
you know who knows thank you you see
you know before so here we are seeing
the emac source code okay so each one is
a currency you can jump to it so you can
see
you know before when you have you know
when you have a function you simply put
a accent sign
you know there's a lot there's a lot of
it so actually let me show you
let me show you all occurrences okay
uh
so you can see all of them in one shot
okay so here is the emacs documentation
you see before you don't have this
backslash backslash equal now you have
to add them
that's the problem so now your source
code becomes unreadable and unpossible
you see now there's this here is four
backslashes
uh and you see so this
1900 lines 1900 lines of this
created by Alan McKenzie okay this
is a major problem this this Escape
mechanism is a major problem throughout
programming languages you know streams
an element can see basically he he
single-handedly
introduce this problem into emacs in
emacs 2015.
okay that is the problem
it's pretty bad okay
so
um
okay let's close that so
close that close that so what is the
it's closer closet
um
so and in emacs 29 it became worse
because before
because the emacs 29 when you have a
when you have a Emax source code and if
you compile it
and if you do not add the slash slash
equal backslash backslash equal to your
accent character and several others it
will make a complaint
saying that you got a problem
so it forces you so now it like enforce
this concept so now you have to like
this for example this
this documentation
let's copy it let's put it here okay
let's magnify so now
you have to
every time that grave accent occurs now
you have to put this
backs slash backslash that and not just
that when you have a backslash you also
have that so it becomes very complex
that's a problem okay
uh
so you are looking at my source code why
do I do it why do I do not add that
because I refuse to
uh so you can turn off the compiler
warnings for that problem okay so I I
you know I looked into and figured out
so you turn off I refuse to use that
this this bug introduced by Alan you
know Adam McKenzie he's he's a German
guy I know him you know online since
2000 early 2000 2014 or so he he he's uh
kind of he always refuse any modern
change he wants emacs to stick with
1980s way
you know so this is a damage one of the
damage
this type of emacs people introduced to
emacs this is you know pain pain in my
ass because this issue involves design
which is a thing I'm concerned at most
okay so lots of rent uh so let's see
let's move on to next Point okay
uh so how do you how do you um avoid the
compiler errors and all that so we can
you know if you so we can find out
I discussed here
uh somewhere
yeah here so emacs 29 by by compile
unescaped single quote warning so it's
not just grave action if you have a
single quote you also need to
you know do do the backslash backslash
equal thing in front the animals so
to so you can
you know either fix it
uh you can turn off the buy compile
warning or you can manually fix it you
know add those things and also you
there's a feature in your emacs in it
you can
turn off this Auto
Otto um
transformation of the quote because the
way they this element because they can
see you know so instead of Unicode
directly in a documentation
you
you instead of add the markup so the
markup when you actually call the
describe function or whatever it will go
through a step of transformation to
remove this you know backslash backslash
equal markup
to then render them as curly curl this
is a adding complexity to it
because now what you see is not what it
is because here you have these
characters but when it displays
something else
and also what about Richard strowman
you know he is not the leader the
maintainer of emacs at the time you know
he he haven't been since about 2010 or
so his world in the emac step is just to
for political any political issues
he has Supreme
uh right to
decide which you know decide what to do
that is that is
that is you know agreed upon when we
choose a new leadership for the Emax
maintainer so at the time the maintainer
is the you know if you read my article
the maintenance is Stefan more near
a guy in Canada you're a professor in
functional programming languages
research
he didn't he didn't really say any you
know he didn't if
really making any comment one way or
another but it's a Richard Stoneman at
the end you know you know just posted
that message
that created the problem but he has no
right to do it because this is a
technical issue this is not some
political or you know GPL you know the
new public license you know thing
so Richard Stroman is uh that's one of
the things Richard Stoneman did very bad
because you know he has a Fame you know
everyone knows Richard solman so when he
says something everyone is like
increases required you know you cannot
argue with him you cannot say oh yeah
but you are wrong and he did a lot of
that you know accusing or the other
developers contributors big major
contributors in emacs you know accusing
them this or that well he haven't been
coded for like 15 years or so
preacher's Stoneman a problem
okay
so that's about this uh very painful
very uh huge damage in emacs
okay that's it that's it on that one so
anything else
let's see the comments and see where we
go okay
uh okay so yeah
so hexa you said you don't like Comax
decision to not change the placement of
z x y keys but you changed
some fly keys to use Escape rather than
caps lock
uh okay I think I know what you are
talking about but not exactly in detail
but I I you know basically in something
like he's
uh I made a change about half a year ago
so that the Escape key by default will
activate
command mod okay that's a little detail
for those of you using software Keys
about half a year ago when you press
Escape key it will switch you to command
mod by default you know without changing
any in it so that decision you know I
think you know if you read the detail I
have lots of I give a lot of reasons if
you read
you know the commit the git command
comments so basically
lots of keyboards
you know you know basically because
first of all Escape key is very
intuitive because of VI and veeam uses
you know a skip Escape key to
programmers is known for switching to
command mod in VI
so
if I do that took some flight Keys the
invest majority of people they will when
they start to use it they don't have to
figure out they don't have to change
their keyboard so they can just press
Escape key okay so that's one of the
advantage
now there are a few disadvantage
two of them okay mostly majorly one one
is that a Escape key on a typical normal
PC keyboard which is vast majority of
people using they are far away they are
on the corner so if you do it you know
if you do it this way is
repetitive straight string injury
uh induction so you are prone to have
hand pain if you keep pressing the
Escape key
in property the proper way to uh press
the Escape key on a normal keyboard is
to move your hand whole hand don't don't
do this okay move your hand you know
press it
okay so that's one of the disadvantage
because most people vast majority of
people they are they are not going to
think about configure their keyboard or
mechanical keyboard or you know
programmable keyboard change keys or
switch to many packages that allows you
to
you know place the Escape key somewhere
else you know things like that most
people are not doing that so they are
just press they'll just press Escape key
and more for most people when you are
younger you are not thinking about you
know whether this way or that way you
just naturally
do that and after a few years you'll get
repetitive strain injury
so that's bad
so that's one of a disadvantage
another thing is that in emacs
Emax has a quirk that
when you D you know this is esoteric
details when you define keybinding there
are different syntaxes but basically if
you rebind the Escape key then in
terminal if you run emacs in terminals
such as
um
you know in power shower or bash if you
run for example I can show you running
emacs in terminal okay
so in uh
so I'm on windows so you can I can start
emacs in terminal or not this one
in terminal you have to run emacs not uh
okay so you see I'm running emacs in
terminal and using soft light Keys too
so I can just go to
my emacs blog fantastic
okay confirm so you can see this is
stuff like he's in terminal so anyway in
terminal
basically in terminal the Escape key if
you rebind the Escape key then some
other Keys such as arrow keys won't work
anymore
the reason is because complicated
history of the terminal protocol because
terminal used to mean you communicate
you know via a protocol to some other
machine so everything you type is
communicated and this and what you send
many of the
Keys such as arrow keys they send
special characters which is basically
Escape something something so if You
rebind Escape key and if you run emacs
in terminal that means some other Keys
such such as arrow keys no longer works
so that's a major problem and it's very
difficult to fix very complex okay so
anyway that's that's the reason okay and
there's a lot of details I'm not going
into
okay so quit emacs
okay so what else uh
what is the negativity installed in the
semantics of a computational device such
as a computer what do you mean that's a
bloated question
yeah
if you want to go back to Nature you can
stop using computers stop using
smartphone go live in a mountain that's
a choice you can make and stop driving
cars you know go leaving a mountain
so that's one of the negativity of using
a computer that's what you are saying
what are you talking about this in the
semantics of a computational device
[Laughter]
okay so what's uh anything else maybe
that's it for today
let's see what else I want to say Okay
so let's see go back to sound talk show
so we talked about
um
maybe that's it for today okay any
questions
okay there is a feature
now this is a great
um feature now it's about emacs
completion okay so emacs since emacs 28
which is 2022 April they they
implemented a lot great features
for mini buffer completion
okay
so I just rewrote my tutorials about
them
you should check it out
so basically what you want to do is you
want to turn on a complete mod and also
set up
you know so this is why it does so it
allows you to finish your command much
easily okay so you want to turn on a
complete mod
in fact I complete vertical mod
and also you want to put
this completion Styles into your emacs
in it
so that
um
so that you when you type a command it
asks you to complete something you don't
have to
you know there are several ways to match
it so one of the ways Flex match meaning
that anything you typed
needs not to match the beginning of the
character or you know so you can you can
type any substring or any character in
order in you know in order
that will match any command so this is
very convenient
so you want to uh so you can grab my
innate code I prepared for you and put
in your unique file okay read this it's
fairly complicated because over the past
10 years you have the icomplete mod you
have the I2 mod then you have the
I switch B mod before I do you know in
the very beginning like 20 years ago you
have I complete then you have I switch
like 15 years ago then you have I do mod
about 10 years ago then about five years
ago you have more elaborate icomplete
mod that features Flex match you know
style so which is like what I do is
using
and then in the past two years since
emacs 22 you started to have a complete
vertical which display choices
vertically you know without without you
spending several hours to set up you
know to make it disabled very complex so
anyway today you can do this easy
okay read my article for that
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
remember PayPal me okay or buy my emacs
tutorial okay so you get my whole
website for the emacs uh so you have
instantaneous
uh lookup search no documentation
uh many testimonials you know since 10
years ago since 20 years ago uh
you know so you uh donate me okay
thank you guys for that
so that's it I think yeah uh and uh we
shut down in few minutes
did I miss anything
so we were going to write some command
in Macbeth yeah let's forget about that
today
okay
bye guys
mm-hmm