good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of star talk show video
check audio check and today's 2021 july
25th and today we are going to do e-max
lisp coding
and some move from language coding okay
so let me summarize what's going on okay
you know um yeah okay so let me start to
say what
are we going to do okay so we are going
to write several commands
uh one of them is we are going to
basically write three emac these
commands to work with wolfram language
one of them is
look up wolf i'm doc that is if you have
a word in wufang language
let's say uh let's say parametric plot
you know then you you know whatever name
you can just press a key and you go to a
wolf and language documentation you'll
see it in a moment okay
so uh so
look up wolfram doc that's one command
and the
song will film reference linkify that is
another command
that is if you have a wolfram language
uh reference link
on the in a buffer you press a key it
becomes
a link you know url becomes a link with
special format
i'm gonna explain and the other command
we're gonna write is wolfram word to
link
so if you have a wolfram language
function name you press a key
it becomes a reference url link to the
wolfram
documentation for that function so and
here is some
example url we're gonna test so that's
the emac this part we're gonna do
so this is gonna be a lot uh i don't
think nobody's here watching so i'm
gonna do it myself
then uh i'm going to um
then i'm going to do uh
some random stuff okay demonstration of
the wolfham language for example this uh
this this this this
is uh actually this is a klein bottle
okay
so actually so let me do this okay so
let me tell you yesterday
i did a video on writing a
wolfram mod so and that is complete
like guys so let me show you okay so
so let's see let's start a wolfram
language code
template so let's uh so here is language
so you paste it you can see
all the function names building function
names in language building function
symbols symbols because language is just
like lisp okay so this
you you call these symbols ufam language
name you know function names are
all colored you see hold on a second why
is this
sign not colored okay so
uh you need a space in between we can
fix that okay so you see
this sign is not colored so let's go to
wufang language
um
uh uh source code okay i mean wufang
language
so let me show you the fruit of
yesterday and
okay somewhere mod okay so you can see
here is the documentation
and this is we just wrote this yesterday
so
there are two 2 200 lines of code okay
and but most of it is wolfram language
function names there are there are seven
thousand function names as we showed
yesterday
so 2000 of the lines are function
from language function names and another
let's see so yeah 2000 of them yeah so
the source code is about
200 lines okay but we're going to
improve a lot
because we just started this casa wufan
mod
now the licensing part you are
interested
i don't think it's going to be free i've
been doing
open source for 20 years and that left
a bad taste in my mouth
you know like test testing
testing a greasy coin in your mouth
so this is i don't think it's going to
be uh
open source i'm going to sell it so you
you can buy it now send me five bucks
paypal
patreon you know just you know mention
you know send me money
five dollars for now i'm gonna increase
the price as i
start to work a lot at a lot of features
you know possibly eventually it's going
to
uh connect via math link the wolfram
language protocol so that you can
actually evaluate
uh like a shell you know connect to
wufang script woofen script is free or
ulfram engine you know you can evaluate
wufang language code
uh fantastic so
so here's the source code so uh let's go
back to talk show page
uh let me write down uh
so yeah you do that send me money okay
that's what i'm here for
i need to eat
uh and okay so so many things to do okay
so we
gonna uh a lot of things to do so
so wufang language uh someone from mod
okay let's write it down
somewhere mod okay so
that is uh we talked about because i
will find mod let's
show gonna be um
okay and let me quickly do okay so yeah
we mentioned before we have a bug here
we let's fix it so you can see
so you can see this sign function this
sign function name
you know sign is a building function but
this part is not colored we need to fix
it so let's fix it
so some emac this coding so let's do
okay i need a key i need i need a key
shortcut to directly call meta x
uh you see you see okay hold on a second
let me show you this
okay so um i need a key
to invoke wufang language mod so let's
do that
let me just do that emacs keybinding
okay
so so you go here so uh
fly
wait where's my key binding for ufam
language mod
uh yeah so here
command dump okay a bunch of keys uh you
know kind of my personal keys
so because uh wolf and mod
okay so the key will be
w so it's going to be space space space
w
that gets you to uh language mod so
evaluate this code
and let's try it describe function i
mean describe key space
space space w it's undefined what the
uh example mod okay so actually so you
need to
so first of all let's add edit here okay
so anyway evaluate this and also we need
to evaluate somewhere else here okay
evaluate it
so now now i call space space space
control h so you can see
here that's a key focus i will find mod
so
actually i can make this buffer into xo5
mod
space please space w
there it is uh okay nothing changes but
anyway so close that
close that okay now let's make this into
fundamental mod let's
shrink it okay fundamental mod
now magnify space space space w
fantastic now you see it works
now describe key space space
space w so now we get into the
documentation
uh of the xiaowu fan mod press enter
to go into the source code then we are
going to fix that sine cosine you know
the syntax highlighting problem
you know this is not being highlighted
so how do you fix that
okay when you have uh when you have 20
years
15 years of e-max coding that is easy
okay
so all you have to do is here
uh let's see symbol um
so rejects opt let's see
reject rejects up this is a
list function that takes a list of
words and we will turn them into a
regular expression
of all you know so so that's what what
this
uh rejects opt does okay
and here's the documentation describe
function and
then okay so you want to
so you want to modify okay so
so symbols research is surrounded by
symbols
okay so this result rejects
is surrounded by
words okay let's try let's use words
yeah okay so let's let's yeah let's try
words so replace symbol so let
me show you my operations replace the
word
replace the word apostrophe symbols by
words okay yes yes yes yes yes yes yes
change them now is it words or word
let's
see the documentation again words yeah
okay
now evaluate the buffer close it close
this
reopen it fantastic did you see that
now the sign is also colored
now wait wait wait where is the u-color
u and v
should not be colored okay okay i know
it's white because
yesterday now let's go back to the
wufang language mod again go to the
source code because
yesterday we we used the symbol u
and v so let's search for u
yeah so you see you see that you see
there you know this
is a mistake we are trying we listed all
the symbols but
x but u and v is actually uh
we used it so we want to delete that
okay
so you and we deleted evaluate the
buffer
close it
close it and uh wait don't close it
so describe key space space space w
go to the source code then go to the
directory
then open this test file open
it close it open it magnify
now you see u and v are not colored
anymore fantastic
fix and fixes so now someone for mod
go to the top the source code we modify
the code so we need to change the
version number
so the version number is going to be 1.1
now
fantastic and
git status git
add git commit
much you do about nothing okay done so
that's about
emacs xsa woof and mod fantastic
so we have let me demonstrate some
features okay parametric cloud 3d so
this is a kind of a function
you can jump to uh you know any brackets
so parametric plot
3d so parametric plot 3d press
enter and press space fantastic
okay so now we're gonna actually we're
gonna plot this thing okay so
i'm i'm we're gonna modify this code
in emaclis okay this is a new one so
so actually shrink a little bit so uh
what do i want to do so we want to
change this to pi
and s equals to one so okay so
let's do that paste it
so that we can close the gap this is a
client bottle a different
parameterization of the client bottle
surface
we explained what's a parametric surface
in math yesterday
so a equals two pi does not work what uh
what what
oh okay okay so a a was um
a controls kind of the the
huge radius so if you want to close the
thing you need to put two
pi here okay so now it's closed
now let's change a to three okay
fantastic
now we are going to
i don't want the boxes i don't want i
don't want the um
copy now i don't want the uh
i don't want the bounding box so so what
you do is
uh let's see let's this is a bit
so i let's make this simple okay so
actually i have another
command that reformat the whole thing
this let's show it
so press the prefix key so you see
f9t will predefine the code so let's try
it okay
f9t okay you know so i'm still working
on it i'm still
trying to find what's the best way to uh
predefined reformat the wolfram line
with language code
now like i talked about quite a few
times in my past video
uh you know wufam language is a truly
white space
insignificant language so so this you
know in
in fact the entire language
can be you know can be one single line
like the whole source code
you can make them one single line
and including form including uh comments
okay do we have
oh actually so we need to add another
feature
to uh create a comment so this this
is common okay yeah okay i need to do
that offline
so anyway so here is the parametric plot
we want to
so right now we want to make it uh
box free okay
okay boxed okay uh
you know then we need to type right
arrow
again we need the shortcut okay let me
let me show you some of the
let me let me work on this
we need so what we need you see boxed
let me show you okay what's going on so
what we want is
box let me type this first okay box
force
okay and axis
axis uh dash arrow
axis force okay now i want to
okay first of all let's try to plot it
okay
so do it do it fantastic
okay so we got this fantastic thing
uh let's let's magnify
okay fantastic now you see it's painful
to type these
uh dash arrow stuff and and force and
true is one of the
most used symbols for central you need
to type that a lot in
from language so i want the brief so
when i type for example i want
when i type let's say f it should become
force
something like that
and for the arrow i'm not sure about
that anyway for the arrow
i i wanted to say just r a okay so right
now my abbrev
i expand to a unicode arrow but that
doesn't work in
wolfen language although it does display
us unicode arrow you can see
but if you want to pasting you need to
paste this so i need a shortcut i i
we should expand to that okay let's do
it
so let's go to wufang source code again
so describe key space space
space w okay jump to the source code
then let's search for the abbrev section
here so let's paste it ra becomes
that fantastic and kuzer you need the
cursor okay
kusa
so ra becomes that and let's say true
enforce okay so
t will become
true okay and f is
false okay evaluate the
the the whole source code close this
reopen it magnify
now let's try it f
yeah fantastic t fantastic
r a space fantastic saves you typing
you know so we are making progress with
the xsa emacs
cassava mod you know saves you typing
so you don't get crippled with your
hands
and abandon your coding career
okay now who is here night people
welcome
to the show guys and uh say something
okay let's see
let me show the comments this machine
hello this machine emily our greatest
coder in star forum emily
good morning emily to uk and the good
good beaujo hi
so okay so
so we did so so okay so we did we we
you know we showed some woofer mod
feature
okay and and now now actually i want to
export this
uh image okay into my website so save
graphics as
so uh png so td.png
okay save in desktop that's fine then
go to go to my website you just search
for
claim bottle okay i'm gonna replace this
one this this
this image is from 3d explore math okay
it's my
from my mentors in my you know
mathematician
3d explore math let me let me show you
some of that okay so
uh richard palace professor richard
palace uh
and professor hermann casher from
germany they are
uh two of the greatest uh differential
geometers
in the past 50 years uh and i helped
them
i helped them do some of the uh
you know 3d supermath uh museum okay so
you know the the website is getting
pretty old and uh
you know anyway i i helped in creating
this website so
you might check them out famous surfaces
so
and uh okay so you know they are
they are you know one of the top
differential geometers
and they teach me they taught me a lot
math
so and
okay so what i want to mention is that
oops i close the browser by mistake
okay press one key to reopen it and
let's go to did we did we show the
yeah new 3d
3d explorer math okay
3d explorer math uh
3d explorer math you know they they use
the
kind of uh the domain name is not so
good
you know i tell them to use a different
domain name that's easy to type and so
on they don't
they didn't uh you know
listen to that recommendation so anyway
so
so so this side so i wanted to say yeah
so richard palace and herman
castro hermann they they are also the
pioneer of tech
so when tech and la tech is invented was
invented like 30 40 years ago
they lead the spreading of tech and
latex you know
richard plays and uh hermann cash
as you know in particular which are
paradise
and they and he is also a pioneer you
know this is 30 years ago
he wrote started you know he's a
mathematician but he also code
so back then the language the kind of
the popular language to use is pascal
so he wrote a program for the mac uh
to plot all these uh all these
uh uh differential geometry uh
uh manifold curves and surfaces okay so
you can see
you know we talked about this surface
yesterday bullish surface
this is a this is this surface is a
representation
of the projective plane okay
i love projected plane projectively
input is part of the projective geometry
which is which kind of fail out of
fashion
in you know math the field of math the
branches
of math also goes by fats and fashion
like in certain decades certain topic is
very popular everyone wants to do that
then another
a decade or century
typically in every every 50 years or
something
you know in other 50 years another topic
become
popular you know so projective geometry
was the most
popular topic in i think 1800s or
yeah 1800s the you know
but it kind of uh fair out of fashion i
mean
but however it doesn't mean it's like
it's no good anymore it's still good and
a lot of
mathematicians pursue it it's just that
it's not
you know the main heart research topic
you know
so the heart after projective geometry
the hot topic is topology you know
topology you probably you've heard of
so anyway this void surface is a actual
uh model they say you know it's a model
of the projective geometry
a projective plan okay it's a projected
plan and you can see how it generated
uh okay so wait uh where are we and uh
uh so they have these you know so this
shows you how it
um you know it tries to illustrate
exactly how the surface is constructed
and there are other website also try to
do this okay and there is this famous
uh sculpture you know made of metal this
is in this is
this one is in germany in uh
mathematical risk research institute of
oberwolf okay in germany you know
if you are a mathematician if you are a
professional mathematician everyone
knows this
uh you know just like in programming
community we know
lots of you know richard snowman or
other you know famous coders
so anyway so that's uh
richard palais my my friend my mentor in
math
and herman cashier and they and they
richard palace and herman castro they
mostly
these two person they wrote um
they wrote a program called 3d explore
math
that was kind of fairly popular in 1990s
in 2000s today's kind of died away
because um
they kind of you know because they are a
lot more technology and also they are
uh now old you know they are
much older than me i'm i'm getting old
i'm about
so anyway so so and and we tried
to put some of it in you know on the web
with javascript so
so so this is actually pretty new just
two years ago so that that's why you see
these are using javascript uh you know
but we can we could
actually do a lot better for example
you know this is actually just a
sequence of
static images it will be much much
better
if we have actual actual porting of the
pascal code to javascript so we can have
rotation and
dynamic generation not not not
static images this these are static
images
i kind of helped to create so and here
you see the generation of the
klein bottle you know klein bottle there
are different models of klein bottle
client bottle is another surface in uh
you know with special properties okay
and here is a kind of the you know so
anyway that's
math okay that's geometry my favorite
topic geometry
uh i want to so
so uh fasting good morning fasting uh
anything interesting here
okay so that's a digression to
you know my friends richard palace and
herman cashew and
and so so i also kind of have a version
uh on my site you know my you know i you
know
this website began like uh 15 years ago
2008 uh this began you know it began
2006 okay 15 years ago about
so and now i'm going to kind of replace
them
using uh wufam language so i want to
read so
so this image you are seeing is from 3d
explorer math you can
you can uh rotation and by the way you
can download it still
on the mac it still works uh
you know you can download it you can
just find a download link
you know if you go around the website
but what i want to do so i want to
replace this one okay let's do it
quickly so
so let's go to um let's go to talk show
and today's talk show here and
d that part and paste the code it paste
the link here
so we can go to the website showing
browser so that's that page
and we remember we exported from
mathematica wuffin language
this image now let's put that image here
so i have convenient command that just
move the image here
and also optimize the png file you can
see
in the buffer now showing browser okay
that's that's a
that's my screenshot from previous
session so actually we don't need this
open it delete it and okay and
move the image again
okay it's doing optimization of the png
file and showing browser okay that's
another
that's yesterday's screenshot uh for my
video we talked about yesterday we uh
it turns out i don't need it so let's do
another
try yeah this is the one okay uh wait
it shows refresh refresh uh
what's going on what is this image okay
i don't know why
let's do another uh move image okay look
at the pink window
uh wait
no more wait what
okay let's go to desktop what's going on
uh
i thought i just exported the image
let's try it again
save graphics as
desktop yeah tt.png okay
oh okay so you actually uh okay this is
the file name if you name the file
something something.png it does not
apparently it does not automatically
save it
in that format you have to manually
choose the format first
that is why we got that broken image
thing because it that
that is actually png file
[Music]
so i got a phone call so i cannot talk
right now so uh
actually i need to take the i i need to
take the phone okay
it's from my wife so
so so so okay hold on a second okay so
hold on a second
let me uh so you can see this is a png
so let's close that
and let's do this again okay
and now showing browser fantastic
now we don't need the old image anymore
okay so you
return to open it press a key to delete
it delete the html as well showing
browser fantastic
and now you need to rename this image
file because right now it's just that
okay so this
will be renamed as client bottle okay
copy that
press the key to rename this is all
fantastic
uh emac list okay
you can see the file is renamed on disk
and also
this uh html image tag is also changed
okay so let's do it actually copy the
url
and paste it again linkify delete the
previous
showing browser fantastic so
we need to remove this random generated
uh string because it generates a random
stream when you
move an image to your website because
that prevents image you know same same
name
collision you know also serves as an id
you know id unique id is a great thing
in computing
okay so actually i need to take the
phone so
hold on a second let me uh shut down i
mean
give me a minute okay
my voice back and my video is back good
morning everyone good evening
and i i am i have to go to
lunch to offend to dinner to a friend's
house
uh so
you know social stuff social um
okay so we are back to these so we
actually we digressed a lot
now let's get back shall we to uh code
emac this and what you guys are saying
anything
any questions are you okay they are
fasting
you okay they are fussing emily i showed
you my code please reply
uh what does the definition of say hello
look like
define say hello what uh so did you
finish okay
if you want to if you want my reply
tag me okay my name sadie so i can
easily see it
did you finish reading an article about
the keyboard layout named no i haven't
finished that
you know it's uh you know i have lots of
to do's
uh what is this keyboard layout name
okay so
uh because self-respecting layout name
tank okay so so let's go back to these
um yeah so let's finish what we want to
do today so i
you know we we showed a little bit of
language you know it's always good to
uh do some variety this is a variety
show
talk show so we did some emac this so
let's get to the main topic which we
talked about woof and mod
so the main topic today is uh
let's show this okay copy that go back
to
uh what is this okay go back to talk
show
uh link we already did that so the main
topic is
we are going to write these three
functions so let's do it now
okay we need we are going to write these
three functions to uh
to do farm language okay so
so okay wait uh
so let's start emac this smart
template paste it there uh delete that
and and open a new buffer so we are
going to write
this function and
this function and they will all be in
uh wolfram mod
okay so actually delete all that and
switch to switch to xiaowulfi mod okay
describe key space space space w
open the mods documentation then press
tab enter to jump to the source code so
you are looking at the source code
and you see we go to diet you can see
there it is okay
then we are going to write this function
okay so
where do i want to write this function
so uh after the
7000 keywords okay so
here okay make a line
okay shrink so you can see make a line
paste these three functions okay
comment out for now we're gonna write
them one one
at the time so different
look of woof and dark okay so
so i've written this kind of command
like
10 times over the past 20 years more
than 10 times
so
the slower way is for me to actually you
know
code it step by step so you can actually
see it the faster way
you know it's just just copy and paste
my code because i've
written this so many times let's just
copy and
copy the code okay for example i have a
command that's
um you know look up google
or google bing search or whatever so i
just press a key now look at the pink
window okay
um let's see so look at the pink window
i press a key
it search the word under cruiser
function in the web
in the web whatever search engine you
configured
so you see so how does that function
work
now describe key uh
space h uh
describe key space ht so you can see
here is the documentation focused lookup
and in this package lookup er you can
get it on its own melpah
and so then we can see
this function cause i look up internet
let's search for it
okay here is the function search the
word on internet so let's copy it delete
it
close it and not delete so we can
actually just
uh paste it here so we based
our code i mean look up wolverine doc
you know you know based on this uh look
up internet so actually let's just
delete that uh
wait delete that
paste it here delete that so
it's not lookup doc look it look okay so
the documentation lookup
current word
a word in
wolfram
reference site okay so look up the
lookup current word in wolfram
okay so
so that's the documentation the url
string is the string of this form
uh and then i don't know okay so that's
right this should
you know
what what it what the is that i
need i just want to code this fast okay
let's ignore the comments i mean
i don't have time to read it now so
let's just start to
look at the code so set what so first of
all you need to get a word grab the word
okay
so set word if what uh let's
remove the option i i don't want i don't
want the
option okay remove the other parameters
so what if what blah blah blah i don't
care
yeah i don't care so yeah you know so
setup word yeah
you know it's actually probably faster
if i write this from scratch
because okay so set set word if region
active
no i don't want region active it's
always going to be um
okay region active so
uh if if there's active region if
there's a text selection then buffer
string no properties okay begin
end okay otherwise current world
okay okay so current world does may not
work so current world grabs the word
under kusa
but however it may not work for uh wufam
language
you know because what do you consider
the word you know does the
does the hyphen or does the underscore
are part of it
so in order to do that uh let's just say
curtain world okay
let me get this finished quickly so
so set word uh so we don't need this
part
so so delete that
so reference url so we need to know the
wolfram language reference url so
here is the example copy it
so basically we we want to get this url
so
set url if we don't care
okay so wait so this this is the url
this is the word
okay so set the url color cue curly
queue
uh yeah
xxx okay so set the url
we don't care about that
purify the code predefine the code so
that is the reference url then my url
replace string
that by word
my url replace
rejects in string then
replace
replace xxx by current word
in this string okay
then then you know then
then this code allows you to you know
it's it's like that because it
allows you to configure configurate
which browser you want to use
and that's too complex i don't want i
don't want
just let's just say browse uri okay
okay so what what is uh okay
okay let's just say that okay i don't
want to no complexity so
close close let me just show you how how
to do this
simply okay there so
okay that's essentially the command okay
dd so here is a command look up
saluka buffam dark look up current word
in ufam dark side
look up the word under cursor
okay
version today so that is the command
and we need a key for this command so
let's go to the key section
to give it a key so
where is the key search section so it's
just search for
map okay and okay
so here is the key section
so okay copy that
so yeah leader map so leader
so we set the key so here is a function
look up current word look up wolfram doc
and and
what is the key edge okay
leader map is f9 so you press
f9 h you look up look it up okay
so let's you know
evaluate the buffer okay now go to the
test page
go to the diode directory open the test
file
close it open it again just to refresh
so
um so now if i put a cruiser on the
parametric plot 3d
i don't even need to have a selection i
press
i press the f9 u
oh not oh
there it is we did it fantastic
okay so fantastic fantastic we're making
a lot
progress this uh now go back to the code
go back to the um and we need to write
more functions
so this function look up the word okay
so we need to
write another function because i will
find uh dot linkify so this time i'm not
going to copy my code from somewhere
because that's actually slower
so because i will find reference linker
five so what does this mean so
given a wolfram language url you want to
turn it into a link
so in html so people can click okay
so so uh here's a ui example
so first of all let's write the dark
because
because when you write the dark you have
a clear idea what you are doing and
that's my style of coding
always read the dark first even a draft
or whatever
spec or thoughts so this um so what this
do
change url under cruiser
into a link html link
with special format
okay change change
wufang language reference
url under cursor into a html link that's
kind of mouse for too much to too many
words okay but we're gonna fix that
later
so my concern is just to get the
code work now so
so a ui like that okay so again actually
i need to go to
um refer to my code because i've written
this a million times
it's easier to copy so
yeah so this is you go to html
site linkify so you go to one of these
uh reference linkify oh actually i
already
written that so that code is in uh
go to my abbrev file go to my emacs init
go to miscellaneous there open it
search for wufram yeah what
okay not in this file ref okay so
this file emacs reflective file
so here is the code cut close
save close shrink the window
closer brief close html
back to the code here so
paste it here so we already have uh yeah
so so i already have the function
because i will find ref linkify
make current word into a link to
uh wolfram language reference site
now the word mathematica is out of
fashion because they renamed their
language wufang language
which turns out is actually a better
name initially i think mathematica
is good you know why should we have a
wufang language kind of
you know but actually now i'm used to it
also
i think it it is actually a better name
for
better name you know for for
who from the company but also in general
it is actually a better name because
wolfram language actually describes you
know descriptive describe the
language while mathematica you know like
what you know so technically mathematica
is
an app you know
for doing math using the wolfram
language but but but actually
you know the whole fun thing is about
that so wufang language reference site
okay
so ufon reference linkify so
let's put today's state since we
modified it so
so we don't need this anymore
okay now again we need to give it a key
map okay
we need to give it give it a key so
let's go to the key section here so
again copy delete that paste it here so
which key is that
uh you know key deciding the design of
key binding
the design of keyboard shortcut layout
that's another
giant science and art because you want
you want the most frequently used
command to have the most easy key
so you know actually i need to think you
know five minutes you know
but i'm doing this live so i have to
make a decision right now
so wufan reference link file let's say h
because
h in html that is uh
that is the um you know that is the key
so
if we do edge that's most consistent so
h
and the volatic so now but if we have
if we give this edge then uh what the
dark lookup will be
t
okay but now what about predefined code
okay so uh predefined code
p okay so we change a bunch of keys
okay that that that that okay evaluate
the whole
file close it
go open the text file close it reopen
now oh actually that is in
wait okay we got
some issue here because this command
wufram reference linkify it
actually generates a html you know it's
actually part of the html mod
it has nothing to do with the wolfram
language source code
so so this function
shouldn't be here so this function
should be should be
inside html mod okay
yeah okay so yeah that is true so let's
let's um
yeah we got we got lots of things to do
so
okay comments comments
okay this this is getting boring i think
okay so this should be named site shaman
wufang language link if i
cut then go to html mod
describe key space space space
h then jump to the html mod source code
then list matching lines linker file
then we got all lines that contains
word linkify so you can see there are a
lot of
different linkify commands so
uh css linkify javascript link of
youtube linkify amazon linkify so
[Music]
so so where is the amazon link linkify
source code
right here okay so let's jump to it
and we're gonna put the code about right
here okay
paste it here so now we have
some html reflective file
okay so this is inside html mod
uh and remove the what is this
anyway so so so so we have that
and we need a key okay so let's search
for
to let's go to the key section
to see if there's a key there's no key
okay
uh but there is any link of file
so
let's put it here okay
so let me explain what's going on so
there is a
general command size html any linkify
that turns a url into a html link
now however for different link different
type of
sites you may want a different format
of the link for example may you know if
you are
if you have a wikipedia url you know you
can make it a link but the link text
usually you just want the words like you
know
america you know the article
let's say president lincoln lincoln you
know an article about lincoln you just
want the word lincoln instead of the
full uil to click on
so and for css file you
basically you want uh you know you know
so different so audio files video files
youtube files youtube links
you for in the case of youtube you want
the link to be a embedded video usually
not just a you know youtube something
something so
so you have all these several uh so this
any linkify
we'll look at the url see what it is
then
call the appropriate command to to make
the
right format link so now we're gonna add
this roof i'm linkify so
go to the amazon check uh part
so we're gonna add so here it is okay
so you see you see this section
it checks for the amazon link check if
the link is amazon so let's copy it
so in this case we're gonna check
um so what is the wolfram uh
language link so let's go to let's now
we need to find what's the wolfram
language
link okay so here is the format of wufan
yeah okay so you check for basically
yeah okay
so you check for that
dot com okay slash dot com okay
so if you if you see that that's a
wufang language url
then you call
okay so fantastic
i think it's it's this is correct yes
yes yes
okay now we just go up we need to change
the
the version date we we modified it so
put a date here
okay save it
so that's uh let's let's make it one
window okay
shrink so that is html any link of i we
okay now evaluate the code so we can
uh evaluate the code now now let's go
back to talk show let's
try if it works so for example
here is the url let's go to it
there it is wufang language reference
website
okay so now we want to link a file so
call any link of i so symbols function
definition is void okay we forgot to
evaluate that
um okay let's go back to the html
so let's go to ufram we forgot to
evaluate the code so evaluate this part
and and define and evaluate
wufang language reference linkify that's
right evaluate
it now we do it fantastic okay
arrow
what's uh
okay so this
okay so actually i made a mistake again
such
so this function actually
you know this function
actually what does do is that if you
have a wolfram language
keyword like that you call it
you call this function okay what's the
name okay
you call this function because i will
find reflective i
it turns a word into a link so i made a
mistake so this function should rename
let's rename it
uh yeah so this function actually should
be this
what to link
yeah so this should be html too so
html will find words to link
will find words to link
okay so that is actually
what this should be okay what to link
now we need to to write another
command to actually linkify
okay we uh it's taking too long so
there's no comments okay so ms you're
going
yes i've been talking for how long
video check audio check i've been
talking
for
one hour okay i gotta go in
in soon so
so what to link that's right what to
link
um you need to give it a key
so
so let's jump to the key map section
what linker file let's give it a random
key now
so uh
because you have i have to think a lot
about what keys to
to give so because there are already
lots of other keys
for html so beside html i will find word
to link
you you know this command is rarely used
especially for other people for me i use
it sometimes but for other people you
probably don't use it
so this is a command that
usually you don't need a key but however
i have found out over the past 10 years
of key binding
study that even
if a command is rarely used it is always
better to give
every command a key okay just give it a
random like
a long key okay so why
because because
when people do want to use it they have
a key and if you don't need you know if
you don't use
this command often that's okay too so
so you want a key okay so for now let's
just
uh so what what key should i give this
i don't know so let's just say random
okay
so i can remind myself to maybe change
it later so
so it's going to be leader uw for
wolfram world to link okay
it's just random okay it's uh
it's uh
should it be you or
okay let's let's make it i okay
so iw okay okay
so evaluate this part go to the
go to the function evaluate the function
now we need to
fix
the function we wrote before
you know this woofer and reference link
of five we need to actually write it
okay so let's write it
go back to the previous position yeah
let's write this
let's write this command wolfram
reference linkify okay
so first of all uh
copy it maybe we can copy it so
so some wolfram reference linkify so
make
uh current make
current link to woofam language link so
to a
make a wolfram url
to wolfram link
okay something like that yeah i'm not
going to explain
details i mean gonna i mean i'm gonna do
the details
documentation later so make a url tool
from link so first of all you need to
get the
grab the url under the cursor okay so
how do you do that
uh how do you do that you are
look at the you know
look at my source code here okay
under this uh any linker file okay so
here is the source code copy it
so
so jump to the reference jump to the
code here
so we need we first of all we need to
grab the url so
here is the code that's too many uh
so if there's a region then reach a
beginning and an end
then otherwise you are trying to grab
the url okay
let that be let's just use that okay so
the point of this part is set the
position p1 and p2 that's the region
beginning that's a link beginning you
are
beginning and you are our end okay
then then what you need
uh p p 1 p 2 input okay
then okay p 1 p1p2
input okay that that grabs the url
then
oh god this this is the more
work than i expected because
let me show you what we need to do so
here is a url
so you want to make it so that uh let's
go to talk show and let me show you okay
let's go to talk show okay so
so you see here is a url but
what you want is
what you want is actually let me show
you okay
what you want is um
yeah what's it uh
it's changed so much
i believe what you want is this okay i
don't know let me
let me let me see yeah okay so we
actually we have an example
here yeah
so you see this is url but this is the
end result
you want the face form just a word so
you need to actually
pass the url
but i have written you know i already
have the code somewhere so let's go
go go to it
so go to my emacs init directory so here
is the
html linkify a bunch of linkify commands
so we have so let's uh
these matching lines to see what
function are there
and
okay i deleted lots of them nks linkify
this is
wufam's new kind of science thing
uh and this is not
what
okay so let's go back to html file
html
i'm trying to find where i have the code
before
search for reference
okay so you can see here
i mean here open it
jump to it and we jump to the
on file
okay so let me just do it
i cannot i don't believe it i don't have
it so
so let's just go to
javascript
uh i'm trying to find
410 okay i need to go
okay i think it's kind of dead and
boring now
and i'm gonna quit i think
so most people left so i'm going to quit
now uh at least we finished two of the
commands today
yeah we finished two of the commands
today so
so let's look at um
lots of things i need to clean up so
let's look at some talk show
today's talk show so we want to write
three wolfram language functions we
finished two of them
there's one more the wolf i'm ref
linkify that
needs to be walked on but anyway
thank you guys for watching if you if
you like my stuff
buy myself donate okay it uh especially
the wolf i'm sorry
mod okay so for five dollars paypal me
and
and tell me and i'll send it to you
okay bye
you