good morning welcome to another episode
of Santos show I'm your host Solly and
today we are going to do some ving golf
with Emacs and sawfly keys and first of
all let's get the video chat let's get
the comments pop-up ready okay if you
are not familiar go to this URL and
there are a lot of topics just type a
topic in the comment I appreciate your
comments
you know just type them your opinions
comments or and pick a topic and I will
talk about that so let's pop this out
and we are going to do some vim golf
on-the-fly impromptu extempore without
preparation that is using soft Frankie's
you know yesterday I saw a reddit post
on Emacs ready to Emacs and people are
saying you know I like to switch to
Emacs but you know but but it doesn't
seems to be efficient then him and that
post was like 20 days ago you know
several weeks ago and that's nonsense
you know let me show you exactly keys
okay first of all with Emacs when you
are running Emacs okay you can you know
you can change your keys now if you are
using the Emacs default keys then it is
true it's no good it's very inefficient
far worse than vim okay far worse it's
like twice's words okay like for example
if you your normal day average you know
coding doing whatever in your editor if
you are using if you are using vim
compared to if you are using Emacs the
keystrokes for if you are using Emacs
will be twice at least twice as much
then if you are using vim okay for the
same same task you are doing that is
when you are using the default Emacs
keys however Emacs you can use the evil
mod which is which is a key binding
system based on VIN so basically you are
using Emacs like the way you are using
vim
so if you are using evil mod you know
the theme emulation then it's like it's
just like vim okay so there is no
English and see there's no such nonsense
that new max is not efficient now that's
using evil mod okay you if you are new
to Emacs try it okay especially if you
are being user before now there is a
cough like keys which is which is a
package I created okay so it's it's it's
efficient key binding system it's even
more efficient than them okay doesn't
matter it's evil mod or vim okay it's
more vision than V more neon dream or
whatever and I'm going to show you so
today I'm going to go to the e go to the
van Gogh website and let's see what we
can you know demonstrate you know just I
haven't went there before you know well
I went there you know like a month ago
and anyway the point is I'm not prepared
so let's see what we're gonna find you
know I'm just going to do some think of
problems with sapphire keys okay so we
got two people watching now you know
type something here and say you know to
say put your comments and opinions and
you know say hi so let's go to first of
all let's go to software keys supply
okay
something like he's sorry profile okay
let me going to show you the website
okay
actually let's let's let's do that so
you know saw flag keys in case you know
if you are not familiar with what it is
now if you have been watching my videos
I'm pretty sure you're familiar because
I've been using it you know every day
you know in my videos so there it is
stuff like keys now basically it's you
know it's a key binding for Emax and
it's modal meaning it's like you know
it's like limits where you have insert
mod and command mod you know you have to
switch between the two and however the
difference is that the V key binding VI
key binding is agent I mean it's kind of
you know it's backward compatible it's
evolutionary you know it's the choices
of keys you know for the commands is
kind of historical evolved from history
while the Suffolk is the key choices are
based on economics based on statistics
of command frequency and the ease of
pressing keys basically the most used
commands have the most easy keys for
example easy case meaning the home row
keys oh you know whatever you know or
whatever keys type typed by your index
and pointing fingers and middle finger
fingers okay hi good morning green deck
so let's go to so green deck are you
know you are Emacs user for sure now are
you using Eva mod or are you using Emacs
default key binding or are you using you
know software keys or some other so
we're gonna let's go to link off let's
start to demonstrate link off okay
I'm gonna beat the hell out of them I'm
gonna demonstrate with stuff like ease
okay think of real limb ninjas count
every keystroke yeah sure and I'm gonna
show you with soft like kissing Emacs
I'm gonna have less keystrokes than you
I don't know
you know let's see if we can do that now
do they require a JavaScript probably
that's okay I have JavaScript I'm
already you are using sulfa keys yay
okay think of here we have let's see if
we have this window okay I suppose the
window must be to the left a little bit
so you guys can see yeah
okay wrinkles now let's see what they
want think of okay we ovum ninjas count
every keystroke that mean just ninja my
ass good morning Justin what's up so we
gonna doing a demonstration of stuff
like using Emacs doing van Gogh so I
haven't prepared wait let me make them
fight so let's let's begin oh we got a
Justin Bieber fan okay okay wait I'm
getting old so I need two big texts I
cannot see any more so let's see open
wing of challenges box it 1192 entries
create a box around a line I don't
like that one okay but you know let's
just see okay so we got that and we want
it to be that hmm first of all let me
copy that copy and paste into Emacs and
on the left side you can see all the
Emacs I call for example iku so you can
see the command I call and you can also
see the key I'm pressing by the way I'm
using
for a keyboard i mean i'm using a brad
key layout okay and I'm also using you
know this Kinesis keyboard okay this is
the best keyboard $300 okay go go buy
for my website I have a tutorial sorry
okay so I'm using this keyboard and I'm
using a variety board layout okay you
can go read my tutorial I have a
complete review of it including video
showing you my typing on it and so on
you know if you like it buy it for my
website support me okay
now let's go back to Van Gogh so we okay
close this okay let's begin then let's
try this one new buffer paste okay so
what we want to do is to make lick let's
magnify we want to turn this line into
that one okay let's do it
the first try okay now again you just
watch the left window it shows my keys
in command so basic paste it and okay so
you want to okay well first of all I
need to know how many how many
characters are there so does
I hope supposing this doesn't count
count words so they are 31 characters
okay
now let's begin let's create actually
create a new buffer so starting with
that alright so I suppose the cursor is
beginning at the beginning they didn't
specify where does the kusa begin so
well so let's just that okay so let's
begin counting the keys now you count
okay at that that that 31 that
that coffee that that that that that
that that okay something's wrong here
wait okay i-it's not 30s he's actually
30 not 31 okay so how many keys did was
that let's try it again okay let's try
it again so new buffer paste so
beginning we begin with that okay now
let me stop so let me count the keys 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15
okay 15 key keys
let's see what what these people haha
20 what you guys failed okay great
victory victory Forks off like his score
one okay great quick tag says I thought
about using you Ahmad but I'm not very
experienced limb users so I thought I'd
better learn and get used to more
efficiently running like you us thank
you great so we did one we are gloating
over it first victory okay let's let's
go back let's try the next one
open wing Golf Challenge challenge parks
it so so so so let's maybe documented so
stuff like he is 15 vim being 21 21 okay
let's put the line let's save it
maybe in golf huh okay so it's hold on
second
okay so that's one let's go back here we
don't need that they want to save no
let's see close that close that okay we
got this is the first problem let's go
to the next problem
so Justin Bieber says victory just
Justin Bieber says is that because you
use the weird keyboard or is it because
of Emacs well it's because Emacs and
because of like soft like keys now I
assume you are new to Emacs the
situation were Emacs you know if you use
Emacs default keys you know basically
Sophocles is a package that provides you
a alternative key binding for Emacs so
and these key binding choices are
efficient you know so that that is why
you know it's just 21 keys I mean you
know that you know 15 so anyway let's
try the simple format the next problem
simple format make it look better
okay so this problem is real okay pick a
chat pick a challenge
fire up dream and show us what you got
simple format so make it look better so
start with lease and woo this one is
okay let's copy that copy switch back to
Emacs so here is the second problem
let's see okay start fire end fire
so we basically we want to align them
along the colon
okay I'm not sure how to do that but you
know we're gonna see
okay no I think the command is a Emacs
command called a line text okay now I
have an option of looking at looking it
up first
but that's not you know let's try to be
natural and you know let's try to find
out it didn't you know so okay so so
start we're gonna do that let's see okay
we want to be like that so let's begin
so MX a line okay that's not it
okay let's start over MX a lie rejects
okay and let's put a colon okay that's
probably probably because I don't have a
selection let's try it again selected MX
my rejects and rejects that okay that's
not what we want
hmm okay I don't like this problem oh
wait actually they also add the they
also need to add the crops okay that's
interesting so you also need to add
quotes then okay they are two actually
there are two I would group them into
two problems one is adding a quote y is
aligned along the colon now for the
quote it's not it's it's easy okay let
me show it states to it okay because I
have this command okay start we caught
Marco key Marco one two three okay start
it that's the key mark well
okay well let's start again start
recorder key mark we'll move it one line
and do that that's good then
stop key mark well then select go to the
button go to the button that then apply
marco to regionalize okay yeah I missed
the first one so let's let's start again
shall we
I mean we're gonna do this simple try so
I guess okay so let's try again I'm not
going to read them you know you just
look at the left and you you can see
what the command I'm coding okay it's
not chemical that in submarine then that
that that that that that that okay and
that okay so basically that's one
problem solved you know six keys or
seven keys and okay the next problem is
to align now I don't know how to do it
offhand aligned rejects so I think the
solution is aligned with checks but
okay let's try that now okay we have to
look look it up oh these people are
doing 20 20 Keys or 20 commands rather
now are those keys of commands okay
anyway so let's go to sorry
Emacs lie okay it's such I have written
a tutorial about alignment align text
well the issue right now is you know the
align align rejects I'm pretty sure
that's a command so we have to read you
know exactly the regular expression what
to use groups spacing repeat so for
example finding a region
well let's let's just try to read my my
tutorial about about it
a lion rejects to align text for example
that becomes that okay and problem that
okay so we have this situation and we
want to align like that so what you do
is
OOP and these these commands are you
know usually okay let's read some
comments
wait wait if I read comments would that
be considered cheating because let me
just try it a little bit okay online
rejects so we basically have two
problems let's go back to so the online
rejects okay so we need to do a control
selected control you for universal
argument then Co allowing rejects then
complex online using regular expression
okay no that's nothing
yeah so the situation now is that we
actually really have to understand about
the command alive rejects in order to do
these so let me just look at what I did
here quickly so choose the group so zero
to nine so anything in space zero to
nine including coma okay so we give an
argument of regular expression and in
this regular expression we have one
group which is this part and this group
supposed to capture these these numbers
okay
then after the group then it matches
anything as suppose that is the KN part
okay then we choose negative one for
group
why do we choose negative one for
grouping here's what it means right okay
then Jason I should a-hole
okay so let's so I kind of get I kind of
I have some kind of idea so let's try it
again control you wait let me get show
the window okay and I'm gonna read the
commenting a bit so control you online
rejects okay and the regular expression
I want to use is I don't want the
defaults I want
okay so we want a to z oops
wait a minute
a to Z okay a to z one no mole
wait actually let's just try these that
okay then justify if negative
yes so negative one okay amount of
spacing or column if negative one
repeat through out lies yes so let's do
it again
yeah okay this one is that fail okay let
me read the comments you know one
problem with Van Gogh is that you know
you have to like there is no time limit
you know actually it makes sense to
actually have time time limit because
you know if we want the wim hof test as
some kind of a test to show efficiency
or superiority of the editor okay you
should have a time limit because that
prevent people from spending for example
right now I can spend the whole day you
know to figure out about the align
rejects command you know the syntax I
spend a whole day to figure it out
then I then I create you know I do the I
solve the problem like in fact
keystrokes okay that's kind of cheating
you really have a you really need a
timestamp or kind of a time time you
know limit because that way then
whoever's got the best answer you know
shortest number of keystrokes plus the
shortest some kind of a time limit okay
not necessarily timed you know somehow a
time limit then we know you know these
are answers such that people can
instantaneously not by you know go back
to read the manuals for an hour and find
out you know you know read old a whole
menu and you find out which way is the
least amount of keystrokes you know
because this way once you have a time
limit then it indicates you know for
certain problem it indicates oh so you
know this problem all the people can
actually solve it you know just we think
let's say five minutes you know instead
of you know spending hours you know
because a lot of this think of solutions
you know I know that they you know these
are nerds right they all spend you know
they try to find the best way to spend
hours or flight then you do the problem
so like right now like right now I'm
stuck with it so you know if I'm going
to actually if if it's a time limit then
then actually I'm just starting to you
know manually align them you know
actually that is actually faster than
then me going to read up about line
rejects command because this command is
fairly complex and you you also have to
actually understand regular expression
which a lot of programmers do not
necessarily know it well you know that's
actually that's true so do we take the
do we count you know the time to
understand regular expression it
literally can take years I mean it's
because regular expression is actually
really fairly complex you know it can
take years to actually understand what
they are so anyways so this problem I
kind of sucked let's say so let me read
comments okay victory is that so break
the loop good morning break the loop
there is a really cool vintage called
vim Adventures I used it to learn vim
keystrokes it costs $25 I consider it
worth it if you want to learn how to use
vim
okay that's not for me I'm gonna use me
I'm gonna use emacs and Sophocles of
course Justin Bieber says okay so it's
really optimized thanks for explaining
Simpa thank you so same senpai that's a
Japanese word you know actually I didn't
know what it means but it's it's it's
kind of it means like like instructor or
something like you know supposed to
sensei which is which actually means
teacher where a teacher is the sensei is
more more senior then same PI something
like that anyway since Empire is
becoming popular word what community is
same type of hero I mean where did when
I mean I'm pretty sure it's knew like
within the last 10 years of five so but
what community is it gaming community
that would spread so Thomas Ward says
hello hello hello hello good morning
Isaac so Thomas Ward says he just found
something okay shut up that's you know
it's not good to talk about that here
okay let's let's try another thing go
thin Oh so same pie is from anime
community okay so let's try another one
one number per line actually wait wait
hold on a second hold on a second let me
just finish this because these people
got you know these people simple format
okay these people got 20 lines 20 year
keystrokes I'm pretty sure I can beat it
without actually using a library friggin
rejects because they are only like 10
lines here okay let's try it then okay
let's do it one two three
actually actually let's see
okay so keyboard start macro you know
the default binding actually there is f2
is the default binding I removed it
because you know okay let's try it
forget it you know I you know by default
the start marker and in marker has keys
I believe it's f3 and f4 but however for
me each one of them is 3 keys because I
want to use f3 and f4 for other purposes
therefore if I'm going to use you know
code Khmer Samarco I'm going to have
penalty or more keys so what I can do
for example keyboard yeah you know go to
my keyboard definition let's search for
f3 you see excuse me I have you know
these said to my own definitions that is
why maybe I can now that's not let's not
remove them it's let's just do it ok so
some way down ok new buffer
okay let's speaking start keyboard macro
and
okay and
did ha okay
okay so that's that's it that's done
let's see one two one two okay I
actually need just two okay so I don't
think I used many keystrokes so let's
read the comments
weeps anime community hi good morning
Danielle I went out last night got drunk
M I am hungover
maybe funk okay
DeYoung good morning Deon good job thank
you
so anyway that that is that is the it
let me do it again okay now you guys can
count keystrokes okay let's see let's
see how many keystroke I actually used
to do this so let's start over again
let's let's start that one two three
four
five six actually next don't do that
well six seven eight nine ten eleven
actually that's that's cheating but
anyway eleven then actually I should
have it like that
you remand and for Team v King
yeah anyway so that you know it's kind
of yeah anyway so seventeen so they they
have twenty I think it's about the same
actually my my solution yeah I think
it's less so anyway so that's that the
problem so close that let's do another
one so yeah so let's do another one I
would say equal okay I would say with
stuff like he sees is about equal to
twenty keystrokes now let's do another
one so let me read the comments so by
the way I heard you said some some kind
of keying America is called chai is this
a Chinese word because tea in Russia is
chai yeah it's well the the thing is the
Chinese word for tea is cha ok let me
say it again
ha actually let me type it
you have to wait a little bit oh wait
Ping's simplified previously profile
yeah okay so that's the character so
that's pronounced hold on a second so
that's pronounced that second second
ton ha and but in I think in Vienna most
certain Asia they they call chai you
know basically it's a transliteration of
Chinese so in shock
sighing Chinese becomes chai or
something similar in Vietnamese or
something and then then American
transliterated from that that's that's
why yeah yes yes yes exactly right so in
India chai is not a flavor of tea it is
T child literally translate to tea in
Hindi okay so therefore I guess you
should never use the phrase chai tea
yeah this knowing America in Starbucks
they just call it chai they also have a
drink called tea but again you know it's
just cooperate trying to create you know
novel new words you know to attract
customers so let's try another wing
Goethe in Emacs email scam for what does
that mean so yeah let's try another wink
wink of so simple format we did this one
and remove lines containing word
containing the word reader okay start
file and file this is this is so trivial
let's copy it copy it so paste it here
reader not read okay in fire so we want
to begin from that too
so new buffer new buffered remove the
word that removed lines continue oh
that's so simple that's so trivial
so we go here so wait wait wait a second
me show so cool
wait Oh delete delete matching lies okay
flash lines containing match type reader
done okay so that's that's for me it's
like two commands or or for keystrokes
yeah so so let's see what they have the
nine keystrokes I wing for keystroke so
they got like keystrokes
ding so okay let's try another vein then
go back to him go and maybe is there a
difficult one or something are they
ordered in particular way
let's see wait are you guys still
interested in Wingo for stuff like you
guys are chatting about chai
okay Cree and group let's try these two
pairs of clusters of letters creates
word so this problem is two pairs two
pairs of clusters of letters okay two
pairs creates what what does it mean
okay start fire is this one let's copy
it cuz that okay then let's paste the
problem here so start with that end file
okay let's see
okay the title actually is not a
description of the problem rather the
title is a just a easy memorization of
the result you know just serving as a
hint of the result so anyway so you
start with that and you want to end up
with that so what is so I suppose it
deletes or okay basically deletes all
quotes and and also removes or coma
basically removes yeah it is so simple
is this is too simple okay new buffer
pasted here okay
then query replaced let's try a query
replace apostrophe comma space ' dad dad
wait wait wait wait a second
parry replace apostrophe comma space
coma enter replace with space enter pan
to replace all
okay so oh it actually wants okay so we
want first of all let's see what exactly
is involved so some of these let's see
so some of these okay so that you want
to remove then Harris they also you want
to remove that then
okay let's just let me just try it then
first a little incest
okay so it's actually so it's kind of
confusing because you don't know so
let's analyze the problem again you know
in real life you know when in real life
when you want to do this you don't you
know you just you know whatever it's the
first method you just do it then you try
to basically evolve step by step towards
the solution you do not you know like
what we are doing now is you know like
analyze the problem and find out the
most efficient way
like when command or to commence to do
it so that's kind of the problem with
mingle
you know again like I said it really
should have a time limit now we don't
necessarily want wanted to be scored by
timing like how fast you can do it
because if you score by timing then
there's a question of you know who can
type faster you know if I can type
faster than you I win you know but but
that's not fair because what we really
want to do is actually to find out the
efficiency of the editor not you know
not the persons in reaction time you
know young people will type faster and
so on so but it so it should be have a
time limit you know for anyway so so
this probably exactly so first of all we
know that this needs to be replaced by
empty space okay
needs to be replaced by empty then remem
needs to be removed replaced by okay
some of them becomes empty some of them
becomes newline
yeah some of them is empty some of them
is newline now is a is there a pattern
so this is empty again this is a new
line this this is empty way
so anyway so so this this is new line
crossed empty so let's find out oh okay
so all of you know
' comma apostrophe needs to be no that's
not true because some of them actually
needs to be new line okay so we have a
situation where okay let's do this thing
let's do this so copy that wait let's
see okay so first of all let's speaking
clearly place
' entered replaced by nothing pen
replace all then go to the beginning of
the map the of the line clearly replace
again comma space
replaced by
new line okay enter No
okay that's a bit of way we place coma
by new line okay do it for then
this is a stupid problem there's no
okay the thing is I'm just like not sure
what to do you know like like you know
what should I like continue to figure
out a pattern or should I just like do
it
so it's alternating so T on say is okay
so the new line is alternating it's no
okay okay so let me read anyway so the
problem is in decision because now I'm
thinking of reading a comment first but
then that becomes cheating base almost
so let me just work out work this out
then just with it push it to so so wait
so I just replaced replace comma by
empty okay no no yes No
and there's no pattern it's annoying no
yeah there's really no pattern well if
there's a pattern it's rather
complicated so so it's actually easier
if you just go through them manually no
no no you see so first of all so some of
them is like that then then repairs
comma space by by empty yes no no yes no
yes no yes no yes no then do it again
I forgot that one and what's stupid
problem how many how many keystrokes
they have 17 so do you guys know are
they counting keystrokes or the
accounting commands well it's a bit
complex because then if you are counting
commands then well I don't know so I
suppose they are counting keystrokes 17
keystrokes let's start over again
replace comma space by new line okay
just do it then go to the top three face
' by empty do it go to the top three
face coma by empty yes no yes yes wait
we got the arrow here creates let's try
it again
three pace
should I replace apostrophe first or not
let's do it replace ' by nothing do it
go to the beginning replace coma
we face coma by it's just the face coma
by space okay wait let's replace coma by
nothing do it no that's not right
because look at the f Krista look at
here it's not right so we paste coma by
space do it then we place one two one
two this is painful
yeah I don't know because you know when
I'm doing video I'll try I want to try
to you know not for being protracted you
know and wasting a lot of time so I've
been talking for 15 minutes so what what
is the so what is the answer guys I woke
in Starbucks good company but crab
coffee chai chai tea latte good company
but crap coffee can he make scan for
okay the neo says I drank I drank a
bunch of Pabst Blue Ribbon last night
but it's the part that really knocked me
for a loop
I don't know Adi talking about link of
blood
Isaac's a stand very nice and kind of
the on offense of using classified keys
just because I want to learn how to
create my own set of keys haha but maybe
I should try out yeah well I mean you
know I don't want to you know you know I
don't want to discourage people you know
not you know I don't want to say oh you
just try Mikey you know Giovanni but
actually that you know that's a lot work
I mean the the bulk of the work in
Suffolk is you know it's not just
defining keys I mean so so one part is
the technicality of learning
to program peace in emacs okay but the
other part that actually took me several
years you know because I've been working
on the efficiency thing for like over
ten years that is actually the more the
more critical the more important the
more valuable that's what I did I know
if I may say so so so you know so a
number like if you want to goof with
something for the heck of it but I admit
I'm in the middle of goofing with
learning work first comma becomes empty
second becomes newline okay so this
problem is nasty
I mean you because there's no first
comma becomes empty the second comma
becomes newline so first of all a long
second first comma becomes empty okay
yes no oh yes that's not true you know
these supposed to be no but actually
it's yes so it's not I don't think it's
alternating yes no yes no okay so it
actually is alternating yes no wait yes
no okay yes no okay yes
no okay yes No okay so there is a
pattern so good thank you so let's do
very query we paste rejects then comma
and question mark coma and actually dot
replace it by empty okay yes no yes no
yes no yes no yes no yes no yes no yes
okay thank you thank you thank you
I was idea let's see yeah do so okay
there's a pattern then after you do
after you do that then basically yeah
it's annoying you know then then you
replace all space by empty okay
then you'll be face or coma by that okay
so let's thank you Dion so we got a tip
you know after analysis we got the most
efficient way let's let's try one more
time so first of all replace so let me
count one two three four five six seven
eight
comma dot okay
eight eight nine ten replaced by nothing
okay 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22
23 24 25 26 then 27 28 wait 28:20 28 29
30 31 32 33 34 okay so actually there's
a mistake you should be T because I
should use the rejects comma space
instead anyway
kind of 30 34 depending on how you count
so what what what is there 17 okay okay
I can see that well yeah I can see that
that's they wing but you know but maybe
maybe there's a better way but you know
one of the problem because then you know
I can't figure out you know what and
analyze the situation okay I think
that's it for the Minkoff because I you
know we demonstrated maybe we should do
more actually you know but we did three
I think that's enough to get people some
idea of you know how it is Sophocles so
let's see the comments
so if you have comments that's you know
type it then you know we've been talking
about phone already usually one hour is
the easy mark you know we might end it
so let's see what what comments so the
new says learn were ranked by the way
you know borax is very efficient I mean
I talked about this before sorry
Borak okay I talked about this before in
my previous talk show so I have this
article like there are five articles
about Borak keyboard layout and it
answers anything everything you want it
you ever wanted to know about Barack now
is it are you going to type faster if
you love Iraq are you going to what are
the issues and so on okay you know you
can just you know read for my website
and you are not going to be faster with
Laura okay also I mean you are not going
to type faster if you already touch type
korte and also there are certain
inconveniences because everywhere you go
in public to the library using your
friend's computer using your co-workers
computer there's a problem of switching
keybinding I mean you have to I mean
although it's not difficult but you have
to do it but you cannot do it in
libraries or any public places so there
are these little issues but it doesn't
really make you faster and it does not
actually save if you have hand pain for
repetitive strain injury Iraq is not
doesn't really help in that way you what
really helps is a better keyboard you
know I have lots of articles you can
read here so what's a good what's the
deal above all right well it's it's
efficient it's actually more efficient
than Cote and it makes you typing more
comfortable so so but if you are
learning if you already touched on Cote
and you you are trying to learn more AK
let me affirm that it's going the
experience is going to be extremely
painful for at least one month use of I
mean assume you types you know you try
to learn it for one hour a day or two
it's going to be painful for at least
one month okay so because I had the
experience in 1994 okay so so anyway you
can check out my children you know my a
bunch of essays about all about Barack
you ever wanted to know and by the way
there is no problem of using barracking
Emacs because I learned work layout in
1994 I was a touch-type since 1987
somewhere around there okay so I learned
I learned back in 1994 and I I start to
use Emacs in 1998 so by the time I use
Emacs it's all Florrick I never I never
have you know try to use Emacs ink with
the quality experience so and I didn't
find a problem you know there's really
no problem with about that I mean that's
one of the frequently asked question so
anyway and especially if you use Safra
keys you know because I'm using Borak
I'm using software keys so it's good for
you
so okay can you explain the benefits of
your keyboard okay yeah let's do that
well I did the explain you know I did
explain a lot you know a a few times in
my videos but you know why not
so if you just go to my oh go Emacs page
let's see if I can show you the screen
yeah so you know I have this article you
can read all about it and basically if
you don't know you know basically this
is ergonomic keyboard you know it's it's
the most advanced economics eboard so so
you see so one okay so first so okay let
me just go over for one minute so first
of all
the key sections are split so you don't
have to like put your both of your hand
in the middle like normally a keyboard
like you have to put your hand in the
middle and and and your your wrist tends
to be like that because you know they
are all in the middle so you tends to be
like that so this is split you know
meaning my hand you know if you look at
my arm you know it's it's like a
straight line you know I don't have to
bend this way I don't have to pin that
way okay so it's it's straight and you
can also see the keys are straight you
know that is let's see yeah you see the
keys are straight so you my fingers move
up down instead of you know no more
keyboard
it's like scented you know weird way I
explained that in my website you can see
the keyboard design section and you can
see design flaws you know the reason our
keyboard is like that because of history
I mean it's so historic historical
package and people are you know used to
it by habit like then suddenly if you
change things people don't like it
that's that is why we are stuck we are
stuck with this traditional PC keyboard
it's it came from the mechanical
typewriter Ciccio this is the shift key
everything basically everything came
from habit of using you know like back
then a hundred years ago 200 years ago
you have typewriters mechanical
typewriters and people get used to that
then we started to have computers you
know in 1950s also and people want to
stay with you know your lectric you know
first of all we have much mechanical
typewriters then we have electric
typewriters people get used to it used
to it you know if you watch this video
it shows you can see a lot history I
mean you can see oh why we press the tab
key you know what you know it doesn't
make sense today but it it is that way
because you know because of history then
you have that's why you have the tab key
and the shift key and why is it called
shift
shift key is called shift key because it
actually shift all the gears under the
typewriter
you know like shift them so you know
like move to a different position so
that when you type you know different
keys strikes out there the capital
letters
but anyway so it's all history but
people get used to that so once you
design your computer keyboard people
tries to make it just like you know a
typewriter that's how you sell it
because if you have something new people
don't want it you know thank you no
that's our habit as well it applies to
programming languages as well applies to
lots of things because habit is very
strong and and actually it's habit is is
habit kind of governs efficiency I mean
because if we already know something you
know maybe a programming language or
muscle memory or the way we do with some
things you know driving to work or
whatever whatever you know there's a
habit you know we we have muscle memory
we already know it we know how to do it
we understand it but suppose there's a
new invention with new new technology
but but it's but you but it's kind of
new in all ways that you have to like
learn it for a week even though it's you
know extremely ultimately is more
efficient you know but people don't want
it first of all you have to spend one
month to learn it you know that's that's
the time train it's like full rack you
know that Verbeck is the same situation
you know you are already used to quote
it and if you don't really type that
much you know if you don't have hand
problems it looks fine
you know it works fine for your mom your
pet your parents your grandpa you know
you know you don't really type that much
like how much you actually type that's
the important thing so but if you
actually do type A Lot then it's a it's
a issue so then you want varrock and you
know other things you know so so yeah so
the way the the reason we have the
keyboard the way they are lots of
lots of you know almost every detail is
due to history it's not because design
you know efficiency of design none of
that is okay so so so that's that is why
people have designed these ergonomic
keyboard is Kinesis advantage so first
of all you see you first of always split
apart for two hands so you don't have
you know like you know like a normal
keyboard typically your hand hits like
they are very close so you have this
spending called code let's see what it's
called there's a name you know the the
doctors they have a name for it owner
deviation and also pronation is this
called unit deviation so first of all
it's you know wide apart so then you
have then you have tip so like a normal
keyboard like if you put your normal
keyboard typically is you know this is
your desk and you know you have to bend
up because the keyboard you know there's
certain thickness and was is that people
have a habit to prop up the back legs of
the key that's actually was you don't
want to do that so on this Kinesis
keyboard you don't have that problem
because let me show you so you see I put
my hands so you see actually it kind of
like let's see if I can see you see it
dips in the key is actually tip in so if
I my head let's see my hand you see you
see the key actually tip in so I don't
have like pinned up so I'm actually
using a tower for wrist pad but I don't
have to but you know if I just let's see
place my hand you see the fingers tip
tipping so I don't I don't have to like
paint up like that so that's another
advantage then another advantage is that
the keys are aligned straight up you
know like a grid so so you don't have to
you don't have this slant you know by
the way you know slant
again this the slant is due to history
history you know because you might be
wondering why are the keys you know
slanted in a regular way by the way you
know they are not really regular because
it's not like they are regular like a
honeycomb or something like that but you
know the reason they are slanted that
way because you see the boss under the
key those paths needs to be equidistant
to each other for the key becomes landed
in this way so that's the history of it
okay I think that's about it today
because we've been talking for 70
minutes let me read the comments okay so
I hope that's a good introduction I mean
the you know introduction to the Kinesis
so you know on this page you have videos
you know you can you can read and you
can watch a video if you like it buy
from my website okay you know support my
work okay so let's see let me read a
comment and dr maya green and kam Fong
that's one of the focal area pairs of
words oh okay now I get it so that wink
of problem it's pair of words okay so it
was yes so yeah I should have known that
it so that implies alternating I'm
pretty sure I can do a better job with
that but you know but again the problem
becomes analyzing the problem like I
have to first of all spend like five
minutes to analyze you know carefully
analyze the problem and do many several
tries then actually you know do it and
with the least minimal count of
keystrokes or minimal count of commands
and that's no good because the time you
spent analyzing the problem it really
should be part of the problem so they
why I say you should have a time limit
because then it's more realistic let's
see where is the problem
yeah okay so two pairs of clusters of
letters creates a word okay yeah that
makes sense so it's kind of alternating
so if we do it yeah I'm very short yeah
so they got 17 anyway so TM MVP MVP is
what is the we did at night gag what you
guys talking about
not too much night gig sorry night gig
what does I mean so how do you stick to
Emacs three did you jump between text
editors Oh backing okay so I started I
used so in 1990s the most popular editor
on the Mac is called BBEdit okay and
there's a large history to that okay so
BB edit that is kind of the hip editor
you know the it's a text editor okay you
can go really quickly pedia and it's in
in throughout 1990s it's the most hip
you know the popular editor on the Mac
and I was using a Mac most four 1990s
because anyway so so but I started to
get into industrial programming in 1998
most of 1990s I'm a math you know I'm
big I'm trying I'm a mess
I mean I'm you know I'm trying to be a
mathematician okay oh my you know
cramping climbing the ladder to become a
math professor so something like that so
anyway I was using BBEdit and on the Mac
and I'm not you know I don't know
nothing about programming but anyway in
1998 I started to do industrial
programming before that is it so
mathematic
Tomy Mathematica so industrial
programming so I started to I learned
about UNIX and then heard you know learn
about Emacs and that interests me
because I have always been interested
interested in this kind of a so-called
hacker community hack hacker type of
things you know UNIX and Emacs this kind
of non mainstream you know he think so
so I learned UNIX and so I read about
Emacs and I remember you know before the
first time I run into goo you know the
goo is not your next project and you
know free software foundation is
especially cool you know it's kind of
weird you know wait why do you have this
new thing I mean what is it like okay oh
it's a project what do you mean it's a
project you know then then they of
course there's a cop he left you know a
bunch of things right with Richard
Stallman but anyway so I was attracted
tracted to it so eventually of course
you read you know you slowly read them
all so I slowly you know I read you know
I then I understand you know what is to
know what is Emacs what is free software
foundation in fact back from 1998 to
like 2000 okay
mm - okay I have read everything
basically everything that's written by
Richard Stallman okay no kidding
everything that that that is available
on the web is the entirety of free
software foundation f F F fsf.org in
nineteen in let's say year 2000 whatever
page on there I have read and also Emacs
you know I was into reading manuals so
Emacs for example let's go to you know
Emacs menu so you see in this directory
there are lots of historical document
documents about Emacs let me show you
some interesting because these days
people don't know anymore because you
know
I'm now like you know I'm not like old
person you know I'm can I can I am like
talking history okay go up a directory
wait go to Emacs info I think it's info
okay
yah see info wave okay I don't think
this is the right directory so go up for
Derrick okay on the Mac I think on the
Mac the structure is a bit different
so go so in go up a directly okay let's
go to Emacs there's a Emacs act
directory okay here you can say act
directory and here you'll find a bunch
of historical kind of documentation
that's included with Emacs for example
let's look at this one interview okay
now you can see GUI is not Unix
conducted by David beds and John Edwards
Richard Stallman discusses his public
domain UNIX UNIX compatible software
system you know this is July 1986 okay
that's one example of old document and
then there's a jokes you know jokes file
then there is you know anyway back then
I read everything basically read
everything about free software
foundation about Richard Stallman and
about Emacs and I love you max because
the back then basically your option is
so as I said you know I'm very much into
the nerd the Gildan you know the UNIX
geeks so-called hackers community okay
so I read so I learned you know so you
have two options kind of like you have
VI okay back then this VIN but there's
several implementations of VI okay beam
is actually one of them and became
popular today but back then you have
evil you have Elvis okay and then and we
okay and VI itself as being implemented
a few times but with the same name VI
well anyway so we are so basically the
choices like VI or Emacs
back then and VI is no come you know I
despise I despise the UNIX ways the UNIX
philosophy I despise the VI VI is
typically the way the VI style me as
philosophy is kind of associated with
Unix
okay because you have you know it's just
like I mean it's a one of the component
of the Unix but Emacs on the other hand
is actually kind of like the opposite
okay yeah and also Emacs is using emag
bits okay this is considered also the
opposite of the UNIX system you have
lists machines okay now if you if you
are young you don't know you may not
know okay the the list machines and ITRC
you know the list machines community is
actually the in opposition of the UNIX
philosophy they they are like they are
on technical issues they are
philosophically on the opposite end
opposite ends you know the sea people
these people don't like to see people
sick I think the least people are stupid
it's kind of like that okay so you have
this war going on so I've read this you
know my opinion I always I'm always I'm
strongly on the list side ok on the eMac
side their philosophy their idea of how
things should be done ok I despise that
see the the UNIX C and the VI way as I
think the VI is the most idiotic
you know possible yeah I don't want it
you know say I want so that's why I
learned Emacs I choose Emacs and you
know pretty soon you know after a few
months I'm living it I'm living in Emacs
you know I've read the Emacs manual you
know the you know the the you know a lot
of it you know in a beginning
so I you know that you know I decided
Emacs is my is now I'm going to stick
with me max so I spend time to learn it
through early you know that's how I
become a you max user so I think that's
it fascinating debate about where I
pretty much nobody bothers with it but
Cody doesn't make any sense though yes
Justin Bieber says so that key ball
really helps a lot again his wrist pain
and stuff
it looks pretty alien yes good stream
thank you thank you do and senses came
he makes me ship with smaller than it is
no well you know there's no reason you
know you don't want to Emacs today is
about 200 megabytes but if you look at
others like atom and stuff you know
Microsoft Visual Basic or whatever they
are like they are like one chica died
you know so anyway I think that's it
today
any more questions questions so I by the
way if you have a question you've
probably already you know asked already
so no okay so see see you guys
so I see you guys thank you for coming
by prepare your questions okay type it
type it you know in you know watch my
videos type it in a comment box and
support me of course you know support me
I have patrons at you know PayPal if you
like my work put your money in there
okay thank you guys bye