episode of talk show bubblegum girl talk
show so today we are going to code emac
lisp and uh yeah emac LP and maybe
something random so you ask questions I
answer if you are here say hi if you are
not here you can play Skip around play
at speed 1.5 or something because I talk
a lot nonstop randomish so bubble gum
girl girl that's generated by Gro so
yesterday or the day before the last
episode we did we talked about the
artificial intelligence and the image
generation amazing and today you know
when you have a pretty girl girls is a
center of
humanity throughout history for example
if you look at artwor more than 50% is
girls and all naked girls from you know
100 years ago or from 10,000 or 1,000
years ago girls if you look at movie
posters if you have look at ads it's all
girls okay I mean majority are girls not
just women girls okay young girls young
beautiful pretty girls Center of
humanity why is that because it is girls
in the human species they make babies
okay that's the most important that is
why okay uh so in other words due to
biology every ad you see or on social
media for example today the zumers
generation social media YouTube
Instagram you know it's all girls they
predominate you know even on Tik Tok you
know so girls so Center of humanity you
know so and also for example if you have
look into artificial image
generation majority of them are girls
pretty girls hot
girls that is just a fact a fact of
nature okay uh uh okay so today you know
you are watching K talk show which I
talk about nerd stuff usually
programming technology artificial
intelligence information knowledge uh
you know sometimes physics although I
don't know much about physics and I talk
a lot about keyboards and stuff okay
fantastic now CH Ching thank you Chris
let me answer your question in a minute
so here's my keyboards glove 0 fantastic
search fori keyboard blog you'll find my
reviews and build lots of photos and uh
also video reviews of all my devices
gra8 ultimate hacking keyboard ultimate
and hacking hack it's favorite word from
the C C+ plus and Unix crowd hacking and
also from the Richard storman generation
the classic so new track B this video
review I did the the Logitech most
common
hyper uh hypers Spin and you know the
spin whe is fantastic
and I will start to uh play with this
yeah it's been delayed for too long this
is called swab board SV l b o a r d
fantastic device okay the most
advanced ergonomic input device press up
down left right and uh you got the mouse
button so I'll be using it I think I'm
going to start to uh do a video start to
play with it because I if I don't I
never get on so I'm just going to start
the live stream and and try to explore
and start to learn
it okay that's my keyboards now let's uh
Shall We Begin with emac this coding or
shall we start random
CH chat bab CH you know the YouTube
Super Chat they need to have the
chatbate sound like every time someone
pays you ching ching what was the
sound amazing thank you Chris Crystal G
most efficient
keyboard uh yeah I saw your question but
but that's I don't think that's
interesting uh what's the most
most efficient or ergonomic let's see uh
what is the most beautiful to be uh
cherished math
curve okay so let's ask work what is the
most ergonomic keyword
ergonomic you know let me tell you what
why I don't think this is interesting
because you I mean do you want image or
do you want text they are like two
different things so if you just want
text you know the answer to what is the
most ergonomic keyboard it's probably
giving you some Lim answer like the the
mass average ergonomic like Microsoft
ergonomic keyboard you know is not deep
so maybe you'll say that okay now if you
ask for image that's a different story
then it's probably going to generate an
image something looks like Microsoft
ergonomic keyboard
but let's ask it what's the most
ergonomic keyb
ask okay needs magnify the screen so let
me do magnify the
screen okay quite mouthful you know B so
answer determine the most economic
keyword can be subjective as it often
depends on individual needs preferences
and specific tasks when performs exactly
that's actually very good however ever
several keyboards are widely recognized
for their ergonomic design aimed at
reduce aimed at reducing strength and
improving typing
Comfort here are some of the most
commonly recommended ergonomic keyboards
as of my last update okay Microsoft
ergonomic keyboard oh fantastic this is
very excellent answer uh I was surprised
okay because GR
you know I I I usually it focus on news
um so anyway this is a very good uh
answer Microsoft ergonomic keyboard the
most common okay kesis freestyle Edge
RGB that's also very popular uh that's a
very good uh keyboard okay ogod do easy
that's also a fantastic keyboard now
this skull
touch let's get rid of that pop the
skull touch adjustable can you see my
screen yes okay yeah the go touch
adjustable economic keybo that's not so
good but that was the good one like 10
years ago uh 15 you know before let's
say before 200 10 go touch adjustable
economic keyboard you know uh then
Logitech ago
k860 uh I'm not sure what which one that
is a wave oh this is the worst [ __ ]
logic she Takeo
k860 let me show you pictures in a
moment okay that's the worst [ __ ] happy
hacking keyboard this
is this is also very popular but
personally I think it's [ __ ] it's the
worst expensive [ __ ]
possible okay so but it's a good answer
because happy hacking keyboard is has
been one of the most popular among the
elite keyboardists
let's say from 1990s to uh to up to
2015 okay because after
2015 you have erod DOS then you have the
entire do it yourself with 3D printing
technology on the horizon you know I
mean it it became popular so you have
lots of uh keyboards you know but happy
hacking is a classic Elite keyboard for
like 20 or 30 years happy happy hacking
keyboard okay and and then Ma has AO Pro
that's also a good
one you know but relatively good
one okay so it says when choosing an
very good answer oh this qu uh I'm
surprised okay great great uh
suggestion then it says when choosing an
ergonomic keyboard consider the
following let's see from an expert
eyes adjust stability okay how much can
you customize the keyboard to feed your
body okay yeah typing style some
keyboards might be better suited for
touch typist While others might be more
forgiving for those who look at the keys
that's true size and portability oh very
good answer very good criteria one of
the criteria for how to choose ergonomic
keyboard uh key feel amazing this is
this is in my opinion the most important
okay then software support yeah that's
also important so overall
gr I would rate gr's answer to this
question 99 yeah actually I'll give it
100 100 out of 100 Perfect
10 in Western speaking you say 10 you
don't say 100 Perfect 10 okay in Asian
speaking it's 100 100 is the top like
the Emoji okay now
um you know any anyway
so great um yeah okay let's digress into
keyboards so just search for S keyboards
and you'll
see uh you have trackable uh reviews I
updated a lot recently on track BS all
the track BS you want to know everything
you need to know about track BS and I'm
using newa okay so
anyway uh so yeah we want to look at
keyboards okay go back to S keyboard
guide and keyboard block oh we want to
look at ergonomic keyboard there it is
okay so you got oh yeah some of the um
for example let me show you some of them
Microsoft ergonomic keyboard so he's
talking about this one okay actually the
classic is this I mean this kind of the
classic
okay that was good before
2010 but not today uh you know and I
would not recommend it any of these
variations uh you know so you know you
have this variation and then you have
this one is pretty good but the key feel
is too stiff okay one of the most
important thing in ergonomic in your
hand Health in preventing Hand p P pan
is you want the linear and light
switches so this one is too stiff for me
so because I got RSI hand pen right
right now right here because in the past
two weeks I've been typing a a
lot so my pen come back you know it's
permanent damage you know this you know
it's already permanent so whenever I
type a audio come up like right now
there's a little burn sensation there so
so Kinesis freestyle which is another
popular one let me show you uh kesis
freestyle which is this one okay very
popular I recommend
it uh ogodo
easy ogodo easy is one of the
earliest from the do it your self
community so it is this one basically in
2012 that
that
um that
um you know basically in 2012 uh that
started to popularize the do it yourself
ergonomic keyboards community so you
know
ergodox but it's the main problem with
this one is that the thumb Keys is too
too much far away okay
so there are several people who got
thumb problems you know then they went
back to the normal PC keyboard
rectangular so you want to watch out
when you use you know you don't want you
don't want to use your move your thumb
like that even on a gra8 you know so you
want to move your whole hand you you
know that applies to the mouse to how
you use the mouse or the track ball or
thumb ball uh you don't want to move
just like the thumb that then you'll
develop the phone thumb
pen okay so that's a good one to I mean
you know relatively go touch so let me
show you what's this go touch uh do I
have it here yes I think uh go touch
there it is okay so before
2010 this is pretty good okay oh wait
this one came out in
2016 but not today uh it's Rober doome
okay it's the key switch is
robot okay
so and uh Happy Happ hacking okay let's
talk about happy hacking happy hacking
okay so wait let's talk about so it
mentioned ago K
860 now I don't even have that listed
here because I consider that's not even
ergonomic so let's search
for uh
Logitech wave there it is Logitech wave
keyboard this is the worst [ __ ] possible
you know you know litech
they try to innovate they think this is
a good thing so so you see there's a
kind of a dent on the
keyboard it's [ __ ] okay and also it's a
robot don't switch it's
[ __ ] uh then Happy hacking okay happy
hacking is the most welln let's go to
normal keyboard section then you got
happy hacking happy hack hack
hacking uh where is it there it is okay
this is the latest version happy
haing it's not good okay you know for
many keyboard Fanatics they consider
happy hiking the best you know by the by
the late M gen and Zuma Jon it's called
end game they idiotic jargons you know
their brand has the zumas in late Millen
gen starting with late late Millen
generation Millennials they
has been R is rotting you know since
since they were born by the clickbait by
the scamers by the grifter on the social
media since they were born so they are
incapable they don't know how to say
something like instead of end game you
know typically that's a situation you
know so what's the replacement for end
game the ultimate you know you can say
ultimate proper English
but anyway but you you see another
factor with these social networks that's
washing your brain every day is that if
you just say ultimate oh that's you know
nobody's going to click you have to say
end
game idiots you know the like like like
like this Bubble Girl Chinese you know
if I put this a pretty girl on my
YouTube thumbnail I I got 10 times more
small
Watchers that's that's why you go to
YouTube Everything Is crap you know with
their face you I discover this new
Theory change the centy you know [ __ ]
these [ __ ]
zomers hello hello hello hello hello so
what is the next question what is the
most beautiful to be cherished math
curve what is the what is most beautiful
to be cherished cherished math curve
okay so that's about math plan curves
okay let me answer that
question uh curve so basically what is
your favorite plan curve okay so
um spatial plan curves so I have a
website starting like 30 years ago one
of my most popular that's beginning my
career doing mathematics
so so if you ask mathematicians you know
planker is special plan curves is a
thing among mathematicians in the let's
say 1500s to uh to to to to 1800 it's
like a classic subject
okay uh so many mathematicians has have
their favorite you know C for example
the most famous
one pre uh preferred by mathematician is
uh this one equal angular triangle okay
this this is also known as logarithmic
triangle so why is it what is the
property basically starting from the
center or called pole the pole p o l e
which is synonymous for Center when you
are talking about the spiral so starting
from the center of the curve you draw a
line to any line okay then any
intersection to the curve to the spiral
will be the same degrees okay so for
example this one
80° can you see it you see so you draw
another one also 80° so it's constant
angle doesn't matter where where is your
line so that's why this is called equal
angular spiral this one is also called
also called logarithmic spiral because
the formula for this spiral is basically
exponential or log okay you know the
expon the
natural uh exponential or natural log
they are they are the inverse of each so
logarithmic Spirals and sometimes the
dramatic idiotic people they we call
this the golden ratio spiral or
Fibonacci you know with their Fibonacci
everything is fibon NY you know the
whole world is everything is fib nasty
my face is fasty that's idiot okay
that's you know but they like to call
this Fibonacci spiral okay but it's not
anyway anyway so why is this curve
famous relating to this question you
know what's the most cherished because
one of the greatest mathematician he
says when I die I want this curve edged
on my tomb St Stone okay that that math
is a f a very famous story okay that guy
is um
uh there uh that guy is um Puli
something okay so Beni okay let me just
read it the equal angular the equal
angular spiral was first considered in
1638 by
descotes deards you know however you
pronounce that deards is the founder of
analytic geometry so before deards in
1600s
the Western people the way they do
geometry is via logic you know like like
you know via logic basically it's very
interesting because you know if you
think about like today you think of
logic is more
about equations in Algebra you
know geometry is shapes how is it logic
you know but interesting interestingly
in the history of mathematics in the the
western western mathematics at
least GE geometry is actually for the
first you know 15,000 years is is tied
to logic you know it's like almost
synonymous anyway that's another story
so so anyway so so so uh let's go back
reading here the equal angular spiral
was first considered in 1638 by Dardis
who started from the property s equal to
a
r
evangelist T
Toren uh who died in 1647 worked on it
independently and used for a
definition the fact that the radi are in
geometric
progression okay that's another property
that is if you draw the line again you
know you you cut a curve but now inad
instead of drawing any line you draw the
line at constant increment of angles
okay constant increment of angles the
the constant may be big or
small okay then the the line will cut
the curve right now you measure the
distance from the center to the
intersection okay so you measure there
then you cut it then it cuts here you
measure this distance you cut you know
then measure that distance you know
again so that sequence of numbers is
geometric progression okay that's
another property is which is shown here
okay so you know so so so this curve is
not just equal angular you know angle is
the same but they the distance radial
distance makes a geometric
sequence that's another property okay
but anyway so so there it is jackob Bly
some 50 years later found all the
reproductive properties of the curve and
this almost Mystic properties of the
wonderful spiral made him wish to have
the curve incised on his
T in Latin okay Adam M Reco okay I don't
know Latin okay so it means the changed
I Rise unchanged so that's a problem
property
so uh let's go to Wikipedia because they
have more information you know just you
just search for this Latin phrase you
come up Boni okay there it
is so there it is that's that's the
jackob boli mathematicians his Tombstone
um you know so there it is you can see
the equal angular spiral here but
actually there's a mistake
you you see this spiral edged on his
tomstone is not equal angular spiral
that is an Aram median spiral okay they
have different
properties but the Tom Stone man you
know they they usually don't know that
much mathematics so oh oh you want a
spiral so they just draw a spiral but
this is a wrong spiral okay that's an
interesting thing so let's copy that so
let's put uh um toass Talk Show so we
have a record of what we talked about
okay then we're going to do emx okay put
that there put that there and uh go back
here go to equal langage spal go back
here put that here make link make a link
make a link make a list sh in browser
there it is what we talked about and we
also talk about other things but anyway
let's go back okay let's not interrupt
so
this uh so I want to go to um you see
jackob
Boni a famous Swiss Swiss Swiss
mathematician family okay
uh but anyway so that's the story so on
a question of what's the most cherished
math curve this is a famous story
okay me
personally
uh me personally now now wait hold on so
are there other mathematicians who are
particular uh who are
like has their favorite uh curve
actually a lot of these has famous uh
relations to mathematicians
okay uh but the most famous is that
jackob boli equal angular spiral okay so
for example yeah many of these has lots
of properties for example what's the
what what is the archimedian spiral you
see when you look at archimedian spiral
they I forgot off hand what is the
property uh polar equation R equals
to Theta n okay so basically they
that means their distance increases
increases as a power of the turn Okay
so yeah the the distance increases as a
power of the turn so depending on what
is the power number the nend you have
different spirals it's a family of
spirals okay so for example all these
are all these are
aredian spiral okay now including this
one and including this one okay they
have different names when they have
special case so all these are
archimedian spiral but the most famous
one which we call
Archimedes spiral is when the N equals
to one so as the so so as
the you know the the radius sweeps out
the curve increases
as the angle okay that's it no power so
that that one looks like this okay the
first one that's the Archimedes
spiral and all these all these others
are aredian spiral
okay okay I need my drink where is my
drink okay we kind of talked about
randomish things mathematics and who
else is here watch
uh say hi
okay orange
juice 11 people not too bad Ching donate
okay thank you Crystal let me and so we
talked for 30 minutes now and we're
going to get on to emac
this so so let me talk about maybe one
maybe a few minutes more
so so what is my favorite you know there
are so many you know I I can talk about
this for one hour you know because each
of these has so many uh very interesting
properties this one for example is what
you see in a cup uh where's my pictures
I have a picture somewhere a
photo CTIC okay let's go
here there it is okay you see that's a
cup coffee cup with a light reflected on
it you'll see this often in fact if you
take a cup right now you'll probably see
that pattern okay uh I can't see it here
because I don't have you know bright
light so this shape is called C
cardioid so many properties so and also
let me show you just another one uh
Parabola the most fun basic you know
Elementary you study this in
pre-calculus Geometry okay so you learn
about the coordinate for example you
study this in high school and one of the
interesting property is the lamp head
lamp you see this this is my car Honda
Civic in year 2000 so 25 years
ago uh okay so that's Parabola so many
of these so have so many properties for
example let me show you another picture
interesting one this one this this is
generated by po okay PO is the classic
uh rate tracing application it generate
it generates kind of re realistic images
via mathematical formulas okay by
tracing the ray okay that's a kind of
like that's that's one of the thing the
idiotic programmers love to talk about
obsessed about like the C and C++
programmers
they they think Ray Trace is the god
task you know for programming they
they're idiots they don't know nothing
about all this mathematics they don't
know nothing about differential geometry
they don't know nothing not a thing
about algebraic geometry they don't know
not a thing zero about computational
geometry all these are huge branches of
geometry they don't know not a thing but
they oh R tracing oh can you do R
tracing with JavaScript can you you know
my R tracing program is faster than
yours [ __ ] C C++ and Unix idiots and
the rust
idiots because because when you talk
about actual geometry they don't they
don't know they don't know not thing
they they oh that's interesting but they
by tomorrow they forgot all about it
okay they then but but then they their
mind is like going back to the r tracing
like the
KAC the the KAC idiot the most idiotic
programmer actually he's very bright but
he I'm talking about the mindset the
mindset of these type of programmers who
grew up with C C++ and rust this type of
people kak is the most extreme case
representative okay kak he did the the
the the first person shooter game you
know made him reach uh what what is the
game you
know so anyway R tracing you know that's
these type of people
hack uh okay so we will back let's go
back to talking about the favorite so
what is my favorite
um I I believe I had um oh yeah so I
forgot to mention so for example what
what about this uh rate tracing what
what about this one what is a property
so when you have a ball you put it on
desk and you shine a light on it the
shadow it casts
are conic sections okay now if your
light source is above the ball then you
get an elisp like right there
okay if your light source is below the
top of the ball what you get is this one
hyperbola okay now if your light source
is right at you know at the same level
as the top of the ball what you get is
Parabola okay so fascinating fascinating
properties of these
curves my favorite you know not getting
fancy is um I well anyway I don't know I
like the conic sections very much uh so
for example conic
sections is one of the most Asian curve
Asian since 2000 or 3,000 years ago
being thoroughly studi all these
property properties I mentioned you know
all these so far I mentioned this you
know
Shadow properties so basically what this
means is that they they are a section of
a cone uh
like like that you know a
k same thing same thing you know just
different perspective when you talk
about Shadow because when you have a
shadow it's a projection you know so
this property you know so conic section
is the most Asian curve other than
circle circle and line is the the the
the most most most Asian line and circle
okay but con properties you know you
could say the most interesting Asian
curve since two years 2,000 years ago
studied by a Apollo okay or what uh
apollonius you know the Greek
mathematician
so aalon okay 2016
2 BC to 190 BC so 2,000 years
ago and he studied this is part of pure
mathematics why does he study it because
just pure interest you know all these
properties okay no little no there are
some applications back
then for example you want to focus you
know Parabola you want to focus the sun
rate to a point
so it can create fire or there's a
famous Greek story where you not UK cite
someone you know Greek
mathematician he when some of the tribe
are attacking their City via the sea
they created this mirror so that they
focus the sunlight on the cells of of
the ships and enemy ships
so so that's the the property of
Parabola so but
anyway he abalonia studied the curve you
know just just just for the interesting
for the sake of you know many of these
properties what happens if you do this
or that and then after,
1500 years later it becomes applied math
why because of the
planets the path of the Earth the path
path of the planet if you want to go to
Mo the moon first of all you need to
know where it is it is and how it
moves that's all conic sections okay
that's all
um conic
sections okay that's that's that's
that's that uh looks like today mostly
we talking about mathematics so
no I didn't try Microsoft one I don't
know what is Microsoft One is that the
office Microsoft Office no they name
that Office 360 right do you reach the
bottom with linear keys I can't break
that
habit that's um you know that depends on
what you mean like a lot of people talk
about hitting bottom
but so but what does that mean
effectively does I mean I guess it just
means you hit the key so hard you you
you you you like you you shock your
fingers that's what hitting bottoms mean
I don't I don't I guess in that case I
don't hit
bottom okay so we talked about a lot
math should we still continue to do EAC
this I'm thinking no what do you guys
think
because if I do a next video so because
I can then name this name this video
mathematics then those interested in
mathematics they can watch
it uh then next video just EAC thisp
then the emac thisp
can we watch that
one because many of them you know they
they are not the same group of
people yeah okay so yeah okay let's
let's just be that
then math anything else guys anything
else maybe we shut
down oh hot dog hot dog hot dog our
gamer Zuma says I'm incorrect about
something [ __ ]
idiot you know know so he's saying you
know maybe I shouldn't talk about this
here because we were talking about math
but he's saying this is incorrect it's
called a b because it's an ephemeral
view in uh into a file and not
necessarily representative of a file it
has nothing to do with memory limits no
[ __ ]
idiots so his question is about you know
something about somewhere I said about
buffer you know so hot dog he doesn't
know the history of
emac so how do I know
because i' been looking into history of
emac but in particular we have in our
Forum a
great person Emily okay
Emily first of all she she's a great
person since Sali Discord began three
years ago around year 2020 also okay so
she first of all she doesn't make
dramatic [ __ ] post she doesn't do that
okay every her every of her post is like
focused reply on something or something
okay first of all and she doesn't talk
about politics you know like usually I
do like sometimes I say elas something
something or the Deep state and everyone
everybody else is going to chime in oh
but you are wrong elus is actually this
or that oh but B Gates but but but Co
you know the drama politics most of
their information is just
incorrect so but some people they never
talk about sensitive issues religion
politics you know so in our Forum we
also have fight about
religion Christianity we have West you
know Orthodox versus
Catholics you know but then then you
have the Jewish religion of course je
you know then you have
islamics you know fight [ __ ] post let's
see who can [ __ ] post the most you know
so Emily she never uh where is Emily
Emily recently posted a lot interesting
stuff but I got too
busy so let me show you
Emily there so Emily uh and she has a
website you know she has I have a page
about her keyboards her uh Power Station
her workstation for example here her
keyboards very you know this is like
happy hacking she likes the key
mechanism of happy hacking which is toer
switch she like it very much so she
upgraded she upgraded from Happy hacking
keyboard to this one this one is more
classic and more keys so yeah so she
doesn't [ __ ] post she doesn't talk about
politics or sensitive or religion
stuff and that's not all and every time
her post is deep nerd dive on keyboards
or on programming languages or on
history of emac so I first learned about
the concept buffer I mean what exactly
does it mean when emac
first the first time emac used the word
buffer okay I learned from her because
she she actually installed the Techo
text editor that's not even emac yet but
the pre predes you know the the father
of emac the
predes the predecessor of emac so she
installed it and learned it and you know
become expert so she know what's the
actual history why does emac do this or
that man a keep buffer you know you have
to very few people do that even even I
haven't I did don't do that but she Al
she also dived into uh different
programming languages like um Erland
she's a master of Erland Prue she's a
master of Prue okay maybe not master but
at least expert Eran prologue okay and
she also you know so very interesting
thing she's Al she's a network
engineer so she knows about networking
stuff a lot you know she's expert in
that professional so she knows a lot of
things and she share those information
and also she is also
a expert top one of the top expert in
contributor to the to
the
uh uh sto okay sto system using modern
computer keyboards you know so I have a
page let's so let me show her uh page
since since we are talking about this a
lot so you go to C website you go to
miscellaneous Tech no you go to fun okay
the fun part then you go
to then you go to Battle Stations there
that's her battle station happy hacking
Emily This Server okay so this was her
battle station about 3 years ago
actually
2019 and she upgraded you know so this
is four years ago and look at her books
earland
programming the Unix you know introdu
uction to the unique system algorithms
in C compilers you know the famous
Dragon book and she's got you know you
know her setup and also then
the ailos
scope she has to measure the
electronics oscope okay and her keyboard
and mouse happy hacking and she has her
own customized unique unque and creative
layout unlike you know she's not the
mainstream Elite you know like like moo
moo are you here listen Okay moo is the
mainstream Elite basically meaning you
go read Hacker News every day you go
read you know this Elite you know Vim
you know whatever the the elite the
python the G what they tell you to do so
they are like among the they are the
Elite so about programming style about
how you should format your code about
what you what tool you should use Linux
open source of course about you
know so some people they they follow
this Elite think you know these so
so-called thought leaders in Silicon
Valley you know like the gido Ros the
most low IQ among language creators
python G R you know and he's not a good
person Nei not not too good a person
because he's put K RM is pushing the
social justice Warriors
stuff and his language is [ __ ] python
among compared to alls is like below
average Python programming language so
anyway there's this group people who are
like following the like they are not the
mainstream of course the mainstream is
is mostly idiotic you know they go to
university because they their their
parents told them to you know they just
program for a job they have no interest
what's Unix philosophy or or whatever
emac V they just use vs code whatever is
easy they get their job done they get
money they go home you know but then
among the program that that's the
mainstream okay so but among them you
have like the hackers you know who are
more into like which one is the emac
versus V you know they need to discuss
that you know which one rust you know
rust versus c r versus goland you know
which language is the best and what's
the programming practice the guide style
guide which you know so you have this
Elite kind of hacker types or Unix
philosophy you know they they they not
they they are very GL about Unix
philosophy small is beautiful or dry
princip I how you know the you know how
you should not repeat this [ __ ] this the
name of my pen this [ __ ] idiots okay
this this hacker
group they you know so they are
represented by like Hacker News okay
like Paul grham Paul grham is one of the
thought leaders okay they tell you what
to do they they they they condition like
what what everyone you know the is
better you know the better way
uh and uh and you know you know
so so they are this type of people
Emily this Emily we are talking about is
not that but the her stuff what she
knows Erland you know Erland is not like
even among this Elite group is not
mainstream these Elite idiots they are L
to rust rust every day rust C or C++ and
rust this idiot
Emily is not like that she's into she
study ear she study
Prue she dive into the sto okay that
that's that sto is you know takes a year
or two to learn so she's and and she
created her own layout not not well she
was also using comac of course she also
know the existing you know what people
say you know so but she created her own
layout so very creative you know and her
hardware for example she bought this
which is kind of
also happy hacking you know kind of know
you know she bought this USB to USB
converter that allows you to program the
USB
device so anyway I learned many things
from her and one of the things I learned
is about emac buffer the history or
engine of the world buffer so this H
this this
are I need to fun I need to make fun of
this hot dog you know hot dog is a in my
eyes he's like common American white
gamer you know you see them on YouTube
all the time they are GL like the l l
Linux Tech tips you know they talk fast
and using jargons using the latest zum
JG
[ __ ] okay that that's it for
today
uh I think that's it for today
why we still in
2024 don't have a voice control desktop
computer we do
actually uh on Microsoft Windows on
Apple you can do that uh it just that
few people actually try to do
it yeah so you know you can actually try
actually you can voice control operate
your windows but I'm not sure to what
degree it's very smooth but I mean for
the basic you can and also for on the
Mac Mac is better in that way okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching let's see what what were we
going to do
originally uh wait not keyboard let's go
to uh talk
show so today's talk show we need to
code HTML lines to list okay we need to
modify that yeah let's do that another
day bye guys bye guys donate to me okay
go to PayPal go to my homepage just
click. info click homepage you go to all
the way to the bottom you can see my
patreon you can see my Amazon gift card
send me a gift card and uh uh PayPal me
okay $100 is nice if you are if you work
for
Google say me few
more you see idiotic hot dog you see he
says the buffer it has nothing to do
with memory limits no the origin of the
idea of buffer in
emac is precisely because it is Lory
memory limits it cannot fit a file even
a small file back 30 years ago into
memory because back then the memory is
what 100
bytes wait back then you know 1970s 1976
1978 what's the
memory uh is it 1 kilobyte no not even
well maybe
you know you have to look up
so so they don't have you know so that's
why even a small file cannot fit in the
memory that's why
buffer that's why the buffer became the
thing in emac everything is buffer
buffer
buffer bye guys