good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today's 2019 September 21st
Saturday night o´clock
a.m.
okay so good morning Emma what is
today's topic
good morning green deck come on into
Russia so what is today's topic let me
begin good morning
Kathi great to see you Cathy Cathy from
London good morning to London so guys
pick a topic okay pick a topic and it
led the chat flow saw talk show today
state it's a new page
make a list cut pay sit here and go to
the page and show in browser so today
this is for today's notes and on the
left side you can see all my Emacs
commands so green deck says Emacs tips
okay let's do that
Quinn deck says Richard Stallman
retirement finally discuss it okay
that's a tough topic Richard Stallman
that's a really that's a tough topic
it's tough not because it's tough it's
tough because censorship YouTube you
know they you know they are going to
shut down my account okay Richard
Stallman I have to be very careful you
see this is this is this is a very
extremely sensitive topic and also it's
heavy topic because it involves this guy
who is a super-rich billion you know
billionaire he and it involves this
taboo the us taboo about you know eg I'd
rather not talk about it but anyway okay
so let me just summarize my opinions
about Richard Stallman okay so if you
haven't heard of the news
let's go to Emacs let's go to Emacs my
Emacs block okay so you can see there is
the Twitter I wrote about a Twitter
Richard Stallman resigned from free
software foundation basically that's the
news okay
basically what happens is that he in my
opinion okay he criticized some wording
of the mainstream media side mainstream
left it's leftist social justice
politically a flee affiliated news
websites you know you have most news
news websites these corporations such as
such as CNN vice aj+ BuzzFeed MSNBC the
verge basically all mainstream media and
especially New York Times Washington
Post the hump in The Huffington Post
they are or very heavily biased
mainstream media you know as Trump says
fake news so these websites you know
every day they they post about news but
however they twist with words you know
the the way you announce some news you
can you can write it so that it's biased
you know when you read it you know
everyone reports the same thing but you
know you can twist twist the words so
anyway so Richard Stallman criticized
one of the article that that that used
twisted words then there is a women
there's a woman who is is you know kind
of the social justice people you know
the the and she she basically criticized
Richard Stallman okay now the details
are in this street okay I
have posted there you know and you can
you can read that you know check that so
anyway she criticized Richard Stallman
and basically she want she want Richard
Stallman to be kicked out okay and she
sent her blog you know she sent this
information to her blog to vice vice is
another very extreme leftist news
website they write fake news every day
vice so so and then other mainstream
media picked it up so it becomes news
over
so eventually basically they pressured
now I don't know the details nobody
knows that know the details but
basically they pressured Richard
Stallman to step down so that's what he
did all this happening happened within
five days four or five days so in my
opinion Richard Stallman originally you
know he criticized the news media's
warding you know basically using a word
assault I agree 100% with Richard
Stallman and also many of this moose
news media they pick on Richard
Stallman's you know Richard Stallman is
a very weird person so he had a lot
opinions that's not not mainstream okay
so many people attacked him now this
subject matter I'm not going to mention
the words you know what they are you
know if you want to know you can read
you know the Twitter link I have it here
you know basically you already know most
of you probably already already know
what's the issue anyway the subject
matter is a is a taboo topic in America
you know for for for for long time photo
four fifty fifty years or more four
hundred years
yeah probably more race more recent for
fifty years anyway it's a huge tap
subject in USA so I don't want to talk
about it
so anyway Richard Stallman have some
some weird opinions so and although
these are the people attack him
basically they Sir Richard Stallman he
criticized this wording of news media
but then all all the news media they say
they did twist
you know they twist awards so it becomes
like oh Richard Stallman supports this
criminal that's all the news media are
saying they are saying witch's Thomas
supports this criminal therefore he
should be kick up you know all this
media fake news they want to make people
angry you know so Richard Stallman
resigned now he now it's not clear
whether it's he's being forced to resign
you know there's a pressure you know
anyway he resigned so we don't know it's
it's likely you know from the look of it
it's likely he's being pressured you
know forced to resign so that's
interesting you know that this this is a
big news as far as free software
foundation is concerned and also all the
you know or view people
Emacs people all the people yeah so so
this is a big news about free software
foundation so Green Tech says so usually
you criticize him but in the situation
in this situation you think he didn't
deserve the what he got exactly I
criticized Twitter storm and all the
time you know like I said this many
times in my video in my past videos you
if you such Sally you know such YouTube
sorry
open-source so sorry free software
foundation of solid which is Roman you
will find several videos that I talked I
talked about I criticized open source
free software foundation or Richard
Stallman you know for hours you know
back in 1998 to for for for like
five polls you know for seven years I
was a fanatic of Richard Stallman I was
a big fan of Richard Stallman I've read
basically everything he has written back
then but around since about 2007 I
started to I think he's wrong okay
I mean what you know it's complex I it's
this this is a complex situation you
cannot say he's just wrong or he's good
or bad okay it's you know the the the
idea about free soft software ideology
and open source it's complex issue okay
it's not absolutely oh this is bad oh
it's good okay it's complex anyway so
anyway since 2008 I started to not I
don't think Richard Stallman is really
doing that good but however still I
maintain that he's a honest person
I mean you reasonably gonna compare
comparatively compared to all other
celebrities in in tech for example which
Roman is one of the very honest and and
how you say integral person so forth for
that I really think he's a great person
you know he for example he he believed
me in free software you know his
particular ideology about free software
you know he you know the word even a
word is is abuse of the word free okay
but he used that word free software
foundation to him that word three means
like like liberal like liberty freedom
in my opinion that's abuse of the word
free but because free to most people
that means you don't have to pay okay so
anyway that's not getting into that
today you can watch my past videos by
anyway so I was a phonetic of Richard
Stallman then I don't really think he's
doing great I mean I don't I don't I
changed my mind
you know after 20 years and today in
especially in the past five years he is
a number one obstacle that blocks any
progress of Emacs
for at least five years five - for the
past five or ten years he is a number
one person who does damage to Emax but
anyway but this incident that happened
today I don't I I support Richard
Stallman hundred percent he I don't
think he's wrong in any way in fact I
think what happened you know so so he's
you know he resigned but actually I
think you know what really happened is
that these social justice people you
know this you know I call them social
justice scan they are like the red cards
in Cultural Revolution of China forty
years ago you know if you don't know
about Cultural Revolution look it up
okay this you know it's like you have a
bunch of people who are brainwashed and
you just destroy things who if you don't
agree they are going to take you down
they are going to destroy your family
destroy they want to destroy everything
they have this Stinnett they follow
that's a China Cultural Revolution so
they they kill they kill professors they
destroy any traditional values
traditional thought they damage you know
they break they throw away Asian stuff
you know thousand dosed of they
destroyed so and so that's Chinese
Cultural Revolution red cards you can
look at look it up okay these young
people bit mostly students red cards
it's called red cards there's a
Wikipedia article on that and you can
see by the way you cannot trust
Wikipedia so because today the American
left the extreme left the social justice
people they are for communism so you
know the red card so I'm not sure you
can totally trust the Wikipedia article
on red cards
anyway so that's culture revolution
there's a lot of people died I don't
know how many let's see Cultural
Revolution so do they say how many
people died anyway so in my point in in
my opinion today's social justice the
extreme left the antifa those people you
know and all almost all the mainstream
media I like the Cultural Revolution
like the red cards this happens you know
this they yeah let's let's stop there
okay let's not get into details so
anyway so in this incident I I support
which a storm and I you know he's just
basically being is a power struggle
there is no code you know normally you
would go into code you prove things you
know or heated did even if all these
social justice is all right oh he did is
he made a mistake he he posted opinion
okay that's all he did he posted opinion
that's not mainstream okay let's let's
say it's Evo Evo opinion okay let's say
it's one of the very evil opinion that's
what he suppose that's what he did I
don't agree okay but suppose that's what
he did he posted the Evo opinion then he
got you know he got forced out a mink
while this billionaire which you know
very rich medium area and there are so
many so many other people in today still
active they are in they are part of the
social justice can okay they are doing
all the you know bad things you know the
the things these people are accusing
Richard Stallman of you know they are
doing all this I don't want to mention
the word okay so they are doing that but
that's the thing you see this social
justice you know they create a situation
so that you know you
the spdm here who is in jail and
supposedly killed himself
you know nobody nobody believed that he
did you know because he is a billionaire
he owns an island like entire island he
only owned it and he's connected to all
the you know President Clinton you know
Clinton and many other powerful you know
people and suddenly he died so this is a
big issue you know anything you make you
know if I say something I made a mistake
they can you know they can have me
killed you know they you know these very
powerful princes Prince and other
countries you know beaters and Prince
you know or involved so anyway so so
doesn't you know does it's almost like
doesn't matter how you look at that look
at this situation there is nothing you
know is nothing wrong with Richard
Stallman okay it's all these are the
people they are doing the things they
you know yeah so that's my opinion about
that they are extremely evil so this is
a big topic you know and you can find of
course
thousands more than thousands YouTube
videos about all these kind of things
social justice you know this thing so
Kathy says it's not about the language
cutoff it's not about the language
clarification or definition dispute of
that anymore it's war between general
belief disagreement okay right or wrong
is not enough here it's more about what
people want to believe instead of who
want to believe yes
dingo says I disagree with most of what
he says when it comes to politics or
morals but he was important to have
around yes
5,000 to 2 million people killed
that's cultural revolution I don't I
don't think that's cultural revolution
that's the let's see maybe you are right
but you see China during that time from
1950 to let's say okay so the so what is
this history of People's Republic
Republic of China 1949 to 1976 okay
restructuring rising power yeah so
anyway from 1950 to 1976 they are there
are a lot of chaos that is the end that
basically that's the late later stage of
mouse life so you have one hundred
Flowers campaign anti-rightist campaign
Great Leap Forward great leap forward is
a big one a lot of people died most of
the deaths happened from famine you know
no food because when society went
chaotic you don't have food anymore
for example America you know like in
America for example in USA you have a
lot Sambi movies you know it's a one of
the American culture zombies you know
you become zombies so in these movies
you know you know so it's interesting to
think about if if if we start to have
zombies you know how long we are the
food go away you know how very fast you
know like if if I go to the local
shopping center you have aisles
you know row after row after I or bread
all kind of bread fruits you know it's
so great laughter but if you think think
about if if the society went chaotic if
there's the
zombie or some crisis or some some some
virus you know half of the population
you
becomes dead the food will will go away
very fast like within one week he'll be
okay okay then you don't have food
anymore you know it's it this will
happen very fast we don't see it we
don't notice because we are not in that
situation you know you go to a store
there's tons of food but when when a big
something went wrong you know chaos or
virus you know have people or thought
you know one third of people dies all
the food go away very fast so that's
okay so let's move on to Emacs tips then
so yeah so okay so let's move move on to
Emacs tips so let's see so I want to
yeah let's let's talk about Emacs stuff
so any any any particular thing where is
my oh I need to look at this is mistake
I need to look at how many people are
watching I cannot see it here so let's
go to my channel let's go to youtube
beta
and let's go - it takes a long time
let's go to videos
so any questions about Emacs you are
interested anyone any particular thing
about Emacs type it type in comments
then we let's talk about that I'm gonna
tell you all about it now this takes a
long time okay so here live stream and I
need to go to live control room
and I need to click live dashboard
okay there we are
and it says zero watching seven watching
okay so
so okay green deck says why do you use
this specific color for background in
emacs why not light yellow for example
this color just works fine I mean it
just worked fine so in eMac you can you
can call you can call for example least
color display okay then it will show all
possible colors and they are hex and
they're hexadecimal syntax on the right
color so you know you can pick any color
it doesn't really matter but I it just
so happens the right the the color I'm
using is Hani true such honey true
okay how many true honey do you honey do
this one okay so so Emacs what what what
topics okay if you if you if you guys
don't give any topics I'll probably just
go random then yeah but I thought there
is more interesting story behind this
color oh no it's just just one of the
color that happens to you know oh I want
is some oh I want is that before it's
white you know by default is white I
just want something that has slight so
it's not so bright at all so Kathy says
I think your navigation shortcuts are
extremely efficient but I noticed that
heavily relies on your programming
keyboard and mouse
well mostly just saw fly keys that's all
just it's mostly just sapphire keys so
if you want to I know you are a Evo mod
user right which is you know that's
that's fine so but
let's seek some packages so I'm using
Suffolk fakies so mostly it's just a
ficus is there any general efficient
navigation setting operations that we
could learn from okay
general efficient navigation settings
operations that that's kind of a broad
topic that's very broad topic like what
depends on what you mean for example
okay it's just talk randomly for example
some people they prefer one screen for
Emacs like that so they split the window
they they you know so so they they walk
their whole day like this you know
there's just one Emacs window and they
rely on speak windows so for example I
can have a shout here you know I can you
know let's up sync to my web server so I
you know I just synched up two files for
example let's go to Emacs block here
some people walk like this
okay so create a new section something
today nice day and chocolate chop cut
let that's their own choc a oh and he is
that correct no oh okay so so there so
there you have it you know I I created a
new entry of today and I make it into my
RSS file something chocolate okay save
it close it I switch to this window I
updated sync to my web server password
so some people work like this you know
one one giant window I don't like this
at all so this is one of the workflow
you know so some people like this I
don't I always work you know I
rather I just work weekly with two
windows side by side you know so I work
with two windows the advantage of two
windows is that Emacs will never it will
never close your window it will never
change the size or move to different
position you see because you have you
have full control of your windows Emacs
or a green system they will not change
it but however if you if your workflow
is based on you know split windows one
maximized window and you have split
screens then Emacs will often you know
screw it for example let's call this
scribe function let's go to for example
V's okay so Emacs Lisp so I have Emacs
sleeps tutorial so eMac B's basics so I
let's say suppose I want to know let's
go down let's say I want to know I want
to know what does not mean okay I'm
agrees so this this this would not okay
so I call describe function I paste not
and I enter okay so you see you see
Emacs splitted my screen so he says not
is an alias for no it's a dysfunction
they just true becomes false false
becomes true so this function so you see
but Emacs change my screen so that's a
problem because you you have you have
them split in a nice way but now it's
changed and now is usually it's hard to
go back to what what you had so this is
a frequently asked question a lot of
people ask about this or how do you
reconfigure how do you and also how do
you you know you want convenient keys to
switch to a particular panel and there
are several
that that help you doing this you know
there's a smart and so on I don't
recommend this way okay I don't
recommend this one window one giant
window way because then you are fighting
about Emacs breaking your spirit config
all the time so I recommend just you
know just to two windows side by side or
if you really want you can make them
like that for example if you really want
something like a sweet split screen then
you can create something like that this
way you see Emacs never never change
their config you know you just have it
the way they are so you see what I mean
yeah so that's one of the tip about
spirit screen so in fact I have quite a
few articles about that so if you go to
Emacs miscellaneous and go down search
for split okay
search for window okay so full screen
versus multiple windows
okay go to effective window management
so this article I talked about so this
is what typical a lot Emacs users they
prefer one window and this is the way I
prefer just multiple windows usually
usually just two so right right everyone
any questions is sale okay so is there a
dedicated time for the live video it
looks like the live session times random
it's really it'll really help if we have
a dedicated time yeah I'm sorry never
you know that's a frequently asked
question I never have a fixed schedule
it changes because my sleeping schedule
change changes around the clock so yeah
no you know the best thing you can do is
just go to my YouTube video you go to
youtube sorry YouTube sorry
then ya go to the sky then you go to
about now if I have a schedule I post it
here not about in the community okay
community if I if I have a sometimes I
don't know I don't know yet sometimes I
have a schedule for the next week you
know for the next five five or seven
days if there is anything like that I
post it there so so let's let's talk
about Emacs so if you have me any
questions just ask okay let me just
check what I you know I just let's talk
about random then so Emacs to Latin to
prayer okay I did this last few days ago
I explained the Emacs Lisp code let's
say let's see some thing something ABC
and XYZ and is calculus okay so you can
convert this to Latin to run okay
you see paste paste that okay so you can
convert this coda command convert Latin
to run and let's do it again convert
Latin to gothic okay
then let's do it again let's convert
Latin to Braille so I have these three
commands that does that that's
interesting and you can look at a code
here Latin to Braille here's a code you
can copy and use it in Latin to gothic
now they are all using Unicode okay oh
these are unicode for example describe
sha so this character is Braille pattern
dot two three four and the Unicode
character code point is over here one
two five
one zero two five six or in hexadecimal
it's two eight zero e okay and this
command is called describe cha whenever
you want to find information about our
character you call that command describe
cha very useful by default it doesn't
have a key but I give it a key control
HC weight now I give it a key my own key
but you can define your key okay so just
just give it a key you know how to
create a key so let me let me go through
my eMac eMac tutorial then so if you
guys are new to Emacs check out my
Emacs tutorial so here is the practical
Emacs for beginners you read you know
just like actually read them one
friendly read one article a day and read
them all
you really will you will become expert
because every day on reddit IC or Emacs
questions they you know they don't know
if you if they've reddit they would know
so come fro Prasad says you can winner
and do two and do two most recent best
configuration yes that is mentioned here
for example on my Emacs tutorial
practical Emacs USC there is this
section manage window topic so first of
all you learn split windows this you
need to master ok you need to memorize
everything in detail because split
windows is the one thing you use most of
the time and and whenever Emacs you know
pop up a window when you call this scrap
function or describe cha you know you
can manage it you know for example you
want to remove this pin you just
Sakhi I've heard Sookie I don't use that
what Sookie - well the Emax default keys
ctrl X 0 okay yeah that's the Emacs
default key so let me describe key to
see what's my key our space 3 that's
right so you know space 3 space 3 yeah
that's right
for example I want to remove the bottom
space 3 you know it's removed so anyway
so so on this article you know first of
all you learn you need to master 3
windows and there are also commands to
adjust split pane sighs you know Emacs
has tons of things like you can learn
that that's what they say for example
then the Emacs
for example this this picture represent
Emacs so you have notepad this is
learning curve notepad picot Visual
Studio you go up ooh then you go down
okay
then VI VI is at the beginning you have
to spend one month to learn then it's
flat then this Emacs learning curve it's
funny because it goes into infinite
curve in sky you know this is this
comics is funny because it breaks many
logical reasons because first of all
notice that this curve it it breaks you
know normally when you have a time and
XY axis graph they they must be a
function that means any time you draw a
straight line vertical line they should
not cross the function more than once
you see but he max so this is actually
not a function so this is not a graph of
function but also it goes backwards yeah
so anyway that's funny so that that's
what they say when you learn Emacs it's
almost a lifetime
actually today I don't learn I don't
learn much anymore like I mean you can I
mean still you can you can still done
but but you don't need to be gone and I
don't want to spend time learning more
esoteric details because I've been using
Emacs for 20 years now so since about
five or ten years ago you stopped
actually learning stuff because you can
do everything you need the the one thing
you still I see you learn is eMac B's so
if you already know a lot in max you
know I recommend go start to read Emacs
Lisp then your power will increase
dramatically even if you do not code
eMac this but by understanding Magnus
you will learn a lot of things so anyway
back to the manage windows topic so
Emacs has lots of commands first of all
you learn spirit with spirit windows
then you can actually call commands to
to adjust the window size like that you
know but typically you just use a mouse
mouse is easier this way you know for
example you can split vertical and you
can drag over here you can drag but you
can also use command you can shrink
enlarge you know enlarge horizontally
and they have esoteric keys you almost
never use you know like you never used
like Emacs is this strange creature like
when you begin you want to learn all
these like you started 200 I just
learned this you know I I need you know
I need to remember this but next year
you got some other workflow then maybe
you don't use this much then but after
three years then you start to change
your workflow you revisit then you think
oh I actually should use this you know
Emacs is like that you you you you deal
with it every day kind of like with like
Linux and window managers you know one
for this year you use
meet window manager next year you switch
easy
you kind of do that all the time so
Emacs so split windows then you learn
about save split windows configuration
for example if I could Emacs now okay
let's say let me quit save Untied out
let's see
untitled okay I don't want untied okay
save and title okay it's magnify okay
split split okay now let's quit Emacs
okay Emacs is gone let's restart Emacs
it will open all the buffers I've opened
before and it will also restore my my
setup you see and this is this works
that way by default but however doesn't
remember my font size and also on the
left window let's call sauce start
command log mod so that you can see all
my commands again on the left window so
let's shrink it so green deck says by
the way what do you think about Mouse
centered control like in plan Nyack me I
don't think that's good okay I I you
know I don't according to them you know
the Rob Pike they believe they think
that it's actually more efficient but I
don't believe it I haven't used plan
night okay so cool for school says can
regular Emacs keybinding
be used in conjunction in conjunction
with Sophocles yes absolutely
in fact in fact sawfly Keys does not
change any control key binding so you
can keep using control key binding for
example can i press ctrl f to move
character you can see on the left window
control
control be go back control P to move up
you see you see on the left window so it
is still walk control n2o control and I
change control and to me is new new
buffer so I pressed control in you see
new buffer you see untitled three entire
untitled for untitled five you see close
close close close close close them yeah
so in sapphire keys they do it does not
touch control any control combination
you can still use you know all the
control keys also it does not touch mate
hugg combination I think except one
meter key or something like that so you
can you can keep using Emacs the way you
do you know the yeah pretty much
so green deck says it's very interesting
to me how there are people who use Emacs
for many years but not customize
anything even not remove toolbars yes
that's true yes I think that's true in
general because a lot of people you know
when we think of Emacs users you know we
think of people on reddit or like me you
know or the basically the Emacs bloggers
who are loud loud you know talking all
the time they tell you what to do
including me okay but actually I think
in reality those who go online you know
talking most of the time they are like
they are I would say they are less than
5% of all Emacs users so in real life
Emacs users are not what you expect
I mean what they are not what do you
think they are and in fact I know I know
very powerful and I mean I know great
programmers you know who are far better
in programming than me including one of
my old boss back in 2000
okay they they use emacs they don't even
for example my my boss 20 years ago he
never used tired I talked about this
last time you know he never used tired
when you know the way he used Emacs is
that you know he start Emacs and he
opened a file then he added when he's
done save it then he quit he quit
Emacs you know then when he wants to
edit another file he start MX with a
file name again
that's what he does he never I saw him
he don't use Emacs but he but he's not
you know he's a expert coder you know he
knows C and Pro and Java and stuff you
know he so there are people like that
yeah and you know it's like most most of
the internet like a lot most people
actually I would say probably even 90%
of people except young people let's not
count young people but most people they
don't you know they don't go online and
blog or or you know I mean even even you
guys like us you know a lot of us a lot
of you guys I know my followers for
example you don't you don't post much
like you use the web right you used with
it or you use Twitter but you don't you
know you don't go out you don't go post
much anything so so the Internet is
mostly you know all the chatting or the
talking is by by this small minority
handful of people and they create put
the perception you know misconception
that whatever is on an Internet that's
what most people think or behave that's
not not true so so back to the street
Windows so you have so ID for example
this page I talk about all the ways
about saving spring windows
configuration and about Samia to the
concession or you can save it to the
register or you can save it to across
sessions that
when you restart Emacs it restores
everything and I tell you what other
commands what are the mechanisms for
example when you quit and you reopen
when you start Emacs you can have Emacs
restore the Windows position and all the
buffers that is stunned by what's called
desktop desktop safe mode and I have
detail for example we still open files
window config you know this this details
about that and also desktop saved mod
it's a new feature in Emacs 24 2014 ok
so this page is pages about safes big
windows config then the next page
effective window management that's what
I talked about about one giant maximize
window versus two or more smaller
windows you know so I much prefer I
think it's much more efficient and
optimal to have two more two or more
small windows this way you can actually
because this way you have full control
of your windows you can possess position
them anywhere that you want you can
remove for example you can remove one of
them anytime you want you have full
control so that's about that then you
have make buffer flow side by side ok
this is one of the feature that's rarely
used let me show you what what it does
split windows horizontally follow mod ok
so let me show you so close that
actually so go to my Emacs blog maximize
window now speak window ok I want to
spread side by side and I want to say
follow mod the command name is follow
mod so if I
so can you see so if I go to the
beginning of buffer okay let's see okay
so you see I move the cursor on a left
pin and the right pane wheel we also
move
that's what follow Mart does you can
make it so that when the left buffer
which the bottom and the right buffer
top will be the next slide so this is
one way to have to to be able to view a
loan documentation I don't use it okay
that I find it too much trouble
you know because I don't first of all I
don't like the one giant window mod so
that's that's let's follow mod okay side
by side make buffer flow side by side
then you have restore open files windows
config yeah we talked about that desktop
save my changes in Emacs 24 you know so
there are a lot of details then set D
for window size you can also set windows
default size so for example when I open
a new window is always this size you can
make it smaller or larger so yeah you
know I would say just you know you can I
recommend with you know read my email or
tutorial just read one page your day be
demo actually so once you after you
finish reading this page
Emacs practical practical Emacs tutorial
then go read in it set up so the unit
set up collection there's another 30
articles also that's all about all about
setting up Emacs because they are so
much to talk about so if there's a
specific topic I can talk about it
otherwise is so much you know
so Emacs init file in stop hack you know
so yeah I would recommend just you know
read my tutorial then the next section
is all about key bindings key bindings
and Emacs keys in this section on the
left it tells you oh you know in
easy way how do you create keys what
does it mean things like that how how
does major Marquis and minor Marquis
work how they are they different which
which one is has priority and so on and
you can bind super in hyper keys and so
on so green tag says how can register be
useful okay
Emacs register there are several use
uses of Emacs which register first of
all what is a register register is
basically a storage place okay it's just
a storage location in Emacs you have
like 26 registers or 30 36 basically
register Emacs register is is named
after
ABCD efg the letters so you have
register the alpha numeric letters or
numbers you have register 1 2 3 4 5 2 2
9 and which is 0 I think and you also
have register a which is the B you know
you can store things in it you can take
info out of it and and the most
practical use is to copy so for example
let me show you okay so for example if
you want this text you need to copy it
and you need to go to for example I go
to my programming blog okay I need to
paste it here for example ok so but then
I copied something else and that so I
lost this so if you want to copy this
all the time you can store it in a
register then then it does not mix with
your copy paste with your keyring ok so
you you always have that in a register
for example let me show you so suppose I
want close this ok suppose I want this
in the register ok
let's just say XYZ okay I copy it I have
a special command let me let me just
show you first okay close that selected
I call this command oops not that okay
you see on the left it says copy to
register one that means this text is now
in register 1 now whenever I want to
paste it I can just say okay I just call
the command southeast from register what
this this command okay and I can I can
paste a lot I can paste anywhere and it
does not it does not affect in fact I
can I think I can close Emacs and you'll
still be available so let's restart
Emacs
okay okay that's it Skoda command there
you go you see it's not pasted from
register what now let me show you the
command okay let's let me show you the
command described key okay here is my
documentation and so what this command
does is that it just paste from the
register one the register named one and
the other command just copy to the
register named one now this is a wrapper
to Emacs commands for example the Emacs
man let me show just show you the
webpage okay so here is the webpage
Emacs one key to copy paste from
register so remember E max has registers
many of them ABCDE and so on and one two
three four and so on so you call there
is a command let me show you the Emacs
version of the command so let's say ABC
okay I want to copy this to register a
for example okay so I select it I call
actually I have a shortcut I call okay
you see the left window it says copy to
register then look at the prompt mini
buffer Emacs asked me Emacs asked me to
type a name of a register to store this
text okay so let's say I say a okay now
it's done now this text is copied to
register a now let's call paste from
register okay you see the left panel
insert register okay so that means now
Emacs asked me to select the register
let's say a okay there you go
I have the ABC back so
so that is one way to use register you
can store text somewhat permanently okay
that's that's about register so but what
about this command I just created you
see whenever we call save to register or
copy register you know Emacs will prompt
you like you know prompt you which
register you want to save to or copy
from I find that cumbersome because
that's more keystrokes then you have to
loop look at that you know you have to
select register I find that most of the
time you just want to use one register
so what I want is I want to press a key
and store text some text into register
one always always just used register one
then press ENTER the key another key
which it will just paste whatever from
register one so that is what these
commands are for you know I wrote a
wrapper I demonstrated this you know
just been so that that's what these are
for now now that's about register okay
but register Emacs which is actually I
have a tutorial here so if you just go
to copy paste register like if you go to
practical Emacs it's all here you know I
feel sad people don't read it you know
so for example if you search for
register you can see okay here so
practical Emacs tutorial you go down you
go down and there is a section on
copy-paste all these tutorials are all
about copy and paste and there is a
section on copy to register you know so
we talked about copy to register and
insert register the default keys for
copy to register is control x RS okay
you know so you have complicated keys
okay that's about register now
registered there's more that more used
to register then then just install
than just saving plaintext you can also
save window configuration to register
like right now I have for example as I
have split pane like that
I want to revert to this spray-paint
config you can you can insert it to
register did you know you can do that
and I talked about that in this window
manage manage window topic somewhere
here you know the save split windows
configuration there it is you see window
configuration to register you call that
command ok
then when you want to restore the
configuration you call the command jump
to register I don't use those commands I
don't you know like I said you know
that's why I prefer sync you know window
you just you just create window
configure self not not one full screen
so that's about richest register now
when we're talking about register you
know one of the most actually the most
useful thing about register is to store
text but however if you really want a
permanent if you want a text to be
always available you want to use a
breathe instead so for example I go to
my abri so example for example let's
create a new one okay so here let's
magnify so XYZ use this because the
curse this is the best okay suppose this
is a text I want to be available all the
time like a template like a header
footer template copyright template for
your programming you know language or
your company's name or your
signature or whatever so you can store
it as a bleep let's say XYZ okay let's
just say x1
okay so eval is buffer okay close it new
buffer enlarge the window type x1 space
there you have it and this is gonna be
permanent in any in any buffer you know
new type x1 you're gonna have that so
this is a permanent way to a permanent
temporary system so this is one step
further better than using register so
you see they have different purposes
sometimes you don't want Tomlinson you
know like today you come across a piece
of text you are going to need often in
the next two hours let's say then you
use register okay close this don't save
go back to my a brief using bookmark
okay so we are back to them Maya brief I
don't want that anymore delete it save
eval close okay we are back okay I think
maybe that's it for today anything else
one hour and maybe that's it for today
anything else cool for school anything
am i anything Kathy I'm wondering if I
should continue anyway so if if you have
any topics just posted okay and
otherwise maybe that's it for today
let's see
Emacs Latin let's see I want and you
know I need to go to accept talk-show I
need to
relax and then we'll have actually a lot
interesting to say so yeah let's go back
to you max so you max - Romeo in each
setup there's a lot you know there's
lots of stuff you know the lots lots of
stuff you can learn and then this
section Emacs saw commands this is all
my personal commands efficient commands
you know if you use these commands all
these you will be more efficient than
anyone okay
for example opening file you know you if
I want a new new buffer you know
normally the traditional Emacs way is
you press control X P okay then you type
a random name let's say random whatever
random then what okay let's try it again
control X B wait is it control X control
B let's try control X control B okay so
it's okay one more time control X P then
type a random name then enter yeah this
is knowing about Emacs every time it
asks you for confirmation
confirmation yes so this is how you open
our new buffer you have to press ctrl X
P type a new random name then press
ENTER to confirm then you got a new
buffer no good okay now I want to delete
this file okay delete it okay so the way
I create new buffer is just press three
keys space CN okay space CN again space
yeah another one
spacey and I want no code combination no
control something oh I can press ctrl n
okay control a new buffer control inches
just like browser okay in browser
control and command n is
is a new window you know just like
browser a new window new window new
window close close close close okay same
thing Emacs like control and Annie and I
have lots of windows so yeah I have now
I have lit like tens of windows so you
can see I have all these untitled now I
want to delete them all okay X yes
no it's all good so that's about new
empty buffers so that's a command you
know it's much better than the Emacs one
and also I recommend I recommend never
ever use scratch scratch buffer is one
of the most idiotic okay you are coming
through Microsoft I key mod I mean okay
I know you are using Evo mod which is
very good
so for e Evo mod users and you if you go
through soft light key mod let's see
some packages sawfly keys there are some
functions there it could be useful but
you know Mac you you have to look at the
code like download the code and look at
the functions some actually actually you
know instead of looking at cracks off
like he's just looking at commands so
all these commands you know go to the
comments section all these commands oh
like basically all of them using some
fly keys they came from stuff like this
okay so if you want to look into what
command you might find useful for for
using Evo mod just go through this this
this these topics but I would I mean if
you are evil user you know evil mod I
think you would have
better more benefits if you just stick
with Evo's ways like looking in the Evo
community you know you know they have
their ways I mean if you spend you know
I mean suppose you have five hours to
spend the five hours you spend you know
go to the Evo community Eva my community
and find what you what do you need that
is time better spent then spending five
hours picking up commands for my for
myself i keys yeah I think that is true
or otherwise just teach teach Eva MA
okay spend one month learning stuff like
ease then you will be you will be more
efficient than Eva MA because that's
what stuff like his design for hello
honking sue
so actually okay so that's it for today
we don't have for a focused topic so
yeah so random chat so that's it for
today thank you guys for coming bye guys