Hello, good evening everyone. Welcome to
another episode of talk show. I talk and
show. So we are going to do wuam
language coding advent of code
day 8 2025. Let me show you my
keyboards. This is ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80.
Okay. And nia track ball and Logitech.
So I have reviews on YouTube. Just
search it. You'll find it. Okay. So
let's go to my screen. So let's go to my
screen. Advent of code 2025 day 8
with Wufam language. The most advanced
programming language.
Starting it. Let's see how it goes. You
know, as the days goes by, it'll get
more and more difficult. I hope you are
not going just going to stare at me
staring at the screen. So three shift
enter to start the kernel
and the magnify 250
starting the kernel. Uh how I hate the
Windows uh auto clip. You see when if
you turn it off then you don't have the
the key features. You see you can have
the keyboard features of uh auto
automatic clip.
So I want that but I don't want you know
I don't want when you drag to the edges
it automatically become uh full screen.
So that's annoying. So anyway there is
wang language and here is a band of
code. So all clear to go. So if you are
here watching it say hi love to see your
comments. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed minimum.
Okay. So let's prepare and let's see
let's uh see how we go how it goes.
Okay. Advent of code day eight
exploration.
Okay. So now so okay so we have
experience advent of code is very lousy
website because they they hardcoded
their website design. So you see when
your phone is large they you know they
they you have to then you have to scroll
the windows like you have to scroll
horizontal scroll very annoying
you know they don't they don't wrap
this is hardcoded website design okay
very bad okay anyway let's uh read it in
Emacs so today's talk show uh yes event
code uh day eight and this uh in the
past month or who we've been doing all
the advent of code. Some of the part two
we failed. So we didn't we failed. Uh
usually I mention it here. So day seven
part two we I failed. Uh I didn't
mention that in the title. I think that
one I failed. Okay. So well we can
complete it later but no worry. Uh so
anyway so so this so yeah so this is
today and let's uh start to um look at
um where where are we? So the the
okay so there problem okay uh start and
here's a problem so okay so blah blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah day eight okay let's let's just go
slowly okay so [clears throat]
uh
kasar
world wrap. I want to uh word wrap. You
see, I don't want this um you see when
when the line is too long beyond the
edges of the window. Emacs will do a
wrap, of course. Very nice. However, it
it wrap at you know uh it doesn't wrap
at the word boundary. So, I want to turn
the word boundary sago
uh word uh boundary. So, I have a
command somewhere. So I forgot what is
the key or the command name. So let's
look for it. Press space. Press um press
space and uh control H.
Then just search for word. Okay. Search
current word. Count words. I spell word.
I search for word. Word. Insert word.
Insert word toggle.
Uh word wrap. So space and space edge.
Space N. space edge. Fantastic and
beautiful. So that's a EMAC tip for
those of you Emacs users. Say hi. Okay,
if you are here. So let's see advent of
code. So equipped with a new
understanding of teleporter maintenance,
you confidently step into onto the
repaired teleporter pad. You m
rematerialize
on an unfamiliar teleporter pad and find
yourself in a vast underground space
which contains a giant playground. You
know that's incomprehensible. I don't
know what you're talking about. very
annoying advent of code story because
usually they are irrelevant like you can
skip you know the irrelevant like and
and also ugly story like they don't they
don't tell you something interesting u
you know it's just like irrelevant and
jarens you know there's no no
interesting thing going on stupid advent
of code but the problems the advent of
code the design you see the gist of the
advent of code of v of code is the
programming exercise. So, and so their
problem I would say is very good uh you
know they are not trivial and uh you
know each one takes like several hours
to do.
So the so you see to create the problem
you also one of the difficulty is that
you have to create the input. So
effectively the guy I'm certain he has
to write a program that generates the
inputs and the you know it's not it's
not trivial to generate these inputs
because you have to generate different
input for different people but the the
but the whatever you generate must be
valid input you know so there's there
are constraints so he creates a vend of
a code a problem for you but to generate
the valid input is a programming ex
exercise by itself, you know. So that's
I think that's interesting. Okay, so
let's move on. Let's see if we can
quickly solve this. Uh but you know, I I
want I I um I want to read read it.
Okay, the plan is to connect the
junction boxes with long strings of
lights. Most of the junction boxes don't
provide electricity. However, when two
junction boxes are connected by a string
of lights, electricity can pass between
those two junction boxes. Okay, junction
boxes. You want to connect them? The
elves are trying to figure out which
junction boxes to connect so that
electricity can reach every junction
box. Okay,
you got junction boxes and they you got
you need to connect them. They even have
a list of also another thing you can do
is you can uh put a break uh at places
where there's a period. So one sentence
per line that's a unit because sentence
is a semantic unit unit of English.
Okay. Uh anyway the elves are trying to
figure out which junction boxes to
connect so that electricity can reach
every junction box. So, so they have
they even have a list of all the
junction boxes positions in 3D space.
Okay.
So, I actually I started to read this. I
I spend like uh three minutes to read
this this before. So, I so now I know
this these are kind of um so anyway each
line is a three numbers and those
numbers are XYZ coordinates. So each
line essentially represent a point in
space. Okay. Is that right? Something
like that. The list describes the
position of 20 junctions. So let's uh
make it one line
per uh sentence. Okay.
So so there's your input.
Uh so the so the list describes the
position of 20 junction boxes. Why 20?
Because there are 20 lines I think. Yes,
exactly. Okay, one per line. Each
position is given as XYZ coordinates. So
the first junction box in the list is X1
162 817 812. Is that right? Yes. Okay.
So each one is a point. Each line is a
point. To save to save on string lights,
the elves would like to focus on
connecting pairs of junction boxes that
are as close together as possible
according to straight line distance.
Okay. So each one of these is a point in
3D space. So you you want to find um so
given you want to find so you got this
bunch of points you want to find like
closest pair something like that. Okay
in this example the two junction boxes
which are closest together are that and
that. Okay so you got a bunch of points.
Now each pair of points
has a distance between them. Now of all
these possible distances you want to
find the shortest one and then specify
which two points you know has that
distance. Okay. So that's these two
distance. Okay. So to find the distance
you you use a Pythagorean
Pythagorean theorem like twice. Okay. So
anyway so so by connecting these two
junction boxes together. So you you find
the nearest two points you connect them
uh by connecting because electricity can
flow between them they became part of
the same circuit something okay after
connecting them there is a single
circuit which contains two junction
boxes okay and the rema remaining 18
junction boxes remain in their own
individual circuits okay whatever that
means now the two junction boxes which
are closest together but aren't already
directly connected are
okay are that okay that's the the two
closest you know right
after connecting them
since this 162 something and is already
connected to another junction box there
is now a single circuit which contains
three junction boxes.
What?
Which contains three junction boxes and
an additional 17 circuits which contain
one junction box each.
What after connecting them since this
point is already connected to another
junction box is it?
Is it
okay? I don't get it. Okay, but let's
move on. The next two junction boxes to
connect are that and that. Okay, after
connecting them, there is a circuit
containing three junction boxes.
A circuit containing two junction boxes.
And okay, okay, I don't understand what
is going on. Then the next two junction
boxes are that because these two
something
uh because these two junction boxes are
already in the same circuit. So let's
highlight some numbers. Let's see. 431.
Okay. 431. So this point occurred
previously.
What about this 425?
It also occurred previously.
So already in the same circuit
something. Okay, then this process
continues for a while and elves are
concerned they don't have enough
extension cable for all these circuits.
They would like to know how big the
circuits will be. I don't understand.
After making the 10 shortest
connections, there are 11 circuits. One
circuit which contains five junction
boxes. One circuit contains four. Okay.
I don't understand. Your list contains
many junction boxes. Connect together
the 1,000
pairs of junction boxes which are
closest together. Afterwards, what what
do you get if you multiply together the
the sizes of the three largest circuits?
Okay. [snorts] Okay.
Uh I don't understand so far. So, so,
so I just know there's some, you know,
there's just two closest point. But
after that, what happens? So, you got
these points. Okay? They call it
junction boxes. Okay? Each point is a
junction box.
Okay? And uh Okay. And uh
so you want to connect pairs of junction
boxes. You want to connect points.
So so okay. And uh you want to connect
them the the you want to pick two points
that's the closest. Okay.
So you see this problem. Let's see how
large is our input because then you have
combinatorial um pairings. So
if you have 20 of points then what are
the possible um
pairings? Let's say
20 * 19. Yeah, that would be 20
factorial.
So if you have 20 points, how many
possible um
pairings are there?
Wait, no, not 20 factorial. So uh 20
something like 20 * 19.
What?
Okay.
So, the first one you you have 20
points. Okay, you pick the first one. 20
possibilities.
Then you got 19 possibilities. Okay.
Then
so,
so we talking about how many possible
edges are there? Um
so the first line will be uh
19 that's 20 minus one.
Now the second then you need to uh
h so this is not actually [laughter]
now I need to draw okay so you know so I
need to draw this is like
but anyway I don't think this problem is
asking that but um
so let's see open with open with
snipping pin sniping. Let's do that.
You know, just suppose um you got
let's say one, two, three, four.
So you got four total. Okay. So the
first one you want to try one, two,
three. So that's three possibilities.
Okay. And then you got then the let's
label them. One,
two.
Wait. Uh, where's undo? Where is my
undo? Can you see it? Okay.
Two.
It's name three name then three four.
Okay. That's the name of the nod. Okay.
Um and
okay we can do prettier. That's the
first one. Okay. And uh we can
so the you then the first one is one two
three. The second one is uh two three.
So second one has two possibilities. One
two
three. So the first one
or not. Okay. So the first one has three
possibilities.
The second one has how many
possibilities? Just two. Okay. Then the
third one has only one possibility.
Yeah. So if you have 20 knots then then
then the um the
so you add them together right? So 3 + 2
+ 1 5 1 2 3 4 5 6 3 + 2 + 1 six one two
So right. So you see 1 2 3 4 5 six
edges. So if you have 20 nodes
then you're going to have uh
19 + 18 plus um so that would be
sum okay we are digressing we are not
doing the problem but um
sum x from 1 to 18.
Wait, X. You need to say X. Okay.
190. Okay. So,
[clears throat]
if you're going to brute force the
problem, you got a you got 190 uh
distance to measure, which is not too
bad.
190 distance to measure. Okay. Not too
But that's
for 20. But how many do you have? Then
let's go to my personal input. Let's
see. Okay. Select all. Copy. Back to
Emacs.
Go to talk show. Search for text. Okay.
We prepared this file. File. Save it.
1,00.
Okay. Save it. So, if you got 1,000, I'm
pretty sure
uh
you got 500,000 pairings.
Good evening, Aspiring Windows. Hi, good
morning. Hello. Hello, coffee. Coffee
and uh coffee and aspiring window
compositor. You guys are from
Scandinavia, Northern Europe somewhere
or somewhere. You know, I always get
confused which one is which. The Sweden,
Finland, Norway, Norway is in the
middle. Finland is on the right near
Russia. Uh on the left is uh Sweden or
Swiss, you know, it's very confusing
names. You got Swiss, you you got
Switzerland, you got Sweden, you got
also Holland,
but anyway, I think it's um it's uh
and aspiring window manager. Yes, India.
I was about to say.
So anyway, uh so yeah, so so we got you
know, we are digressing. Okay, so
so anyway, so we don't understand the
problem yet actually. So, we got
Yeah, we don't understand the problem.
So, what what is the problem? God [ __ ]
Have you guys So, have you guys uh So,
we got more people. Hi, AC from Fairfax,
Virginia. Fairfax. I I I don't know
where is Fairfax.
Virginia. Uh VA is Virginia, right? I
believe
uh that's the like on the east side of
USA.
Um so anyway, so this problem [ __ ] you
know we spend like how many we spend 30
30 minutes and we don't know what's
going on yet. So we got bunch of points
and you you and okay so you got so we
got list of coordinates each one is XYZ
coordinate. you got 20 of them in the
sample input. Okay. So, you want to find
the the uh
you want to find uh
a pair of them that are closest, you
know, the the the the least distance.
Okay. So, in order to do that,
so so we already have a problem. You
know, let's say you got a bunch of
points. You want to find the the the two
points that's the closest. Okay.
Uh but if you have
let's see how many am I am I correct in
this measurement.
You see I think I am
like do you guys see?
So this is about you know you can you
can this is a simple um
um
graph theory problem. So given n knots
how many edges how many possible edges
are there?
I think it's just uh the sum summation
of the number of knots. Okay.
Uh if you go to Wikipedia it'll tell you
right away and you can also ask gu. But
let's check our math again. So uh see
four you know we start with four nodes.
So 1 2 3 then the second one is one two
the third one is one.
Yeah. So the second one right? So one
two. Yeah. So basically uh then you sum
them up. So you sum them.
Now is there a name for this sequential
sum like 1 + 2 + 3? I know if they are
multiplication that's factorial but I
forgot you know this math.
Um
okay let's let's just digress then.
Let's ask uh guac
where is where is guac?
Okay. It's uh here. Okay. So let's ask
oak
[laughter]
given n
how many edges
are there?
Okay will answer it I'm pretty sure.
magnify.
Okay. Given end nodes with no self loops
and no multiple edges between. Okay.
Then the answer is what? Factorial n
minus what the [ __ ] is uh
this um
oh yeah so that I think that's you know
that's the um
that is the uh you know so if you change
this to n that will give you the formula
basically n * n n minus - one not
directed. Okay. Undirected symbol. Yeah.
N * n minus one divided by 2 fac. Is
that right? So this it will give you
symbolic result. Okay. Yep. It not
factorial fraction this. Okay. So so we
are learning several things. For one
thing the guac is not showing the
formula correctly. It's not rendered
rendering them correctly. That's uh lat
tech
format which sucks. Okay. This damage
from Donald Gruth.
We you know became very popular because
it's free like cigarette given to
children you know that's a huge damage
to computing industry this tech. Okay.
And uh damaged to mathematicians like
widely adopted.
If you want to know more about that,
search on.info
on why latte sucks or why tech sucks. I
have an article on that. Okay, so
anyway, so the given nodes,
how many possible edges are there? The
that this is a solution. Okay, you just
sum this one to n and uh you have a
closed form. So that's 1 /
2 * n * n uh uh emphasis one. Okay. So,
so that answered one question and uh so
uh so we have if we have 1,000
nodes which is my input then I have to
do 500,000
times of checking the distance which is
500,000 not too big we can do it I mean
uh so that's a brute force way.
So, we don't, you know, we don't know
exactly what's the problem yet, but we
do know that we absolutely have to find
one pair that's closest. Is that right?
Actually, we don't even know that
we just digressing talk show of
digression. Okay. Oh, [ __ ]
So, are you guys making sense? Am I
making sense here?
So what is the problem yet? We don't
know. But
okay, have you guys done the problem?
So in this example, the two junction
boxes which are close together. Okay. By
connecting these two junction. So you do
have to it looks like you do have to
find at least one pair that's the
closest. Okay. Now what what are some
other ways to find the closest you know?
So
let's see um
you know we we are in 3D space is there
some like shortcut
uh obviously
you know if the coordinate are all equal
then you know one one thing we can do is
we check if any two coordinates let's
say the x coordinates are equal
then that means the two points lies in
the same plane.
Okay. Then then must then it could be
shorter. But um
so but then if we find two points such
that two of their coordinates are equal
then that means they they lie not on the
same only not they lie in the same plane
but they also lie in the same axis. So
their distance is simply the difference
of the third coordinate.
Okay.
So you don't have to do the square root
you know the normal distance formula of
basically x^2 + y^2 + z² then square
root
but I mean but that's uh not many
operations needed. So, if you're going
to do this for 1,000 um
you know, if you have 1,000 points, then
you're going to do this 500,000 times,
then you just compare, pick the
shortest. But what? Okay. So, anyway, so
what is the problem then? By connecting
these two junction boxes together
because electricity can flow between
them they become part of the same
circuit. Okay. Like whatever
uh after after connecting them there is
a single circuit which contains two
junction boxes and the remaining 18
junction boxes remain in their own
individual circles. Okay. Circuits.
Okay. Whatever
uh northern Virginia in DC. Oh yeah,
it's uh near DC. Uh what's about the
binomial formula? Binomial formula is
just um
but well I don't I don't know so I
forgot you know. So anyway so but um but
where is it? So you are looking at the
brave. So what is the brave saying? Oh
[ __ ] So brave is saying that okay so
you got a formula undirected okay then
if you want directed you got that
formula if you want undirected but you
do include self loops that is the point
connecting it to itself like you make a
loop then you then then it's binomial
formula if you want directed and self
loop allowed then it's that [snorts] and
if you have undirect okay you know So
that's you know that's graph theory but
the most common you know the most the
the normal in the normal graph is just
this okay undirected and simple okay you
don't have like a point connect to
itself nor do you have directed arrows
okay you just you know simple just like
we the way we did it okay like you know
you just connect dots
so the binomial formula it says if you
have this condition then that formula
comes up. Okay, binomial formula is a
formula when you multiply
uh binomial a polomial
of two terms okay that you get the exp
that's how you count the exponential or
you can get that from Pascal's triangle
so if you don't know about that look up
okay Pascal's triangle
okay so anyway so the so we uh so so We
read the problem, but we don't
understand the problem yet. So, we know
you need to find two points that's
closest.
Okay. Then what? Um,
so you so there are 20 points, right? So
in this example, copy copy new. So there
are 20 points there. Okay. 20. So now if
you found two of them that's the
closest. Okay.
Then what?
Why does it say this is already
connected to another? I don't understand
this 162.
There is now a single circuit which
contains the three junction boxes. So
where is this 162 connected to?
It didn't say like what the [ __ ] is this
stupid elves and [ __ ]
Equipped with a new understanding of
teleporter maintenance, you confidently
step onto the repair teleporter pad. You
[snorts] rematerialize
on an unfamiliar teleporter pad and uh
find yourself in a vast underground
space which contains a giant playground.
Okay. Across the playground, a group of
elves are working on setting up an
ambitious Christmas [ __ ] Through
careful rigging, they have suspended a
large number of small electrical
junction boxes. Suspended. Okay, their
plan is to connect the junction boxes
with long strings of lights. Okay, most
of the junction boxes don't provide
electricity.
However, when two junction boxes are
connected by a string of lights,
electricity can pass between two. Okay,
the elves are trying to figure out which
junction boxes to connect so that
electricity can reach every junction
box.
Okay, they even have a list of all the
junction boxes positions. Okay, so this
you got a bunch of points. The list
describe the positions of 20 junction
boxes. Okay,
so you connected a pair of them. Then it
says
after connecting them there is a single
circuit which contains two junction
boxes and the remaining remaining 18.
Okay. So wait, so you connected these
two then? Okay, so there's another new
pair involving the first point.
Okay, so 162 A17 A12. Okay, there it is.
So once you connect these two, then it
says now the two junction boxes which
are closest together but aren't already
directed connected. Okay. So once you
find two closest
then you look at the rest. Uh wait,
you see this 162
is already connected.
I don't understand what the [ __ ] is
this.
Do you guys understand?
Have you guys done the advent of code
day eight?
Very annoying. You know, you know, we
spent like 30 minutes and we don't
understand the problem yet.
Junction boxes
[sighs] uh after connecting them since
that is already connected to another
junction box. There's now a single. So,
so these two are closest. Then it's
claiming
now it's claiming these two are closest
the second closest. So which involves
one of the same point in the first pair.
Okay, that's what it's trying to claim.
The two junction boxes which are closest
together but aren't already directly
connected.
Okay. So he claims this is a second pair
among all the pairs
and and they are not already connect
directly connected between these two.
Okay. So after so you so now it's saying
that you you you make a connection you
connect these two
since that is already connect to another
there is now a single circuit which
contains three junction boxes. Okay. So
you you find you find another pair
that's closest.
Then
if if this new pair contains already
contains a point in your previous then
you know then they are like together.
Okay. Otherwise not.
Okay. So the next two junction boxes to
connect are these two. Okay.
Then after connecting them there is a
circuit contain containing three
junction boxes. Circuit containing two
junction boxes
and 15. Okay. So basically
you find the list of pairs
the edges by their distance. Okay. So in
other words, each edge between two
points has a has a weight. That's the
distance between them. So you rank them
from the smallest first. So you once you
have the smallest, you know, they form a
pair, you consider them connected. So
every time you add a new pair
of closest, you go through the rank. You
know every time you add a pair you
consider how many disjoint
graphs are there
something like that. Um
yeah how many disjoint you know
so let's see um
AC says the goal is to connect all nodes
into one big circuit using the shortest
amount of edges possible meaning we need
to always connect to closest nodes that
aren't already connected. Oh,
so looks like you have read the problem
and uh you found the uh Looks like
[laughter]
you you beat me. So, but let me So, are
you going to solve it? Can you like can
you solve it in whatever language? What
language do you use?
Can you can you solve it? I'm I'm I'm
slow. I'm kind of slow. [laughter]
So anyway, so
so you are saying, you know, I'm going
to connect all nodes into one big
circuit
using the shortest amount of edges
possible.
Okay, I don't quite get it though.
So you see, so each edge has a distance.
I'm thinking alone. Okay. So, see if you
can solve it uh using mm uh wam
language. I didn't know you also using
wam language. Okay. You might have
mentioned but I don't know.
So anyway, so so yeah, let me continue
to read um you know the way I understand
it
uh analysis like this is the
interpretation part you know even this
is even before actually we already did
some analysis we already did some
partial analysis but we don't fully
understand the problem yet
so it's saying the next two junction
boxes that after connecting them the
circuits containing three junction
boxes.
Okay. Then next the next two is that
because these two junction boxes were
already in the same circuit nothing
happens.
Okay.
The process continues for a while and
elves are concerned they are they don't
have enough extension cables. They would
like to know how big the circuit will
be.
After making the 10 shortest
connections, there are 11 circuits.
Okay? Meaning that there are 11 distinct
disjoint
graphs.
That's you know and circuit is also a
technical term in graph theory. So it's
just like they are connected group.
Okay. So so so after making 10 shortest
connections. So you follow you go
through the shortest
you simply go through each shortest you
know rank them. Then after you did 10 of
them let's see what is the
configuration. So it turns out there are
11 circuits. So 11 separate groups. One
circuit which contains five junction you
know. So, so one group you have five
dots. They are all connected in some
way. Another group
contains four junction box. So, so, so
wait there's a there's a difference.
Okay. So, in graph theory a circuit is a
loop but in here it is not. It's simply
you know for you know so for example if
I have
you know so there there's a difference
okay so if I can do another screenshot
there's a difference
let's let's be elaborate okay let me
just draw and uh and just talk okay so
in graph theory
Let's magnify. You need to magnify this.
Yeah. Jesus.
So if you have a point point
uh point, okay, in graph theory,
a circuit is when they form a loop.
Okay. But
let's say one, two, three, four. One,
two, three, four.
One, two, three, four. Okay. But so in
graph theory, a circuit is a loop. I'm
pretty sure. But here,
this elves elves thing, a circuit may be
may not be a a a loop. It may be just
like that. It's like a, you know, it's
just just just that they are all
connected.
So it's just called connected. Okay.
Okay, I think that's a proper term. Um,
so save this. Okay, so
so it's a bit confusing.
Um,
so let's go back to the problem. Okay.
so let me let me let me try to
understand. Let me hold on a second. Let
me I mean read the comment later. So So
anyway, so after so you go through the
ranking of distances, you connect them
you know one by one. So after you made
10 of them. So there are 11 groups. 11
uh groups. Okay. One of them contain
five points. One one of them contain
four points. Uh and and two of them each
has two points. Okay. So basically like
just pair of points like they are single
lines.
Um you know you got two of them and then
you got seven of them. Each one is a
single junction boxes. So meaning that
they are just seven. They are remaining
seven points that's not connected at
all.
Then it says multiplying together sizes
of the three largest circuits.
Okay. 54 and one of the circuit of size
two. So you multiply uh together the
size of the three largest produces 40.
Tricky. Why three? You know, so it's
getting into magic numbers in
programmer's jargon. You have these
magic numbers.
You got two magic numbers. First of all,
it's just you pick the top 10. Why 10?
It's not specified. Just pick the
connect the top 10 shortest. Okay, just
do that. Then after you do that, then
you pick the three largest,
you know, so-called circuits.
Okay, then you multiply them, you got
40. Okay, your list contains many
junction boxes. Connect together the the
first 1,000 pairs of the junction boxes
which are closest together. Okay, I
think I understand the problem now.
Afterwards, what do you get if you
multiply together the sizes of the three
largest circuits? Okay.
So the problem is
more straightforward than I thought.
Basically you just so you give you are
given a bunch of dots in three space.
You want to find you want to compute all
the distances.
You want to find the the top uh how
many? The top uh 1,000. Okay. You want
to find the top 1,000 shortest
distances.
Okay. Then
the top 1,00 shortest distances. Then
you then you have to like then you have
to connect them. Oh god. So the problem
is not so trivial.
First part of the problem is to find
these top 10,00 shortest distances.
Then you connect them. Meaning that you
you want to find all these distances
which one shares the same point. So you
are basically you are building a group.
I mean not group you are building a
graph.
Okay.
So you you are you are actually building
a graph. Then you want to know you know
you want to know which one is separate
which one is not. So you form several
you know
uh
disjoint
graphs
then you pick the top three that's got
the most number of points and just
multiply them. Okay. Uh yeah I
understand the problem and the problem
is not easy. We're going to do it
tomorrow.
So, let's see. AC.
Yes. Wan language. That's why I love
your work. Thank you. So, Wuan language.
Yes. Fantastic. May we maybe we should
uh start by looking at all nodes. Find
the two that are close together. Connect
them. Yeah. Start somewhere. That's good
approach. Now, we have one pair and n
minus one. That's right.
Yeah. So we can start to work on that.
Oh god. This problem you know. So
[laughter]
we are correct. We have to.
So the first problem you know let's we
can we can write it out. So we we're not
going to do this today. We we just
analyze the problem. Okay. Today the
problem is to analyze the problem.
So problem
actually so let's see let's say
okay so we
cut close and open that paste it okay
that's a problem description and
unedited by me okay so we got that so
now analysis of the problem
two parts Let's
first
find the
least of uh
shortest
distances among the points. Okay.
Find the top 10 one uh top 1,000
shortest distance among the points.
Okay,
that's that's that's that's one that's a
big problem. That's the first problem.
Okay,
then rank them
shortest come first. Okay.
Uh yeah, of course that's kind of
together. That's one problem.
Okay. Then
for each
start from the shortest
connect
uh
the points um
do this for
all the 1K
uh distances you found.
The result
is a
bunch
of this joint
graphs. Okay, it it may be this joint,
it may not be.
So
it you know it's possible that all of
them got connected.
Is it possible? Actually we don't know
that depends on the number of nodes and
you know we are going to connect
basically we have 1,000 edges we're
going to connect but how many how many
um
yeah I think we have 1,000 nodes right
so let's search for
how many uh yeah we have exactly one
1,00 points so it may so happens that it
just becomes a line so then everything
is connected it
then then the answer is just you know
the top three is just 1,00. So 1,00
times oh it's tricky because it says
find the top three. So
it may so happens that the whole result
is one one single graph one single line
connect them all. So, so the first group
will have 1,000 items.
Then the second group will um let's see
let's look at the problem the problem
you know. So the first group
multiply you know so what do you do get
if you multiply together sizes of the
three largest circuits. Okay, so the
first largest circuit is 1,000 points
1,00. So you want to m multiply that by
the second largest circuit which is
none.
So the size is zero. So 1,00 multiply by
0 is zero and again so it's zero. So
it's it's zero.
That's one possible answer. Okay, that
if it so happens that all your points,
you know, 10,00 points are connected by
10,000 lines.
Okay, but okay. So, let's go back to our
analysis.
Where where is our analysis? So,
problem is pick the three
largest
disjoint graphs
multiply
their sizes.
That's what they want. Okay.
Okay. So, well, so the first problem
find the distances. So, we have to we're
going to code this like tomorrow,
but we can think about it now. So,
uh
you know, so Wuam language they have
like 1,000 building functions on graph.
So maybe [laughter]
maybe it's just like already building
function
um you know because
that's true you know so because we can
look at so this gives us a opportunity
to um let's go to wuam documentation to
learn about graph theory it's been quite
a while when I did graph theory so you
know so they have a dedicated section on
graph and networks.
Okay. Uh construction and representation
and visualization which is the most
fancy uh you know
visualization we can
uh but okay so but they so let's see uh
graph and networks. So what do you have?
So you got graph
graph data. So you got you know you got
quite a few
and uh so anyway so let's go back to our
problem. So what uh can we do find you
know find the uh
oh it's a bit tricky. So if we do by
brute force then we have to do this
500,000 times
500,000 times which is doable in a few
seconds
uh because of computing power right
and uh and the distance is just going to
the distance by the way if you haven't
that the distance is just this formula
okay x2.
Um well actually so the distance let me
write it down here
A B C okay that's a point let's say
that's coordinate and uh x
uh y z
is okay so basically basically
is uh so let me show you how to do this
quickly in wam language that and square
root of it. Okay.
Okay. So let's do let's do that. Okay.
Copy that pop out. So comment and uh so
wait uh okay. So warm language.
So comment the distance between that
that is we can compute that just that
that that that's a solution. Okay. Do
it.
It'll show you the actual formula.
Uh no
wait. Uh
you you need to do the sum. You forgot
not not square root. Okay. Uh,
you need to do
is that right?
That's right. Okay. So, that that's the
formula. Okay. That's a formula for
computing the distance between two
BD coordinate corn coordinates. Okay.
Right. So we can so we need to do this
for 500,000 times
which is easy. You finish in few
seconds.
Um then we just sort them 500,000. Can
you uh so how many? So if you let's say
array how many items can you have before
your browser will crash
500,000
items.
You can ask guac or you can try it. Um
where is guac
and see a new guac.
Uh no I don't want to go history. Okay.
Go new. Uh,
would browser crash if I have 5,000k
items
in a array?
Yes, the browser will very often crash
or become completely unresponsive for a
long time. Oh, if you try to create an
array with 500,000
elements, but it heavily depends. Okay,
so actually you cannot do this brute
force.
Well, actually yeah. So um
do you use uh old tab? Uh yes because
well no because I have uh hoover click
auto you know I hoover the mouse pointer
to whatever windows it will
automatically activate that window. Okay
so this is supremely convenient. I
highly recommend it. That's why you see
all my windows, you can you can see they
always have a little area that's exposed
that allows me to easily switch to all
my windows. I just you see can you see
my mouse hand you know like you can
oops
you see I can just move you know so this
is supremely uh hand saver if you have
hand pen. Okay, I highly recommend it.
How to do that? You can do that on
Windows, on Mac and on Linux. Uh if you
search my website for example today's
talk show, go to my uh keyboard page. Uh
you'll find all kind of you will find
tutorials
uh programming keys. Okay, that's how
you you can find it. you know, configure
keyboard and mouse for Windows, Linux,
Mac, everything you want to know in EMAs
and all sticky keys and mouse uh
autoclick how you do it on Windows,
Linux or Mac how to it's fully detailed
there. Okay, so highly recommend that.
Uh otherwise, you know, otherwise I have
a a key shortcut. This key I press,
you'll just go to the last window. Okay.
So anyway,
okay. So, um Okay. So, I think that's
it. So, we learned, you know, we
actually you you can't really do this
brute force. So, it's a bit tricky uh
because 500,000 items will crash
browser.
I mean you I mean you can have more
memory but I mean so typically no you
shouldn't you know uh it'll crash most
people's browser if you have 500,000
items I think I think grog is
you know you can try it you know we can
actually just try it now um
but yeah probably so you don't want to
do brute force and also you want the
first 1,000 of them you don't want you
know So,
so what do you have to do to optimize
you know so you first of all you find
for each of the point you find
you try to find it so that so that they
um let's put this back
uh
yeah so that's the solution yeah
put it back syntax color showing browser
go down so you can So let's go to the
problem. Uh
so let's look at um
yeah I mean so so they so you
in your problem you want the first 1000
of them. So basically you want to
compare find find two points such that
they have the same
xcoordinate.
they share one or more
uh coordinates, okay? Like identical
ycoordinate or identical x coordinate or
or z. So once they share a coordinate,
it's it's more likely they are shorter.
If they share two coordinates, it's even
more it's it's it's very likely they are
among the top 10,00. Okay. Shortest
because
Yeah. But but this doesn't does not
guarantee though. Yeah, it is true. It
doesn't guarantee it'll be shortest
because you see this is tricky. So in
three space you can imagine two very
close points
but they don't they don't share
coordinate. They are not on the same XY
or Z-axis direction. Nor are they in the
same like orthogonal plane. They are
like diagonal to each other. So they
don't share anything. They don't share
any of the coordinates. So but but
imagine they are very close together.
Meanwhile you can have other points they
share the same like x-axis direction or
y or z
but they are further apart. So,
so by by by trying to find the same
coordinate does not guarantee
that the first shortest
1,000 of them is going to be like that.
In fact, the first 1,000 shortest
bunch of numbers may none of them share
any coordinate. Imagine all of them are
inside this ball, you know. Imagine all
of them are inside this ball while all
the rest numbers like on a grid. They
share coordinates. But then you got this
10,000, you know, lots of numbers inside
this tiny bowl. So,
okay. So, this is interesting question.
The first problem is how do you find the
first shortest distances
you know you you can try to find the
shared coordinate but that doesn't
guarantee your work
Jesus
so this is a computational geometry
problem actually I don't know what is
the solution I don't I'm guessing there
is no propos solution other than just
brute force.
Very interesting computational geometry
problem. We can ask guac. Okay,
let's let's try
uh
let's see
this
first part about finding list of
shortest
distances is a classic
computational
geometry problem.
Okay, let's ask a book.
Given end points
in space in in in
3D space okay in actually it works in 2D
too. So let's just say 2D. Let's make it
simple. given end points in two 2D
space. Uh
that's a good
algorithm to find the top 10 shortest
distances between
any two points.
Okay, let's ask guac. Let's see AI how
advanced are you and also teach me
computational geometry let's see
given end points in two space 2D space
what is a good algorithm to find the top
10 shortest okay are you going to do is
it going to brute force
here's the most practical and efficient
approaches to find the top 10 shortest
distances the 10 smallest is pair-wise
distances plus the corresponding pairs
among end points in 2D ordered from best
to worst in terms of practicality versus
a symptoic performance. fantastic
fully addressed solution is telling us
quick rank ranking approaches okay and
even a year perspective okay uh and less
than 5,000 okay brute force [laughter]
if if n is less than 5,000 which is true
for our problem it says brute force
[laughter]
If if n is less than 50,000
then we have to do kd tree all pairs k n
then it's going to be n
log n + n * n
complexity uh Jesus if n is less than
few million divide and conquer
Jesus basically it just says brute force
what the [ __ ] [ __ ]
[laughter]
I think that's the that's we need to
calculate the distance between every
possible pair then sort all pairs from
shorties. Yeah, that's that's brute
force.
Do you use all tab? Okay. Okay. I think
that's that's it for today. Um, so we're
going to try to code it tomorrow.
Actually, we need to think about more
about this. I mean, are we going to just
brute force it? That's crazy.
I don't suppose, you know, advent of
code, they're going to
ask you to brute force
uh 500,000.
Okay. If you keep all the possible pairs
in your array, then your array it'll
crash the computer, right? But you don't
you only they only want the top 1,000
shortest distances. That's what they
want. They don't want the entire you
know
500,000
possible pairs between two points,
right?
So um
so maybe brute force is the only way I I
mean I can't think of the other any
other way just except brute force.
Okay. But and but the but the problem is
more than that. Once you find this list
of shortest distances, you have to
um then you have to like
you have to basically build the graph to
you know
then that's another thing that's that's
require thinking you know how do you
build a graph and you need to you need
to have a data structure
Oh yeah. So, so every time you started
to have a connection between two points,
you put these two points into a group uh
let's say
array array of these two points.
Also, it would be helpful if you label
each point. Give them them a name like
by the index. That's nice. So you can
say say you know 0.1 connect to 11
right. So you so each index is got a
coordinate for that point then you can
build a group um you can build the graph
by
put them into array. So array is a list
of indexes
uh list of pairs of indexes means that
they are connected. So when you have one
array that means all these are
connected.
Okay. So at at the end you want to find
the the the the one array with the
with the
unique number of point indexes. So you
need to like merge them merge the edges
and just count the indexes unique ones
find to find the largest.
Then you pick the largest three and
multiply them together. I think we got
the algorithm basically. So, but um
yeah, but we're gonna do it tomorrow
then. I mean, maybe you after tomorrow,
but we're going to do it next.
Yeah, brute force. Good luck, guys. Good
luck, AC. Let's see. You know, so don't
don't rely on me. So you guys going to
go walk, you know, go walk in your
favorite programming language. You can
do it in Python, in JavaScript, in
Goland, in F, in C, in whatever you
think is the best Rust Rust lens. Um,
very interesting. Okay, so that's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching. Bye
guys.
It was a you know, we didn't do we
didn't code anything, but it's
interesting. It's like reading poetry,
you know, [laughter]
we avoid the hard part. The hard part is
the actual coding, but we can talk about
the problem. You know, it's like people
talk about like philosophy
uh okay by
so I'm shutting down. So shut down. So
let's see.
plus that. Okay. And this is we drew the
graph and we need to put the graph um
into our uh screenshot
into our talk show so that people can
later uh so uh so this delete.
Okay. So now this today's talk show and
let's put the
uh screenshot here.
Fantastic my fantastic Emacs command.
Can you see that somewhere there? Okay.
Showing browser. So we did the
screenshot explaining about our approach
the graph theory. Fantastic.
And for you programmers, AC and Oh
Jesus, AC is already giving out a
solution. Wow.
Wow. Fantastic. Is that Wait
compression? What?
Rank rank equals to constant array.
What? That doesn't make sense to me.
What are you doing? So anyway, so we
going to
Okay, so that's it for today. So, uh,
let me just I'm going to shut down.
Thank you guys for watching.
Um
I
So yeah, AC I'm not sure what what what
code are you posting? What? That doesn't
look like solution to me. What
I mean maybe that's part of the you know
whatever you are doing. Anyway, bye.