thank you
hello guys welcome to another episode of
guitar talk show
check check am I alive yes and look at
my fantastic keyboard This is glove 80.
glove 80 keyboard okay I just got it
today but today we are going to do emac
live emac Beast live coding
we are going to continue
uh coding emac this writing a python mod
from scratch part two so continue from
two days ago also uh but you know the
first few minutes let me show you guys I
got this new keyboard you can read about
it or on my website or here okay so so
this is new I I don't have it connected
yet so I'm just showing you but anyway
this is glove 80 keyboard okay I have it
now uh wait can you see it actually you
cannot see it so I need to switch
yeah okay just a glove 80 okay let me
just show you a little bit around okay
so this this you know my first
impression I'm gonna talk about this
keyboard for three minutes or so I'm
gonna do review I'm gonna use it and
review later on okay so watch my videos
but this is Club 80 so my first
impression is that it's it's it's
a super light okay light and delicate
and
light okay I mean you know some people
like them heavy like grandfather clock I
don't like that I like them super light
and this so this is fantastic super
light my first impression super light
elegant
um
and uh
delicate okay so so this uh Palm
rest you can uh unscrew and take and
take them out you know it's removable so
it's super light I love them that way
fantastic okay
uh and the seems tiny I mean you know it
it does so it doesn't you know when you
look at the picture you you know you
compared to the Kinesis Advantage for
example that is huge so this is super uh
kind of small
uh and uh you know so fantastic I'm
gonna you know review and uh tell you
guys about it the you know so so let me
put them away
and let me show you my website about you
know some information about this
keyboard okay fantastic glove 80 okay
thanks to the glove 80 people
um they sent me one
okay so now let's go back to the um our
regular program so let me put the
keyboard back my you know my current
keyboard which is set up
you know my my desk is messy I have a
huge desk but it's
you know every corner is filled with
stuff so let me put my uh keyboard back
and put the
this pen box under so I have negative
tilt
and cigarette box makes you live longer
okay
now my uh yeah so
put them back the way they are so now I
can walk
okay so now let's switch back to my
normal setup
yeah so no more Marcos
okay so now
so first of all let me talk about this
keyboard okay just search my website
glove8 you'll find it and this is new
photos I just took a moment ago so and
you know I just unboxed it so it's
fantastic my first impression so you
know the curve beautiful curves
uh and the key switch is uh chalk switch
chocolate switch okay and so you can see
so my first impression is it's it's uh
elegant delicate and uh super light I
like it very much okay
so uh this is the box and uh yeah so go
check out my website and check out their
videos I'm gonna do a review myself and
gonna fully integrate with stuff like
he's you know I'm gonna program them
it's programmable and and it's a
Bluetooth wireless okay
uh it's Bluetooth
uh yes and uh anyway find the details go
to their website okay more ago
moreogo.com you you can find JavaScript
and you can find all the details about
it
okay that's about more ago uh keyboard
now we are going to go back to our main
program which is code emac we continue
from yesterday okay
Okay so
so let's see let me let me see uh ready
uh ready you guys ready
yeah video audio check okay so on the
pink window is my Emax command course
and the keystrokes I'm using a workout
keyboard and the the keyboard I'm using
now is Xbox okay
okay let's continue from yesterday uh
continue yeah so
so we gonna continue code
python mod from scratch so first of all
let's show the code uh if you go you
know you can go to my Saudi talk show
search it you'll find uh two days ago
we did the first one
I mean we did you know in that video we
coded uh Evac uh emac with python major
mod from scratch and now let's go to
find that package our code
so our code search for python so there
it is python mod make a backup so here
is a code
now it's pretty simple Okay so yesterday
or we have just 50 lines of code
and we did syntax coloring of these two
uh class of keywords okay now
syntax curling we have that and we also
did
um yeah so this part
you know this this these three lines are
basically for syntax coloring
all you have to do let me let me recap
what we all you have to do is set up
this variable
and then set that variable to uh here
font lock defaults that's all you have
to do for syntax coloring
then the other part is coloring comments
and string okay and that part is this
section we talked about yesterday you
know all those those lines Plus
plus this line will
will make your major mod have syntax
coloring for comments and string okay
we explained yesterday why you know why
you have to do them different ways the
traditional the synax syntax colony is
done by regular expression but the
syntax color info comments and string
are done by setting up a syntax table
okay so that's our code yesterday so
let's go to uh
tutorial there's a section
how to write the major mod and this is
the video we did yesterday and last year
we did one for Golan okay and so we're
gonna continue to continue continue from
yesterday so copy that let me copy that
let me get ready to code so go to guitar
talk show
so this is today
I think yeah
so paste the link there
so we have a reference
to it okay then go to the
um close that go to go back to the this
code paste it here so we can easily jump
to it okay so let's continue from
yesterday
so yesterday
you know writing a major mod we did we
did the syntax coloring uh which used
font lock mod and we explained a little
bit about how you know defining a face
and how to color comments in stream and
we also did a how to write a common
uncommon command which is just these two
lines very simple
when you when you know how to do it okay
uh okay so so far we have syntax going
and we have common and uncommon command
now there are more things to do of
course
yeah of course and yesterday we added
this line which makes it
so that whenever user opens a file
ending in dot py it will open in your
new in your mod okay so we did that this
yesterday
now more to do so what to do what are
the things you need to do
to do okay so
so the other important thing we need we
want to do is uh to write a keyword
completion okay
we're gonna write that okay and the
keyword completion if you want to read
it you can just uh read it from my
website keyword completion and uh
we
also need to create key map so what's a
key map you know basically in a major
mod for example if you use org mod or
whatever let's see a new buffer
metax org mod okay so now we are in
ogmod
God why is ogma taking a while to load
okay oh come on okay I don't use much
myself so you can see
um now in ogmod in any major mod you can
press Ctrl H M
to look at the documentation for that
major mod so you can see here's the hook
mod documentation so in each major mod
typically you have lots of keys that's
just for this mod you know so in Walmart
you have all these meta X meta shift X
meter shift
arrow keys and you know lots of
typically they begin with Ctrl C then
control something okay major amount keys
so these keys will only will be specific
for the major mod
so if you are going to write a a new
major mod for programming language you
need
of course you need these major Mark keys
that is why we need to do
um how to how to create key map for
major mod okay so we're gonna do that
close that
key map okay create key map
that's what we need to do then what's
next
a brief template okay a brief template
is also important so that you can press
for example in emac be smart inside you
makes this mod you can press D to become
different then become the whole template
so
that's what we need
uh
so usually for me I
put the template and keyword complete
completion as one single thing they you
know different major mod in emac
baseball they do things differently so
you know so it's not there's no one
universal way to do it for keyword
completion and for completing a template
you know like for example different
order parameters sometimes you you know
you need that it's very convenient so
you don't have to type all the brackets
or the parents so
so different people use different you
know there are many different ways to
implement them so for me both of them I
use the Emax abbreviation mechanism that
does both in my opinion that's the most
the most efficient fast and simple you
know I don't like elaborate like some
mod they have elaborate they prompt you
for typing a parameter you know in the
mini buffer then you cannot get out then
you have to fill out all the parameters
you know then you can exit I don't like
that so for me simple
keyword completion we need to do and
template then create a key map then
and if we have time we're gonna do a
documentation lookup meaning that you
press a key then you'll jump to whatever
documentation your Cruiser is on you
know that about that function so
so in the python case you know python
documentation really sucks there's no
page you can just look up a
documentation for a function name you
know python people they refuse to do
that
uh yeah so
anyway so okay so I'm not we are not
going to do this one it's pretty easy
okay so if you want a function in your
major mod
to just look up the current uh function
name documentation all you have to do is
just 10 lines of code you know just you
know look at this page you'll see how to
do it provided that you must have a
website that takes a query you know
function names such a great example is
PHP you know PHP language you can just
search any function name just look up
the documentation for that
for that function so PHP for example is
great emac this
is also great except that emac this you
don't have a website just to look up
that film function but anyway many many
languages too okay so anyway we're gonna
skip this so okay so let's just uh stop
talking and let's just implement this
too uh we also need indentation because
Python language you need indentation
okay let's begin okay let's see how far
we can go
uh any people oh we do have five people
watching okay say hi okay say hi ask me
questions you know
help me go about
okay so you know if I'm too slow or
whatever just tell me so let's
um so first of all let's let's
um let's go
um get some python code so that we can
test as we go okay so this is yeah so
this is python code uh close close
close that okay so we're gonna save it
here
save us x x star p y
okay so we can you know look up and
easily
um debug and whatever okay paste it here
so that we can jump to it easy okay
so you can so so you know
yeah so that's that's the code
so okay so now actually even on the
whole buffer open that file
uh no it's not in Python mod I mean this
is a default python mod so why is it not
working
he found a buffer open the file
yeah now it's inside python mod because
you can see in the mini buffer you know
there's a summation so that's
you know
you can see the summation sign here
okay
okay so so now let's look up uh let's
look up that file again
see
okay so we so let's see what uh you know
suppose we are coding python so common
is colored
string is colored now single
uses
double quote is called a single is not
colored okay now what about triple quote
python is triple quote okay triple quote
Yeah they just work like double clot
yeah okay so but
uh triple
single quad
okay we need to fix that but let's not
worry about that
um okay focus
so what do you need to do now keyword
completion uh create keymap let's create
a key map now for now okay so if we are
in Python mod right now it's sub python
mod so again we press Ctrl H M
to call the command describe mod
so now you can see
we have the documentation for
um
focusr python mod you see right now
there's not much there's no you know
it describes the key bindings there's
you know not much you you got this
product in Den six that came from Prague
mod remember because we based on our
code
um
POG mod
okay okay so we need to let's do a key
map okay
[Music]
you know
when you do key map you need some
function because you know some functions
specific to your mod
so that when you press the key you'll
call that function but right now our mod
doesn't actually have any
um it doesn't really have any kind of
special things you want to call
uh so what do what what to do so we need
to create some kind of function so you
can call
okay so
[Music]
um
okay let's go to key map
yeah okay so let's copy the code for key
map and let's walk through it
even though we don't have any function
so
but we'll explain as we go so let's
paste it here so first of all
you see first of all you define a bunch
of commands you know my mod command one
so let's just say
uh python right
because some python mod
python command one okay do something and
this do something will be insert
something okay so let's say let's
suppose this is our example command and
we also have several other commands we
don't need
okay delete it so here is the section
about key binding okay
so change the my mod to XA python
okay change my okay change my took
python okay change change change change
uh actually undo and do and do
uh you missing a hyphen okay do it
change change change change okay now we
have the proper prefix
name for our variable okay do it here
I'm gonna expand everything okay so we
got so here is how you define key
binding okay
so all you have to do is to create a
variable
named named as in a python mod hyphen
map
emacs will automatically automatically
recognize this variable as your key map
by emacs this convention
you know well it's ending in that uh in
dash map that means it's a key map so
this is a variable for a key map okay
for our mod so you see
so you define VAR
and make sure that one name is your
major name followed by Dash map that's
that's right that way
uh the define derived mod will
automatically set it as a local map okay
so I'm gonna so let me let me just
explain uh
not
okay that's a convention ending in dash
map remember that okay and here is how
we actually create the key map so you
have to do is you
call call make sparse key map that will
create a new key map assign it to our
variable sub python mod map then you
just Define each key so for example ccca
Will Call some command uh in our case is
this command
okay and the others are examples we
don't need it so you know by convention
e-max major mods Keys should begin with
the form control C control something
okay
okay so this two part is uh is this this
part is the defining or key binding for
your major man okay it's cut
and let's put them in an appropriate
place okay we're gonna see next table
then we put that this is a key binding
part okay
and we also defined a function here we
also Define the function here
okay let you know this is a example
function it just inserts something
cut so let's move it to the top
uh you know
okay and now go down
so syntax table so key binding we Define
key binding
now we need to No actually that's it
okay so
but
because the define derived mod will
automatically look for
look for a variable name that's named
your mod name in
Dash map so emacs right now we already
recognize it we're gonna check okay so
okay so what else
sample major mod with its own key map
Define it and okay okay I mean delete it
this we don't need okay so that's our
code
okay so uh can we shrink it a bit so you
can see the hole
okay that's the that's the whole code
so we added comments
okay let's let's just shrink them
let's just shrink them so uh
so that we can have more kind of space
okay
let's try it okay render code then
and now
open the file
now Ctrl H M describe mod expand the
window
there it is you can see now at least
sub python command 1. you know then you
can jump to it and see the documentation
you know do something yeah that's the
example so actually so let's try it okay
Ctrl H M
so the command is some python command
one
ccca so let's try it close it
Ctrl C
TRL
a there it is something Ctrl C Ctrl a
fantastic it works
okay now close it now
remember we said that you know in this
part we it automatically recognize this
you know uh
major amount name
Dash map
but if you want to be careful you could
actually add it here so let me show you
let me let me show you actually we want
to let me show you
define derived mod we say this thing
okay
you know use local map so a key map is
local to every buffer okay emacs you
have a lot buffers this is a buffer this
is a buffer uh you can open a new buffer
every buffer has its own key map okay
perfect logo so key map is above a local
variable
so it so depending on the buffer each
buffer may have different key maps
that's why when you press a key on this
buffer it do something but not in other
buffer and how is the keymat key map set
that's because
when in the major mod created a key map
you know we just did okay
so close that so so this line use local
map that's that's what it does so
actually you need to say python mod here
so let's say who knows I can copy that
variable
there you know use local map you know
that sits the so it so any buffer when
you you know open a new buffer and when
you if you say you know sub python mod
it will load
um
it will load this function because our
python mod and and in that function you
will set the local key map to this so
that is how each python mod has each
major mod has its own
major mod Keys okay that's a mechanism
how this works
but this line is optional
because
when you use the define derived mod
emacs will automatically try to find a
variable
my name
hyphen map
and we automatically you know
eval this line I mean even if you don't
have this line okay but to be um
it's always better to be explicit okay
so it's so simple so simple our mod is
not fantastic
so we actually
finished
creating a key map
you know next time when we add a new
command you know eventually we I'm going
to because you know
each mod you have you you you might have
many features you can call a function
delete the current function you know you
can create a
command that delete the current function
or whatever you know so every time you
create it you write a new command a
function you can add it to the
you know you just add it to your key map
here add a new line
that's how you tune that's that's so
that's fantastic okay next
keyword completion template okay this
part is also pretty easy
keyword completion template Okay so
so
um
well
when you actually do it it's it may not
be so easy
um
yeah so now we want to write a keyword
completion uh you know before we can
write this we really need to collect
the all the Python's keywords you know
here like
you know yesterday you know last time we
did this we
we just
we are sloppy you know we just grabbed
some keywords so this is not a real good
list of keywords you know because some
of them are keywords then some of them
are
um you know up to this part they are
kind of python keywords then this part
uh they are function names you know
um
so my point here is that before we write
a keyword completion first of all we
need
a list of all the keywords in the
language
so what to do uh we so what to do
but let's let's forget you know let's
just try to complete some of these okay
I mean you know we are just going to
show how how to write this mod
how to write the major amount okay so so
suppose this is your keyword so for
example you have a keyword reversed so
in in your python mod
you know you just want to you want to be
able to type reverse and
and tab and your complete reverse okay
suppose that's I'll show you at least
okay let's let's do that
suppose this is all the keywords you
want okay and this part is syntax
coloring
okay so we got a bunch of keywords you
need completion
um
so actually I have to kind of refresh
myself how to do this how long have we
been going
uh almost I think any anyone watching
still
Okay so
keyword completion
uh yeah actually I I should prepare
so yeah so you want to be able to so
given first of all you have a list of
words
that you want to complete then whenever
user types some character then call a
complete Command you know call command
to complete it then it should pop up a
list of available matches
okay that is the overview of the
functionality we want okay solution two
things you have to do write the function
completion it point and add
completion a point to the hook
completion and point function in your
mod command body
okay the function completion at point
will will not take any argument you will
return a list of the form
okay this is complicated
uh copy and paste uh okay so actually
here is a code
we can kind of just copy it
yeah it will work
okay this is one way to do it they are
again there are a few ways okay so this
is this is a basic way
um okay
now there is another way solution 2
using I2 for completion okay
uh this is better I think
okay let's try let's try let's go with
this in fact you know because emacs 28
included the functionality of I do so
before so what does I do do you know you
can search you know search my tutorial
type I do you'll find
you know you'll find my you know what
does it do so basic but basically I do
is just popping up
a list of choices
so that you don't even have to press tab
to complete so that's what I do
uh mod does you know it's not part of
emacs before it was not it's part of
emacs since five years ago or so but now
I2 itself is becoming obsolete because
now you have vertical
I complete you know so you know read
this article okay I complete mod I do
Fido so I Fido mod is part of icomplete
mod that comes with emacs too you know
Asian and now it has the functionality
of
of what I do does
you know it's it's just different ways
to
make it make it easier for you to
complete a command name okay so
so so I complete and I do I did a video
on this several month half a year ago so
they kind of replaced the functionality
of I do
Okay so
now we go back
um
you go back
so now when we write a completion
uh keyword completion
we no longer
need to use the I do
but however the way it will work is
basically the same so let's copy let's
start to code it okay again we want to
write a completion for these words okay
let's start to code it
now uh
comments and questions hello Justine
hello great to see you hello to Canada
how is it going there how is your you
know how's your work in in Haskell and
and uh
and what's that uh JavaScript I mean
Java functional programming language
Okay so so here we want to do
completion uh let's say keyword
completion okay so we don't need I do
anymore
and search for I do
uh which is not okay so ABC keywords
these are the sample keywords we need we
have that already it's here okay so it's
python keywords okay
so we don't need this ABC keywords
anymore
search for ABC
okay so replace it by that
and here is a function
okay so it's just a function so this
function whenever it's called he will
add things to the right of course it
will pop up a list of choices that's all
it does okay this function so let's
rename it because it's a
python okay so let's rename
so
python
okay so python complete symbol that's
what we want perform keyword confusion
on current symbol symbol just means the
current identifier okay which means
function function names or variable
names
that's a Emax
that's a lisp programming language
ID
idiosyncrasy you know they call identify
as a symbol because it's actually a
symbol they are type that's that's and
that's because it's symbolic programming
language because every identifier is
actually
a symbol you can manipulate
okay that's how lisp different from
differs from many other languages
so version so let's put today's date
so perform keyword completion on current
symbol that's right
this uses I do mod actually we don't
need that
you know we're gonna remove the code for
I do because now emacs 28 you have Fido
automatically do that
okay so let's see how this code works
okay
uh bounce of things at point so this
function will return you know with it
will return the
the position
of the current identifier the beginning
position and end position
so if my cruiser is right here he will
return an integer that is the beginning
of this word identifier and end of this
word that's what this
bounce of thing at Point do okay so you
give it the value symbol that means you
know so it returns a pair counts pair of
two integers beginning and in the
positions okay and P1 is equals to car
BDS so that's the beginning q1 is
position one so beginning of the word
and end of the word P2 okay
now this now this local variable current
symbol is equals to um
so if P1 and P2 is not defined for
example if our Cruiser is is not inside
any word
then I think those the result will be
near so if they are not defined no no
um
or
if P1 and P2 are the same thing you know
because it's not a word then do nothing
then just return
I mean so the current symbol will be
empty string okay
otherwise
put for substring no properties
otherwise you copy the word okay so you
know depending on where your Cruiser is
so this current symbol is just the
current word the cursor is on okay
fantastic
now result symbol okay this is the
result you want the completed form to be
okay
working cartling fantastic kotlin Python
and JavaScript because of the people I
work with fantastic
and pure script for fun cool
is company is I company the same as
company mod
you mean I complete
I I think you mean I complete no I
complete no so
so I complete so let me explain this one
I complete mod is ancient in emacs like
20 years old okay so we can look up
easily
um so those of you don't know actually
you should look up my tutorial on
icomplete mod because it explains the
whole thing
but so but basically I can plead for
let's so for example describe function I
complete mod
okay so you can see here's the
documentation for icomplete jump to the
source code open it and go to the bottom
1000 lines of code
go to the beginning you can see it begin
in 1992 so I complete is ancient and
it's used in emacs everywhere that's
when you do meta X or find file
you know or fine fire or anything
anything that pump that the mini buffer
pops up asking you to type something
that
and and when you turn on I complete I
complete helps you you know in different
ways to complete the command okay make
it easier so that's icomplete very Asian
in building emacs
uh and the company mod you are talking
about is you know it's an external
package that began maybe 10 years ago
that you know the the the stadium point
it's also for completion but but it pops
up a little window at where your Cruiser
is
and it it you know it helps you it's
also for completion but it's in a new
kind of new generation way trying to
copy other editors uh I believe it
originally is trying to copy text mate
you know like other editors you know it
just pop up where you are at instead of
the mini buffer you know
so I complete and you know it becomes
very big and very complex and with huge
amount of add-on to a complete you know
I mean company so you know so the
history actually there is one before
company I think
yeah there is another one very popular
but companies kind of
a fork of that anyway though anyway
those are external packages okay I don't
use it I don't like them because I want
things simple I like things to be
building as much as possible just use
the building facility
and uh you know as much as possible and
also native you know fast
and no extraneous coloring you know
fancy coloring uh if not necessary you
know I I you know so if some coloring is
not really functional I don't you know
I'm not excited about them I don't want
just pretty for pretty
Ness and sink
so anyway so I you know but it's a good
package company company mod okay
so yeah
um
yeah and you have to do a lot of setup
anyway yeah I complete you also have to
do setup so I complete in Emax 28 got
the major upgrade major
so that now it supports you know it
supports vertical pop-up you know like
again you know
so major upgrade in Max 28 two years ago
I mean
years 2022 you know last year came out
so major upgrade so now I don't use I do
mod anymore so I just use um
I complete you know so I compete also
you know Fido mod is part of icomplete
you know it's a bit complex so yeah
so anyway let's go back to our
completion you know trying to write a
confusion so
so okay so so
um
company oh okay so yeah cool
uh yeah cool so when
so when not current symbol so if the
current symbol is empty
you know when your Cruiser is is not on
a word then just uh
silicone symbol is not defined just set
it as a empty string okay then now here
is where we want to do the resourcing
symbol okay so the result symbol that's
the return completion will be right now
it's this line but we're gonna change it
okay
instead of I2 we just say completing
read okay that should be it
you know we don't need I do a mod
anymore because now
the I complete
provide the feature of vertical
completion
okay so I think every argument or the
parameters arguments are the same so
let's make sure let's read the
completing read documentation okay
describe function
prompts okay completing read prompts
collection okay collection is cloud
python words
then optional credit card require match
record require match and the initial
input
initial input is kind of simple okay
history okay we don't care so let's just
leave it like that
then you say delete region you know
delete the the word the cruiser is
currently on then just insert the result
so simple so simple fantastic
python complete symbol okay so I'm gonna
copy that word
okay now Eva the buffer let's try again
the buffer
show the pink window
buffer
um
so you can see
now let's try sub python complete symbol
okay let's
let's go to our python mod open it close
it open it again okay
now what what words we have let's see
wait let's go back reverse okay let's
try reversed
so coding coding and r e
okay let's just r e and now we call
python completely symbol do it
a fantastic it worked
uh e okay I E
V okay one choice enter fantastic we got
completion
we got word completion okay
go back so so to make it correct we just
have to now you know complete you know
gather all the proper keywords and
function names of the Python language
okay then now of course we need to add a
key
because typically you don't want to you
know meta X complete symbol typically
it's a Tab Key
a different mod have a different way to
do that but that's for our purposes you
know just for this tutorial we just like
we just add a key
copy this line the function will be
subhead and complete symbol and the key
will be let's just hard code
tab okay
now when we press tab you'll just do
compute symbol now this now this is not
a proper way to do it okay but this is a
simple way because when you are if you
are writing your own major mod
emacs has several
um
you know emacs has kind of its own a
convention
with bunch of
you know let me let's go to for example
let me show you go to go to emacs
tutorial and then go to completion let's
just search for completion
okay
uh so by emacs convention
I mean yeah by emacs usage convention
the
the the command completion at Point
should be a universal command doesn't
matter if you are in Python mod Sim mod
Java mod whatever when you call
completion at Point
you know that should do this completion
okay that's kind of
um
so in your mod you know we can
you know we can not follow that
convention we can just do it this way
you know
so when when user press tab you'll just
call complete Command
or if you want to follow the emacs way
which is a bit complicated you know you
have to make the completion so you can
make a Alias you you can't make a area
well I mean
you have to make the completion a point
somehow call your command and also
you know emacs has a way that that set
up what tab key do in every mod so
is complicated and it's not good in
general okay so that's um
so I have another article that discuss
about these let's see uh so this article
is about emacs completion yeah tab okay
yeah so search for
let's search for
so this is the article you you want to
know it let me write it down
so we have a reference okay
it's a name completion that's one thing
you want to know that's uh emacs
convention and the other thing is how do
you set up indent it's a very confusing
topic okay and it's such indentation
there okay copy the URL paste it here
make it so okay so as you see
this is the Emax convention so these
commands indent for tab command
you know basically the question is when
your user presses Tab Key what should
happen
you know is sometimes you expect
name completion
sometimes you expect indentation
sometimes you expect inserting a tab
character
so each one of these scenario is very
common you know so depending on what
kind of community or programming
language you know it depends
so emacs has you know supposedly have
this this set of commands that allows
you to
configure your emacs to you know
supposedly whether you want it always be
indentation or
or just name completion or you know
these commands
Okay so
but it's fairly confusing and uh you
know it's very confusing so but if you
want your major mod to to be absolutely
you know following be a good boy and
following the e-max convention so
so when user you know configure any of
this command that we also configure your
mod you know
that's the ideal okay but it's not so
good okay
for now you know you can study you know
if you are writing your mod you know
study and
um
I'm not gonna
tell you how because because I don't
know I've you know it quite deep cried
esoteric and details I don't know
offhand I have to look into I mean I
forgot okay
so yeah so let's just try our current
hard-coded way I think it's actually
better because not every mod
actually follow this if you want if you
want your major mod to be part of gnu
emacs then you do because otherwise they
won't accept it okay but if you want
your mod to be I mean let's say
Innovative you know because
usually if you follow the convention
then you don't have Innovation so
you know sometimes it's good to have
kind of
you know you can go outside of the box
and try different things
so we are trying different things okay
okay so evaluate the buffer done let's
go back to a python mod let's go back to
the python file now let's say r e press
Tab Key
didn't work
IE tab it is it didn't work okay
close it what's going on why did oh oh
uh needs to be all capital okay that's
that's just a quark the Syntax for the
key needs to be all capital for tab okay
reopen last opened
Type R E press tab fantastic we have
completion and V okay we got completion
okay
now we have a completion but we don't
have
the complete template
now reverse you know the in Python
reverse is a keyword as part of the sort
argument I mean sort function I believe
so
so there's nothing to complete further
but let's go back let's look at python
some of these are
um
filter for example filter is a function
in Python
I'm pretty sure so you know you have
arguments
so
let's open the python so if you type
f i tab filter
now if you press space or tab you should
have you know you should have like param
you know at least
uh function I believe
okay so we we want a we want the
completion of the template how do we do
that
okay let's write that
okay so after we do that that's it for
today
um Okay so
but now it's already complete now our
package right now is complete now we
need we are adding a new feature so we
finished
so we did keyword completion then now we
just we are adding a keyword I mean a
completion of a template feature new
feature fantastic
so we go back to
um emacs tutorial emac this tutorial
we yeah so read this page okay how to
write a keyword completion so simple you
know so simple just
10 lines of code here
now we want to a new feature a brief
template that's what we want here so
it's also very easy
10 lines of code copy it copy
go back here
put it button and let's just go through
it
okay let's see what it what to do
uh okay so yeah so
Define so we we we are going to define a
abbreviation table
so that means you know for example look
at this line M will become you know
parent messages you know this is for
emac this
so for example I can do it I can do it
right now for example m space become
message
space again oh God Saves 10 keystrokes
fantastic so that you see that that
magic is is just this this a brief table
entry okay
so now first of all we're gonna create a
brief table with the proper name should
be
you know again
we need a mod name prefix sub python
a brief table okay that's what we need
Define a brief table then actually
defined here okay
so Define up we call that
with this variable name he will Define a
group table
and uh what so first entry let's see
let's say filter okay so let's say
f for filter
so whenever you want to filter a list
array you just type f
antastic then
let's add another entry filter will be
like that at least
and function okay something like that
okay hundreds more you bet
okay so these two
okay and then you have the okay so so
far so good you just defined a preview
table
then a documentation a brief table for
okay that's a documentation then
you have these um
configuration for the brief table
regular expression this is the part you
want to
you know
like consideration of where the
underscore or hyphen is allowed in
symbol name
something like that so in Python hyphen
is not allowed
but
you know actually we can like ignore
them for now you know you can study
later case fixed yes okay in a brief
system yes okay that's just
configuration
this this means
um this means your abbreviation here in
you know is just for system meaning that
it won't be mixed with users
abbreviation set okay so anyway so let's
copy the name and you gotta have the
name properly
okay something like that so
so okay so now here's your mod okay this
line that's all the that's all you need
hold on a second
so we got have the name properly correct
okay
so copy let me show you okay hold on a
second so first of all
these lines is important okay cut now
let's put it to a appropriate place okay
and say here paste it here and this
section is gonna be
a brief table okay
and templates
okay we are going to use the Emax abreve
table feature to implement the template
completion system okay that's what we
are doing again different major amount
they made some some others maybe they
may use
skeleton you know there's other
mechanisms you know but a brief is my
favorite
so that you don't have you know you
don't have the mini buffer asking
you know you don't have to feel each
parameter you know they control where
your Cruiser needs to be I don't like
that I just want to press the key
everything is I can just navigate and
type myself or delete okay so anyway so
so this is what you need then
you need to add
these two lines cut
into your
your definition of the mod so let's add
it here
okay so add add those
okay
so this every mod on means turn on the
abbreviation okay the agreement and then
you have to say approve table
so this is kind of a
this line just means that
tells emacs that whenever you know user
runs sub python mod it will set the
above table to this
again when you use define derived mod it
will automatically look for a symbol
with the name name Dash table so you
don't actually need this line but
however let's be explicit okay so let's
add this on my okay so cut
Ting the code uh wait
by the way this colon something that's
uh that's another quote of this
anyway that's that's basically just
means set the variable a brief table to
this to this value okay okay now even on
the buffer
now go to open the python mod
let's type f
okay f space
didn't work
f space
didn't work save close what's going on
so do we have the
exam python a brief table did we get the
name correct yes
uh python approved table so let's look
up the documentation
so actually
seems to register because we can see
so F becomes filter then
so what's wrong let's see if
um
okay why yes Snippets
I don't like yes snippet yeah okay yeah
no I know what you mean yeah I don't
like why I say why I snippet that's the
one where
it prompts you for all the parameters of
course you can change it you know but
it's complex you know I I've been using
I was a fan of why I snippet
for in when it began in
2008 or something like that 2006 or
something so I was a big fan of why I
snippet I use it for about 10 years
until then one day you know emacs has so
many features one day I learned about
emacs a brief then then after you learn
more and more you know you know then it
then it occurred to me I don't need why
I snippet you know why snippet is
another huge package
uh you know very it's written by a
Chinese guy
uh who went to MIT I believe I don't
know if he graduated already or not you
know time time flies so it's already
like 10 years over 10 years
uh why I snip snip it the original
author
so anyway so so now we uh let's find out
what's going on why is it why is it not
work
okay
so we have the brief table let's look at
the message buffer see if there's any
errors
okay almost done I'm tired too so close
that
even on the buffer one more time
open the file
f space it's not working so now let's
call
described variable
and let's say python approved table okay
the table is there
so why is it
let's try f-i-l-t-e-r
space nothing
not close
let's remove this okay let's maybe leave
out the buffer
okay open it f space nothing
uh let's see
describe variable a brief mod
value is true that means it's on
so a brief mod is on why do I not have
any a brief close it
brief mod so why is my brief table not
working
hahaha
dude we have a spelling error
case fixed true
maybe the rejects did we is this
let's try that
eval
open last closed f space no work
uh okay I don't know why so let's read
the tutorial to double check did I miss
anything a brief template for major mod
okay so this is what you want to do
template solution
Define a brew table then that then then
you just say that that
or should work
but why isn't it not work
okay always spelled correctly
so here is how it works explanation on
how it works
um
Define a brief table
oh God
each abbrev each abbreviation can have
several properties okay we don't care
oh okay maybe these oh I missed
it's uh
wait where is it
how a brief works okay
enable function and
what
okay so this part
said local brief table that's the part I
missed I think
yeah okay
set local a brief table so a brief table
is local Okay so
somehow
okay let's try that Eva the buffer open
last closed
type f
magnify type f space fantastic fantastic
no it didn't added the space okay now
let's remove the space and now type
space again fantastic we have a brief we
have template feature
okay that's it for today now of course
this is something you need to fix you
see F becomes filter then there's a
space
no good you have to remove the space
then space again so actually remove that
let's go back
I can close the buffer let's make it
just
um
you know so you know so there are just
little things you need to fix okay if
you want to know how to fix you know
read my tutorial but for example for now
we can we can start it to add more fancy
abbreviation
uh what What's some some example of
python
um
you know defend I guess defense is used
most often
uh if okay if let's write let's try to
add if then else okay let's make a a
brief for if then else okay
so filter is that then
so if you wanna if okay so this is
basically what to do
so that's that's that's a tab
uh God I hate python
they should use tab as the convention
but instead of they use space when the
problem is when you use spaces spaces
for indentation there's no way to tell
just how many
semantic in you know semantic nesting
there are when you use space there's no
way to tell
but when you have a tab
for indentation in the Python language
then it's absolute one type means one
indentation two tabs means two and it is
it's semantically significant you know
because Python's nesting determines the
semantics you know the the of the
language so let's just use tab here so
tab in emacs you can represent us
backslash T okay
backslash T so no space and you need to
um
actually normally you don't want to say
quote okay so let's just say X
it's just let's just say that you know
let's make it a quote okay remove that
copy that and actually
okay so that that is uh if you know run
it
open as closed not this one okay now
open the python file
if
space fantastic this is the way I like
it I don't have to you know feel the
param again just delete it if I want
fantastic okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching how many people
if you guys like it pay me okay donate
uh thank you there are a few people
yesterday who
who donated so I'm gonna you know I'm
late I'm gonna send out my tutorials or
whatever and thank you for the donation
okay you can find you know you can find
my Python tutorial sorry dot info uh you
can find my payment donation information
at the bottom
okay thank you guys that's it for today
and uh
look forward to see my
review of The Glorious glove 80 keyboard
thank you Justin and
that one bye guys
shut down shut down shut down in one
minute
fantastic we completed
the python mod features uh okay so
review so what did we do so uh at what
point how good is our python mod from
scratch
first of all paste the keyboard link
here so that we have
you know so
this is today what we talked about today
keyboard Club 80 and yeah our code
let's put our code into the page
so that you know you guys can
can run it can you know
close that yeah so first of all clean up
okay clean up a little bit
so date you know so this is like a
version number
commands this command we don't need
anymore you see this this dummy command
but now we do have a um
yeah so this command we don't need
anymore remove it
okay leave it empty
we have keyword completion command
that's the command we need and this I do
no no longer necessary
okay we got commands syntax coloring
then we got syntax table for coloring
comments and stream
and we got
completion of templates you know you can
add hundreds few hundred more
to your preference you know whatever
language you program you know in Python
you can you can have your own completion
all you have to do is just add one line
so simple
uh and you know you can have a bunch of
Single Character completions for example
for example my Excel emac this mod so if
you just go up go up go up you see all
these uh completions templates you know
for example switch to buffer uh you know
you know hundreds of functions you can
you can create a completion and then you
can you can have many single character
uh completions these are the most
frequently used
functions in emac disp so you can just
type one character in just complete
fantastic then you can have double two
characters completion so in each
language each major mod you create you
can have that
okay close close yeah so we got that
then then some of that then we Define
key binding okay that's it yeah so good
pretty good okay copy it back to here
back to
today's talk show
add the code here paste it
syntax color show in browser
fantastic
bye