test test
hello guys so this is streaming he might
Emax life now what what is today's topic
I don't know I don't have any topic so
but basically I'm going to work you know
my daily stuff Emacs and stuff
Emacs coding and stuff and writing blogs
and video streaming and stuff so if you
like it come on and ask me questions and
our answer so yeah so and the other
thing is I'm actually testing streaming
because I'm still a newbie about video
streaming so I'm learning things you
know I'm learning my interaction with
YouTube the very complicated YouTube and
streaming stuff and the live chat you
know stuff so I'm just going to walk so
let me try to type something
can I type something actually I cannot
Jesus hi Chad don't show these tips
again you [ __ ]
I want to stir those tips how do I get
it back
so Chad [ __ ]
language English okay location United
States fine
restricted mod of history and help now
what the [ __ ] is health what do you have
to say change your name remove YouTube
videos on channels contact the YouTube
creators so whole team
as if that's gonna solve anything
upload videos need more help
no see I'm doing this because my hand
hurts watching your eye so I'm doing
this because my hand hurts it's right
here let me show you you see my arm now
it's right here so this is a marble pole
now remember if you have a question just
ask okay this is about Emacs
and Emacs Lisp and I'm using Emacs Lisp
to write my blog and it is more
efficient than Oak mod or anything any
any of those that content management
system what happened will do whatever
the name hide and cried or something
something so so this is a marble bowl I
have two of them you know you use that
you tore it in your hands like that you
can go touch less they don't touch you
to eat each other
go in the other direction or you can
have them touch all the time this is a
metal one
[Music]
so this is the metal one this is the
marble and so you can see okay that's
the master plan and right now I'm using
this as a hammer to him I don't know why
this happens okay to people watching you
know if again if you have a question
just ask okay type it type it and I'll
see it and wait help shut up
hi chat no show chat yes well actually
you know last time why did the streaming
test yesterday it looks like you may not
be able to type now can you actually
type that is a problem because the
modern technologies 100 bunch of
problems you know although in general it
helps the masses you know like right now
like tens of thousands hundreds of
thousands people are streaming I mean
not right now but they can you know like
that happened on YouTube you know
everyone is streaming that so so but the
technology details is still painful like
right now okay let me recap what I want
to do what I want to do is to stream
live with with my screen you know share
my screen so this is my Emacs screen so
let me adjust that turn auto click off
adjust the screen and yeah get a new
screen GNU Emacs frame or new window
then go to
[Music]
go to my blog and go to Emacs alpha
command of mod yes yes yes yes Eva Eva
Eva and now you can see all my Emacs
commands turn auto click back on so you
see oh my young Emacs commands including
IV something okay so you can see all my
comments on that window and let's see
okay how do I know if I'm like how can I
check if if you guys can type because if
you cannot type but I don't know because
I but I kept saying you know guys just
type something so let's go to youtube
youtube now YouTube is suggesting me a
bunch of a bunch of things you know yeah
it's not use let's go to here okay
my twitter is new to notifications yeah
twitter is sucks no there's not a
problem they they use algorithms to
control information that you know that's
a massive it has a massive effect they
use algorithms same thing with Google
you know they use algorithms and
Facebook they use algorithms to control
the information flow so it's a massive
censorship not just that it's a massive
massive you can say hidden sensitive
censorship you know so anyway so yeah so
on Twitter if you retreat euro treats
you retreat euro treat they may not show
they won't show because I know because
I have another count here is my ogre
Emacs account so I retreat something
from Saudi I treated it a year ago I had
retreated it's about some programming
topic ok it's not nothing political it's
just programming topic I retreated but
on my Emacs account I don't see it so
it's it's talking password correct
Sacha is great I need to reply to her I
haven't done yet because I went out
today so well but first of all let me
get back to checking about YouTube so I
think this is ok that's me shut up and
go to my account home live now sorry
live stream live now ok click to
watching now
okay so hey look so glad to see you are
streaming hey great to see you too
break the loop that's good break the
loop now can I say something
sighing - Chatta [ __ ] it you know
sighing I have to sign in to chat okay
signing day okay but I'm gonna close
this window and back to Google Chrome
open the window paste there so I can
kind of see myself and come on show up
oh hey Brazil cure me they'll meet sick
succubus okay I cannot pronounce
anything you know we should do some help
so we you know let's do some hangout so
anyway so I'm still running streaming
and stuff and stuff so you know but you
just have to do it you know like right
now I'm doing it you know that way I
learn then you know we're gonna start
have so it's best typing so one of the
problem right now is that you see when
I'm seeing my streaming myself on this
window but if I go through this window
now I'm supposed to see the chat here
but it's not showing you see that's the
problem okay okay one guy went away or
to watching okay so anyway so I'm
supposed to be able to see the chat here
but I cannot so that means you know I
have to do this it's not in you know
doing little things lots of problems you
have to spend a lot of time to learn it
so again if you have a questions ask me
okay so I'm going to I'm going to check
the the chat regularly do I have to
where is this life why is it not showing
how you have to click that
ok this yeah streaming okay so I know
this streaming there is about
five-second delay
stop
so there is five-second delay like every
time I say something then after about
five seconds then I see it so that's you
know something interesting okay
someone's reply to my mastered and stuff
Master Dan you know Master Dan is the
the other treater like social network
it's it's something you know a lot of
open-source fans like but it's not going
anywhere you know it's not you know no
people nobody is using it except you
know a few so I'm working on my so yeah
so again you know if you have a question
ask then you know we might get into
interesting topics
I'll check the text regularly I'll check
the chat regularly so anyway this is my
heart blog you know interesting things
about heart related or random you know
funny things so I was walking on this
page now I want to see now I want to
check
you know I've been mourning like some of
these pictures today you talk about it
people shy away because of the you know
political movements like you people you
know people will become like nice and
creamy and you know shy away from things
that's that's actually desaturate
disastrous to society you know this is
not so you know ten years ago but anyway
i'm going to check my website links
validate links so so this is a : script
I wrote few month ago so let's check run
it so it's running if there's any bad
Bank here tell me for example what what
do you mean by bad link for example I
have something there that's a bad link
so you see don't know bad ink but
suppose if I say I had a space here and
go back here run a script again you see
you tells me it tells me there it is on
this file there is a bad link in that
string is there so you know that I can
turn this lets see a pretty output so MX
output cuz I'll find output mod so now
it's color it's pretty I can just press
a key and go to the link and press it
and I'll jump to the link right here see
now I fix that save crows crows run the
script again and it tells me it's
beautiful
it tells me I'm beautiful thank you
okay so now I'm gonna check my entire
website I have like five domains so now
I'm gonna check my entire website and
meanwhile I can work on here Emacs work
on some other page come on rock my
clothes Lina's okay so this is my name
Braga come bearing fires if yeah
yesterday I was talking about that cuz
it's gonna take few minutes to check my
entire website so hikes are with
well-known Emacs users like Richard
Stallman experiencing cappuccinos issues
do you think there is any merit in the
idea that Emacs might contribute to
couple make problems yes of course
that's absolutely in fact Emacs of all
softwares in the world Emacs is the
number one software that cost couple to
note in syndrome what you know maybe not
technically that but in Emacs is the
number one software that caused hand
damage or hand injured hand injury you
know where people have to see doctors
impacts is a number one it's so severe
it's so bad you know but he makes people
but in Emacs community you know as we
know it's like a coat you know as much I
love Emacs and EEMA crisp and it looks
like you know I'm getting old so I'm not
likely to change but even despite that
you know so far I looked as [ __ ] you
know I actually have not you know
seriously tried other editors you know
these days I haven't
seriously tried atom or vs code you know
hold the idea J editor okay who now
second my roommate
so I haven't really actually tried deal
editors but I still dug Emacs so any
email I mean even even I mean based on
all the comments from elsewhere its
Emacs still is pretty good I mean it's
old but it's you're pretty good
but anyway Emacs yeah so he max causes
hand injury by far and the reason we
don't hear that is because there's a you
know Emacs has a coat situation you know
as you know you probably know you know
VI and VI versus Emacs it's so common
it's it's a code situation for like like
20 30 years now you know the in
programming community and the elsewhere
as well the often we have code code
culture you know like within programming
languages for example Perl is one of the
most notorious potent code culture and
we have code culture of the Mac you know
Mac phonetics and also the open source
code culture you know and so so so what
does I mean so basically in code like
you have for something like a community
that forms a code like behavior or
thinking beliefs basically so what it
means is that the people they are what
they typically agree I they what they
perceive is not it's not true okay it's
not just true so anyway so the reason
you don't see that much in emacs
community for example reddit
because people don't want to say it you
know because it seems to be a bad bad
marketing you know you know people want
don't want to hear Emacs causes you know
hand pain pain
yes so you say you know this seems VI is
better in a couple Department because it
it is sequential pressing of key
sequences instead of Emax key
combinations that's right that often
require more of a claw handshape that
exactly so so Emacs
I mean V key binding is better but
however know that there are also people
who got hand injuries by using vim you
know exclusively so I mean so what so I
was talking about this on the other day
on the stream there's this one of my
stream you I think it's worth checking
out let me show you so you know I think
that's a good one
I think that's a good one you guys
should watch it you know that's my first
streaming test and I was just like I
didn't tell anyone you know I just come
on and try to test it and turns out like
nine people came you know into the room
and asked me questions and I end up
talking about talking like one hour so
watch this one
you know you know watch this one later
you can copy you can see that you are
out there and copy it later so so and
here I mean this this one is one hour
long but but starting at 26 minutes and
there are some interesting topics about
programming languages then at 35 minutes
about Linux versus Mac versus windows
and at 53 minutes I talk about Richard
Stallman free software foundation I
think that one is interesting but anyway
I'm starting to do streaming or video
often now so you know I'm going to do it
frequently you know I hope to get into
you know the streaming stuff and video
and also hang out so when we do have you
know you guys can join we can join
together and so we can talk in what's
each other ah no problem I mean that's
what you know the thing about video
streaming or any any kind of talk show
is I just repeat and repeat it's like
you you know I learned it's it's like
that's the nature I mean that's how
that's that's what we are living you
know that's how things are because why
right turns up rock so I write tons of
rock and you notice I have to repeat I
mean I like I saw questions on the web
you know and at first I thought you know
isn't that FAQ like that's an FAQ I've
been 10 years ago I mean why is people
asking fa Q's there was you know back in
like you know 2008 for example you know
I noticed 2010 okay I made it you know
I'm thinking gee why is people asking
every Hughes they it happen it happens
you know you have after year and it's
more frequent and it's more like it
becomes more and more beginners question
then I realized oh it's not because they
are as
frequently asked questions it's because
I'm getting old and I've been thinking
you know because then you you see a
question you want to reply but next year
the same question you have to like
repeat like you you you you find that
you answer everything hundreds of times
like there's more and more topic topics
that just repeat and but it turns out
that's just the cycle of life you know
it's so happy you think I think about
that and I think you know if you look at
cat college you know they teach calculus
for example right they teach calculus or
physics or whatever and what they do
they repeat the same thing every day you
know that's what college is ah so you
know so so it's not it's not one should
not be surprised I mean I should not be
surprised if I'm reading my blog and you
know I find out you know I have to
repeat everything because like today I
look at reddit almost you know a lots of
questions if you you know if you just
spin one minute on my blog you know the
answer you know the full answer better
the better better answer than all the
answers right there so so anyway I you
know take think for yourself you know
you don't have to believe me for
anything I tend to talk that way you
know I just I just want to say what
whatever I think it was sorta sometimes
maybe I am too self-centered you know
just my opinion so but you know you know
take it as it you know if you have
different opinions say it and you know I
don't mind at all so I mean this is
supposed to some most you know people in
America you know most people style they
tense you know especially today you know
they want to be collide and reserved oh
you know by the way have you did you
know that it's possible you know you can
do it this way you know they you know
that's what they that's the
the typical manners you know on the
YouTube you know when they say that you
know it's actually not truthful to
themselves you know because actually
they [ __ ] know the answer like
hundred percent correct you know answer
but the instead of saying the answer you
know oh just do that that's the way you
solve it but instead of saying that they
say oh by the way have you you know
did you ever thought maybe there's this
way you could try you know so but anyway
that's that's not my style so soon okay
so let me see
most likely the biggest contributors is
simply how has been typing on any
speaker specific editor most likely the
biggest contributor is simply hours
spent typing more than any specific
editor what do you mean about what so
okay thank you I want you trivia stream
sorry can you give some good keybinding
examples that you used for perfe and
windows management okay let me talk
about that that's that's my favorite
topic okay so I'm back here and so you
can see my Emacs windows
let's move my windows around so
so this golden script check links it's
finished everything is good so close it
close it and that's my other blog so
close it close it okay so we want to
let's go to my Emacs box so okay so the
question is about let's see I want to
answer the question instead of me you
know going about
okay got that so can you give me some
good key binding examples that you use
for buffer and window management okay
here's what I do so well I'll just talk
about the topic you know many people
they like to use first full screen like
that so you know you have a full screen
and you know maybe you you split your
screen like that and maybe you run a
shell here this is a shell let's see
which state you know anyway that's you
show and maybe here you run a calendar
or something let's say okay so but you
know so some people like to work this
way but the problem with this way is
that whenever you do for example there's
a function let's say for what would you
know this is the least function and you
know you want to look look it up so you
call describe function so control H F
forward word and you know it it shows
here you know and maybe this is not big
not big enough so you move the it's
turned a little click off you know so
but basically so now you're you know
you're well divided pain is screwed up
so you have to go back so you have to do
a lot of that adjustments so I don't
like the I don't like the full screen
method so I mean go back so instead
instead of full screen I recommend when
you open Emacs you have two windows - OH
Emacs frames Emacs color window frame so
two frames when I have three but you can
have like two or three usually I have to
usually I don't have this one so this
this window shows my keys although
kissing can commence in Emacs so I would
suggest you just have two two frames so
this way okay let me show you so this
way you can freely close any window you
want like right now I'm switching
between two windows and I can create a
new one so now I have three I can create
another one now I have four but I don't
have I don't have a convenient key to
arrange them but you can you can write
one
I didn't write one because I don't
actually need to procedure then position
them often so like right now I have four
screens you know
Emacs is not is is never going to change
your position or change the size Emacs
will not touch that so right now for
example I can do describe function for
word word for example and it just shows
you know nice and big and if I'm done
you know just close it you know close it
can go here and go to that you know I
press one key look at the key look at
the key at the left that's a key I'm
pressing to switch windows you see seven
times eight times nine ten times twelve
and twelve you can see you see what I'm
doing my keys W and that that is on
Borak keyboard but on quality keyboard
you would be the coma so I'm using stuff
like keys which is this one
you might try it so soft like he's okay
let's finish one topic head first so you
know you might try it so anyway so I
would suggest always just have two
windows or two Emacs frames
so right now you know it's because it's
flexible you you set up your window
position and all that I mean even if you
want you can do it like this for example
you can do it like this oh you know if
you are into tiling Windows you can use
windows you know for example now I have
like four Emacs frames now remember the
important point about using you know
multiple windows like this is that Emacs
will never close them or change their
position so it's fixed so you can do
whatever you want and then you can you
know freely spread your windows here or
you know if you don't want you just fit
you know put it back you know and when
you are done with this window you don't
want it anymore just close it you can
see now I have three you know if I'm
done with this one and just close it now
I'm back to one and you know okay oops I
want I want another one you know now I
have three you know I don't have okay
you know I don't have keys to proceed
position them but I can you know just
put it here basically usually I put one
here and that never never moves you know
so the red wine is basically my main you
know I can just go to browser and you
know so this is my blog over here it's
so let's say second so you know
something something okay and view in
browser you know I can see it here so
you know when you are you working maybe
you are programming or you are working
on something you can see side by side
and of course you can also position your
browser you know once you position them
and incise them for me they are kind of
fixed you know you don't touched it
but then for example you know I have the
freedom like you know I have the freedom
for example to full screen this one you
know like just for a few minutes you
know because for some reason I want to
and once I'm done go back to you know
small screen and you know when I'm back
to the way I am you know so I would
recommend to you know multi multiple
frames instead of one big screen so
so okay once you have multiple frames
what what what are the major things so
one one command let me show you them is
this one so let me just type it up okay
so I have this command saw next window
of him it's on my website for example
you can look at describe function and we
are basically when you have to split
pens your switch among them you know
like switch switch switch switch switch
switch but if you have only one you know
if you don't have split pens can you
just switch the windows you know I'm
using a normal standard terminology but
you know Emacs cause windows frames so
but you know let's just use standard
terminology so I have like three windows
I can split them
once you have split this command which
is cycle among the split pane and okay
okay so split and unsplit let's do that
so any just type it so that's the one
you want
a window below okay so there you have
sob that's exact
window or frame you know that this is
convenient because no mori the Emacs
Emacs has other window the window
command what I do is you know control XO
you you probably familiar with that and
that's painful the key is very painful
you see you cannot hold it down you know
suppose you have like three three pins
you cannot code it down but with you
know for example with if you have a
single key like W I can hold it down you
know I can just go to whatever frame I
want but with you know controlling so
like control X oh okay control X oh you
know that's painful so first of all you
want to change the key for the other
window but even better is that you want
to expand the functionality of the other
window command so that so that when you
only have one you know when you have
only when you do not have any split pin
it will actually switch window like
right now so that's what exactly the
sonics window frame does you know you
can look up let's see it's on my website
you know whenever I show come back
whenever you see any command here you
can just such a name it's probably it's
most likely on my website okay so this
one okay I actually do not have this one
on website but anyway it song is it
syncs off like he's you know stuff like
he's using github okay so next window
frame delete or the window DV or a
window is just get rid of you know just
get rid of all split pins you know just
press one key then you read you read of
all split pens so that's this command
your window and three window below it's
just that like that like that and you
also have another command to split
window side by side so that command is
so yeah so I think that's all basically
that's that's that's the major you know
that's the fundamental commands I used
to switch to manage my my spray paint so
you know windows or stuff you know what
I think when I use spray paints very
often for example let's look at the
browser okay so this is my eMac eMac
sprog you can see there's tons of pages
no no let's say if you want to search
for some word let's say you want to
search for RFC here so but then you want
to go back to this position so what I do
is let me show you the yeah so what I do
is spray the pan I search RFC okay you
see there we are this is this is the
word I want so maybe I read it or do
some editing you know something then
when I'm done just you know unsplit you
know I'm back to the position I was you
see now there are other methods to jump
back to your position but but you know
ultimately I tried you know many other
basically all the methods I so I my
conclusion is that actually most of the
time I just do this so you know dude
let's do it again
spirit window such and it's such for
Haskell okay I found it do whatever I
want to do here when I'm done just close
that and I'm back to you know my own
journal position and another advantage
is that you can compare
you know let's say you know let's say I
want to search Haskell so such a game
you know so you see I have two places
that contains two what has cow you see
nine for hunt rifle for one one and in
lying you know 100 something and I can
compare them you know so so that that is
the advantage of spit pain okay that's a
lot talking I hope I hope I'm not like
all of a sudden just like talking to
myself
super thanks thanks for you know well
thanks for coming by and thanks for the
questions yeah yeah so my current
keyboard a mouse okay
I've been actually I've been trying
showing this but okay so you can see now
I don't have a camera you know I've been
talking about these before
milk multiple times so my I'm going to
buy a new camera but right now my I have
two cameras here but both of them are
pretty lousy you know the one I'm using
right now is like 10 years old you know
it's ten years old you know it's like
you can you know it's a lot you take you
know ten years old like ten dollars on
Amazon but my other camera it's not you
take my 22 okay not you take c920 too
and that is the worst camera don't buy
that because it cannot focus so that
means I was I have been unable to do
keyboard reviews the one I'm using right
now it does not even have focus I mean
it's fixed focus so it's it doesn't have
variable focus so this is the best you
can see so this is Connie's Kinesis
advantage too and that's that is the the
Logitech six something you know it but
yeah you know I want to show you this
spin feature the wheel you can see I
showed that yesterday yesterday was what
about them
but let me let me just quickly show you
oh mercy oh yeah yeah I don't you know I
don't know what you can do about that in
Brazil I mean as as well as in Europe
and Russia or other countries you know
in China as well when you buy the
you know super expensive so I you know
let me show you the let me show you the
mouse the Logitech mouse the this one
now I have a video here that's a good
video you can see the spin of the wheel
it can spin like for 20 seconds or more
than 20 seconds so this is fantastic
because right now for example let's go
to Twitter you know three notifications
okay so I go to my home page I go
through hold on a second let me stop the
video here so I go to my treat
right you know Twitter has this infinite
infinite squirrel you can see once you
reach the bottom your show more so you
you know you just spin the mouse you
just keep going you see so I don't have
to touch the mouse you know I can just
press and you know right now it's still
spinning so you know it's just waiting
for Twitter to load you know Twitter is
like getting slow in the past few days
but anyway so you can see there are so
many pages here you know if I use page
up in the you know a Paige Paige Paige
Paige Paige Paige you know Paige Paige
Paige Paige Paige you know so it's a
huge amount of stuff and with spinwheel
it's so convenient to control anywhere
you know like that you know it's
intruder it's no good because it's so
laggy so let me show you here so this is
my keyboard block you can see you can
see I'm spinning a mouse you know all
the way up and down I don't like Miami's
here like you know my n is here and so
it's it's extremely convenient when you
have long Paige this is now this is
especially super important and
convenient on Linux why because our
windows in mac on a Mac you have
accelerated squirrel let me show you
actually this is the critical point on
the mouse on the Mac you have
accelerated squirrel let's see we're
scrolling speed right now I turn it off
so that because I have a spinning wheel
so when you have a spinning wheel I want
the speed to be constant so so you know
how fast I scroll depends on how fast
this the wheel spins and since it just
can spin you know so fast you know I
want it to be constant but if you do not
have the spin wheel you can you know the
Logitech the Logitech mouse there is a
button you can press now it's it's not
[ __ ] on a second
okay so you see before he was spinning
no it's no it's not spinning stupid but
anyway now it's creaky
now anyway so this sucks
so anyway so what I'm saying is that the
Logitech
the Logitech mouse can you know you can
put it to spin or you can put it to
crickey mod so when it's quickly mod and
if you put you know acceleration scoring
speed to fast this is what happens you
see you can you see this is a long page
like 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 when
you're 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 but
you see if I want to go all the way to
the top and just do one wait 1 2 3
you know for swipes and you know not
even for like 1 2 3 went to it because
I'm I you know I you know I try to
scroll it fast its accelerated but if I
scores slowly it's very slow so
ultimately what I mean is that with when
you have accelerated squirrel you can go
to any position any desired position on
a very long page in just one or two
swipes you know I can finally control on
Windows you do not have that but if you
buy any Microsoft Mouse or Logitech
mouse then you have that now that's a
situation like five years ago
I don't know what's today but basically
if you buy any Microsoft Mouse or
Logitech mouse then you also have
accelerated squirrel so that's excellent
but are we on on Linux you don't have
any of that dinner suck so bad on Linux
it's like this you know you just like
you know you score score doesn't matter
you know you cannot use the mouse to
control things oh you have to like
carefully grab the scrollbar and you
know that's that's so painful so that's
the situation so I recommend I highly
recommend
that our Linux you get the mouse with
[ __ ] we're okay on a Mac or Windows
it's not really not necessary but it's
still very good it's still very good
spin wheel
so let's screen speed yeah let's put it
back to - no no acceleration because
because I can you see my mouse is
spinning spinning spinning so that's
about that's that about Mouse so let's
go back see what thanks
so five years ago rehaan loaf and some
well I don't make much money you know
I'm still pretty poor so I was I talked
about that topic came as stream as well
because that's that's a topic that's a
shall we say that's a dramatic topic you
know because topics like that tends to
you know get people interested in you
know but no I don't well I don't
yeah I don't I have like the poverty but
of poverty but you know that's how
things are so what I want to do okay so
any any other questions because I want
to you know I was so I was going to try
the stream for a while how long how long
have we been doing it for an hour maybe
already so how many people how many
people are watching for people okay so
if you have a questions let me know and
did I get that question about about
Windows management is that did I did I
answer your question I mean you see
yeah okay so the windows management I
hope that I addressed that let's say you
max Prague so the keys you know actually
I have a article you know I
let's see where so it this is about
Windows Manager management so because in
the article it's you know it's the
question is answered rather fully be
I've been right I've been you know
talking about this point so many times
so where is it
Emacs packages Emacs miscellaneous Emacs
modernization will be Emacs
miscellaneous okay yeah here it is
fullscreen versus multiple windows so
you know you can just copy the URL you
know just this is a go Ameristar dog
that's my local file but but here's the
URL so i give more detail actually okay
here effective window management you
know you know you can read more about it
and you know i have explanations why and
stuff
how most recently so what I have been
what have I been doing most recently so
for computer programming or actually I
just read my blog you know I I don't
remember myself you know it's probably
easier just to look at my blog so I was
talking about so I have like 6,000 HTML
pages so basically every day I'm trying
to maintain them and update them you
know on you know many languages so well
anyway so what is what have you been
doing maybe well I didn't let's not look
at my blog so anyway I have let me just
talk you know I have I have a Emacs blog
ever let's go to this go to my home web
page let's go here so sorry that info
now sorry that info is my main website
now the content on the website is math
and programming basically that's the
only content on the the category of
content on this website so Anwar and
keyboard and Unicode miss famous but
they all have to do with programming
they all have to do with computing so
and I'm sorry that info I have I have
like four blocks so keyboard blog is all
about keyboards now programming block is
mostly about programming programming
Linux Linux tips programming languages
you know some interesting stuff about
programming language design and things
like that and Unicode in design of
Unicode and whatever details sometimes
political organizations that you you
know anything related you know
HTTP protocol and stuff and web there
web dev is mostly about Java ciao
Java JavaScript CSS HTML so you know
it's interesting I spent like I spent
like two four years to study JavaScript
so I have this JavaScript in depth you
know I I've been blogging Emacs for like
20 years
well 2010 you know 12 years something
like that 12 years blogging Emacs and
I've been coding new Mac this for like
over ten years but however my email is
this tutorial is practical you know it's
a practical tutorial it is not in depth
by that I mean you know any programming
language you can look at them in depth
in depth meaning that you you understand
the details of how they work but usually
it you know those kind of questions are
you development to actually you know
using a language you know but it's still
useful and interesting so anyway what
I'm trying to say is that my JavaScript
in depth tutorial is actually in depth
because I spent basically full time for
two years on the JavaScript language the
JavaScript language is very complex but
anyway but compared to my Emacs this
tutorial which actually I didn't you
know it's not like focused effort you
know I just I just write it as I go
anyway so if you like to learn
JavaScript you can try to you know you
can try my tutorial but javascript is
actually the worst language you know it
is I mean even considering Eggman script
2015 which is the latest version it's
vastly improved from the old version of
JavaScript but but overall it's still a
very bad language so anyway I have the
deadlock temper my dead block is
JavaScript CSS HTML
then I have math block now math is a
subject I truly love but I'm not doing
much you know with it so I still trying
you know I still try to do but you know
math is the topic math is a subject such
that it's so deep and it's beautiful
it's so deep and beautiful and difficult
you know you you know you think I think
I'm smart but when you are here math you
know they are not people far smarter
than you
but okay the other point about math II
said it's a black hole you know you
study it intensively you know for years
and there's no reward basically other
than you know just for yourself there's
no financial reward there's no there's
no new board of anything you cannot even
find a job now this is in contrast to
programming where in programming you can
study it for one year or two and you get
a job and there's a lot you know huge
amount of money and then the programmers
talk garbage all day you know like the
JavaScript you know the Haskell people
is the Perl people the Java people
they're talking about programming styles
defensive programming idioms in this or
that and my my way is better than yours
my language is fear in your language is
what [ __ ] you know the programming
the programming subject there is no
concrete foundation like math in math
you know you cannot talk [ __ ]
basically okay you cannot in general
talk [ __ ] because everything is very
concrete and precise you know so there
is not much you know code or something
like that in math you know everything is
almost absolute but in programming is
like you know you have you know random
stuff Enderman [ __ ]
and each one think they are you know
they would they know or not they know
better than you you know also that
happens in this community as well you
know Common Lisp and scheme this okay
that's another topic so then I have the
Emacs blog my Emacs blog is in Ocoee max
website so so but I haven't answered the
question so what I have have I been
doing lately okay well I can look at my
blog but the better thing is you know
it's probably better if I just talk
without looking at my nose and stuff you
know so I've been doing you know I've
been doing a lot of video recording and
streaming my grant right now you are
seeing and and okay well so in past year
I have also been studying golden and
very I colon has become my favorite
language now I'm like I'm amazed by :
not because it's actually you know
better than functional language or it's
not even a math language you know I like
math languages but but : is so practical
and so fast
it's basically okay in summary think of
this way this is my opinion about : you
know you have Python in Ruby's right
Python Ruby PHP JavaScript these are
extremely popular in the industry and of
course you have C and C first first two
and they are extremely popular in Java
but golden is a language that it is
extremely simple to learn okay really
I mean you can learn you know that you
can basically have a good picture of the
whole language in one day