Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show. We are
coding emac bisp today. So this is uh
for advanced eac bisp coders. So if you
are
emacs l this coder this is good for you.
If you are watching offline play at 1.5
speed and if you are here say
hi. Okay. So we what we gonna do is
let's see. So video check, audio check.
Uh yeah. So here's what we gonna do. So
we got so in EMAC there is a bunch of
new functions
uh introduced about I think maybe 10
years ago by now but it's not well
known. So you have like about 20
functions. map apply, map contains key,
map copy, map delete, map do, map
element and so on. Um, so they so I am
going to write the tutorial for it. So
if you check, you know, I have a eac
list tutorial. If you search it, you'll
find it eacis basics. So So I'm going to
add this to uh my eac this tutorial and
meanwhile maybe explain some of it. So
you for you Emacs users you may you
might check out my workflow. So I'm
using keys
uh most efficient key binding for Emacs.
So here is the source code 4,000 lines
of code. It's on GitHub and uh you can
check out the documentation and video on
this page fly keys. Okay. It's most
efficient key binding for Emacs. So
that's what this about. So you don't
have to press control or meta or old
much like vim but more efficient than
vim or neo vim. And the pink window
shows all my command calls uh the
command name as I type them. For
example, delete the entire body section.
Just press a key you see. So that is kas
smart delete in kasa html mod. You can
see so that is um so the command name on
the right the keystroke on the left I'm
using a vorac keyboard layout okay so
that's the introdu introduction so so
yeah so kafly keys close uh close uh
what is this emac blog
so so I need to yeah show today's talk
show page so we need uh so first of all
we want to know when is this added you
know it might 10 years ago. Let's see
uh map filter. Okay, let's check
uh let's
check describe function. Um go to so
they are in this file
map. And uh let's see the header. So
this is
done in 2015. So I think this could be
10 years ago, you know. Uh but but let's
know so what they do is that you know in
eac this view have okay so let's let me
show you go to eac this copy the page
close that close that close that so
delete that so let's paste a link here
emac this basics so go there then you go
to data structure
section data structure and in eaglist
basically List is the most important
data structure. Then you have
specialized list. They are also list but
specialized. They are association list,
property list and then symbols property
list. Okay. So association list is
basically a list of pairs. So it's a
list but each element is again a list of
two things. Okay.
Uh and property list is is a list but
every even element is considered the
key. Uh every art. So you got key value
key value key value. So it's a list but
it's in
interpreted interpreted as a uh list of
pairs. So this is called property list.
Okay. So both association list and
property list they are uh you know they
are they are just lists but with special
uh structures special use. Then you got
you got symbol property list which is
which is essentially a property list you
know uh key value key value key value
but however they are attached to to
symbols. So all these are lists you know
list is the fundamental data structure
for lisp languages. Okay. Then then you
got few other data structures. You got
vectors which are just like arrays. They
they are fixed. They cannot grow. And
then you got um then you got hash table.
Okay. Hash table is again hash table is
again a key value pair specialized in
the emac. So in Python they call a
dictionary. In the immac case the hash
table is not a list. So it's a dedicated
structure data structure for key value
pairs. However their user their
interface you know so-called API Java
would call it interface. Their interface
of hasht or association list or property
list or symbol property list. They are
the same. I mean they are just a
sequence of key value pairs. Okay. So
they they essentially have the same
interface. So then they introduced I
think so 10 years ago they introduced
um you know they they introduced this
generic so-called generic functions to
deal with all these key value pairs. So
their arguments can be a association
list or a property list or a hash table.
Okay. So that's what they are. So I
think not many people know it know them.
Uh I think so I've been wanting to write
about them for a long time. So I need to
you
know go through them look for you know
learn them for myself but also uh write
a full documentation with usage examples
you know for each one of them. So this
this will take me um you know if I work
it
fulltime eight hours you know a day but
so usually take me a few days to write a
complete tutorial okay like my um like
what I have here. So you see so in EMAC
list we have a list data structure but
then 10 years ago they introduced uh I
mean so I mean
they they introduced like 20 functions
generic functions to deal with se uh
lists. So these are you know so I
documented here. So you can see sequence
functions you got. So so these functions
will work on on list and will also work
on vector and it will also work on
string. So they are generic
functions. So in a similar way that's
why they also introduce this map dash
something that's
for you know generic function for any
kind of key value pair.
Okay.
So, so we know Okay. So, let's see. So,
first of all, we want to know when is it
added. So, for examp so, this file um is
added I think so around 2015. So, the
other thing to check is check out the
official documentation news. So, Ctrl
HN. Okay. So this is the official
documentation for Emacs. Every new
version they are documented. So you go
to the directory you can see they call
it news. Uh but basically it's these are
features. So this one is a current for
uh for um for Emacs version 30. Okay. So
let's let's let's search for uh check to
see when is it um are these added. Okay.
So let's let me try this
map. Okay. Search for that. Uh okay. Not
there. Let's let's let's go to 29. This
matching lines. Okay. Not this. Close
28. This matching lines. Uh okay. So
they got a
new so they modified it. You can see
some of these. Uh so let's have a
look. Okay. The function changed. Now
use copy a list on a list. Okay. So PK's
map uh map eel. So this is the this is a
library that contains so that 80s keys
are now consistency compared with equal
okay PKs function. So they they updated
some of them. Okay. So that's Emacs 28.
Go to Emac 27. Search for it. Okay.
So yes. So it's also
here new gener generic function map
insert. So they are still adding to it.
So this is Emac 27. 27 is like seven
years ago or something.
uh Emacs 27, you know. Um yeah, 27 is
probably
2017. Okay, so let's go to 26. Search
for
map new optional argument test function
in a list get map el and map put. Okay,
so they are pretty old this map package.
Um okay, 25. Let's
search.
Um, there it is. So, they started, it
began in Emacs 25. The map library
provides map manipulation functions that
works on association list hash table and
uh and array. What what is
array? Okay. Uh, all functions are
prefixed with map. Okay.
Okay. So we know so must be Emac 25. Now
when is Emac 25? 2014. Yeah. So 10 years
old.
God.
Okay. Hello D.
Hey I'm doing well. Thank you. Have some
tea. This is uh this is lingin tea.
pretty hot today here in California. So,
Emacs 25. So, let's go to
version. Let's go to my page on Emacs
version history. Emacs 25 released in
2016. So, it is 9 years old.
Jesus. Yeah. So for 9 years old I didn't
document
this. Uh yeah so I want to go into the
you know it's um very interesting. So
let me start to prepare go to talk
show today's talk show. So they are
created in EMAC 20
uh EMAC version 25. Okay. So let's
see. Yeah. Okay. So they are created in
EMAC
25. Okay. So let's show. So these so
here you have the functions. So the
first thing okay
so first when is it created that we
found
out the next
thing add them
to
s e emac this
mod okay so that I have syntax coloring
for example if I um pop this code out.
Oh, they are already syntax colored.
That means I have added them in my emac
this mod. So, let's go
there. Describe key. Press press uh wait
describe key. Press
press. Then you go to e list mod. go to
the source code and uh search for map
dash
uh list matching lines. So there there
we have it. So it's over here. So you
can
see so let's make it uh one word per
line. Okay. So all these sections are
like M. Okay. So press press press press
one word per line. Okay. So now search
for map dash. Okay. So starting here. So
I got them. Okay. Fantastic.
So I already added them to my eagisp
uh
mode. And now what what to do next?
Okay. Make a backup.
So the other thing I need to do in EMAC
this mod is let's write it down. Okay.
So todo close scratch close uh put it
back
uh close that. So another thing to do is
to
add function templates. Okay let me show
you how that works. So let me let's do
that. Okay. add function
templates.
So, so let's say uh
wait yeah over here.
So, yeah, these are not okay. So, so
let's say map let search for it. There's
no other
occurrence. Map into no other
occurrence. So there's
no So what does what does what about map
apply? What does it do? Let's
see. Map apply is a function in map.el.
Map apply function map. Apply function
to each element of map and return the
result as a
list. Okay. So it doesn't return a hash
table. So function is called with two
arguments the key and the value. Okay.
The default implementation dedicate to
map do. Okay. So it returns a
list. Okay.
So and what is this undocumented? So we
can do to
array. Now
array array in eac lisp is not an actual
data structure. It is a name for a set
of data structures. So let's see. So you
got list, you got con cell, you got
vector, you got sequence type. Let's
click on that. So here is a overview of
data structure in lisp.
So all of them is called I mean so this
so these are sequences sequence is not
an actual data type. So but inside you
have list you have association list you
have property list those are
lists and then also includes array. Yeah
so yeah array just means vector and
string. Okay, array is not an actual
data type in lisp in eacisp but it means
either vector or string. Okay, that's
what array means. So it says here map
can map to vector or string. Okay, and
uh why are these
undocumented? I don't know why why does
it
say you know I hate these generic gener
generic functions crap
uh let's you know for let's take a
excursion why does this you know where
does this come from undocumented
thing I believe because they are
implemented using common list exactly
you see common list define generic map
apply something
something.
So, so those documentation that
says that says
undocumented these sections are
automatically
generated meaning
that the meaning
that okay so you actually write a imp
implementation for each of these but you
don't have documentation okay something
like that. So, close the news. Go back
here. Map applies. Let's search for it.
Uh, let's search for
it. Define CL method. Okay, that's how
you do it. You you you implement each
um I think let's highlight it.
So you see if the argument is a list or
if the argument is a hash table or if
the argument is array and they didn't
document each one but you don't need to
actually that's right. Okay. So okay
that clarifies the
uh you know this undocumented thing.
Okay. So okay news 28 close. Um okay. So
next now we
know now the other thing I want to know
let's look at this a little bit more. So
this package this maple go to the
top let's read a little bit so we have
some kind of more general understanding.
Okay. So it says map eel provides
generic map manipulation functions.
Okay. Working on a
list association list property list
hashts and arrays. So what does it mean
when it says it works on array? That's
probably
means it's going to take a pair at a
time of a vector or string. Okay.
Probably all functions are prefixed with
map dash. Functions taking a predicate
or iterating over a map using a
function take the function as their
first
argument. Okay. All the functions that
take the map as their first argument.
What functions taking a predicate or
iterating over a map using a function
take the function as their first
argument. All the functions take the map
as their first argument. Oh, I
see. Okay.
So some functions the first argument is
a
function such as map something but the
others the first right okay
so all the functions take the map yeah
this is you see this is an issue of
technical writing this sentence is not
well
written it could be written better so
it's Just saying
that for those map functions that takes
a function the function usually come
first but otherwise if it doesn't take a
function the you know the first argument
is a map obvious
uh so in fact you should remove this I
believe it would be better remove this
paragraph okay to do as support for
chart tables okay chart table is rarely
used. Maybe add support for uh GV now.
What is
[Music]
GV?
GV. Okay, I don't know what is GV. GV
get GV get is an autoloaded uh function.
So what is GV?
Go to the
top. Stefan Moner, someone I can trust.
Okay. So,
[Music]
GB.El. This is the re the implementation
of the set F machinery using a different
underlying
approach from the one used earlier uh in
common dispander.
Okay. So that's what GVS is. It's kind
of underneath wood voodoo
voodoo which I don't care
much. You know this you know this kind
of thing is like uh the C and C++ people
gets excited
uh GV which uh I don't care. Okay. So
but but it's a reimplementation of the
set F. Okay.
set F in my opinion should be
banned. That's
crap. Okay, let's go back to what uh
what we need to do. So GV Okay. Uh see
if we can integrate text properties.
Okay. Yeah. Marco similar to let a list
but working on any type of map could be
really useful. Okay. So anyway, so we
have some idea of this package.
Now let's show a example of creating a
template. Okay. So for example, let's go
back close that
uh close this news. Close this occur
close messages and
uh okay then showing
browser is the font large enough? Okay,
that's so what we want to do is now
Yeah.
Okay. Go to EMAC list
block. Okay. Let's say I want to map
apply something. So first of all let's
create a association list because that
one is easier to understand. Oh property
list. Let's do association list.
Okay. So
um let's say define v xx let's say dot
uh uh a list okay let's just say that
initial value
neo as a list okay now what is the value
the value would be set that um then list
let's do the simple way
Okay. Cons uh Okay.
So cons is a pair in this in this. Yeah.
So uh first element let's say uh
one
5 six
Okay. Pify it. Pify it. That's good.
That's association list. Okay, now we
want to do the map apply. Now I don't
know how to use it. So let's manually
try to uh do it. So two argument
probably the first one is a
function. Check the
documentation. So there it is. Okay. Map
function uh map function map. Okay. So
what the function will be? Let's say
something lambda. Okay.
Uh something lambda it takes two
arguments a uh okay a a and bb and what
you want to do to them. Let's say add
one. Okay. So it
returns what what okay what is the
requirement? What does the function
needs to
return? Uh does it like does it must it
return a pair or must it return a single
value I think it doesn't say so um I
suppose a single value
okay so let's say a single value let's
add them together let's
Say let's say string okay
uh format
okay format
uh two things
uh let's let's say uh comma that okay a
bb okay now put this there and put the
and uh beautify the code Okay, let's run
it.
Okay, eval that eval
that eval and
insert. There it is.
Okay. So, we are trying to find out what
what this function do. So, here is a
example. Fantastic.
Okay. So, now we know kind of we know
the form of the function. Let's now uh
let's now add a template for the
function in this mod. Okay. So actually
it's just that. Okay. So go to this mod.
Search for map and found. Now let's go
just go to abbreviation section. Uh
so yeah. So there is our abbreviation
section. Define our abbreviation and
templates. We want to add a map
apply.
Uh so first of all let's let's go to the
full
um so we getting technical
here key
map. Yeah. So somewhere here. Okay. We
want to add something like that. So by
first of all copy that and duplicate and
just say that and and then you just
paste that there and remove this whole
thing. Okay, that's your template. Now
once
you do completion, you want your cursor
to be here. So let's add the cursor unic
code character.
Okay, describe char. That character
is this unic code character called black
vertical rectangle which is suitable
to represent a
cursor. Okay, so we got that added now.
Now eval the buffer. Make a backup. Go
to the directory. Bite compile it just
to be sure we don't have any error.
Correct. No error. Open the back compile
file. Delete it. Close it. Okay. Now we
go back to our list code. Okay. Put it
back. Reopen it. Now we can
say map. Okay. First of all, completion
map apply there. Now press enter.
Fantastic. Automatically added
that. And now let's improve it. I want
to add the lambda. Okay, because this
function usually you're going to you
know usually you're going to say lambda
something. So let's just add the lambda
there. Yeah. So the function is actually
just lambda. Let's add it there. Okay.
So, let's like
um and in fact this is
a you know you got two things two two
arguments.
Um okay. Something like that. Okay.
Evaluate. That's good. Make a backup. Go
back to the code. Anyway, so we
finished. We finished. We completed
another job which is add a function
template to emac this
mode complete. Okay. So that's how you
do it. Now if you are you know if you
are not familiar you can go to you know
go to.info info Emacs tutorial and go
to create major mod tutorial. So here's
a complete tutorial on how to create a
major mode for your language for your
favorite language JavaScript or Rust or
Python or
whatever. And uh how to create a
template there is a dedicated function
uh about that.
Uh let's see
uh create key map create functions
keyword
completions we you know we have that uh
then create template create function
template we do this by using
abbreviation okay by using the
abbreviation table feature of Emacs.
Okay so let me demo it again. So show in
browser. Okay close that. Close that.
Switch back. Close that. Go here. Show
in browser
now. Now all these functions
um Okay. So let me let me
try search for that. Okay. Not oh why is
it not
there?
Um okay. So
there's so anyway so let's pop this out.
Uh we are missing that map can wait map
can is not part of it. Map can is
something
else. Apply function to each element of
sequence. Uh but okay digression. Now a
little digression. Let's go to my Emacs
tutorial on
list. And uh we want to know where where
is map can like I don't remember. I
should have it in my
tutorial. Okay, I forgot. So cut it. Go
to Emacs page. Search for map can. Let's
see if we can find it
somewhere. AZ, hello AZ. Hello, Diego.
Hi there. Why is the link in your
description still insecure? Oh my god.
You know, go to
um go to Kasar Discord, okay? You can
find it on my
um you know you can find it on sadi.info
info
uh that you know there is my my YouTube
my discord so go there and uh talk to me
so you can tell me all about it how to
do it and if you are really want to help
if you are really patient and want to
help we can go through step by step you
know arrange for an hour or two
uh you know uh tomorrow or next
If you are really
concerned about that issue, it's very
easy to make your site secure and it's
dangerous for anyone visiting your site.
That's a total Did you Did you
listen to my um Did you listen to my
rant yesterday? Oh, yeah. I turned off
the I made the video private because I
was talking about JavaScript and I
wasn't doing a good job.
So, so anyway, yeah. So, you you know,
go to Discord. You know, I I probably
should do it, but you know, it's really
nasty. Okay, let's go back to this.
Okay, so map
can for some reason I don't have this
document document
documented. That's that's not good. So,
that means I'm missing something on my
tutorial. So let's put this
uh let's put this in to do.
Okay. I don't know where this kind of
let's look at the emac this
documentation. So
um let's see. So map
can show in browser mapping functions
map
car map P. So why don't I have map can?
I believe map can map the function
applies function to each element of
sequence like map car but instead of
collecting the
result the font is too small right
um let's see okay so
let's okay that's
But instead of collecting the result
into a list, it returns a single
list with all the elements of the
result which must be lists. what by
altering the
result like with map
car. Uh I'm not sure what is
doing. Okay. Anyway, that's a
digression. I'm missing this function in
my tutorial. So, okay. So, let's ignore
it for now. Okay. So now we
have we have added a template. We have
add the syntax coloring of this function
map apply. We have also added a
template. Let me show you other
templates. So D for define space become
def space become template. You know DV
for define v
space. You see so you can
lm lamb for lambda space become the full
template. So all those are implemented
in s e emac this mod
uh using the abbreviation feature.
Okay. So you know you there are like a
thousand of them you know the like the
top 100 or 200 most used functions they
have abbreviation and they have template
for example you can see a full list of
them for example here is the most
frequently used functions you have
single character abbreviation
uh so for example L for let is a
fantastic Q for quote actually Q is not
very frequent And uh but P for point, V
for vector. So you
know you know so uh then once you expand
V for vector then you expand again you
get a template. So those are all
abbreviation. Okay try to uh learn it.
Abbreviation is not just useful for
implement implementing a EMAC major mode
but it's most useful for writing English
for
example I have one cat you know uh how
are you so a become a you become you
things like that and by the way expand
to by the way BTW and so on. So
uh you can see I have
like 1,500 abbreviations. Okay. And if
you want to learn about that it's
all
documented just search for Emac this
abbreviation tutorial set up hundreds of
a brief. So you can learn this in 10
minutes and you'll have a much better
life. So it's not just used for uh you
know for for
example I can quickly get all the emoji
I want. Uh and RA for right arrow.
Fantastic when you are writing
mathematics.
A map to B for example. So abbreviation
I think it's the top five most best
feature of Emacs.
Okay. Okay. That's about abbreviation.
So cut this close. Uh let's add it back
to talk show. Okay. Let's mention it
here. Uh create a
new text block. paste it there just so
that we
showed about abbreviation. Okay. So,
uh yeah. So, copy
that. That's digression link it. And now
let's go back to Yeah. So, now you see
you see
this. Oh, yeah. So, next thing we're
going to do. Okay. Next thing. Uh let's
see.
Okay. All good. Close
that. So we got we got uh so close that
close that close that close close. And
now we want to okay remove that. So we
have demonstrated that. Okay. So yeah.
So we have syntax coloring. We
have abbreviation. We have template.
Done. So we I I just need to do for each
one of them. Add them the template to my
Emac this mod. Okay. So I'll do that
offline, but I showed you how to do
it. Next thing, the next big job is to
write a tutorial page for for all of
these. Okay, so that's the next big job.
So let me just So here's today's talk
show. That's all good. So next job is to
write the tutorial. Okay. So let's do
that for 10 minutes and that'll be it
for today. So we go back to
um so if you like my stuff, pay me,
okay? Go to sardi.info.
If you you know if my teaching is
helpful, is
fun, Amazon PayPal, Amazon gift card me,
okay, Amazon G, you know, and or PayPal
me $100. That'll be
good. Okay, so now we want to write a
tutorial. Okay, so let's go to this
basics. Let's go to
um so how do
you you see writing a tutorial that's a
new uh whole thing. So uh in fact there
are like 20 functions to go
about copy new buffer. So like yeah 20
26 25
functions. So what where do you want to
add it? you want to add.
You see it's kind of odd with these map
functions
because they are generic functions but
they don't
have like in EMAC this there is
no generic
name to mean any of property
list association list and hash table.
Okay, you see for lists you do have some
kind of you know you call all of them
you call them
sequences then you got a bunch of
sequence functions starting with seq
that works on any sequence data
type okay but
now for for these map functions they
work on anything that's kind of having a
pair of things so So that would be hasht
and association list and property list.
Okay. But you don't have a generic name
for for this uh data type together. So
that's that's that's a idiosyncrasy with
emac disp because in Java you would
because they you know in Java you you
group them according to the interface
like they are mathematical
uh shape which is called
interface. So the question for me is
where do
you you know you you I'm probably going
to have one or more than one page for
these functions. Where do you want to
add them? Like obviously you create a
new page uh but you create a new
subsection for sure.
Um okay so it would be after hasht.
Okay, you see all these functions is not
necessary because hasht already has
their hasht functions. Uh add entry, put
hash, rim, ren, you know, remove entry,
rim hash, get hash. And for for the
property list you also already have a
lot functions probably you know p get
lax p get p put and for association
list you also have
um many uh dedicated functions for them.
uh for example a list get alist put a so
string and so on. So so what but what
this do you know what this new generic
thing do is that they kind of make it
more unified. So you just have one
interface to work with any of
these which which is kind of better but
it's not really necessary. It's It's not
exactly
um you know perfect for
this. Okay. But anyway, so so where do
you add them? Okay.
So for now I'm going to base it on hasht
page.
Okay. So hasht page. Yeah. There. Okay.
Going to be after this page. So let's
put that there.
hasht and
uh and then we
have okay so hash table okay let's let's
begin to do it okay so this hash
table copy it paste it and uh this uh
how do you call them okay so there's
another
issue what is the name
For these
functions, how do you call them? Do you
say map functions? You know, you need a
title for the
section. So, you know, so these are
issues about writing a tutorial or
programming language
documentation. Hello, we got a bunch of
guys.
Uh, so what you guys are saying? Let's
see.
Wait, what is
my
control shift + control + one?
So usually
control scroll
up will magnify it but now it is not
working. So alternatively control plus
sign will magnify it but I don't know
where is my plus
uh sign. So let's
see. So I'm using also I'm using sticky
key. So that's why it's a bit all
confusing. Okay, there is plus. Okay, so
control shift plus. There it is. Back.
That's why you hear the beep because I
got sticky keys going
on. So
a so go on to uh Discord like you don't
know things. Okay. So you are saying no
HTTP is causing are you still here or am
I wasting my time because you are saying
no HTTP will cause you to have middleain
attack. Yes, in fact that happened to
me. Okay, because let me you know so
search HTTP
[Music]
um let's
see you know I can talk a whole hour
about this HTTP stuff. Uh so there is um
so
um let's search for
scam scam on Apple i store Google
sitemap.org or domain typo squatting
scam. Okay. Sound talk show talk show.
Uh ink cartridge scam by follower
scam. Carbon browser crypto web 3 scam.
Wikipedia donation scam. Google AM scam.
Okay, we'll get to it. Google Chrome
browser login scam. Translation SEO
scam. Web spam spam scam SEO. There.
That's the index page. Okay. Now you go.
So on this page there it is. China ISP
ad injection 2015. Click on that. So
this is my web page. A scene in
China in 2015. You can see Can you see
that?info. Now there is this ad of this
dude wearing uh sunglasses. You know
that is not my ad. somebody added there.
Okay, that is not me. So
apparently in China when you view my
website in China because my website is
not
HTTP
they
inject ads into my website and they
remove Google's oh wait okay so I had
Google's ad before but anyway they added
their
own ad. Okay so again it happened again
here. Okay. So, it happened again here
and you know I have friends in China
back then cuz I was uh in Chinese forum
talking to China's
programmers. Uh then they showed
me you know so you know so these are ISP
injection China did it. I don't know if
it's legal. I don't know if it's like
like government are doing it or like
some third party. I'm not sure but they
are doing it back back then. Okay. I
don't know about now. So this why can
this happen? Because I don't have
https. Okay. That's is like that's what
you are saying so excited. Oh s but you
did you know this? Did you know that?
But you didn't know what's happening is
that there is a magnitude bigger scam
that is Google that is
Google and uh they brainwashed you guys
a so you guys don't know so you you guys
like promoting the scam for
Google you know so effectively now they
are banning a few million websites okay
like websites like mine
like I have a totally fully functional
link in my YouTube. You click it, it
says, you know, doesn't work. Then it
tell you a scary things like, oh, this
site is not secure. Maybe you think re,
you know,
reconsider. them, Google. And UAZ
is like helping them promote it like but
you don't know, you know, you don't know
stuff. You need security because it's so
important. Oh, look look look ISP
injection. You don't know a
thing now. Now, of course, it's a choice
to do it. But, but what Google should
not do in the browser is that you know
they they prevent link perfectly working
website. They and no fishing, no more
wear, not asking your credit
card. You know, my website very popular
by the way.
uh you know Google know Google is fully
capable of knowing if a website is like
doing scams okay they are too powerful
to not know they they know
everything but they but but they they
going to you know they're going to
prevent people visiting your site anyway
they know your website don't have
viruses they know what your website is
not for shopping does not ask for credit
card or personal information they know
it but they're going to say oh this site
It is uh Jesus something HTTPS cryptic
insecure ISP something something message
something protocol protocol them
okay that's what hap that's what is
happening and even like I demonstrated
yesterday you know in in fire let me
show you okay so go to YouTube search
for gets me angry
AZ, are you here still? So, let me let
me prompt you. AZ, so right now I'm
talking to you. I don't know who you
are. I think you are a good person. I
appreciate you talking, but but let's,
you know, talk about this
thing. A says SSL is a global
requirement, an an easy implementation.
It has nothing to do with anything you
are saying.
Are you def Did you just listen to what
I'm I said before you know like click on
YouTube s okay live fantastic I'm doing
this live today episode 657 emac this
generic map functions okay uh actually
we need to go on writing the tutorial
but let's do the digression okay so I
did this fantastic
um animation
yesterday. Uh yeah. Okay. So, let me
let's digression. Okay. Let's forget
about the emac this
technicality. We did this beautiful
thing yesterday mathematics. Okay. Let
me show you
something.
Uh okay. This is animation created by
Wufam language. Okay. So, you just copy
the code.
Start wam
language. Cheers.
Tea. You know tea got this
ingredients, some chemicals that calms
your
nerves. That's why you see Chinese, you
know, the in kung fu movies, they always
sip
tea. So, we need to have some tea before
a fight.
So, lots of comments. Okay. So, if you
need me to address your question, tag my
name. Okay. Because I, you know,
u got too many things going on. Okay.
New wam language page three. Shift enter
to evaluate.
Now control scroll up to
magnify. Now paste the code. Copy it
from Kadi website.
Beautiful. Okay. So paste the code
there. Oh, now it's too big. Okay.
That's uh
150.
Uh okay. So,
actually that's still too big. Let's
make it uh let's make it 125. Okay. Now,
split control shift D to split into two
sections. Now, move the cursor here.
Control shift N to make it type set.
Now, you got beautiful type set things.
Okay. Control shift D to split again.
Now load my packages. Shift enter.
Fantastic. They are loaded. Now shift
enter to evaluate this thing. Then you
got this beautiful thing. Okay. Now
you've seen this. You probably tired of
it. Let's try something uh different.
Okay. So yeah, let's try this one.
Flashing diamond. It's going to be
shiny. Okay. So, select all
paste. Now, control shift D to split it.
Okay. Now, evaluate that
part. There it is. Okay. There it is.
Fantastic and beautiful
animation. Okay, let's export it to a
movie. So, let's say flashing diamond.
Let's save it. Let's just say xx.
Okay, xx
diamond. Okay. And let's say MP4.
Okay. Shift enter to run it.
Okay. AZ says, "I'll be here every
stream until people are not at risk."
That's not good. If you do that, then
then I know what you are here for. You
are like a
spam. Then you get banned. Okay? So,
don't do
that. Okay? In fact, I'm kind of Anyway,
so MP4. Now, let's go to desktop. Let's
go to
documents. So, you got XX
Diamond. So, there it is. Now, open
it. There it
is. Okay. And now I want to do I want to
ex export it as a GIF. So all you have
to do is change the file name. Shift
enter. Okay.
So refresh. So wait, where is my gift?
There it is. So open
it. Fantastic. There it
is. So control H for the original image
size. Beautiful. Okay, we did this
yesterday. Uh but well actually I did it
offline, but I showed how to do it.
Okay, but now I want to Yeah. So let's
go back to YouTube. So I say you know
notes at this link. So you click
it in Firefox. Then you say secure
connection failed because they
automatically put a S in my URL. They
changed my URL. Does not you see there
is no S there.
http. So what can you do? So what you
can do is you
copy you you copy this you know. So Ctrl
C copy it new tab paste it and then you
got dot dot dot because these Google
scams you see the way they go into to
prevent you from you know they they they
do like today you know. So anyway, so
what so you right click and copy link.
Okay, so if you do that, they know you
copied the link. Okay, so they tracked,
they get information about it. So now,
new tab, paste it. You see, you know,
it's a scunt. Okay, so if let's
go to Emacs. Okay, new buffer, paste.
You see this is what you you copied. You
copied YouTube redirect. So they not
only know you copied a link on their
website, they also know when you
actually visited it. So this is this is
the scum that Google and this you know
these big giant corporations are trying
to
do. Okay. And uh
then Okay. So then you got this part.
This this this, you know, this is
actually what a what a scam, you
know, extremely scam, you know, this
this
thing. But let me show you. So, so what
you want to do is close that. Okay. What
you want to do is you want to use a good
browser. So brave okay brave does not
follow the what you know brave does not
follow the deep state things that
YouTube google is doing. Okay. So if you
go to brave then same thing. Okay, new
tab, YouTube. Search for
XR. Okay,
so go
there. Turn on
JavaScript so Google knows what you're
doing. Okay, now you click on the same
video. Okay, stop it. Then expand that
and magnify the same link. Okay, now you
click on that link.
Click. Oh, it works
perfectly. There's no
shenanigans. There's no mysterious. Oh,
hacking scam crypto.
That's browser. Okay, let's try uh
another browser I haven't tried long
time. Vivi.
Okay, which is like open source kind of
thing. You see the nasty thing about
this is let's try it in Firefox. Okay,
the Firefox you click it, you get this
secure connection failed. Okay. But if
you go to the the browser settings, you
can
[Music]
see I have it turned off. Privacy and
security,
uh, history, password, auto field. I
turn them all off. I don't want auto,
nothing. Okay. So permissions Firefox uh
security dis uh
certificates there
httpsson
mode don't enable httpsson mode I have
it
clicked but it ignores it beginning
about a month ago. Okay it just ignore
it. So this is uh extreme nasty you know
by default that is on. By default this
uh I believe it's on.
Okay but you know you you turn it off
but it just ignore it. That's that's the
that's why this is nasty.
Okay. So now um you know so so this
demonstrate you know this Google this
this mainstream deep deep state um
corporations mega ja corporations they
are really doing you know so it I mean
this demonstrate what they are doing is
not just for the good heart of it okay
they say they are actually trying to
promote security but but actually that's
not really that's not really the reason
okay they are are pro promoting security
uh and they fool a lot of programmers
you know tech
nerds. Okay so let me check let me see
what we going to do because I already
talked for over an
hour.
[Music]
Um, you know, a is like just dribbling
about. I don't know who you are. I don't
know what your intention. Okay. Don't uh
spam and
stuff. Interesting sub subject. What
kind of forum can I pay attention to?
Diego says asking about Chinese. Yeah.
So around year 2012, I started to know
about Chinese
programmers. Uh because I was in
poverty. I asked for help. I was in
extreme poverty. And
uh then all of a
sudden, you know, I I asked for help.
So, I got about
$8,000 donation from people. And it
turns out majority of them are from
Chinese in China. You know, that's a
extreme. That's totally surprising to me
because I never wrote I didn't, you
know, all my blogs are in English. I do
not know anyone in China. Okay? I never
talked to like Chinese programmers. I
don't know nothing about what they doing
in China. This is this is around
2012. I know that some people in China
and Taiwan where I grew up, I know that
some of them they they know me, you
know, because I have a blog. I say, you
know, I was born in Taiwan. So, some
Chinese I know, you know, some of them
know me, but I never
know any of them. But then when I ask
for donation because I'm about to
die, all of a sudden I see these Chinese
people in China. I never know. I never
talked about, you know, I don't know.
They they donated the most money to me.
Okay, so that is
very very much something. Okay, that is
incredible
because you know I don't want to get
into the rant because I've been writing
Emacs tutorials for 10 years before that
since 2006. I'm very well known among
Emacs community known by just about
everyone and any Emacs user who ever
read Emacs stuff online or write blogs
about Emacs, they know
me. But when I'm dying of
hunger, you know, the the the the most
the money came from
China, not from this American white
fox. That is the point.
Okay. So that you know I you know so
that that so I started to you know so
they donated to me. So I started to uh
talk to them. I went, you know, I joined
the Chinese um programming community in
China, you know, trying to learn about,
you know, something and started to
practice typing Chinese because I I
haven't typed Chinese for like for I I
don't, you know, for for for for a
decade.
So anyway, that's that's why I'm that's
how that is
how then after a year then you know you
know you know they they showed me that
my my my website got ISP injection in
China. Okay. You know, so lots and and
also in Chinese programmer, I I still
don't know them that much, but it's uh
you know, they have their community
uh they have their like own kind of
habits and culture. Okay. Uh they they
become so great today. You know, the
China the rise of China in the past 10
years is just incredible. And I'm really
happy to see it too because I'm Chinese
blood. So, um, you know, and then the
USA government is just, you know, lying
like lying through their teeth every day
about about China and about Taiwan.
Okay, let's forget about China, about
Taiwan. I was born in Taiwan. The USA
government lying through their teeth
about Taiwan since
1990s. Okay. So that's that's kind of
that's you know that's about so China
they they rose incredibly you know they
like today they are like they they they
overtook USA they became the the the
number one in just in everything in
anything you know I I believe there's
only one thing that we Americans are
still doing better than China that is
Elamusk's space X rocket okay that is
phenomenon
that only that not NAZA, not whatever
our technology, not Google, not our
programming languages, not not the HTTP
crap, not nothing, not programming, not
AI, not not you know, we are doing we
are losing to China. Okay, but there's
one thing not space station, not not
space technology, not medicine, not not
chemistry, not what whatever. But
there's one thing as far as you ask me,
you know, my judgment, there's one thing
we do better than China and in fact a
magnitude better is Ela Musk's Space X
rocket that can launch that can launch
and and come back and land.
Okay. And has a payload far far more
than China's rocket right now. Okay. So
that
is Elamusk that you know that is one
thing that we still do better but but
everything else we
became you know we became you know
because because of the deep state
corrupt politicians like the a anything
idiot like saying about HTTPS the Google
you know they are doing all these nasty
things. Do they like they you know what
why are they pushing HTTPS? Of course.
Oh, for security for your own good. But
is it actually what they doing?
[Laughter]
No. So that is uh so so you know look at
Brave browser it just works. And also
Apple Safari it just works. And oh yeah,
let's try. We haven't tried
um Vadi browser. So let's open Vavi. I
haven't used Vadi for like two years or
so. God, this Uh so paste it
there. Paste the my
YouTube and uh turn on JavaScript. Okay,
turn on
JavaScript.
Refresh. You see, I usually even turn
JavaScript
off. You know, I only turn on when
necessary. So, let's click on that. So,
let's first of all magnify. So, you see
there's no S in HTTP. Okay. So,
now click on
that. Ah,
So, Vad is doing the same thing.
Now is it is there a browser settings?
Oh
Jesus. Now if in the settings if I turn
off then if it still does that then it's
really nasty. Okay. So
um so where is the uh view
options tools windows tools develops
tools uh settings. Okay. Now vadi
options there's like a thousands of them
so it's really
um you know I haven't uh used vari for
over two
years so wait startup close and exit
updates language um so what I want is
the privacy and
security okay god elaborate
Enable
ProtonVPN. No, Proton is like
questionable. Protocol handling sites
can ask to handle protocols. Uh, private
Windows Google extensions meet. No. Uh,
I don't want any of that. Google
services protection. No.
DNS. No. Auto field. No.
Uh god, where is the
https payment methods?
[Music]
Uh yeah. So this tedious, you know, all
these technology tools that makes it
Allow sites to check for saved payment.
No. Save and field payment methods. No.
Save webpage password. No. Enable
additional certificate. No. I don't want
to know
nothing. I don't want auto HTTPS. Where
is it?
Uh, and I need to magnify this page. Can
I
magnify? No. stupid.
Uh, anyway. Okay. So, so I don't know
what what
um, you know. So, that's a problem. You
see? Okay. So, anyway, so about the you
see, but why don't I just do it? Okay.
Actually, have you tried Zim browser?
No. So, you know, I could
uh I just need to look into, you know, I
need to spend, you know, a day or two
because I really look into all the
details because now you see it's pretty
nasty. Now they are doing these kind of
things. So, you know, they prevent
people going to my website. Now, let's
see. Let's try Google.
Okay. I don't think they do actually do
it. Okay. Turn on JavaScript, you know.
Let's say
uh Casar Unicode. Okay. Let's search for
Unicode arrows. Okay. Let's see if my
you see my page is still the top top
result when you search for Unicode
arrows. Now let's click it and let's see
if we get this HTTPS arrow. Click
it. No. Okay. So it's just that YouTube
is doing these nasty things. Okay. Okay.
So I think
what's you know what may be happening is
that
YouTube. Okay. Now I got better idea. So
YouTube this link. So let's look at the
source code. Okay. Actually, maybe it
actually changed the source code
even. So, control shift
I to look at the source code.
Inspector. So, I
want to see right click
inspect. You see this is what YouTube is
doing. Let's see.
So, okay. So,
what? Yeah. So, okay. So now let's right
click
copy right click and
[Music]
copy copy out
HTML and show it here. So this is what
actually YouTube is
doing. Okay. So highlight it. Highlight
http
yellow. Okay. And uh there it
is. Okay. So this
link. So can you see? So this link is
actually just not my
link.
YouTube
added this tracking crap.
Okay.
So, so you see I'm wondering if it works
in Brave is because maybe Brave actually
remove this tracking crap. You know,
Brave has that
feature and Safari didn't do anything
extra. That's why Safari is not working.
So this this YouTube very nasty because
you cannot you know you cannot add a
link without it not becoming a link. If
you want to do that you have to
say you know you have to say manually
like http space to break it the link you
know like that then tell people to like
remove the space. Actually I'll do that.
So this YouTube is very nasty
scum. You know they, you know, if you
just add a link, they they become this
YouTube
Okay, that's that's about that.
Um, I think that's it for today.
Okay. What else uh you guys are
saying? Mr. Mogi, have you tried Zim
browser? No, I never even heard of it.
That's another new thing. you know like
every two years they have like a new
browser like championed by the open
source
fanatics it was valdi but I suppose now
there's a new thing vin zen vavadi is
actually not open source like they you
know so who else is anything uh Diego uh
okay so that's it for today thoughts
on Uh KK80. Oh, that's their new
keyboard. Um ultimate hacking keyboard
80. You know that I think that's the one
got function
keys.
Yeah, I I don't think that's a good
idea. You see, let me briefly talk about
this. Okay, if you are still here, you
see if you're going to have the function
keys, you need to have a gap between the
function keys and the number digits
because otherwise you cannot it's very
confusing. You don't know which row you
are on because they are so far up there.
Okay, so you need a gap. The other thing
is that you have function keys. If you
going to have all the function keys, you
need a gap of every four or three keys.
So f_sub_1, f_sub_2, f_sub_3, f_sub_4,
then a gap, then five, six, seven,
eight, a gap. You need a gap. Okay?
Because otherwise you can touch, you
know,
usually it's very good to touch type and
feel, you know, you just know the
position, you can feel the gap and you
know which one is F6 or F7.
But without gaps then keys like F10
becomes like basically become not usable
because you have to look like where is
10. You cannot just feel it. So so it's
great to add function keys but not not
like this. So I I'm not sure this is a
good
design. But here they added the thumb
keys. That's very good. Okay. That's
very
good.
Um, yeah. So, how much they, you know,
how much they charge these for? How is
it different? I mean,
pricewise, how much extra you have to
pay for
this. Yeah. Anyway. Yeah. Okay. So, I
think that's it.
390. Wow. So that's fairly expensive.
Yeah. So I mean but I know from my
experience with automat hacking they are
truly quality. Okay. I mean glove 80 is
truly quality too and also Kinesis 360.
I mean they you
know they are all good quality. Okay. in
different ways, you know, but overall
they are all great. But the edge uh
ultimate hacking the guy like they they
are really concerning every about every
detail. Okay. So if this is your kind of
thing, I can recommend it, you know.
Okay, that's it for today. Uh kind of
rambled in the past
hour. So I have like like what 20 uh 13
viewers. Okay, bye
guys. Pay me. Okay, go to kasadi
kasadi.info
uh and pay me kasali.info and go to the
bottom pay me Amazon.
Okay,
so code go there all the way to the
bottom go to Patreon me a month or
Amazon gift card me or PayPal or you can
get my entire website about 6,000 pages
on programming and
mathematics for just $300.
Bye.