Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to code JavaScript. Today
JavaScript and uh we are going to write
a JavaScript application that transforms
English letters to this squared version
of Unicode.
Uh so if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed minimum because I
ramble. If you are here, say hi. I love
to see your comments. Okay. So
JavaScript coding. Uh so let's we have I
have some examples. Unicode search uh
fire. So that's unic code search written
in JavaScript in fact TypeScript. Now
there's some other examples that similar
to today. So for example here is upside
down
ABC
upside down text. So that's one example.
Actually we just going to copy the code
so uh so it's easier so we don't have to
rewrite everything.
Okay. So that's upside down text and uh
then you have let's see then you have
math font. So let's see a b cde e f
something
how are you today and you can change to
bold or double stroke. Now these are
unic code characters. For example, copy
it. Copy it back to here. Open a uh back
to here. And uh let's say
um let's paste it here.
Uh it's showing browser. Okay. So So
these are characters. For example, in
Emacs, you can you can call uh describe
char. Uh not there. Yeah.
uh describe char and you can see that
character is this character and the unic
code name is mathematical doublestroke
small a so it is actually a character
okay these are not you know using uh
different font so that's a example of
you know uh math fonts so let's uh paste
the link here
so delete delete delete that delete uh
copy that wait Uh so copy the uh URL
make a link make a list go to the uh URL
go to the bottom search for so here copy
the extract the URL close it and paste
it here make a linkify them make a list
and D the first one show in browser so
we have you know upside down text math
font and rune so so select
A B C D E F something. So there are some
examples and you can choose different
rune type um
rune characters and then then there is
another example uh that's Braille. Okay.
So A B CDE E F. So we what we are doing
is just we are uh converting the
characters to different
different unicode characters. Basically
this is actually not a uh translation
because for example for the rune you
know it doesn't this is actually not the
correct translation for something.
So anyway, so let's start to do it. And
uh let's copy the code.
Uh uh let's copy the code. Let's see
which one I want to use. So upside down.
Go back and font size. Uh font size. Can
can you see? Hold on a second.
Okay. So, let's go back. Let's start.
Um,
let's test my audio. Audio is good.
Okay. So, we want to pick one of these
as a prototype. So, convert ma math
font. Uh, let's see. Let's see some
others. run.
Okay, so
got other examples. Hold on a second. My
uh my wife is talking.
So So let me uh
hold on a second.
So let me just code um silently for a
while. Okay.
So, hold on a second.
So, okay, hold on a second, guys.
Sorry about that. I'm back. So, let's
continue coding. So, okay. So, so we
going to copy this file, math font. Um,
God. Okay. Hold on a second. So, close
that. Uh, so go back to talk show. So
today's talk show and uh the the one we
want is the unic code letters. Okay. So
search for section uh uh section D
that. So we want to open this file. So
we're going to write the application in
JavaScript to convert ABC to the squared
version. So we need a JavaScript file.
Make a backup backup. Go to the
directory and rename this uh TypeScript.
Okay. So this this this is going to be
our typescript file. So delete it or
copy the file path and uh so go back
here and showing browser. So we going to
in the at the beginning we going to make
a section new section box. Okay. So here
is a typescript. Okay. Close it. And now
we going to copy the file. So copy. So
go to the directory search for math. Uh
so search uh let's list JavaScript
files. Okay. So list.ts.
Um so what? God. So do it again. Back
slash.ts
because the dot means any character. So
we got a bunch of uh so math font. So
this file we want to copy. So open it.
Copy. Close it. Close it. Close it.
Close it. Okay. Open the JavaS here.
Open. Uh, so it's here. And uh, paste
it. And uh, save it. Okay. Now, close
it. So, we got we loaded. So, so uh, so
we loaded the JavaScript in this new
section. Now, we need to get that uh, we
need to get that HTML.
Okay. Am I doing good? Am I doing good?
Okay. So, let's get the HTML. So, math
font. So, there uh so open uh math font
page. Uh wait, what is this page? Okay,
it's not here. So, close it. Uh search
for math font. Okay, open. We need to
get the HTML. So that would be
so copy the entire thing cut. Okay. Then
go to our squared character page and go
to the top and uh
and uh we
so paste it there and uh
and delete that.
Put it here. Comment out for now. DD
section. So we made a duplicate. So this
is the A B CDE E F. Okay. This is the
math font. So can we magnify? Yeah.
Let's
let's magnify.
Okay. So this is for math. So um so
let's
so let's
see. So that's exactly the same. So we
don't need that. Okay. So now we all we
need to do first of all is trick the
interface
the HTML part. Then we're going to
modify the JavaScript part. So convert
uh
alphabet
to squared
characters
something like that. Okay. That's a
title and the display.
The display is the area that you want to
display it. So, uh let's rename it.
So,
display
copy it.
Replace display
square
char. Okay. Then put a random number.
Do that and search for JavaScript.
Search for JavaScript. Open it.
Do the same replacement. Uh,
wait. Not the popup.
Not uni code popup.
Uni code popup
highlighting. So wait, where is our
um
oh typescript this is a mistake. Okay,
so open that.
Compile it. Uh wait, not that key.
Compile it.
So we got the JavaScript file. Okay,
refresh. Uh
there. Okay. So So close that. Close
that. Close that. Close that. So this
needs to rem rename JavaScript. Okay.
Then then what did do we copy? Oh yeah,
that uh so we need to Yeah. So open open
this JavaS uh open the TypeScript and uh
do the replacement
change. Okay, let's change that.
Okay. And uh
and
now go back to the file. So now show in
browser we need to change convert
alphabet to squared uh characters. Now
there are two versions of squared
characters. One is white, one is black.
So we need to make a choice. So these
are radio buttons. Okay. Uh
now right now it doesn't work because
because we didn't compile it. So compile
it,
refresh
ABC. Okay. So let's say double stroke or
italic or script. Okay. Actually that
should be a bigger size. So let's
change. So okay, hold on a second. So we
need to uh ching Hank. Hello Hank. Thank
you. Any tips for running a low
headcount tech business such as yours?
Uh, most of my time in professional tech
was in falling MSP.
I don't think selling things I can't
deliver like them is fun.
Uh, MSP
I don't know what that is. And uh
uh any tips for running a low headcount
tech business? I'm probably the wrong
guy to ask that because I don't actually
have a business and I'm not making
uh almost zero amount
except you guys donations. So yeah, I
don't really know. I'm just a tech head.
So I'm I'm you know focusing on
technology programming languages mostly.
um in mathematics. So so let's get back
to the code here. Um so we
so we frank and double stroke. Okay. So
that let's rename franctor to
uh type face uh
uh white square boxes. So we got two
versions uh let's see squared negative.
Okay. So y is white and let's say
frctor
replace to
white letters white box letters
something like that. Okay then open the
JavaScript
uh close that open the open our
JavaScript file. Um
where is our JavaScript file? So search
for JS. Yeah, there. Okay. So find and
replace.
Do that. Frantor replace to white box
letters. Okay. Now go back here and
frank
then double stroke replace
by black box letters. Do it. And go back
to JavaScript. Do the same replacement
there. Okay. Now, now this this uh bold
we don't need itallic we don't need math
script we don't need uh mono space we
don't need showing browser okay so we
got just two choices now we need to name
them
uh
let's say letter uh
white squared letters
let's Just say white. Okay, white and uh
black. Showing browser. Uh black.
Showing browser. White and black. Two
choices. Now go back to uh TypeScript.
Let's remove the things we don't need.
So So this is kind of long. Let's make
it one line. Make it one line. One line.
One line. One line. One line. Okay. Now
many of these we don't need. So this is
white box letters. We need to change
that. Change all these characters. And
black box letters. And this uh math bold
we don't need. Delete.
Italic. We don't need delete. Math
script. Delete. And uh this
math mono. Delete. Delete. Okay. So we
got so so let's change this to the
letter uh uh
uh square letters. Okay. So
so
okay so press a key to format it. Now
I'm using Kasa JavaScript mod and I'm
using
uh Emacs Kasafly keys and the pink
window shows all my command calls on the
right and the keystroke on the left. So
Kafly keys if you don't know already
it's the most efficient key binding
system in the universe more efficient
than BIM. So here's the source code.
Open it. Showing browser. You can
download it for free. This is for Emacs.
So you don't have to press control meta
or old. Okay. More efficient than BIM.
So some fly keys. So and the you know
the pink window shows the command codes.
So here we got we got this. We need to
replace them. Okay. So how do you do
this efficiently?
Uh
you see you need to replace the right
column to this. Um
[Music]
okay so let's show let's demonstrate
some EMAC efficiency. Now if you are
using Emacs check out my commands on the
ping window. Okay so I'm just going to
do it
management managed service provider. Oh,
okay. Yeah, I don't know about business
side of things. I just know tech. Uh,
can I make my own key binds based on
yours? Of course. Stop keys. Just try.
There's a tutorials, there's
customization pages, you know, lots of
So, anyway, let's So, we need to turn
this. So, let's see.
Okay. So, now we got that. Now let's say
uh my own command insert a Z. Okay. So
starting a 26. So there we made it.
Okay. Then we need to let's say add
that.
Fantastic. And then let's just say
quotation mark
uh none. Okay. Fantastic. Now do it
again. Now this times square brackets
comma. Fantastic. Is that fantastic and
beautiful? So we got that.
Uh and then we don't need this this this
part anymore. Okay. So go back and go
down here. Delete that. So shrink shrink
and uh shrink shrink shrink. So that's
one line. Okay. And then we need to do
the same thing here. Okay. Uh okay.
We're going to do this all over again so
you can watch it again. So first of all,
we need all the black
uh black characters.
Okay, let's just copy it here. the black
squared characters. Copy it. Close it.
Actually, we shouldn't close it. Yeah.
Okay. Reopen. So, go back here. Paste
the black. Make them into one by each uh
one online each. Then, let's say
um
yeah. So, let's go here.
Insert column a start with a 26 of them.
There we go. And now
now rectangle
insert
that that. Okay. Then now
quotation mark none. Okay. Now
now now add a square bracket around it
with a comma at the end. So those
commands are called
uh sort lines. Okay. If you are
wondering you know for efficiency so
quot lines you can search on the web
you'll find the command.
So we got that the black letters then
then uh then we don't need this uh
thing. Okay so shrink shrink shrink
shrink shrink shrink shrink fantastic
and beautiful and now formatted auto
format.
Okay. Now version of course this is
copyright copyright by me uh you can use
it
if you link to the if you must give
credit and link to my website. Okay so
copyright and version number and okay so
I think that's it. So we got double
check double check uh black box letters
when you copy paste and turned one line
into multi-line did you mark a region?
No. So when there's no region it
automatically works on a block of text
block similar to paragraph it's defined
by empty lines. Okay. So so for example
you know this would be a block. If I
have something here, then this would be
part of a block block text block. Okay.
Or you can make a selection and do that.
Okay. So anyway, so so we got the code.
So we got that code. And is there
anything we need to change? I think not.
So the rest is kind of, you know, is
JavaScript DOM. Okay. So
um but should I go explain it? But let's
make the code work first. Okay. So tap C
to compile the TypeScript file. So now
we got the hide hide the details. So
here here's a JavaScript. Okay. Now
close close
show in browser.
There it is. So select all ABC.
Fantastic. D E F
and something. So now if I want a black
version, fantastic. Okay, so that is
done. Now
how does it work? I mean uh so let's go
to the uh JavaScript again. Open a
TypeScript file. How does it work? Well,
that if you want to know, just search
for
search for JavaScript in depth. Okay.
anxiety.info.
Then there is a DOM section. This is all
you need. You don't need a framework.
You don't need any libraries framework.
Okay. So, DOM scripting tutorial from
from the ground up. Okay. beginning
friendly
uh and using no frameworks and you can
you can so so so what we want here is
you know you first of all you create use
HTML to create this input elements and
uh that you can find you know HTML input
so here is how do you create a button
click click click and then input text
Jenny something, you know. Uh, and
here's a code. Here's HTML code. Here's
a JavaScript code. Very simple. And, uh,
then text area.
This is a example what what we are using
today text area. Okay.
And then then you have radio buttons.
Okay. Radio button. This is origin of
radio button. This is what it it means
because when when you press a button
down, the other buttons pops up. If you
are young, you you haven't seen these.
Uh but if you are older like me, you
know, these are standard radios on cars.
So that's why they are called radio
buttons.
So for example, you click bird, then the
the other buttons are deselected. You
click cat or click dog. So here's a
code. So that's what we used. So you
know we got a radio button here.
So if you want to know how the code
works, you can look at the code and look
look at my DOM tutorial. And I think
that's it. Okay. So is there anything I
want to um
display square chart? So where okay that
is the selector. Okay. Update. Uh I
think that's it. So compile it again to
make sure we got the latest version.
Close it. Show in browser. Fantastic.
And this let's you know this font are
too small. I want I want to make some
change. So let's go up here. Display
square char. So find it. Okay. So let's
add a style.
Uh
uh. Wait, wrong key.
add a style and font family. So, open a
new file.
Turn to CSS mod font family. Actually,
font size. That's what we want. Font
size. Okay. Uh 1.5. Okay. That. Okay.
So, select that. Put that there.
Showing browser.
Okay. That's that's good.
Okay. Anything else? So fantastic. Now
we got this application
say fantastic
black. Okay. Actually we need to make
some changes. What if if you have a
capital letter because then now it
doesn't change. So uh that's pretty easy
to fix. Okay.
So go to the JavaScript file again. Open
it. Then somewhere you you want to
lowerase
um
yeah somewhere you want to lowerase the
input.
So function update uh for each
replace regular expression. Uh so let's
see what is this. So,
so font map is a new map. Then function
update. So, here is
uh type face value query selector input
type face
uh then
input text box. Yeah. So, there
here is how you get the value. Wait. So
where is the input
uh document query selector input input
name type face. So let's go back here.
Okay. So here is the input type face.
You know that's the that's the radio
button. Okay. So
name type face. Okay. What type face to
use? Then the value is that. Okay. Okay.
Now back to JavaScript
TypeScript. So the type face this is how
you get the value. Okay. Type face
value. Okay. Then the result equals to
then you result.
Let's see
the result. You know, if you are
wondering why do I have a bunch of
numbers there at the end of the
variable, that's because I have a habit
to make every variable unique
universally,
but that's kind of that's over um that's
over the top. So, let's change that uh
result. Let's just say three uh three
digits. Okay.
Okay, that's kind of smaller value.
Okay, highlight it. So,
so for each replace. So, here result you
need to lowerase it. Okay, so
wait uh input box.
Okay, so you need to lower case. So, how
do you lower case? Well, let's go to
JavaScript in depth.
Okay, JavaScript in depth. That's about
strings. So, let's go to strings, string
overview,
uh string operations. Okay, substring
length, join string, string methods.
Okay, methods. Uh then you got so a
bunch of methods you want to
uh lowerase. Okay. Search string search
convert to array letter case. Okay. Put
a type two lower case. Okay. That's how
you do it. Two uppercase two lower case.
Okay. So close that. So that's that's
going to be two lowerase
completion
there.
Uh so this is what this is a uh method.
Okay. So two lower case then dot. Okay.
Now compile it.
Okay. Now back to the browser. I mean
showing browser. Let's try
ABC then ABC. Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay. That's it for today. If you love
it, if you like my stuff, donate. Okay.
So go to Unicode. Go to uh go to the top
kasal.info.
info and go to the bottom. PayPal me,
Patreon me, or Amazon gift card me.
Okay, if you are working as a
professional in programming or
otherwise, pay me $100. Okay, $100 a
year is not bad.
If you are not having a job, if you are
neat, you know, pay me a few bucks. That
would be appreciated.
Uh my first version of DOM tutorial is
2005 years. I've been you know I've been
around for quite a while. You know I
watched the birth of HTML then
JavaScript then CSS beginning in 1995.
I love those spines. I'm amazed what
binds. GPS
the key bindings. Okay. most efficient
coder Diego. Hi.
Okay, that's it. Thank you guys for
watching. Bye, guys.
And thank you, Hank. Yeah, I don't know
anything about business. You need to
you need to like register a business,
you know. So, I'm I'm a nerd. So when it
comes to financial issues, filling
paperwork, you know, business is lots of
filling paperworks or then then you also
need to contact lawyers sometimes. I
don't know,
I could be good, you know, like a nerd,
you know, a nerd is such that you can
focus on one thing. So there, you know,
let's talk random for a bit, you know.
So I'm a nerd, right? I'm very extreme
case of a nerd. So I'm very good at
computers, mathematics, you know. So but
I thought you know I have thought as as
well as many other nerds you know we are
not good at socialization. We are not
good at business. We are not good at
talking to people. We are not good at
being a salesman being a smooth talker
or we and we are not good at negotiation
things like that. But however we could
because we we are nerds you know so
given a thing a technology or whatever
we can okay this is a task we need to
figure it out what to do you know we can
focus on that so for example there are
some nerds you know like often nerds you
know you don't get girlfriends but then
but you can focus on that so girlfriend
is a problem we start to analyze you
know how do you get a girlfriend you
know how you know that like analyze in
every way then you you know create a
plan like some some things you should do
some things you should not do and what
should your behavior be you know then
you create a you know to-do list you
know these are things you do to do in
order to get a girlfriend things like
that so similarly for for being a good
uh lawyer salesman or being able to talk
to a lot of people or being able to give
a lecture uh those things. In fact, many
nerds has written about it. So, you
could, you know, pick one of the the
things you don't know uh well and do
that. But, but usually it's just not not
uh you know, doesn't interest me that
much, you know.
Yeah. Pen spinning. Fantastic.
Okay. Bye, guys.