good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is August 23rd 2019 Friday
California time and today we have a
topic and the topic is JavaScript
and related things to JavaScript good
morning pathala mu J s and good morning
Z Tron crazy
so that bathroom UJ s that J is now
stand for JavaScript okay so so Beth
amuses Bethany says he's picking the
topic about JavaScript so I have
JavaScript we can do I'm going I can go
over JavaScript watts
you know that because JavaScript
language has lots of problems in the
code JavaScript language oh I can go
over JavaScript es2015 features are you
familiar with us with those bathroom you
and Xetra javascript 2015 they it's
basically a complete new language now no
bathroom you say is something about the
job you want to talk about javascript
wrappers oh you are not familiar with
yes 2015 then you definitely should we
actually I think we should talk about
that because when you talk about easy so
sabatham you wants to know about you
know my opinion about several javascript
wrappers for example the most popular is
typescript then you have CoffeeScript
CoffeeScript is basically basically
obsolete you know CoffeeScript was
invented about without ten years ago and
it's it's basically a wrapper to
JavaScript so basically it provides a
complete new syntax of JavaScript and it
comes
to JavaScript so basically it's kind of
like a new language but more or less you
know similar to JavaScript it just
provides a new syntax so back then ten
years ago when 2015 is not there yet you
know because javascript is a very bad
language so so so this guy created
CoffeeScript which which intended which
you know basically it's like a new
language so people like that it becomes
it became very popular Heidi you know
extremely popular
you either code in jumping in
CoffeeScript or you go back you know
code the plain old JavaScript so let's
see Co ffe script and let's have a look
at their website by the way the author
of CoffeeScript you know there is a
CoffeeScript mod for Emacs and I think
the author used my Emacs this tutorial
to write a CoffeeScript mod for Emacs
and he gave me credit so thank you thank
you whoever I mean let's see if I can
find it
sorry coffee script Emacs okay I have
kind of acknowledgement somewhere I
don't I don't remember well anyway so
CoffeeScript you can see that see
everything is an expression that's great
that's a everything is an expression
that is a fantastic principle of
functional programming languages you
want everything to be an expression what
does that mean for example if statements
now in general like C or JavaScript or
goal an if statement it's a statement
meaning that if something then do this
or do that
but in the do this or that you have to
say return otherwise it doesn't return
anything and anyway the whole thing the
if block of code it cannot return
actually so you it's you know it's not
an expression it's just
statement statement means that kind of
like a command you know do something do
something it doesn't return a value okay
let's let me let me talk about if
statement so if statement so everything
is an expression that is a principle of
functional programming languages okay so
okay yeah yeah so everything every
should I read it out let me know should
I like usually if I read it out then the
talk is gonna be kind of more coherent
because otherwise I you know ramble
around but the disadvantage of writing
it out is it takes longer because I have
to copy and paste and type everything is
an expression a fundamental principle
function of programming languages okay
functional programming languages okay
that that is a thing for example if
statement typically so so in C for
example you have this thing also
available in JavaScript let me show you
JavaScript ternary expression okay if
expression okay there so normally when
you say if you know let's say if 3 is
true or not
okay let's say okay let's make it more
intuitive so constant x equals to 3
right let's see if I'm doing okay so so
for example constant equals to 3 so if
you say if x equals to 3 then let's say
print console.log yes okay yes otherwise
you can say else else then else
console.log no for example okay so
that's a code we'd run it
oh yeah I need to save it so xx dot
today's stage starts JavaScript ok
Mitzvah it says yes you see the answer
is here so that's a statement now it
doesn't return a value
so so what does that mean so for example
let's say x equals to 3 then returns 3
otherwise return no ok let's say you
know if you run this it does let's say
this ok console.log okay then put the
whole thing inside it's not going to
work it's going to be syntax error
because it's you know counselor takes
one argument and that argument must be
your expression so you know what it so
it's a it's a statement if if statement
it's a statement it does it it's not a
value you can return so whenever you do
want to do something you have to you
know it's it's it's it's a programming
language design issue so if it is not a
statement you cannot you know you cannot
kind of embed it in as part of other
expressions you know but however C or
C++ I don't know what's or engine but
this this syntax let me show you what
this is syntax so this syntax condition
question mark condition question mark
true force okay so so in in C or C++ and
JavaScript in JavaScript you have this
syntax this is called it's called
ternary expression ternary means 3
meaning that it's an expression
involving three things it's a bad name
anyway but anyway it's typically
traditionally called ternary expression
this now this is exactly the same thing
you are basically it's exactly the same
thing as a if statement except except it
is a expression for example to to the
same thing we can do let's
let's move this out so that's a if
statement and let's say x equals to 3 if
it is true then return yes otherwise
return otherwise return no ok so this we
want to console.log print it okay for
example comment this out and let's run
it you see the answer is yes you see so
this is this is the if expression you
know it's just like if statement but it
has a value it's very useful so you know
so in CoffeeScript you know you notice
how they say everything is an expression
so that's kind of a powerful construct
so that is one of the advantage of the
semantic advantage of CoffeeScript over
JavaScript by the way so JavaScript to
have this if expression but other things
it doesn't have expression for example
for example console.log is not an
expression
okay console.log doesn't return the
thing you know but in CoffeeScript it
says okay everything is expression so
CoffeeScript basically the force the
power of CoffeeScript is that the the
essence actually the the peep the people
like it the most is because of the
syntactic element in CoffeeScript let's
see what is this ok great ok else else
if yeah ok so on the left side is a
CoffeeScript on the right side is the
JavaScript traditional JavaScript you
see JavaScript is you know lots of
cumbersome on the but the CoffeeScript
is very short concise syntax now this is
this is why CoffeeScript became hugely
popular I think it around started around
2007 or something like that you know and
and because javascript is
bad in but however you know everyone
knows JavaScript is very bad so starting
with 2015 they created called Akuma
script 315 the standard so basically
essentially you have a complete new
language okay
now the syntax okay anyway let me go let
me tell you so you have a complete I
mean it's it's truly a complete new
language it contains like 20 more lots
of syntactic new features and lots of
new functions like like home base it is
you know the JavaScript mm yes 2015
expect triple in size to the previous
version so let's go to JavaScript let me
show you
Java's let's go to my javascript website
so I have a I have this javascript in
depth you can search the web and you'll
find a URL and you know if you like it
by my tutorial because I spent two years
to write the whole thing every day you
know I studied JavaScript in detail I've
read you know the JavaScript SPECT you
know mm
starting with mm you know Achmat 262
Edition 5.1 then then this Akmal script
2015 you know I read aspect and and 16
and 18 so anyway if you like it you know
buy it for my website okay there's a
button there oh you know you can PayPal
me to support my work so JavaScript in
depth so mm yeah so since 2015 they
fixed all the major problems they are
still problems by anyway it's a big new
complete change okay
now that if we go over to let's see
so here is a summary of 2015 features
you can see this link and since 2015
every year they have a new
you know they decided every year they
are going to have an new JavaScript they
expect you know adding new features so
you have 2016 2017 2018 2019 is already
decided I'm not sure Wayne said out it
must be out already I think yeah but but
2016 2:19 they added basically each year
they add like one or two functions
something like that one or two functions
or some new change of syntax you know so
it's very small change but the 2015 one
that hats it's a huge you know it's a
new language so so CoffeeScript you know
it's you know it was 2000 2008 you know
so basically since the 2015 came out
that's a that's the that's a dagger to
the heart to CoffeeScript you know you
just people don't use it anymore I'm ok
so because you know 2015 you know this
it's a part of the language it's
building every browser you don't need
you know many of these things
improvements in CoffeeScript it's you
don't need it anymore
ok what about the other part you see
CoffeeScript is very concise you know it
doesn't have the braces you know the
curly braces that in American we call
these braces you know the we have the
per in parentheses braces or square
brackets that's an American term I know
in England or Europe maybe in Germany
they they don't say that they say well
parenthesis you have round brackets
square brackets is square brackets then
these braces is called curly brackets
the United Kingdom their way of speaking
actually that's more logical typically
American is more logical because the
spelling for example for example you you
know you
have color well in Britain you have CEO
arrow you are things like that but
Americans we form this very any anyway
so
so since Eggman script to that 2015
that's a big hit you know a nail in the
coffin to to CoffeeScript you know I
think there are still people using it
but basically in the industry it's gone
it's you can consider a dead
why because okay so CoffeeScript they
also improved let me show you second you
know the CoffeeScript they also improved
the syntax right but you see there are
two forces that killed cured
CoffeeScript one is X Eggman script
fifteen okay let's just go a JavaScript
15 you know 2015 that basically you know
removed lots of the advantages of
CoffeeScript the other thing is that
because since the past years the so many
happens you know in JavaScript land
you got you got typescript you got it
elixir you got a quite a few egg moaning
yet in Dec ways so let me show you some
of the JavaScript alternatives or
rappers so folks first of all most
famous is typescript for example I have
this code let's say let's see draw okay
so I let's see index okay sorry
info row Zadro and test okay here index
okay and let's view this in Chrome okay
and this is my code to plot math
functions you know I wrote this and it
is written in
it's written in typescript for example
the code for this page the whole code is
just these two things you see F SVG
parametric plot then you you get the
element to attach it to then here's a
function then here's a range from flat
from 0 to 7
you know x equals to 0 to 7 so you got
that then another we do another plot and
you got that ok that is you know using
my own library you have that so the
library code is this one so this file
it's 500 lines you know this is my
project I want to it's been stagnating
for a long time I I need to finish this
so anyway so by the way it's not using
any libraries you know today you have
tons of library Java JavaScript land
here you have 1000 libraries and usually
you cannot trust their quality and
there's also deeply very famous very
popular d3 fold for all kind of graphics
in on the web anyway I read in my home
because I like it because I I mean to
you know I know the math visualization
that's my thing so so anyway this is
written in typescript and you can see
for example here I define a range
function now I define a range function
so so this is using an arrow function
well you have to know es2015
ok so if you don't know I go over I go
over yes 15 features ok but anyway you
know typescript is a wrapper it's its
base it's a wrapper to JavaScript but
but the main thing about typescript is
that they added a type you know type
system where every variable you have you
you can declare your type so once you
have that it
Alima
it's many programming errors because the
type will match the before you run the
program you know you compare it to
JavaScript it will find any type type
mismatch errors so that is actually a
great help especially in a team you know
a large project so types typescript is
actually the most popular today
so typescript you can see you know this
for example this so I have a error
function here now this is a hairy
function now this is the parameter part
of the error function and this is the
party part of the function you see this
arrow so this is how you define a
function error function you can see I
explained here that that part is
JavaScript 2015 but however look at the
parameter declaration you see I have
four parameters minimum maximum Delta
okay and then you have this thing number
then you have this same number those you
know this called a number thing that's
from typescript you see so if you run
this in JavaScript it's it's a syntax
error you see because JavaScript doesn't
have this code and number thing that's
this is added by this is this is from
typescript so this means this parameter
or argument is going to be of a type
number so if you call range and if you
by mistake you give it something not
number or complaint before it compiles
so this range function basically just
generates a way it's like pythons range
function it just generates array of
certain lengths you know from from 7 to
100 for example so typescript is a
wrapper of JavaScript it adds type also
another important thing that main types
scrip extremely popular is because
typescript is 100% JavaScript compatible
that means you take any JavaScript and
you you it is it is also typescript
already
you don't have to do anything it's
already typescript you know so you can
start to add you know you can start to
add so-called type annotations you know
if you want to you know so you can take
a project you know let's say medium 1
million lies you know you can start to
use typescript then you do all you have
to do is you just start started to start
to write add these you know type
annotations gradually you don't have to
so it's not unlike it's not like you
know switching to a new language where
you have to you know rewrite start over
you so so so this 100% compatibility
with JavaScript you know a kind of
strictly mother said you know how they
say that super said you know it's a
superset of JavaScript so this this
makes typescript very popular because
it's extremely adaptable you can switch
your projects to begin to use type
typescript so typescript today is the
primary choice for industry you know
coding in those in the industry it's not
the only of choice of course because you
know see over the past 10 years there's
so many folks and some failed you know
let me show you some examples ok
typescript
here are some other languages so there's
JavaScript powershell ok
let me show you Julia CoffeeScript you
know coffee
CoffeeScript began in 2009 ok yeah dot
okay dot is language created by Google
now good you know back then you know
around 2000 i/o 2010 everyone is
thinking you know we need to fix
JavaScript you know JavaScript because
this is around 2009 Apple just created
iPhone you know just starting to become
very popular and Android Android you
know Google also want to get into the
into the into the money back you know
Google created Android phone is becoming
extremely popular
because everyone uses the phone most
people are not computer nerds they don't
they don't want they don't want to have
a laptop they have no idea what's a
browser like like Google did a survey on
YouTube they go to the street as people
do you know what's a browser
people don't know however they do use
the web you know they say oh oh is that
he said that ye I can't that's that's
the browser you know so to us you know
sometimes we have misconceptions because
the vast majority of people they don't
even know what's a browser but they do
now everyone has a phone they still
don't know what's a browser they they
don't even know what's an app
they just know you know push buttons
push these to go somewhere that's what
they know most people are like that ok
so especially talking to those those of
you Emacs users thinking oh you should
you know that most of you don't know
nothing you know they are not
programmers that's and that's no more
that's because you know anyway so 2009
is a time when the phone you know become
popular everyone needs to get a phone so
Google created Android and yeah and so
meanwhile this also means JavaScript
becames
became extremely popular you know before
2010 in in 2000 JavaScript nobody wants
it you know any any programmer think
it's kiddies language the worst possible
any you know so but so 2009 you know
phone became on a singing phone is of
course web so javascript is big part of
the web so it becomes very popular and
also not jeaious got created you know so
so not yes you know which which is you
can run you can write servers with
javascript you know so it becomes hugely
popular it's that you know is over
southern javascript in fact today you
can say javascript is a number one most
popular language I mean depending on how
you count you can count the number of
libraries you know the you know in many
ways javascript is number one you know
more than more than ccc first first java
ok but you know depending on
how you can't but basically you can say
it's sure it's one of the top five you
know you have C++ Java PHP JavaScript
okay basically those so and you might
consider Python you know top five most
popular languages so it but you know
JavaScript has a lot problems some
people needs to fix it so CoffeeScript
in 2009 is a solution then in 2011
Google created dot you know Google's or
needs wants to fix JavaScript the so
what do you start like dot is like
turning JavaScript into Java both in
syntax and both in semantics
that's one sentence description of dot
it's it's it's basically like Java that
Google wants to turn everything into
Java I don't like it at all I don't like
it and also thought taught basically
failed nobody use it I mean there are
still people you know you start but
basically it failed nobody is using it
now typescript invented in 2012 but by
the way dot is a complete new language
it's not 100% company is not compatible
with JavaScript at all it's kind of you
know in that respect it's like
CoffeeScript you know all the syntax is
different
you have to compile it then it generates
JavaScript you cannot for example begin
with a JavaScript project and maybe
change a little bit no you cannot do
that you have to start all over so dot
and it failed you know it you know and
now we can look at some of the
backstabbing and you know the politics
you know Google at one time the dot
people they are trying to get browsers
to incorporate that into their in the
browser engine because if this happens
then dot will become very popular or
even you know take over javascript but
nobody wants to you know Google ad they
they talk to the Apple people you know
Microsoft Apple
hey can you can we you know you know I
have a hey Greg you know I love your
process can we start to put that engine
in the you know your brows I know nobody
wants to Google the Evo yeah
2011 that's when Google is about to you
know or sort of Evo happening with
Google and they said no and that
basically thought nobody nobody uses ok
then typescript 2012 from Microsoft
now typescript did it right because well
because they have one thing hundred
percent compared compatibility with
JavaScript that this reason made
typescript
tremendously popular that is the e force
behind types types quit because because
you know that's one of the reality when
you want you know everyone you know as a
programmer you may think oh let's just
rewrite the whole thing you know I'm
going to rewrite the whole software but
in reality corporations they they don't
want to you know they they cannot and
you know the you rather want to
incremental improvements so there it is
typescript so typescript
today's naanum is a number one most
popular rapper or alternative to
javascript then you have Elm ok Elm is
another thing like alternative to
JavaScript I haven't used which is like
Elm is a function of forming language
for decoratively
creating web browser-based graphical
user interface okay so anyway um M is
Elm began from a PhD thesis in 2012 by
this guy I never tried it I never
studied it so I don't actually know much
about it but oh oh I know is that it's
like a functional language you know very
you know III would like it if I have
time to study because it's functional I
love functional programming Elm
it's popular in some niche areas in some
niche basically functional you know like
like Haskell people you know they you
know so um but I mean if you're talking
about industry typescript is the
basically the it's almost the only one
so there's Elm okay and there's also
hacks I never used either but anyway it
compares to many languages I don't know
much about it hacks and it's been around
for a long time it's been around since I
don't know when then you have elixir
elixir is what okay
elixir is basically turning a line into
JavaScript you know a line is this a
line is this functional programming
language which has been around for like
20 years and you know and so I don't
know Alan and I haven't used I haven't
looked into addiction either but again
it's nitch okay it's kind of niche you
know like Haskell you know yeah there
are some companies using it that in
general no so you'll ixa it leaks a helm
these two are kind of you know among the
among the hackers they are kind of have
some popularity Elm and elixir and there
is pure script okay let me show you pure
script there it is pure script okay so
let me write it out so I read it out so
that we get if statement versus if
expression okay so that's the thing and
JavaScript alternatives okay we talk
about dot typescript elixir elm and
it takes then n pure script okay
now pure script is basically like
Haskell it's like it's like pure
functional programming you know in your
very pure sense like so you have you
cannot declare variables so you cannot
have new mutable variables things like
that it's you know it's loved by Haskell
type of people so okay so there is more
so let me show you another more another
one bugs bug bug script bug script is
basically or camo the meta language in
the in JavaScript okay so let me find it
you know their name is confusing
now perk script is the one I'm into
among these for example among you know
typescript are used because it is the
mainstream it is the mainstream I'm
using typescript dot I don't like we are
never used because it's trying to be be
Java you know in every way I don't like
Java now it leaks a Elm pure script they
are all functional programming kind of
thing okay I would like them but also
but however there is bug script this is
the one actually I'm most interested now
books script let me tell you what it is
it's basically or camel or F sharp as I
mentioned before in the beginning you
have the mid you have Mao a language
called Mao it's called meta language
then you have standard ml s s ml k
standard ml then you have camel then you
have Oh camel then you have F sharp all
these are the same family you know ml
than which f sharp is Microsoft's
version so then then then you have box
script or this there's another name ok
but let me find it so box script this is
the
[Music]
they have like confusing names like they
have two things not just bug script so
bit anyway box script is like okay my
language in JavaScript
so javascript back link a JavaScript
back in for camera focus on smooth
integration anyway so there is another
name though okay let me mean there's
another better better one so let me try
to find it JavaScript
okay moe okay okay more JavaScript it's
created by Facebook you know it's reason
okay reason reason is the one or reason
reason script okay
reason ml yeah they called reason email
okay and now box squib is somewhat
related to them but anyway so let me put
this
okay so so today
well yeah I'm writing about that so so
JavaScript
alternatives so so reason email okay
let's look at the reason email let's go
- lets go - let's view it in Chrome
now reason ml is basically or camel but
however they change basically they take
the ochem oh semantics you know okay mo
is a functional programming language
just like Haskell but it's not a strict
assess cow so it's actually more
practical that is why that is why
Microsoft choose Oh camel you know they
created F sharp as their functional
programming language you know on the
other hand in Haskell everything is very
pure and strict you know they are trying
to follow you know this computer you
know functional you know theory in
theoretical computer science but in
practice you you sort of have lots of
problems you know become slower things
like that so anyway okay mo the ML
language family or camo camo F sharp and
reason now they are they are like
Haskell but they are not you know
strictly that they are not that pure so
if you need you know if you need change
change variable you can so anyway reason
now reason so it reason is okay mo in in
JavaScript syntax okay so you take the
okay mo semantics everything functioning
but however you dress it like a
JavaScript syntax so for example this
code for example you're looking at
that's reason reason ml okay and just
like all the others they compile to
JavaScript now this I am interested this
reason ml I have interest in this one
more than more than L need more than
pure script more than elixir okay more
than more than any of them but I haven't
actually studied it because you know
yeah it takes time to study and
I haven't really studied it and by the
way reason reason ml pure script Elm
elixir they are all kind of niche you
know there's nobody I mean there are
some companies you know you know here
and there they use it but it's not
really big it kind of like Haskell okay
it's not industrial if you want to be
practical if you want to find a job go
to Java to go to typescript okay okay
that that is about the alternatives you
know but in CoffeeScript is kind of dead
okay don't you know forget about
CoffeeScript I think well you know they
mentioned CoffeeScript - yeah I don't
know but you know I basically I would
say it's dead well don't don't take my
word for it because I don't know but as
far as I'm concerned it's CoffeeScript
is dead now those are the alternative of
JavaScript okay so let's but first of
all remember before you learn all these
you actually you need you really need to
know you need to know JavaScript 2015
okay because this is a major thing you
know all these others they are like on
top of JavaScript 15 you know because
this is you know part of core Java
Script for four year for four years now
and it's gonna you know you know anyway
I think I'm gonna cover it but let's
read comments a little bit
YouTube dashboard okay seven people
watching so good Moni so Kathleen is a
best rapper it wraps all types to have a
nullable and there is also a type any
which I have been seen like that you
know yeah okay cover yeah Kathleen JK
joking okay well can't you see today um
like almost lots of languages can
compare to JavaScript you know before we
are talking about these alternatives now
these are these alternatives you know
typescript are the elixir and so on they
are actually dedicated to to the web
programming in other words they are not
they are not considered a language by
themselves you know they are like just
focus on the web you know JavaScript and
don't they have their 100% focus on the
you know programming on the web on the
other hand today so many languages they
all can compile to JavaScript for
example closure you have closure script
for example so many you know closure you
have closure scripts then you have colon
colon also have a version that compares
to JavaScript okay
ml well book script is is compiling
Okemo
to JavaScript okay which is different
from reason reason is okay mo in
JavaScript syntax you know it's a new
syntax you still compare though you
still have to compile but but oh camp
but the bug script the bug script is is
actually a tool that compiles or camel
language code into JavaScript okay so
that's another thing Erland okay so
elixir is you know land in JavaScript
clothing yeah I guess so
Haskell I guess there's also ask our
project that compares to JavaScript is
here so anyway my point here is like
today so almost like lots of languages
they compared to JavaScript but however
they are also a language independent by
themselves so when you do that you know
it's not exactly like the you know these
these JavaScript alternatives you know
there's there's more complexities and
issues you have to deal with what's some
of the example ok goal and now I don't
know if I don't know if Ross has a
compacting compared to JavaScript I know
julia has a project that compares to
javascript you know so almost like every
language now you know you can compare to
javascript but we are not counting them
there because we don't count them here
because then then is every language and
also they are in different levels of
maturity also I mean a lot of
complexities come seeing actually so if
you really you know so you rather
consider these you know we talked about
this this alternative first before you
get into the others and also JavaScript
landscape is changing all the time you
have do you have this ASM JHS which is
mint you know it's the thinking is a
JavaScript ASM Dutchess is kind of a
subset of JavaScript so the thinking is
that you know in the future we don't
code JavaScript anymore like every any
any anyone can call any language they
like they all compared to asm.js which
you considered as a assembly of the web
assembly language for the web you know
ASM Dargis is kind of like a subset of
JavaScript a very fast low-level you
know so it can compile fast you know a
lot of low-level subset of JavaScript so
you write whatever language you like you
compared to a SMGs you know and today
you have lots of games you know like
hardcore games like I don't know that
you know the old
and first-person shooter games written
in JavaScript that is they they compared
to asm.js it and they'd run on the web
you know like doom right I don't know
much about asm.js you know it's I you
know there's a lot like did there's also
emulators like I don't know what Mac
emulators or what running another
different computer in in a browser like
oh yeah I think there's a you know
browser you can run Windows 95
yeah people have done that they take the
window 95 code they compared to a SMGs
or something like that then in browser
I've seen it I've seen it you know so
it's you know lots of things are going
on so anyway so so let's see so reason
sabatham USA's reason reminds me of the
Mac DAW is ASM touches competitor 2 web
assembly I think they I think web
assembly is kind of the descendant of
ASM Diaz yeah I'm not sure you know I
thought I wrote this in 2012 it changes
you know these things changes you can so
I think web assembly is kind of that I
think it's descendant kind of the idea
something like that ok I don't know
yeah so that's you know if you are in
the JavaScript community you know there
are a lot of people know this a lot more
and everyday they are talking about oh
this is the future but but if you are
not in that community it's like far
ahead you know like you know like a lot
of people don't haven't studied yes 2015
yet you know this so many things are
going on changing and stuff so I like so
for example I don't know nothing about
you know what's going on there
it's this oh it's bleeding edge so let
me get a drink then it's so let's talk
about let's give a
Marie of the 2015 features okay what
what's up any questions anything you any
opinions posted okay so good morning yad
good morning good afternoon good evening
take ways Dec ways where you form again
what country or in sitio or C key so
today's drink is today's drink is
cranberry plus Concord grape press
energy drink sugar-free
okay tech ways is from Germany great
German German German German is nine
o'clock now like 10 o'clock almost right
p.m. so yeah so let's let's talk about
then 2015 features okay yeah well this
is gonna be this is more serious topic
you know yes you know generally none
tech talk like we've did before that's
easygoing you know I can just Lambo this
is this is gonna be more I'm gonna walk
and then you have to be you know you you
have to know the stuff and you know you
have to be correct in anyway this
there's a anxiety
anyway 2015 so anyway you you if you
want to coach our script yeah you can
consider these alternatives but the most
important thing is this you gotta you
gotta know this way okay JavaScript 2015
this is like the fundamentals the core
the foundation okay like all these other
things
pure script you know reason ml they they
are fancy they are dramatic everyone is
talking about it don't like oh oh
typescript you know the elixir oh yeah
it changes the world but actually no
stick
you know you before you talk about those
got you know no 2015 very well okay this
is the foundation but also and also but
by the way if you know this well you you
may not want to use any of those others
because you know and also if you go type
script then absolutely you need to know
2015 JavaScript you know 2015 because
typescript is a rapper so it's based on
you know J's 2015 one more thing you see
one more thing I want to say about those
no I guess not
yeah okay yeah one more thing one more
thing is that when you actually go
javascript you know you code web
applications fancy web applications
javascript language is one thing but
actually the most important thing is Dom
you know like 80 percent of the time you
are dealing with dumb stuff not not the
JavaScript stuff so anyway web
programming it's very complex so there
are two parts the language parts
javascript you know yes 15 or you know
one of these alternatives that's the
language part you have to know you and
you kind of have to know where but Dom
DOM is actually the main thing because
the language doesn't cover how do you
manipulate you know change your new
image you'll rotate some subject it
doesn't cover that that all those are
Dom you know you could eat dumb is a
very complex Tom or bomb boom yawn you
know be om which is browser object model
basically you work with a browser so
this how to change CSS how to change not
you know those let me show you I showed
this yesterday so but let me show you
again you know this shows show example
of JavaScript application you know what
I mean by writing a JavaScript
application okay let's see you know
playing Chinese chess now I didn't write
this program but someone did so I can
play chinese chess for example and it's
written in JavaScript okay this is
taking too long let's change the time to
one second okay so let's get them going
let's see this is my pong he's taking my
poem oh no I gotta take it back oh my
chariot is good
so that's JavaScript you know so you you
can look at the code for example you
look at the
JavaScript I didn't write this okay
someone y'all state and it's written
before JavaScript es v 2015 so the code
is very ugly when you know this is a
code okay you know writing a chest
this is JavaScript let's see okay so
this is just let's look at that okay so
chess let's see I mean let's look at
some interesting okay this is the main
you know this is JavaScript code this is
before 2015 so you have these vows and
stuff yeah so what I'm saying what I was
saying is that you know you have to deal
with for example this something dot add
you know you you move these pieces this
piece are images you have to remove this
image and move it those those are not
JavaScript those are Tom you know you
have to so when you actually write a web
application most of the time you are
dealing with Dom then today there are so
many libraries for example react react
yes Lucia's let's let me show you some
of that react jeaious we are Jess okay
that's one that this is the most popular
library for dealing with Dom okay
basically every company every website
use it or more almost so react.js this
is the most popular so you can use it
together with typescript yeah so so
front-end program is very complex
because you combine this library with
typescript they compile to JavaScript
it's gets more and more complex because
the reactor is also it's not just a
library for JavaScript it is also
actually a new new wrapper new syntax
you cannot just put react in JavaScript
you you know it's actually a new library
with new syntax so you have to compile
react with JavaScript code you know it
compiles to JavaScript so but if you are
also using typescript it gets very
complex you know any any way we act
every
uses okay then there's view Jes this is
another fairly popular don't rapper okay
it helps you do Dom vue.js and there's
also Amber images and there's there's
also another popular one is called
Google's from Google that's I don't like
that one it's so here's images all these
are helping you do the Dom you know I
don't know any of them I know a little
bit react but I don't use it my code is
or pure standard technology you know
pure JavaScript yes 2015 and all these
pure thing we are build with build
building with building in a browser
without any library so let me yeah so
let me I want to show you a library for
example this one so this one I wrote it
convert your characters to this run
characters suspect or something you know
convert English Latin half bet into run
run is this Asian kind of old you know
language so you can convert to several
type of run so so these are these
interactions that's that's Dom okay
that's even if you have a master
JavaScript you wouldn't be able to write
you wouldn't be able to begin writing
this because this is about you know the
browser Dom stuff so Dom DOM is actually
almost like 80% of what you need to do
so here's my dumb tutorial you can you
know if you want to do that don't so
let's go back to the JavaScript it's
yeah let's go over the yes 2015 features
so there's a lot to learn you know you
have to you know you know also
JavaScript for example : Oh
Python you just learn Python and and
that's it you just learn : and that's it
and you can of course if you want to do
graphical programming then you have to
use you know graphical widget and stuff
but anyway on the web you you know it's
JavaScript and Dom so yes 2015 features
how shall we cover these
I'm wondering how what what should we
cover okay so I think I'm going through
a introduction or pic because yes 2015
there is a lot stuff you know new syntax
and new semantics a new object you know
the entire new object set object is
basically a hash table a proper hash
table o map object is a proper hash
table and then you have set object which
is kind of like a mathematical set it's
kind of like a list but do not allow
duplicates so for example that's a new
new feature so now you can you know
create a set without using without you
know writing code to check if there's a
duplicate then you have reflect you have
you have a class which is a major major
new thing added to JavaScript yeah okay
so let's let me just go over quickly the
the kind like give an idea what kind of
features are there
okay first so first of all let let and
constant they are declarations for
variables they replace the the keyword
var why because the keyword var when you
declare a variable with cube keyword var
it has lots of problems
it has scope problems I'm not going to
go into detail because the scope problem
is it's very complicated you know so I
have explanation here the var
declaration the VAR keyword it has it
has what's called name hoisting meaning
that if you have vowed somewhere down
below it will actually move it up it
will function as if it's on top of your
code in other words you can
when you declare VAR x something you can
use the XP for VAR however the value is
not set to X you know so it it kind of
moved the VAR declaration to the top
however the assignment does not move
that does not move with it so so the so
if you declare some variable var at the
bottom you can you can use the variable
X you know above it it sort because it
automatically it pretends the var
declaration is on top but however the
value X we are not have the value 5
because the actual assignment does not
get moved it so it's very complex you
see in order to expand this then you
have to show examples it's this is 1
this is the reason why JavaScript is so
bad
so anyway this this kind of feature this
is called name hoisting ok so that's the
problem with a var and another problem
with the var is scope you know it has
what's called functional scope it's very
bad ok so anyway that is why in yes 2015
they introduced let let is just like
it's just like keyword var declaration
in other languages it doesn't have the
name hosting thing and it doesn't have
the functional scope complexity it's
just like you know the scope is what
whatever the trace is you know the curly
brackets you know that's a scope so
anyway let it's for declaring a variable
and JavaScript introduced constant you
know it's also for it's like let exactly
except once you declare something with
constant you know Co and St you cannot
change the value later on if you change
its a compiler error you know that that
that is all otherwise is exactly like
that so these two are very useful you
know everyone uses so yes through 15
2015 introduced arrow function so
our function looks like that it's kind
of a new syntax for function so let me
show you okay I think I may not took I
may not be able to cover the whole
because this is you know the whole
language so maybe I'll just cover some
of them so anyone what's your opinion
and stuff say something okay keep yeah
so people say hi and you know hi j ji oh
is it jl hi ji ji say how i keep it a
comment coming so questions opinions so
we can you know so we so I got more you
know enthusiasm for what we you know all
direction where we are going because
otherwise I don't know sugar free is
hassle free yeah so we are we were
talking about yeah we okay so let's
let's explain arrow function so arrow
function so before I have a function
when you declare a function UT you
define like that function okay function
that okay let's say function f F then
let's say a parameter X and you return X
plus 1 okay that's how you define a
function okay then you can call it f f3
okay let's run it so the answer is four
you can see in this panel so that's how
you define function in JavaScript but
however there are quite a lot watts with
function with the function in JavaScript
quite a lot it will take half an hour to
explain them very very complex for
example for example for example what I
can do it you know I can read my
tutorial or I can do it offhand but if
I like making websites with pure HTML
CSS
okay that's great I'm also already
familiar with a comma 2015 so okay so
great thank fantastic whoo event
fantastic so so function function you
know the function in JavaScript has a
lot a lot of problems let's let's put
some examples problem
lots problems okay let's go to my talk
page function in JavaScript has lots of
problems okay for example let's name
some of the examples function expression
versus function Decorah definition okay
and the argument object and the well
let's just go to my website because then
because it's written out or summarized
well so define a function for is for I
am function yeah function declaration
versus expression this you know this
nobody you know very few people in the
world like one you know let's say let's
say 10,000 people actually understand
this well 10,000 people you know it's
not be too let's let's say 100,000
people understand this nope you know so
what happened is that you can declare a
function like that and a function in
JavaScript is also a value so when you
when you say function f something so
it's an expression it has a value the
value is a function you know it
represent you know this function so
therefore you can also assign it to a
variable like this you know constant of
or let you know let F equals to you know
some function but however there are lots
of problems okay
because if you use function
you know definition like that you know
function name parameters you know body
if you do it like that then this this
this syntax is considered function
declaration in turn it means you will
have hoisting name and value meaning
just like a variable just like that for
variable meaning that you can put the
function definition at the bottom but
you can call it before before you
declare it because javascript compiler
will kind of like moved all the function
declarations to the top okay however if
you do it using the function you know if
you assign a function to a variable then
if you do it that way that you know it
this moving doesn't happen this whole
thing does not happen okay therefore if
you define it like that so it you need
to whatever you call a function it needs
to be defined on top you know somewhere
before your source code on top so that's
called function function hoisting okay
but it's more than that it's it's it's
extremely complex okay here's another
complexity okay function function and
declaration must be top-level so what
does I mean so okay so you write a
function like that you know a function
name you know something that's a
function and function declaration now
yeah now look at this expression okay
look at this expression you define a
function you know with a name function f
something-something but you also assign
it to a variable
you know constant G so so the question
here do you do you do you get F you see
oh you know or do you get a Jeep in this
case you don't get the F basically so in
this case when you do it like that there
is no function f happens you see you see
contrary to its not intuitive because
normally you think that whenever you
have this function you know with a name
you know that's a declaration so you
would think that in this case both F and
G will be available it's like the same
function but that's not a case you know
you only get G you don't get F and
there's more complexities what if you
know so anyway there's a lot of
complexities so so that is a problem
with the this is one one of the watts
with a function you know you might say
okay this is nitpicking but not actually
not really because because when you do
JavaScript sometimes you want a function
inside a function or sometimes you want
to do a closure you know a lot people
like closure which which essentially
means you have to define if defining a
function inside a function but when you
define a function inside a function this
take this whole thing you know the
meaning of this you know the behavior
this hosting and this change it again
because now when if you have a function
inside function all the rules are
different again so that's a problem
major problem with the JavaScript
function keyword and that's not only one
the other one is the the other problem
is the arguments of argument object okay
a JavaScript function technically you do
not have to declare any variables for
example when you have a function with
arguments like function you know X
returns X first one you do not have to
diff you do not have to declare the
variable so what do you do for example I
can say this okay return return argument
okay
argument okay okay I guess I have to
type it out our argument
okay so return arguments is zero okay so
let's try that so this function is
supposed to return the argument plus 1
so let's doing it it works you see so
technically you do not have to actually
to define and to declare any parameters
of the function because you have this
kind of the magical variable called
magical object called arguments which
can be used on the inside functions body
and this magical arguments object is a
array so that's how you do it you know
so that's another problem because it's
and another problem is that it's
actually not an array because in
JavaScript you don't have true array so
the argument object is actually so
called array like object now a real like
thing is another big words in JavaScript
you know it's gonna take half an hour to
explain so so that's why it's problems
in problems lots of problems so so yes
2015 the argument object is considered
after you know people you know the
people tell you don't don't use it
because besides these problems you know
there is also a problem of
implementation because with the argument
object turns out that it's very
difficult to write a compiler so that
it's efficient if you use if your code
uses the argument object so basically
it's considered absolute now so so
that's some of the words with a function
ok so that is that now the function
keyword is not obsolete you know it's
still used but however in JavaScript
2015 they introduced a arrow function
notation so let's show you what what
that is so anyway that so let's so here
is our original function so this is
function that adds one to arguments this
is alternative way to write it and I can
write the same way using let's say let
me show you this okay so let's see I can
also write it this way okay so I can
also write it that way which because
function is an expression so now you
have a function you assign it to F F and
let's run it for okay good
and you can also now in 2015 you have
arrow functions so you can write it this
way constant arrow function okay FF so
you say X plus 1 you see so this is how
you write it
run it for this is our function and so
this is introduced in 2015 so this is
very useful because it's concise and all
say okay let me show you let me talk
about another problem with JavaScript
functions you have this this keyword
this keyword is extreme complex it's a
major pain in the ass this keyword so
this is you see the comments take aways
I make web making website pure HTML so
okay who else is here bathroom you you
still here I'm thinking maybe I should
okay let's finish this function talk
let's talking you're finish talking
about this Fink function that then let's
see where we go okay so let me know your
comments okay type comments guys so
let's talk about this keyword which is a
big thing a major thing JavaScript now
many people consider this keyword a a
wat a cancer in JavaScript but however
it is not it's still in JavaScript so
is not absolute and people still use it
even with even with 2015 but the problem
with this key keyword the you know this
keyword is that for example limit for
example the famous the the guy who
invented Jason you know the universal
format Jason interchange format Douglas
Crawford he never he and you know
studying around 2000 I he never uses
this keyboard okay did lots of words you
know when you talk about years 2015 you
cannot you cannot not mention JavaScript
wats together with it so so let me talk
about this
Douglas Crawford actually it's not
linked here it's somewhere on my web
site
he you know he never he never uses new
the in JavaScript you have this new
keyword actually so that's interesting
it's let's just bring it up the old UGL
a s CR aw Crawford
something like that
Douglas Crawford Saudi discovered the CG
war again no
what's his name
these people I need to find my website
not the other
okay it's not coming up so let's just go
through my JavaScript website search for
Crockford not kaufold okay I was wrong
SIA OC k Crockford
should be named there it is
okay so he has written you know he's
most famous for writing the book
javascript the good parts back in late
2000s and he also is famous for creating
Jason so he stopped using this keyboard
you know in his code you never see this
keyboard and also he stopped using the
the keyword new for good reasons I never
used them either so it's useless
you know to most people and especially
industrial coders they are still using
new and this you know every day that's
not good that also this this keyword and
new keyword they are major words in
JavaScript and also core for day and one
time they stopped he stopped using new
and he stopped using this keyword and he
proposed to always use object out create
create but even that he stopped because
he treat he treats about it and he has
videos you know talks you know
presentation talking about it yeah it's
a good reason to not use those
especially if you do functional
programming don't use the new keyword
and don't use this keyword because their
behavior is extremely complex extremely
let me explain what's this what's with
this keyword okay so let's see then we
probably finish you know we finish
explaining the function so javascript
function you have this this keyword
javascript function object properties
inheritance there okay
wait javascript function
okay here these binding so what what is
the purpose of this binding in
JavaScript you you have the keyword you
know this so in JavaScript every
function every function you defined with
the let's go back to the code okay so
you know you see the here we define
several functions now you see we define
function with the keyword function okay
any function defined by the keyword
function they they have a concept they
have a concept called
this key binding so what what does I
mean basically that means when you call
a function you know typically normally
when you call a function you pass the
parameters as arguments right you define
you declare parameters and when you call
it you give arguments then the basically
the arguments determines what's the
output you know the result of the
function but however in JavaScript there
is this magical thing called this
binding basically it is it is designed
so that when you have a function you
know there is one value that's not part
of the arguments so there is a magical
value called this you know so you when
you call a function you don't have to
explicit three so it went well function
is called there's a magical value called
this spending you know that is not in
the arguments what so so what is the
purpose of this why do you have this
magical value this binding why don't you
make it part of the argument because so
that so this the disc binding is so that
so that so that func so that the
function can find out you know via the
disc binding it can find out it can have
a object you know it basically it has a
object associated with this function and
it may do something with that object
you know without being a
said arguments oh yeah in a similar way
it's kind of like in Python you also
have that when you when you define
Python when you have a class or a castle
object you the first argument you know
you when you define a method the first
argument is this so it's similar to that
but in JavaScript it's it's like hidden
so that's what it means
so anyway so the world would be a better
place if Brendan Eich use common this
stuff a new instance creating JavaScript
yeah so anyway so let me read so in
JavaScript when a function is called it
has a Associated value called this
binding that's right and in function
body the this binding is represented by
the keyword these okay the purpose of
this binding is to allow function to
implicitly work with a object that's
right without actually passing the
object as argument that's right so for
example when you call you know my array
dot push the function push this binding
is the my array yeah that's yeah that
that's how push knows about my array so
that that's the purpose of this binding
so basically you have this increase it
magical value whenever you call a
function and only if you know so here
comes the complexity you know remember
this applies only for function defined
with a function keyword it doesn't
happen if you have a arrow function like
when in this function when we call it
there is no disappointing but in the
phone if you define a function with
using the function key ball there is a
magical increase it magical value hidden
somewhere this you know called this
pointing and so that that is one of
that's a complexity okay so this finding
is the this keyword has a value
typically only went inside a function
for example for example let's
find a function let's say if let's
change the names here first
so now let's define a new function new
function okay
let's name it f5 and let's say return
this okay we are returning this magical
value this okay
now we call it let's see what happens
okay run it fins wait is that valid it
should be valid okay why is this error
okay returns it returns this huge global
object you see yeah it returns the
global object that's right now yeah
that's right so if we go back now now
global object is another complexity in
JavaScript because javascript is a
hosted language meaning that the global
object there is an object code the
global object what is its value its
value depends on where you are running a
javascript so right now I'm running the
JavaScript in not jeaious so in not yes
if I run it the this value here is the
global object so the value of grow per
object is this huge thing you know
basically basically it's a whole entire
Javas not jeaious language but however
in browser the global object is the
windows object let me show you so let's
go to back here let's start the
JavaScript console and let's run the
code paste it and right you can see it
returns this window object okay now I
expanded its you know this whole you
know giant thing basically its entire
Chavez entire browser inching over you
can kind of like like that entire
browser engine
oh it's functions and stuff thousands of
items properties
so that's that's a concept about global
object why were you talking where are we
talking about that because when you cook
when you call a function that is defined
with the function keyboard key word you
have the concept concept of this binding
represented by the keyword this okay and
when you simply return it by default it
its value is the global object and what
is the value of global object that
depends on whether you know what's your
environment if you are in not just the
global object is a key word global G
yeah I think some GL obal with us you
know that's a key word global if you are
in an environment of browser the global
object is a is a object represented by
the key word window okay so so that's
that is the so many watts we are you
know starting to see you know one thing
this is to another and that is not
always so so for example in this page I
talk about what you know what is the
value of these you know it changes all
the time that's another complexity
depending on how you call the function
the value of these changes and you know
for example when you call you know this
in ethical this when you use new
something a constructor call you know a
global function call this is what
happens here you know we are we are
calling the function f5 here this is not
a method call because we are not going
calling it as you know something dot f5
we are calling it as a function call so
that's another complexity because once
you define a function the when you call
it there's a distinct distinction
between global function call you know
like that oh oh
something like something Oh object dot
f5 you know that that's a different way
of calling it then there's a different
behavior because when you call you know
the the the value of this will be
different
then this Inga nested function that's
another thing you know so this key
binding is very complex first of all
it's because it's implicit magic oh it's
a magical value so that's another thing
that's that's the complexity of
JavaScript functions okay now remember
we were talking about we were talking
about that because we were talking about
arrow functions now arrow functions is
new in in 2015 and in arrow functions
you do not have this key binding it just
gone eliminate it so that so if you like
functional programming always you know
just always use a function like that you
know always always just to constant
arrow function constant give a name G
then declare variables for example X
plus y then then whatever you want to do
for example so we here we can say X plus
y so now we can call it let's code
console.log GG 3 3 4 for example we run
it let's comment that out Lynnette we
got 7 you see so if you like functional
programming always you know Co arrow
function and always just use arrow
function and never if you you know if
you have really want to do pure
functional you know you want to be
strict then never never ever use the
function keyword you can do that so we
covered a few things I think that's let
you know maybe that's it for today so if
you have any comments or questions type
it okay
any comments one more minutes then that
that's it for today
so Dec ways so Dec ways your Dino
JavaScript now Common Lisp is actually
not a good choice because hey Benjamin
heaven okay so good morning Common Lisp
is not a good choice because common list
is another major words for example I
have a collection of articles the famous
programmers on how common this sucks you
know you got something from guy steel
which basically he created scheme disp
and he's also a part of the Java team he
you know on a committee of Java and we
have Richard Gabriel he he began the XE
max you know the loose it was the Lucid
email inc which is AI running on list
machines basically he began as we know
today XE max if XM x XE max died out
anyway he he also commented you know and
poor granham he also commented you know
Common Lisp is bad it's it's a cancer
the near Weinreb he died in 2007 also
2012 wait he died in 2012 yeah he also
got you know common problem with common
lisp you know some of the famous people
so what's my weekend schedule so I just
discovered I just discovered this thing
okay sorry so it's basically it's 12 o
clock so let me show you YouTube
actually go we're gonna go go there and
see my schedule I think 12 o'clock noon
basically noon every today tomorrow and
Sunday so you go to my YouTube you go to
communities I discover that here I can
you know you can post messages so I'm
starting to you know anything about my
youtube I'm gonna start to post there so
you know yeah so that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
so yeah well yeah about JavaScript today
I kind of rambled on a lot you know not
not very efficient talk about you know
es 15 but so if you have you know
specific questions you know if you like
me to cover for you yes 15 is very big
you know also because JavaScript has
lots of problems so some of them you
know take half an hour to explain
JavaScript object is another big item to
go over JavaScript object is which is
extremely complex and the inheritance
system you know basically the foundation
where it's class inheritance is based on
very complex it it ties with the this
keyword and new keyword then also
JavaScript they introduced a class
keyword the class keyword is supposed to
make everything easier but it's actually
more than what it seems the class
keyword so but anyway yes 2015 is
something that you actually have to know
well you have to actually know it very
well before you're talking about you
know before you want to get fancy about
you know our more pure script or you
know elixir yeah because it's
fundamental
then then actually you have to know Tom
very well the fundamentals of Adam I
mean today most JavaScript you know
programmers in industry they kind of
they don't necessarily know this well
they just you know follow the
instructions about you know they just
use react and they just use you know
Stack Overflow they just look up oh just
just type this in work you know that's
that's kind of like the JavaScript
situation but but here's the thing you
see if you are like that you never
master JavaScript and you will never for
example you will never be able to write
any any of these react view Elm a member
for example these people these people
for example or d3 you know d3.js let me
show you that's a major one of the most
popular JavaScript library for doing
graphics you know all these interactive
graphics they are fantastic ok any of
these authors you have to know you know
they are master of the years 2015 master
they are master of it and also they are
master of this dome without any library
because you cannot you know if you write
this you know they you cannot oh I will
be dying you know they are not react
extensions on the other hand react
doesn't rely on you know rely on boooo
you know others you have to like go
fundamental so that's what you know if
you are into yeah you have to know this
in depth great yeah so yeah thank you
guys for watching today and that's it
for today with JavaScript you can just
use NPM to get any library for whatever
you want anything yeah that's right
just you know bloat you know 100
libraries that's it for today
bye guys yeah if you have new topics you
know if you like to know about
JavaScript you know you know type typing
my comments and my YouTube comments or
else well you know comments on my
youtube you know here so I can you know
I can you know just start to talk about
next time bye guys