hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of some talk show
so today we are going to do wufang
language coding so here's my website on
today's talk show wufam language coding
and i'm going to show you some exposed
keyboard okay expose keyboard
which is right here
long time no see it's being a month so
today is 2021
uh november
8th good morning allen
dual camera
indeed
everything money can buy so
i want to show you so yeah so let's
focus on what we're going to do today so
today we are wolfen language coding and
expos okay i forgot to
make a link so you you can
on the video you can see how operate how
i operate my computer so show in browser
so you can see export night keyboard
they send it to me let me show you okay
so let's see video check audio check
audio check video check yeah let me show
you it's the fantastic exposed
keyboard
now you see
now you see i have actually two of them
one is the exposed natural which i got
uh about two years ago
they sent it to me so the one at the
bottom is exposed natural you see the
thing in the middle
the
you see that lights up okay i'm not
going to show it today so
uh but this one is exposed night okay so
you go to my website you can see
you see the problem is that they sent me
you know they just said they just sent
this one to me um like i got it last
week but the problem is that they sent
me a brown switch
i don't need i you know i can't not use
brown switch they made a mistake
so
you know
in order to review it properly i need to
put it here and use it every day you
know actually expose is one of the best
okay i can tell you guys expose is one
of the best keyboard you just go out go
there and buy it today
i recommend you know so they are you
know this they send me one for free so
they are kind of you you could say they
are sponsored okay but however of all
the keyboard i've used anyway go to my
website you can see all the photos and
my review
of the previous one okay
so
uh this is um
so this is my you know you can see these
photos are mine and this is another guy
from saudi discord you guys okay so
thank you for the follow so he also
bought it and quite several uh people
also bought it so
so i of all the keyboard i have used uh
so let's see so this one is the old one
the xbox natural
they don't make this one anymore but
they have a cheaper one actually i mean
the
price is lower so it's fantastic okay so
let me show you about my keyboards you
know i have um
so you can see
in this photo where i you know here's my
desktop this is my battle station here
here i sit i control the world
[Laughter]
and okay so here are the keyboards i
have
uh and you know so i have another expose
and i um so of all these you know i just
i
the kinesis advantage which is this one
and this is uh ultimate hacking keyboard
okay so you can see this i use this as a
marker pad so you can see how operate my
computer and alan your quality theory
so i recommend you know you need to get
this one of these you know
but you know yeah you have other uh
reasons such as typing russian and stuff
in korean so anyway so
my power station my keyboards and of all
of them
the the tool that i come back to is the
kinesis advantage you know this is the
most comfortable and exposed exposed
every time i use it it's just a joy okay
and i highly recommend you get the red
switch okay
like if you never had a mechanical
keyboard before or you if you are
looking into ergonomic keyboard i
recommend go out right now just buy this
one okay
say so
of course you know the kinesis advantage
is more expensive and it's curved so it
gets more used to so it's more weird so
it's up to you so but
you know if you are a student you don't
have money you know go go get the expos
right now i'm going to ask them i'm
going to you know email them and ask
them to send me another because i cannot
that's a brown switch you know so i have
a brown switch exposed and i have a red
switch exposed so the i i always use the
red switch the new one is brown switch
so um
oh and also another tail let me tell you
guys okay you you see my pinky
okay so you can see i mean not pinky the
ring finger it got damaged
you see
so so this finger so you know it it it
won't it won't straighten it's heating i
think eventually you know after several
months you'll go back but but now it's
got a problem it's just like
a chicken claw i got a chicken clothing
got damaged because i was playing with
my wife you know pushing around and
and the knuckle got pushed in
more than it's supposed to go i suppose
so
there's like almost no pain just just a
very minor very very minor tiny so
it's a problem so i'm now i'm a
i'm officially crippled
you must respect my opinions
because i'm a
disabled person okay so today so that is
that enough about keyboard let's begin
shall we into the proper topics of the
e-max the technology of our ai
artificial intelligence era and wufam
language oh my god
let me tell you guys about wufang
language okay the most fantastic by a
magnitude beyond all languages beyond
haskell erlang closure or whatever you
know or rust
so alan says you may be disabled but you
discriminate on switchy space on color
yes indeed
um
okay so let's do
uh let's see i will look at my kinesis
advantage 2 now
yes indeed
okay so let's do
let's do the hey hey hey uh jeremy
junkan missed me missed me on
on the
um master then
the federation master that
macedon
sad
sad story of the open source
how many people are there now like 10
okay yeah so i abandoned master then
nobody you know nobody's there and
and by tomorrow there will be a new
another one federation you know my
student you know
people already forgot what he's mastered
you know but next year maybe soon soon
very soon sooner or later some open
source phonetics will create another one
oh this is the best one this is
federated yeah yeah because of this is
web3
recently i heard the web3 jargon has
been going around so this is the web3
you know open source phonetics it go go
nowhere
you know there's several uh
histories of that before you know the
similar things to masterton you know gnu
has one and
several
and after after two or three years
nobody remembers it
uh okay so today let's go then now let's
do uh wufang language and let me tell
you about ufam language so am i uh doing
good so 6
14 now good i'm doing good
so wufang language okay so
uh
let me so in the past month it's been a
while it's saying in the past month i've
been working on diligently on
on writing a wolfram language
um uh mathematica tutorial okay so now
it's complete in fact i have several so
you just go to you know search saudi uh
language you can arrive at this page
you know i did several videos before
fantastic geometry mathematics crypt
crypto analysis and you know you can do
that
with uh
wolfram language blockchain whatever you
know mathematic
differential equations differential
geometries and all that so i did several
videos of that go watch it and also this
relates to like i i said many times um
theoretical computer science such as
haskell you know has got proof systems
uh
meta programming the pattern imagine
symbolic pattern matching the
uh
the
combinators and the lambda calculus it's
all here okay it's all related you know
um so anyway i
i did several videos before go watch
them okay and now
let me tell you so here this section i
in the past month or two i spent time
to write these tutorials now i consider
them basically complete okay you know
the top four uh complete okay so you
have first of all you have wolfram
syntax okay this discuss a very
um interesting topic that is the syntax
of nested parenthesis now you lispers
out there you know you are crazy about
parentheses and especially you racket
people the racket these the skin people
especially the racket people they are
excited about the racket language how
they have a feature of changing syntax
my ass okay
so here is a proper
way to do
a programming language with meta
expression in original
mccarthy john mccarthy the creator of
lisp
vision about language syntax what he
calls meta expression
and where is that that is on in wufang
language okay so this article wolfen
language syntax operators i talks about
basically complete
coverage of the
the meta syntax okay so you i'm you know
i'm going to talk i'm going to do a
video
maybe tomorrow or so
about this topic but anyway so
go back so then there's a wolfram
language tutorial now this this is a
tutorial about let's say you never coded
wufam language before you come in from
python javascript ruby
java c c plus plus rust golem okay you
coming from those languages so even
haskell and you wonder what
what the is talking about how just
how
is it possible wufang language is a
magnitude better than all of them well
you begin here wufam language tutorial
so i show you the basics the comments
uh how do you get the version number
first of all that's important in every
language you need to know what version
you are running the comments
how do you print something
how do you do string in wufang language
how do you end uh starting to introduce
you to functions in language which is
the most
basically the most important and the
only thing you need to be concerned when
you code wufam language in other
languages such as c c plus plus you need
to be concerned about syntax in
semantics because every every place it
has a different meaning and you need to
worry about shooting yourself in the
foot such as
malloc you know memory pointers you know
you know so in those but in language
that one one of the very different
characteristics is that when you're
coding language basically the only thing
you need to be concerned about on how do
you write your program is
functions okay how to find the right
function
now um
comments okay keep keep comment keep the
comments going okay
how to write a function so anyway so i
started to introduce you to functions in
language you know what they look like
how you you know and then
you get the sense of how do you find all
the functions so for example
so that's wu from language okay so you
go read this tutorial okay i spent the
past month writing it
uh let's let's let's start up wufang
language let me you know let's show some
um
interesting things okay so maybe yeah
let's say let's say you know what what
google's tell me to do you need a
trailer you need a trailer for your
youtube
google says oh you should put a trailer
so that one that way you'll attract more
uh audience
well what they mean is that that way
they can make more money
you know follow where the money is okay
one plus one please tell me oracle one
plus two what is it three oh my god
thank you oracle
so you can see
uh what should i show you what i should
i uh show you okay so this article um
you know wolfham tutorial which is
which i'm not going to do today but in
the coming weeks i'm going to do it okay
but for now let me just show you some
fancy graphics which we did last time
okay so let's you know let's copy it
so this is a trailer for for today's
you know paste it here janet you can see
this fantastic beast okay
this is called inversion geometric
inversion of
cubes in three dimension okay
fantastic geometric inversion deep
mathematics with complex analysis and
the relativity
differential geometry cosmology okay so
you wonder what they are you know get
into math begin with you know begin with
the basics trigonometry calculus you
need you you need to okay so this is the
wolfram language code and this is uh you
know mathematica geometric inversion of
cubes in 3d
so so okay so i've
told you that i wrote a lot of tutorials
on wolfen language and one on wolfram
syntax and one on you know beginning
tutorial and i would claim
let me tell you okay what
what is so special about sas tutorial
you know
this tutorial we will teach you all of
you beginners who never coded wufang
language before you you python
javascript whatever
you come to from language you can learn
you can learn from a thousand materials
in the woof and language
the wolfram website
okay the wolfram you know woofam alpha
you know the wolfram website they have
you know
i've read you know i've read you know as
you know i'm an
obsessive about reading documentation so
in in this year
i have read thousands you know
how many pages you know hundreds okay
you know basically but basically i i do
have a sense of how many pages are on
the wolfram
uh
website okay not wolfram offer woof and
mafa is the artificial intelligence
knowledge search engine okay it's
written in language of course
but let's go to woofam.com okay the
mothership
so how many pages are on wufang website
you know i have some good idea i can
tell you
uh so
let's see
one thousand um so on my websites
casari.info saudi.org orgo emacs
i have about seven about eight eight
thousand html pages on wolfram site they
have let's see
so i have eight thousand on wolfram's uh
page they have
one hundred thousand okay that's my
estimate
you know because you know i know the
company since 1990s so i would estimate
on the wolfram website right now there
are maybe a hundred thousand pages
okay
for each woofam
version the wufang language
documentation itself is
uh is about
about 2000 or 3000 pages oh wait wait
wait wait
you know the current version of language
has 6
900 functions okay now let me show you
how that that is done okay
um
so you type that that lists all
okay let let me show you okay that is
all functions building functions in
wufang language okay so you can see okay
let's magnify
so
so right now you are looking at all
functions in language and how many are
there okay so let me show you
so you want to know how many are there
so let's see the last result
get the first element
then
the last element i believe that's that
uh
let's just try it i i don't know uh no
okay
uh okay so
okay so last again
yeah
okay so i need to um okay so let's
yeah okay you cannot see it now you can
see it
information okay so information
keep it a string
and give it that
um and
and that will return
basically a list of all possible
functions and now let's do length so
okay so length is one
so now let's do
the length of that
five okay
now
okay let now let's see what they are
okay so
system okay so now i know what to do
so system get
get all the symbols from the system
then
um
length
okay so wrong oh yeah so the you want
you need the first part of the system
okay so you need the second part
so there is a list of all past order
functions in language building functions
now let's do the length okay see
six thousand nine hundred eighty
functions in language prd you don't have
to load libraries not like python oh
when you need to do regular expression
oh you will what length what what
library do i need to load you said read
or reject or whatever when you need to
traverse a directory you know let's say
find replace all files in your email
directory oh my god what what library do
i need is it system or is it directory
that's true for almost all industrial
languages in wolfram language if you're
on a directory
uh
these trials okay
this file is no file list okay so file
names okay so you you let's say you want
all files let's see
okay so let's copy
so
so now we are in emacs so here is a
directory of some talk show open the
file you can see this is the file go
back and you dive into emacs you can see
your list of directories okay so
so the file path of that is that okay so
now copy that now let's go back to ufam
language
files okay so paste the file path
and
and delete the particular file name
okay so files you need a pattern the
first argument is the pattern what kind
of files you want so
so start html
okay so now you can see
it's returning a list of all files
uh in my talk show directory under saudi
info okay so now
so now let's um
let's see the uh
let's see the length okay so like before
we do length you see there are 362 oh my
god i
i've done 300 at at least 362 star talk
shows by now yeah wow okay some of them
okay
yeah
so
so so what you are seeing is the this
file name this is how you traverse the
directory now this is a very interesting
uh phenomenon going on here let me
explain
okay
uh
hi hi andrew
so
so this function file names returns a
list of all directories given a um
you know given a you know star html
you know files in html so let's go to xr
so let me see let's see how many files
in some info html files
what 4
that's not right
oh ok so it's actually it's not
recursive
right so sardi info is only got four
files because this is actually not
recursive way
yeah okay so you see
here's an interesting uh thing to to
notice okay so this this line of code
okay takes three arguments okay
let me let me show you okay
so this line of code file names takes
now three arguments
the first argument is a pattern a a glob
okay what kind of file you want to find
the first the second argument is the
file path right
so it lists all possible files in that
directory according to this pattern now
what's the third one
that one is the depth
of the directory okay so
so if you don't give it then by default
it's one so the first level of the
directory has
four files now if you say second level
then you get all these files okay
uh
that's that's include
uh that's
that's the that means the
including level up to the second level
or only the second level i forgot which
okay so
so let's go back oh god
i forgot which okay but
there's a easy way to do it so
let me just try this
okay so if you give a anyway that's a
that's a depth okay so if you want the
up to the depth for then you can do that
but if you only want
if you only want
a directory at the depth of four
you know level four depth
then
you can do that you you add a braces
around it okay now this is very powerful
because
in unix you know the fine file or or in
powershell for example in powershell
let's magnify
okay let's cd web sardi
info okay
oh that's cd web let's magnify more okay
so you can see
uh it's cd web sadie
dot info okay so
in
in bash but right now i mean powershell
so the way you do that in powershell is
the
recurs
okay
files only
and include okay and
star html so that gives you a list of
all files recursively
there are about uh
3000 or so under exotic info so another
way to do it so you want um
anyway so you can specify uh
depth wait does powershell have a depth
option i don't
i don't think it does but in bash find
you can okay but however
it
they
you know give a depth from depth
1 to
n
in wufang language you can acc actually
specify a
specific depth
okay
that's interesting but okay
okay i'm kind of digressing but let me
get back to the other interesting point
about this
about
the perspective of programming language
from a programming point of view
algorithm point of view versus a
mathematical point of view so in wufen
language ufam is a math language so it
doesn't
uh give you from a
programming like algorithm point of view
so whenever you call a function in
wolfram language it's
from a mathematical point of view why
because let me explain the difference
okay so you see
in in powershell you have the option
because
similarly in bash
dash are recursive okay so what does
recurs mean you know it's kind of an
action it's a verb so it tells you okay
to dive into subter and you know so it's
a process okay so so this language is
spatial and powershell and
essentially every other language python
ruby javascript java you know c and all
they
the they view
the programming language view tasks as a
process you know even in haskell when
you have a function it's still a process
but the wolfram language views it as a
mathematical function so instead of
asking how to you know in in in
powershell right now we are doing a
how-to you know directory because file
include you know kind of how to
specification the recurse
but in wolfram language it's not how to
it's about what is okay so
even though these two commands right now
does the exactly the same thing but the
wolfram language there's no like recurs
that you know you don't give it the
recurse option
there's no such
like process point of view there's no
recurs
you know because from a mathematical
point of view if you want to list all
files in a directory you know just say
this is a specification i want all files
in this directory from level one to
level four or you know exactly just all
files in level 4 with you know with this
pattern so so you are asking a question
give me a result that's you know these
double files by this spec there's no
like
a process point of view
okay this is a very interesting
aspect so in wufang language every every
function everything you do in language
is is from a math point of view
uh you know there's no
kind of concept you know recurs con you
know uh
of kind of a process concept
you know okay yeah so this is an
interesting point about
traverse directory you know the very
concept you know the very word traverse
directory in most languages you know in
bashing in python
you can you know sometimes it's called
walk walker directory you know or
traverse you know so
you have the concept concept of walk
including golan you know you go to the
golan there's a library you know what
you know every language has it
so you walk a directory but inform
language it's not like that you don't
you don't walk okay because that's a
verb that's kind of you are doing
something it's you know it's not
it rather it just give you an answer
okay uh like mathematics
this
means this this this function returns
you know this function is mapped to this
output it is no
like a process thing
okay that's just interesting question so
today we are supposed to do the uh
george's code okay so let's start to do
that i i did so that's a giant
digression kind of so let's do this code
so but actually i i also want to uh tell
you about this article okay so i wrote
this one a few days ago what's the
difference between language mathematica
wufam engine and wufam script you know
it's kind of confusing because the
wolfram
uh inc the woofam corporation
incorporated now they have several
you know so many products and there's a
lot marketing talk
so
so you kind of confuse what's the exact
difference well so wufam language refers
to the language
mathematica is a
classic name
it refers to wufang language but also
the application and wufam engine
is the actual
the compiler the engine that runs
wolfram language okay
and
then woofen script is a app for command
line interface tool from language okay
let me show you
so what so what i'm saying is that go go
read this okay go check it out go read
this
in my blog you know you you go you go
through from language sadly search for
it you'll you'll find a link to this so
you know this will answer lots of your
questions if you are interested in uh
language now wufang language is free you
know you can download wufam engine again
you can just go to this side
you know download from language for free
i tell you you know i give you the links
uh then i explain what's the difference
between uh you know ufram language
mathematica with an engineer from script
and so on and what's the difference
between front end kernel notebook uh
it's all explained here
okay
so that's that and then now there's a
questions here i'm gonna answer if you
have questions post it now okay i'm
gonna i think i'm gonna end this stream
in 10 more minutes
uh
so yeah so read this and now let's get
back to um
let's go back to talk show
today we are supposed to um
you know live live coding wufang
language on this george
george's um script this is a great
this is a great written in wolfen
language by george are
our expert in programming you know
george is uh you're a member of the
saudi discord and he
of all the people on saudi discord you
know
since like a year and a half ago you
know many people there and george george
is one of the top three i would say top
three who
i would consider
um you know he showed a lot of code in
different languages wolfen language or
camel ruby which is what he called every
day um you know so i think georgie is
very quick in picking up a language
you know so he you know he downloaded
wufang language you know and he right
away coded this script to do grip the
unix script which i talked about in my
last few videos
so i was going to so let's try to do
code this okay because i'm i'm going to
try to kind of try to make maybe make it
more
um
you know
compact compact the
the
make it more efficient
you know maybe i try to optimize it
so alan says how is your experience with
the wolfram editor console thing
especially pleasant to work with no
that's a flow that's a problem of wufam
language okay
um
yeah so let me show you okay so so you
are looking at wolfram you know you uh i
mean you are looking at power you know
your uh windows
command line interface
you are looking at powershell so let's
start wolfram script
so wolfram script start okay so let's
say uh
okay so let's let's let's do the exact
same thing here so let's
cut you know
show all files in the saudi
directory
okay
um
paste okay run it
there you know so this so there it is
7 about 7 000 files how many how many
wait how many lines of code are i mean
how many
um
so here is the um
god
you know
the windows command line has this
problem you know this empty place
empty at the bottom
okay so let's do this again let's do
length okay
oh so there's only 44 46 files you see
all files or html files
inside
info
but at directory level four
so there are only 46 files but now if
you do
if you do
infinity
okay
you see there infinity so that tells wu
from language
start from level one to whatever you
know so recurse okay recurs the
directory so let's run it
wait did that did we run it
run it there it is okay now let's see
how many
4524 files
in xali info html files
okay
and we can do exactly the same thing
here
um
so infinity okay
so infinity and give length don't show
the output but show the length 4524
now what if we want to let's say uh all
files not just let's say jpeg files okay
jpeg
yeah okay
so jpeg files four thousand three
hundred jpg files what about
including all files doesn't matter
whatever type
sixteen thousand files sixteen to the
16th
okay so you are comparing you see here
you are looking at the notebook okay in
the notebook you can see you
so the difference between the notebook
let me delete the output okay
so uh evaluation let's see cell
i want to delete all the output because
this is too much to scroll so
there's the option to delete or output
okay so now we are back to so
so you are looking at the notebook now
the notebook has 3d graphics that allows
you to do that but in the wolfram script
interface you you don't have that
uh but okay so but we are showing uh
yeah so we are showing how many files
are there so
let's run that
yeah okay so this
so this is just level four
then
this is uh
all html files
all jpeg files
and all files six thousand sixteen
thousand okay and here that we can do
the same thing so
hey wait does it support yeah okay so
the woofam
the wufang notebook and the wolfram
script interface are not good alan that
answers your question they are uh
they sucks okay they are not good for
wait what what is the key to actually
move by word okay i don't think you know
the wolfram script doesn't even even
support it
not on windows i suppose
so now if you run the same thing let's
run it okay
so you see length output uh five okay so
wait what's going on
okay now
now it functions screwed up
now somehow
i think i did something wrong now now
you see now the output does not
three
four yeah
yeah so exit okay so quit
and start again
so anyway you get you get ideas so alan
question you know is it how is it uh how
easy is it to edit it's not
let's see if i can
yeah i cannot you know control arrow
does not move the cursor
let's see control b
no it no does it support you know i want
to jump by word so it doesn't
yeah so you you can see so the in the
xiao interface ufm script is not too
good
now on the woofen script you can of
course you can control to move cursor by
words you know you can yeah but still
it's no good okay so now it's time let
me show you xsa e-max mod okay
so you see so now we are inside e-max
mod so this is e-max we are talking
about okay so let's introduce
let's actually not here so the emacs
working emacs is the best thing so let
me add a wolfram language uh tag you see
you see there
so pre you know wolfen language and
paste it here
and now just like oakmod i press a key
i have the code here into a buffer by
itself okay
so actually so okay so there it is now i
can run the code so
run it
so this is
mod you can buy it with money
yeah no you know error no valid password
around that's uh you know that that is
because i i have a wolfram script
instance already running so i need to
quit here
and
then
eval
okay yeah okay it
shall command succeeded without output
because i didn't print it so i need to
call another command in in in
ma to actually print the result so you
can see result at the bottom 16
287 can you see it
you see right there
so if we show the
show the messages output you see 16287
which is the same here
okay so this is a
wolfram mod
which you can see
um you know i can
i can modify it i can you can i can do a
lot of things for example this is a
string i want this whole string gun i
can press one single key look at the
pink window one single key and delete
that whole thing
on here if i use a notebook i have to
click on that twice then i got it then i
have to control
x
to copy okay
ctrl z
to undo or i can press the
backspace
you know too
but in emacs you know
there's no control nothing soft like
keys okay one key to undo
one key to undo again
and now i press one key to move closer
it's not even arrow key so you see i
press these two so i'm using very
keyboard so h and n move
uh you know back and forth so i put a
cursor here and press one single key to
delete that
string the whole string one key to undo
so that you know so i can press one key
to move the crystal all the way to the
back here and one key to eliminate that
whole entire
uh
the bracket you know square bracket okay
that's about that
uh
okay so kang shao guang welcome good
morning uh map oh oh oh let me mention
so kang here
he is a expert of wufam language too
so kang
are you in china
so i know because we were on twitter and
you know so i've seen you know khan
sometimes tell me some tips about
wolfram language
are you in china so
far
so
so he's saying
uh map
file extension and count uh distinct
okay so
citix is got a question let's see
needs to be in the next ocean's
internship movie saying a lot
question can you count unique files yeah
of course so can't distinct fantastic
thank you kang
he's the expert of language
okay i think that's it because um
hello gavin freeborn
so come join my discord okay
oh oh jesus you are in the same city we
should meet up guys uh
hey uh yeah so we should
so you know join my discord you know
twitter twitter the scum
you know i so i i try to avoid using
twitter basically i stop using it i go
to twitter only to post my stuff
so um let's see
yeah so i don't you know i don't even
you know i don't
use twitter you know i just go there to
it's a marketing tool that's what
twitter is
uh with twitter themself market you know
they
so don't you use twitter so uh
maybe join my discord okay sorry discord
you can find the url and then we can you
know let's chat
you know maybe we can meet up have a
coffee and you know
um
i think that's it for today so we could
try to um work on this um
this is george okay so let's let's run
it okay so
so this script is from george what it
does is a unix script okay so now let's
save it okay hold on a second wait
uh actually
okay they are before before we uh we do
anything let me tell you about wolfram
script okay so i'm pedaling you know and
you know donate i'm paying him for your
donation your money
so you go to casa
emacs
website
by the way so this is
i'm about to move it to cassady.info
so pretty soon by next week all
you know everything on logo emacs is
going to be
gone it's going to be on saudi.info
instead so you go to a you know sell
emacs and and go to sadie packages
then you can uh go to um
uh saw fan mod okay somewhere here you
know so
where is it uh some input mod because i
will find mark there okay so here
i read i wrote this about two months ago
i spent a month
less than a month actually
well about month because you know
anyway so this is somewhat mod if you
like it pay me okay pay me to get it
uh fantastic features you know like okay
so let's show the features so
so go to crystal email okay click close
emacs uh go to star talk show
so you are looking at sas today's talk
show
and here's the wolfram language language
called george's code which is here okay
so press the button to remove the syntax
curling so we can actually look at the
code then press another button to move
the whole thing into a into a file by
itself so you can see
this is the wolfram language mod you can
see here
so actually uh let me show you the code
okay so press the key and press press
press press
and here is the documentation for
someone mod okay
you can see
uh some woofer mod
okay then let's jump to the code okay
jump to the code
you know so right now it's 200 to 2500
lines you know you go to the top
you know so this is the woofer mod
yeah so
buy it if you like it okay now let's
let's go now let's go to the george's
code so let's use someone for mr to
actually run this code to to you see the
syntax coloring you see
every wolfram language building function
is colored in blue so you can see and
every user
you know functional names is in yellow
and every
every building local variables is in
green so you can see this list pattern
is in green so let me let me get rid of
the you know i don't like the global
highlight okay so let's remove that so
you can see
you can so you can see green that's a
local patterns
here here let's magnify okay so local
patterns here here here here and also
this this is a
building variable kind of syntax for uh
function
arguments okay so those are in green
okay so that's a
wolfram mod for emacs for you emacs
users buy it thank you
so you can also donate me via patreon
and paypal or amazon gift
okay now let's um okay so this is the
woofer this is the george's george's
file so okay so let me rename the file
so go to
so let's rename uh
uh wolfram
w grip okay let's just rename the file w
grip
w grip dot e
dot dot dot wl okay
so here's the name w grip so
now open powershell
now let's run wgreb
so wolfram script
file
what is the wolfram script
option to run a file yeah file i think
file
w grep
okay
so now you want to give a word to grab
so let's say let's scrape pascal so this
will
grab or
extraterrestrial files for the word has
got let's try it
usage okay uh usage pattern path okay so
now you need to actually give a path
okay current direct let's see if that
works
fantastic this is george this is george
george's wolfram script doing a unique
script so it's output all files that
contains the word haskell there it is
there it is there it is
okay but i think that's it for today uh
is george here george is not here
george should be
any any
other questions comment
yeah okay it's one hour today and thank
you guys for coming by
so celtic says
uh my guy on the inside says they are
running zos okay from the movie
from the movie um
oceans i haven't seen that movie you
know so that movie is like
several females right like a new version
you know because there's you know the
you usa politicians they are pushing for
um you know women things
i mean but
you mean i mean a movie
of women hackers is great but however
you know they are pushing those things
okay that's it for today uh thank you
guys for watching uh
bye then so we shut down um yeah in a
minute
so
yeah i'm going to code this but yeah but
we we demonstrated so let's um
so let's delete that put the code back
here
and
put it into
syntax color show in browser
okay
okay that's it thank you guys
anything i missed let's see xbox
keyboard yes what's the difference
between wolfram language wolfram engine
wolfram script mathematica we did that
uh get wolfen language for free indeed
we did that
uh
we didn't talk about syntax operators
that's for tomorrow so
so thank you fantastic
thank you ian kovyo
yeah so we did yeah so in the coming
weeks tomorrow and i think i'm going to
start to do
one son talk show a day again maybe or
every other day so watch for my youtube
i'm gonna you know i don't have a
schedule set up yet i'm thinking maybe
every day
uh 11 or 12 o'clock you know san
francisco time noon so maybe every day
san francisco time noon something like
that you know i'm you know my life is
chaotic i can never
you know
pre-schedule so
um
so thank you alan and alan is now
starting alan talk show
if you guys don't know
alan
uh you know he's starting his youtube so
let's you know let's let's let's
let's let's you know let's have a look
at alan's um
allen's talk show uh you know so anna
what's your channel number so that
that's a problem alan you need to do
marketing because last time i asked you
is there an easy phrase for your user
can type and and get to your website
you never answer that you know you
answer about something else you never
actually answer that so
so i'm trying to say that's a good tip
to you know because i know i type allen
you know at add on at the video you know
talk show i don't know what's your allen
talk show okay
yeah that's not you uh so you know
need need a phrase you know because my
name is kind of unique so sound talk
show works but what you know what um
yeah okay yeah so see you guys but let
me but i want to show you um so let's go
to alan's um
so where is it
quickly let's go to there alan stream
yeah that's right island stream
so you see i have multi browser system
so this is google chrome
um
you know this is uh varadi
and google chrome
then
uh brave you know multiple systems so on
variety javascript is off by default so
copy the wait
so copy the
url close it go to google chrome close
that commercial crap open a new key i
mean open a new um tab paste it go to
island stream
so there it is alan's talk show okay
thank you guys
bye