good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
today is 2020 9 o'clock
30 minutes after night uh
in the evening san francisco time today
is saturday here
august 15th and today we are going to do
a
emacs and evacuees coding and
so i think you know so we i might be
talking bilingual today
english and chinese and so first of all
let's show you the background image
so today's image is this mx donuts
and we have the mx donuts this happens
to be
a donut shop then you have
vim fitness someone took this photo
okay so that's a background image by the
way the
mx and vim veeam seems much more popular
you'll find
the name veeam in many places
okay that's the background image now
let's begin
uh to do what we want to do today emacs
lisp
so if you have questions comments
comment i love comments okay type in the
comment
in the chat box and let's go here then
let's start to do
uh emacs lisp coding
uh share emacs these
senses okay so let's see what we want to
do
magnify on the right window you can see
all my keys and commands
whenever i press some key it will show
on the right window
and also the command name so if you
don't know what i'm doing you can just
look
uh up the command there usually there's
also a source code
so let's do e-max e-max coding okay
before we do before we begin let me
mention
that um there is a online meetup
for emacs people uh
hosted by the great jeff t
he is hosting the emacs meetup
in san francisco but now because of the
kovite 19 there's no
real meetup so we have a online meetup
so you know you go to the website you
know
you meet up san francisco
then you you want to register you want
to
um you know reserve a place kind of
because because we are going
i mean he's doing a online meetup you
know we chat about emac stuff
and uh there is a limit of how many
people i think
20 you know he's gonna have the 20
people only
so go there and sign up and this is
going to
be on uh
what's the date uh august 20th
so next week next week thursday there's
a time there you can go
check it out uh i i think i will be
joined
but i'm you know um you know i don't
because i do emacs a lot
so i'm thinking maybe let other people
join because there's only
20 people i you know i think i like to
join
uh we'll see i like to join talk to some
of the people i've met
jeff ogg uh
and john wiggly he's the
maintainer of emacs yeah many of people
many people here i've met
face to face so yeah that's the emacs
meetup
so let's talk about let's start to talk
about um what we are going to code today
so first of all youtube link if i okay
so let's quote that
hey good morning guys dave johnson yes
so i'm going to talk bilingual today
good morning aaron hall how's it going
aaron hall is the great python
programmer the number one
uh person who answered python questions
on stack overflow
and that's not easy to do hey new
musical
namashiko good morning to hong kong okay
so
so i'm going to talk chinese
uh so if i go talk chinese you english
you know just watch what i do okay we
are going to call emacs list
so so uh
okay i'm going to hold
someone
what we're doing is
let me show you an example okay so
uh let me show you what are we doing
what is the task
what is it that i'm i'm i'm coding
so okay hold on second
let's magnify sega okay
and zig okay so
showing show in browser
youtube okay
copy okay
you want the time you want the time
stamp
you see there's a timestamp here because
i want the video to start at some point
but however my existing command doesn't
do it
for example let me show you copy okay
time stamp is gone
i i what so what i need is this
timestamp
over here in my command
i i need my command to recognize to
maintain the
timestamp so let's do that
okay so where is the command the command
name is youtube linkify
um okay let me
just take a youtube link of file
youtube linkify so here's the command
name
so let's write it down
html youtube link if i to
recognize timestamp
okay just see about the sentence so
let's go to the source code so here's
the source code
and jager okay kai gashinda shindetons
open a new buffer and save it
we are going to modify this here today
okay secrets now
let's go back now we need to modify the
timestamp
so what's uh okay so this
is the timestamp
it needs to become your bench and start
equals to something yeah be a better
there
so let's just copy that without
okay let's paste it here so we have a
reference
okay so let's start to code let's just
go to the place
the so let's see let's see do we have
chinese or english
hello hello okay no comments uh
so d so first thing we need to do is to
extract to recognize if the url contains
the t parameter just y'all kind of
a url your mail is a good t parameter
if the t parameter is there we want to
extract it
once we extract the time parameter then
we can add
insert it
so how do we check if there's a time
parameter let's do
okay it's a tiger so there you go so
it's a good
so he take just input string so we got
the input string now we want to
check if the input string contains the
match
so input string
string match okay congratulate your mail
stream match input string then
you want to check a regular expression t
equals to that's what you want to check
t equals to zero to nine digits
one or more question mark
yeah let's not check question mark let's
just check let's just check that
stream match okay let's search that
uh before we do let's test it
just the answer yet okay wait
so we're gonna test this run it
it is true it returns a position where
it matched
you see at the bottom it says 29 so so
this is the correct code to run
so we
we want to um
let me let me write it up check if the
url contain
time stamp
okay that's this line
the wall so if it matches what what
we want to extract it so timestamp so
let's add a new variable
new variable
okay
so if that then
program
set queue timestamp
equals to matched string
okay so here is how you do it so you
need
a parenthesis that match the string
you need a two backslash
how do i know because experience
uh because emac this regular expression
is full of backslash and slashes full of
it
it's called toothpick syndrome in
programming community
uh so yeah match the timestamp yeah so
so you'll just read regular expressions
so if the match string
timestamp if match string
so here is how we get
the the the captured part
match string one the first one
option no option now if you are
now you need to uh give a string here
that's that's what you need that's what
we want to do
so if
if it matches then
get the timestamp okay now otherwise
let's just say
timestamp equals to empty string there
it is
there here is our code she wanna
now i want to make the code better in a
better
more readable format so let's trans
let's change it
so instead of instead of uh the whole if
expression then say that we want to set
you see
if
so um
okay
there it is so we have two versions
of the code
india
so this is a better um
a better form okay so so let's
let's let's let's comment it out
yeah okay so
okay so now we checked we have the
timestamp
now the rest is easy now the rest is
easy
so now you just go to the ho hunting
so here somewhere so you want to uh yeah
so you just add it there so
so you want um
see once yes i'm gonna let let's let's
go look okay
which one what is the code we need to
add
here you need this part just yeah jazzy
like okay so it
here and the string
yeah that's what we want and here
uh wait okay something is
not right look at the coloring
okay wait um
oh we we need to add it here okay
here and here we have another parameter
so here is time stamp okay
i think that's it
jesus so now i think that's that's
that's it
that's how our code works make a backup
i think your work change the date so
august 15 and let's try the code
let's try the code
but in the documentation string let's
add another variation because this
documentation string
tells you that the command can accept
several formats you see you can accept
this format
or this format or this format or this
format
or this format okay
let's try it
you know with the timestamp
okay let's let's let's let's do it okay
so that's the code
uh okay now evaluate the buffer
now go back to html let's we can try it
now we are done so okay so remember that
uh code
remember that url we get we just try it
let's see if it works
so youtube linkify do it
cannot find the youtube video id
in url oops
problem
let's go back to the list code cannot
find the video id
why is that
okay i think i know why so once you
any comments and questions paul edward
should not put should not input stream
be set to zero
not
um not input string i mean you mean the
timestamp
no if we found the timestamp then
then we uh we set it to the match string
if there is no timestamp it should be
empty stream
oh yeah so i i think i get it
wait i mean this should be time stamp
okay we got it wrong so hold on a second
it's alicia tall okay now let's try
again
eva buffer go back to html
and let's try the command again youtube
linkify do it yeah fantastic look
you see this that's the timestamp we got
it to work
now show in browser showing browser
if i play this video it will start
somewhere in the middle let's try it
there it is there it is
so ah so successful this is mission
complete
so anna one yet very good
okay so that's it for that i mean
we are so now actually we can shut down
um
unless you guys want to do something
else should we
yeah so any questions we can do another
how long have i been talking we can do
another
uh lisp short one or something or if you
have any
questions ask me okay anything you
um what's not clear or something or any
any emacs questions or stuff
so i've been talking for 27 minutes
so we can actually do another so
let's clean up
so go back to the code go back to the
code so here is today's code
uh
so here is today's code we want to put
it into the
html mod because this is from html mod
let's let's do it
actually let's see
so actually let's do one more thing okay
let me explain
so sometimes you are given this this
command will allow
um just a
youtube video id so that's a youtube
video id
oh yeah that works okay so never mind so
okay so what we're gonna do is we copy
the whole thing
cut go back to html mode uh
go back to html mod
describe key space space space h
here is the html mod
you go to it tab go to it
then search for magnify search for
youtube
search for youtube linkify so here is
our code
here is our old code
delete it
make a backup copy paste a new one
there it is here is a new one so you see
here is the date now save it now go to
the top
here's the version we want to update the
version number
so insert a date in this format
and increase the second digit because we
improve the code then delete the the
original line so that's it
save it now call magic status
magic status okay
okay so
magic git now you can see
here are the changes we made today we
changed this code
fantastic okay
now we want to press s to stage it
out github okay to commit
you press cc okay
cc
so what's a command we just uh called
uh i don't remember youtube linkify
because html youtube linkify i don't
remember the command name
we need to get the command name
okay let's go to the file there
now accept timestamp
in url okay
okay ctrl c ctrl c to commit
pp to push to github
now it's on github okay we are done
anything else
de niro
good morning anything else let's go to
html mod okay let's go to
git hub and just have a look
so html mod so that's my mod
oh not here well you go to github's okay
so github
so there is github and we just did a
commit let's look
[Music]
so that's our code today that's what we
did
that's that's what we did today so it's
good
okay i think maybe that's it for today
uh the short one let's keep it nice and
simple for today
um thank you everyone hope to see you
again if you like my tutorials
buy it okay go to my emacs emacs
tutorial you go to
[Music]
emacs lisp you have a complete
introduction to beginners you can learn
emac this from the very basics to
more advanced including how to write a
major mod
if you like it by it thank you thank you
guys
bye
let's see yeah i'm gonna close in one
minute let's see did i
is there anything i want to talk about
anything
so close that uh what is this
close that
yeah that's it bye