Good morning. Good morning. Good
morning, guys. Welcome to another
episode of SAR Talk Show.
And actually, I'm not ready yet. So, I'm
going to
Yeah, I'm so I'm live. So, I'm going to
leave.
I'm going to be back in 5 minutes. But
so, I'm going to leave this um
uh window up. So, I'm going to start
start in 5 minutes.
Be be right back. Okay.
I'm going to leave this up.
And uh hope I'm back.
There will be
a thousand people. Okay.
So, I'll be right back.
Uh let's leave that there.
Okay.
Mhm.
Hello guys. So, any anyone here yet?
Three people watching. Great.
So, I'm back.
And I
And I got milk.
And I'm ready to talk. Great talk.
The talk of the century.
Hello guys.
So, say something in the comment box.
And today we're going to talk about
two topics.
Uh I have two topics in mind.
And one
let's see let's
adjust the windows, so
This is milk, okay?
Wonderful milk. Milk in microwave and uh
And you can see
This is
What? Milk.
Milk,
my keyboard,
my mouse,
fantastic mouse.
You see? Infinite scroll, you see?
And uh
Well, milk Milk is my breakfast.
Kind of my break breakfast. Let's see.
Let's put it back.
Okay, so infinite scroll.
Uh like the Infinity War, you know?
Every Kimball, good morning. Every
Haven't seen you before. Where you from?
I always ask that question. Like what
country, what region.
So we So we going to I'm going to talk
about two things. I have two things in
mind. One is this
this
fantasticomical
uh
fantastic
you know what?
Fantastic uh keyboard, very strange
keyboard. Then there is the elegance
versus
um simplicity in coding style.
Uh well, let's just begin.
Um
So Let's Let's make sure I'm like
talking. Like sometimes
I'm getting so old, so out of touch that
I talk for like 10 minutes and the audio
is not on.
Okay, so um
So the keyboard.
Uh the keyboard Okay, so Emacs online
problem. Yeah, the Emacs problem, the
keyboard, and the coding style.
And and and uh JavaScript.
Okay, three topics. So let's talk about
which topic should I go first? Uh
Let's talk about keyboard then because
keyboard is like um
Saudi keyboard, okay, because it is like
universal topic among programmers. It is
the topic that has the most attraction.
So, go to Saudi keyboard blog.
This Ergo Dox keyboard
is see how um
how advanced, how crazy things has
become in a in a keyboard space.
So, in in the beginning, so uh as you
know,
in the beginning you have the PC
keyboards. Now, these are idiotic
keyboards, you know, today. It's
rightful to call them idiotic. They are
loved by people who do not touch type.
They are loved by second hand, you know,
elite keyboardists, you know, they they
think they got the greatest keyboard. Um
you know, but they are just like as we
say, they are normies as some people
say. I don't even like that that jargon,
okay? Normies. Normies means like normal
normal person, okay?
I'm a weird person. You are the we you
are a weird person. We are weird
persons, okay? So, anyway,
and you know, so a lot of people love,
you know,
like the the the difference of choices
between these, you know, PC keyboard,
they are all the same. Like they are all
the same, but some of them are very
expensive such as this one. The most
idiotic among them all, this Happy
Hacking keyboard. This this This Happy
Hacking keyboard is like $270
USD, okay?
It's the worst among them all, you know,
in terms of features, ergonomics,
everything. It's
including the key switch, you know, that
that's using the well-known key switch
called um
uh
Topre. Topre is actually the name of a
Japanese company.
Uh it's a capacitance
uh keyboard switch, meaning that um
well, I'm not going to go into that, you
know, about that detail today, but you
uh it's it's uh based on
capacit- capacitance switch, meaning
that you know, when you talk about
keyboard switch, there are two aspect to
it. One aspect is the electronics
switch. How the electronics actually
makes the contact, you know. That's the
electronics
switch, okay? The
the meaning of switch actually.
Uh the other aspect of keyboard switch
is uh is is kind of uh how how does it
feel to press the key, like tactile or,
you know, um
you know,
it's usually called called mechanical
switch, and that's the aspect most uh
keyboard enthusiasts uh look for because
that's the as- aspect you actually care,
you know, how it feels, you know, as
opposed to how the electronics makes
contact. What what is the mechanism the
electronics make makes contact because
that aspect
although there are good designs and bad
designs, but but but, you know,
ultimately actually, you know, when you
press a key, it
needs to make a contact, you know, it
it's not something
um
of concern,
but the more uh
the more sensational, actually literally
sensational, aspect is the how the key
feels. But anyway, so this one is called
Topre switch used by Happy Hacking
Keyboard, and it's loved by
you know, it's like it it has a elite
hacker status among, you know, hacker
hacker type of programmers.
Just like Unix, Linux, and you know,
uh
you know, Unix philosophy, those those
those sort of things, you know, you you
have a sense of being
elite, like being superior, being more
difficult to learn, being more
expensive, you know.
But it's like crap, you know. Like
scientifically, functionally speaking,
ergonomically speaking, with respect to
science and, you know,
happy cat and and also the price, the
product quality uh divided by price
ratio, it happy cat again is one of the
worst possible. It is no it's not
programmable. It's doesn't have a lot
keys programmable I mean, it's not
programmable and it doesn't have a lot
of keys. The keys actually are, you
know, a number of keys are small and you
don't have thumb keys. So, and the
design is bad, everything.
But, you know, it's like it's got a
elite status among programmers. But
anyway, back to the previous topic. So,
I was saying, you know, among uh
among the choices, you know, the PC
keyboard and the ergonomic keyboard, you
know, in the beginning you have this PC
keyboard. Then about 5 years ago all
sort of ergonomic keyboards uh
began to thrive, like, you know, we are
entering digital age, right? AI age
right now in the AI era. And in the same
way
evolution is happening like everywhere,
okay?
I mean, so you can you can say that the
evolution of, you know, new era is
happening all across. I mean, it's not
just like in in sciences because it has
consequences. So, anyway, in keyboard um
you know, community, you can see all
these begin to thrive. About about like
5 years ago, I would say begin with the
um
truly ergonomic keyboard.
Uh actually, you'll find it uh ergonomic
keyboard history beginning with this
keyboard.
Uh
let me show you which one uh which one I
have right there, but it's buried under
a bunch of papers.
So, it began with this one in 2013.
Then, you have ErgoDox. I'm pretty sure
you guys heard of it. ErgoDox um
Uh okay, I'm going to show you.
Uh
So, then you have then you have ErgoDox.
Okay, let's show ErgoDox then. Oh
ErgoDox is one of the do-it-yourself
keyboard. So, after truly ergonomic
keyboard, you have this
uh ErgoDox.
Again, it's one of the keyboard loved by
many hackers because one of the great
reason is because it's open source.
Yeah, yeah. We love open source. It must
be open source. If it's not open source,
it's evil. It's, you know, it's killing
people.
That's what open source wants to think,
you know. Open source and free software
foundation, you know, the Richard
Stallman school sect versus the open
source sect. They are different sects,
then they fight among themselves.
So, you know, so then after truly
ergonomic, then you have uh
ErgoDox, which began around
uh
2004.
Oh, I didn't say when it began.
Well, yeah, 2013.
Uh 2013, but but it's actually after
ErgoDox, okay?
But anyway, ErgoDox is a copy. It's kind
of like, you know, copied idea of the um
Let's Let's go to my um
my Let's close this. Let's go to my
keyboard blog because local version
because then we can open things faster.
So,
So, you have Let's see. Um
Let's magnify magnify magnify. I mean,
not magnify, but
um
Taneli Sora
Good morning, Taneli. Haven't seen you
before.
And uh Taneli says,
well, I'm I may pronounce uh people's
name wrong, but okay. If you care, just
say so. Okay, type like what should it
be pronounced.
Taneli says,
"Topre are the only key switches that
have ever really made my fingers sore in
use."
Okay.
Yeah, I don't I don't like Topre switch
myself. I haven't actually used it like
for, you know, prolonged period of time.
I only, you know, tried it. I know I
don't like it because
well, I'm not going to go into detail
about that.
So, anyway, truly ergonomic keyboard.
Then,
uh okay, some of these ergonomic
keyboards are uh kind of ancient, you
might say. For example, this Maltron
uh it began in uh
Jeez. I didn't say what year they began.
You know, it's a flaw in my blogs. I
should I should have mentioned
somewhere. Anyway, it began around 1970s
or Okay, 1977. There it is, 1977.
Then, it was copycatted by Kinesis.
The original name is Kinesis contoured
keyboard, okay? But now it's just
Kinesis Advantage. The Kinesis Advantage
began in 19 at least 1991, okay?
They copied
Yeah, they basically copied the
um
the Maltron, okay? Maltron is a company
using in UK, United Kingdom.
So and this is by the way, this is my my
main keyboard right now. It's great,
fantastic.
So anyway, you have these bunch of So I
was saying, you know, since 2013
the ergonomic keyboard community is
thriving, you know, you start to have I
mean, I'm not talking about
do-it-yourself like, you know, the
keyboard community communities where
hackers, you know, they Yeah, also
partly because the 3D printing started
to thrive, you know, that you can
actually print stuff and so people start
to build
you know, it's a era, it's a new era,
you know, it's a era AI era, you know,
we are entering into. So
So back to what I was saying. So you you
begin with truly ergonomic, then you
begin with several of these commercial
ones, you know, these are I'm not so I'm
not talking about the do-it-yourself,
you know, which is limited to, you know,
essentially
handful of people, you know, who are
programmers or engineers, you know,
mechanical engineers, you know, they
they do it. Yeah, they create their own
design things, but but these these these
are commercial made by companies. You
can buy like right now.
So So since 2013 it began to thrive. You
have so many designs. For example, this
this this this this they are all new
like in the past 5 years. This one
Microsoft, this one actually too is new.
So, you have all these designs.
So, okay, that's about the thriving of
keyboard community. Now,
back to previous topic. I was saying,
you know, between the PC keyboard, you
know, these common shaped ones and the
ergonomic ones, the the major
difference is that basically for those
people who do not touch type, like if
you do not touch type,
the the ergonomic ones will not
will not attract
you will not find the ergonomic ones
attractive.
That's basically the dividing line,
okay?
If you type I mean, if you do not touch
type and if you never had hand problems,
you're going to love, you know, the PC
keyboard, you know, that's vast majority
of people like, you know, even in the
keyboard community like on Reddit, you
know, mechanical keyboard
room, okay?
You got all these pictures every day
this CD people.
They they there's no innovation. They
like they post their
normal PC keyboard all day, you know, uh
But anyway,
once you type, you know, a lot and or
you have hand problems,
uh
or then you may start to learn, you
know, you actually start to, you know,
dig into issues like details science
science of it, you know, why why do I
have hand pain, you know, because that's
when things became serious. Uh
or if you type a lot, you don't have
hand pain, but also that's when things
get serious because,
you know, you need efficiency and you
know
you so you throw away the common, you
know, idiotic advices on the websites.
You look into details. That's when you
start to look into the ergonomic ones,
you know, usually these are for people
who really type a lot or have already
hand pain,
uh, you know.
So, that's the general dividing
uh, kind of like what kind of people
choose which kind of keyboard. So, you
have the ergonomic ones and the PC, uh,
ones. So, anyway, the ergonomic ones,
uh,
began to thrive around 2013.
Then, let me show you the bunch of
do-it-yourself designs, you know, the
So, it became incredible, uh,
so many of them.
Like so many variations, okay? Uh, each
one So, each one has a typically they
have a GitHub, you can go there if you
are into, you know,
creating your own keyboard. You buy the
parts, the electronics, the PCB, you
know, the board, the keycaps, you create
you make it yourself, you know,
following the instructions.
And then people come up come up with
uh, all sort of designs.
A- And typically they also they follow a
certain form, like, you know, you you
start to have lots of thumb keys, you
know, uh, keys for the thumb, you know.
And you know, uh, for example, this one
and many variations, you know, some
people think, uh, you know, the Ergodox
is this is, you know, has certain flaws.
So, they created a variation, they think
that they improved it, you know.
Different people have different ideas.
So, you got this bunch of, um,
many variations, uh,
in design, you know.
Uh, many of these people I know, you
know, for example, the Atreus is one of
the famous
the Signal people is by John Trong, I
think. Uh I
we are acquaintances.
And you know, the the Planck is one of
the most idiotic Planck keyboard.
Humble Hacker is one of the earliest uh
do-it-yourself keyboard. Um it's created
by the I met him actually one day in a
keyboard uh meetup in San Francisco.
This one began in 19
in 2000s, I think, around um
Oh okay, 2009.
Um anyway, so
so these are do-it-yourself keyboards.
And some of the some of them are from
Japanese keyboard community. For
example, this
uh Eucalyptus
uh Helix and uh the Ben- I think Benzen,
I'm not sure.
And uh the Utron is also the Mutron is
also from Japan. Um so, you got, you
know, many varieties. And also
and there are some So, there are levels
of craziness with it, okay? For example,
the Planck is the most normal idiotic,
you know, without imagination. The And
they they they are this Planck keyboard
is also very highly pop- popular among
the hackers, you know. Uh by the way,
keep the comments coming, okay? I'd love
to see them. You know, if you have
opinions, questions, you know, comments,
just type it.
Hello, Victor.
So, the Planck is actually the worst,
okay?
So
so you have categories of levels of
innova- innovation or creativity or you
know, fanciness. So, you this these are
the most
you know, normal normal like, okay? Then
you have, you know, these uh fancy
ergonomic ones, okay?
Uh
Okay. Hey hey uh Tanali. Uh okay, so uh
then
then you have more fancier ones, okay?
So, these are, you know, uh ergonomic
fancy ones.
But, at the extreme end, you start to
find these uh ball
ball uh ball surface kind of ones like
the tactile the tactile manual form.
The Colosseum. You know, so some of
these are incredibly uh
you know, uh weird and fantastic fan
fantasticomical.
What what what's that word? I forgot. Uh
you know,
um
So, then you have the this Colosseum is
from Japan uh
a year ago like I mean it's still
active, you know, you can you can you
can go and buy the parts and build it
just
Look at these
keys, you know, that the way thumb keys
is going around.
Then you have this Naive uh from a guy
who
who we you know, who contact me.
Uh and he this one is still in process
or something like that, you know,
um
then you have, you know, so let's go
back um
then you have this KeyMouse, okay?
This KeyMouse thing is like keyboard and
mouse in combination, so you move the
whole thing as a mouse.
Uh you know, both hands both hands or
you can use the you know, score
um
ball
trackball on it.
Uh so
so uh so you have these weird uh fancy
ones and to today yesterday
uh I discovered this one, Ergo Drap.
Ergo Walk keyboard.
No, I'm not I'm not I'm not actually
sure how this one actually works. Like
where how do you put your hands? Like
you know, and this looks like a
trackball. Like
how do you use it? And what are these,
you know, loops?
I haven't looked into detail, you know,
like what what the heck?
But, I have opinions about these fancy
ones. Of course, I have lots of
opinions. So, let me and then let's talk
about that. I'm going to
uh tell you why what I think about these
um
and uh let me read the comments.
So, hi uh
so, please feel invited to comment on
the keyboard.io
butterfly keyboard. Thinking of dropping
three uh hundred for that. Okay.
Uh and now this is going too far. Yeah,
this this is crazy. crazy, you know,
Ergo Drap.
Uh but, first of all, let me talk about
the keyboard.io
keyboard.
Uh
I haven't I haven't used it, so I cannot
really uh give you a good
uh
review.
I have tried it, you know, just for like
few minutes uh during keyboard meetups.
So,
um
this is created by a Pearl guy I know, a
Pearl programmer.
Uh since, you know, Pearl is like from
the 1990s. So, he's a well-known
uh Pearl programmer
in a Pearl community.
And uh you know, I
So, anyway, so this keyboard uh
you know, so I I I haven't really uh I
haven't tried it, so I can't really uh
review it well, but from
purely from the design aspect, I think
it's very good. Excellent design, okay?
Uh so, you know, you can read my review.
Um
Okay, so I So, let me comment, you know,
something about this keyboard. And
there's a video of showing you a people
you know, this guy typing on it.
And they have their own forums, you
know, you can go there and see lots of
people who own it
and who they have lots of photos,
videos, and you know, they have lots of
discussions, comments, you know.
Okay, so about this keyboard. So, yeah.
So, I think it's very well designed,
okay? I
Yeah, yeah, I would recommend it, you
know. Um You know, like which one to
choose, you know, like some people
always, you know, they have a sense.
They want to ask you, "Okay, so which
one in your opinion? I want to hear your
opinion, you know, which one is the
best?" You know,
"Which one is the best?" You know, and
then don't give me like general generic
um
reviews. I want to I want you to tell me
which one you think is the best. You
know, a lot of people will want to ask
me that. But actually that that
question, you know, it's dramatic
question and it cannot be answered
because there are lots of variables. I
mean, the the answer is it really
depends on you. Like uh do you want it
to be portable? I mean, is it you know,
like
so many issues, you know, depends on the
person. How big is your hand, you know?
I'm I'm a Asian, so maybe you are a
white guy or black guy. You you you have
basketball hands, you know? Or maybe you
are a Asian female, then your hand is
even smaller than me, you know? Even a
centimeter difference in length matters,
you know? So,
depends on your hand size, depending on
whether you want it portable. Do you
prefer it to be very compact, you know,
like this, you know, uh or do you
actually love to have, you know, like
this one, you know, or this, you know,
this Kinesis, you know, humongous? Do
you care about the curved surface? I
mean, does that really matter to you?
You know, some of these questions, you
know, like then you can assign a score
to how important is each of these
questions. So, there's no like one
absolute answer. And how how
programmable do you want it to be? Like
this one is truly the most uh
programmable
of them all, okay? It's, you know, this
one. I have this one.
Uh I did a review like in my videos, you
can see.
Uh and videos here. If you go to my
website, Kinesis blog, you can see, you
know, you can watch the videos. It's not
showing here because I have JavaScript
off. So, anyway, so this one is the most
programmable. If you want the, you know,
program keyboard macro more than macros,
because all of these
uh this this
Wait, this this this
this this, you know, lots of them all
support keyboard macros, but there's a
difference when you actually go into
detail, like what what kind of macros or
how kind of You know, I'm not going to
talk about that in detail because I do
have articles here that goes into
detail. And also, uh some of them
features driverless programmability,
meaning that you don't need Like
typically, you have to to program the
keys, you have to fire up, launch a uh
software, you know?
And uh so, for example, this one,
but some of them, for example, this one,
Kinesis, you do not need that.
You you want to program the keys, you
just like right now, I can just press
the keys and program a macro or swap or
remap keys, you know? I don't have to
launch a software. And that is just a
wonderful feature. You know, it doesn't
matter you are Linux or Windows or
you know, Mac whatever operating system
you want to
you know,
you know, for example today you feel
like you know, swapping the caps lock to
something to old you know, or control
whatever or VI's escape you know, you
can just like I can just do it now you
know.
So that's that's really
a very great feature and and that
feature is in Kinesis but however
in both of these Kinesis but however
it's not it's not in ultimate ultimate
hacking keyboard.
You know, so portability programmability
how how it is the interface to program
the keyboard
whether it's open source, you know, for
example keyboard.io ultimate hacking is
open source
but the others are not.
You know, so all these is a question you
want to ask you know, yourself how
important it is to you.
You know, so there's no one answer about
which one is the most
the best you know. And also
this S Rail you know,
this one is $500.
$550 something like that $500 and you
have to
it's it's from Japan okay.
And they also have you know, just
English versions but it's $500.
You know, is that worth it you know, so
it's up to you.
And this Mo Tron is also $500 you know.
Uh
so if you want to factor in the price
then that also makes a
you know, really big difference because
this Microsoft Sculpt
it's not programmable and you know, it's
you know,
and they but it's only $70 you You you
can buy it you don't like it throw it
away, you know? And it's it's pretty
good design, you know?
Um
So, if you fact and also this Ergo Now,
if you don't care about uh tenting,
which is, you know, uh have your hands
uh like that
like instead of flat. If you don't care
about that
then you can go for the Ergo, which uh I
also have it, which is also excellent.
It's also uh programmable. Um
Yeah, so that's, you know
But if you do care about tenting, then
maybe you want to go for uh this Mistel
Mistel Barocco, which is also
uh not very expensive, 150, something
like that, okay? Check out it you know,
by the way, if if you like my review
you uh buy them on my Amazon link, okay?
Support me.
So, anyway, so uh
So, they are so So, they are, you know,
all these features. You really have to
look for yourself, okay? Uh
And okay, about Keyboard.io, I have I
have like I do have one complaint.
You know, in general uh the
What what I like about keyboard is like
I want them to be efficient and and also
in a sense of being economic.
Like like economic in a sense of can be
mass produced and and not elaborate, not
baroque, not you know, highly decorated.
I don't like those things. For example
for comparison, you know, cars. You
know, Honda Civic, which is a cheap car,
mass produced, you know?
And compared to, let's say, Lamborghini,
okay? Lamborghini is this extremely
fancy car.
Now, which one is efficient? Well,
depends on what you mean by efficiency,
you know?
Obviously, Lamborghini is not efficient
in many ways.
It gas, it cannot be mass produced, you
know, it's expensive to produce, and you
know, it's expensive to maintain, and
it's not actually practical. You know,
on the other hand, Honda Civic, it's
cheap, it's, you know, well-made, it's
well-designed, it runs, you know, you
know, it's practical. So,
of course, if you have money, or I mean,
even
if you if you
uh look at these two cars, uh and if you
forget about price, forget about how
they how how they can be mass produced,
if you only look at the
the, for example, the advancement of the
engineering, the engine, the power, you
know, the horsepower, the speed, and all
that, you know, obviously, Lamborghini
is the better one, you know.
But, that's if you, you know, if you
ignore the, you know, price and, you
know, all the the other issues. So, in
general, I don't like those uh
Lamborghini, you know, those
too fancy and elaborate and specific
kind of uh design as as as far as
engineering concerned is concerned. You
know, I'm a nerd, right? I'm a
programmer, so I'm I'm concerned about
engineering, but I'm also concerned
about efficiency in many aspects. I want
I want the most elegant design. I want
But, meanwhile, it must be also the most
most simple that can have effect on on,
you know, huge scale.
So, you know,
in other words, if you look at the
world, you know, the human uh
wellness, you know, affairs,
obviously, the Honda Civic makes makes a
huge more
uh impact to the welfare of humanity
than the Lamborghini, you know.
So, So one point of view, okay? But, but
it's not to say I don't care about
design. No, I I want the most elegant
and best design and most efficiency as
well. But anyway, another aspect to
another analogy is, you know, look at
the all those
Baroque buildings. Let me go to Let me
show you some of the um
uh
Let me give you another analogy about
different aspect of design.
Okay, I got that that uh that that's a
sculpture in China from 1970s
uh
1700s.
Uh Ming Dynasty. That's a sculpture.
Anyway, so I want to go to
uh architecture um
um
So, let me give you some examples of
design, you know,
about judgment of elegance, about the
choices, about uh judgment of
aesthetics. Uh you know, like we are
talking about how to choose a keyboard.
But in relation, let me talk about, you
know, how do you judge? You know, what
is What is efficient? What does
efficiency mean? What What does uh
beauty aesthetic mean? Okay. So, one one
aspect is you see these old churches.
They are extremely expensive to build
and elaborate. Look at the ceilings, you
know,
uh incredible ceilings and every detail.
You see the windows, you know, so those,
you know,
You know, so this is also
you know, beautiful and but it's very
elaborate. You know, the word is
Baroque. It kind of like one of the word
to describe it. And also like the
grandfather clock, you know, it's a
wooden, it's it's carved. It's carved
by, you know, well-known sculptors, some
some of the grandfather clocks. It's
very intricate, you know, built by the
most
talented craftsmen, you know.
So, you got grand grandfather clock as
compared to, you know, a digital clock,
you know, $5 cheap digital clock.
So, anyway, so so one aspect is this
baroque design and expensive, you know.
On the other hand, on the other extreme,
you have the most modern
like technological um
thing, you know, this this
these domes, for example, they are very
cheap to build and, you know, and
they're also beautiful, you know, um
you know, you know, these domes and some
of them, you know, um
obviously, some of them are not
practical, but some of them are, you
know, this one is this one is actually a
high school in USA. Um
but I'm going to I'm giving you some
examples, you know,
um
I mean, you get the idea for you know,
it's like this this one is, you know,
modern you know, buildings, you know,
they are not
they're also beautiful compared to the
old ancient churches and, you know, but
they are like very kind of efficient and
minimal and, you know,
so, in general,
okay, just in general, I I like them all
because, you know, they are art, but I
like the
you know, I kind of prefer the
technological
ones,
you know, the efficient, minimal, and
can be mass-produced, okay.
So, that's that's about that. Now, so
let's go back to keyboard, okay.
So, about the keyboard IO,
I think it's very well designed and
but in the beginning, you know, it took
them a long long time to make it. Took
them like 3 years.
Let's see. Am I Am I still alive? Yes.
Yes. Okay, keep the comments coming,
okay? So, I like so I I think it's well
designed, but it turns out the guy
he
you know, in the in the beginning I
thought it's going to be, you know,
mass-produced very great, you know,
design, you know, for all the people.
But it turns out they went into this
rather baroque approach, like luxury
item.
So, you know, they
Yeah, it's well designed. They they pay
attention to every detail, you know,
every details of it.
Uh
but they turns out, you know, they the
design they they kind of the direction
of design they went into this elaborate
uh not for the masses, you know, this
elaborate design. And for example, look
at their
look at their uh
you know, the legs for the keyboard.
They came up with this elaborate
octo feet.
Octo feet, you know? So, this thing is
like this you got this
uh large-ish size keyboard and it's made
of wood, made of wood. I I don't like,
you know, I don't like made of wood, you
know? So, it's made of wood and uh
so that means, you know, they
is kind of it's more expensive to
produce, you know? If you read their
blog, you know, this he also
write a lot blog in their process of
creating this
keyboard and company, you know, how
how they go to China, they have to get
factories to make it, the stories, you
know, you know,
and it turns out actually they got
cheated by one of the person,
a female, a girl, a woman,
they, you know, who
cheated their money like tens of
thousand dollars. Anyway, so anyway,
they, you know,
so the keyboard IO went into this
elaborate design and, you know, this
keyboard legs, you know, they came up,
you know, like it's like they they
studied all ways to create keyboard legs
and eventually they they decided they
they want this octo feet and to me
I don't, you know, I don't really
I don't like it, okay, as a direction of
aesthetics. I mean, this is like it's
not
um it's not practical. I mean, you got
this huge thing, you know, attached to
the bottom. And by the way, it's also
the way it works is that so you got this
huge um
static
block. Like it's like a brick, okay? And
you you put it on a desk on the top,
it's like
uh
uh slanted. It's a slope. Uh look at
this picture, okay? So it's it's sloped.
Then you uh put a screw uh into the
keyboard. So when the keyboard is
attached to it, the keyboard will be uh
slanted like a slope.
Um
that's how it is, you know, inclined. So
by this design, you cannot actually
adjust the incline nation, you know?
Um
you know, and it's not
you cannot also
uh this oriented you know, basically you
cannot adjust it, you know, and
so to me that's a
that's not that's not optimal design,
you know, as far as, you know, the
science, the art of design goes, it's
not optimal. But
somehow to them
you know, they they they decided this is
this is the best for stability, for
whatever, you know, they decided this is
the I mean they they too, you know, they
they look at every aspect of design and
they
they end up with this. So, but I don't I
don't think this this is the you know
great design as far as the design goes.
But but overall the product, you know, I
think it's good.
So, that's all I have to say, you know,
um
about the Keyboardio.
Okay, I kind of actually talked a lot
about the keyboard topic. But originally
I want to talk about this um there's
actually one more thing I want to talk
about. Uh let's see, keyboard from
keyboard do-it-yourself. This Ergo Rock
what? Okay, Ergo Rock keyboard.
Now, I want to talk about uh there's an
issue about uh this going crazy, okay?
There's a actual issue. Let me read the
comments. Um
Uh Victor says,
"It looks cool but not practical. Having
Having glue in your design is
impractical."
Uh the Keyboardio
they I don't think you need to glue. I
mean, there's no glue, right? I mean, I
don't Yeah, so I mean, there's you don't
have
you don't you don't have to glue it.
It's just a screw, right? Yeah, but
um
I mean,
you probably do not mean you have to
glue. I mean, maybe you meant that, you
know, the fact that you have to screw
them.
Oh, the feet are glued up. Okay.
So, let's see.
Uh
let's see, where is it? Do it uh
Fun Keyboards. Yeah, I suppose so so I
guess it's uh
where is it? Uh wait.
Um
ergonomic keyboard.
Uh keyboard IO
Yeah, so I guess you you are right. They
the
Yeah, the uh they require Yeah, I mean
so
So they went into the elaborate design,
you know,
uh
I mean it's not simple, you know. I
prefer things that the design I prefer
design that are simple. So they they
didn't choose that route.
Anyway, let's go back to the um ErgoDox
okay. Now this is getting too crazy,
okay. Many of these designs. Now for the
curved surface
that's already, you know, getting into
um kind of fancy, you know, which I
actually use. But I think this is great.
Actually I I love the Dactyl.
You know, I I I I do not have Dactyl,
but I tried it for 5 minutes and to me
and my hands I it's actually the best,
okay. I I find the Dactyl uh more
comfortable than than the uh
the Truly I mean the Kinesis I'm using
right now.
So uh so Dactyl is a great one, okay. Um
So Dactyl is a great one. Now some of
these designs they become so fancy,
okay. Uh you know, the ErgoDox is is is
a example. By the way
And so when you go into this degree,
actually I don't think you you you come
to a point you you are crossing a
boundary, okay. You are crossing a line.
You are crossing a line such that
I think they're uh altern- alternative
entirely different designs that's not
keyboard, okay. That's much more
efficient, okay.
By the way, it's not easy to learn these
things, you know. As you know, I mean
even even for the curved surface, it
will take you 1 month to adjust your
muscle memory to actually type on this.
So, for vast majority of people, notice
that vast majority, they don't even care
for split. They are, you know, they are
just happy with this normal PC keyboard.
You know, if you go to the, you know,
Reddit, you know, uh
mechanical keyboard uh
forum room, you might the vast majority
there are just happy with, you know,
these PC normal keyboards.
Then, you go up next level you have
these, which is, you know, if you have
hand pain, you know, which is still, you
know, good, which is works great, you
know, all these.
Then, then you get
get into the next level the
um
you know,
this extreme and also the key mouse,
okay?
Um
They I think they are crossing a
boundary where
it's not actually, you know, it will
take a month or
to adjust uh your
you know, to learn to use it. And but
also at that at that level, okay, I
think there are much more better
alternatives. Let me show you.
Uh let me show you the few examples of
coded keyboard, okay?
Because I I have studied them, you know,
I have studied all these
uh keyboard. So, coded keyboard, there
are a lot variations. And also, there's
another one
uh you probably uh heard of like Anyway,
coded keyboard, which is entirely
different level, okay? Because at this
point, you are not just pressing keys.
You want you you press codes. And in
fact,
co- co- uh co- coding keyboard is
actually uh
one magnitude more efficient than
than all of these uh you know non-coded
keyboard.
So, and over the past, you know, 30
years, there are many uh designs for
coded keyboards. Some of them are
commercial, for example, this one. But
they they they are failures. They never
made uh made it, you know, they never
became popular, then the company closed
up.
So, anyway, I was saying, so when you go
into this level of craziness, you know,
you begin you you are crossing a line
because they are quite a
you are crossing a boundary into the
different input systems such as coded
keyboard. Those are a magnitude more
efficient than than these, okay?
Uh truly, okay? They are a magnitude
more efficient, meaning you you will
type, you know, uh 200 words per minute,
you know,
or beyond. And it's also easier for your
hands as well. Uh but but of course,
depends on which which exactly which one
is the design. This one is not good,
okay?
And then, you have the stenotype
machine, which is also a coded keyboard.
Uh
So, you know, you you could buy these,
you know, this this machine because they
are a niche uh market, so they cost like
a thousand, two thousand dollars.
But if you actually spend, you know, go
spend a month, you know, you buy this,
you spend a month or two months to
master it,
you know, you'll be far more efficient,
you know, like a magnitude, like you
know, like twice as fast as you type.
Or or more comfort, you know,
uh than any of any of these uh any of
these fancy ergonomic uh ones.
Okay, that's uh
then there's a stenotype, but that's not
it. Okay, then there's the historical
this one is still in use. There's a
piano keyboard, okay.
I'm going to show you some examples.
For example, this one if actually um
you actually use a piano keyboard to
type and uh and there's a this
researcher who created this uh called
piano keys. You can
uh it will work. You know, you you will
um let me let me go to the uh YouTube so
you can see.
Okay, for for so for example, she has a
video showing you actually using a piano
to type uh text.
And you can read the PDF. You know, you
can learn it. You know, so so you spend
uh you you
you uh you spend like
$300 or something to buy a piano
keyboard or a controller, then you spend
like two or three months
to learn.
Excuse me.
The piano input system.
And in my opinion, okay, I have studied
them uh but not actually I have I have
not actually learned the piano key
system. But from my study about input
systems, fingering efficiency,
you know, in my judgment, this will be
far more efficient. Anything coded is
one magnitude more efficient than than
the sequential key input, okay. So, if
you you know, so spend $500 to to buy a
really good quality
uh
the so-called uh these are called um
um
uh MIDI devices. Uh they they are called
controllers, okay. In the music in the
industry, they are called MIDI
controllers. Anyway, you buy a piano
keyboard.
Uh, 300 is a good one, okay? Or 200.
Uh,
uh, dollars.
Uh, hold on a second. Ah?
Ah?
Hold on a second. There's something
knocking at the Sorry.
Hold on a second. I'll be right back.
My roommate is back and she just knocked
my
on my door for fun.
So, uh, I was talking about this. So,
um, yeah, so you spend like $300 to get
a really quality,
um,
uh, MIDI controller. Let's see. Am I Am
I still
Am I doing good, guys?
Comment, okay? So, you spend $300 to get
a, uh, really good,
uh, MIDI controller, okay? Like this.
It must be good because piano keys, just
like, you know, computer keyboard keys,
the tac tactile sensation is matters
greatly, just like mechanical keyboard,
you know? Like, you know, it matters
significantly.
So, you want to get a good, um,
you know, like $300 get get yourself a
good MIDI controller. That's so called
MIDI controller.
Okay? Then you spend 2 months to learn
the, uh, piano key system. Uh,
you will type a magnitude better. But, I
mean, all these things got problems
because then,
you know, are you going to put the piano
in your work? You know, you're going to
have that issue.
You know, it's going to be weird and and
then you have you you have to look into
portability issues. For example,
that is too big, you cannot carry it
around. Then you have to look into maybe
uh buy these smaller ones.
You know, uh
but that's research, you know, you have
to you know, start to do research. So,
but if you are truly
interested in keyboard efficiency, you
know, on you know, the input system
design, uh
like this guy, you know, ErgoDox.
Forget about this ErgoDox, you know, you
want to uh look you want to get into
this you you want to jump beyond, you
know, the sequential keys. This is
actually far more efficient. And for the
same energy, you know, the guy who built
this, you know, maybe he spent a year to
study, you know, design it, it's wasted,
okay? It's
relatively wasted. You want to spend
that that year
uh investing in this piano keyboard
because in my opinion, it's going to
it's just going to blow away the
sequential systems. By the way, it's it
also With this system, you you can also
do control uh C, control uh you know, X
uh shortcuts, you know, you can, you
know, you just have to It's you know,
it's just part of the research.
So, you have these uh piano key, then
you have this one. This one is By the
way, uh there's a uh kind of a niche
community who are using these. Very
efficient, you know, there are different
input systems people have designed, you
know, um
you know, again, it's a coded keyboard.
You know, so at the point So, so my my
point here is
you know, when when you are at the level
when you spend this much time to create
this kind of crazy keyboard. Uh
in my opinion, it's it's not you know,
it's inefficient. It's it's wasted.
So, I think that actually that that
covers what I want to say, concludes the
topics about this Ergo Warp keyboard. Um
you know, you can read you know, so I
have these articles. You can read the
details why they are efficient, you
know, and and so on. By the way,
you know, to
if you are using a
for example, piano keyboard or if you
are using a you know, stenotype. By the
way, they they do not actually require
you to spend more time to learn than
these, you know.
Because actually
touch typing itself, it takes actually
takes a long time to learn. Because for
example, she uh this guy this girl
who created this um
uh who created this uh pia
what what's her name? She's got name
piano key, I think.
Piano text, okay? She created this piano
text.
She she's a researcher in uh in input
systems. So, she has you know, research
into study, you know, compared to how
long does it take to learn this piano
text system
compared to how long does it take to
learn a normal touch typing on a normal
PC keyboard?
And uh
so, the time spent is the piano text
system is not greater. It's actually not
greater than the uh
than touch typing.
You know,
this may sound uh surprising to us
because it's really because habit, you
know, because we are all used to the
keyboard. So, we are, you know,
accustomed accustomed to it, you know,
so we think
you know, touch typing is no big deal.
We can type stuff, but actually
it really took us, you know, I've been
typing for like more than for 30 years
actually, literally. I have been touch
typing since 1987, you know, 30 years of
practice. So,
and you know,
so it's actually not takes more time.
The only difference is it's it's it's
just like it's new. So, you know, like
everything when we perceive things,
everything we judge
huge part of it is because habit, you
know.
It's like if you go to a different
country and start to live in China, for
example, you you will begin to have a
culture shock, so-called culture shock,
because people do things differently
than you. They think differently, you
know, then you have to spend, you know,
a few weeks to learn chopsticks, you
know, that. So, anyway, so that's
that's that.
So, I think that concludes that topics.
And so, I have been talking for over an
hour now.
Yeah, I can I kind of actually talked
about a lot about keyboard. And I think
maybe that's it for today.
So, today's topic is just about
keyboard. Um
So, comment. This is a good time to
comment. So, so any other questions? Um
I'm going to read the comments, okay?
So, any any questions or any other
topics you want me to go into? Actually,
I want to
Yeah, so comment, okay? Let me know.
Yeah, there are a few things I want to
talk about as well, but
yeah, maybe I'll save it. I'll save it
next time. But, I think actually I think
tonight
I'm going to do another style talk show.
Um
you know, I I I think it's better where
each talk talk show I discuss just one
topic.
So, any questions? Come on, guys. Five
people watching. So, let me read the
comments.
So,
So, have you tried using stenograph? No.
Uh I saw some guys on YouTube who used
it to write programs. So, it seems fast
and efficient, but it's probably very
hard to use. No, I haven't used it
because but actually my opinion of that
is do not I do not recommend it, okay?
Uh I do not recommend it.
Here's he Here is the thing. Uh let me
let me show you uh why.
Now, if you are uh going to learn
stenotype and if you are using steno
machine,
I recommend it. I highly recommend it.
Do it, you know? S- spend a thousand or
two thousand to buy the steno machine,
okay? And
and start to use it, you know, research,
you know, use learn it, spend, you know,
two one month to learn and research it,
you know, learn it, and use it so that
you can use it to program, you know, for
programming and whatever you uh you
write. I
I do recommend steno machine. But
however,
when people uh talk about uh you know,
these keyboard enthusiasts,
uh you know, the keyboard fans, when
they are talking about steno machine,
they are not talking about, you know, uh
buying a steno machine. They are talking
about
uh
do-it-yourself. They are talking about
using a normal keyboard, like a normal
computer keyboard to do steno
stenograph. Like they are talking about
this, using a plank keyboard.
Let me show you videos. Like there are
people doing it.
Okay, there's this woman who created
this stenograph system called plover.
Okay, so plover is a stenograph system
but designed to be used with a normal PC
keyboard. Like you know, she's got a
video here and she's typing
170 words per minute with it, you know.
So
you know, she's starting this movement
to use normal computer keyboard,
including PC keyboard, you know. Uh
as a stenograph machine.
No, that's no good. That's that's
idiotic, okay. That's the worst idea,
okay.
Now, the steno machine, the idea of
using a steno machine
is that I mean the the the gist, okay.
Why is it efficient? Two reasons. One,
it's using a uh
phonetic-based input system. You are not
not actually typing letters by letter.
You are typing how the word sounds. So
you you type the phonetic and it you
know
uh words. For example, words is two
two uh phonemes. Words, you know. You
know, so you just type one key, kind of
one code. Instead of instead of w o r d
s, you know, five
uh keys.
So one reason steno
uh machines and with steno- stenograph
system is efficient because
you are using a phonetic system. You
don't actually type, you know, all the
letters. The other reason is because the
code the coded keyboard. And the
keyboard is designed, you you this is
important. It's designed for you to
press multiple keys at once.
Not like control V, like hold down
control, press V, release V, release
control in that order, not like that.
You you press any key
simultaneously, okay? And the keys are
big and and positioned and shaped in
such a way you can easily, you know,
press multiple of them at the same time,
you know, in both hands, you know.
That is why steno machine
uh and with a stenograph input system is
is a magnitude more efficient.
But
when people, you know, when programmer
idiots, when
you know, this
elite hacker groups or your hacker, you
know, when they talk about steno, they
they are talking about using the steno
with plank, you know,
keyboard. It's idiotic.
This is the most
This is the fastest fastest way
to get you into repetitive strain
injury, okay?
Do this, you'll get you'll get hand
pain, you know, in in in in a few
months, guaranteed. Depending on how
much you type. If you are average
programmer, you don't really touch
type that much, this works fine. Like
most programmers look looking at this,
they think, "Oh, this works you know,
this is so great, you know, wow wow
wow." You know, but as soon as you
actually type
nonstop for, let's say, 2 hours a day,
nonstop you're going to get repeated
repetitive strain injury, you know, very
fast in in a few months, in half a year.
Then you're going to go see a doctor.
Then doctor's going to tell you, "Stop
typing now, or you're going to never be
uh
be able to type again."
You're going to
they're going to cut off your
hands. Yeah, do that, you know,
stenograph.
Don't do that. Okay, so don't, you know,
so that's my opinion about this.
So,
about this plover, you know, good.
Uh
So, how are stenographs for programming
something in Lisp like C? Are there any
people that use Yeah, there are some
people I I've known some people actually
um
I know some people do this. For example,
she's one of the example, okay?
Uh she's not a programmer, but I think
she learned
part of it. You can Well, you can I
mean, there's a plover forum, okay?
There's a website. I I think I have a
link here somewhere. You can like, you
know, you can go to their website. They
have discussions, you know, you can
learn about it. But, personally, I I
know
uh an acquaintance or a friend, you
know, uh
uh who does use Let me show you. Let me
talk about that. PC keyboard, Ergo
keyboard.
Um
the Keyboard.io,
okay? Now, Keyboard.io has a great
software and also it's open source
uh for programming the firmware. And I I
kind of know the guy. He's a
acquaintance, friend. Uh he's a great
guy great guy and he's in Germany.
Uh and he has a Mastodon account.
He's active there. And so, he wrote the
software for open source for the
Keyboard.io.
And it's also one of the greatest
programmable firmware software, okay?
It's called
uh Kalida something, okay?
Uh okay, here. I I talked about it. So,
um
But, anyway, the the guy who wrote you
know, who who is part of the team or I
think it's a main guy who wrote this
um
So, that's a guy I know.
Uh
he
kaleidoscope, okay? He has so many
things. I'm not sure which one is it.
But, anyway, he's uh his name is
Acheron.
His nickname his online handle is
something like Acheron.
Uh I don't I don't know how do you Well,
if you look, you'll find it, okay? He
He's online handle is Acheron. And his
his profile photo is kind of a mouse
a mouse head with the with wearing
glasses and typing, you know, a mouse
like cat and mouse a mouse head. You
know, he's he that's his online profile
photo, but he's a
a German guy, I believe. So, anyway, he
he has learned
he has learned the Planck system.
And you know, you using the keyboard.io.
He He's a developer for keyboard.io and
he loves
keyboard.io.
So, um
you know, and he has a blog. He has
written about, you know, I remember
reading his, you know, he like it, you
know, but
yeah, you know,
Okay, so, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Uh yeah, so, I
I think I'm going to do another one
later today, maybe in in 6 hours so.
Um
Yeah, we'll see, you know, that's the
way
I I goes, you know, I'm not
never
you know, things are not planned. So,
but I'm thinking maybe I'll do another
one in 6 hours. So, thank you guys for
coming.
Thank you guys. If you like my stuff,
put money in my pocket, okay? I got
Patreon.
I got
I got Patreon and, you know, PayPal and
stuff and, you know, and it's all over
my website, you know,
the links, Amazon gifts and links and
buy stuff. Buy stuff from my website.
Thank you guys. I see you next time.
Peace and prosper.