Hello guys. Hello guys.
Hello guys. Good morning. Good evening.
Welcome to another episode of Sun Talk
Show.
We are going to
do randomish randomish talk, okay? My
keyboard, this is ultimate hacking
keyboard, UHK80.
And this is Nulia trackball, N U L E A.
Nulia, what is it?
M505.
Okay, fantastic. This is Logitech
uh G502, fantastic.
I have reviews on my YouTube for them,
okay? So,
we're going to do randomish. Mostly, I'm
going to code. I'm going to code Emac
Lisp
uh programming language, and I'm also
going to code possibly Wolfram language.
Uh so, I'm just going to do my work.
This is my office hours.
You are here. If you are here, say hi.
You can just watch me
do my work, or you can ask me questions.
Post your questions in the comment.
If you are watching this offline, play
at 1.5 speed, okay?
Uh play at 1.5 speed or twice as fast.
Let me have my coffee.
Okay, so
today
uh there's always a lot work to do.
Um in this AI age, you know, personally
for me, I got lots of things
I need to do Wolfram language coding,
but also
study proof theory since so on.
By By the way, the thumbnail you are
looking at is
AI generated. You know, it's funny. It
says,
"Do what I want, stupid robot." You
know, so AI generated.
Hot girls fighting.
Okay, so that is from Twitter.
From a Twitter post someone did.
So, AI is becoming incredible, of
course.
The AI can write poems, can write code,
can um can generate artwork or cin-
cinema
uh cinematographic
um
like Hollywood
style movies.
So, where is it? So, let me show you.
Okay, so
uh
that animation. Yeah, there's quite a
few. There's actually tons.
So, the one in the thumbnail you are
looking at is this one. Okay, let's
Let's play it. Why not?
Okay, it's amazing.
Fantastic. Now, this screen stuck.
Let me unstuck it. Actually, it's stuck.
It's good.
Wait. Did it
It's stuck. Yeah. Okay.
So, notice it's girls, of course. Hot
girls showing their
legs and feet and tits
and fighting.
Of course, in real life, you girls, they
are never warriors.
Girls, they are not soldiers, they are
not warriors, they are not fighters.
Uh
almost never. I mean, rarely,
occasionally, you might have one.
In like one among a million.
But, usually not.
So, but however, it's a
men's fantasy
to have girl warriors, girl soldiers,
and
lots of like like all the like all the
games, you see all the female
characters, fighting games, or whatever
games. All the female characters, they
are like all fantasy.
And also,
yeah, well, anyway.
But, um
what you know, so
so one you know,
also this is true in Chinese kung fu
movies. Like in kung fu movies, you
often see
uh
Chinese women.
You know, and and you know, they they
doing great kung fu. But, that's not
reality, okay?
Like real reality, and it became
apparent in USA in the past 10 years.
We can see because of the trans
movement.
You know, girls in
in terms of their physical capabilities
compared to men,
they are not comparable at all.
Because you can see in the trans
movement, you know, the trans, they bre-
broke the record of all female sports in
like everywhere.
Well, these trans men, they are like
at the lower bottom of of ranking among
males.
But, if if they compete with women, they
they break the all the women's records
in every sport.
So so so that kind of folks, you know,
that that shows the reality of all these
female warriors and female right
fighters. They they don't exist.
And also um
you see also in in boxing, for example,
in real life boxing um
you know, we have heavyweight,
lightweight, whatever classes. And also
um
M MMA um
multi-style martial art competition,
something like that.
You know,
there's also female competition, female
versus female, but
but female, they are basically no match
for males.
Physically, at least.
Um so
this is important because I think
because
we we don't, you know, we like in modern
society, we forgot lots of things, like
lots of things we don't know.
For example, you don't even know how to
kill a cow or a pig or chicken for that
matter. Like you don't know. You don't
know how to but you do eat chickens and
beef and pork, you know, you you enjoy
them. You have to eat them. Like like
almost you have to.
But you forgot how to kill them.
Someone else do it, of course.
Uh so that's the situation of modern
society.
Um
there's good, there's bad. So it's by
the way, it's not some old you know,
it's therefore something something. It's
not
some magical theories. It just
you know, some of the fact of how things
are.
Okay, that's that's about that
thumbnail.
So,
okay, so actually
you know, what one of the issue with
doing streams is that like usually every
day I have a lot of work to do.
But, when I do stream
if I just get on to do my work
then the video is very boring because
you don't know what I'm doing, you know,
you just you know, like it's became
very it is very boring.
But,
if I do explain and make it interesting,
for example, I want to explain for
example, there's this Emacs task Emacs
Lisp.
So, for those of you
well, I have to kind of explain what is
Emacs, the most powerful editor for you
programmers.
You know, some of you use Vim or NeoVim
or VS
Excuse me, VS Code. Right? So, I I have
to like today this fewer and fewer
people use Emacs. So, I have to tell you
what it is for especially for the young
people, you know, the young people who
got nothing to do that's
likely that that's that's that's the
like the majority of audience watching
YouTube actually are these young people.
Because when you are young, you have
lots of time, you know, you you go to
school, but you have lots of time. You
do random things. You watch videos.
But, when you are older usually you
know, you have a job. You get tired
coding at a job. You don't watch videos
or you have a family. You need to take
care of lots of things. So,
it's mostly younger people watch. So,
you know, younger people you may not
know what is Emacs, so I have to
explain.
Then Emacs Lisp even rare
people
know about it. Then I have to explain
what
So anyway, my point is that so when you
do a live stream
if I do my if I just do my work work
work on my website, the video is very
boring. But if I start to explain
then I cannot do work. I you know, there
actually
there's no serious work done. So I just
end up talking to you guys is what this
is about
along the way
for 1 hour.
But I don't I didn't you know, I don't
actually do any
not many not much progress in what I
need to do.
So for example, that you know,
for example, here is example HTML
opening browser. So for example
this Emacs for example, I can press a
key
that will show the current buffer or
page untitled
file well titled file save. It'll show
the current file in a browser, right? So
you can see.
And so so what so how does that work?
Well, that is actually because I have
written a command called
cxhtml-open-in-browser.
Okay. So I can describe key then I can
show you. So here is a command
cxhtml-open-in-browser.
And this file cxhtml-mode.el.
So let's open it. So here is a source
code you are looking at uh
2,000
you know, 3,000 lines of code
uh for that file, but actually there is
um
you know, there's actually several
files. So altogether there may be 10,000
lines of code
for my HTML mode.
So anyway, back to the so close it close
it. So, anyway, so I'm saying so I got
this command that opens the current file
in browser, okay? Switch back. Now, but
I want to make a modification. I want to
make it so that whenever I have a source
code
Let me explain. Okay, so let me explain
what I'm doing this.
Um
So, what is this? Uh
so
office hour so actually you need to
Where is that?
Okay, so it's actually here.
Okay, so I have another command that is
size HTML re HTML-ize
pre code buffer. What does that mean?
Let me show you, okay? So, you see
basically whatever I do, it will take
like 5 minutes or even 10 minutes
simply to explain it.
Then, wherever you are watching
uh you won't you will find it
interesting.
You know, for
for example, I have to explain for
example, what what it what does, you
know, I explain I got, you know, HTML
mode. I showed you the source code.
That's what this command do, show in
browser, right? I have to demonstrate
it. But then, I'm saying that it should
automatically call this command. But
what does this command do?
I have to explain. So, let me do a demo
because
doing a demo is easiest. For example, I
start a pre tag, let's say
uh let's say JavaScript, okay? So, I
have a
pre class JavaScript, then
copy it out, then console logs three,
okay? Run it.
You can see I can create a JavaScript
kind of file
and I can run the code. It prints three.
This is JavaScript code and I put it put
it back. So, you can see I can create
this
free tag of the class JavaScript of a
programming language. You see? So, now
I'm showing browser, you can see scroll
down, you can see you got this you see
JavaScript code embedded code in HTML.
This is all
um
org-mode
So, you may So, so then what? So, but
let's say for example pre So, pre log,
let's say ampersand. So, let's say I
want to say this char
uh
is called
ampersand in English.
Okay? We are talking about that
character. You see? Ampersand. So, run
it.
It works. You see? This is JavaScript
code. Now, put it back.
Now, showing browser.
Um Okay, still works, but let let let's
see let's say I want to do this
Uh let's say I want to say in HTML
to create a paragraph
you have to type
uh
>> [sighs]
>> like this.
Okay? Then put it
Okay, let's say
Okay, in HTML to create a paragraph you
have to type, you know, that that that.
Okay? Now, run it. You see this is valid
JavaScript
code, right? Now, put it back.
Uh put it back. Okay, now showing
browser.
Now, you look at the code. The The code
now is [ __ ] up.
You see, it says in in HTML to create a
paragraph, you have to type
what? Empty.
You see, it's it's You see?
Why is that? Because this P is
interpreted as HTML tag. So, in other
words,
in the inside this pre tag,
you need to escape these HTML tags,
right? So,
how do you do that? Well, there are many
ways, but one of the easiest way I have
this command. Press press press. You
see, it become that. So, that command is
called "counsel HTML re-HTML-ize
pre-code buffer".
Meaning that every pre
tag in in the file,
they will be
re-HTML-ized, meaning syntax colored.
So, any special
um tag or characters, such as ampersand,
they will be escaped like this. So, you
see, this is called HTML entities.
So, that LT means less than
symbol.
Then P, then ampersand GT means greater
than. So, that is basically,
you know, the
less than P, then greater than. Like
bracket.
So, anyway, now, this Now, you go back
to the browser and you refresh here.
Watch here. Refresh. See? Now, it's
good. You see? In HTML to create a
paragraph, you have to type that that
like this, right?
So, now you understand
there is this command.
Uh this command is called
uh here.
Sign HTML
pre-code buffer. That means
check the current file
whenever there is pre something
uh,
basically syntax color it, okay, and
also escape the
the,
um,
entities.
So,
so now it makes sense. You see, now so
in Emacs
add a hook to SiCHTM mod mode. So, when
SiCHTM open in browser command is called
which is this one, okay, open in browser
command is called, automatically
do call the command SiCHTM re-HTMLize
pre-code buffer.
Why do you want to do that? Because if
you forgot to,
you know,
let's say I'm doing a demo, I finish it,
put it back,
put it back, you know, I don't I didn't
I forgot to,
you know, encode this,
then I go to sleep, you know, but if you
show this in browser, obviously it's
wrong.
You see?
So,
so what I want to do is that, you know,
make the command so whenever you show it
in browser, it make automatic
automatically do that.
Right? So, that's the idea.
But you see, no, so
so if if, you know, I'm doing this by
myself, I just, you know, I just do it,
I finish in 5 minutes.
But if I do a live stream,
it kind of actually takes 10 minutes to
explain it already.
But then you guys
may find it interesting, you know,
especially Emacs users. So, you know,
you you can see, oh, so that is why you
need to do this. And how do you do it?
We haven't done that yet. So, so we need
to do that. Then I'm going to explain,
okay, so that's we haven't done that
yet.
So, anyway, but so far I'm just
explaining how
about the process of
of doing live stream versus um
versus just coding, you know,
like this this issue which I wrote I
posted a blog about here.
Uh matter of fact, let's see uh shift
shift uh control I mean control
scroll up magnify, you see.
Problem with live stream is that if I
actually do work, the video is very
boring.
If I talk about interesting things of
what I am doing, such as programming
language design issues, why you need to
do it, and how to do it, things like
that, then
then I wouldn't get serious coding done
because it's just me explaining it
became
like a tutorial, like a lecture.
So, you see, so there's this dilemma
because usually I don't like to do the
you know, I don't like to do tutorials,
like you know, well
because tutorials usually they are few
reasons, usually they are pre-recorded.
Um so, first of all, okay, let me
briefly explain it. Hello
uh
Nanja Han.
>> [clears throat]
>> Let's hope we don't go up
too late.
But if you actually hope you don't go
up, if you you know, you have to be
careful of what you wish for
because
you have to you know, like if there's a
genie or
genie or a god, you can make some wishes
come true.
If that is true, then you actually have
to be careful. Is that really what you
want? You know, hope we don't grow up
because if that comes true, then you may
suddenly realize there's lots of problem
with that. You don't want that. Okay,
like that.
You know, you you want to grow up be
good, you know, you don't want to stay a
kid forever.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh obviously, there are several, you
know, like if you are staying as a kid
forever,
you know, you may be, you know, you
don't have prejudices. You don't have
like worry. You don't have to worry
because your parents provide for you.
You just play every day, right? But but
you do have lots of
even as a kid, you do have lots of
stress, too, even as a kid. Because
when you want some candy or toy, you
have to ask your parents and sometimes
your parents says no. Then you cry, but
there's nothing you can do like and also
sometimes what happens, you know, when
you have your parent is not a good one.
It does happen.
In fact, often.
So, that mean also called abusive
parents or you know, like we
like when we are child, we don't know
what's a parent, what's a adult, but
eventually, you know, pretty soon we all
became a adult and we know we don't know
[ __ ]
Like do you Do you know you how to raise
a child? You don't know.
So, when you raise when you actually
have a child, which which does happen,
you know, for most of us,
you don't know you don't really know
what like what is a proper way to
parenting, you know. So, often or half
of the time you make mistakes. You you
did things that
you know, that's not good.
Uh you know,
and that's for good people. Then on the
other hand, there are bad people. Like
for example, you got robbers, you got
thieves, you got
all sort of evil person, right? You They
cheat or they lie or whatever.
And those people, they have kids, too.
So, they don't care, they know they
abuse their kids or even sell them or
whatever.
Right? So,
So, when you make wish, I mean
So, I mean the common saying
like you know, let's wish, you know, we
don't become we don't grow up, you know,
like
you know, if it become true,
it may actually be problematic, so
So, that's a a part of like a bit of
philosophy there.
About thinking about all the different
things, okay? So, anyway, we are back to
So, I was
um
you know, like for example, so I wanted
to work on that, so it's okay. Let's do
it. Let me do it.
Okay, so if you are here, say hi, okay?
If you enjoy, you know, whatever you are
watching, just say hi.
Uh otherwise, I'm I'm just going to
code.
Like
I explain if I feel like it, if it, you
know, if it's better. If I did not
explain,
but if you want to know,
any of you can ask.
So, you know, actually, so we got
Actually, I have a lot to do. So, you
know, so there's Emacs coding, right?
So, there's that Emacs coding here.
There's another Emacs coding. This one
is about modify xhtml move image file,
so it
has a random letters letters in file
name, not just hexadecimal. Okay, that's
another Emacs Lisp coding
job.
So, if I do this, it will be of interest
to those of you Emacs users, Emacs fans.
Say hi, okay?
And there's quite a there's other
things. Um there's about polymorphism
in Wolfram language, in Python, in Emacs
Lisp, you know, I can explain.
So, this is about programming language
design and programming practice.
There is this thing called polymorphism,
which is
in my opinion, that's a idiotic jargon
from the
from the industrial coding idiots,
polymorphism. Okay.
That basically means a function
that basically basically means a feature
of a programming language, polymorphism.
A feature of a programming language such
that
when you define a function, the function
can easily
behave
according to
the type of the argument or the number
of arguments.
In other words, the function you can
easily define a function, its behavior
depends on what is the type of the
argument or how many arguments are there
given to the function.
The you know, so if the if the
programming language allows you to do
easy do that, then you say
it's a it supports polymorphism.
Again, now remember again, this is for
function definition, okay? For functions
parameters.
So, we're going to explore like can you
do that in Emacs Lisp or can you do that
in Emacs Lisp? Or at least, can you do
that in Python?
And we ask I I did ask AI, you know, so
I can show you. And also can we do that
in Golang, Go programming language,
okay?
Do you guys know Do you guys know
Do you guys know my work? Like how many
of you guys are here watching?
Um Golang, okay. So I have lots of
tutorials, JavaScript, uh Visual C, C++,
Golang.
So
can you do that in Python?
Can you do that in JavaScript?
Polymorphism. Can you do that in Golang?
And
how do you do that in Wolfram language?
So I can demonstrate that. Okay.
So that is up to you guys. So, you know,
I'm um
So if you guys are here, you if you are
interested in any of these, you want uh
see me
do, and just say, okay? Otherwise, I I
think I'm just going to uh do whatever I
come up across. Um and also there are
some more things to do that I wanted to
do.
Oh yeah, so write the psi HTML ampersand
to end
instead of psi HTML decode ampersand
entity
or in code, so
so that it is that one.
And the other issue about polymorphism
is
what is a better jargon than
polymorphism? Is there a better
terminology
for polymorphism in computer science
programming languages?
Okay. For example, what we can we can
call it argument form dependency,
argument
form dependent.
So, if you say that
I think that's actually more clear
because it when you read this jargon,
arg form dependent, it kind of
Um it kind of tell you what it means
better than polymorphism.
Like big because when you hear
polymorphism, it's like what what is
that? What what polymorphism? Like
multiple forms.
Okay, but but then
argument form dependency might be um
might be more clear. I don't know.
So we can So there are other things, you
know, I'm currently doing about
Anyway, so let me just do a stuff, okay?
So open in HTML browser, HTML
re-HTML-ize,
okay? So copy that command and this five
key, press that key.
Go to the source code.
There it is and all we want to do is add
a hook, okay? So psi-HTML
open in browser hook. So I already got
two hooks. So let's see.
So this is potentially a new one. What
are these?
Okay, so it goes long, so let me expand
the window. So we got
this hook, which is HTML validate HTML
buffer that we want.
Then [snorts] there is this hook clean
white space
we want, but we want the clean white
space first.
Um let's see.
When you add a hook, it's added to the
front. So
Okay, so yeah, so
display HR as line. We don't We don't
want that. HTML add paragraph tags
buffer. We don't want that.
Okay, but
but
Okay, so that's it re-HTML-ize buffer,
okay?
So, basically
do that first.
Clean whitespace and then do that.
Should that Should that be it?
I think so.
So,
this hook is a variable. You can
look at it. It's a variable. So, the
current values are You see, there are
two values there.
Clean whitespace and the validate HTML.
Mhm.
But now, let's kill it. I mean, set it
to nil, okay? Do it.
Now, describe variable, same variable.
Now, the value is nil.
Okay?
Now,
just run this, okay? Run it. Run it.
Run it.
Run it. Okay?
Save it. Now, describe variable
that.
Now, you can see the value is that.
That and that. Okay, [clears throat] so
we added re-HTML-ize pre-code buffer. We
added that, okay?
So, we can uh
call the command. Let me show you this
command. This is VC diff.
Okay? So, do this VC diff.
So, we can see we
we added this line.
And we
well, we just added that line. This is
kind of idiotic.
What this is?
Save.
Do it again.
Yeah.
Right? So, we just basically we just
added that added this line. That's good.
Okay, close. Close. Close.
Now,
so now when we show this file in
browser, you see there's this tag which
is not
encoded to entities. We need to encode
them to entities.
Okay, so but now we're going to show in
browser it will automatically encode
them into entities. Watch.
Show in browser.
You see? So, now look at the browser.
It's good. Now, go back. Go back to
Emacs. You see? Fantastic.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay. That's one thing done.
Fantastic and beautiful. So, this thing
is done.
This thing is done. So, remove the X
office hours. Let's remove that.
Uh
office delete. So, you you see in X HTML
mode, I can press one single key
and remove the corresponding
um
semantic unit and syntactical unit.
That's this
LI which is a list, okay? You see?
Press one key, it's good. Undo. Now, you
can see the command is X smart delete, a
single key, E.
Okay, if my cursor is here, I press the
key, it will delete the entire
list. For example, let me show you.
Closer here. Press, you see, fantastic.
Undo. Okay? So, but now we just want to
remove this part. So, press, you see,
that is gone.
Back to browser.
You see, watch here. Refresh, it's gone.
So, that item is done. What about this?
E-mag this modify X HTML move image
file. So, it adds
a random letter. Okay, let me show you
what that is.
This one, okay? So, I have a command.
So, for example, I write a lot blogs, as
you know. So, I
I want to make a screenshot. Let's say
that.
See?
So, I have it set up, so it opens the
folder. So, there is a screenshot we
just did. Delete it, okay?
Cancel.
Now, let's say let's make some uh more
beautiful screenshots of something.
Click here.
Um is there some like um pretty uh
pretty stuff? Uh see, the the font is
too large.
Smaller, please.
Okay, this guy is like a political
commentator. He's very knowledgeable,
this
guy. He He's uh we call him Professor
Gen.
Okay?
He He is on YouTube. He has a channel
called Predictive History,
which is idiotic sensational name.
Because let me let me tell you guys,
okay? Let me digress, okay? Into this
topic.
Predictive History. First of all, let me
introduce you guys what who he is, okay?
So, about
a year ago or two,
he started to became popular
among the so-called
the manosphere.
Basically, among the
American politics who are talking about
MAGA, Make America Great Again, or
Christianity, or concern about
the other race,
you know, and
you know, that like the political, you
know, talking points, you know, we've
been talking so much about also about
Trump, about the Middle East wars,
um
right?
So, it you know, like
a year or two two ago,
he started to appear, and he's got
YouTube channel Predictive History.
Uh and apparently, so
apparently, he's a Canadian he's
Chinese, of course, Chinese blood in
Canada.
Uh Canadian citizenship or something,
but anyway, the first video I saw of his
in Canada
talking, I think, you know, maybe this
you know, the background is Canada.
Anyway, so he's supposedly like
Chinese
Canadian, and he
And anyway, so he he he have a YouTube
channel Predictive History named That's
a China name.
And what he talks about, he talks about
very knowledgeable guy, okay? This guy
is very knowledgeable guy.
Uh so, I I I've spent by now I I watched
I watched maybe five of his videos.
Like, each one is 1 hour long, or two.
Uh so, I've I I've I spent by now like
maybe 10 or 20 hours watching him. But,
he's got like lots of 10 10s of videos.
like you have to watch him like 50 or
100 hours, okay?
Anyway, so he's got predictive history
channel. The name says that, you know,
he's
So, what he What does he talk about? He
talks about several things, okay?
He talks about mostly history related
Western, you know, okay, let me tell
you. He talks about religion.
Uh history of Western religion.
You know, especially, you know, the the
Abrahamic religions, Christianity,
Islam, and Judaism.
History of Western religion. He also
talks about um
so-called geopolitics of of the current
situation, okay, about Trump.
Uh and uh
religion and and also he talks about um
civilization.
Like the general concept and history of
Western civiliza- civilization, okay?
Like I think almost all the things he
talked about is
the Western part.
Western history, Western religion,
Western civilization, okay? The all the
history of
So, he talks and and what, you know,
what makes a civilization, what makes a
empire rise or fall. He talks about all
these kind of things.
And one of the thing he is saying is
that he's doing uh prediction. He, you
know, he claims he's using game theory.
He is looking at current political
situa- situation, geo you know, doing
analysis of so-called geopolitics
using
from game theory perspectives.
And
then
predict what will happen. Okay? That
that is his
like premises.
That you know, that's why the channel is
called predictive history. And he's
using game theory. You see right in the
title, let's game theory.
So
but it turns out if you watch him, he's
extremely knowledgeable. You know, he
just like he you know, he can talk about
these topics, Western history, religion,
society, civilization.
And also the current political
situation, you know, Trump election and
so on.
The powers in in Middle East and so on.
Uh so I was quite impressed.
Uh you know, so one thing I don't know
much you know, there's a lot of things I
don't know because each each human
animals, you know, you are pretty petty.
Uh looks like I'm losing
watches. But anyway, let me let me talk
about this.
So
so a lot you know, the the
lots of things I don't know, but you
know, what but one thing I don't know is
uh
the basically the Western religion, the
Christianity. I don't know that much
about it, you know.
And Islam. So
so he when he's talking about that, you
know, I learned lots of things. And also
he's not you know, like the typical
educator.
Like I've been living in USA for 30
years or plus or more.
So of course I
you know, you live in USA for long, you
know something about Christianity.
But he's not just like teaching you the
normal Christianity. He's he's telling
you you know, from his perspective,
history of Western civilization,
Christianity
with a twist.
Uh effectively, he ties it to like he
has this kind of
take about
secret societies.
Freemason.
Uh
and what what's the religion that before
Christianity, like the pagan paganism.
Paganism or monoism and also, you know,
relates to monoism, polytheism.
You know, one god or multiple gods. So,
he talks about all these topics.
Uh but he has a particular take.
Basically, he's saying that um
you know, I you know, I don't want to
say what he's saying, but, you know, you
you you you can kind of
watch him talk, okay?
But anyway, so to me I find it very
uh
knowledgeable. He you know, he's a great
educator. So, even if you do not agree,
you may find it very pleasant to listen
through and you will probably learn
many things, okay, from this guy. Even
if you are, you know, a white Christian.
So, anyways, so it's very um uh
I was very um
uh
impressed. You know, very knowledgeable
guy.
But But But, you know, but
his conclusions, I
do not agree at all. I mean, he you
know, like like he he's like
he's like the the heart of his take is
that he believes the world
is going around the way the world
the entire geopolitics moves, the powers
is because there are these
so-called Illuminati or some
uh like like some people will call
globalist, you know.
He actually he you know, he believes
that these they are these people
kind of mystical
uh people that controls the world, okay?
That is actually his like final
conclusion after all his, you know,
his knowledge about civilization about
empires, about history of religions, of
different branches, you know, like
everything, but but at the end he's he
believes that, you know, there's this
Illuminati
that controls the world, which is
So, it makes him like
conspiracy, you know.
Kind of like to me it's you know, if you
ask me, I think it's idiotic. It's like
just pure [ __ ] okay?
It's funny. Pure [ __ ] So,
but not Again, let's go back to the
title, predictive history, okay? That is
a so-called oxymoron.
Okay? You can never predict
anything.
Okay, that is a fact. That that is like
by definition.
You know, you cannot predict. It doesn't
matter, you know, game theory, whatever
[ __ ]
The simple fact is you can never Nobody
can ever predict nothing. Not a thing.
Okay? That is a fact. That is if you
believe sciences, okay?
And you do not believe voodoos, magic,
sorcerers, you know.
Only the sorcerers, you know, or God
they will say, you know, you can predict
something will happen, something will
not happen. The stock is going to go
this way, you need to buy that stock or,
you know,
that's what predict me prediction means.
Science, what about science? Can science
predict? Well, yeah, a little bit. You
know, that that's a key. That's a key
theory about science. You cannot
predict, period.
Okay, nobody can predict what will
happen. You know, you you could in some
scientific way like you we can we can
predict what we what where the tomorrow
will rain. We can predict whether next
week will rain.
But when it gets a bit further like next
month
precisely this time will it rain? We
don't know. Nobody knows, okay? When it
gets further, you know, that's science.
So this So this guy, you know, he came
out like, "Oh, I I'm I'm going to use
game theory. Therefore, I can predict.
My channel is called predictive history.
I'm going to predict everything and the
world is run by Illuminati, you know,
[ __ ]
So to me that's like idiots, okay? But
the white people, the Western society,
the white men, they get excited. Because
the white people they are into this UFO
UFO you know, aliens UFO Illuminati or
these Freemasons, you know, they they
Rosicrucians, you know, they they they
get very excited these Christian people
about this kind of thing. End of the
world like the end of the world
apocalypse like they talked about it all
the time. So anyway, that is my take.
Um I find it kind of silly, okay? It's a
predictive history.
Uh and you know, so what about but he
became
So right now he became very uh kind of
very popular.
You know, he all of a sudden like
to a lot of people all of a sudden. Like
a man, you know, he's being interviewed
on lots of the podcast who's got
millions of followers, several of them.
You know, he got interviewed by them.
But, you know, he went on to Piers
Morgan. Uh
you know, like he appeared on Piers
Morgan's like
yesterday.
Uh and but again, he makes very uh a lot
of his
commentaries
are very interesting, okay? So, he make
a lot very interesting commentaries.
But, I can't you know, I I I I don't
believe these um
these secret societies and mysticisms
and the end of the world, you know, es-
eschatology, you know, the crap.
And predictive history. No, you you
can't predict [ __ ] okay? Nobody can
ever predict [ __ ] That's just a fact.
Okay, you don't predict game theory
[ __ ] Game theory is a math math
mathematical theory and you know, it's
like it doesn't can't predict [ __ ]
So, anyway, that's that is my take about
this guy.
So, Charlie Jack says, "This professor
is a liar. He prays on the ignorant and
feeds them lies. You wouldn't drink
poison water."
I don't think he's lying. You know, I
mean
Okay, on this issue, I don't think
anyone knows. You know, just like a lot
of these politics, you know, like like
Nick Fuentes.
You know, like you are a fed. No, you
are a fed, you know, like
they are you know, like every day, you
know, this this Spider-Man meme.
I I I think nobody knows, okay?
Like he's kind of, you know,
No nobody really knows.
You know, whether he's like
and but I know but he I think he's
lying, you know, because you
you
you can kind of tell.
I mean, you could say maybe he's
like what he mean is that he's like an
agent. He's paid by someone to do this
talk. He's not I mean, but he's not
lying. Like he's not acting but because
you can tell he know the stuff, you
know. It it it looks to me as far as I
can
you know, I my perception. He's like
real.
He know he
he knows the stuff by heart. He can just
tell you right away why he thinks this
way or that way and he believe he is
this he believes in this mysticism. He
has a
complete coherent picture, you know, the
whole Western society and history and
religion
to support his conclusions. So, I don't
think he's like
someone who doesn't know anything, you
know, fed by script or whatever but to
to act. I don't think that's the case.
But is he like
paid?
That become, you know, that then that
becomes very complex because, you know,
because it's very difficult to um
it's hard to even to define what what
you what what mean you know, what is
meant by like an agent or whatever.
Because if you say he's a agent there's
there's there's to me there's there are
many definitions like
is he officially,
you know, worked for worked for some
agency by contract or is he
Anyway, there's a lot of things going
on. So, anyway
I think I digressed a lot about that.
Okay,
I don't want to anyway, so let's go back
to to code. Okay, so anyway, we were
mentioning him.
Um
Okay, let's do a screenshot of this. Uh
So, let's say I do a screenshot.
Okay, so you see it's there. So, I can
um
Press press press press.
And that screenshot
gets moved here.
And it automatically adds these all
these tags. So, you can see you can open
the file. You see, it's there. And it
also automatically do um
optimization
of the image. And also um
removing the metadata, redundant
metadata, and optim- you know, optimize
the PNG, okay? So, you see. So, so
there's a file. So, fantastic. And uh
let's rename it.
Uh
Professor John, okay? And this is PNG.
Let's
convert it to JPEG. You can watch my
pink window to see what command I'm
calling, okay?
Convert to JPEG, okay? Done. You see.
So, it says uh what?
It says
uh
Done. Convert to JPEG.
Um
Original size
100 new size
I mean, 371K. New size 161K.
So, saved half.
From PNG to JPEG, okay? Open it. Good.
Okay, and uh rename this um
this figure caption. So, you can do that
by press press press press. Okay? So,
you got Professor Jen. Now, show this in
browser.
Okay, we got the screenshot here. But,
there's a problem. You see, whenever I
call that command, by the way, that
command is called um
So many command it just um
You see, there a there is convert to
JPEG.
And uh the other command I'm doing I was
um
Uh I'll just show you here. Okay, so
let's see.
Press press press press. So, the command
I was calling was csahtml move image
file. Okay? That command.
Now, when you call that command, it will
move a image file from from your
screenshot directory
to the current file's directory. Okay?
Automatically. So, fantastic.
Also, when it moved the file, it will
automatically attach uh
uh kind of this random
hexadecimal to the end of it.
Okay? So, let's look at the source code.
Okay, that is the command. So,
70 uh 170
about 70 lines of code. Okay?
So,
what I want to do, I want to
add
You see, it adds a
there.
But, I was thinking I don't want a
random hexadecimal.
Let's see.
Okay, so that's a hexadecimal. Press,
press, press. That's a hexadecimal, you
see? These are hexadecimals.
But, what I want I like I think it may
might be better if I uh
have a
random string
of
letters.
So, not just hexadecimal. Hexadecimal is
0 to 9 and A to
E. A, B, C, D, E, F, G.
I mean, to E. So, I want, you know, A to
Z.
So, instead of just a hexadecimal here,
I want a sequence of random
letters. That's what I want to do. Okay,
so that is what I want to change. Um
Uh
okay, so what do you do there? So, make
it text, okay?
So, what I want to do, yeah, so change
um
That would be somewhere here.
So, you see, this is the line. Okay, let
me make a copy.
So, actually, you see, this whole thing
This whole thing is where you
create the name
for the file, okay?
So, the hexadecimal line is here. So,
format
five spots of hexadecimal.
Then, you do
uh what?
Oh, so string to number match string.
So, what we are doing here So, what we
are doing here is very interesting.
In fact, you see when we do a
screenshot, let me show you, okay? So,
screenshot.
When we do a screenshot, the way
Microsoft creates screenshot is that you
know, if you go to the screenshot
directory,
it appends, you see,
a date, of course,
year, month,
date, then it appends
hour, two digits, hour, 17:00, then
minutes.
And two digits, then seconds, okay? So,
hour hour minute minute second second,
six digits.
Okay. So, when you do a screenshot,
Microsoft
uh
creates this format. You have minute,
you have hour, minute, second.
Now, what my code does is that take that
hour minute second, you see you see this
uh this regular expression?
This regular expression match year,
month,
date, then hour,
minute, second, six digit of them.
Here, regular expression. And it turns
that into a hexadecimal. In you know, in
other words, what the command does is
it formats this
um
this six digits
of hour minute second into a hexadecimal
digit.
That's what the my command does.
And that's what you see here. So, it
becomes 2989C.
The reason I'm doing that is because so
that this way
you see, this is not the random number.
This way you will have um
you will maintain order of the file. So,
if you have a lot of screenshots, you
know, let's say I do another one.
You know, you can do another screenshot.
So, if you have lots of screenshots
and when you do my call my command, they
change the hour minute, second.
You still have the correct order of the
time when they are taken. You can still
order them.
So, that is why
uh that's what I did here, okay?
Does that make sense? Is is this
interesting? So,
hello author. Okay.
Is this interesting?
Coffee, just coffee today.
So, the question is what do I want to do
now? Okay, so
uh so
and the code here is fairly complicated.
I was never happy about this code.
Uh do you guys know why? Because
if I take the temp time to explain
this
it's going to take another 10 minutes
just to explain. You see, because this
is about Emacs Lisp
programming language and the issue is
about um kind of coding style,
functional programming style.
You see what I have what I have here is
basically
you are setting this variable
X new name.
That is
that is meant to be the new file name
for the image file, you know, new name.
So, but what would I what what I so what
I do here is so let's temporarily create
a variable XX.
And so here is form path, that's
original file path of the where the file
is from.
You take out the file name extension,
then you take out the directory, so you
just got the file name there, XX.
Then you set it again by
do a regular expression replacement.
Replace whatever begin with TT a number,
remove that, okay? The reason is because
whenever I do a screenshot, you know, in
like
all in all my personal files in desktop
directory or in document directory, if
the file begin with
TT
then a number,
that means those files
whenever you call the command, it will
move to the current file.
Anyway, so those files, any files
beginning with TT means
means that I want to blog those images.
So, it could be anywhere, it will just
find it and move it to my current
blog directory.
So, that's what this does. It will just
remove the TT something number, okay?
Remove that in the name.
Then the next thing it does it replace,
you know, the screenshot spelling or
screen space shot
uh
to remove remove those words because you
don't want the you know screenshot. You
remove it by ss h o t. Shorten it and
normalize it.
Why do you want to do that? Because on
Windows, on Mac, sometimes on you know
on different operating system
the screenshot each operating system
they have their own different ways to
the file name. You know, some may say
screenshot one word, some may say
screenshot two words.
That's why you do this replacement,
okay?
Then the next replacement is that you
want to remove remove a bunch of weird
characters like comma, space
parenthesis or at sign or
the vertical bar in the file name.
Remove them. Replace all by just
low line.
Okay?
So anyway, so that's what this part
about. And the last one is like remove
the last six digits. That's hour,
minute, second converted into a
hexadecimal.
Uh
they convert them into hexadecimals so
that
so that the file name still remain
the the order they are taken. You can
still order them.
So for example, if you are reviewing
keyboards, you you take a lot photos.
And when you call this command, they
they move all the files into your
directory. You can see or know which
photo come first, okay? That's why.
So this is great, but you see the this
uh the coding style aspect. You see, if
you are doing functional programming
but what you are doing here is you set a
variable. You set you know, this value
to this variable. Then set it again. Set
it again. That's like
So what you have is so-called um
mutable. You know, you you know, you are
mutating the variable's value. You you
you know, well, how do they say? Um
You are changing a variable's value
repeatedly. So, but in functional
programming, you don't want to do that,
okay?
So, that's why I'm saying I'm not happy
with this code.
So, how do you fix that? Well, the you
know,
it's not easy in in Emacs this because
if you like normally you would just do
it like um
Uh
For example,
uh
For example, let's remove that. Let me
show you how
you would do it, okay?
So, put that there and you don't need
that, okay?
You didn't see that. Cut that, put that
there and you don't need that, okay?
Cut that and uh put it here, okay?
And
cut uh then then you just um then you
put that. You don't need that. You put
this in the XX place, okay?
So, this is how you fix it, okay? And
you cut that. You don't need that. Setq
new name
this this, okay? So, you see
this
um
this block of code
now become this block of code in a
functional style. There is no variable
mutation anymore.
Fantastic.
However,
this you know, this this one becomes
unreadable.
Uh well, you can you can try to format
it a little bit, but it basically is
still is unreadable.
Okay, so for example, let's
let's uh
Okay, let's do some formatting.
Lambda, okay?
Yeah, it could become kind of like that.
Still, this is like
uh basically
Yeah, you see you got this uh got
Mhm.
Very hard to format. You can you cannot
really possibly format it
well.
Okay. So, anyway,
so you see
this is very clear and you know, much
clearer and simple, but you have the
variable mutation.
Here, you don't have the variable
mutation, but it's like very nested and
hard to edit and hard to
read.
So, that is the problem.
How do you fix it in Emacs Lisp? There's
no easy way, okay? So,
I have not found a satisfactory way.
Hello. Uh
Okay, that's about the
coding style about this functional
programming coding style issue.
Um
So,
so now if we go back to our code, what
we want to do is add a um
Well,
we wanted to add
like letters, but now I think maybe not.
Mm.
Because this represents the uh
the
hour, minute, second.
So, you see this hexadecimal represents
the hour, minute, second. So, they are
actually meaningful. They are not just
random
hexadecimals.
So, but
why do I want to add, you know, from A
to Z? Because it's easier to refer to.
For example, if I want to jump to this
file name,
in this case, I have to search for 298.
9, that's
harder to type compared to if it's just
it's some of some of these um
>> [snorts]
>> letters. For example, search MTP. Okay?
For example, search QSQ. Okay? Let's say
I'm here, search DMN. You see? I can
easy search DMN, easy jump to any of
these random
sequence of letters.
But
if I want to jump to a random sequence
of hexadecimals,
that may not be easy. For example, this
this one is DB. So, search for DB there.
Uh what about that one? So, you have to
search for uh okay.
You have to type a number six
D. Okay?
So, I mean, my point is that
it requires requires you type to type
numbers, and numbers are on top of the
keyboard row.
So, usually it's harder to type.
So, that is why
I was hoping to change
change the command so that it it uses,
you know, random um
append random letters to the file.
But,
now having looked at the code,
I think maybe not.
Why? Because if you add it,
it is going to be too long. You are
adding a lot long file, you know, the
file name is going to be too long.
That's one thing.
The other thing and and then the other
thing is that you cannot just replace
the hexadecimals because they represent
order.
Um
So, now having looked at the code, I
think maybe not, okay?
But,
okay.
So, let's but here we are doing
what we are doing here is the
comparison.
Okay,
what
um
Okay, here
and
Okay, I got a connection disruption. Am
I still good now?
Looks like I got a
internet
connection disruption. Am I still good?
If you are here, say hi, okay?
Uh
mutating a variable.
Not good functional programming
style. Okay?
And in this style
is good functional programming style.
But hard to read.
And
hard to modify.
Okay, so this is about
functional programming style in Emacs
this issue. So, let's cut that.
And let's go back to our talk show and
let's add it there, so people know what
we we
um
and do let's show show in browser. So,
people know what you know, we were
talking about this issue.
Next uh I make
item potent API with Claude code agent
AI. So,
okay, item potent API with Claude code
agent AI. So,
So, what is your point?
Item potent, you know, don't don't use
that word because
like whenever you see that word, it
usually whatever the code is no good.
Don't use that word. If you want to say,
just say
you know, like
like I don't think you ever need that
word actually.
I like to say item potent. Okay.
Are you trolling me?
Because I I I I read that I read about
that.
Item potent, that's like
you know, that's like people who don't
know what they're doing say that.
Um
Okay, so we we we talked about that
issue. So
and uh we talked about that coding
style.
You know, functional programming
uh mutating a variable issue in Emacs
Lisp, which is impossible to fix, okay?
Also, we addressed this um
change we were thinking of doing, but
let's not do
because now we looked at code.
Now we looked at the code. Uh what is
this one? Yeah, so delete that.
Oh, there's a few more, okay? Open it.
Delete.
Delete. Delete, okay?
You know, on that.
Um
close close close close, close, okay?
Open that.
Uh
yeah, the code here
let's
uh
see if we made any changes,
okay?
So, we added a new space. We don't want
this. Remove the space. Check.
No change, okay, good.
So, we were going to make some change to
this file, but now I decided maybe not.
Okay, this this xah-html-move-image
um
it's better not to, I think.
But how do you do um
you see this this functional programming
issue, how do you avoid
this uh
variable mutation
in Lisp because you see, the problem is
Lisp does not have the the
the pipe syntax.
In Closure, you do, but not in Lisp.
So,
so this is a problem.
Okay, so what's the next? I'll show in
browser.
So, we talked about this guy.
We talked about the first thing.
Okay, we talked about that thing. Next,
okay, next topic is polymorphism.
Uh should we talk about that? Maybe not
today, maybe next day then. Okay, so
I saw I made item potent API with Cloud
Code Agent AI. So,
skeletons delight. So, item, you know,
like item potent API. So, you have to
think about what the [ __ ] does it mean?
You see, item potent typically means
it is a it it it it's a name for a
property of a function.
So, that when the function is applied to
an argument
and
the function is applied again to the
result, it does not change.
Okay, that's what I item potent means.
For example,
um
uh
let's say absolute value. Okay, so
absolute value. So, it's a function. So,
three the absolute value if you give it
an argument of three
the result is still three.
Now, you apply the function again,
absolute value of three is still three.
Does not change. Okay.
So, what if you give it -3?
Absolute value of -3, okay? The result
is three.
You apply it again, it does it change?
No.
So, it means a function
repeated application
of the function does not change the
value.
If I uh recall correctly, that's what
item potent
means, but I have to make sure. Am I
check Check, am I drunk? No.
It's coffee.
Right, am I correct? Item potent.
Yeah, repeat repeated application does
not change the value.
That's a property called item potent,
okay? I I'm pretty sure.
So,
but that's a property of a function.
Now, when you say item potent API, now
well, that's something that what does
what does that mean? Because item item
potent is a property of a function or
operator.
Operator is just a
syntactical aspect of the function of a
function, okay? Operator and function
actually are the same
same thing.
It's just that one is a syntactical
perspective.
Okay, so item potent is a property of a
function.
Now, API is not a function.
So, when you say item potent API, you
know, API stand for applications
programmers interface,
which is a idiotic jargon created by
Java. Java, okay. Well, actually
it's it's not idiotic jargon. It's a
great jargon.
Application programmers interface,
but
the Java people who since 1995 abused it
so that the Java programming language,
they call themselves API. Like the
programming language itself is an API,
the [ __ ] Java.
[ __ ] it, you know, these industrial
coders.
Do you guys Do you know what I mean?
API stand for application
programmer
programming interface, okay? Basically,
it just means a set of functions you can
use, you can call
to do something. It's documented, you
know,
to in to interact with some other
system, you know, among two different
systems. So,
for example, I can in Emacs or in
browser, they can call the operating
system's API. So, the operating system
can
you know,
the launch an application or or
something or or go to a
or
um
What does operating system do? Well,
depending on what kind of level
of API. So, you know, for example, you
are programming
networking, you can
operating system provides API
to allow you to um
do TCP IP, you know, like
internet traffic, talk to some some
internet
uh node or server.
It's So, application programming is
interface. So, item potent is a
the uh
is a name for a property of a of a
function. So,
but what does item potent API mean?
Well, you can kind of you can try to
infer
it.
If you try to infer it, then item potent
means um
you know, something that does not
change.
Then you got item potent API. So, it
could mean that every function in the
API is item potent. Okay.
But first of all, let's make sure we
understand item potent correctly.
Item potent refers to an operation,
function, or request that can be applied
multiple times without changing the
result
beyond the initial application.
Exactly.
That's what I said.
The outcome remains the same whether the
operation is performed once or many
times, okay?
So, but so it's a you know,
operation function you know, that
describes a function or operation, but
it does not describe API. So, but when
people say item potent API, what does it
mean?
Well, you can try to infer. Then it
could mean
that every function in the API is item
potent.
Or it could mean
somehow the I API is like doesn't
change.
That's kind of silly.
You see, so this is when
you know, this programming fad usually
like this start start up in Silicon
Valley here. They
you know, they they all people who don't
know a thing about programming language.
They they try to impress you. That's
when they say
that you know, that's when you hear all
these kind of jargons.
Um
mashup
Okay.
So anyway, so
I'm doing
Uh [ __ ] I'm I'm kind of you uh um I
actually
[ __ ] You know, I got things to do, but
when I started to do live stream, I just
explain things and uh
find I find it difficult to actually do
anything useful.
Okay.
So let's regroup. Okay, so
So we did
explain
We explained this cat girls fight. AI
We explained what did we do today? We
explained um then we explained this
treat. Okay.
Uh let me since we talked about this, so
let me just copy that. Let's summarize
what we actually talked about today.
Okay, this this this Professor John very
interesting.
Okay. So that's a link to it.
And we did explain this this uh this
this um
Uh
>> Check, check, check. Okay, so this
this video, okay, we did explain that.
I reposted, okay, copy that.
Uh showing browser, we Okay, we use that
as our thumbnail.
Okay, let's add the link here, so it
Now, it
it really shouldn't be here.
Cut that. Let's move it down. Let's move
to the bottom.
Uh
new section. Is it there? Remove the
to-do, remove the date, showing browser.
So, scroll down.
There, okay. We explained that thing.
And we explained this Professor Gen, so
let's move down, okay? But first of all,
we
after that Cat Girls fight, we explained
uh
this thing, open in browser, so let's
organize.
Okay, that's this thing we did.
So, that thing
Look.
Okay, so um
before Professor Gen, okay, so we
explained that thing, okay?
Uh Oh, so that's just uh
Cut, cut, cut.
So, go down here.
Ctrl break, show, now showing browser,
fantastic.
Okay, we talked about the Cat Girls
fighting AI, then we talked about this
eMac this coding.
HTML open in browser. Yeah, so we did
that. Fantastic.
Show in browser. Fantastic.
So next thing
Okay, we did that. Then we then we
explained this Professor John. Okay.
Yeah, so let's put it in order.
Go to the top. Search for j i
a n. Okay, there.
And cut go down.
Go here.
Break. Paste it. Show in browser.
Okay.
Then we explained
then we explained we were trying to do
this cuz I HTML move image file.
So it adds a random letter in file name
not just hexadecimal. Okay.
But after we looked at the code we
decided we don't want to do that.
We you know, we did some experiment.
Okay. Search for hex.
So this is hex
decimal. Okay.
Okay, this variable out.
Um
So we did that.
And what is this? Cut that.
Cut that.
So yeah, so we did that and cut cut cut
cut cut.
Now go to the bottom. Let's start a new
section. There. Okay. Then delete delete
delete and also here.
Cut.
Okay, new section.
What?
Cut.
Okay.
New section. Cut, cut, cut.
And here, cut.
Okay, now showing browser.
Okay.
So, So, here we have a empty section.
Search for section, section, section,
section. We got empty section there.
Delete.
Refresh.
Okay, so we did
talk about this.
Then we talked about, okay, let's make
them a separate section. So,
d y h. So, search for d y h there.
Cut.
Okay.
New section. Paste. Delete, delete,
delete, and go down.
Delete.
Show.
Okay, we did
that. Then we did that.
Then we did Professor John. Then we did
that.
Is Is it good? Yes. We decided not to do
it.
Okay, and we talked about the coding
style issue of mutable variable in Emacs
Lisp, nasty problem.
Uh
You see, this is This This is um
not really a practical problem because
for vast majority of people
it is not a concern.
You know, people just you know, get
things done. The code works, right?
But to me, I mean
through certain like if you are focused
on programming language design
or certain philosophical aspect of
coding,
then you are concerned about this
because this is about coding style.
This This is about
coding a functional style without
mutable mut- mutating a variable versus
mutating a variable. So,
Emacs is predominantly a functional
programming language.
So, if you code in functional
programming language style,
usually you do you do not want, you
know, mutating a variable like here.
So, how can you improve it? That's the
issue
we are talking about here. So, you can
remove the uh you know, variable
mutation, but the code becomes much
harder to read, you know.
So, that is like the issue we spend time
on.
So, like like why is this helpful? I
mean, for for
most people, you know, most industrial
coders, this is not an issue.
You waste time, you know, you waste time
to think about this kind of problem.
Because the code is, you know, just
works and correct.
But however, you see, this is about
This is kind of like about design
and about elegance.
So,
and
which is significant in other ways
because without thinking about these
kind of issues, you will never improve
um
um like design issues. Like this you
know, like for example, functional
programming. Functional Functional
programming by itself
is almost unnecessary almost because why
you know C works C++ works you just
mutate variables what's wrong with it?
But it turns out I
actually there's there's lots of
problems you know like when you need
you know function critical situations
like nukes
um
you you want things to be provable also
when you are writing programs that prove
theories or automated proof systems
which is very advanced AI you know
that's like uh
perfection of AI that's our final goal
you know could we create an AI that just
automatically
create all the theorems possible in the
world you know you don't need
mathematicians anymore
you know in the world
the most important
people in in a sense are mathematicians
because they create theories that
computer science and physics physics you
know physicists and chemistry all depend
on basically mathematics okay and you
know
and prove and and and what math depends
on is
proof theorems okay you need theorems
so can't can't can't you just create a
machine that can automatically create
all possible theorems that's the
ultimate goal
so but
then you you know if you look into that
then you you know you know we have you
know in the past six years of experience
doing that we learned
we learned that okay you don't want you
know
in programming languages you don't want
mutating variables
because that creates lots of problems
and you then you cannot prove things
because if you want it do proofs
you want a system that doesn't do the
the the the variable mutation, okay? So,
therefore, then then you know, you have
functional programming
and many of it and proof theory theory
and type theory and type inference.
These
technology advancements in computer
science even
in those imperative programming
languages such as Golang.
You know, Go language is like
is is not functional programming
language.
And it is meant to replace C++ you know,
it's like imperative programming
language. But however, in Golang it has
uh
type inference
which is significantly
basically it came from
these functional programming
research.
So,
that's what I'm saying. So, that's what
I'm saying, you know, like some problems
like um
you know, you you seems to be like you
are concerned about style and which is
may not be practical. But not not but
actually
it depends, you know, there's like
complete different ways to look at
things.
So, this this this style issues become
critical because they create a entire
new branch of
uh programming language and and
theorems, you know.
This about
you know, variable mutation
issue.
Okay.
So, that's uh that that, okay? So, no
but nobody comments?
No comments?
>> Okay, let's see how far I
I'm going to go with this. Okay, so I um
So I already talked for
Uh Jesus, I already talked for um 100
hours.
I mean 100 minutes.
Okay.
So we talked about that. We We did this,
which is what I want to do. Finally
done.
We talked about Professor John, which I
didn't want to do,
but he's We talked for 20 minutes about
it.
Um
Anyway.
Uh but anyway, this this is actually
interesting. I mean, I do want to talk
about it, just not
in programming session. Because this
kind of topic, in fact, when you talk
about this
kind of topic, non-technical,
non-programming related, actually
there's a lot of people who are
interested in them.
In fact, that's what you see people talk
about on Twitter often.
Oh, I got new um
Jesus, is Dave Cooper idiots.
Anyway, so
Anyway, so you know, like most people
they you know, they don't know
programming, you know, so they they
won't actually if you talk about
something non-technical, non-technical,
they can actually appreciate. So anyway,
I wanted I do wanted to talk about the
Professor John about
you know, because this relates to
philosophy, religion,
and current political situation
And I want to
tell you guys about my opinion about
this
like um
this white people obsessions about, you
know, end of the world,
you know, religious
Oh, actually, I have a
I have made a post actually. Let me Let
me Let me mention it.
Okay, since So, let's make this uh talk
show. Let's just, you know,
Actually, I I made a post about um
Professor So, I've been watching this
guy. I started to know about this guy
here about this guy since last year
Octo- last year June.
Okay, so by now it's almost a year.
Uh
spect- spectacular guy, okay? But what I
wanted to say say is that um
Okay, I want to uh
tell you guys, okay?
I haven't talked about before.
Uh
God, this guy is a idiot.
This guy, Bret Weinstein.
And his brother is worse, far worse,
Eric Weinstein.
Like academic mumble jumbler.
You know, they they would
>> [laughter]
>> Whatever they have to say, you know,
like something simple in a sentence,
normally you can say it. But they will
take that sentence
sentence and twist it and make it like
10 sen- sentences with twisted logic
so that you don't understand what
they're saying and they think it's
profound. That's these these people.
These these two brothers, like they
their brain is somehow
um
works works that way, okay? They they
like they they are unable to like they
are unable to express simple ideas. I
mean any idea they when they want to
express it, they twist them up into this
academic academic mumbo jumbo. As these
these two people, these twin.
So anyway, about the Professor John,
what I want to tell you guys is that um
>> [clears throat]
>> And by the way, another thing
interesting on Twitter is that, you
know, like
what do crypto people do on Twitter? You
see a lot of them.
You can see a lot of them.
And there's also the my lady and there
there's ugly monkey, you know, crypto.
Like all these and of course they are
all along and [ __ ] posting. Like like
a lot of them and also my followers, you
know.
Like um
for example, recently yesterday one of
my posts become super popular.
Okay, so many you know, like all these
people, you know, today's world, all
these people, you know, we got all the
people that I know. But but but you see
uh
So where where are some of the But
anyway, you can see a lot of them,
crypto, okay?
So the the thing So this, you know, so
you wonder what do they do?
Crypto people. So I asked AI. So this AI
says crypto people on X
form one of the most active, chaotic,
and influential communities on the
platform.
It's basically
24/7 mix of finance, gambling, memes,
networking, and performance art. Okay,
shilling and promoting coins,
farming engagement and cloud,
[ __ ] posting and memes, alpha hunting
and share sharing code codes,
complaining about rugs, scams, or bear
markets.
Post market takes and prediction, you
know, like just crap. Like total crap.
Today's generation like
Like some you know, some of them are
following me, right? But you know, they
they think that this like
that's how they make money. I don't
know. Maybe they are making money, but
it's like scam.
What are you guys doing? You so so so
You know, so so there's crypto then the
the other thing is about stocks, you
know.
Um
So about crypto for example like
So you So if I don't know what you guys
think, but you know, you are thinking so
So if you can make money, let's say
$10,000 of you know,
but you know that you are doing scams
like scamming people.
They all gambling like this you know,
but you you are willing to do it. Is
that Is that what these people are
thinking?
You know, that's good. You know,
But also
But meanwhile also, you know, you cannot
you can never
unless you are actually criminal, you
know, you you actually scam people.
You can actually never
like do crypto and make a lot money
for certain.
Well, actually you know, crypto you can
you can hold, you know,
But anyway, this is just like [ __ ] you
know, this this are like what what they
say kind of like gambling, okay?
Crypto people. Anyway, on on the jam
what I want to say, okay, I think I'm
going to shut down.
Okay, on the Professor Jan, here is what
I want to say. Okay, yeah.
You know, so he's into talking about
eschatology.
Which which just means religious
thoughts about end of the world. Like
how the world is going to end. Okay.
So he's he he likes he believes in those
kind of things and he think
um
So but so whenever he talks about that,
I think he's just like a nut job or an
agent.
You know, it tickles the white men the
the like the
basically the Christian society people
or especially the American Christians
like
American Christians they are into UFO
aliens
apocalypses
and whatever and 4D chess, you know.
They they like to think about that all
the time.
You know,
and also especially about geopolitics.
You know, I have friends like into into
that. Like when they when they look into
and when this white people they look at
this
political situation, they don't you
know, they don't look at
they don't look at them in a normal way.
They have they have always look at they
need to look at them via this 4D chess
and stuff. And and God.
Very funny.
Okay, so I think that's it for this
video.
Actually, I'm not too happy about this
video. Maybe I I delete this video.
How many people are watching?
Four, okay.
Because
in video we talked a lot about politics.
Okay.
Anything else?
Mhm.
Yeah, so let's copy the link.
Is there other things I want to do?
Yeah, there is about polymorphism.
Okay, polymorphism.
>> No, I'm not going to do the polymorphism
because that's going to be
that would take a while by itself. Okay.
Uh
What what are the other things to do?
So,
I'm the same. Yeah, so I can write a
function.
Here is that function I can write. I can
do that in 5 minutes.
Okay, that's it. Bye, guys.