Yellow. Hi everyone. Fantastic. Good
morning, good evening, good afternoon.
We are going to code emac this and
random random topics. So if you have
questions ask okay. Hello David. Hello
Diego. We going to if you are offline
play at 1.5 speed. If you are here you
can ask me questions. Okay. If no
questions I'm going to
begin coding. So this is programming.
This is for nerds. I'm going to code
emac bisp and uh and and and just chat
random stuff. Okay. This is my walking
on my website. Okay. So hold on a
second. So let's see. So undo, undo,
undo, undo. Yeah. Live stream. Yeah. So
okay. Yeah. Remove that. Showing
browser. Fantastic. So you are looking
at Emacs. Uh what else we need to
prepare like prelude prerequisite that's
it introduction okay so yesterday we
installed the AI bot interface in Emacs
talking to the llama bot okay so let me
demo so this is fantastic
okay so again ask your questions if you
are here otherwise I'm going to start
hello Renato so so um uh so let's ask
the question uh what what question
should we ask AI bot
What is
T made of? You see you can type in any
buffer. Okay. And you just select it.
Then you press the key uh which I have
the key is this key. Okay. So delete
return. So delete key is right here on
my left hand thumb. So that gets you
that will call the
command GPTL send. So if you don't know
what we are talking about, watch
yesterday's talk show. Okay, yesterday's
talk show we
installed this
uh AI chatbot so-called large language
machine model largem you know that that
name is very annoying. Let's just call
it AI chatbot. Okay. In fact, you know,
like as you know, if you have experience
in observing linguistics, how language
changes changes, you know, the LLM is
going to go away. You know, nobody is
going to call it that. Okay? They're
going to just call it AI chatbot. And in
fact, the AI will be removed. So after,
you know, next year or two years after,
it'll be just chatbot.
um or and even the chat will be removed.
It's just bot because AI is going to be
everywhere. So anyway, yesterday uh
start talk show yesterday we installed
the Emacs interface. Okay. And then
before yesterday we installed this llama
chatb chatbot
uh with a deepseek model so called you
know or llama. This is fantastic. So you
know if you haven't you can check out
previous videos and see how to install.
So anyway let me demo
uh so what is t made of? Okay so uh
delete enter. Okay before we do that
let's look at our GPU and
CPU you know it's going to take massive
you know loading. Okay so delete enter.
What is t made of? You see it says
querying or lama there at the bottom.
[Music]
So you can see the GPU start to go up.
That's a GPU memory
usage. So starting up is slow. And now
it's begin. You see reason thinking
think. You see think what is teammator
think. Okay. I need to figure out what
is tea made of. Um, from the earlier
response, it seems like tea primarily
consists of the of the
chameleia synessis plant. Let me think
about this step by step. First of all, I
know that tea can in comes in various
types like black, green, white and
oolong. But all these different TE's are
processed. You see in any buffer you can
just ask a question and press a key or
just start to um you know think. So
after thinking it says okay so that's
done you see now so remember we are in
EMAC in any buffer you have the full
power of Emacs for example this long
line I don't want it I can press a key
then it becomes um you know 80
characters per line by the Unix
[ __ ] convention but I don't want
that okay return to one single long line
but how do you solve this edge you know
cutting off issue you Okay. Uh visual
mode. Visual line mod. Do that. Okay.
Uh space and uh in softly keys I'm using
space and V. You see toggle visual line
mod. So now you can see the the words
are cut off properly. Okay. So it says
deepsek says T is primarily made for and
okay. Let me show you another command.
press a key then it become sentence
oriented each sentence is a line each
sentence is a unit you see that's so
that command if you want it is reformat
to sentence lines okay let's see if I
have it uh
online there it is URL okay so you go
open that show in browser Emacs reformat
to sentence lines so you just press a
button and any long text such as Alice
in Wonderland or philosophy text you
know then each line is a unit a semantic
unit a sentence so this command will do
that uh it will help you reading and you
know kind of understand long
essays so close that close that we
digress okay so so so for example make
it one long line and
and and you can either you know do the
format that uh you
know anyway let's not repeat okay so
let's so tea is primarily made from
chameleiais plant a species native to
regions like China and India different
types of tea such as green black ulong
teas and white result from how the
harvested leaves are processed after
picking
exactly green tea under goes minimal
Oxidation keyword while black key uh
black tea is allowed to oxidize
affecting its color and
flavor. There it is. I'm drinking tea.
You cannot see it but because in this
modern
scientific metal thermal
bottle by the way this this is amazing.
You know when you pour hot water in it,
it'll stay hot like for a whole day.
Quite amazing. So the thermal technology
have improved. I didn't I didn't know
before, you know. It used to be a
thermal bottle is like very big because
you have walls, you know, air like an
air surrounding it because air is not
heat conducting. But anyway, but but
these modern ones you don't have
like I don't think you actually have a
air um in insulator that's called okay I
don't
know but let's further process this
output from the AI machine. Okay. So you
see I want to make it now sentence
sentence lines again. So one line per
sentence. Now the last
uh the last sentence says herbal teas
may come from different plants or herbs
rather than chameleia synis. Okay.
Herbal tea is
[ __ ] It's some kind of I don't like
herbal teas at all. Okay. Tea to to
Chinese people to Japanese is is not
herbal. Herbbo is some kind of I don't
know what's the origin of herbal tea.
Okay. Let's ask it.
Okay. What is the origin of herbo T?
Okay. So, you need to select it or let
me demo a different way. Okay. So, a new
buffer. Open a new buffer. Paste it.
Then you don't need to select it. You
then just delete
enter. So, now it says querying and the
uh the GPU memory goes up.
What is the origin of the herbo tea? And
meanwhile, let's go ask
Gro you know Gro is another uh
artificial intelligence
chatbot. Answer please. What is the
origin of her t? So by the way I noticed
this deepseek this model I'm downloading
is inferior to gu. Okay is better. It's
much
faster even if you use you know the
guork website you can just go to
guork.com okay gu is by Ella Musk
uh but locally because you know
deepseek deepseek is uh very good okay
however let's see where is my talk show
uh talk show so we installed deepseek
uh you know two days ago so there it is
DeepSk uh it's amazing but however when
you install Deepseek locally you know if
you want the real deepseek R1 you need
to spend
like you know like
um 20,000 times 16 so you need to spend
like
$300,000 to buy the graphics card to you
know the GPU and CPU
you if you really want to run the real
deep seek then then it might be better
than guork. I don't know but you know it
was you know but then um but I you know
I don't have you know if you are just a
normal guy
$1,000 gaming machine you cannot really
run the real deepseek R1 so instead you
run a some sort of reduced model so
called distilled that's a key word
distilled and quant
quantized so so I'm using so what I'm
using is um so let's turn on
JavaScript. So what I'm using is this 8
billion
parameters not the not the
671 billion parameters. So 8 billion
parameters requires five gigabytes of
graphics card memory which I have you
see it's almost full is you know I have
six gigabyte
um graphics card GPU memory so if you
run this model 8B requires 5 gigabyte so
that's the max I can use
um but then higher of course lower means
less quality so anyway I turns out the
you know this local one is
not Gro is much
better because you know yesterday you
know actually do I have it saved you
know I asked it to show me how to set
the PowerShell's prompt to be color okay
actually this is a good thing okay like
how how do you set the uh PowerShell
prompt to have color and Gro answered
right away correctly
So let me show you. Um, so I'm I'm I'm
talking random. Okay. So So let me show
you. So
Groke. So this is how you do it. Just
paste that. You know, then PowerShell
will have now I have color. Okay.
Fantastic. Let's go to Let's open a new
PowerShell
uh programming block. Okay. Close this
one and magnify. You see? Wait. You see
I prefer I prefer the prompt above the
cruiser position. For example, I can do
a d here. You see list of all my files.
Let's do it
again. So you know it adds a new line
and now I got color. Okay. So this code
you know you know these days you can
easily get it.
So, but when I ask Deepseek to do it, it
says, you know, oh, you know, you can do
it in a in bash. This is bash
profile.
Incorrect. So, anyway, so here is what
is origin of herbal tea? Oh, I I missed
[ __ ] I missed the typing the
t. So, we got different uh question
here. Oh, but you figured out, you see.
So, now let's turn this. Okay. Her tea.
Let's make it one sentence. One sentence
per
line. Herbal tea originated from ancient
civilizations such as Egypt where herbs
were infused in water as early as 5,000
BC BC. Okay, that's annoying BCE thing
because they are
anti-Christianity you know before it's
BC and A
D right and the way I think of it is B
means before A means after okay so you
know but now these academics they don't
want to be associated with Christ you
know so because in This is western
tradition, western society, western
society is oriented with God the
Christian God. Okay. So that's why you
have you know so AD and BC is you know
actually we can ask uh Gork about what
is the full spelling of AC. It's like
after you know basically it's based on
the date the supposedly the Christian
the Jesus was born. Okay. So today is
the
So today is the year of our
Lord
2025. Okay, that means we have
2025 years after Jesus was born. But if
you want to count a year before that,
then it's called BC. But then in America
you got these academics, you know, they
don't want to associate with
Christianity. So they they started
a a different way. Instead of AC and BC,
they say BCE and something. Okay. So
anyway, BC. So before it's BC and A D.
Okay. So let's let's let's ask. Okay.
What is BC and A D? Okay, copy that.
Let's ask woke. But before we do that,
finish what we started first about the
herbal tea. Okay, so what is herbo? So
deep seek lower version says herbal tea
origin originated from Egypt 5,000 years
ago, 7,000 years ago. This practice
spread through the Mediterranean region
with the Greeks and Romans who used
herbs for social and medical purposes.
In India, herbal teas were integral to
uh to uh
uic medicine. Okay. By the medieval
period, herbal teas became popular in
Europe. Uh
uh. Okay. Now I need visual line mod.
Okay. Um, popular in Europe blending
into cultural practices that viewed them
as healing. Okay. That's associate
associated with women women things. You
know, women is into herbal tea and
stuff.
Healing. Thus, thus her te's history is
a mosaic of diverse cultures and
tradition across time. You see, notice
they didn't mention China. That's
correct because we when you know I was a
Chinese, I grew up I, you know, there's
no such thing. What the [ __ ] is a herbal
tea? It doesn't taste
good. Here, here is a real
tea. Okay. And what is quantized model?
Let me explain a little bit. Okay, let
me let's finish the herbal tea thing. So
here is Grog's answer. Okay, let's see
what Grog
says. Uh, okay. So let's magnify. So
Grog says her tea, also known as Tisan.
Oh, Tissan originated thousands of years
ago with roots in Asian cultures across
the globe. It it begins as tied to the
use of plants for medical and ritual
purposes. Oh, Asian China 2000
uh
2,700 BC Chinese text mention infusion
of herbs like in ginsen and
kamya. Well, gin jinsen is not a
traditional western herbal thing. So
ginen is like Chinese stuff but it's not
like the western sense of herbal tea. So
anyway, Asian Egypt
by 1550 BC. Okay. Then Mesopotamia and
India early
civilizations something something. Okay.
Then Europe, middle evil Europe,
medieval. Then indigenous cultures,
Native
American. Native American. Now is this
is this the coloring of the social
justice
part. I
wondered Native American and African
tribes steeps steeped local herbs such
as sumac or louisi boos for ceremonies
and remedies. Okay, but what year? What
year? Okay. So then it says unlike true
te. Exactly. Because I you know herbal
tea is not like you know the typical
sense of Chinese tea.
Uh herbal teas use diverse plants
reflecting local flora and cultural
needs. Yeah. Okay. So herbal tea you see
herbal tea is just
a you know water you
know use different plants but tea in the
in the China sense is a specific plant.
Okay. So which one is better? I think
I'm guessing the Grog answer is more
accurate. It is it is just my guess.
Okay. Now to finally confirm and verify
the correctness of our research, we can
go to Wikipedia.
Okay. Press press press press. There it
is. Herbal tea. You see herbal tea looks
like that. The western tradition, you
know, a bunch of flowers and stuff.
Women women's stuff. You know why? Why I
think of herbal tea is women's women's
stuff. You know they like you know in
the women's bathroom they have these
flowers smells good aroma
stuff. Uh okay herbal tea. So what does
Wikipedia say? Herbal tea is technically
known as herbal infusions. Oh that's
interesting.
Interesting. Uh
okay. And less common commonly
called tisan.
Okay. US also tang. Okay. Our beverages.
Let's
magnify. Our beverages made from
infusion
or decoction. Oh, that's a new word.
Decoction. What does it mean?
Decoction of herbs and spices. Okay,
let's jump to history.
Uh there there you see you see women
things a promotional poster for Tisan
Gulu is women things you see I'm I was
correct because these kind of things
attracts
women
ethmology composition and usage I don't
care I want history varieties okay I
don't care uh ya mate that's that's not
exactly about tea But uh I
mean uh where's the history
section? Okay, there that's the
traditional Chinese. Okay. Uh jeans and
stuff. Now where's the section? Where's
the history? Health and
risks. You know, Wikipedia are supposed
to say
history. [ __ ]
Okay, let's search
history. Human history. They don't have
a section on her tea history. So, uh,
okay, that's digression.
So, so, so let's see what you guys are
saying. So, it should do. Okay, let me
explain. Okay, the quant quantized
model. Okay. So, when you go to Olama,
if you want to Olama, okay,
Olama, we talked about this two days
ago. Fantastic. I recommend it. There's
another one called
um called U um Llama
Llama.cpp. Okay. So, some some people
say that one is better, more link.
Anyway, I this one this is what what I'm
using. So, so, so you download first of
all you download a llama then you have
to pick a uh pick a model like okay we
can start here okay so for example uh
let's go to today's talk
show today's talk show open this
directory in powershell and that command
is this open in terminal and you can get
it by uh describe function open in
terminal. There is a command and the URL
is this here. So you go there and grab
the code and you can do it just as I do.
Okay. Open terminal. Fantastic. Works in
Mac, Windows and Linux. Okay. So we got
this
window. But now
magnify. Okay. Talk show this
directories. Okay. Uh um yeah. So we
want to uh do the lama. So let me demo.
So you see so so lama you can do gcm
means um get command. Okay. Which is
equivalent to the Unix Linux where
command. Okay. G G C M O L L A M A.
Okay. So you can see it is you know you
can see the path you see it's installed
there. So when you start so you can o l
a m a help then it'll give you options.
So what you do is you lama then you run.
So if we want to run the
the so let's go back here. Yeah. So you
install llama first then you just say
llama run then then that okay deep seek
uh one comma 8b
okay so you pick a model then if it's
not installed it will install it okay if
you want to remove it just say remove
okay here r okay so what is the model so
model So basically so they have you know
so quantized. So so okay so usually
these these AI chatbots you know large
language models they require tremendous
uh computing power you know either
dedicated neuronet network chips or GPU
you know and require a lot memory. So
for a typ typical computer like your
home desktop or your phone it's not
powerful enough to run it. So they have
like re reduced
model and uh so this is about neuronet
network technology. Okay. So there are
many ways to
reduce memory and CPU
requirement. Okay. So but as far as I
know so let's say there are two major
ways okay there are many but you know
this is a deep science you can study
this for a year but so but as far as I
know you know I don't know much so two
major ways one is
quantized version which means you see
this neuronet network computation what
they do is basically they create a giant
function this function is mostly uh
matrix multiplication. Okay. So you have
like like when they say 27 billion that
means that means there are
27 numbers I mean 27 billion numbers
they need to multiply. Okay then it's
like whenever you ask a
question that question English sentence
or Chinese sentence let's let's see if
we can get to type Chinese. That's very
interesting. Uh guen.
Okay. So when you have
this the way they work is they basically
have a mathematical function just a
function. Okay. So when you type the
input input is what you the question
whatever you typed or image okay it
turns this text or image into a a a
sequence of numbers. Okay. A vector
sequence of numbers. Then this sequence
of numbers becomes the input to the
function argument. Okay, input to the
function. Then the function will compute
like multiply this 27 billion numbers.
Then you will come come out another
sequence of numbers, a vector. Okay,
then that ve vector gets turned back to
the text. You know that's your answer.
That that vector becomes this. Okay.
Uh well not basically well basically
they work one word at a time. So that
vector becomes the word herbo then herbo
with that you put that back to the
function then it come out the next word
herbo t okay so so you have to do this
multiplication of matrices like bill
billions and billions of times. So that
is why it's heavily computational
intensive right am I am I live guys say
something
okay okay so so yeah so computational
intensive you know so let's go to
um let's go to uh I want to show
um kasar
code search uh artificial intelligence
index. I want to show the equation.
Okay. How chat GPT how chat GPT works.
This is my learning notes. I started to
learn it in 2023, you know, like what is
this magical thing? It can write poems
and stuff. Amazing. So, I started to I
spend a lot of um time studying it. So,
I know how basically it works. Okay. Uh
the article actually I recommend is
Stefan Wuam. This one this one gives you
a
introduction to how it works. Focusing
on how it works not just oh just run
this equation and you will do it. Mo
most others are like that. Okay most
other for example this guy he'll tell
you you know just you know in Python you
just do this and that's how it works.
But the Stefan Wuam he takes the
perspective of you know as a scientist
or as as as a philosopher as someone as
an curious and and an intelligent
earthling suddenly you see this chi you
know technology how does it work you
know how things work that's what you
want to know how engines work how car
engines work how hydraulic engines work
how how how how how airplanes work.
Okay, that's that is the perspective and
approach of Stefan Wolf's explanation on
CH GPT as well as his other or other
explanations. Okay, it'll take like
several hours to
read. So how it works not not like the
typical tech geeking you know oh Python
code you run this code and then you
download this library that library does
this and therefore you get this you know
it but this doesn't
explain which this is great this is
great but however it does not explain
how the
technology magically can write poems and
answer questions okay Stephan wa so I
recommend that okay so you can see So
it's about neuronet networks and then
okay so and then you know I started to
read so ultimately is this function okay
in wuam language uh notation it's this
so each of these m is a matrix you know
you got thousands of matrices and they
are large matrix so that's why you have
billions you know you have billions
numbers of multiplication and this this
video by this guy three blue
Brown I also highly recommend okay he's
a great
guy so intensive multiplication so how
do you reduce it so how can you you know
go to the Apple phone store or Android
phone store and download a chat GPT app
you know your phone is like tiny you
know it doesn't have
GPU well so one one method is that you
reduce so each of these number two
billion or 670
20,000 billion uh like deepsek you see
671 billion numbers if you want the real
deepseek six 671 billion numbers if you
want to you know a phone cannot do that.
So one way so all these numbers are
floating numbers floating numbers like
um 32 bits or something. So one way to
to reduce memory consumption is instead
of using a floating number let's just
make it eight bits you know so you cut
the precision of the number sign you
know by a lot so that is what quantize
model means okay so for example for the
deepsek R1 you have models here listed
okay so you got then okay so you got
Um you you you got um are they
quantized? Uh they doesn't say for this
but in other places you will see it.
Um basically they turn the floating
number into just fewer bits. Okay. Uh
how do I know how do I learn? Wow, I
learned it via Gro. Just ask it.
Fantastic work. Okay, like you know, let
me ask a new one. I asked before.
So, what does quantized mean in large
language model LM? Okay, you'll say then
there are different techniques and so
on. Okay. So you can read you know it
takes you an hour and takes you multiple
hours if you want to
um know the technical detail. It's very
short but I asked you know anyway so
that's what it
is. And distilled means distilled means
you um you see some of them say
distilled. Uh let's go back to the
models. I want to show the quantized
click gamma 3 is from Google. So does it
say quantized? Yes, somewhere. Okay. 27
billion parameters model. Quantized
aware trend model. Okay. There's QAT or
technical
jargon. So quantization you see. So
these are reduced
models but there are many techniques you
know one technique is that you just
reduce every number you know every
number in this billions numbers for
every number you reduce it that's one
way more simple or you can
reduce you know some part of it and or
you can train the
model beginning with reduced
number precision to begin with. That way
you actually get better result. Okay. So
that you know so that's quant
quantization. Then you have distill.
Okay. So does it mention distill here?
No. Okay. So you go back to the uh
deepsek then you'll see distilled
version there. Distill. Distill.
Distill. Dio means kind of like you
train a
model
then then you create um
another that train based on the output
of the previous model something like
that something okay I don't I don't know
exactly so anyway that's that's the
that. So, okay. Anything else
interesting? You know, I um So, let me
copy the stuff we talked about. Open
terminal. Go to talk show. Go to today's
talk show. I want to paste my links
there. Uh okay. And go back to browser.
Close it. We talked about that. We
talked about that. Uh, lama deep sea or
lama is
fantastic. Okay, then we talked about
herbal tea. Herbal
tea and uh, you know, I don't like the
visual line mod. So let's turn it off
you know because when you have visual
line mod then your link you see you see
you then your link becomes you know you
got this long space uh
there so am I good am I doing
good okay so turn off visual line mod
okay so we talked about her t the
history
um we got it from chat bots
And uh we got um okay and what else? So
there are uh topics. Okay. So this is
like
um the answer of what is
um herbal tea. So the point is that you
just press a button and you just start
to type. So, so back to what we were
talking about this Deep Seek R1, the
model I'm using is inferior to
GU. Okay. So, I might need to you see so
I might to need to try another model.
So, but I'm thinking doesn't matter what
model I try, it's not going to be better
than Grog. That that is a big
disappointment. Why? Because this work
they run on billion dollar machines you
know so if I'm if I need you know
whatever I install locally I cannot have
this billion you know I can only have
like four billion you know like very
small version
so so the result is not going to be
competitive to whatever group will
answer so meaning that you know you if
you want real quality answer to
programming questions to whatever
science questions, physics,
mathematics, you want the you know you
want a good
answer. Yeah, you can run locally but
the answer will not be good because you
don't have you know
uh
$100,000 GPUs and stuff. So that's a
disappointment. Okay. Anything
else? Latent rep. So let's see what you
guys are
saying. So there's a there's a
frequently asked question from a young
guy as
assume. What makes Emacs better than VS
Code? The simple question, the simple
answer to that question is that Emacs is
much more powerful
uh and much more link. You see, because
if you I you know if I turn this into a
VS code, I open open this in VS code.
Okay, open VS
code. VS Code will
start. Okay, and you then you go to you
see this is VS Code. This is Emacs. Now
you go to the memory uh part. You look
at the processes. You see Visual Studio
Code is using 600 megabytes of RAM right
here. I cannot enlarge this window
because Windows sucks. You know this
test task manager. Opening one single
file in VS Code. Fantastic VS Code. So
easy to use.
megabytes. Now in my Emacs, I got this
bunch of things, you know, three buffers
and I can start a shell, you know.
Here's a shell. Let's say U LS, you
know, I can do LS in, you know, I can do
another, you know, so
Emacs, where's
Emacs? Emacs is
using 112 megabytes. You see that is the
difference.
VS Code, fantastic, beautiful, easy to
use, no learning time, 600 megabytes
something. And if you open like two or
three more files, one gigabyte of memory
bloat, Emacs, I can, you know, I'm
running like I'm running O Lama. I'm
running the chatbot here, you know, 100
megabytes.
Okay, that's So, Emacs is much more
powerful, much more lean,
uh, and, uh, much more flexible in what
you want to do. Uh, because basically
it's a lisp machine environment, which
by the way, I have like over 200 300
videos. Today's talk show
is episode
648. So I have done about 400 you know
or more EMAC tutorials and talking and
about stuff. So you can watch
it.
Uh good question. Ronaldo says, "Is it
possible to deactivate the thinking
process and go straight to the final
answer?" I've been thinking about that
too because this thinking is knowing.
So, let's try let's ask a question. Um,
uh, what is chat
GPT? No thinking. Okay, let's just say
that. Do it.
And you know, so it's
running. So, oh god, thinking
again. So, how do you turn off thinking?
Okay, let's go
ask how to turn off thinking in deep
seek
ask. So, we are multi- chatting with the
AI
machine. Discipling the thinking process
chain of thought or coot in deepseek
models particularly deepseek R1 is not
straightforward. Oh, because the
thinking process is integral to how
these models generate high quality
response. Oh,
okay. Technical detail. So, this is a
fairly technical detail. So, it's
a chain of thought. Okay. So it's some
kind of variation of technology to do
that and it's integral. Okay.
The co teach of thought often output
with thinking tax is a core feature of
deep sea car one as it was trained
using reinforcement learning to reason
step by step for better for better
accuracy especially on tasks like math
coding and science.
Oh, so by the way, so if you want to
learn about these neural networks,
there's a lot good videos, okay? I mean,
there's there's like thousands of
videos. Uh I would say maybe 90% is bad.
You shouldn't watch it. You know those
like 90%. Okay. So the trick is to know
how do you know which one is good, which
is bad. Okay. So for example, let's go
to YouTube. So there are videos that
explains many of these models deepseek
or other llama or you know how they
differ how they work you know so you
know I' I've so let's
see deepsek are one okay let's see I
watched one of them it's pretty good I
haven't finished yet so so what you want
to avoid is first of all this dramatic
fox Okay, like this open AI is not not
god. What the
[ __ ] Okay, AI explained you know this
this the [ __ ]
grifters this one you know when whenever
they have flags you know run deep what
whatever at
home [ __ ]
[ __ ] I truly despise these [ __ ]
You know, they they like what what the
[ __ ] do you know? Like, uh, hi, I'm
Dave. Welcome to my shop. You know, I
might be wrong. Some of them may be
good. Okay, but there's lots of
grifters because they are cashing in
because this AI is like dramatic.
Everyone wants to know like how how to
become a millionaire in one day using AI
full of
it. And this deep seek crash course
crash your
ass and this this this bad news this
[ __ ] this you know t of them you know
they are all trying to
explain h Jesus you know but there's a
good one okay I know where to find it uh
there's a good one
moto showed in our forum Okay. So you go
to saw
discord saw discord go to the AI
section. Uh so we have a lot technical
people here you know who followed me and
you can find kasad discord address on
kasadi.info. Okay. So there is a video
post by Mo Mo rage quit because he's
talking about politics and he rage quit
uh two days ago or so. So there is a
uh so we were like we were competing you
know like we were talking about which
you know whether Linux has a better
um text recognition or Mac you know so
we are you know so he's showing you an
example a very big let's see how can you
do that in Mac and Mac came out
instantaneous and I challenge you know
so can you turn this can you do OCR
so-called OCR optical character
recognition you know
basically today is part of AI you know
this is like AI in the 90s about
recognizing
text you know you want to turn an image
of text into text so but but what if you
have a table like this this is written
in 1992 my my code for the HP you know
graphing
calculator when you do this, you know,
you got a problem. So, he explained how
it it's done. So, anyway, so Mo Mo Mo Mo
Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo
Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo Mo is kind
of a machine learning
expert. Uh but he posted a video about
how Deep Seek works, you know, like
that's a good video
somewhere. Uh ignore this like troll,
you know, this [ __ ] Malaysian Zuma
[ __ ]
videos, you know, memes so-called. They
they love you, you know, since late
Maren Jen and uh there. Okay, this
one. Let's check that out. Is that the
one I watched? Yes, I haven't finished.
Okay, so this is how Deep Seek rewrote
the Transformer. Okay, very
technical. I try to understand
Transformer. It's like
um you know it it will take me a a month
to really actually understand it because
in order to understand what is a
transformer you need to have a basic
understanding of neural networks
matrices linear
algebra regression of calculus uh and
lots of others. Okay. And you you need
to understand why it's transformer is
significant. you know what what do you
do before the transformer you know the
new
neuronets. So you know so this is like a
a science by itself. So this this video
I can recommend
uh you know look carefully by Welch Labs
created on March 5th 2025 25. The video
title is how Deep Seek rewrote the
transformer. Okay, I can recommend this
one. You see, there's no drama pictures,
you know, Xiinping versus Trump. [ __ ]
[ __ ] them. You know, American flag
versus China. Oh, how how you know oh,
Chad GPD is going to die. These
[ __ ] the zoomers and the Malay
genen
[ __ ] Okay, this video you don't
see that. Okay, so it's very technical
if you want to understand it.
latent representation. Yeah. So machine
learning and this especially the LLM and
the neural network that's really a huge
topic. It it it is actually a field you
you know you need to like actually spend
a year or two at least if you already
have a degree in computer okay like you
you already are a programmer but most
programmers don't know like don't know
what the [ __ ] is this you know they they
are like the prompt engineer you know
they just try type different you know so
so they have a new title I'm a prompt
engineer but they don't know how it
works okay So but it's very interesting
if you are the type mathematicians or
whatever philosopher like Stephan Wolfam
you know I talked
about you want to know how it works okay
so for a programmer if you are already a
programmer or if you are a you know
engineer or mathematician so you can
study how it works it's a field by
itself so you need linear algebra you
need some calculus you need then you can
then you can you you know it takes a
year to really understand so I'm kind of
doing
that okay and especially you know in my
past few videos I talked about proof
theories like the ling programming
language you know so I'm also learning
that
so so the you know so so they work
together great because neuronet networks
by definition by the by its nature they
are never precise like they cannot solve
math problems. You know if you ask what
is a plus b where a and b are like
20digit number it they got wrong. Okay,
we show this many
times, you know. So, for example, uh
let's say a random number. Okay, random
number. Random number.
Okay, let's say times. Okay, let's can
can we run this? Save this in
uh let's say Python. Okay, Python print
that is it big enough? Okay, so that
times that. Okay. Now ask chat
GPT. Uh okay. What is Okay. You you'll
get it wrong.
you
know can assign a first number second
number perform multiplication result is
that usually it gets wrong but I think
today it gets right because because it
actually calls Python let's
see no it's wrong you see this is the
correct
result okay
uh quark result. Okay, this is a correct
result. This is a G result.
Okay, incorrect, you know, idiotic,
totally wrong. So, you can fix that. You
know, it it's just wrong. Whenever you
need some simple
computation, the seemingly advanced AI
bots, they will always get it wrong
because this is this is very interesting
and fundamental because they cannot
compute.
Okay, it seems like they are so smart.
They can write poems. They can answer
difficult questions. They can tell you
what are the theories of math. But they
cannot compute simple calculation. they
cannot
do. Um so in order to so that that is
the
nature of neuronet network okay they
cannot do it simp that's it there's no
fix okay the the llama bots they just
they just cannot okay that's a
fundamental nature of
neuronet that's why it's called machine
learning you know they don't actually
they compute
so a lot of people tries to fix it. You
know, one way is to have proof system
link, you know, we like so when you came
out the result, you validate the result.
For example, when when you determine
when when the chatbot determine it's oh,
it's kind of like a math
question, they can feed it to Python.
They, you know, they just launch Python
and just do
print. Then they they then they'll tell
you the correct answer. You see? So
that's so that's how the lean proof
system and their health. Anyway, that's
it for today. Thank you guys for
watching. No
comments. Am I like one one people
watching or something?
11. Anything else? Okay, that's it. Uh,
random chat, random I random talked for
enough. Let's go back. Um, let's clean
up and shut down. Uh, so what are we
doing? Paste it there. Oh, that's
Python. So, press
Python. Yes. Yes. Okay, that's Python.
Put that into Python. Syntax color show
in browser. Go down here. That's Python
versus
Quoke. Uh, do you have a programming
degree? No, I'm
uncertified. Uh, and I'm kind of
self-taught for reasons. Okay. Because I
I I wasn't normal. I don't have a normal
background basically. Okay. So, this
this uh this what is T made? Okay. Okay,
let's open a new window and
uh let's do a screenshot of
it. Anyway, that's it. Uh bye
guys. Bye. Bye bye bye. So uh pay me.
Okay. Go to PayPal. Go to
kasadi.info.
kasadi.info. And go all the way to the
bottom so you can pay me. Okay. We are
doing a screenshot of that. And uh
um and go back to s talk show. Oh yeah.
So I wanted to do something. Yeah. Let's
forget about that.
Uh
what? Okay, let's make the screenshot.
There. There we have the result of the
herb tea. What's herbal tea? Screenshot.
And
uh what is T made? Okay. Text. Okay. And
uh change it to underscore.
Copy the file path. Close it. Paste the
link. Link it. Make a list. Show in
browser. What is T made up? Fantastic.
So we have a record of it. And what is
this origin of? Okay. New buffer
paste.ext.
Okay. Copy the file path. Close. Okay.
Wait. We want to replace space by
underscore. Rename. Do it. Okay, there
it is. Copy. Close. Close. Uh, what is
emac shell? Okay, we don't care about
that. Go back here. Where is
our open and link
list? What is the origin of herbo T?
Okay. What
else? Uh, what is chat GPT? No thinking.
Okay. So that's another question. It
keeps thinking because you cannot remove
that as we learned. Very
interesting. Uh you cannot remove the
thinking in deep seek. It needs to
think you
know hey answer me this question but do
not
think. Okay.
So you know it it just um it needs to
think. Okay. Uh what is this? Okay. So
turn close that Python we don't need. Go
to the talk show. And here's the
question we asked. What is chat GPT? No
thinking but he thinks
anyway. Then Gork told you that you know
Deepseek has to think. You cannot tell
it not to think because it part of it.
Okay, bye guys. Shut down.