good morning everyone
welcome to talk show and today is okay I
need to get these correct
today is let's talk about stuff then ok
stuff so talk show for the title correct
and we gonna talk about going in stuff
and let me sum yes so so yesterday
someone asked me about my opinion about
dynamic typed languages versus
statically typed languages and I kind of
PAP out for the oath for 30 minutes but
here's the thing okay so in summary you
know in summary it's in summary okay
dynamic languages are actually easier to
use for prototyping and studied their
faster and and I was watching a video
talk by the Ryan Dow the guy who created
not Jas I admire him very much
he's a mathematician and he's a you know
very great programmer and he saw he
mentioned that dynamic languages
actually mean for scientific computing
for example if you are you know kind of
data scientist old you know data
scientist is like a fashionable term in
the past five five or so years and data
scientists have been drinking this
for like the past five or six years
every day this is my Grateful Dead Pool
but it is some kind of a cheaper version
it does you
so anyway if you're gonna drink that you
know never drink the sugared version
never never drink any of those sugared
like I never drink Coke or sugared water
Coke Pepsi and you know sprite and stuff
7up this is a 100% grape juice by the
way I mix them together
but anyway so I've been drinking these
you know energy drinks for like every
day for the past five years six years
and you know for of for several years I
was drinking the sugared one but
actually you know in my life I never
drink true good stuff but you know you
know so I was drinking the sugar one and
it does your body no good you started
you start to get sailor loose you know
on your thigh you know or you know like
you know wrinkled skin fat so I stopped
drinking that you know you don't eat so
even drinking the energy drink you know
I'm not sure it's a good I mean it's
probably not a good thing but if you do
drink I mean just don't don't ever drink
sugar
okay don't drink sugar drink Pepsi coke
whatever and act in fact don't put sugar
in your coffee I never put sugar in my
coffee like don't sugar is just no good
for you period okay don't eat sugar
anyway here's to mathematics so we got
one guy watching say hi
typing the comments here say hi here and
so I was talking about yesterday I was
doing talking about okay dynamic typed
languages versus static statically typed
hey hey no man great to see you two guys
watching now how is that you and me so
you know in that bad boat for 30 minutes
but the gist is that okay the gist about
dynamic versus static is that
yeah grinding down Brian tau you know
the guy who created the JavaScript not
genius you know he he mentioned that you
know if you are doing scientific
computing you know basically you want to
use dynamic languages because you know
static type languages even with typing
influence they just you actually have to
do a lot you know some more work you
know just basically you know I like I've
been doing : in the past year and I've
been doing JavaScript you know for many
years and Python so I like gold I'm very
much but you know but I noticed that
wherever you know at you know web
whatever I want to confuse something
simply just for your eyes golden you
know like when you start a : let's see :
okay this is my quick way to start go
around so you can see go go three okay
go go okay you see first of all you need
this template even though it's simple
for me to type it because I have set up
a briefs and everything but you know
that's the first thing you need to do
you need the package you import fmt
which is for the print statement which
is essential so so anyway in short you
know when you are doing any type of
scientific computing or even Mathematica
for example Mathematica is not typed
it's like Lisp you don't need you know
the the typed languages does you it's
cumbersome to actually
okay so that's what Ryan doctor say it
said you know I agree you know when you
when you are actually doing typed
computing I mean the scientific
computation you don't want typed
languages because I was thinking you
know or at least you guys in any of the
typed language fans such as Haskell I
mean you have the thought that you know
you love it so much you think you know
type inferencing techniques and you know
function composition can be extremely
short very expressive you you might
think you know you know all these other
advantages will actually blow away will
make you code faster I don't think
that's actually true for example okay mo
is also a strongly typed language with
type inference so anyway dynamic
languages are generally better for
prototyping quick stuff but the read
okay back to my opinion about you know
dynamic versus static typed so I so so
yeah in summary tandem dynamic language
is still good I sort of them this
JavaScript for example Python although
I'd have like Python in JavaScript but
anyway
but but the other point of view I very
much are into now in the past five years
is that strongly typed languages such as
Haskell you have if you view this
programming language as a as a logical
system such as doing math proofs like Co
G there's a parami language it's called
proof proof system a proof system coq10
you want types because type theories
that is one of the major foundation of
mathematics for doing proofs therefore
if you view Haskell or similar languages
as a as a proof system as a logic system
you know computational computable logic
system then you actually want you know
very strongly typed why
because because then those types becomes
that's the main dish I mean that's what
you actually that's the meat you know
you know beef before you know in when
you're doing you know computation like
scientific computation calculations you
know find a solution to a matrix or find
the plot math surface
you don't need types types are like by
by-product of computer engineering I
mean they are there because you know the
compiler writers need to have those to
make it fast you know otherwise is you
know talk slow so it's a byproduct of
computer engineering but if you are
doing proofs like a logical system or a
verifiable program software you know oh
you know if you are doing foundation of
math then you you want types you know
that because that's the need that that
that is what you actually want to use I
mean you cannot do math proofs without
you know you know types you know because
yours because you are doing type theory
essentially so that was like the summary
of my yesterdays you know half an hour a
brain so there's not no ultimate answer
even for me as to which one would you
pick you know if I can take only one
language language you know typed all and
type I can say you know because normally
every day you know I want untyped I want
you know dynamic languages but but I'm
but I'm very interested to study of our
proof systems logic system the
foundation of math you know automated
proof seasons by computer and that you
know type is like the the heart of it
you know so so that that that was about
yesterday so I got we got five people's
here so say hi skies say highs so that
was kind of a summary of yesterday's
rambling and today we gonna do let's see
some talk show today we're gonna do
here's to health house going nomen so it
is a seminal crock 740 in your location
right East Coast so we gonna I think
we're gonna do
Golan I'm gonna start to do Golan you
know I can do lots of things sometime
you know I we haven't been doing a
random chat for a while random meaning
like none technical like I just I talk
about you know what's happening you know
and you know sometimes we can ingest
inject some technical stuff like me max
but you know like lots of things YouTube
you know I wanted to talk about that for
a while but so we haven't had a nun
technical talk show so-called talk shows
on talk show but but also but you know I
need you guys to type to tell me let you
let me know because you know so the more
conversation are you guys going you know
then I see it and then it becomes more
fun you know but I also realized you
know I cannot just rely on people you
know chatting because many people I
suppose you don't want to you know type
he's like you know you just want to
listen whatever so actually so I'm going
to start to talk about I think :
okay so let's see this is my Emacs let's
see where okay here's today okay so we
discussed typed verses summary of type
versus dynamic and it's good to be able
to do that and
okay teach : yeah let's do that then
okay so I'm going to go through my :
tutorial its viewing browser let's go
and go to an tutorial and you know so I
mean you know I mentioned this before
I've been walking around with my surface
book you know surface book surface book
this is actually a surface book this is
called surface pro you know so I walk
around and taking notes and there are
some things I need to correct but
actually it's it's good let's begin to
do that goal and because you know I so
I'm doing videos I learned a lot I'm
trying so you know one thing I want to
improve is to kind of like condense what
you want to say instead instead of you
know sitting there and you know so I can
condense you know get not avoid empty
you know videos like you know people
wait for me to do things so go down we
talked about it yesterday so you just
download go down and you can read but
today let's begin let's start by let's
go let's do this so I'm going to start
to code a small problem goal and let's
see where is it
some talk show so let's let's do it here
so let's just add okay let me show you
the so add a tag for Golan and just pop
it out and we can start to type goal and
go okay and what I want to do is to
write a program that prints the first
first hundred prime numbers okay so
let's begin so we run this this is just
33 so oh my god this is going to be a
task do you know I go arrow hand ring no
so good so no man you do you have so
many experience with : looks like some
people prefer exceptions oh I don't like
exceptions Oh for heaven's sake no
exceptions however the goal and air
handling is is very very tedious
cumbersome it's like every ten nice
every ten lying in your code you gotta
you're gonna have a catch error let's
see yeah great great sorry exceptions
you know exceptions is the worst thing
in computing industry in programming
languages is of the worst okay so I
looked into this topic a few years ago
so I wrote a essay and you know first of
all okay this guy says the exceptions
they are one of those most complex and
ridiculous thing ever devised
I concur Chuck Jonathan Blow I forgot
what what he does but he say this is
from a YouTube talk he's given I think
he say T yeah he is a language the one
of the language the creator oh you know
the major you know guy I think I forgot
yeah but also okay so let me talk about
exceptions maybe a little bit yeah so
you know you know you you guys ask many
questions are you go into that topic we
get we get back to Google and soon so
exceptions first of all note that what
you know you know you guys what do you
know of exception is actually may not
actually be what it is because
exceptions you know exceptions typically
okay you have exceptions in Java in
Python in JavaScript okay
for example the those exceptions are
pretty much similar okay but however the
history of exception of the of the
jargon exceptions disease is entirely
different and exceptions in other
languages is entirely different okay
they are not they are totally like Inc
they are completely different concepts
so if you are one of those people you
know from Python or Java or Python or
Java or JavaScript you might think okay
you know you might think okay I like
exceptions or I don't like it because
but you know note that other people's
concept exceptions is actually entirely
different your concept of the exceptions
yeah it's actually just one you know
once more well not not small but you
know because there are a lot of Java
coders in Python your concept of the
exception is only one of them okay and
also your concept of exceptions in Java
Python they are entirely different from
the history of exceptions okay the
history of exceptions actually it came
from Lisp everything came from this
however the the exception single is it's
not it's not it's totally different from
whatever you know Python Java okay it's
not that at all I am NOT going gonna go
into details about that but anyway well
you can you know you can read this
article if you like then you know many
of these information are from Wikipedia
you know so you can read about it you
know in detail so anyway so first let me
just give you a few summaries
first of all exceptions may not be what
you think okay your concept of
exceptions
that's just your concept
okay well let me I actually have a
summary summary here let me read it
programming languages differ
substantially substantially in their
notion of what is an exception okay your
notion of exception Python Java are
totally different from other languages
okay then exceptions in most imperative
languages such as Java Python JavaScript
is a form of go to yeah that's a good
point
so so in Python or Java you know your
concept what so what does the exception
do they are actually just go to you know
the go to a statement but they are like
increase it go to I mean when you have a
go-to statement yeah I mean you you know
you you know you tell your program to
exit the loop or go to some other part
in your program and start from there
let's go to okay
you have go-to in Perl you have go to
again
you know this this stays not many
languages have go-to while you have some
form of go-to emag B's let's show it
then sorry
Emacs Lisp exit
yeah catch so here is you see
so remember exceptions you usually have
the catch throw he think you know catch
it so emag list also has that but Emacs
Lisp is catch catch though is entirely
different from your you know catch throw
in Python or Java okay in email list you
have throw and catch they have nothing
to do with exceptions well they are like
lists you know original kind of related
to original concept of exceptions but
anyway
throw in catch they are just go to
immigrants play okay when you throw
something you put a name attack you know
then the program will find somewhere
else in your code that has the tag catch
they will just jump the program start
from there that that that is basically
it so it's a go-to it's just a go-to
statement there's no implicit you know
arrow exceptions that that's hidden
somewhere I mean everything about the
throw and catch is like just in your
code you know there's no hidden
exception you know with fire arrow
exception there was something like that
it's not like that so at least you have
catchments though and okay so let's back
to the summary so it's a foam exceptions
in you know Java Python JavaScript there
they are a form of go-to they are
implicit go to okay and for that reason
it's it's pretty bad because as you know
good you know proper programming you
usually don't want implicit stuff you
want everything explicit okay and then
in some languages exception Institute is
just a syntactic form of go to and that
is all yeah for example like a Mac this
you know the throw catch is just go to
with a different name that's all
then okay then in some languages such as
Java Python exception is more than just
go to but go to with a tree of go tooth
which runs out of your control
exactly you can simply throw or simply
try in the language we will do things in
the magic realm that is true for Python
no Jesus I truly despised Python every
aspect you know so in in so in Python
you have like you you know you try
something then you throw or you catch
you know but what would what happens you
know this because so the base basically
you have a hierarchy of go twos
underneath it you know not not in your
program not in your source code but the
language has a tree like a hierarchy of
goals you know exceptions you know so
this exceptions parents is like
exception that parents so it's very bad
then okay then this item okay Google's
new language : does not have exceptions
because the designers consider
exceptions humph oh yeah because if you
go to google colons blog you'll find
this i have a link here : faq they
discuss why they do not have exceptions
in : basically excuse me Rob Pike and
you know I think Thomas the inventor of
Cola and they decided you know they I
mean not they decided but but their
opinion is simply that exception is just
bad it's a bad feature in programming
languages so they give a reason you know
they give a reason now okay last item of
summary if you don't like typical notion
of exceptions in C++ Java Python be
cheered that many way or no expert
programmers do not like them neither and
never use such features in in their own
code yeah that applies to me I never
ever liked you know I never liked the
exceptions and I never
I used them once in my 20 years so 30 30
years of coding I never used them once
not not in Python not not in Java well I
haven't really coded Java that much but
yeah I don't use them you know you know
I I didn't use it I mean I wrote this
article in back in 2014 but all that you
know 20 years before I never used them
because I don't I find them you know
extremely convoluted and how to
understand you know you don't know
what's going on you know I like
functional programming you know
basically every program I program I
wrote is functional programming I don't
like your pee but you know in Java in
Python you can still do functional
programming without ever using you know
pee you kind of can't you know I decide
do that but in Java for example Java is
simply your Opie language you cannot not
do Opie because everything is a class
then object yeah okay yeah so so here's
about exceptions now okay so so you know
I go into details about exceptions this
the say my petticoat problem and the
solution to say my petticoat problem
what is the say my petticoat problem the
term see my predicate problem the term
captures the problem I had for a long
time namely when a function returns a
value but the function might encounter a
error oh right has he for example
invalid input how do you signify that
error yeah so so that's one of the
issues related to exceptions and there
are several solutions you know in the
history of computing we we have several
solutions to the semi predicate problem
yeah exception it's not only bad but
also programmers don't understand it I
mean if you don't get all the code in
the industry many of them just use them
incorrectly and many of them use it just
as I you know just as a year lazy
laziness to to avoid doing anything and
here's a history of exceptions ok so
anyway then there's a video what is this
video Jonathan Blow okay
Oh in Haskell okay at Haskell also have
exceptions this guy you recall this guy
Eureka Kong I he's a Quentin's he's also
a Mac heavy email is user I think he
also called he Magnus yeah I think he
does but I'm not sure I don't know if he
wrote any packages but anyway he he has
been commenting on my on my on my
website for a long time for many years
and he's common always come through to
be the most the best comment you know
the high quality like usually you might
have some opinions okay for example
about the exceptions then you get a
bunch of idiots like they oh I like I
like existing exceptions because they
don't know nothing they'd never studied
the problem they don't know in nothing
about mathematics they don't know
nothing like zero about Kathy erratic Oh
computer science they do not know
anything about history of programming
languages what they what they know is
like like they are just average
programmers do you like the hacker types
they did you know average programmer
there's some experienced you know five
years of programming in different
languages then they have opinion then
they're gonna tell you oh you know I
like you see I like exception you are
wrong because this is see that but they
never they don't understand what it is
and and and you know then what the
bottom line is that they never actually
spent dedicated time time like to study
some issue they just throw their
opinions and of course they say oh you
don't understand you don't understand
either you don't know if either
you don't understand this that so most
comments are like that but this guy Yuri
Kong he's from I think he's from Russia
Oh some Russian Yuri comment so he knows
a lot he also so every time he comment
it usually answers sometimes I have a
question you know he answers my question
you know exactly the way I asked because
in my life you know oftentimes I have
questions of course I do
about programming languages or
mathematics got lots of things but
usually why I ask them the response you
get is that okay you have lots of these
you know ignorant people but if we
exclude those then sometimes you got
mathematicians you know who actually you
know know things but but then but they
don't understand your question like they
dismiss it like they saw it and then
they they give you an answer that is
like FAQ you know frequently asked
questions that they are not answering
your question they don't see the
question you know well you know because
you know you know for mathematicians
there are exceptions for example the
John John page sky he is a great you
know he always see my questions and an
answer to my to you know really helpful
to you know like my questions are
usually not you know to have the
frequently asked questions because I
looked at things you know I study things
then I find a question those questions
are usually you cannot find answers you
know you know because they are kind of
ok anyway so you recom guy is very great
knowledgeable and he's he's also he's um
active list you know you can see his
post there but he's also knowledgeable
about Python he's he's a fan of - okay
so we disagree on that and he is also I
believe he's the export of his car so he
here he give a explanation about how
exception works in Haskell now I don't
know Haskell
so I learned it you know I learned
things from him
so he give you know so Haskell is
exception so he has copies of course
entirely different from your you know
Java Python and and so on okay that's
about exceptions now back to a goal and
no so goal and you know they don't they
don't have exceptions so how do they
handle the same I prayed a great problem
they handle it by let's see basically
there you have errors let's see well
basically what they do is that you know
the primary way they solve the exception
problem is your handling is that a
function returns can't can return more
than one value its called multi return
so let's go through function so here is
: and on a second me maybe a let's see
if I can
yeah okay so here is good : so this is :
how you define a function and okay so
you define a function func F F
parameters in the type and then the
return type you put it here then you
begin the function body okay here but
okay motive for return types so here's
how Golan handles it handles arrow you
know to indicate that the function
cannot compute you know it's a hero
it returns multiple values like this you
can just return multiple values then you
know written multiple values then when
you want to get the value all you have
to do is assign to a to multiple values
like these for example we defined a
function here you know F F F you know X
Y us input and and it returns x and y
two values you know it just returns the
argument to values so it's not at least
it actually returned two values but how
do you get those two values you just you
just assign them to a variable with you
know two variables that's that's how you
do it so so yeah so function returned
two values now when you have a function
that say for example possibly you'll get
an error for example XY and you want to
divide X by Y so if Y is 0 it's an error
right but you want to return you want to
indicate you nowise cannot be 0 if Y is
0 you want to return you want to tell
the coder you know something's wrong
so you just return two values the first
value is the answer the second value is
the error that's how you do it you just
have the function
you know the second value is an error so
whoever course the function can just
check the second value to see if it's
error or not so that's how you do it
let's see
okay so let me show an example but
before we do that let me read the
comments
hey Nicholas greetings from hey hey from
Hong Kong so you guys know do you like
going on your hunting
I have very light experience with go
learning it ok great
accepts exceptions are fancy go to and
have some of the same problems yes
Olin has a very limited form of
exceptions mostly useful non local and
local returns in propagating processes
propagating process exit cool yeah I
never learnt :
Earl and I like to but I just never got
to yeah is interesting ok so let me show
you an example of each section of colons
you know the error handling it's very
annoying you know for one thing I I'd
love it that Golan don't do exceptions
great its most it's wonderful but high
goal as it so happens you know it it
turns out you know you have to do a lot
error code handling like every 10 lines
everything nice your function will
return the second value you know as
error indication then you have to check
that value so it's kind of annoying but
however still I don't want exceptions ok
rather you know this is still better
than exceptions so let's just go to a
let me show you show you exemption
problem okay so here's my program what
does it do it does find and replace let
me show you example then a new buffer
so let's go through my Emacs blog let's
go to the diet directory let's go up a
directory ok let's look at eMac manual
let's look at either Maglis manual so I
copy the path and close the window so I
so this this is a : script for doing
fine to be faced you can you can see the
code here on this website let's go to
the website and you see this is not as
like 200 page 200 lines it does find and
replace with a bunch of features it can
do a whole directory including nested
directories it can you know filter out
files by fire extension or using regular
expression it can it can take a list of
files instead of directory so if you
just only about you have a list of files
you want to process you can do that it
your auto do backup if you want it can
you it can have multiple find/replace
pairs so if you want to do find replace
or multiple pairs you can do it one shot
so these are the future features of this
go line script and I'm going to give you
a demo of that
so first so so what you to use this
program you just open the file and
change the parameters in the beginning
for example here ok
so this is the introductory file name
rejects is dot HTML you know HTML files
right to file true no I want to force
don't write to file because you know
because that's my that's my Emacs manual
and do backup to backup server for
suffix true ok and then finally paste
pairs so let's replace or eMac Emacs
Lisp by
let's go okay let's do that and I just
run the code let's it's they are like
1000 files so run it right too far is
for stun
okay so that well basically it says
there's no replacement that cannot be
true
so basically says it does not find any
[Music]
let's try to search for it oh so the
entire eMac list manual does not contain
the word emag Lisp that that cannot be
true
oh okay I know why wait because the
capitalization yeah I think so
so capitalized okay let's do it again
yeah there we go
so they are like 900 files changed
actually they are not saved because I
have read to fire force but you can see
otherwise you know 900 files are changed
eMac this is replaced by Haskell so
that's how this program works and okay
so now I'm going to show you where the
error handling video it's really it's
everywhere like every 10 lines you see
it for example this function to fire
okay so this function to fire is just
open the file and you know open the file
read the contents and to find replace
and save it so that that is this
function do file and okay it's it's okay
it's like 20 lines and then this
function takes a path fire path and
returns the arrow
okay it returns nothing but arrow so you
just return arrows so okay so let's look
at the code to do to file it's okay
actually I don't have any code that
checks well okay let's forget about that
one let's look at this one
IOU tio read file so this is when you
want to read a file into a text so read
file takes a file path and returns it
returns two things why is the content in
bytes file content and the returns an
error so so the this read file is from
the IO uto building library so it's very
common you know ii o co lines libraries
is common very common almost every
function returns two things the second
thing is error so here's an example so
once you do that then you have to check
the arrow you see this this line if
arrow is not nil then you have to do
something
you see you know you print so if this
arrow I want to print out what path I'm
currently processing and the panic panic
just means exit you know so that that's
an example of arrow arrow handling but
you'll see this in a lot for example
let's search for arrow so this one
there's another one you see here rename
file you know I'm trying to do backup
here so this rename file function it
also returns arrow and you have to check
the arrow because if you don't have the
code to check there or go compiler will
complain I think it will for example
it's for example if we delete this line
let's delete it and let's run it
you see okay arrow decoration not used
[Music]
because I declare the arrow here so yeah
but then we can try to remove that and
see what happens but we we can try that
let me do a backup okay let's run it
okay it's okay yeah so for this case you
can skip the arrow checking but
basically yeah you know basically goal
and kind of like wants you to always
have your Zeb I mean in real life you
have to do this a lot because otherwise
compiler will complain so that so that's
one of the problem you know of go line
you have you know that is kind of
tedious you know you have to every ten
lines you have to check arrow you know
in panic you know here's another one for
example this this one like when you do a
rejects okay be Jake's Mac man rejects
match string it hoes our heads has to
return the arrow and if you do not catch
the yellow I me if you don't check the
error let's see your complaint yeah it
contains you know
well it so anyway so that you know you
know that's a issue so let me read
comments hey Danielle
but I have to go so remember people all
command keys can be changed
JK what do you mean no one says no one
says in my C code I sometimes rap
explicit error checks in a mark well to
reduce the checking clutter
oh I see so you see see support mapo you
know I had no C+ first suppose you know
some kind of marker but I never you know
I never programming see first first I
don't really understand I don't really
know what how I think they yeah they
called preprocessor is that preprocessor
you know basically it when the compilers
meets your source code it first you know
it I think it does a find and replace on
your source code we know in the
beginning of your source code you can
define some kind of fine and replace and
the commander read it he owed us do the
finding we faced then you start to
compile I think that's a gist right see
processor okay so that's about
exceptions I'm wondering okay so 46
minutes I think we can continue back to
Golan yeah let's hang on a second let me
make sure my programs to your business
it does
that's good cuz it close it so I think
let's go back to between the first 100
prime numbers maybe we can do that
we have 15 minutes but okay so we have
eight people watching you know guys say
hi say something you know in a comment
just type anything like you can type
we're which country you know which
country coming from coming from
Singapore coming from China Beijing
coming from you know United Kingdom
y'all coming from Russia
well let's do the goal and then this
this let's do yeah so I'm going to print
the first hundred prime numbers let's
see you can do that so first of all
every every go program you can't happen
to have this kind of template okay
that you know basically here we go file
so how do we do it
so print we're gonna use the prime save
method so to it yeah let me do it so so
what is square root of 10 okay 10
um okay how do you do it how do you do
it you know we can't look up Wikipedia
but let's try not to do that because
this should be simple we want to use
sieve method
you know Steve myth is a 1 to 100 so
let's say so I want to train the first
100 times okay let's just let's just say
I want to print the first the prime
numbers within 100 so basically you
start with you know okay you go through
1 2 3 4 5 for each number you multiply
it by 1 plus 1 1 plus 2 wait okay it
starts from 3 for example 3 times 3
times 1 3 times 2 3 times 3 3 times 4
okay each one's got a result and for any
of those result you cross them out you
know in your list of 1 to 100 that is
the basic you know that that's basically
the outline of the algorithm then then
you you know at the end you just look at
your numbers you know in your list from
1 to 100 and see which one are not
crossed out those are primes yeah it
sounds simple but now is begin to code
it so so first of all you know I'm
probably gonna write a bad program but
you know the goal is to do it know this
so let's just do it let's not pay too
much attention about elegance and
efficiency so first of all I want a list
of numbers oh my god how do you do how
do you get the decimal numbers in goal
and it's the sir wait wait how do you
get to do some number in colon slice
what this is impossible
okay the other thing I remember about
Golan is that it's kind of it does not
have many functions like for many
functions you just have to write you all
for example I remember there's no
function for minimum like if you have a
list you want to get the minimum you
know you got you want to get the element
that's the smallest number there is no
such function you have to write it
yourself imagining finally pairs
random number differ pointed system core
[Music]
okay this is pretty bad now I want to
wait again anything you want to get the
range of numbers what's this no I don't
I don't but I don't remember there's a
range function okay well no more if I'm
coding I just go I just call a trench
and Stack Overflow where your comfort
come up okay I'm gonna a key range
map of integer to integer to record
which are marked what do you mean
map of integer to integer okay let's
just start to write it then let's just
use a for loop for loop let's say what I
to 100 okay and for each thing we want
to ice begin with 1 and let's say print
okay I okay
and for each okay so ice
okay priest int so plist is a slice
which is microarray but extensible the
length can change so this this will be
our final result and the first of all
push wait so I want to feel the list
with 1 to 100 I don't think there's a
range function and I don't want to look
at stack overflows
so let's go to loop not loop but slice
so slice
okay so 0 from 0 to 100 and I so P list
I equals 2pi minus 1 okay and format it
expected expression okay this is wrong
P list okay that's just slice it should
be right oh yeah so yeah so you just
want declaration you don't have values
yet so this declares that P list is a
slice okay so format it that works and
[Music]
then it import not used okay yeah go
line has lots of you know this kind of
annoyances because when you import a
package and if you don't use it you'll
complain so when you are doing
prototyping you have lots of these you
know annoyances because you know import
you're gonna use it like eventually but
you know you cannot just leave it there
yeah
so we're gonna print previous okay the
net okay
runtime error index out of range
index out of range so plist fearest one
this this will be first one runtime
error index out of range what okay I is
0 to 100 0 to 100 and why can't it work
okay how do you assign prints lies
length of size its
okay this is this is not good this is
going bad because I haven't been coding
: for like three months three months you
know in order to do this I should have
you know I should have practiced it for
you know a week because yeah so wait so
what we gonna do so what are we okay so
we are trying to find out why the index
out of range why should the index be out
of range
[Music]
oh you you need to use a pend you cannot
assign let's see your ray so here is
array so here is how you assign array
elements that should work
let's try that
okay this is getting stupid
okay even here is wrong
[Music]
okay
that's good
knife all five okay that works
okay yeah this is not going well
you know I'm even just trying to get a
range of numbers and it's taking too
long so I think that's too bad I think
that's that would be it
well maybe Josh should I continue a wish
because we still have eight people
watching yeah we should you see the
problem right now is like and they're
like I you know the problem the problem
is I forgot the basics you know I you
know you need to be fluent with it in
order to actually do this in real time
otherwise you know you're just gonna
look at me struggling with you know the
syntax and stuff
the problem here is now I have a P list
which is a initialized 2 which is a type
slice of int which is you know and the
first three elements are 3 4 5 then you
assign the index 0 to 9 so that works
then lets you know so this works you
know knife will fight but if you add
this it does not work because exit
status well that's the reason is because
let's say exit status 2 because index
out of range so because you are you know
for example let's say
print print length theorists so length
is three then if you do these that works
that doesn't work yeah so you cannot
assign index that's that's that's not
the next you know available slot to yeah
this works then you can do three oh you
cannot because wait this is wrong array
array we have a slice here now slice
slice the the slots the number of
elements in slice they usually okay I
think I know why you cannot you know in
order to do that you have to use a pins
you cannot just add you know extra
elements there like that you have to use
append so let's do that then so so
[Music]
so upend
I now this is very inefficient because
append returns a new slice every time so
what we are doing here is actually
returning this is very inefficient but
it works you know because because append
it returns a new sliced every time so
every time you add a new element to us
to the size it actually create a new
slice I think it's very inefficient or
should we do another way of you know but
another way let's this forget about
efficiency it's just pressing on with
the prime numbers so okay now we have a
number from 1 to 0 0 to 99 actually we
want to we want 1 to 100 yeah so now we
got the TVs now we have to start with 2
to 2
yeah it's just it's this - ok for I
equal to 2 to 100
okay
[Music]
so normal says I was thinking something
like map int int oh that's key value
pairs right so do you do your loop and
make non prime staying zero values in
the map how your Prime's that makes
sense yeah that's a good approach
actually yeah that's yeah we should do
that but we already begin this path so
maybe we just keep pressing on here yeah
so now I want to do 2 2 x 1 2 max so for
1 2 max if 2 times I is in is 210
yeah this this is so bad
I wonder if I should continue because
okay actually you know to actually do it
you know you know the this a Chinese
saying that if you make haste you gonna
be slower so if I'm gonna actually do
this I have to like think you know
instead of just stop you know instead of
banning on keyboards I AK actually have
to you know take five minutes to think
think about exactly what you know think
about the algorithm that'sthat's my
style of coding you know I spend you
know five minutes to think about the
exactly the algorithm what what I needs
to be done then I start to code then you
have idea you know you want to use you
know what kind of loop or map or data
structures or map you know hash table or
size then you you implement you know
your plan so so just yeah maybe we just
listen let me talk about you know I'm
sorry I'm not sure I'm gonna you know
this is not going well so but you know
let me just talk about them what what am
I going to do so we want first of all
actually that the the problem you know
is the first 100 prime numbers but you
know to simplify that it's beginning
with you know just be stuff the prime
numbers that's under 100 that's what we
you know we can do that first so Oh
prime numbers 100 so we want you know 1
to 100 then we start with each number
each number you let's take for example 3
then you multiply 3 by you multiply 3 by
1 the motor by 3 by 2 is 6
you know so you got numbers like 3 6
9 12 15 18 and for each one you want to
push it to a list for example you know
this this because concerns about
efficiency but let's forget about that
for now you know it's it's just you know
we don't care about that for now so
anyway so full and stop for example
number three we multiply it by 1 by 2 by
3 and so on and until let's say on tier
103 times 100 yeah let's not care about
efficiency for now
then for each result we we can push it
to at least for example let's just push
it to at least ok then we do that for
the number 4
yes this way is getting extremely
inefficient we do the same phone number
4 we do the same phone number 5 you know
like 5 times 1 times 2 times 3 and so on
and put a result you know into this big
list of except the number 5 itself ok
then we do the do it for number 6 except
number 6 itself so we start with 6 times
2 6 times 3 6 times 4 and so on for the
reason you noticed then we begin with 7
and so on and here we begin we have
these 100 then ok after all this done
you want to find out in your P list
which is 1 to 100 you want to find out
which one is not in the existing list
then those are prime numbers
that's your resource so you you can do a
yeah not Union not intersection
but - you know this list - that is
basically okay so that's the basic
that's a very inefficient algorithm you
know we can so the next step is that we
can rethink and refine the algorithm
because there are a lot of
inefficiencies repetitions over there or
we can just start to code it yeah let's
start to coded them because since we are
doing goal and you know we want to show
the goal and stuff okay so so we got a
list so we start with number three okay
so we got this so num Prime's then
Prime's is at least okay okay and we
start with the number two number two
let's begin with number two number two
times okay so here's what we do start
from two two
none prime equals to 2 times 2 times I
that's right
so 2 times I so non prime will append
two times I that's right two times I I
start with two for each one we misters
do that so that looks good
2 6 4 okay that looks good let's let's
try this for 3 again
so starting three six wait three times I
this should be too so beginning here you
can see start with the earth then the
third multiplication with three six nine
twelve fifteen so we do this then we do
this for four that's right so that that
is correct
starting with four eight starting with
eight there it is
so these are the motor motor fires for
four so that looks good
so now all we need to do is just double
loop a nested loop okay so we do that
for 0 to 100 okay for two to 100 okay
for each one we want to so Jay Jay Jay
this will be J looks does that look
right so we have a nested loop and
[Music]
we don't need that anymore let's try it
well a big one this is an example where
Emacs slow down because if you have a
one huge line Emacs becomes the
extremely slow it's not due to Golan but
it's tick due to Emacs trying to display
the huge line it's pretty bad
so that's gonna go out for a while
actually cue it yes so if I do not print
it out it's pretty fast it's already
done
you see yeah so if we don't print it out
it's pretty fast but ok there are some
now we want to put in them Prime into
the least number I'm only if it already
does not exist let's try to do that so I
mean our algorithm so far is extremely
efficient well it's not worry about that
for now because basically real life
anything you do you know in the
beginning is going to be extremely
inefficient then you got refine it and
refine it so I haven't coded you know
seva prime since like 1991 and the quick
you know the easiest solution is
actually just go to Wikipedia you know
because they will tell you there's the
the proper efficient algorithm actually
they're more advanced optimizations
because I remember reading that few
months ago but you know we don't want to
do that because the fun part is to work
things out you know see you can see how
we are thinking I mean this is an easy
simple problem you know a good
programming exercise when you learn a
new language so okay so what so let's do
Smith solve this one problem so we want
we have two lists we have one elements
we want to find out you know whether
it's already in that list you know if it
is don't add to it
okay this problem is actually easier
than if we have a hash table like a map
so let's switch to map then you know
like normal suggested
yeah so let's go to map so maybe after
we do map you know after we create the
map data structure and let's go here
today because this this is not this is
in no way a good demo okay so so
non-prime let's change them from to a
map and the map declaration is map key
type key type is int and the value type
will be value type will be true or false
right yeah let's do true or false so
what is the type for true force it's
bullying but how do you spare it
so let's go to basic types basic types
puh ok pol so the value is int the the
key is int the value is pool now how do
you set value to a map create map with
me okay we don't care a set set value
okay it's like that
then for okay for
then Prime
J
equals two oh this is true let's run it
numb prime D pretty clear in this blog
okay
so comment on in it type map into is not
an expression okay
yeah that's right so this actually
should be let's see in it for expression
yeah let's create an empty one okay we
can do it this way or we can do it this
way
this way you simply declare the Varnum
trying to be a map this way you actually
create an initial value in our case
which is empty just empty map so let's
do it let's run it it works great so now
we got a map so now we can print
non-prime let's print it out great we
have getting better and better
okay so this is fantastic so let's look
at the map so let's copy that new buffer
magnify nets space to new line okay so
we got this 27 is true oh we need to oh
it's not sorted let's try to sort it
that looks right
except you know it's you see two is over
here so you want to sort by first field
so let's call the command control u 1
then M X sort fields sort numeric fields
okay that looks right so two three four
five no this is not right because five
should should wait this is no this is
wrong this got every number okay we yeah
something is wrong
two three four five six seven why is
that
oh you should oh yeah it should be that
stupid
okay so now it's finding a big number
so anyway yeah I think that's I don't
know if I should continue you know yeah
because it's not 1 hour and 20 minutes I
think you know this is this is no good
you know I'm not sure I'm not doing well
here ok let's let's optimize a little
bit because the way we are doing it is
like hundred times 100 you know we got
lots of numbers yeah I hate you watching
me yeah ok let's let's try out a bit
more how'd my energy drinks I need my
energy drinks I need a drink
so this is extremely inefficient that's
not the way you - I mean my algorithm so
far Oh algorithm is very bad because you
don't you don't go over over 100 so
first of all what is 100 square root
square root of 100
so 10 that's 10 right so let's think
about algorithm a little bit because we
don't want to add a huge bunch of
numbers there because we are only
concerned about you know numbers within
so whenever okay when it's impossible
when simple solution is if okay wait wha
x equals to cut okay now that's the
value okay now if X less than 100 okay
max let's say if if X is less than that
then we do that so if X is less than max
that's right max is 100 let's say max is
101 then we push it to non-prime yeah
that that would reduce that a bunch of
numbers mastery that's good it looks
like so fast yes you know before we are
wasting a bunch of calculations okay
let's look at the result magnify repays
space by return okay and we're gonna
select that actually let's just see that
then we're gonna select all control you
to M X sort numeric fields
okay so wait and let's do it again
control you 1mx
so two numeric fields that's it that's
great that is finally okay
actually we almost basically we solve
the problem because these are non prime
numbers yeah that's that's it four six
eight nine ten wait
so two is a prime three sub prime 5 7 11
is a prime correct 17 so far correct
2192 23 23 subprime yes yeah basically
we solved a problem already okay what
two more minutes we'll be done
this is success let's try okay first of
all this peel is we don't want wait wait
no okay um yeah we don't need to
actually we don't need the P list
anymore make a backup actually just
let's just comment up then then we just
do a loop for 1 to 100 okay max then we
just if I is not in the num time then we
just print it out then we are done great
if I is not in okay so how do you check
if a key exists in a map gate value TD
key they get patio mkwii turns to values
first value is a key is the value of the
key okay the second value is true if the
key exists else force
so if
okay so M is non-prime okay if if that
okay so here's what we do
KB
if P if P is true if it exists it
returns true so if P equals two force
okay wait
if not P then print that's it print a so
I think that's it
oops
go format era so we
so what is the pooling wait okay so what
is the pooling to negate oh yeah
exponential I mean the band exclaim
nation undefined plist okay wait how if
you want to print okay wait if P is true
then don't do anything
if P is true don't do anything if P is
false print a
print
I
a declared not used this is a issue with
Golan you I mean if if you have a
variable not used declare but not use
your complaint so it's not very good for
prototyping there we have it 97 so all
prime numbers within 100 but now the
problem or internally is 100 primes so
we just increase it by vampire moderates
see ya doing cheating so this is the
first 97 primes here
it's just increase it by 600 perfect now
we clean out the code so now we you know
we spend like one hour to clean up the
code then we show it to people you know
then we say look how beautiful it is
that's what happens on the hacker news
and you know online you know you you
spent days and you king of ensure okay
we we have the result you know we have
the program that prints the first 100
primes we actually we printed more but
we can you know so there we have it
so okay great um thank you guys for
watching I hope you that was a kind of
you know not so good demo of Golan but
you know I hope you liked it thank you
guys I'll see you next time be sure to
comments okay you know you can comment
on my video a youtube video comment so
you can comment you know on Twitter or
you know just say something you know let
me know what you want to watch next you
know and you know I'll you know I'll get
prepared for you know : maybe another
demo of coal and instead well maybe we
can do this in JavaScript that'll be fun
and also maybe in Python so thank you
thank you know man and nickers hey so
see you see you guys bye