hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk
show we are going to do exploration of
the YouTube
download uh YouTube
download okay so you you know I want to
download YouTube and uh also videos on
Twitter uh or on Rumble videos on any
website so there's a command you can
download it
but you know you want to be sure it's
not some virus okay so let me talk about
that today that's the topic welcome to
another episode of talk show if you are
here say hi I love to see your comments
GCS good morning if you are not here
skip around and play at 1.5
speed because I Rambo okay so YouTube
download so let's just begin
okay so show in browser today's talk
show so um go to Kad kadi search k.in
info type
YouTube and download so you can see
there's a command to download YouTube so
this there is yt- DP
so you click on that go to the GitHub
page and uh there it is
however um so this one
got
100,000 Stars okay but a few years ago
they got taken down by uh by GitHub or
or something okay something happened to
it so and also some people complain that
the code update is too slow you know
they have to update it constantly
because whenever you you know you you
download the YouTube uh you know
YouTube um video you have to pass the
HTML to find where is the video link
usually it's not one link and usually
you know there's a lot of hack to make
it so that you cannot download the video
usually a video for example 30 Minutes
video they are fractured into you know
five minutes pieces and all cryptic so
they they you know all the websites
video website they want to prevent you
from downloading the video
right so so that's why you got this
YouTube download command okay but they
have to change it like every week every
month uh because YouTube you know once
they know you got this program they
change their code so they Shuffle around
so your code to download video no longer
works okay so they have to update
constantly so then then few years ago
about two years ago uh the you know uh
either GitHub shut it down or something
or someone hacked I forgot uh I think
GitHub shut it down something so there
people start to F it so then you got
this new command
youtube-dl instead of yt- DLP so you you
got a fork and this
one this one let's go
there there you you know this this
website and let's go to the GitHub so
actually let's copy the URL go to the
talk show page let's paste the link here
make a link make a list showing
browser there it is okay so we go there
so you got this new version YouTube DL
now okay so supposedly it's
better and it's also on GitHub of course
so you click on that um documentation
download uh let's go to uh GitHub
where's the
GitHub download video from YouTube they
can download from YouTube or any other
uh most major video websites so let's
click on Doc documentation so there it
is your uh
GitHub so you see so but you have to
update these commands about every month
because after a month you try it again
it won't work it says you know the
YouTube code changed so you have to
update the program so typically they
have a option YT DLP for example let's
go to so let's go to
Powershell mag ify the
font okay uh what is this command YT
DLP YTD
LP so let's see GCM g g so there it is
so YT DLP G GCM stand for um get command
okay that's the abbreviation for get
command in power sh and this so it
basically shows you whether you have it
installed in your path you know and uh
it's analogous to the Linux witch
command Okay so anyway
[Music]
you uh GCM and let's say Dash Ed okay
Dash Ed is for
help uh let's magnify Dash Edge again so
there is an option for update so you can
just you know command name and dashu I
think to update the latest version from
GitHub but there's a problem you
see there is a problem you see these
open-source websites they became you
know this open source software they
became popular because there's open
source so a lot of the open source
idiots they love it because you can look
at the
code so you can be sure that there's no
nasty virus or spyware installed on your
on your computer you know this is very
interesting because in the '90s usually
you just download a software and run it
such as emac or VI so how do you know
you know this program doesn't actually
check you know what's your photo album
you know what's in your bedroom you know
or start your listening devices camera
and you know Snoop on you you don't know
the the the the sure way to know is you
can look at the source
code so that's the idea of Open Source
so the open source
idiots uh it be they they became idiots
because lots of fake news lots of
propaganda so they you know we trust
open source right but when you use this
for example when you use this YouTube
download you need to up
updated so but how do you know somebody
doesn't didn't introduce viruses or
spyware into the program you don't know
you just press you know YouTube download
dasu update then then you got the latest
version and when you try to run it it
actually maybe check what photos you
have what's your friends what's your
contact you know things like that how do
you know it's not there you don't know
vast majority of the open-source idiots
you know they think it's open source but
they never looked at the code okay they
never looked at at the code so so I have
these commands you know YouTube download
I've been using them starting around
2012 okay I don't use it much you know
like like once every few month usually
but there's a need sometimes this
important video I really need to uh you
know to to save it sometimes it's my own
uh YouTube okay my own
video so you want to use this program
however you you know usually it's a mess
this open source there's lot lots of
folks and usually you don't know who is
the author like sometimes they are
sponsored by uh Google of course you
sometimes it's good you know Google just
you know we are we we we are helping the
open source but actually they are
controlling full control taking over you
know this happen in the past 20 years
this this commercial for money
Enterprises Google Facebook
Microsoft they sponsored open source
like today all the funding is came from
this without their money open source
dies right away like overnight okay
including Linux you know without this
Google or this red hat red hat is like a
small company but not really they are
backed by Google and Facebook and
Microsoft okay there's all sort of
connections so if Google Microsoft
Facebook or or Amazon you know they pull
out open source will die overnight okay
so anyway here the point is you have to
look at a source code that's a you know
that's a goal you want to make sure
there's no viruses but who does that
most people don't you know
nobody so you have to actually do it um
so so usually I'm very careful about you
know this you know every program I use
every extension every browser I mean
browser is so big millions of lines you
cannot possibly look into okay so so I
never actually looked into the browser
source code especially Google
Chrome today it has become so nasty okay
so nasty you can't believe it for
example today when I started the talk
show I relaunched
um uh
uh let's go to screenshot okay
so I relaunched the Google Chrome and I
got this you know uh ublock or engine
was turned off this extension is no
longer supported Chrome recommends that
you remove
it I just got this today so Google
Chrome browser they are from Google of
course and they want to control it and
you know they don't let you install this
ad blocker so I have to you know so that
means you know you're going to spend an
hour to look into so anyways open source
open source okay so means you have to
look at the code or you rely on someone
you really really really trust who is
into you know watching these things then
you know you know maybe you can trust
them uh anyway I talked a lot I want to
start to uh get this okay so like this
open source you don't know who they are
who wrote them sometimes they are backed
by Google but sometimes it's good
sponsorship sometimes it's nasty you
know they actually you know you know I
give you money hey I give you a a
million you know for something this
popular it's going to be like a million
dollars hey I give you million dollars
you do you know make sure your program
do this this or that for me you know you
don't know like you know this like I'm
particularly talking to you bunch of
guys who are like so poor open source
like Linux is the best why are you not
using Linux oh you are stupid you still
using Windows uh you think this is not
good but actually you don't know but
actually you are a [ __ ] idiot okay
this Linux this this open source not
just Linux they are
actually promoting crimes promoting the
massive damage to
programmers uh they but they don't know
because they are they are like the they
are like just the pawns you know they
are manipulated by the big Powers so I'm
particularly talking to those type of
people a lot of them follow
me uh so hello GCS and uh um
yeah okay so loving the T-shirt yeah
this t-shirt is the talking point it you
know is see this t-shirt is actually not
my
style this t-shirt is actually not my
style because I'm I'm a serious guy I'm
a I'm you know I'm a I'm a serious guy
I'm not into jokes or comedy but this
this t-shirt is a uh is a talking point
so it it makes it easier for people to
approach me
because uh compile mod of emac that is
really great Dam dam serious gamer uh
yeah I I haven't actually played games
games much but anyway let's look into
this okay so so I want you know you know
so right now my my YouTube download tool
is so outdated so what I want is to
update it but but I don't want just to
run the update okay so let let me show
you
okay uh so let's go to
aeve sometimes some command you don't
use for a while you forgot what is the
appr okay so let's go there so you see I
got two of them one is running the
YouTube download and the other one is
running the YT DLP okay
um you know like you guys are saying you
know which one is the fork cve which
looks like they are
like oh yeah so the YT DLP is a new one
okay my
mistake so
um yeah so YT DLP now let's I want to
look at the source code because you know
I want to use this but
um so first of all does anyone of you
actually know like can you tell me for
certain this is still good you know like
you know like you know you have to be
sure uh before you use
it so new buffer so I want to
um let's just get clone okay get clone
that but however I don't want the
history so because you know I don't want
the history code so uh because that
takes longer to download so let's go to
git index let's see if I so here's a
tutorial learn git in one hour s.
info practical G in one hour okay so
that's all you need to know now from a
project uh do I have a
I don't have I don't I don't have the
without history okay let's just get the
whole thing or we can
search
um get clone without history
okay okay it's just a dash dash
dep okay let's just do that get
clone that and the dash dash dep one
let's say two okay do
it okay so now it's there go to the
directory uh search for UT UT okay there
it is the directory there are the
files this is going to be you know takes
an hour or two to actually look into
because
um what are they
um so this is python
99.9% python code
okay uh I'm okay with python you know
I'm not too bad with python
so you got lots of these darker [ __ ]
compos yml you know yml so this is like
you know when you do a real job at a you
know company this is what you have to
deal with uh so here's a bash bash
script so you got to know so then you
got to know do do this is
do configuration
uh the Y
yml uh
template so in it so so how do we
actually look
into um you know I'm not too familiar
with all these Frameworks and structures
and
stuff so a bunch of
tests so here is the actual source code
uh it's big it's maybe 10,000 lines of
code so this one is 4,000 lines of code
okay this is 4,000 lines of code just
this file so all
together uh it might be 10,000 lines of
code 10,000 okay 10,000 is not too
bad okay why is it all you know some
coloring got [ __ ] okay yeah some
coloring got [ __ ] because this is you
see this part is a string but but the
rest become string color so I'm using S
python mod so something in my code you
know my my python mod is like just just
a quick
hack okay let's see where it where it
things starts to [ __ ]
up it's still good okay now back back
back back okay starting
somewhere must be a regular expression I
suppose okay now
starting let's
[Music]
see there it is starting here it got
[ __ ]
up I knew it because regular expression
you know regular expression is extremely
hard to pass the problem here is that
you see I'm using SAR python mod which
is only like 100 lines you know it's a
quick hack because I don't like the
default so if I switch to the python mod
the bundled python
mod you see the problem goes away you
see the problem goes away but if I use S
python mod you see the coloring got
[ __ ] up beginning here in this line
because of of that double
quote uh and this is not a trivial
problem to solve because this happens
because you have
to pass the double quote you know that
that is called quotation mark the full
Unicode name okay you see quotation mark
so one of the let me talk about this
okay
digression one you see the the use of
the quotation mark for string is one of
the most
harmful uh tradition design from C
[ __ ] okay back in 30 40 years ago
uh well I don't think it start from C
begin you know but but anyway the
quotation mark for string is one of the
major [ __ ] up why because the quotation
mark is not a matched pair okay such as
parenthesis when you have a matched
pair such as paren bracket or curly
braces okay then for every character
there's exactly one another character
that matches okay but not for quotation
you know because you know because you
are using the same character
to to indicate a bracket basically so
there's no way given a quotation mark
there's no way to determine whether that
is a beginning or the end there's no way
okay you have to look at the context
okay so that's when things gets
extremely
complicated and that's also how um yeah
that that's a you know that's how you
get extremely complicated that's why you
have this problem you know the confusion
of which part is string which part is
not okay so let's uh so that so this is
a program in language design issue in
particular it's
a programming language syntax design of
the syntax issue and more specifically
more narrowly it's it's a problem of the
choice of characters or lexical grammar
in the syntax design of a programming
language okay this is critical because
because when you you know you know you
you know it's well known that regular
expression with all the back back slash
they have a toothpick syndrome and they
are
unreadable why does that happen where
does this problem belong to this problem
belongs to the lexical grammar the
design of the lexical grammar of the
programming languages syntax okay
critical we got all these problems
because some
idiot this designer they follow
tradition they follow the C syntax
because it's well known every idiots you
know coders follow it if you use
something else they they see oh this is
OD you know why can't they just use the
you know sing double Cote for the string
you
know so you got this problem of
unreadability of regular expression okay
and that's all because of
the lexical grammar design of the syntax
of the programming language so sometimes
you hear people say you know syntax is
not important you know the programming
language the most important is semantics
that's the most idiotic [ __ ] idea okay
spread by some so-called computer
scientist okay and spread all by all the
C
C++ and idiots
so sandov visis says I have to write an
article about o versus functional for
college thoughts on the matter yes I
have a very good article on that let me
show you okay remind me Christopher says
one day I will have a computer where I
understand every program I run uh yeah
that's um that's ideal you know that's
that's a good thing to follow I mean you
can be a normal a Nory which you know
you don't care much like vast majority
like 99% of computer users they just use
Windows like my wife or what you know
whoever you know windows or sometimes
they use Mac you know they just download
programs they they have no idea what's
you know what's the app you know what
what's the source code they just use it
um but even some you know a lot of Linux
uh users they also just use it they
don't actually check the source code in
that so anyway back to so we were
talking about the syntax design the
lexical grammar design the choice of
characters so that's one thing uh let me
let me hold on a second let me uh gather
myself okay so make a
screenshot so we have a record of what
we talked about
okay so close that let's go back to
um c talk show put the images here okay
and uh showing browser so that's what we
talked about today this is a
lexical problem of passing
string design lexical grammar syntax
design
truth pick syndrome of regular
expression that's some of the things we
talked about and let me just show
you um you know I have like 40 articles
on regular expression
okay truth
okay let's just say
truth pick syndrome okay so especially
bad is iMac disp so you can kind of see
this you know this is passing a image
tag you know but
it it become unreadable okay so let me
just show you some examples so you got
this uh you know 12 backs slashes in
sequence you have to do that because of
the
escape and the most what so then there
you see this one so anyway that's the
toothpick syndrome okay that's known as
the toothpick
syndrome okay we talked about that and
also okay we talked about the brackets
so let me show you the
brackets so there it is n syntax design
bracket versus beginning and end of
indentation so that's another related
issue okay so
uh so let me show you some of the
Articles that's all related to
that okay so next syntax bracket versus
beginning end versus indentation okay
that's another kind of um Hot Topic okay
I'm not gonna go into that close that
and this page shows you all unic code
characters for bracket which is
fantastic because then you can choose so
many varieties of brackets and then you
don't need you know you don't want the
back slash Escape you can avoid
that if you are designing a programming
language Sy tax okay so close that so so
these are uh part of the brackets these
are math brackets each one of them is
used mostly for mathematics designed for
math those are in Unicode okay so copy
that okay so we talked about that then
we go let's go back uh let's go back
let's go back yeah so so let's switch
switch to python mod oh not run python
shut up kill
it python mod okay so now we don't have
that
problem so this you know we were going
to look into this um you know this
source code let's say Define this
matching lines 179 matches for defin so
there's like
179 functions or nested functions okay
so and uh what are these functions catch
and save extension error one if short ID
add info
extractor uh to stand out to
screen you know to look at this code it
will take several hours
so yeah it will take several
hours so let's let's make a screenshot
of
this okay and uh this is just one file
import look let's look at the
import import one gazillion F import
collections context Library copy daytime
a
DT error
error output file input function
tools uh cookie jar IO iteration tools
Jason local
operator H it has to import
operator and operating system random
okay re regular
expression uh sh utility strings sub
process system temp file oh temp file uh
time tokenize Trace back Unicode data
okay that's all these are
not not so odd but I don't know what is
the context
lib and I'm not sure what is copy
uh yeah the rest seems
self-explanatory okay
so yeah but there's 179 so that's one of
the file
close and
uh then
dependencies
crypto crypto doome
and so this is you have to deal
with okay so anyway I don't think I can
properly you know look into so let's
digress uh extractor yeah this is
huge so here's Amazon is is there a
Twitter that's what I'm interested
okay so you see base regular expression
you see they change this all the time
that's why it
fails uh I
suppose uh yeah you know so coding has
become so complicated so much hack you
know why is it you know like normally if
you want to embed a
video it's so easy you know like MP3 you
know I for for example
this you just use the audio video tag
okay then let me show
you search for video tag there it is you
know if you are Twitter if you are
YouTube you know if you want to embed
video all you have to do is a video tag
with the you know path to the video file
right but of course they don't do
that the reason is that oh because you
know then you don't you know this
doesn't support uh translation or
whatever but the actual the real
reason they don't do this is because
then you can just download any video so
this tremendous hack to to [ __ ] it up
you know that that that is why then then
of course the hackers you know the the
the open- source idiots you know they
think they are Freedom Fighters oh
you're gonna do that so I'm a coder I'm
gonna code the YouTube download so
you're gonna [ __ ] you up you know so so
that's why then you got this tremendous
bunch of incomprehensible code and
nobody actually read it so then
eventually you got a situation like
today like we what we are we have to
spend hours just to make sure they are
not doing like illegal
stuff the real proper you know attitude
is
that if they are doing something
wrong you sue them okay if you are doing
something nasty embedding some some some
some some nasty code or you
know they go to jail okay they go to
jail and meanwhile whatever you use you
pay for it okay you go to Google you pay
for it you don't demand you know we must
have open source otherwise we I'm going
to tell all my friends to stop using
your stuff that is when things beginning
to [ __ ] up okay you open source
[ __ ] because you demand you know
all the source software must be open
sourced you know so so Google Twitter
your Facebook you know they have to they
have to be free and actually open source
basically means free because other
because if you if it's not free I I take
your open source I create my company
using the same code then you Google you
don't have you know you don't have
customers you know I I sell it
cheaper open source essentially means
just free you have to give it out free
but then the open source [ __ ] they
they are scums okay they lie they say oh
open source doesn't mean you it's free
uh you can charge but just the source
code must be free like the Richer
storman storman [ __ ] him okay that's
evil that's a fundamental evil of Open
Source only Richard storman can make
money he still make money because you
donate because he's the God right he's
the greatest most ethical
guy so anyway so you have to pay okay
pay for what you use and don't demand
open source instead demand law if they
[ __ ] up whoever runs the company the CEO
go to jail immediately or the death
penalty okay if you dare to like do some
nasty things you could go to jail that
is what you should demand not the open
source because what happens if you just
demand open source that's what you have
today you know you got the Google Chrome
which is 10 million lines nobody can
possibly understand it why it became 10
million lines because all the hack to
you know to prevent you know this this
or that trickery that's what it
is and why do they keep adding things to
browser exactly because that they don't
want you to be able to like understand
the thing
so they pretend Open Source yeah Google
Chrome is still open source you you just
go you know this version open source
then we added our own reasonably so you
know we got Google Chrome if you want
open source we got chromium for you for
you open source
[ __ ] okay and even chro chromium of
course nobody can understand why don't
they Google just you know release the
Google Chrome as open source
of course they cannot do that because if
they do then every other company will
have a Google Chrome then Google Chrome
will have no business
anymore then the other
thing the the other consequence when you
demand open source is that they move
they move to the cloud like what happens
today you know everything you do all
your data is in someone else's computer
in their computer they keep it for you
you know your email your your email your
Twitter you know whatever you
say they are so nice they keep the files
for you if you want to download whatever
you have posted in the past year it's
impossible before you know few years ago
Twitter provided like download you
download that it's incomprehensible it's
like one go [ __ ] you know that's what
happens they move to the cloud why they
move to the cloud because because oh
they you know we need the super
computers your your computer is too
small so we are doing all these things
good for you but the real reason is if
they don't move to the cloud they are a
software and you open source [ __ ]
demand it to be open source so they move
to the cloud they are no longer in the
software business we are in the servers
business so your open source
has no power you open source and free
software Fanatics [ __ ] that's the
problem that's a situation you guys
created in the past about 20
years okay so we become like you think
you are the freedom fighter you are so
based I love you you know hacking this
you know no trust the Google but hacking
open source
that's exactly what they want we are
destined to be this little petty
nothingness you know like doing little
things you know meanwhile the or you
have no other way to survive because you
write code they are 1 billion open
source on GitHub sponsored by
Microsoft one billion of them and who do
this people work for you know this this
YouTube download you think they are hero
right they are great hero they work for
Google they work for Google Microsoft or
you know or or JavaScript not you know
these corporations they make a lot of
money 10,000 a month
minimum at night they are for your
freedom they create all this open source
so so that it robs or any other
programmers job like me if you don't
work for Google you have no job
okay because every code you write
there's 1 billion free open source
written by those working for commercial
organ organizations with 1 million
lawyers you know they Chun out this open
source on
GitHub so you open source
[ __ ]
like you know I can't totally blame you
because you don't know you you know you
don't know you you are just little P
manipulated by the by the
machines okay that's a giant digression
and but anyway we did look into this uh
and uh as I know you know I cannot
possibly
like understand the code you know to to
have a little understanding of a code
we'll take a few days um but but I
wanted to talk about this issue so in
summary you you know you you can't
totally just trust these tools like like
um you know like running update so let
me try to run update okay for example I
want to get
um
so no not YouTube download so you know
it's always confusing like what the um
yeah I forgot what's my Abri so I have
to go
to
cytd okay so CYT
D CYT D okay that's the one I want so
let's try to to download a video okay so
let's say this one you know this one is
a this one is
spitten um you know maybe that not that
one so because that's politics so let
let's go to something like easier you
know not not so
sensitive uh oh by the way I want to
mention you know this image
um yeah I want to mention that but let
me let me get back to that later okay oh
yeah so there's also a question I'll get
to
that so I want to hold on a second okay
I want to download let's download a
video okay so
let there a fun video there it is let's
get this
[Music]
one pretty girls
the universal appreciation okay so I
want to get this video so copy that copy
that go to um let's try
it you see unsupported
URL
um yeah it's not unsupported well
because
um so okay tror also change name so
let's try
Twitter command not found okay wait
yeah you see you got error so error no
video could be found now where is the
update
um so let's update okay
so
yeah dashu let's try dashh is that
supposed to be help
okay uh search for update okay so there
it is capital u for update so let's try
it so capital u so this is when you
in advant in
advant download a virus to your pro to
your computer you don't even know
it you know it's like muscle reflex oh
it doesn't work you need to update it
there it
is so you see and on Windows you got
this executable you just got
this uh yes open literally you know you
just got this
executable okay 18 megabyte
there
um yeah so that's why so you have to
look into the code now if I try that
again you know download this video you
know what will happen it'll probably
work
but but you don't know if it what what
it did to your computer you don't know
you
know okay that's about it so let me
answer the questions and uh yeah so
there is a question about functional
programming versus
O So for that question you could there's
one article okay let me show you you can
search for
op um and uh
functional style of loop
um so lots of lots of Articles let's
see object
oriented there it is okay this article
object oriented programming jargons and
complexities okay you open that so this
article written in
2005 basically gives you a understanding
of oop in terms of functional
programming okay this is one of my
popular
article
um object oriented programming jargons
and complexities in terms of so it
explains class methods objects in terms
of fun
code okay what exactly what you know
what exactly are they doing what exactly
is you know these class methods objects
then you
have then you have static and instance
variables you know what are they what
the [ __ ] is static and instance then you
have the rights of Constructors and
accessors you know o joggin what exactly
do they mean what actually what do they
actually do how are they different from
you know what is what you know how they
are they different from a sub routine
you know what makes it qualify as
Constructor or what what is accessor you
know these op Jons then the rise of
access
specifiers access specifiers private
public then you the rise of inheritance
what the [ __ ] does it mean what does
this mean in mathematics you know I want
to know mathematics I don't know I don't
want to know the what of Allie [ __ ] I
don't want to know the computer idiots
jargons programmer idiots I want to know
permanent
mathematics what does what does The
Inheritance what is this in mathematics
that's what I want to
know the rise of
inheritance then the rise of um the rise
of class hierarchy
then you got a hierarchy of the class
then the rise of and mutation of
interface and the rise of abstract class
and Abstract methods then the rise of
iterators and
enumerators okay and the babling about
code reuse and the Jon of
polymorphism okay so this is my essay
written in
2005 beginning and that kind of
explained the whole thing in terms of
simple functions okay so there is a
relation between functional programming
and O um so that's my
explanation so I think that might be
useful to your
essay okay I think that's it
um have I written compiler
no uh I wanted to I haven't no yeah
so so that's it thank you
guys
um yeah but uh let me mention one more
thing okay so one more thing
about
gr okay so before we have lots of these
you know
gr since three three months ago it went
bad uh the gro image generation so all
the image you see these are generated by
Gro all you have to do is ask you know
draw a beautiful Chinese hot girl hot
Chinese girl wearing a shirt with Le
written on then you'll generate this you
know these photos you know show me a
drawing black and white uh you know
wearing a hot top of a hot
girl then you got this okay or Draw show
me a emac got this you know all these so
all these are generated by Gro three
months ago okay now draw draw me
something you know surprise anime girl
you'll show that okay
beautiful and you know VI versus swi you
know emac versus
swim and then this wolf and you know
wolf and girl okay this amazing
beautiful extremely
beautiful you know draw me a girl and
with a wolf and you'll draw or draw me a
beautiful Chinese girl with a wolf
okay
fantastic okay and this one is
interesting this is draw draw myself
based on my
treats it show me as as this Warrior
Panther okay and and oh my God this one
is the most hot this is is the hardest
one amazing I love it so much it's so
beautiful as as as a human animal you
have to appreciate Beauty okay and
Beauty predominantly they came from
girls young girls that is the essence of
Beauty in humanity okay when you stop
appreciating Beauty you lost you get you
know you got lost you you lost your soul
okay then you you start to [ __ ] up chaos
you know which is kind of like what we
have
today okay so um so that's gr and uh and
then um but sometimes in December gr
went walk the gro image generation okay
so this is before and now you ask
exactly the same thing this is what you
you
get exactly the same prompt okay gr
became so bad okay so here's a summary
of before and I tried here is what
happens after you know I tried and tried
this you know you try all kind of
different prompt you know all you get is
this crap and some of them you see even
censored can you see like all these are
closed there's nothing you know like
controversial but some of them to they
got
sensored so this is very interesting
gr image generation part went w okay uh
but what made it worse is that you see
Adam musk who created quo he emphasized
so much that things must not be work
emphasize so
much
but but since December update you know
last year 2024 December gr update image
the image part the text part I think
it's still good I think it's getting
better but the image part went so bad
but however you see on Twitter no like
nobody talks about it barely any because
Gro before you see all the mara people
say oh yeah Gro is so bad better you
know thank you Adam musk but now it went
the image generation went completely
woke and always quiet you know every
time Adam mention quook like nobody this
Mara
[ __ ] I support Mara by the way but
I mean but but you have the situation
you know all the replies are ask kissas
nobody mentioned that g becom so work
this is this is you know this is like
this
is the opposite of what El musk is
promising but you talk about it on
Twitter like you don't get re you know
like nobody sees your message like
nobody is talking about it so this is
very kind of odd and
nasty situation you know I I have
replied post it to the go team you know
you don't get much you know you don't
get response
so that's the um that's a quook okay and
that and I think that's it uh let's go
back to talk show and that's it now so
you like my stuff just pay me okay I
want to need to mention this every every
video kinfo you go there go to the
bottom is patreon you can do patreon but
I prefer Amazon gift card or p PayPal
use the link okay because if you don't
use the link you you I won't get money
okay so because you R you use the wrong
email address or you use Amazon from
Japan or Germany I cannot get the money
okay you paid
Amazon Amazon basically ate the money
you know I cannot get the money so you
have to use Amazon USA you know follow
my link okay so go to kinfo botton you
know pay PayPal me or stuff 100 bucks
thank you so that's it for today uh
anything
else bye guys