good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show today is 2021
uh july 3rd july 3rd
tomorrow is july 4th
the birthday of america
and today as the american would say this
is a long weekend today is saturday
and here is san francisco time san
francisco two o'clock in the afternoon
so what are we going to do today so if
you have a question
for me put it in the chat box uh with my
name okay
hi exact i was wondering uh what do you
think of this and that
hello cortez so
okay so uh otherwise i'm gonna start to
do
i'm gonna start to do some emacs okay so
uh let's go to talk show
in the pink window and i wanted to show
you
you know let's talk about some recent
happenings in emacs
as a prelude so bob says i want to buy
kyle kyle box navy switches
they are super heavy do you recommend
again instead
um that's fine
that's fine but like i said if you have
repetitive strain injury
or if you type a whole lot like
continuously more than one hour a day
if you lock your key strokes you'll know
uh then i would recommend linear
light switches i talked about it in my
last
video two linear light switches uh
such as 40 no more than 45
grams of force required to activate the
key so
if you type a lot aspire a key lock
really a lot and if you have a hand pin
then you want linear light switches
otherwise uh that you know whichever key
switches that's fine
such as the happy hacking topper
okay so let's talk let me tell you
something about emacs okay so
there's a updated command and thanks to
uh thanks to divine dominion
christian tears uh who
helped me uh debug this command okay
so in emacs you know in applications we
have copy and paste
and in emacs you have you can have all
uh
paste history so you press a key you can
see
you know you can see all the uh paste
histories
you know uh there so that's this command
show key or ring you you can see i call
the command right there
in the pink window and you can find the
source code so that's
one thing new uh
then there is a you know
i want to see what to talk about
something
yeah key switches it's kind of personal
okay so
some people have heavy hands you know
you might need
prefer a heavy switch linear you know
red switch is too light for you
it's uncomfortable but but as
as i said if you have you know uh
hand pan or type a lot linear switches
is probably your
best choice otherwise it's kind of
personal
nobody can say so there's a question
pixel outlaw says do you think it's
possible to make a
small diagram drag and drop float chart
maker with emax svg library and mouse
click
operations do you think it's possible to
make a small diagram drag and drop
flow chart what do you mean drag okay
drag and drop you mean like like user
interface uh
flowchart maker with emacs svg library
and is where which one what is the
e-max svg library and mouse click
operations you mean within emacs
so clarify your question so you mean you
want to generate a svg diagram
just say a little diagramming tool so
first question is are you going to are
you talking about generating the
diagram in to be viewed inside emacs or
do you mean
um generated and viewed in browser
and interactive in the browser do you
mean within emacs or interactive in
browser
so let me so let's go to some fly key
so let's show you so i have
here you are looking at sunflower keys
and
you scroll down scroll down scroll down
again let's turn on the javascript
so we see the youtube so you see what i
so you see
there's a svg diagram and
so this is in your browser it's not you
know you can use emacs
so let me show you the page okay so you
looking at the svg
svg diagram and go to emacs open the
page
and search for svg you can see
this block of code is the svg
you know so you can use e-max to
generate this
of course because it's just a test text
file you can use e-magnets to generate
it but what
then it's a javascript coding to make it
uh do things
so yes generating and viewing inside so
if you want to view
uh i wouldn't recommend it okay so so
here's the svg source code you can see
let's go let's you see you see this is
the source code inside
html file now
now let's go to uh let's go to keyboard
okay
let me show you uh
let me show you some svg file okay
we're gonna talk about keyboard actually
yeah
okay where is it um
where's my images what
the hide hide the
so here is my bunch of images
oh i don't i don't know okay so you can
see so here okay
hang on a second so here is uh
this is a directory and here is a bunch
of image files
and some of them are svg you can see
those highlighted are svg files now
now watch the pink window okay i'm going
to call command
show in the folder viewer then you can
see the windows we are
on windows and magnify and
alt v for view l for
the view type and idiotic windows you
don't have a key to switch to different
type you have to use arrows so there it
is
so let's see extra large icons so you
can see
this photo is full of images and some of
them are png and some of them are svg
okay
cancel so for example this one is svg
so it asks you which browser you want to
use to open it
okay brave so you can see svg scalable
vector graphics so you have infinite
resolution
you know clarity instead of the jpeg or
png
bitmap crap bitmap like the javascript
canvas
invented by apple idiots and the gamers
you know the cc
plus plus programmers the memory
management they love it
they love bitmap
uh so bitmap is no good okay svg so
svg is good so here's another svg file
now
now so the so lim so i want to uh
so okay so go back here close that back
to emacs
so we showed some svg file okay so let's
open one of them okay so here
svg file open it actually let's open
this one whatever this one okay this one
is
uh cormac layout layers
wait what what kind what exactly
i mean is call my layout layers i i'm
not sure
exactly what type of core mag it
anyway let's look at the file okay open
it
so you can see so here is the svg source
code as a file
instead of embedded inside html so
here is how emacs shows it uh but can
you
can can you actually view it as an image
i'm not sure actually let's open it
and let's say image mod
okay so you can you can actually view
svg files
inside
e-max okay i
okay i i i must have done this before
but i don't remember okay but
let's see if we can magnify uh image
you know describe mod to see the
documentation for the mod am i alive am
i talking good
comment okay so now we are looking for
increased size okay
image uh increased size mouse four five
you know the
idiotic e max jargon
which key the is the mouse four
and five
control c control four and five is the
score
scroll wheel okay so the unix the x11
you unix idiocy incomprehensible
so c is control mouse45 that means hold
down control key and
scroll up up and down doesn't work but
actually i think this
i think maybe uh
anyway so it didn't work for svg but
it probably works for a jpeg file so
let's try try png
okay wait uh let's try hold on a second
let's try
another png file let's just magnify okay
the normal magnification
um doesn't work
okay describe function so what is the
increase rate image mouse increase
size okay um
i'm trying to magnify
okay let's see okay
a plus okay wait that's increased speed
okay just plus sign i thought so but uh
okay so there it is so that's a png file
you see we are losing resolution here
because it's a png file
sign for increased size minus five sign
for decrease size okay
now that's a png file now let's try svg
file
okay now go to image mod
now plus plus good
good good okay there's some
issues with there is a problem with
emacs you can see
svg stand for scalable vector graphics
infinite resolution but in e-max it's
not
infinite resolution
because why i can tell you why because
the implementation
the way emacs view svg image is probably
first first converted to png
okay that so that's a flaw you know
some people you know of you emax
phonetics you'll say oh emac is the best
in everything
so i'm showing you actually a problem
where every software that does svg don't
have that problem
but in e-max you have that problem but
among e-max communities communities
you'll never hear it so
you know this kind of problem is
everywhere in emacs but you know people
just
ignore it like like you know the
phonetics
so svg you know in every application
that display svg
it's that the heart of of svg is
you know scalable but but then when you
view emacs in events
it doesn't okay i don't know we i don't
know
maybe on wind on linux it does better i
don't know
is that is that so so anyway back to
your question you are saying you want to
so you want to basically if i understand
you correctly okay
uh you know uh answer me if i'm not okay
like right away so if i understand your
question correctly
you want to have a svg diagram
generated in emaclis of course and and
view it
entirely in emacs like here
and and uh
wait why is it not why is it not
okay and uh
what why why can't i just uh
magnify again
yeah some some sometimes you run into
problems you know that that's that's the
problem
of emacs why can't i
okay now i can you know again you lose
resolution you see
so you want to do svg inside emacs and
yeah not recommended okay forget about
it
you know first of all you already see
seen the resolution problem then
i think i believe you are you you want
to actually make it
interactive forget it
okay converting svg to unt that's a flat
earth level genius probably
some leap carrier stuff okay so i'm not
using emacs on linux
on linux it might be better okay not
it's it's not for sure you know it
always have these kind of
problems even on linux but i don't know
for sure okay maybe on linux is
it's better but that but but
even even if it works in linux you still
have the problem you know
emacs supposed to be cross-platform
just like wufam like wufam language you
know
one application runs everywhere the same
now you wanna so now if you wanna do
what what's the point what's the point
browser is you know one one one thousand
times more compatible
used by everywhere else you generate it
showing in browser
can view on the phone can view anywhere
you know javascript html svg standard
technology
you do it so what what is the use what's
what is the possible usage on
svg emacs well there's some use for
example
you know so for example i can see some
use for example uh
stuff like keys right this is a key
binding package
it would be nice you know when you when
i talk about this key binding i can have
a diagram inside it here
actually we can have that actually
so let's let's do let's let's
do some of that okay so let's see
um so did i miss any questions
so let me read the comments in a second
okay hold on a second let me just
uh uh yeah let's try to embed the image
because that's
okay so uh so what
what are we doing to do okay let's just
for example okay so
so this example let me show you an
example okay
digression okay so there is a a
movement by the you know keyboard nerds
trying to
improve the standard layout of a laptop
keyboard
so you can see this is a normal laptop
keyboard layout
which sucks because it's a 100 years
package
you know the staggered layout so
this guy this is a japanese guy you can
see the github here
you know he's get her page he has
improved he he changed it over the years
anyway so so this guy created
a ergonomic layout
you know trying to kind of standardize
it
you know he published on github telling
other people and
you can see this is uh this is his
results symmetric
and uh you know symmetric and it's and
you can
and one of the surprising things is that
with this symmetric ergonomic layout you
actually have no more space
now you have more uh spots for extra
keys fantastic
i mean now you see this uh space hugging
spacebar you don't need that such a big
bot
you know people like that because habit
you know habit is a problem
you know if you look at your key you you
never like you you never need to use use
your palm to place
spacebar you know i have an article on
the on the spacebar you just search for
um you know what some article here
anyway so
this is an improved ergonomic layout and
in turn and it gives you much more uh
thumb keys you know windows key alt
control they are right under your thumb
in backspace
much better and in fact you have actual
more spots for extra keys
so this is a surprising
surprisingly so this is then someone
another group okay this this group uh
called
uh you know they are
you know this keyboard o o llkb which is
a keyboard
club keyboard you know uh fans
they they created this
uh ortholinear layout for laptop
uh but by the way this photo this is not
a real photo it's a fake it's a
computer generated uh picture so they
are trying to
ask people whether it's good you know
they are trying to design it
anyway it's a good move so we are we are
trying to have
you know uh kind of a ortholinear or
or ergonomic layout for laptop keyboard
and we are trying to
uh kind of standardize it in some way
so like gradually more and more people
for example more and more
do it yourself people uh actually this
this laptop is kind of open source uh
laptop
so you go to the reddit link i have here
you go and you can read in detail
so more and more people you know maybe
beginning with a
fan clubs you know the do-it-yourself
community
then we have a standard uh laptop so
maybe in 20 years
maybe possibly 20 years later
all the laptops is going to have kind of
this layout or maybe this
uh so this is a seed you know who knows
what will happen in 20 years i'll be
i'll be gone
and you young people you know maybe you
have a family
most of you are young people you know
because all the people who know things
you know you don't they don't have time
to um watch youtube
so maybe in 20 years you'll have family
you'll be married you'll be managers and
you'll be
you'll forget about the unix crap you
don't talk about it anymore you'll be
out of the software
industry
uh so anyway so this is a good thing
okay so what
what i'm trying to do let yeah what i'm
trying to do let's let me show you okay
so
press the key copy these
okay copied okay now go uh split window
let's uh hold on second speed
okay let's um let's go to my emacs
blog okay now let me show you okay
add a section uh and add the picture
here
show in browser and it's optimizing the
you know
you see fantastic
screenshot and right away it's on my
browser so
so you can find the command on the ping
window okay so here is the image we just
did a screenshot
okay now we can embed this screenshot
inside
the source code of emacs so so
go back to the flag keys for example
let's go
make a backup let's paste it here okay
wait
go back here open it copy it back to the
source code software keys
paste it you see fantastic now you have
an image
embedded inside emacs
okay that's fantastic and by the way you
can do it with the wolfram language okay
i wanted to talk about wolf pham
uh uh
oofam desktop okay so let me use this
opportunity to show wufab
desktop you know we'll find desktop so
new file
paste it wait did it work paste
okay so uh when you have you know
copy image okay so now
you paste there it is so why did the
paste did not work you see
that's because emacs e-max is idiotic
let me explain okay
so we are trying to do i'm trying to
copy your image
you know so the content you know copy
the image
the content is basically you know for
example you can do it in browser copy
image okay so the data is kind of some
kind of binary data
supported by the windows operating
system you can do it on the mac as well
then on the mac or windows uh you can uh
open microsoft word you know i don't
want to open it but
uh you know any application you can
usually
typically paste the image for example
let's see
let's see let's see in discord okay
let's
paste the image there it is okay
so we copy the image from the browser by
just any
any any web page you know you can just
right click copy image and you can paste
it
but now so we also paste it in wufang
language you can see
but now in in emacs it doesn't work okay
that's another problem you know the
problem with emacs lots of problems
so we uh so what what are we doing so um
what uh i want to what are we doing so
yeah yeah i've i screwed up
my supply keys for some reason
okay anyway so i want to open a new
buffer
wait what okay a new buffer now let me
try to paste it okay
paste
and it works um
okay anyway let's forget about that i
i'm not sure it what actually works
it works because we were using the old
email
uh emacs image from any anyway forget
about that okay
so i want to say so you see the woofing
language you can paste it and you can do
you can start to do a photo image
processing you can change the color
for example let me show you
quickly let's see if we can
okay so
i'm i'm digressing on the fly
into a territory i'm not very familiar
with okay
so because
image manipulation what i'm trying to
show you is that
wufang language can be used to
manipulate
image in a programmable way that is you
just write code
you can invert the image um you can even
use
artificial intelligence you just call a
function and the input
of this image as an input argument then
it will tell you what what
you know is it a cat or dog you know for
example
um so image processing here's uh
all the functions about image processing
you can see
uh you know so
okay i'm not going to do this then
because i'm not familiar with this
uh functionality this is introduced
within 10 years uh 10 years ago
you know you can you can you know you
can gaussian
okay let's try gaussian filter this
[Laughter]
okay let's just try this simply okay so
what okay so wait i need to input this
uh okay then
then the output let's try it okay so
here is the input of the image we just
pasted
and now let's say gaussian
let's magnify so you can see
so gaussian filter okay
and and the input is the image
let's try this okay let's let's let's
let's do this so you can easily see
x image equals to
copy it here back to there
paste it here so you actually you know
so i'm trying to show you the
integration of image and
programming language source code that's
what the mathematica notepad is so
we just pasted the image and we assigned
it assign it to x
okay a variable let's say enter okay
there it is output
now let's delete this crap now
now we say okay let's dd describe
now we say gaussian filter x
image in two one zero okay so what
whatever those arguments are
okay two one zero okay
enter fantastic
okay so we have to adjust some kind of
um
that's you know that's not much too much
contrast
let's see what happens oh now it's
better
so that's a little demo of wufam
language okay
it's free wufang language you just go to
xari
ufam free
then click get wufang language for free
you can buy a raspberry pi kit for like
fifty dollars
then it's free or you can download
wolfram engine or you can download
woofam script
i haven't yet you know i'm i i i need to
work on mathematica i i
you know i need to start to do a lot um
you know coding with mathematica i'm
going to show you okay
so anyway back to the question okay so
so so there are a lot of comments i kind
of missed okay so
so back to the emacs so we uh let's go
back to emacs okay
close that what's going on real text uh
coding system
state coding system what
close that what what's going on close
that
yeah real text whatever slack coding
system
i hate that when that happens okay
close that close that
i think i you know this
is one of the bug with e-max
yeah so it's uh you know because we
pasted
a image into uh sapphire keys
now it doesn't not it doesn't know how
to um
it doesn't know how to um
how to how to encode it you know what
kind of encoding to use
so undo undo so now i think we are
okay
okay now i think we are we
screwed up on the mini buffer
yeah yeah we restart emacs okay
restart emacs uh save with untitled what
buffer entitled
don't save close it don't save yeah
you can't even what what the
yeah e e max screwed up
untitled close select coding system
i wait when should i select the coding
system
okay control x
wait meta x meta x
keel buffer let's see if that works
cure buffer untitled okay fine idiotic
so what did i did we screw up something
i guess not so let's go back to emacs
blog
okay which we kind of showed that um
you know image in source code that's the
point that's the thing i want to show
it's useful because when you are
you know maybe you are writing some
program for geography
for you know for manipulating coordinate
you know earth coordinate you know gps
or if you are writing a program for key
binding
you know setting up keys so if you are
writing a driver linux driver for
uh firmware keyboard firmware you know
why you know typically you know the
point is that you
you should be able to have images
or whatever headers and section you know
names you know inside your source code
you know editor you know the editor
should not be limited to just text
that's a unix philosophy idiocy that's a
that's a that's a consequence of the you
know the unix
damage in society but now after 30 years
gradually we start to have that because
for example the python
julia notepad you know that no julia
notepad they copied
woofam notepad idea so you started to
see
especially you guys new generations you
started to see
you know an editor that you know has you
know section heading or math type
setting or including images so
so that's a point you know
it's a good thing okay source code do
not
necessarily should be uh just um
plain text and by the way you know you
see this image in
language let me save this okay so let me
show you this
uh neat thing so for example let's name
it tt untitled in desktop okay
now let's open this file so you can see
the actual source code
of what what kind of what kind of source
you know what kind of format it saves
this
uh image you'll be surprised let's go to
desktop okay
in emacs so here is a file we just saved
okay let's hide the you know detail okay
so open it
you can see pure text
but how how does it represent the image
you can see you see
this this thing you know raster box
raster you know remember
we talked about raster image format jpeg
png this is a raster image format
so this is how wufam language represent
um you know the uh
the uh binary binary code wu from
notepad
by the way so wolfram notepad is all
plain ascii text text okay it's not even
unicode so
the source code of wufab notepad is is
pure
um ascii code so in fact we can edit it
manually you know unix people love it
you know it we need text format so
therefore
people can edit it so let's edit it okay
so
you know so this part we don't need this
is a by the way this
kind of the parenthesis asterisk
that's the comment for wufam language
okay
so let's delete that so they're talking
about you know let's delete that and let
me
just show you you know delete those we
don't need and
and the entire you know again like i
talked before
ufan language is kind of like a family
of lisp okay you can think of it as a
lisp
so the entire syntax of wolfram language
is nested brackets like this okay so the
entire file you are looking at now is
begin with the notebook okay then
bracket then everything is inside okay
that
you see let's go to the matching uh
bracket okay
so you you see that's the end then
then at the end again it's a bunch of
the comments you know the cache
information
uh let me show you okay so you can
delete that
you can delete that you see notebook uh
online blah blah blah those are
temporary information we don't need it
okay so we we used
we used wufang language to create it
you know some a notebook we save it and
then then we open it in
emacs and we are around with it
and and i'm going to let's let's do
something okay let's rename
you see in the wolfram language we have
we
we name the variable y okay let's rename
it
to i mean we named the x
you know the variable the image is x now
let's let's just
you know let's do a surgery to rename
the variable
from x to y in emax then we
will be opening it in wolfram uh
notebook okay so let me show you so so
i'm trying to demonstrate the real
you know how the wolfram language is
actually just the text file
and it the whole thing is just a nested
nested brackets you know
the woofing language syntax extremely
uniform
so we rename it let's see okay so rename
it
y then uh you know this binary format is
actually so let's see if there's um
so where is the gaussian let's search
for g-a-u-s-s
okay so we call the function gaussian
filter then robots let's see
why okay i believe that's it let's save
it okay
save it close it
wait uh did we save it
opening our profile permission denied ah
on windows on windows if you have a file
that's opening another application
the window won't allow you to save it
but however on the mac it
it allows that so in order to save this
in emacs
we need to close this in wufang language
first okay
now in emacs save it okay now it's saved
now opening desktop uh
so here is a file let's open it again
let's see
there you have it you see this y
okay that's the power of wufan
language no notebook okay newfound
language syntax
and and everything
in fact i can you know actually i can
right now i can actually create a new
cell you know this thing
in an uphill language notebook you know
they are they group things by sell
for example you can have a title for
example uh what's the shortcut for title
cell format
style sheet uh
font format format style title old one
okay
for example press old one
the fantastic
land okay so save it
that's a title so wufab notebook it's
not just source code
it's you know think of it you know it's
like oak mod
you know you you emax users you are
familiar with oakmont oh okama can do
everything
it can export to a thousand different
format to html
to attack to mathml to whatever wufam
actually can do exactly the same thing
in fact more
so export uh do we have export
revert publish uh i haven't used publish
to cloud
save to cloud uh open cloud
you can um
i haven't used this before but you can
export to be
pdf to html to to um
i haven't used this feature for
you know the last time i use it is
probably 10 years ago i
don't know where did the export
menu went
some somewhere okay you can you know we
can start to look for
uh you know search for exports so but
since i'm talking about it i should show
it and forget about it
anyway so wolfram notepad you can think
of it it's like a oak mod
okay but much more powerful much much
more powerful so you can integrate you
know
image title heading subheadings and
and the type settings which are
demonstrated in
my woofing language video live stream
a month ago a month or two ago i have
several so go watch that
okay so that's a that's a huge
digression now
now let me uh kind of go through the
comments
and maybe that's kind of it i
for today i have uh you know we talked
about i kind of talked about a lot of
things
um so we've been talking for 40 minutes
okay
we can talk for 20 minutes more
digration okay so back to emacs so
it is indeed so close that it is
indeed useful to have images such as svg
inside uh you know a source code or a
text file
okay so you wanted to do svg and e-max
yeah you can but
you want interactivity and things like
that you know
e-max you know
even in oak mod e-max is actually you
are
kind of pushing the hack you know
because e-max is not really designed for
it
uh you are kind of using all sort of
hacks to to try to do it
such as you know when we you know yeah
so i wouldn't recommend it
so yeah let me finish reading the
comments uh
let's see okay so did i answer the
questions kind of or did i
digressed um so if you again comment now
okay so we'll see
so hexa meat says meet patel says hey
is there any particular reason you
swapped from mac to windows
haven't been here for a while yeah i
talked about that a lot of times
um i mean not well i talked yeah
i talked about a few times because
because about three months ago
i bought a pc okay uh
you searched my youtube three months ago
i talked about that so you can see
my new pc because my mac is
five or seven years old my mac is a gift
from a professor so you can see
yeah so this is a common topic everyone
wants to ask you know why why do you use
mac why do you use windows why do you
use
linux in blah blah you know so you just
just read my
articles okay so here's why my history
of operating system usage
then then
this is my imac 2009
anyway so my mac here
a gift from a professor uh
in 2017 however the mac the model is
from
2000 from the model is 2014
so the mac is six years old so now
and but now thanks to you guys
donation on patreon i got something like
four thousand dollars
after four years uh so i got a
new gaming computer so this is january
january this year
so event so i got this is what i use now
it's powerful so you can see
six mega bytes of ram only have are used
all the
applications open you know before i have
to
be very careful you to close this close
this open that then close that
now i'm i'm free and the
fancy nvd or gpu and whatever you know
it's not
you know cpu you know and stuff so i
have a full document i documented my
purchase and detail and also also about
here is why i bought these kinesis
thread switches
also i bought around the same time so i
expand here
and that's why
okay so i mean you probably have
questions like which one do you think is
better linux or mac or windows and
you know that's uh i like i got asked
that all the time
so if you want to know the answer it's
all explained
in in in in the article uh
in the article here okay full detail
so let's let's that answers that uh
let's go to talk show let me just
uh quickly write down what we talked
about uh
now there are several things i wanted to
talk about but
we i didn't have um
we probably gonna skip it today
okay so here is
some things i talked we talked about
mac late mini
uh
we also talked about that
okay wufang language for free
uh this i don't wanna talk about okay
then there is that
okay uh yeah we talked about that
okay
okay here are several uh things we
talked about
on my excel talk show page okay
and uh you know blah blah blah and what
else
this i don't want to
so we talked about svg okay so let me
tell you about
svg uh
so we talked about that stuff like keys
paste it here
and uh and i must mention
this page okay svg tutorial complete svg
tutorial from the ground up
learn yourself a javascript then you can
be
a svg master now this this for example
this page shows you how to write a
analog clock in svg just
50 lines of javascript okay
learn svg in one hour okay so copy that
close that what what what what
what paste it here
make a link okay we talked about svg
then
what what else um
scalable graphics yeah so
um then
okay so let me go back to read
read the comments
am i doing okay so okay so
let me take a break
have you used your google recently have
you changed the layout okay so that's
the question
guyo liano have i used my google
keyboard recently
no the google keyboard guy is a
fantastic guy he gave it to me
you know he sent his keyboard to me and
he also
sent me some money uh you know because
he's a good guy
so it's a keyboard so that's a do it
yourself
google you know actually he sent me two
so this is the first one i have it i
don't
you know actually this is
a book okay so where is my google
keyboard
um
should i show it yeah it takes it's some
trouble to take it out
um
yeah yeah it takes some time to take it
out it's in in a drawer
and it's it's in a box but it broke
that's
that's why anyway so
so i use this keyboard for like three
months
not as uh my main because i use because
my
well because you know this is not not a
full-size
keyboard okay let me let me talk about
that a little bit
so where is the um so again let me show
you my keyboard so you can see
so you can see okay so
so this is kinesis advantage 2 and
that's the that's the
um ultimate hacking keyboard which i use
for
uh like a
marco pad okay you can find all the
discussions
uh reviews on my website so the google
keyboard is fantastic
okay you know this is not my it's not my
favorite because i don't like
the 60 40 keyboard okay
he's a big fan i'm not a big fan of it
but he get you know he gave it send it
to me so i can
this is the first time i actually try it
you know so i can actually have a good
you know i can solidify my opinion i can
maybe i'll change my mind so
it you know um
so 60 keyboard is
uh useful but it's not for me in general
because i have to
because
because you have to type chinese you
you don't have enough keys okay now let
me explain so
the 40 keyboard people they say so you
just use
code so you have lots of thumb keys
right but even with code you have
you still have like you have 100
commands and you only have 10 keys
basically well you have like 50 keys
but then you have 5 500 commands
you know in switching windows or you
know also the
switching windows you know or minimize
maximize photoshop you know you have
basically
in general you have 10 times shortcuts
then what possibly you have keys or key
codes
now key codes are great and and and also
i have an article on how many
um codes you can actually have you can
you know you can have a thousand no
problem
but still once you get after 100 you
know you
you started to have lots of code lots of
code
and you have to memorize it you know you
have to memorize you know
what application or whether you are on
linux or mac
this this on windows is that you know
minimize window even minimize windows
different keys okay so quotes
you know so then it's not that great
okay so it's i don't think it's
um the 60
or 40 is not the ideal solution
for a power station situation power
station meaning
you sit here that like i'm on my power
station you control the world
you know nuke it you know you can
everything you want to do just one
button
piggy press you know the it is your
power station
so 6 60 they are good if you
you know have a small apartment you live
with your mom you have to
carry it around your airplane you know
tiny
you know and uh you know but it's not
i don't think it's suitable for power
station situation especially also
because when you need to type
a lot math math symbols for example math
symbols
okay so when you consider math symbols
then you know
there's really a lot of problems also i
type chinese okay i have to type chinese
so if you have all these symbols you
really stress out the code
situation under 60 in almost
this 60 percent they don't they don't
they don't they don't type that much
you know but if you need i i do i need
to type
i type more than most programmers you
know two or three times
because i write a lot i write blogs i
have like six blogs you know
math on programming on art on
the english literature you know and i
chat you know i talk non-stop on my
discord
telling you telling people what things
how things should be
so and then i have to type math symbols
you know then
then you know the ap our programming
language not just api you know wolfen
language you know
math symbols and so
so that is why i don't recommend i mean
i i
i would say that 60 or 40 is not the
ideal
it's not ideal keyboard for a for a
power station
keyboard at a nuclear center okay
nuclear you know weapon center okay
so this is not your battle station you
know if you sit in your
battle station this is this is not ideal
but it's you know so anyway so
also so i i'm thinking you probably
uh are interested in my review right so
but
it was you know it works fine and i
devised
there are few things you want to uh be
careful okay just read my review okay
i outlined some of the some of the
issues with
the google so if you want to buy this
keyboard make sure
that don't get the flat keycaps that's
you know don't get flat keycaps you want
to
uh sphere code curve okay you also want
a
uh kind of a tactile nipple
on the j and f keys because on this one
it doesn't have that
then oftentimes my hand is on the wrong
column or the wrong
row and i cannot tell i have to look you
know so
that's the issue so you want the
spherical top keycaps
you also want
the tactile bump you know on the j and f
and also you want you want the key
switch to be
the at no more than 40 grams okay
the one i have is actually 55 grams he
sent it to me
because because it's a miscommunication
you know anyway so so
55 grams that's not good okay
so these three are the major issues with
this
particular one i have so if you want to
buy this i recommend you know
make sure you know you get the one i
just mentioned you know those
those things then also
this you know also these you know this
uh do itself you know you need a case
you want a case okay
you know the way it came it looks like
that you know you flip over
it's your pcb world it is scratchy you
know he
hitch hitches your clothes and you know
it's not
it's not uh robust
okay so you want to get a case you know
so if you really you know if you want to
buy this you want to buy
something like that you know with a case
you can 3d print it and so on you know
so that's that's what i think of google
and also one more thing i want to
mention so
so google they have a default layout i
tried it it's it's okay but
i created my own layout okay so google
layout i
this is fantastic works on with soft
light keys
in emacs fantastic okay i would
recommend
you try this my layout even today i mean
a lot of people think of my website you
know it's uh is it still relevant it is
still relevant
try this red layout okay for google
keyboard
okay that's google now he actually also
sent me
even more extreme googleplex
and you know so this this
is my photo uh and this other
this is other people's photos so you
know
make sure you want the curved top
keycaps okay make sure of that
and you want the case like that okay you
want you know a nice case like that
not you know not like the one i have you
know plain pcb
um so there it is but i this is even
less keys
like you know 36 keys only
i haven't had time to actually
set it up you know the problem with this
studio yourself is that these nuts you
know he's a
great guy but these nuts they don't they
don't take
the trouble to actually
try to explain how to make it work
for example i got this fantastic okay
i got this i'm gonna start to use it you
know i love i love playing with
keyboards so
but i cannot you know what do i have to
do
i have to literally literally spend
three at least three five hours
to to study the
to study the um
the qmk configuration tool now for the
google keyboard that's easy because
they already have options so even that
you have to spend a few hours you know
but for the google plex they don't have
you know that
it's not bld on the site i have to like
download the
qmk tool maybe compile it you know maybe
i need gcc
or whatever compiler you know so
so so that so that's
i haven't had you know i haven't got a
chance to um
to configure this yet
so that's that's a that's the issue okay
yeah so anyway that's my opinion about
google in google flex
quite a few people on saw discord also
bought it you know
so yeah so
so i want to so let me finish the
comments okay we are about done i have
to go
so uh do we have more comments okay
i think that's it
okay so
okay so yeah we do have google fans yeah
so just remember check out my article
make sure you you get
you know those keycaps and stuff and
you'll be good
doctor racket okay handy animation okay
uh
algorithm write an algorithm where you
need to label points and search exactly
so that's a
you know uh image or diagram in source
code it's very
sometimes extremely helpful when you
especially when you document
you know especially when you want to for
example you need to explain
the detail of the algorithms you know
sometimes for example if you are doing
graph
you know drawing graphs or i mean
keyboards and lots of applications you
need that
julia yeah julia julia is also good uh
okay so wait julia yeah julia the
programming language julia is good
uh this is crap to store file in source
code what
long time no see akira hello akira
what's your preferred browse uh
preferred mouse or trackball okay so
i gotta go so but we can we can talk
about that a little bit
okay so we talked about keyboard so go
back to emacs
so hold on a second so let me
talk about mouse and that's it uh two
more minutes
three more minutes okay um
svg clock what's going on uh google
keyboard paste it here
okay google keyboard and
google plex
okay mouse okay so let's talk about
mouse uh
i should talk about you know let me talk
about mouse next time because
actually i got a lot of things to say
right now my mouse is this one it works
okay but it's not
it's not perfect okay because yeah but
it works okay because i already have
lots of the you know
fantastic keyboard marker you know
programmable keyboards
uh and also one more thing important is
that you know i use
the hoover to click can i mean hoover to
activate windows so that's
critical that's a great time saver okay
let me talk about mouse another day
uh trackball i don't have but i just
actually i do have two trackballs but
those are
let me talk about that another day
okay so here's the question are the low
profile keys a problem
for hand health no no no profile keys
are good okay
little profile keys are uh good
i mean yeah yeah you want mechanical
okay
be sure it's mechanical so let me uh so
what
um yeah those are chok chok
those are choco um key switches okay
you know on the google uh choco is a key
switch made by
in china so let me show you um
here choco coyote chock switch chocolate
you know
uh so they have a video
you know the this marketing video
fantastic high tech
so yeah they are good okay because i
have you
because i have used it uh on this
keyboard and of course on the google
you know the chalk keyboard that's great
make sure again make sure you want
the activation must be
no more than 45 grams okay anything
above 45 grams
above 45 grams doesn't matter it's
linear or not
i don't like i actually have a problem
so it must be 45 grams or less
or you know even 40 grams
okay so uh yeah chalk
switch
yeah so i uh gyolano says i
i sent a linkedin article uh
on your previous video showing some
interesting concepts with
a 34 key but i think the
comment got deleted i didn't see it
that's a problem the youtube
you know the google doing things you
know i don't i didn't see the comment
and sometimes i see a comment in my um
i didn't you know i have no idea about
that that comment
sometimes i see a comment on the
uh where's the you know on the you know
there's a
anyway it's not on this page anyway
it's problem with youtube okay google
controlling things so sometimes i don't
see the comments
the best thing is join this code you can
you know kind of
uh but on discord we talked we talked
about lots of things
okay so be mentally prepared we talk
about
lots of wild uh things on discord casa
discord
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching donate okay donate
put money in my pocket you know you go
to my website you can see
my uh patreon or paypal and you know
amazon gift card you know
yeah again then you have to type pinging
on 40
you know many of these 40 fans they
don't get it
like you you you okay this is getting
into the
you know the controversy kind of you
know i'm going to show
the kasa personality it's gonna
going to piss off lots of my fans you
know
you know sometimes they i get donation
from fans you know they
really love my stuff then they say
something
but usually i don't know who they are
unless you pay me a lot you know
like i don't know and especially you
guys you know use act
you know anonymous you know i don't know
you're i cannot associate you know
on youtube you have one name on discord
it's another name
you know and so and next month you
deleted your account things like that
you know these
people you people anyway so
so sometimes my fans you know they like
myself
and sometimes they put an opinion at
night
um i dissed them then they got pissed
you know that's
that's not good that that's not that's
my flaw that's my
flaw okay uh but anyway yeah so they are
a lot
40 fans and happy hacking fans you know
they
uh anyway anyway you got a problem okay
forty percent keyboard you know
for typing ping and russian
you have problems but again then then
you have people who type russia who says
insist that there's no problem anyway
yeah mx fields speed silver is good okay
that's it thank you guys for watching
guys uh actually you know today i got
uh other things to talk about but uh
well i guess that's it one hour wow in
ten minutes
we we i've had other things to okay next
day
bye guys
oh what do i prefer mouse or um
if i really have to pick one i would say
mouse
okay i'm always i always have a heart
for trackball for like
for since 1990s i always believed and
you know i really want to be
i deeply believe the trackball is
actually a better device
you know better in in in
intuitiveness and also better in
uh efficiency in how in in in the
maneuver and control and it turns out
i believe that's false okay now
let me d okay again i need to talk about
that next time
because this is gonna be an hour because
okay
well in fact i have articles on it okay
i have articles
you just go to my trackball articles
trackball versus smiles how to choose
the track roll so i have a kind of a
detail
on the you know the full
uh things about trackball versus mouse
which one is better what are the
advantages who says what
who believes in what is your scientific
data
you know and how do you test it how do
you you know
you know all these things i talked about
uh anyway trackball is still very good
okay but it's
not it's mouse
let me put it this way if you want the
most efficient
um control of the cruiser
meaning that the best example is playing
first-person shooters
okay mouse is better than trackball by
magnitude okay
but but but otherwise trackball is more
intuitive intuitive okay but trackball
has got other problems because
trackball you need to clear it like
every month you need to like you know
take a minute
you know just just one you know just
actually 10 seconds
but still that's uh that's the issue you
have to do it every month otherwise
the the ball becomes less smooth
but with the mouse today you know
optical or laser you don't have to do
that
so it actually it's more convenient
and the other issue with trackball is
that because the mouse is
massive market for each trackball there
are one literally 100 or more
different mouses so the mars market is
huge
so there's lots of effort and research
in you know
10 buttons 20 buttons the the placement
of buttons
the switch of but you know you have lots
of
uh research and you know stuff with
trackable
but with trackball the market is very
small so there's not much
you know for example a mouse today you
can easily find
lots of you know gaming mouse that that
they have heidi programmable
you know uh you know choice you know
highly programmable
and all sort of things on the firmware
okay you have you know the cpu
they have a chip on the mouse you know
but on a trackball
you don't you cannot find one okay a
trackball
you also have a lot but the point is for
each trackball you see here you can see
oh wow my god there's lots of choices
but actually for each one
here you have literally 100 different
uh type of mouse you know so the mouse
market
is far more than trackball and for
trackball you cannot find one that's
actually programmable today
i mean with bld memories you know the
real
actual programmable uh uh
like a programmable keyboard not not
relying on software not relying on cloud
okay
you cannot find one i so far as far as i
know
um i don't think any of these has
you know i want it to be firmware
programmable that you know just like qmk
just like keyboard qmk you know what i'm
talking about right
or condenses keyboard you know the
program you know you don't have that on
trackball
that's a problem but you do have a mouse
so that's a issue with trackball because
small market and so on
bye