Good morning, good morning, good evening
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Kasan Talk Show. We are going to do
advant of code 2025
day four part two take two. So yesterday
we began to do it then we got distracted
into talking about a demonstration of
what is wufam language Mathematica. So
you can watch yesterday a great
introduction to Wuam language. Hello
that beast. So so this is yesterday's
talk show uh wam language. Let me check
audio check video check. Okay. So, wuam
language you know symbolic algebra
graphic system Julia set animations
uh and and generating sound synthesize
sound and play it and uh 3D graphics
interactive and geography
uh and graph theory. So, wan language
can do lots of things. So that was
yesterday.
Uh and so today we're going to continue
this advent of code 2025 day 4 part two.
Uh I'm going to try just to code it. So
in previous weeks I talk a lot. I talk
as I code and I give analysis or
opinions about different things. Uh
today let's try something different. So
I'll just try to code it without much
talking but I'm going to explain what is
the problem first. Okay.
So if you are watching this offline play
at 1.5 speed or two
times as fast. Uh if you are here say
hi. Okay. So the problem is that event
of code 2025
day four part two is that you are given
can you see it? Yes. So you are given
this
text file a grid each at sign.
So you have many ad signs and some dots.
Okay. Now for each position of the ad
sign you want to find the neighbors. So
you have uh neighbors including upper
right including diagonal neighbors. If
it has
less than four neighbors that are at
sign. So you want to count at signs
around its neighbor. So it has less than
four then you consider that at sign
special. So you go through each ad sign
look at its neighbors. If it has less
than four at sign around it then you
consider that particular ad sign
special. Okay. So you go through that.
Then the problem part one is that you
want to determine how many special o add
signs are there. So uh problem part one
uh the solution is 13. Okay, I mean the
toy solution is 13. Uh this is 13 right
here. Okay, my personal answer is 1527.
Okay. So part one find how many ass
signs that has
assigned neighbors that are less than
four of them. Okay. Now the second
problem part two which I'm going to do
now is that
for each ad sign you find
the special ones that has less than four
add signs around it. Okay. Once you
found it, you remove that ad sign.
Okay? Then you repeat this process. You
do it again. You found the ad sign that
has less than four four ad signs around
it. You remove that. Then you repeat,
repeat, repeat until there are no ad
sign that can be removed. In other
words, you end up with this picture
where each ad sign has at least four ad
signs around it. Okay, so the problem
asks
um
in the whole process how many total ass
signs you removed. Okay, so that is a
problem and I'm going to code it uh
without much talking.
a MacBook still top tier for programming
and uh software
s I don't know what is SWE software
something but MacBooks so if you use a
computer
mostly for the purpose of coding like I
do but actually I use also lots of
things I use it for um well watching
videos but mostly coding okay so if you
use computer for mostly coding
your great choices are Mac. Mac is a
great choice in general and uh also
Linux. Okay. But if you also play video
games or if you explore uh virtual
reality
uh or you uh or explore lots of other
programs then Windows is uh you know is
is common choice.
Okay. So let's just let me start to
code. Okay, without much talking. Let's
see. Let's see if I can f finish it
fast. Uh may maybe in 20 minutes.
Today's drink is tea. Black tea hot.
So we just I'm just going to go relaxed.
Okay. So play at 1.5 speed or two.
Okay, let's start to code show in
browser. So that's today's talk show
notepad notes. Okay, so uh section go to
go to let's start to code uh wam
language I introduced so much I don't
need to. Okay, let's just start to code.
So let's go to I'm I'm still going to
talk a little bit but but uh I'm mostly
just going to focus on coding. Okay. So,
we need to copy the uh the previous code
uh clear neighbors. Okay. Copy that. Is
this the right code? Yes. Okay. Paste it
there. And also we need
we need this solution. Okay. I mean the
previous
input
uh
PhD based not Linux.
hardcore tech geek BSD. Congratulations.
Um, okay. Code, code, code code. So, I
need to code. So, turn it into a matrix
of zero and ones. And we got this get
neighbors. Uh and and we got these
dimensions. We do we need dimensions?
No. No. Okay. So, uh
Okay. So, dimensions. Let's see.
Okay. Okay. Delete that. Delete that.
Delete that.
Okay. That's what we need. Matrix one,
two, uh index num positions. And uh then
neighbors.
Okay. Neighbors we delete delete delete
because we
Okay, that's our code. So input. So
here's the input. Turn it into a matrix
of zero and ones. And here's the gate
neighbors. And then here is the main or
index is where cell is a paper row. Okay
[clears throat]
index of
next of paper row. So you get the
position. So each round. So you get the
position then you
you need to count you need to tally. So
this so you get a bunch of positions
then you apply total right. So you apply
this function um
you apply this function so you need to
replace that variable um get neighbors.
Okay. So
okay so each time you do this you need
to remove those cell remove it and you
need to repeat. So
each time uh I need to write it down. Uh
each time
input is a matrix.
Go through the matrix.
Remove some cells.
Repeat
until no
cell can be removed.
Count number of cells removed.
Get total number of cells removed. Okay,
that is the essence of the algorithm.
So you write a function that takes a
matrix then it returns a matrix. Okay,
let's plan
write a function ff,
it takes a matrix and return a matrix.
Okay, but no but uh but every time it
does we going to do this in pure
functional way. So every time this does
so it takes a matrix it takes uh so
so it the function will be have a
signature like this
and count of removed sales. Okay.
So the function will do take a input
matrix
current count of remove cells beginning
with zero.
It will return
a
a new matrix
and it will return a
list and the list is going to be
new matrix
and uh
new
total removed sales count.
Okay.
Then
so the function takes a matrix current
count of remove sales and return a new
list.
New matrix
total remove sales. Okay.
And let's make this into one single
input
so that it can recurs by itself.
Then use
nest
uh uh fixed point.
Then the solution is fixed point FF.
That's right. Fixed point will recurse a
given function until result no longer
changes.
That's right. Look up the documentation.
Fix point f expression. Okay. You need
the initial expression.
Uh yeah. So fixed point then
input matrix zero.
Okay
that is the plan our aos step. Okay now
we just going to write this function. So
the function we'll take will have this
form.
Okay. Input matrix current count of
removed cells. Okay. Then it will
do whatever we're going to do. So block
is a local variable.
Okay, basically group the whole body of
the function like lisps p r o gn.
Okay, then input matrix. So
so we need we kind of need this part.
Okay. So let's let's move that somewhere
here. Okay.
So this function
this function we define like that. Um
and uh
so so so you each step you need to um
total. So
so this gets a total. Okay. So this code
this code just gets a total of special
cells that is also known as removed
cells going to be removed.
Meanwhile you need to return the matrix.
So you can see you can you can say
cells to be removed. Okay, that's one
variable and the result matrix that's
another variable and in fact you reverse
the order.
Okay, two local variables.
Okay. And what you do so and and uh and
oh becomes simple and simple. So this
part is the cells to be removed. Okay.
Then it just return
that. Okay. Now this part sales to be
removed is already done computed there.
Now the new return matrix. How do you do
that? Well
um
Given a matrix certain positions in it
needs to be removed. You need to know
those positions. Okay?
So you need a variable
positions list. Okay.
Um
to remove
position list. Okay. We make our
variable long so it's like readable so
people can understand it. Okay. So we
make our variable very long. This is in
contrast to C and C++ idiots style.
Wuang language typically have long
descriptive names
you know all the building function like
um that is the tradition basically from
lisp that's a lisp tradition names are
usually very long descriptive
okay so this is critical to remove
positions list
how do you get that once you know that
list you can easily delete it delete
those positions by
uh by
let's uh how do you do that? So uh
result matrix let's color it. Okay. Uh
result matrix equals to something. Okay.
Yeah. result matrix equals to delete.
Uh well,
it's going to be
map.
delete to this to remove positions
then that will return a new matrix
assigned to the result there. Okay, then
you just return that. Fantastic and
beautiful. So now the job is to define
this to remove position. Okay, but first
of all, let let's uh look up the
documentation for delete.
Right.
Okay.
Now,
let's um
do a test case just just to be sure we
got this right. Okay. So,
delete in this matrix and uh you want to
delete position 2 two.
It'll return 1 2 3 then 4 5 then 7 8 9
it
annoying when you start with language.
You see? Perfect.
Perfect.
Three. Shift enter
to start it.
Magnify 150. Enlarge. Okay.
Copy that.
Paste it. Shift enter. Fantastic. And
beautiful. That's how it works.
Now the question is how do you
get this to be removed position list?
Okay,
well that part the code is similar here.
So um so you need to actually hold on a
second.
This list will equals to
something like that. Okay, now forget
about total. Now let's see. Um,
let's make it more legible. So,
okay, I know what to do. So you
let's see
position. Let's look at the
documentation. Position return elements
position via a pattern.
position, expression and pattern. Given
an expression, if a pattern matches any
part of the expression, it will return a
list of all those positions of that
matched expression. Okay, so this is
effectively
given a list could be a tree nested
list. You want to get all the positions
such that the element matches this
pattern. Okay, that is what is this is
doing. Okay, so
the matrix is our input.
So input matrix. Okay, now what are the
patterns?
How do you match a pattern? The pattern
needs to be such that you know it has
less than four neighbors.
Well,
this function will tell you this get
neighbors and and less than four. So
this [clears throat]
um so
okay so this needs some work. Okay.
Now, where where is this index of paper
rows? Uh oh, that's not defined. Is it
defined? Oh, it is. Okay.
All index is where the cell is a paper
row.
Oh, so every time you need to do this
again. So, this needs to be moved inside
the function. Okay. So,
So okay. So now let's we need now it's
getting a bit complex. We need to clean
up a little bit all indexes where the
cell is a paper row. Okay. So first of
all copy that
and uh move this here.
Okay. So we got now four local
variables.
This this should be count. Okay.
Okay, it's getting closer and closer.
Save it. Make a backup. Close it.
Reopen. So, we got a fret. We remove the
highlight. Okay. So, again,
this function
This function
local variables index a paper
rows.
Okay. Actually, let's rename it
Rename hell. Let's stop stop that. Okay.
Position of paper rows.
Now this is inconsistent naming bad.
Assign position list better name.
Now this to remove position list.
Okay, now it's more consistent name and
even shorter.
assign positions list of positions to
remove positions list result matrix to
be removed count now it's better
now highlight them okay let's begin our
journey of coding so assign position
list that gives you all lists all
indexes all Let's uh
positions where the cell is a paper row.
Back the paper roll as sign.
This is very inefficient but we don't
care because advent of code they don't
appreciate efficient codes they just
care about an answer this is inefficient
but
don't care okay
assign position list okay you got that
to be removed to remove position list
this we don't know yet but first of all
we need the
Um
so let so this is to be removed count.
Let's we can move that there. Okay.
Uh
okay. So that and to remove position
list. So how do you do this? So you
you map this function wait
to this basically
map
index. Okay.
So actually
now let's experiment a little bit. Okay,
I need I needed to have like some test.
So the matrix is that
put it back.
Create a new wam code and uh
you need to do some testing. Okay. Uh
what?
Yeah.
Okay. Concentrate.
Map a function get neighbors. Map a
function get neighbors. So it returns.
So map assign position list. So you map
position, right? So
you map that to a list of positions
and uh each become
okay. So hold on a second.
So let's modify this. So let me show you
what we going to do. You map a function
to assign position list. And what
function you're going to map? Here is
the trick. Okay, here is the function
you're going to map. But hold on a
second. Let me uh clear it for Okay,
you're going to map a function
such that
okay here, focus on here. Okay, here
we're going to write this function one
shot. We don't need these two lines.
You're going to map a function through
this list of positions.
Okay. Wait, what?
Hey, how did that get there? Okay, hold
on a second. Okay,
remove that.
Remove that. Okay,
you're going to map a function
[clears throat]
that is a function. Okay, map a
function. The argument is x. Now what
does the function do? It's a if
statement, if expression. Okay, if get
neighbors returns a list
and total them,
if it's less than four,
you return,
you don't return one, you return the
position which is x.
Okay.
Otherwise
what do you return? Nothing.
This is the tricky part. Okay. Nothing
in wam language is like no or no.
Basically when you have nothing in a
list this nothing automatically
disappears. Okay. It's like new or
undefined. You know in programming
language you have this 1 billion
mistake.
Nothing represents an element of a list
that will automatically be removed.
Okay, this is new in uh when is it 2015
10 years ago when I was coding heavily
in Wuam language I don't have this but
now you can have this. Okay. So if
let's make sure this is correct. Okay.
You map a function that function
to to
all the positions of the at least. Okay.
If the total you sum it up of all the
neighbors
is less than four, you return x which is
a position. you return that position
otherwise nothing in uh okay another way
to do it okay now we remove this part so
we don't doesn't get confusing we are
coding this part to remove position list
we want a list of positions we want to
remove okay
in fact
[clears throat]
in fact we don't need to do this map in
fact we can do
Let me let me hold on a second. Let me
think. This will work. But um but there
are better way. But hold on a second.
Let's not get distracted like oh but
there's a new way. Let's try that. But
then there's another way. Let's try that
instead. Then then you never finish. So
let let's just stick with um Okay. So to
remove position list,
that should work.
But actually there is a better way.
Okay.
You just say
don't don't map. Okay. Don't map this.
Okay. You want basically you want to
filter this assign position list.
You see it's a list of positions. you
just want to reduce them. For each
position that needs to be removed, you
remove that position. Okay? So you
reduce this assign position list. In
that case, you can use cases
uh or or select. Okay? So
select is like filter. Okay. Data and
criteria. Okay. Let's do that. Select.
It's make it simpler. Okay. Select
filter. Okay. Select from this list.
What is the criteria? Well, the criteria
is this function basically. Okay.
This function if total something
something is
greater or equals to four
then
true
else false.
Okay. Is this simpler? Yes. You see
select two arguments data and criteria.
The criteria is a function. Okay.
So that
so you see uh hold on a second. So you
see we have two implementations of this
um
of this generate the list of positions
to remove.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure it work. Okay, so
let let's let's get on let's finish the
problem. Okay, this function so far so
good.
you guys watching.
It is superb functional programming.
Superb. There's no variable mutation.
There's no for loop. There's no plus+
like the C++
There's no objects. There's no
iterator. There's no accessor. There's
no constructor. All those All
these are pure function.
Position a necessary concept when you
have a list or indexes, position,
matrix, you know, all the all these
concepts are fundamental and necessary
because they came from mathematics.
None of the accessor, iterator,
generator
um you know the object oriented stuff.
Okay. So
assign position list
then
to remove position list
then then actually to be removed count
you don't need um
actually uh you can uh just to remove
pos you just count the length of the uh
that and So you see we improved so much.
Let me do alternative code here.
You see now the to be removed count is
just that you don't need this anymore.
Is that right?
Uh we need to think about it to be sure.
Okay. Oh, so one more last check.
Assign position list.
Then
select
with this criteria.
So this should be less than four not
greater than equals to four. Neighbors
less than four. That is to yeah we got
to make sure that is right. Yeah
to be removed position list.
Then
then the count is just
length of that.
Okay. Then the result matrix is you map
delete to this list.
Actually you don't map you you just uh
let me show you. Okay. You don't you
don't map. Okay. You simply delete.
Delete.
Yeah. This this is incorrect. Delete the
input matrix by this to be removed list.
Okay, all those positions delet them.
Then return result matrix and uh
remove count.
Now let's rename again. This is not to
be removed, you know. Ban the word to be
very complicated.
Rename it.
Just remove count.
Very critical naming of things. Okay, I
think we done. So, let's compact the
code. So, so the code is just that.
Okay. Uh,
it's probably unreadable to you.
So let me just remove these comments.
Let's uh put the comments
to there. So just in case we need them.
Okay. So now the function is simpler.
Can you see it?
This function input matrix current count
of remove cells.
Oh, you need to add them. So, the remove
count needs to add
uh plus
current count of remove sales plus new
remove count. That's right. Because they
need to accumulate. Okay. So, this is a
return value. When you have a bunch of
expressions, it returns the last
expression return value.
Fantastic.
Now the final solution just call this
okay let's see final solution fixed
point FF input matrix zero
then it will return
this list
the first part is the matrix the second
part is just just a number
and if we run this one shot you know
this is like one short coding there's no
trial and error I I wrote this in my
head
we run this will it give us the solution
okay let's let's check one last time
um compact the code
we don't need this um
comment redundant because now the naming
is clarity at sign position list.
So let's check one more time
this function
and uh since now each variable is used
once we can actually replace the block
local variable dynamic scope by a width
which is constant local constant.
We can do that just you need just need
to make sure that they are not used they
are not mutated they are not but however
the this variable uses the value of
previous variable so you actually need
nested
with local constant that's not good
let's just leave it like this okay
assign position list remove position
list result matrix x remove pound. Okay.
Input matrix. Now, where is input matrix
used? Let's see.
Input matrix.
Where is the input matrix used? That's
not good. Oh, yeah. So, you forgot it
should be here. Not X matrix.
Oh, you got to be careful. Okay. Not X
matrix, my friend. That's input matrix.
Okay. And you got X matrix here.
Yeah, that also needs to be input
matrix, I think.
And what what is this? Delete X inputs.
Oh god, you be careful. You don't want
to up. Okay.
So you see input matrix. Okay. Save it.
Close it. Uh back up. Close it. Reopen.
Refresh.
Now input matrix is a thing.
this rename that variable.
Let's just say count of remove cell.
Okay. [clears throat]
Uh let's too long.
Remove count. Okay.
Input matrix remove count.
Okay. Color level.
[sighs]
And in fact you don't need remove count
because remove count is this expression
and you just replace it there. You don't
need it that variable.
Result matrix delete
to remove position list. Okay.
So far so good. So far so very good. I
think
now let's copy that
is mature enough to put into wam
language uh wam notebook so we can see
how it formats
you know actually we can run it is there
a syntax error no you see the wam
language formatted on the fly well
with all the indent indentations created
on the fly as part of the rendering not
hardcoded space or return or tab like
the Python C C++ Java idiots industrial
coders
[clears throat]
it's like a long form essay you know
what one what you know one thing let let
me digress again okay one thing about
wuam language is everything you can make
it into one line that's still valid
expression okay I I'm so used to is like
I can I can make my whole program one
line. Well, except uh when you have text
uh string but but but other than string
which is kind of hardcoded syntax within
a programming language.
Uh but otherwise the like wam language
you can make everything one line. Okay,
that's still valid
which is true too for lisp except the
stupid lisp comment.
uh the you know like I can show you
stuff like keys go to my emac this code
you know except this can do that too
except for example for example this uh
wait go to previous buffer that's what
this this key do you know go to previous
buffer or go to next buffer back next
back next back back back
okay that's what this function does okay
now I can make it
one line still works okay this also has
this property except except this this
idiocy this comment when you have this
comment you make it one line it's
up it no longer valid this code because
the common syntax has a
uh stop the show floor. That is it
relies on
a new line, a line break, a hardcoded
formatting character to work. It serves
as the delimiter for the end of common.
See common syntax
uh lisp
fatal idiocy because of this
the lisp syntax perfect nesting can no
longer be free for you know
but if you don't have this comment this
still works okay but then if you have
this com this this comment then you make
it one line it stops working so very
annoying so the a remedy I've been
thinking is that just make all your
comment a string.
But but that's inefficient because
string it will evaluate
but but when you have like um well you
you you can't actually put a string
here. Yeah. So you got some issues.
Okay.
So that's a lisp problem that basically
you cannot fix like in eac list you
cannot like create a new function. So to
fix this, no, it's part of the like
fundamental syntax. This common syntax,
a f fatal flaw of this.
Okay. Anyway,
make sure I didn't change anything in
Sly Keys. Close it. Okay, close it.
That's a digression. Let's uh previous
buffer. Okay, let's go back here. Uh
yeah.
So, are we ready? just copy the whole
thing and run it. Uh, okay. Let's let's
remove this. Um,
I I think so. Okay, let's see. Will I
fail? Maybe.
You know,
if you bet me $100, then I going to
check one more time. Okay. But since
nobody is betting, does anyone want to
bet $100? Like I run this one shot, it's
going to work. Okay. So begin by the
input a string block of text. We turn
this by this fantastic expression. We
turn it in into a matrix of zeros and
ones. Okay. Then we define this get
neighbors function we defined in
previous days. This can be much improved
anyway.
Then we describe today part two's
algorithm. You know each loop you need
to remove certain
member of the
matrix. Okay. Then we defined so the
essence lies a new function this f FF
you know in functional programming
you know it would be better if you give
it a proper proper name like remove you
know let's name it remove cells
but you see in mathematics
you know in mathematics if you read for
example mathematics medical journals,
topology, graph theory, uh you know,
usually they have gam gamma, alpha,
alpha, something you know like summation
or integral, you know, you don't see you
don't see a name like uh like this is a
cell like current cell or to remove
list. You don't see that every symbol is
just usually a single character
alpha gamma beta zeta zeta function you
know so so I I'm I I I can I'm very used
to a function just ff
okay so anyway this function ff takes
two a list of two things and return a
list of two things then at the and you
just fix. Let's just run it. Okay, I
started to talk too much now. Let's
uh yeah, this is one single cell. Let's
run it. Let's see. Please no error,
please.
Okay, it is wrong because there is no
such thing as input matrix.
God. Okay. So let's let's write
X matrix. You got X matrix but
uh okay. So yeah this is wrong. This is
uh this is X. It should be X matrix.
Okay.
Okay. Let's just do that. Let's just do
copy this line actually just copy it
here
and back to from language and
oh this function
shift enter please. Uh
why is X matrix not defined or
something?
X matrix.
Oh, wait. X matrix. H capitalization.
When where where did I just got so
with this? All this
capitalization. Why did did uh
Yeah, I shouldn't be capitalized.
Okay, let's fix this.
No capitalization, please.
Now run it, please.
specification.
I got this. I got this wrong. Now, where
does it come from? Oh god.
Longer than depth. Okay.
Okay. So, what what what what does all
this color? Okay, put it back.
Make a backup. Scene task color showing
browser. Okay, one shot incorrect.
So now let's do it again.
Okay, so it says something about
part specification. Fixed point part
specification
longer than depth.
Okay.
Okay. Now, well, you need to debug.
You know, we we we did this like without
trial and error at all, but it's not,
you know, wam language is not pleased
with my
one shot. Something is wrong. So, where
is this input matrix?
[cough]
like this. This will work, right? So,
okay, we need to debug. Uh, okay.
This this returns
at sign position list. Yes. Yes. Okay.
Then this returns um
to be removed list. Wait, did did didn't
we change them to be to remove list
position list? Okay. Okay, let's try it.
Do it. Okay, that's the problem.
Okay,
a problem. Select criteria.
Select event Q. Okay, we select it and
uh uh pick out all elements ei.
Okay,
so
select is our function. The first
argument is assign position list.
Oh, wait. Obviously, no. You use the
wrong list. This must this should be the
input list.
Wait. Uh, wait.
Oh, yeah. So, I I know what's going on.
So, you wrote you basically you you use
the wrong list. Okay. So, select assign
position list by this function. So,
let's let's fix it. You see by this
function. And this function needs to be
what?
So did we do we have a like
okay precedence we got it correct. Get
neighbors input matrix.
Oh wait this this is X matrix. Okay.
Yeah then. Yeah, that works.
That works.
Uh,
confusing name. So, let's let's check
let's check um let's rename them.
Okay, let's not rename them. Well, the
this input matrix. So, let's just say
so that it is more
So it worked right? Yeah. Once you get
the matrix
assign position list for this position
list you want to remove some of them.
Wait to remove list right? So the one
you want to remove is get neighbors
of the X matrix the input matrix and X
is the position because it applies to
each element in the position list. So X
is the position.
So get neighbors of this matrix at that
position and if the total is less than
four then true
means
Oh, it means keep that. Okay, so you you
want this you got it. You got this
wrong. So it must be greater than equals
to four,
right? That means to keep all uh reverse
the true and false here. Okay.
So if it's less than to remove list,
wait, let's see.
You got list of positions to remove. So
it's less than four.
True. Wait. Okay. So
[clears throat]
to remove. So,
so what is 13?
One, three. So, this this add sign.
No, that shouldn't really be removed.
1 3 1 4 1 6 1 3
1 14 Wait, did did we get the logic
wrong? So if less than
four.
So 1 13 is a add sign 14 is a add sign
and six is a add sign. Check.
And uh to remove list. So it says 13
should be removed because it has one two
three neighbors. Check.
Then one four should be removed because
it has one two three neighbors. Check.
Then it says six should be removed
because it has one, two, three
neighbors. Check.
Then it says 17 needs to be removed.
What?
1 7 because it has three neighbors. Then
also 18 and one nine.
They all needs to be removed. And 21.
Then second column. First one. Yes.
Needs to be removed. But not 22 two
because 22 has got one two three four
five neighbors.
You see not 22
and not 2 three. Correct. And not not 25
neither. Wait.
One two three four five. 25
has
No, not two five because it has
neighbors. One, two, three, four. Yeah.
So, the next one you want to remove is
37. So, let's check.
Stay. Stay. Stay. Three. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
So, this one needs to remove. That is
correct. So,
our to remove position list seems to be
correct. Okay.
Now, put this back. So it don't
uh wait what
okay so so what so what else is wrong so
to remove position list
is so far so good. Yes.
Uh to remove position this so far so
good. Yes.
And then you have remove count.
Could it be wrong? I don't think so.
Shift enter. 13. Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
Then
then you return this
[cough and clears throat]
uh then what? Wait then then result
matrix right then you need to compute
the result matrix. Okay.
[clears throat]
Oh you don't delete my friend. You don't
delete them. You replace it with a um
you don't simply delete them because
when you if you just delete them in this
matrix, the matrix shape collapse, you
know, some row will have less columns.
So, so it's no longer a matrix.
So, we found the bug. So, you don't
delete them. This is
incorrect. you want to replace it by
zero instead.
Okay.
So, what is a way to replace? Well, I
forgot. So, let's showcase my wam
language tutorial. Search for it
language tutorial. You'll find it. Uh,
so you go to numbers booing list. Then
you go down length vector is a list
introduction to vector array matrix
tree. They are all represented by this
single syntax list. Okay. Then you go to
list operations.
You want to change parts. Add elements.
Delete elements. Change elements. Okay.
Replace part by position. Okay. That's
what you want to do. So,
this is interesting. So, I need to have
some more tea.
We are almost done.
Almost done. We've been going on for 90
minutes. Jesus
coding takes a lot of time.
[clears throat]
So, hold on a second. You want to now we
want to replace parts.
Uh
right. So if you give a single number
then that's the index.
So but if you give a list then that's
the position
right? So you got to have you get you
get these the positions then. Okay.
So instead of that
now let's let's code it here so that we
can actually um
wait
result matrix is the part you want to
fix. Okay not that. Okay. So let's code
it here. Copy it. Not delete. So instead
you want to replace
part
that's right replace part of the matrix
x matrix and uh
and uh okay well so what so what you do
is you well you you wouldn't understand
but
But I let me just code it. Okay.
[clears throat]
Replace it by zero. Okay. So this is
what you're going to do.
Try it.
Okay. Now you see the first row is
almost all zero. Now
uh let's check the first row is you see
all zero except the the third from the
right you see let's go back to our
matrix you see those one one are gone
except that one this one is also gone
because it's got three neighbors this
one you see this one got one two three
four so that one stayed you see so 0 0
and zero and one zero zero
So go back here. That is correct. So
this is the code correct code. Okay. So
result matrix this is wrong. This is
correct. Now go go back to previous
occurrence.
This correct code. Now remove the
incorrect code.
I think that's it. [cough]
[clears throat] Then you just return
result matrix and whatever. Okay. So now
let's copy the whole thing and run it
again.
Select all paste. Just run it.
43 my friend. It says 43.
Does it check?
43. [laughter]
Fantastic. And beautiful.
One shot coding. Well, it's like
threeshot coding. Okay, now we delete
all these experimental like pad
debugging part. Okay, we we got it
correct. Okay, actually we got our code
and this part this we don't need e
either. This we got it correct. So this
part take it out put it back just for
example sake
we show how to use that delete and now
here
now this is clean code. So that's the
here that's the input turn it into a
matrix defy define our gate neighbors
function
and for today's part two problem
description algorithm description
and uh wait why why does it not
and Microsoft flag keys is behaving
incorrectly or something
anyway so algorithm description and the
plan to how to implement this algorithm
plan in wolf language write a function
ff FF will have this input form that's
in Java they call it signature which is
idiotic okay in mathematics a function
you don't call a signature well
you don't anyway so f function ff has
this input form
one single argument of a list of two
things. Okay, it will return a list new
matrix and total remove sales count.
Okay, then we just fixed point. This is
recursion. This is supreme fixed point
even more supreme than Hascal. You know
Hascal and schem scheme racket schem
they they are into recursions but wen
language fix point more supreme. Okay.
So we define this function FF. This
looks complicated. So you can go to
Wufam language and copy the formatted
code. So click click click click
copy
and uh paste it here. So it's like
formatted code better. Okay. Remove
that.
And then you run that and the result is
what? 43. There it is. Okay, we need to
copy the whole thing and it shows
uh it shows the
output.
Fantastic and beautiful. So, put it
back. Cut. Paste. Paste again. syntax
color the whole thing and pop it out
again. This time we're going to do our
personal input
and uh
so what is my personal input?
Okay, you need to go to search for txt
there.
So this copy close back to code. Okay.
So you need to uh Okay. string paste
remove the last
character.
Okay. Go to the top. Is that right?
Yeah. Go to the top. Yeah. Input. So
this this this is copy the whole thing.
Go to wra language. Select all. Paste.
Shift enter. Shift enter.
Okay. Inefficient code. Who cares?
Because at the end of code, they don't
care.
Wait, how how inefficient is this? You
see, let's see. Every time you call this
get neighbors, it recreates the entire
matrix. That's how inefficient it is.
But also
this get neighbors actually needs to get
improved a lot because this get
neighbors
you know it creates array pad every time
you call it it recreates the whole
entire matrix. Okay.
So to fix that instead of creating array
pad here you should just array pad the
input then this function just work on
the padded array. So,
so every time this function is called,
it doesn't regenerate a new padded
array. It just use a global variable of
the padded array. So, that's that will
significantly make it faster.
Okay, this is not still not returning.
No, that's problematic. It's like too
slow. Okay,
so anyway, so that's one problem. But
there's also other inefficiencies
because here you are deleting cases. You
are deleting
[clears throat]
uh what is this? Uh delete cases.
Oh yeah. So it's um this this part is
actually just deletes the um
the the the cell itself except the
neighbors. I mean so it it it wants to
return the neighbors but you want to
delete the the cell itself. So it has to
look through all the neighbors
then delete the part. That's no good. So
you should you should instead of using
delete cases you just should say delete
nth
But if you code it that way then this
function will have difficulty in general
generalizing into n dimensional matrix
because right now you see this function
can be trivially generalized into n
dimensional matrix. So it's no longer
just like get the neighbors of a
two-dimensional matrix. We can have
three-dimensional matrix or
fourdimensional. This function get
neighbors of a given cell can work on
arbitrary dimension matrix. That's
that's that's like the power of the wam
language.
But but but this is inefficient. So so
the higher dimension is still no good.
You you you basically you look through
all the neighbors. So if you have like
100 dimensional matrix then for given
cell it has like 100 or whatever
neighbors you know that's another
interesting question given a matrix of n
dimension how many then then then g then
then given a a a cell in the middle of
the matrix how many neighbor does it
have that's a mathematical question
could be a advant of code question but I
don't think the the guy ever going to
have a question like that. You see given
a two-dimensional matrix
how many neighbor of a middle cell have
this is easy I mean if also we include
how u we include diagonal neighbors okay
but given three dimensional matrix how
many u neighbor it has including
diagonal that can be easy found out
let's say 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 at top eight
at bottom. Then then then you got then
you're going to have one two three four
five six seven eight.
Okay. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 top 98 bottom
eight in the middle slice. So 998
8 * 3
that's 24 24 + 4 2 you got 20 uh six.
So you have 26 neighbors in
three-dimensional cell. What about four
dimensional? Then you you need to work
out okay then you can you you then you
see a pattern you can generalize through
n how many neighbor so let's write that
out because it's an interesting problem
question how many
dimensional how many neighbors. A middle
cell of an N dimensional matrix has
counting diagonals.
Okay,
this is in resting
math question
can be a coding problem.
Well, it's not exactly a coding problem,
but it can be. Then in that case, you
have to
like you know, you try to code for a
threedimensional matrix and fourth
dimensional then you see a pattern then
you can write the function you know
but so it is interesting. Okay.
Okay. So but where are we? Did we get
the final answer? We did. So it returned
the answer yes 43 because uh wait
you know this so this one got sizing
memory 479
kilobytes
that's small that's trivial
you know Google chrome is like sucking 2
gigabytes we are only talking about one
megabyte so the answer is 8690
okay 869 90. So, show more.
Wait, show more.
Yeah. 8690.
Can Can you just get that? Oh, God.
You know, so we can [clears throat]
actually the last output. Wait, wait,
where did we type it? Okay. So you just
say
the last output the last output and uh
apply the function last that will give
you that number
8690.
Please make it work. Are you sure? Yes.
Submit. Submit.
That's the right answer. Yes, of course.
Fantastic.
Okay. Nobody's here. That's uh well
that's sad. Okay. Someone should
congratulate congratulate me. Okay. Some
somewhat you guys.
Okay. Let's put the answer here.
Okay.
Okay. So, we solved it. Put it back.
Syntax cutter the entire code in the
HTML page in showing browser. And let's
summarize what we did today. And that's
it. So we took about 2 hours
actually. Uh when did we start? So we
did uh 1 hour and 30 minutes. Oh, okay.
Not too bad. 90 minutes. Congrats. Thank
you. The beast. That beast. Thank you.
So summarize
today's talk show episode 732.
Uh
not too bad, pretty smooth. The input we
show the delete whatever is input. So
the input we turn it to a matrix of one
and zeros. We write we use the get
neighbors function we wrote before. Then
we figure out the algorithm steps the
and the plan to implement the algorithm
which essentially relies on writing this
function one single function and we use
recursion of fixed point. Fixed point
means apply the function to itself
until the result no longer changes.
Okay. Then it returns this you know the
result matrix and a number. The number
is the total of total count of the sales
that has been removed.
Okay. Then we use the personal input and
it takes a while. I don't know how long
uh but but advent of code because
if you pay attention you work five hours
to make it efficient. They don't care
like nobody would know your code
actually is very different from all the
other people who does it fast because
their code they don't you know they
don't care care about efficiency. So
when you spend time on efficiency, you
get punished.
That is often the case with the Unix
stuff. Unix and C those type of people
because they don't care about extension.
They don't care about design. They don't
care about they don't they just care
they do care about fast though, but they
don't care if they don't care about the
algorithmic efficiency like the older
like
So for example for example a given
problem let's say you have your input is
less than 100 okay like the typical
input so the C and Unix type of people
and including C++ and pretty much the
industrial coders including Java okay
but mostly C and C++ okay what they care
is that on average all these inputs
their program is the fastest okay their
program is just beats everything. We are
fast the Coders. Okay.
But if the input becomes 1,000 like
beyond expected input,
their program may crash or takes a day
to finish. But they don't care like
nobody's ever going to have the special
like art input. Who who is going to do
that, you know? They they don't care.
It's a C and C++ and the Unix
They created a computing industry like
that. Okay. So, so it's like bug new
version patch bug new programming
language based on C because we need to
fix the some problem in C and then C++
and oh but Java we need to create Java
because C++ got got this problem. Oh but
well actually Java got all this problem.
we we we need to create C sharp that's
or C the daddy of all the problems C and
Unix okay that is like my
uh very biased point of view but it is a
point of view that has some merits okay
you can think about C and C C and C++
and Unix the origin of the order damage
in computing kind of
Okay, that's it. Bye, guys.
If you like my stuff, okay, pay me. Go
to my website, kasadi.info.info.
x ahinfo.
Okay.
http no s not secure because I'm not
asking for your credit card. So, you go
to.info info. Then scroll down the
bottom. Then you go to Patreon website,
Amazon gift card website, you or PayPal.
You go to their website. Their website.
Click
click their website is secure. So you
can put credit card to it and pay me.
Okay. Thank you for your support.
Bye guys.