good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
today is 2021 november 20th and today we
are going to do wufam language coding
wufam language tutorial
okay wufang language fantastic
so let's begin so i did several wolfram
language by now maybe 10 in the past so
watch them okay so today it's purely
wufam language nothing else you can you
know
please do ask me questions okay ask me
questions so uh any comments technical
so i'm going to work on
wufang language and i'm going to work in
emacs and wufam language notebook and by
the way you can get them free
download for free just search for you
know xrd
wolfram language get wolfham language
for free
or you can buy raspberry pi it come with
it or you can you can just buy it okay
so i'm going to go over wufang language
today kind of tutorial i'm going to work
on my uhufam language tutorial and
in wolfen language i'm going to um work
in emacs as well
so this is my keyboard kinesis advantage
too this is ultimate hacking just search
for xadi
ultimate hacking xari
advantage you'll see them you'll see my
reviews and video reviews so emacs stuff
like he's showing browser so let's begin
so muffin language so first of all let
me show you several ways to work in
wufang language let's say integrate so
uh integrate okay so if you uh let's say
1 over x with respect to x okay do it
oh that's log x interesting so let's go
back here
let's go back here let's make it make
them into a
oh
fantastic mathematical notation
none of the latex
crap
okay so let's change the integral so
actually uh so let's go to input mod
let's uh by the way you can also edit
this directly
but in general i don't like it but okay
so let's say x squared okay now showing
that
do it
oh
fantastic
okay that's a wolfram language
mathematica notebook you can buy it okay
now let me show you in terminal okay
everyone loves terminal the
unix people linux people loves terminal
so let's begin
so we'll find script run it
then we're gonna integrate
okay 1 over x with respect to x yes
yes
where's my bracket there it is okay
enter
okay log x okay let's do it again now x
squared
enter one over x and uh nicely formatted
fantastic
and let's do the same thing in xiaowu
fan mod okay so let's show you so my
emacs here is the emacs workflow for you
emacs users so i'm going to for example
i'm using when i'm using xr
html mod okay so let's see
so you can see at the bottom you see
this that means i htm and what i'm going
to i'm going to show you okay um
describe key
press the key for
calling html mod here's a documentation
for
html mod and let's turn on global
highlight mod okay so here's our html go
to the source code open it
there is a source code
about
six hundred lines of code go to the top
and here is the url go to it
show in browser
you can see xy html mod buy it okay buy
it support me
uh and it's open source okay
so html mod and meanwhile let's show you
so here is my all my mods so in
so hide the unix thing
delete those tilde files
press x to delete them do you want to
delete them
yes
okay so these are all my emacs packages
and you can see search for wolfram there
it is cause i will find mod which is
what i'm going to using i'm also using
soft light keys
soft light keys which allows me
efficient operation of all the
you know efficient keybinding in emacs
because not like keys
so for example open it
go to the url showing browser supply
keys it's on github this one it's on
github use it and the stuff like keys
and i'm going to okay open it go to diet
okay not here
uh
yeah close that go to diet so and there
it is woof and language mod in which i'm
going to show you
uh on the pink window you can see all my
emacs chords
and the keystroke i press i'm using
borac
layout
okay so here we are looking at wufang
language mod you can see wu from
language mod and go to the top there it
is the url
open it
show in browser
woofer mod search the web you'll find it
okay and now let me demo demonstrate
some woofer mod because um we are going
to actually use it so because html mod
insert the code template let's say
wolfen lan okay so you can have you know
you have wolfram land here so one plus
one for example
and press a key
it opens in its own buffer you can see
and we can evaluate
uh no valid password found that's
because i'm running a wolfram language
session here now i need to exit here
now let's run this again
uh okay let's do it again
so you can see two at the bottom uh can
you see it let's see
okay so hide these
so can you see yeah you can see there
too
uh now let's type the same thing so
integrate okay so
completion okay that's a feature let me
show the pink window so i n t e press
tab so you have all these uh
press tab you have all these wolfram
language functions so you want enter
great integral integrate there there it
is okay 1 over x with respect to x
evaluate it
okay
evaluate and print so you can see the
answer the answer at the bottom but
let's go to the message buffer so you
can see there is the answer so let's do
it again but this time
x squared
do it
fantastic you can see there is answer so
this is in
language mod
okay so we just showed you know several
we showed three interfaces of using
wufam language
fantastic now next so
so
so what i'm going to do today is a kind
of wufam language tutorial
on the task of text processing and shell
scripting for example if you are using
bash
powershell
or if you are
a developer for example you are a
system or devops you know the modern lan
gen turn devops
uh so the kind of task is share tasks
text processing or you know launch your
program if it's you know amazon s3s
whatever um you want to check the status
of processes you want to go to a
directory recursively find the file if a
file exists or change something config
no those are share tasks
and we are going to do
those uh using language today
i mean i'm going to i'm going to uh okay
hold on a second
let me press a key
then they are back here show in browser
you can see we have today's code ufo
language and
press a key
you can see undo now watch this okay
watch this
let's magnify so watch this
press a key three keys so that command
is
toggle syntax color attacks
the key is f9 tt f9 is this key by the
way so i i have it on my kinesis so
let's do it again
undo
f9tt they become
you know wrapped with these spam html
tags now press the key to show in
browser fantastic
you can see
they have you know syntax colored so
this is part of the feature of xa html
mod
okay so so what what is it we are going
to do today okay uh text processing
tasks okay let's
open it so i have a tutorial from script
tutorial so what is woofam script
wolfram script is this
terminal
console command line line application
which allows you to
uh
run wufang language you know called
wolfram language in a text
command line line interface
that's wolfram script
you know it's bundled with when you buy
wolfram language or you when you
download the free wolfram engine
so
so that's what wufram script and here
you know i have some you know i wrote a
tutorial you can see you can go check it
out and we and so
so today i'm going to continue working
on this tutorial
on some of the
shell tasks
okay so i'm kind of just gonna work on
my tutorial and uh and you guys hello
huang
uh questions ask posted okay
so
get current directory uh so what i want
to do so let's see uh get current
directory so let me show you some of the
so for example
typically
in shell you know one of the most common
um
uh let's go to let's see let's go to web
cd directory
cd web xrd
info
then go to talk show okay cd to that
directory change directory
then you can say duh
you know
you list a bunch of directories so you
can say in in bash it's ls same thing
and right now i'm using powershell you
know powershell the
in fact the full command name is get
child item
yeah same thing so
cd to a directory and what's the current
directory current directory pwd
you see it tells you what my current
directory is
so all these commands cd calendar
at least directory and these directories
recursively let's go up okay cd
dot dot go up the
recurse okay that will this directory
recursively so you have like about two
thousand three thousand files here
now all these commands are typical shout
tasks and they can be done in language
too
so
for example let let me
let me show you okay so wufang language
so how do you uh ch cd to a directory i
don't know actually
so but uh you know cd to a directory is
not usually used in a script
usually because
cd to a directory is usually interactive
session but you can do that in wolfram's
wolfram language too but i believe is
that set directory yeah there it is
set directory okay let's click on that
to see the
um
health documentation hello german
german molina
why mathematica does not give the
constant of integration even if you
integrate the integral that's a good
good question because
because by decision you know it doesn't
make sense to do so
i mean if
you know mathematically speaking when
you integrate there's a constant right
but programmatic programmatically
if you you know
create a what's called computer algebra
system which is what mathematica is and
also maple and
and they're not many these days i mean
there are a few okay maple is the one of
the big competitor
so this application this kind of
program or language is called
um computer algebra system or symbolic
programming languages okay
so when you actually
create a programming language to do
integration
you know they can you know they can for
example when you design it of course
someone has have to design you know you
you might want to return a constant you
might say okay the result should be like
plus c where c is like some building
variable that can stand for any constant
okay you could you can do that but
it's not practical you know you just
want to return the integral you can you
know that's so that is a reason
uh i hope so that i hope that answers
the question so um and okay so let's uh
yeah so we were talking about set
directory so let's go to um so let's go
to the documentations of set directory
set the current working directory that's
right for example so we can say set
directory let's let's do it okay let's
try to do it first of all what is the
current directory let's do it this way
that will return the current directory
okay
users start documents okay now let's cd
to the current directory i mean to the
sound talk show okay so let's copy the
file path in emacs
now paste it here
so
cd to start talk show
okay
evaluate it
now let's do directory again
that's that shows the current directory
do it you see
now we that's a equivalent to the unix
cd
or powershell
set directory so let me show you edius
so in powershell you have lots of
aliases
get alias okay
then definition
then cd so this means i want to know
what is uh actual full name for the
alias cd do it
oh okay wait
so actually uh well what you can do that
by help cd okay it will tell you set
location okay
quit help now or you can do it get by
get alias dash definition
uh set location
local group set local users set location
so you can see powershell tells you
the alias for set location is either cd
or ch da or scl you know so so they
provide these edius is for unix
or the
command exe you know console
window con windows console users so it's
a convenient so cd is the most
convenient change directory okay so
so i have you know so what is this about
so i just talked about you know the
various language design issues and
naming of functions which i
have particular interest so for example
we've seen in bash it's just cd okay
there's no full name cd is just it
cryptic cryptic what the is cd so
you know so and in powershell they
provided by default you have this bunch
of idiosys get children for the ols
now in wolfen language we've shown
so you know
directory
shows the current directory
corresponding corresponding to unix pwd
okay in powershell what is pwd
it's get location okay get the current
location you know that's pwd now i i
don't actually remember what exactly pwd
is in bash i mean what does it stand for
uh path
you know
it's a unix cryptic pwd
so but in wolfen language you can see
they came from a math mathematician's
uh perspective
so directory
gives you the current directory and i
think it does something else i mean it
does uh
yeah it just gives you the current
working directory you know you know the
notion where at any time you have one
like current location you know that's
actually the old concept
so anyway set directory is like the cd
okay
and what about ls you know in unix
you have ls or the you know these
directories okay the the the
analogous the equivalent in wolfen
language would be
file names okay let me show you okay
file names do it you see
uh okay so
let's
so you see it's gives it returns a list
of all file names in current directory
you know
uh
yeah so let's do it again so cd talk
show
okay duh
you see at least the file names so in
wolfen language that's file names
you know
um okay so what what about if you want
recursive
you know
what what what if you let's say so these
are html files
so and some of them are text files you
can see some of them html some of them
text
what if you just want html files okay
let's do it
so you the first argument would be a
pattern so
star
html
okay enter so you see now it
just give you a bunch of html files
now what how many files are there so you
say
you say let me let me show you this okay
length okay
run it
369 html files so that means by now i
have run 369
youtube videos start talk show so on in
powershell we can do
um the
include
star html
then
type it to
length
i mean not linked okay i mixed up wufang
language with uh
okay pipe it to measure
okay that's how in powershell works okay
what
the include html what's going on uh
okay that's all html files
there it is now why is that zero before
i made a typo or something so wait maybe
is it because i don't have recurs that
shouldn't be
i don't have recurs and it's not showing
uh yeah i don't know why
so anyway 369 files that's the way you
do it in powershell and the full name
would be measure something
measure object
yeah that's a full name so in in wufang
language it's a length okay
and by the way that syntax is equivalent
so the above syntax is equivalent to
let's let me show you okay
common questions post it okay
so this
double slash is you know this file name
double slash length is equivalent to
this syntax
so the double slash they function just
like the unix pipe okay that's a post
post fixed notation
so this double slash length means
do whatever this
then
when
then takes the output and feed it to the
input of length so that's what that
means
okay let me read the comments
pw is print working directory oh
oh my god the print working directory
the unix
mysteries
what
integrate integrate x x x the result are
you are you saying there's a bug in
wufang language
not likely
i mean there are bugs for sure but not
for that simple thing
so so you are asking a question
integrate integrate integrate x
twice i mean integrate x then take the
output and integrate that again
and you are saying
you know i don't know what's the math i
forgot about calculus so but we can you
know we could try your result i don't
know what so are you what are you saying
are you saying there's a bug not likely
but it should be three
uh it should be three third power over
six plus cx i don't think you are
correct
so okay so just just just to be sure
let's um
just to be sure
hey diors so um
okay it's x third power over six i'm
certain
i'm 100 certain that is the correct
answer
okay so
hi do you know of any web app
none math project built with wolfram of
course
of course wufam alpha okay that's a
giant that's you know stefan wolfham
likes to call it uh the killer apps you
know the killer apps is the notion among
hackers of the 1990s and early 2000s
you know stephen wufam he's about 10
years older than me so we are kind of in
the same generation but today the
killer app notion is kind of good paul
graham for example the
lisp god paul graham the creator of
hacker news
he's also you know uh
you know like you know he the the notion
of killer abs is also in his mind
because when he wrote the yahoo store in
common lisp you know he created and sold
it to yahoo for for millions of dollars
you know then he wrote article about why
lisp you know is the powerful secret
weapon for startups to make you uh
become a millionaire a billionaire
and then he says you know so his
killer app is the yahoo store written in
common list
so for wufam language the killer apps is
wufam alpha wufam alpha obviously so
let's go to let's go to a browser here
wu from offer computational intelligence
oh you need javascript let's turn on
javascript okay
okay so now you wanna let's do integrate
let's do integrate here so let's do this
integrate twice let's see what wu fam
have
say so woofer martha is written in
wufang language
okay enter
oh wait okay so it says um
okay so why is it um
indefinite integral
okay so that's um
okay that's yeah i i see what you are
saying
so
what is the answer so that you know you
know good question so when you integrate
something
there is a constant right there's a
constant
but if you omit that then the constant
disappears so in tech so you know yeah
again
um is you know again i would say it's a
it's a you know this is a question of
decision you know it's a design issue
okay so
so when you integrate x
over x
the result there's a constant however in
wolfram language that constant is
omitted
so when you integrate that again of
course depending on whether you have a
constant that constant matters
so but
but you see if you know the programming
language uh language you know
that the constant is omitted therefore
when you type this expression
it's not what you wanted the syntax is
wrong in other words
but let's see okay let's focus on the
question why what happened to the
constant so let's look up the wolfram
documentation what happened to the
constant there there might be an option
you know so for example you know you
click on uh integrate okay
so integrate blah blah blah minimal to
max you know definite
integral then
then multiple integrals okay then you
can specify the domain of the you know
of the variable
and okay you can also specify a
geometric
region which is called um
uh which is called a double integral
what what is the chord i i don't
remember green integral or something you
know it's been a long time
so let's see what happens you know let's
focus on the constant where did the
constant go i mean they they probably
have some explanation
okay a multiple integral used variable
constant iterator notation
uh
for indefinite integrals integrate tries
to find results that are correct for
almost all values of parameters okay
for definite integrals the following
option can be given assumptions okay you
can have some assumptions general
condition okay whether to generate
answers that involve condition on
parameters
okay principal value
okay whether to find koshi principal
values now i'm not sure what is
principal value let's click on that
okay i don't know i don't know what is
the
principal value go back
so what happened to the constant
okay
it didn't say here or did i misread i'm
pretty sure that you know the answer
somewhere
okay scope you know lots of lots of to
read scopes options possible issues
let's click on possible issues
indefinite integral
many simple integrals cannot be
evaluated in terms of standard
mathematical functions yeah that's
obvious
well
i mean that's obvious to mathematicians
the indefinite integral of a continuous
function
anyway that's that's just the design
issues okay for example let's search for
constant
uh
okay let's
see so
yeah so you know generated parameters c
so include the constant constant of
integration in an indefinite integral so
if you want the constant
here is what you do okay copy it
you know wufam language their
documentation is very succinct you know
there it is you know there it is the
constant you know very succinct so
because they can there are 6 000
functions okay you know i showed before
you can you can
you can type this you know yeah
you
can but
you know you can type you know
um
this and it will list all functions then
you can get the length
okay let me let's show it okay so just
enter it you here is the list of
or
close to 7 000 functions okay 7 000
functions so you want to know that how
many are there so you do that and uh
length okay let me do this a few times
and and we'll see
ah okay
anyway that's not important you know
that's digression so
seven thousand functions okay there are
seven thousand functions in wufam
language some of them are very advanced
special math functions only a handful of
people understand in a world
you know
like a thousand or two thousand some of
the functions okay mathematical
functions now for the mathematical
function integrate that's a very common
function right
uh
billion uh you know billions of people
understand this but what i'm trying to
say is that wolfham language
documentation is very
terse and concise so when you look up
the
mathematical function or whatever
algorithmic function computer science
theoretical computer science function
combinators whatever when you look up a
function documentation
it assumes that you know
the mathematical
meaning the you know the mathematical
issue of it you know for example when
you look up integrate
it will not try to explain to you oh
integrate is uh part of calculus it is
you know
you know the meaning is that when you
have a you know uh raymond sum
that's how
the function will return the riemann sum
it doesn't do that okay it assumes you
know what integrate means and all the
complexities
such as the constant okay so the
document the wolfram documentation
will
be very condensed it only explains what
ufam language
uh
aspects of
of this mathematical function it will
not try to explain
what is in you know the math notion of
integrate so it assumes you already know
you know it because it's a
fundamental fact that when you integrate
this a constant it doesn't even even
mention it it just
it does it did mention it so you see so
that's how we found this you know so
so that's kind of a digression on the
documentation
on the
one aspect of documentation of
fulfillment language i'm talking about
this because i am very interested in
documentation yeah okay digression
integration let's go to so
let me recap so wufam alpha is written
in wolfram language okay
and wufang language itself is mostly
written in wufan language itself okay
wolfen language is written in uh
language plus c c
provides the fundamental call
just like lisp okay emac list
is mostly written in emac list
same thing with common lisp okay common
lisp emac these
they are written mostly in themselves
but with except ten percent is in c okay
same thing with wolf and language you
know this
kind of list from my family so wolfen
language is written in uufam language
except maybe 10 i don't know
i don't know how many percent you know
a core is written in c or c plus first
they they might have you know part of it
is c plus plus and and probably a small
part is assembly okay i don't know the
you know you have to
that's a wolfram you know corporation
information
and wu famafa is written in wufang
language and basically uh i you know the
essentially the whole website you know
the woofam website the documentation you
know they have like
300 000 pages this is all written in
wufang language
okay that answers part of the question
and we
and that also answers the you know
integrate you see it's when it's
interesting is that what uh you know
when you use wufam alpha to do this
it actually shows you
you know the constant there but not when
you use wufang language why
because wufang mafa is a the audience is
generic public public you know
it doesn't assume you already know what
integrate is actually supposed to have a
constant it doesn't assume so it
so you see it so that so there's a
smartness you know so depending on the
audience you know they they they do that
okay so let me answer some questions we
kind of digressed a little bit so we
talked about so
ufo alpha is written in uh language and
we talked about
some the integration details and some
aspect of
documentation of wolfram language and
let me show you
documentation you know i'm obsessive
about reading documentation obsessive to
a degree you cannot possibly imagine
like i said before the wolfram language
in the 1990s i called it for over 10
years so the wolfram language book is
this thick you can find it all on my
website okay so
let me show you okay lots of digressions
we
let's get back to coding wolfen language
pretty soon okay so
here is all my wolfram language
tutorials and guide i've written
and for example ufam language book
okay so back in 1990s every version from
mathematica it was called mathematica
there's this book it's a 1200 pages you
know this thick
so i had you know i read it
cover to cover word for word every word
you know including whatever words it
says on the frontal piece
preface table of contents
front cover
back cover inlet
and
how do you call this part i forgot i you
know i used to know every part of the
book so i i have to read every word not
just every word but including i have to
notice the spreading
and the punctuation okay that's my
obsession obsession since
since late since i was a teen okay so i
have an obsession with reading
documentation so i read this thing
three times in different years
uh in 1990s okay
yeah so digression so you know this kind
of thing people like to watch but
we should get back to uh wufam language
technical detail the digration you know
i can talk on this for for four hours
okay so but hold on let me just show you
some more okay so language documentation
i'm obsessed about
so i have a complete
documentation of
of my reading documentation
let's see where see so computer language
perving
on lisp
syntax soup semantic noodle you know
lots of docu lots of essays hundreds of
essays on semantics
um syntactical issues okay tons of
articles um this
all these articles are about lisp
and uufam language is a lisp and uh
complaint perving so i have past videos
you should go watch and jargons okay
jargons in the industry what does oop
means what's this comprehension what's
the lambda what should it be is the
lambda you know naming of things is it
proper with respect to what you know
what is a criteria
to have a good naming you know name is a
thing programmers are concerned all the
time you know
naming of things jargons tail recursion
that's the obsession of skin these
people what's currying what's closure
you know this typically the unit the
elite hacker types they are
they are obsessed with this jargon repo
ripple their ass okay they don't they
don't know what they talking about they
they have no general sense of the
the the
the the linguistic
aspect and social aspect of naming of
things jargons why is there why are they
there they cannot even define it they
don't know this indeed hacker unix
types you know they
they just they just enjoy their sloppy
puns like the unix cd pwd you know
that's
so all these jargons automata you know
persistent data structure attack union
you know so this part is about jargons
okay
then
jargons let me let me let me go to the
documentation part i mean the
doc by dummies okay so here's a
collection of articles where i either
criticize the documentation of
programming languages um or
related issues you know how it should be
the writing style the
organization you know so they you know
it's like you can do this for years
most programmers they don't know nothing
they don't know they you know how do you
you know what is the documentation what
are the aspect of to writing a
documentation
first of all you have organization
issues for example php python perl
closure
java
e-mag list
their documentation are all entirely
different the old just the organization
part okay i can like i can go now i can
right now demonstrate each one of them
php documentation java documentation
python documentation javascript
documentation which doesn't exist by the
way but uh but the basically you go to
mozilla that's your javascript
documentation
you know enclosure documentation and and
unix documentation the man page the bash
you know so i've i've read them in
detail you know in depth php for example
php documentation is like a thousand
page
more than a thousand pages i read them
every page
i read the entirety in
2006 okay
twice i think i think twice then then
there's also mysqr documentation i read
it from cover to cover okay
a thousand pages so documentation issues
so this is a collection of my articles
on documentation doc by dummies these
idiots most the worst documentation is
the unix okay the unix
they don't know how to write they don't
know what they're talking about and they
they don't know what
what they are uh trying to say they they
confuse the idiot you know they they
just think gwok woke is the word i'm a
unique squawk you just oh you when you
read something you broke it
unix okay that's a lot of digression so
so i came so
so here is for example what is this um
computer language documentation size
comparison so i compared for example
closure documentation is 30 megabytes
okay svg scalable vector graphics
documentation the official specification
for svg 1.1 is 6 megabytes
closure 30 megabytes
css3 spec
is 1 megabyte okay
css 2 spec is 15 megabyte it's like 30
times bigger
then okay then then java 8 doc
396 megabyte java 8
396 megabytes okay
then then okay php
doc
100 megabyte you know
on my website i used to actually have a
copy a mirror of each of these
documentation
eventually i deleted them because they
you know there are thousands pages you
know on my website you know i just did
them
so python doc python 2.7 is 34 megabytes
python 3.3 is 37 megabytes you know this
some of the deta one of the aspect of
the documentation okay so i'm obsessed
about reading documentation you know
then i have criticism on python perl on
style now writing style is another
aspect of documentation this you know
uh so lots of things to talk about
documentation so that is why
i just
spontaneously gave you
certain
of my analysis of one aspect of wolfham
documentation about
terseness
you know about
concession okay
you know where i said that ufam language
like documentation they have 700
functions 7000 functions
when it comes to mathematical functions
they don't try to
teach you what it is they assume you
already know what integrate is in
mathematics they just cover what the
wolfram language actually
uh do do with it
okay
so okay actually so today we already
talked for one hour we um
you know lots of questions comments i
haven't get them to them yet okay so but
what are we going to do now i was going
to
um
i was then trying to do actually
write my tutorials
live stream but
it's already one hour
so the anyway so this page is about
wolfram script tutorial
but it's also about
i tried to tell you some of the common
function names you know
when you want to use wufam language to
do uh shell related tasks
so we yeah so we let's go back so we
explained for example how do you list
directories
so the let's delete the output so hold
on a second
so i think we are going to end in 5 or
10 minutes
so let's delete the output
edit
cell delete all output okay now it's
better
so now we can see
so you you see i showed you what is the
equivalent of the or ls in language and
also with a pattern and also
this is this is uh this let me let me
tell you let me let me continue with
this one okay this this is the beauty of
wolfram language what if you want
all
html files and
okay let me show you first of all let's
go to powershell so let's go to xrd dot
info okay what
cdwebsardi.info okay so
the
so here's a list of directories there's
lots of files now let's say the
recurse
file only
we don't need it we actually we don't
need that part let's say include
i want to i want all javascript files
and
css files okay
so
recursive you know but all javascript
and css files so there you go so now
let's do just names
okay so
quite a few javascript files and also
css files okay let's let's modify let's
just say i want typescript and the css
okay then let's see how many files are
there measure
okay type script files and css files
there are 105 of them
in
xali.info okay now let's try wufang
language
here's how you do it
so give a list so you have two patterns
dot html dot html then you have another
pattern
css oh wait
css and typescript okay
ts okay so do it
oh
the current directory is wrong uh so
remember we have to set directory
so set directory
exactly info okay so switch to that
directory
then
then do this
oh then but you want recursive okay
so um
so the current directory okay so yeah
so here is the current directory
directory
okay
then recursive
so
instead of saying recursive for example
in powershell you say dot
you say dash recurse
in
bash you say dash r
capital
r uh depending on the unix you know bsd
unix
gnu linux you know they they have
different uh option names for recurs but
in wufang language you you give it a
number you you give a number to indicate
the depth you want let's say 99 okay so
do it
so here is a list of all css and the
typescript files okay now let's say
let's see how many are there
lengths
do it
105 agree they agree you see
now but what if you have more than 199
directories let's say you can say
infinite
infinity
do it
105 and you can make this into a
you know into a mathematical type set
you see that infinity
run it
100 405 okay so i showed some of the
equivalent of the ufam language you know
the the you know the unix
ls or the power shelter or the
language and so
so then but then you know you can delete
directory you can you can check if if a
file is a directory
or a file or you can check if a file
exists or not or directory exists or not
this is how you do it in language or you
can get the file extension or get the
file name or get the directory path you
know these are common very common tasks
when you use sha
so you can also get the file date the
modification date the creation date the
access date the you can get the file
size you can get a file hash you can
print file content for example the first
10 lines or the last 10 lines things
like that you how how do you read the
file how do you turn the file into a
string you know get the file content
write to file and and replace string and
so on so this
so that's what this uh page is about
okay that's it i'm going to read the
comments now and that's it for today
hi deuce
if okay if you like my stuff ching ching
you see the dollar sign somewhere
okay pay me okay paypal patreon amazon
link amazon gift card you know i have it
you know you can find how to pay on my
website
or you know buy my wolfram language
uh
you know by my wolf you know wolfram
language package or some fly key
or my emacs packages you know i've
showed you before there are quite a few
so deals you are wondering you know what
app has been written in language it's
written it's used by engineers okay it's
used by scientists and engineers so if
you are a physicist
if you are a physicist for example or if
you are a mathematician physicist mostly
let's say
chances are
let's say more than 50 of them more than
50 percent
of physicists on this earth
is probably using wolfram language right
now okay
now you don't know because most of you
uh we you know we are programmers
programmers are not physicists we are we
don't know mathematics we don't know
engineering most programmers you know
programmers
so you don't know so
nasa for example nasa
or
or whatever you know when you do rocket
space or design car engines those are
engineering mechanical engineering
material engineering chemistry when you
petroleum you know all your gas
you want to dig into a hole in under the
ground or you want like um elements
self-driving cars wufam language it's
all over artificial intelligence
research and prototype it's all over
okay that's a that's a you know that's
the application of
language like where is it used
chinchin thank
by the way i'm drinking
milk and
this is um milk banana
milkshake
so
t34 keyboard what is i don't know what
is a t34 keyboard
oh
remind me that i haven't finished i
haven't
read this um
i haven't finished reading it i haven't
you know went back to read it
um
yeah remind me on on discord please
you know just paste to discord
keyboard you know if you haven't already
joined discord very a lot diverse
opinions interesting people
and i rent my rants on discord all the
time
not your problem my problem
can we talk about how we can how we get
your elis updates and if we can send you
upstream pull requests oh yeah so gosh
you bought my emac this tutorial i mean
that the emac this because imac this
package but i don't know your email can
you please send me your email
so you know be sure
when you paypal me
include your email
i looked i cannot find your email so do
that please
uh if you want updates i you know i'm
like
i'm a single person you know i'm just a
hacker
okay so i don't have like
commercial organizations you know i i
didn't i don't really have a like
streamlined system
where you automatically get updates you
know those nice things so everything is
manual so when we use email me you know
you send me paypal oh someone sent me
paypal you know i got money
i manually
email it back to you that's usually how
it works with some help of my script you
know
but it's not you know it's not it's not
under amazon system or whatever payment
gateway system it's not like that
so it might take a day for me to respond
so right now i don't have a system to
automatically like send you update i
don't even have a decision on what kind
of update you know
code update for example let's go to some
packages
you know and so i'm starting to sell
them it was they have been open source
for over 10 years
but
open source very sad story
uh it got me to
near death by hunger so
right now they are still open source but
you pay me
but right now i don't have a system like
when
so if you want to update easiest just
email me okay don't you don't have to be
shy like i mean not just you a lot of
people you just say cuz now can i get
this i paid you i i bought this
you know on this
this this month last month or whatever
date a year date can you send me your
update is there any update i'll i'll
just do it okay
once i got a lot of that i'll try it out
i'll just i'll start to have some kind
of automation to do that right now just
ask me i'm kind of like free
free i'm a free man and i i don't have a
like set up schedule and and things like
that
so i have heard some people say wolfham
language is slower than other language
is that true yes that is true
because
language you know you got all these you
know it's like
who fem language is the highest level
language by a magnitude nothing comes
close like you you have c okay you know
you have four trend here fortran
the fastest
if you are talking about number number
crunching four triangles fastest okay
you have fortran
c
c plus plus or c sharp or you know c
plus plus then
c sharp maybe java then you have
javascript then you have pearl python
ruby you know and then bash you know
kind of and maybe haskell somewhere you
know haskell
rust just around c you know
like that okay
then you have bash is the slowest okay
then you have mathematica but so but
mathematica the level the high levelness
of mathematica is
certainly a magnitude beyond them
so if you want to talk about speed okay
yeah people you know people are
concerned see idiots
mostly particularly the eunuchs
philosophy the sea the sea prosperous
the rust lovers they are the idiot they
are the type who is chanting about
speed dribbling about speed oh speed
speed they are idiots
they made the whole computing industry
the most slow they
see so if you want you know let me let's
talk about speed okay
so i want the i want to compute pi
to
3 000 number of places okay pi
give me pi to 3 000 number of places
okay do it
speed
are you talking about speed how fast can
you do this in c show me show you show
ways of code
c is fast right four trans fast
give me pi two three thousand places
okay
instantaneous there okay so that's pi
okay three thousand places not enough
let's say let's say 30 000 let's let's
push the limit
instantaneous jesus
you know if you add one more zero then
it's gonna take a day to scroll okay now
not just pi let's see
i want the golden ratio okay
now is that golden ratio okay golden
golden ratio okay give me golden ratio
to 30 000 places oh jesus now let's
solve some complicated
differential equations okay
you get idea okay i forgot i forgot you
know i don't remember my mathematics i
don't remember the differential
equations so for example soft okay
uh you know sub you know i which
function to use for solving different
you know
solving algebraic equations okay let's
let's try some random
you know okay you get a point you know
the if okay so let's see
um
s o l v
okay solve there
okay stop attempt to solve the system
expression of equations or inequalities
for the variables fast okay so you can
you know it's solved lots of things so
here's some examples for example we can
try it by the way we can run code right
here too you know in the wolfram
documentation
but uh
but when you close it it will it won't
be saved you know the documentation is
protected protected
but you can for example let's say third
power let's run the code right here you
know there it is you are solving now
this is a algebraic equation of third
degree polynomial and what's the
assumption assumption is x is what a
real number or complex number okay
so here's a solution okay and typeset
you know
try to do this in la tech you know the
unix idiots the open source idiots try
to type this it takes you one hour just
to type that
okay so i mean if you want to input form
for example this you are looking at tab
set you know i press one single button
you got the input form okay now let's
copy one single button let's go to
emax new buffer paste it there it is
okay that's a solution of a algebraic
equation
so
c is fast you know you know how many
lines of this in in language is one line
how many lines of is that in c
ten thousand
ten thousand and it will take you a year
to write it
okay
you know like the
like i said before the unix
philosophy the unix idiots and the sea
idiots they go hand in hand they
brainwashed the entire computing
industry into some idiotic thought you
know like speed
portability
hackability you know
kind of like that that's the sea that's
the brain of the sea and today rust okay
that's a same lineage same kind of
thinking c
c plus plus
rust this is kind of uh same same type
type of people they don't like golen on
the other hand
okay so we talking you know i'm
demonstrating some speed okay so speed
wufang language and lots of other
examples i mean here we are showing some
mathematical example what about code
code what about like
algorithmic you know like the things
programmers do every day we do every day
there's a lot okay
i i you know there's two too many you
know you just one line of code is fast
okay and and also let me mention
[Music]
speed okay anyway so
that's it for that okay um
okay can ufm language hook up to gtk
uh
not to gtk but you there's a hook to uh
python to ruby to
uh julia to you know i'm not sure about
gtk yeah anyway that's it for today
thank you guys for watching bye
so we shut down in one minute or two
so right now i'm just going to close my
you know i'm going to link to what we
talked about today
um so okay cut that so let's see what is
this okay i'm just going to document
what we talked about today add wufang
language paste it here show in browser
so that's the output
and
okay this keyboard i might you know this
about layout article i might talk about
i mean i might
continue read about it remind me okay on
this code and so close that open offer
we don't need it close that so sorry
info close that move on mathematical
book copy that here okay
um
okay uh
wu from language copy that paste here
close that
dock by dermis indeed okay
locked by dummies
okay go back
go back
go back close that
close that
movement script tutorial okay it's
already here close that stop
woofer mod okay
paste the link because that
saw packages okay by my
packages thank you please subscribe if
you like it please thumb up if you don't
like it don't them down okay
and please comment okay am i idiot or
not please answer let me know what you
think i love you
stuff like keys copy copy
bye bye
now you are looking at the power of xr
html mod showing browser fantastic
and wufam language there it is pi
you know i'm curious let's add one more
zero let's say pi to the three hundred
thousand let's see let's see we'll
like explode my com computer let's do it
instantaneously let's scroll down
pi to 300 000 places
okay you know so they got you
you got the full thing so now
let's let's say pi squared you know
maybe you thinking oh they actually they
stored in this in memory maybe
so let's say pi
squared
okay let's say square root of pi let's
say pi times golden ratio okay
300 300 000 places do it
there it is
okay
you