Frank guys so today I'm going to show
you a max coding Emacs Lisp example I'm
going to write a command so I'm not in
my blog so let's see so I'm running my
blog and this is my art blog on
animations by the way this this guy
Richard Williams is great one of the
greatest and mater there's a lot science
and art to it it's very interesting
anyway so I'm writing my blog and often
times I want to include the video like
for example here let me show you in
Safari because in Safari
I have video turned on so so this video
I'm doing it's going to be 10 or 15
minutes if I if I go over time you know
just keep skipping around because I I
tend to look lose track of time and go
you know so anyway so so when I run
write blog I often frequently I have
videos you know I had a video so that
leads to a example let's go to YouTube
YouTube
so let's see animations speak animation
okay
Hellboy Hellboy that's a good okay so so
suppose I want this animation it's copy
it I can't copy the URL and let's say I
want to add it here I paste here and I
have a command the command name is
excited HTML any link of I so it becomes
it becomes from UI R becomes a youtube
link and let's have a look
and see the key is this so there it is
Hellboy
okay that's great and now you see what
happened is that usually I want to add
who did it you know the title of the
video and who create who uploaded or
created it and what date so so I copy
that copy and put it here and Harris boy
so delete this my DVD did that I don't
need I don't need okay that that that's
what I want you see this is the title
this is the I don't need this money so
title oh well this is PI okay this is a
guy who uploaded and for which date
so let's look in the browser now in
Firefox I don't have the JavaScript on
so you don't see the movies yeah we
don't need to see it so anyway so the
line becomes one line that's not good I
want what I want is this br br so save
it go to browser refresh you see that's
the format I want okay but but you see
here's another one Richard Williams
animation movement title by and
published date you see here it's become
one line it's no good so I need to add
BR here here it gets tedious so I'm
going to write this command so I can
select a region and code command and the
BI is added to every end of line like
here here here okay so let's start
reading that okay open nuke new buffer
it's just give it a random name and the
fun okay defend let's say what I do what
do I want to call this
you see it said that naming is the most
difficult thing in programming
so anyway so let's say XHTML had the
let's just say that for now okay so that
dark string
add a br like add a B to end of line to
current end of line or selection if
there's one so give a date
you should I put the date version so
okay so right so that's okay so what we
wanted to so first of all we want to
check if there is selection so let's do
that if what's name for check for
selection
I forgot you know normally actually you
know normally why I called him Alex this
I just go to my my team well I have
written a lot eMac beast code so I just
usually I know where similar
functionality are having another
function I just go to that function and
copy and paste you know that's copy and
paste is it's actually the most
practical way to program with weight you
can even go to yeah this is what I want
to do so you seek stuff like he's I go
there and open there's huge amount of
functions you know four thousand lines
so go to the big that's the beginning
let's go down
so you see there's a lot functions and
actually I can just I know where to find
but let's not do that because if I do
that it kind of loses the point of doing
a video you know interactive coding
tutorial kind of thing so if I just
struggle adhere myself then you can see
you know you can probably get you know
pick up my body language and see okay
where how things are done okay so anyway
what I want to do is I want to check if
there's a selection selection now what's
the function name there's a function
name I forgot so let's call a proper
select wait in Emacs selection is called
region active region so okay I think
okay the command is called use region P
use Regency let's see yeah there is you
see I'm using soft like way I'm using
solid emag be smart so I just typed
abbreviation like use user u RP and
usually that will work so use region P
it will return true if there is a region
and basically yeah so if it is true then
we do this if it's not true then we do
this so if it's not true then we just go
to yeah my alarm alarm clock we know let
me turn it off
sorry about that
I'm back so yeah the alarm clock
no it's like every 30 minutes it tells
me to get up to walk because otherwise
my hand is suffering
you know typing too much so anyway so if
there's no region let's go to end of
line you know that way he said right in
the running is a moot point to end of
life yes that's what we want so end of
line and it just got to end of line and
insert
beyond he's alright let's go back to Oh
wrong I thought there's something wrong
so yeah so so that press tab to indent
well so now so if there's no region then
just do this very simple now if there is
a region okay here's what we want to do
we want to narrow to region so first of
all save restriction yes they narrow to
region in our to region region beginning
region end that's right so this we are
narrow to region narrow to region is
like have you ever used it it's very
good like you make a selection and you
call the command narrow to region and it
eMac will will act as if the entire
buffer is just your region so so for
example if you are doing find and
replacement you want you know you only
focus on the region you want you know
make changes outside this of this region
so that's very good so if you want to
get out just go widen widen is you know
remove the narrow to region so anyway we
are using now to region in the program
so what so what's the save restriction
that means you know once you done with
your region you want to basically widen
where is it
yeah yeah you know remove the narrow to
region and and emag miss you co you you
you - Yuko Savior restriction so anyway
so yeah so program save restriction
narrow to region that's right
and then
let's then let's just do fine replace
that's the idiom for when you want to do
fine replace so what you do is while
such forward wait before we do that you
want to go to go go to the cha-cha go to
character go to the position point mean
so point mean is usually zero that's the
beginning of the buffer so anyway so go
to chop point mean then Wow such forward
weight so let's see I mean there are
many ways to do this and I'm thinking
what's the best way anyway let's stop
thinking about that let's just do this
you know it cuz yeah let's just just
finish this
so you want to here we want backslash I
just got a new keyboard so so the keys
are position I'm unfamiliar so X ash
there okay so search for word for lying
returned character and yes so if it's an
you know ignore bound and stuff so if
it's true then you just replace wait
search for that replay replace rejects
no I don't think that's I haven't coded
eMac peaceful for a while so let's go
let's go to my eMac this tutorial that's
the that's the that's the most practical
way to do things so they are so there is
the idiom for such replace where is it
writing commands yes fine replace text
they are how do we place match that's
right so you see while replace match so
while that we face match that's what we
want we face it with
so replace with that that that that's
that that that that that okay that's
that's that's it I think that's it let's
just try it then you know we don't need
this anymore
I put that there is so that the last one
does not get moved to here because
sometimes you know because when it's not
moved there it's like you can you can
like you know delete brog but if it's
there sometimes you TV blog and your
syntax is wrong anyway that anyway that
doesn't matter so so here's a code here
is the finished code let's try it then
Eva wait what do I do
so Eva last six okay save now let's go
back to my HTML file there it is so
let's call the command
sighs TM l had er oh yes that's
good now let's try selection else that's
wrong okay
you see what happening is that you need
to you want the BR before the line break
that's right so Eva Eva last sex and and
do and do and do and it's select call
the command that's good that is good now
but there is one more thing because it
should remove the selection I don't know
why it's not removing the selection
program end of line insert break so save
restriction
we don't need to let any more so we
never need it in the first phase
so anyway why is it not let's see I
don't know it's let's do this one so at
okay that's I don't know why well I
think you know usually usually when a
command is called it should the
selection will be removed
yeah I have to look into it what yeah
what yeah let's okay how long have we
been running this ready well I don't
know how long have we been doing this
but I'm thinking wait make a dog better
so yeah okay let me think about it let's
see if we can solve this in a minute
otherwise it's just called a day okay so
save restriction arrow to region go to
cha while it's not it's let's try this
okay if I make a selection okay such
failed that's expected
yeah but the selection should be removed
savoury section narrow to region save
restriction
I don't know I have to look into it okay
let's let me look at my code n so let's
look at this command
actually wait hold on a second let's see
okay let's look at this command sort of
a later case because because in this
command I intentionally try to keep the
selection on so let's look at tar go to
case code this is the code you see so I
have the act deactivate mock Neil you
see normally it song that's a variable
so when that is on that means when the
command is finished the selection of
region will be inactive being activated
it will be made inactive
so let's look at the documentation the
activate mark deactivate the mark if
transient mark is disabled this function
only does nothing right transient mod
transient mock mod basically is just
it's a minor mod that makes erection
highlighted that's all basically that's
that's all it does so if this function
only does nothing nothing but if force
is no Neil it the active a it
deactivates the mark anyway
okay wait deactivate mark is a function
it's not a variable
okay my safe back to kneel
well anyway I don't I don't know what's
the right direction but we can you know
for the sake of this video we we we
could you know if all we want is just to
solve this problem then we can just call
that
you see so let's try that let's select
this code a command way
right
deactivate what if transient is disabled
okay the documentation is pretty lousy
you see it deactivate the Mach if
transient Mach mod is disabled this
function normally does nothing okay so
if it's disable this function only does
nothing but if force is Nanao it
deactivates mark anyway so this is kind
of silly okay
you see the documentation is not I don't
think you know in my first impression
it's not it's not well written why
because it tries to discuss two separate
issues kind of being one sentence
because first first of all it talks
about whether transient mark Martis on
you know with you know it says when this
mod is disabled this this does nothing
okay but what if it's enabled it doesn't
say but it went down to talk about the
optional argument yeah so it's kind of
confusing but anyway I know what it
means you know I know what's trying to
say because because normally transient
mark mod is just just make the region
highlighted make the region active so
anyway let's just try that I'm like
rambling too much so now it should work
select all correct
no wait what
if you use the region
where is a change in Emacs 26 this would
be interesting is control edge and easy
control edge and gives you new Emacs
news with which which is Emacs way of
saying features like new features so
this is wait hold on a second
curse curse okay be open now I want to
change you see it by default the news is
in our line mod and online mod the keys
its key bindings are problematic like as
you know and I'm using soft like keys
you can see sulphide keys which is a
special key binding and okay it works
anyway so let's anyway let's let's
change it to poke mod you see oka mod is
basically a extension of a line mod and
the key bindings is more sensible and
far more features so anyway so I mean
the Emacs 26 yeah you see in acts 26
News and let's look at what wait such
park
such such deactivate mark
okay hold on a second let's go back
let's such that it's just paste it here
such okay this does not happen anywhere
in the fire so but it's okay I can mock
active so copy that close paste such
okay it's not there either
okay so I don't know what's going on I'm
you know I don't know I have to look
into it the actor very much so
well this this one more thing we can try
to quickly just set the Pam mark to to
knee oh yeah so mark you see mark active
is a variable so you just said it to
Neil and TV that run select go to
command court yes your doesn't work it's
use it is it because let's see
copy your new buffer paste now I mean
text mod so maybe you make the
difference no there's something going on
so I don't know what it is I hope it's
not some other anyway
okay let's say that that's it for today
I hope you learned something
thank you for watching
bye-bye