test
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show today I'm going
to teach you a max regular expressions
okay I'm going to teach you a max
regular expressions for the first 30
minutes also you know 30 minutes 40
minutes then perhaps we are going to
chat randomly about things about
programming things JavaScript goal and
programming languages and so on you know
maybe after that so but first first of
all I'm going to give you a introduction
you know maybe a bit deeper than
introduction you know if you are Emacs
user I'm going to explain and teach you
about Emacs regular expression but
visually this video supposed to start in
in seven more minutes so actually I will
be back you know so people can get on I
start early so start at 5:00 p.m.
San Francisco time okay that's in seven
minutes
okay so yeah let that let that be that
so I hope people come on to my
livestream and today's topic is Emacs
regular expression yep
okay now I'll see you in five minutes
okay now it's 458 so so welcome to
another episode of our talk show today
is August 4th July August 4th and 2019 5
o'clock p.m. and we are going to teach
Emacs regular expressions and possibly
some Emacs Lisp
so as usual type your comments your
thoughts you know say hi type where you
form that way the talk gets better you
know typically the more people talk we
get you know I get more topics to talk I
get more relaxed and it's and people get
you know when people see other people
type stuff then they start to type too
so you know things get busy which is
good for us so I'm going to teach about
Emacs regular expressions okay shall we
begin let's see two people watching so
let's make the windows over here so you
can see and let's move the windows over
here now now am i we Emacs my Emacs
window there are two windows here on the
left you can see every command cycle you
know forward walk back walk backward
word who's up previous line close it
down you know every command basically
every command delete things like that
you will see it so when you see
something I'm doing you are not sure
exactly what you can look up the command
name typically it's on my website so you
can get a code to use for yourself
okay so let's let's talk about Emacs
regular expressions
now Emax regular expressions as you know
regular expressions is a wave for you to
pattern match strings text you know text
like that for example let's say I want
to find you know this is my Emacs blog
this file HTML file showing browser so
you can see this is my Emacs blog lots
of pages and suppose I want to find all
mention of the word Haskell I can again
call the command let's see what the come
at least matching lines okay least
matching lines a scowl I type Haskell
press ENTER none found so there's no
word has cow let's type subscribe it's
UBS okay okay one occurrence let's try
to find archive okay to occurrence but
let's say I want to find any words
beginning with AR and ending with a e so
let's do that
AR dot plus E space okay now the dot
means any character so it's a wild-card
you know like in poker games or some
card games it's called wild card so the
dot matches any character and a plus
sign means a personal sign means one or
more occurrence of whatever pattern
before that so here a dot plus means one
or more characters so we have AR dot
plus e and space that will find any word
okay let's put a space in front so any
word beginning with AR and ends with E
let's see what we get okay so we got
several so we got article we got we got
article we got arguments actually these
matches or other things and then we got
a ray like object code equal so it
actually
to match your sentence you see this
sentence array like object Emax curly
quote they began with AR and ends with E
so so that is the pattern space AR dot
plus E space now you see we don't want
for example we don't want sentences we
just want what's so we can do what we
can do is let's let's try to do it again
so least matching lines then the pattern
will be let me give you the pattern okay
okay so now second okay AR square
bracket then a dash Z then after that of
first sight so what this means is that
we are going to find any pattern that
begin with a space a are then any
character any one of one any one of a
twosie you know the alphabet then plus
means one or more of it then end with e
then space so this should give us all
words that begin with AR and ends with E
so let's try it
indeed we got article so why is not
archived not part of it because archived
here begin with a capital letter so if
we want also capital letters we can see
we can we can do it like that we can
okay let's let okay so capital letters
we can do it this way let's see we're
gonna okay square bracket a and capital
a and lowercase a okay
oops on our second capital a and
lowercase a okay let's try it
so we still only get articles so why is
not archived part of it let's try it
again
so space capital a lowercase a o menos
we are we have a space after that it's
remove that space okay so we got that so
we got archive article argument you know
so that is illustration an example of
using regular expression you see so
regular expression is a way to capture
you know patterns you know patterns in
text or string now I guess most of you
already familiar with regular
expressions just in case you are not
okay so let's get on to the Emacs
regular expression so in programming
languages Perl Python Ruby Java
JavaScript almost basically : every
language has regular expression building
in Emacs of course you have that too but
notice that each programming language
their regular expression syntax is a
little bit different basically they are
all the same but as you know sometimes
it you know a little bit different now
for Emacs regular expression in Emacs
Emacs regular expression is particularly
different from the other languages so if
you program probe Python Ruby PHP Java
JavaScript their expression you could
say they are all the same okay they are
like 99% the same you know you can you
know you know one you know them all but
in Emacs it's like 90 percent is the
same but the rest 10% is a bit different
event so what is a major difference let
me talk about that just a little bit
just soso for you guys already know
regular expression in other languages
you can immediately see
what's Emacs re-expression difference so
folk a let me talk about that let me
just say so okay so actually let me type
the topics we are talking so that we
have a sense of what we've talked about
so example of regular rejects use we
already cover that example of regular
expression then we talked about we we
were using this matching lines so so the
command is this matching lines you know
MX least naturalized okay so okay so you
know we we've tried we demonstrate that
in Emacs least matching lines is a this
matching lines command is a great way in
Emacs to learn regular expression
because whenever you want to learn the
syntax of regular expression Emacs you
can always just use list not code this
matching eyes and give a pattern that's
a great way to learn regular expression
this command is a great way to test
learn rejects in Emacs okay so we cover
the example use of the regular
expression let's talk about difference
difference between Emacs rejects and
other land rejects rejects are all
similar in Perl Python Python Ruby PHP
Java JavaScript act okay but Emacs
rejects is slightly more different
okay
Emacs rejects is slightly more different
the difference between Emacs rejects and
other lengths it rejects
okay so let's cut and it's so what is
the difference between Emacs regular
expression and others basically so in
other in other regular expression you
have backslash T would that stand for
digits okay
and backslash W stand for word you know
basically any a to Z a to z and and
digits okay so in other regular
expressions you have that but in Emacs
regular expression you do not have that
you do not have the backslash T you do
not have back slash W actually in Emacs
regular expression you do have the
backslash W but however the meaning is
slightly different from the other
regular expression okay so so what so we
are trying to say the main the major
difference between Emacs rejects and
other land rejects ah so that and that
actually I have that written out
somewhere so let me let's see where is
that hey guys hey ex stock prints not a
touch typist
so Emacs default are fine with me what
do you mean you mean you mean the the
key binding
so so yeah we're talking about Emacs
regular expression so what's the major
difference between Emacs rejects and
other line rejects let me show you I
covered that somewhere here okay okay
here
so you see JavaScript purses Emacs
rejects now JavaScript regular
expression is pretty similar to Perl
Python Ruby PHP Java okay they are all
similar so so so JavaScript versus Emacs
rejects so yeah so here are the major
differences so you have so in other
languages when you want to capture you
use parenthesis but in Emacs regular
expression you have to backslash
parenthesis you know the parentheses
character is literal in Emacs then we
talked about you have digits you have
words you have white space backslash s
for white space in other languages but
in Emacs you don't have that so in Emacs
if you want to do that you have to use
these syntax like double square bracket
then colon digit : okay similarly
forward in space you have to type the
word space so anyway so this is for
those of you already know regular
expression so I'm trying to show the
major differences but I'm going to
explain more in detail using Emacs
rejects so if you don't know wiecek's
already that's okay we cannot talk about
it these are just the major differences
between Emacs and others okay so now
let's get back to talk about Emacs
regular expression how we use it and so
on so first of all least you know least
matching lines is a great command to try
it okay so you know if you have Emacs
you know if you are in front of a
computer try it just called list
matching lines you know for you can open
that any any file any buffer create a
new file then start to type something
you want
you try to match for example like email
then you call this matching lines you
know lists matching lines lists lists
matching lines you know you you call it
let's say dot add dot you know then you
it will pop up result in the you know in
another pin split pin okay so so that's
and another great command to test
regular expression is query replace
rejects
now this command actually have a key
binding let's see what is is now guys
type your comments and thoughts okay
let's get the chat lively so another
command great to call his query rejects
query replace rejects now what that
command does is that it allows you to do
find and replace in the current buffer
using regular expression so let's let's
demonstrate that so let's say I want to
replace the word Adam let's let's say I
want to replace the word article to
archive let's say for example so we can
do let's let me get the rejects ready
here so okay so what we can do so let's
say we face the word article to archive
in this buffer wait it's not a good
example
let's try email so because email is a
common commonly used pattern people want
to do so let's say Sally at gmail.com
let's say Joe at gmail.com it's a when
Rand at live.com okay some some some
random names so we have several email
addresses and we want to replace let's
say it replace the dot-com to let's say
this is dog okay so we so we have a
bunch of email addresses we want to
replace you know the the dot org or
dotnet into something else dotnet so
let's say Jane and Jane outpost darn it
okay you know several random email
addresses we want to let's say replace
all the surface to or calm let's say so
we can say where we replace with Jack's
okay okay so I just called a command
curry replace rejects and the type of
pattern let's say let's say dot first
dot means any character first means one
one or more then at Sai at sign @ at
sign outside then
then anything not dot okay this this
this pattern is getting complex you know
regular expression syntax is such that
it takes some time to understand them
hey good morning Beth Beth Lomu you know
regular expression takes sometimes to to
get familiar so if you are not quite
getting at don't worry because took me
several years you know I've been using
regular expression for for more than
twenty years now so but I do remember in
the beginning first few years it's
always like confusing like you like
sometimes you want to replace something
you tried many patterns many times and
take hours it doesn't work so it takes
time to get to know them well ok so
right now we are trying to you know
match the email addresses and so what
pattern to do to use that so one way we
can do is this you know so if you are if
you don't know what I'm doing that's
okay you you you know did eventually you
will I'm just going to do it for now
okay so let's say so the pattern we want
is that this will be literal dot then
dot dot dot okay let's say three words
yeah okay wait actually this will be
actually the sweet happy more
complicated than I thought okay so let's
say that dot plus so I think this
pattern will walk that you know let's
try that so actually I'm going to
explain in a bit okay so let's do
credibly place rejects let me call the
command query we face rejects type the
pattern okay that is the pattern we want
actually we we need more than that
actually so we need when you see these
you think you might think oh my god this
is so complicated I'll never learn
regular expression you know regular
expression is tremendously powerful you
know like if you working any job you
know like even if you go to chop chop
interview often they'll ask you you know
how well you know regular expressions so
you want to really know them well
because it's tremendously useful so let
me try to finish this pattern okay so
I'm going to need that plus sign okay so
this is a pattern that will match email
like this okay so let's try that copy
that and let's call query replace
rejects well first of all let's do list
matching lines remember that that's a
great command to test regular expression
so let's let's test it first
so let's call this matching lines give
the pattern let's see what it finds
okay okay it found a lot of tons of
things so that means our pattern is to
general this is not good
oh yeah so actually okay so let's try
that again
a to Z hey to Z okay let's try that
again
then then a to Z okay so
then A to Z okay okay so let's try that
again lease matching lines we give a
pattern there it is fantastic you know
don't you think this is fantastic you
know we have you see we want to get all
email addresses in this file
you know this file has you know this
file has you know 900 lines and now we
we just call one command and we got all
the email addresses you know this is
here you know so this is wonderful
so now if we want to replace part of it
we can now try the query query we place
rejects so let me show you so let's call
prairie jex we replace I have a keyboard
shortcut you know that caused the
command you can see the command on the
Left panel okay now I need to give a
pattern so pattern will be that and what
do you want to replace it with let's say
let's say we let's say we just want to
be placed like this is a email address
okay this is done so we just replace
with the text this is an email address
okay let's say okay okay so it found one
occurrence it's going to ask you what
you want to do about it you can be face
it you can you know skip it and go to
the next match you know and the Emacs
will say you know type question for help
you know there are several shortcut keys
you can oops
you know shortcut so let's do it again
so query we trace rejects
use this pattern and replaced by you
know replaced by that text say yes I can
say yes yes yes yes you know that that
we face them all
now let's try one more thing okay let's
do query replace rejects the beginning
pattern will be the same as we used
before let's see yeah this pattern so
let's use that pattern and let's say the
ending pattern will be backslash 1
backslash 1 means the first captured
item you'll see what it means let me
show you so okay so yes yes yes yes you
see so what it does is that it replace
the whole email address by just the
first name you know name you know the
beginning part of the email address so
so you see now how regular expression is
used and that also demonstrate the power
of regular expressions so regular
expression can be used to find email you
know find any text patterns you want for
example in programming language when you
code what you want to refactor you know
find function names replace with
something else or find variables names
or find some you know a universal ID oh
you know encrypted key they usually have
certain pattern you can find them all
and you can also to replace so that
demonstrate the power and one example
usage of regular expression and now now
let me explain the syntax of regular
expression now this is the part that you
really want to learn okay okay so but
let me write down what we have just done
demo the power and example of rejects
use okay for example finding email
addresses in a file okay we have shown
that example okay then this is the
pattern used okay this is rejects
pattern used
now you can see in browsers so we have
you know written out what we were doing
so so okay we have demonstrated the
example of usage of regular expression
now let's talk about the syntax of
rejects that is the heart of the thing
when you learn rejects it's about you
know the syntax so let's see let me read
the comments hey tech ways good morning
or good evening so bathroom you say yes
reject seems complicated at first but
you just need to learn it and understand
how it works yes exactly
be persistent then it becomes very
powerful yes exactly so Dec way says
rejects is we use it at work to tokenize
documents for further processing yeah
yes yeah it's interesting you know the
the history of the regular expression
you know that like the name regular
expression it's kind of seedy you know
it's like regular expression first of
all you know you don't think you know in
programming languages you when you when
you see the word expression you know you
don't think you know you like expression
has a value right in programming
languages but this regular expression it
doesn't look like expression you know
then it says regular you know what the
heck it's not regular I mean look at the
syntax you know it's not it's not in any
way rate you know it it doesn't come to
mind is regular the reason it's called
regular expression is historical it's
very complicated
it's rather you know very complicated
but in basically it came from the study
of theoretical computer science study on
passing you know also you know part of
it is known as automata like Oh Tom
automata and basically is study passing
okay
given a bunch of you know it study
formal and it's part of the formal
language originally in a regular
expression it they came up because
originally it's a part of the
theoretical this is this is important
theoretical computer science not related
to anything practical it's related to
theoretical computer science on the you
know in the branch of formal languages
what they want they are trying to do is
that they are trying to find find a way
a syntax kind of to match to be able to
pass or match any so-called regular
regular languages that is a language
with regular grammar okay so that is why
it's called regular expression you know
because it's trying to it's trying to
eat it's supposed to be able to match
any computer language whose grammar is
called regular grammar now regular
grammar the word itself is very
confusing because the regular grammar in
regular languages they are in no way
regular in the in a daily English sense
they are not regular okay so so anyway
it's convoluted history it's a regular
expression so actually let me show you
some articles about that if you are
interested so sorry automata and sorry
pause compiler okay so you know these
are interesting things you might look
into
how compiler works okay that's part of
it so I have this tutorial that is a
introduction really truly basic
introduction about how compiler works
now if you read this you will begin to
learn you know how compiler works you
know like this is not in depth you know
this just gives you an intro idea like
what exactly compilers do and then if
you read it you'll learn passing you
know you know passing what does it mean
for a programming language to pass the
language then you also learn about
grammar you know a grammar of a
programming language how is it defined
exactly what it is then you'll also
learn about Backus no form which is a
standard kind it's a syntax to specify
programming language grammar now once
you know that then your your start you
or learn about you know regular grammar
you know one of the class of grammars is
called regular you know so languages
with regular grammar is called regular
languages then you also learn you know
you hear often can't context-free
languages that is also very confusing
jargon because it is not in the normal
English word context-free when you have
a context-free language actually doesn't
mean it's context-free it means it has
specific meaning so so anyway you are
learning about regular languages then
you are learn about you know
context-free grammar then you'll learn
about regular expression this is when
regular expression comes come up because
it it it tries to match all regular
languages so any way that you can read
that but there's another interesting
thing about regular expression that is
when you read about regular expression
you will often came to the term automata
again this is very confusing and not
and it has very interesting history and
linguistics as well you know so why do
they call it
automata you know finite state automata
and so on automata you know this is very
interesting I digressed we're gonna get
back to Emacs okay practical to talking
a bit but automata basically means a
machine okay it's asian it's like two
thousand years ago this this guy this
guy from Greek mythology
Talos his name is Talos he is a automata
now automata what does it mean it just
means a robot so back in the Greek
mythology days so you have this guy
Talos he's a automata he's a giant
you know mecha you know you if you watch
Japanese anime you know it's a kind of
like mecha back in two thousand years
ago so automata means just just means
like a machine that operate by itself it
doesn't need you know human input it
doesn't need someone to tell him it's
not like be more controls or anything it
it does you know it has it controls
itself that's automata then they in
computer science they started to call
something you know they call it automata
which is kind of bad naming because in
no way it so it's it's self operating so
anyway it's complicated you know
linguistic and very interesting history
about how this word came to be so let's
go back to regular expression so we
talked about so there's a common
question about you know like for
beginners when they learn regular
expression they have a common question
so what's the difference between
wildcards you know like in file names
for example in UNIX you can you have
this wildcard
you know Asterix I which stand for any
sequence of characters then the question
mark
stand for any character one single
character you know stand for any
character then you know so in UNIX for
example it's you can do that let's say
open in terminal okay let me open my
current directory in terminal so I'm
here so let's do LS okay OS this is a
UNIX let me move this up so you can see
so you see so I'm listening directories
LS so let's say LS Asterix a L that will
list any file name ending in a L okay
let's try it you see you see that's
that's that's the that's this wildcard
by the way this wild card is called
Claude this wire cards system of
matching text patterns is called Club it
came from the UNIX jargon it's called
Club you know so so this is club and
it's also in you know in Windows you
know you can also do that in Windows so
when people learn with regular
expression they think I already know God
you know what do I need you know regular
expression seems small complicated the
thing is so Club you know so you have
these patterns it's not very flexible so
when you for example you cannot use club
- for example - to catch or email pad
patterns you know because yeah because
if you use Club you'll get bunch of text
not that's not email you know it's not
powerful enough that is why you need use
you need to learn and use regular
expressions they serve kind of the same
purpose but the glob is very simple you
know it's just for you know very simple
regular expression is the you know far
more powerful one so I give some
examples where you can use regular
expression to match
thing but gloves you know just cannot do
and okay so let's talk about some you
know some common patterns for regular
expressions so these are the most
frequently used patterns and that
basically that's about you know okay
it's something else and I'll talk about
about using regular expression in emacs
let me read the comments first so dick
ways says today I wrote some Java
bytecode
reminds reminded me of learning assembly
compiler act in unit university so
battle of Musa is minor note I think the
singular is automaton while the prune
row is automata you are right yeah so
yeah yeah correction you are right
singer is automaton that's you know that
word is just so interesting to me you
know and ex stock prints says there is
no god but Emacs installment is his
favorite okay okay so let's talk about
Emacs reject syntax so I give some
patterns these are the most commonly
used so you know so if you want to learn
be checks you can start with these
patterns now it's hard to read them out
you know it's hard to read the regular
expression syntax so for those of you
not watching a video you just have to
actually go to my website and you know
look look at these patterns so yeah so
these are the common you know most
frequently used patterns so when you
want to you know again as I mentioned
you can just try list matching lines and
try the patterns and you can see you
will understand what they match they you
know they for example they do one or
more digits one or more than digit
characters one or more letters
well more letters digits or - or one or
more letter digit underscore or you know
one or more either digit - underscore
that's all common then you can also
match or CAC ASCII characters then you
can also match on an ASCII characters
for example you want to you have a emoji
let's try that so for example let's
match
so in this my Emacs block you know this
is 1000 lines I want to get I want to
get all characters that's not asking for
example I have some emoji characters or
arrow you know math summation or arrow
symbols I want to get all of them see
what they are so I call so I call this
matching lines and I call I give this
double bracket then then colon colon
then I say none ascii ok let's see if I
got the syntax correct yeah okay so I do
that and with a so that so double square
bracket then two colons then inside that
you say non ASCII okay this pattern will
match any one non ASCII character so so
then I put a plus sign oops
okay let's do it again okay let's do it
again
none ascii then I type a purse I means
one or mo of it okay let's say enter
okay so you can see the results let's
magnify you see I have quite a few I
have quite a few Unicode here so we have
the list ellipsis we have the curly
quote we have the bear symbol for
YouTube subscribe and bear
you know alert we have rooms you know
the room Asian rune alphabet and we have
the you know Unicode Z symbol which
stands for what is Z for natural numbers
integers I think and we have the
summation sign we have the copyright
sign you know so so this is how useful
is the unicode is how useful is the
regular expression you can match you
know these kind of things and you cannot
do with you know the wild card the gob
so ok these are the common patterns in
regular expression ok one more thing I
want to mention is how do you match a B
turn you know return character or tab
character in Emacs to do that you have
an image to do that Emacs you cannot you
cannot use the backslash in okay like if
you came from other programming
languages you know you call this
matching noise and then you say
backslash and that doesn't work so
instead to enter a literal newline
character you know to match a newline
you have to type ctrl Q then return so
ctrl Q enter you know that's what do you
how you type so let me show you an
example so let's say I want to okay so
let's say I want to match let's say
least matching lines okay I call this
matching lines you can see on the Left
list matching lines then I say I say
that less equal to less than okay
then I type less less than sign / code
greater than sign so that matches the
code tag the ending code tag then I type
ctrl Q control
you enter wait oh I have wait and I got
this wrong actually let's let's do it
again
this matching line is code then ctrl Q
ctrl J okay okay my tutorial is actually
incorrect oh my god for years this
I got this incorrect information
so actually you need to type ctrl Q ctrl
J okay okay ctrl Q ctrl J that will
actually insert a new line character
then I type that okay that will match
any occurrences of you know let's do it
enter you know match any occurrences of
these you know there's only one
occurrence you see so anyway the point
is when you want a new line character
you have to type ctrl Q ctrl J now why
do you you know why is that well it's
because it's a bit complicated it's
because Emacs key syntax history of
Emacs kissing X I have a article
explaining that but anyway let me go
fixed fix my article ctrl Q ctrl J okay
so
so that's what you need to do
so for several years I got this wrong
because you know I kept updating my
articles like every two years like
hundreds of articles and you know I try
to rephrase it
try to improve it it's rather very
tedious work so anyway that's corrected
that so anyway so so i actually that's
about it for a max regular expression
okay yeah so I've been talking for like
for fifteen minutes that's that's good
yeah so I think I don't think we could
not talk about so that's about the main
thing there are other things like case
how do you control case sensitivity you
know there are other things but you know
I think you it's nice to stop here
because you know we don't want to get
too much in too long if you like you
know you can read my Emacs tutorial
which gives you information in detail
let me type it here and let's read the
comments and let's just chat randomly
for five minutes or something you know
any questions comments opinions type it
okay so let's see - so there is no god
but eMac saying Stoneman okay
so oh there's no more comments so so far
so good so anything else
so guys guys comments okay so oops I
don't want to pause
so let me go around so pastor Ramu is
from Germany now Germany is right now oh
it's like 3 o clock in the morning
Wow and the thick ways we from Dec ways
I forgot and we from Dark Prince rupee
operators yeah so can you so dick way
says can you take a look at Ruby
operators well hold on a second
I'm not very familiar with Ruby and I
haven't done Ruby for you know I only
spent two months studying it and that
was like four years ago base in four or
five years ago well beginning in 2012 so
operators in Ruby Oh Dec ways is also
from Germany oh you you two are friends
is all right Pat Salome you and the tech
ways
I am using a odd blah ad blocker you see
my main you see right now you are seeing
Google Chrome which I actually don't use
much but basically when you use Google
services you have to use Google Chrome
kind of because Google has become so
evil that they you know if you use other
browsers often there fails and stuff you
know since I'm doing YouTube you know
which is Google's account so I you know
so that's why I'm using Google Chrome
but normally my main browser is the
brave browser and also Firefox browser
also Safari actually I used them all you
know for different purposes brave is a
browser that's based on Google Chrome
chromium and it has it has the adblock
in building you know it's a new kind of
system so and in Firefox
I have JavaScript of that so you know
when you basically when you have
JavaScript off that that makes
everything much safer even safer than ad
blockers because when JavaScript is off
websites can hardly do anything you know
all the viruses and more where they they
don't walk you know but when JavaScript
off most websites will be not readable
you know they they come up empty or you
know things are getting bad like that so
what about so about Ruby operators so
what do you want to talk about that like
I don't know like I don't even know what
are the Ruby operators like so I if I
recall correctly a few days ago you were
saying they are confusing right
yes I think you were saying they are
confusing or something like that but I
don't really know Ruby right right
takeaways anything else answer answer
like so what what what's about Ruby
so that way says they have single symbol
operators for many things like private
oh that
okay that I that is not I don't think
there are operators they are B they are
the let's see Ruby variables let's see
where is this true versus hash table
function rap yeah so Ruby let's go to
Ruby basics printing strange coding
strange stream manipulation numbers and
string conversion everything is a object
variables yeah so Ruby variables you
have this condition you have this
syntactical markup basically I have a
article about that let's see where is it
oh yeah so Lisa wait
so you have a bunch of predefined
variables now ruby has a bunch of
predefined global variables they all
start with a dollar sign but the thing
we are out here so variable name prefix
and variable scope so ruby has follows
this compiler enforced syntactical rule
about variable names so if it starts
with the dollar sign is its scope is
global it's a global variable if it
starts with a @ sign then it's a
instance variable of a class if we start
with a double at sign they enter class
variable so you know that's part of the
syntax it's it's not a operator I don't
think so
so they have single symbol operators for
many things like private public yes and
I think actually you know in my personal
opinion about you know programming
language design so these are actually
called cgo you know Perl began with the
name they are called see Joe okay and I
have you know I have strong opinions
about that actually I think that's a
great thing
let's see sorry see Joe War I actually
have a quite a few articles about that
you know because I think it's a good
thing because you know they me you know
I don't you know I don't know if you are
interested in that but probably because
this is an interesting topic about
programming language design okay let me
talk about that
I want to be on my own keep and have a
keyboard okay we got a lot of topics no
they I think they are great maybe I can
let me explain my my view okay so maybe
maybe your you know maybe your think
about maybe maybe you know possibly
you'll change your mind you know like
how how we have functional for me you
know we have strongly typed languages
for example Java C C++ : Haskell
especially Haskell or camel they are
strongly type of typed and in functional
programming like Haskell F sharp or
camel they have type inference you know
which is like a fancy mechanism to infer
types so basically if you are in a scow
community you know you know they have a
strong concept about like type you know
type solves everything you know like
they you know like type you know they
type
prevents many errors and and can be
useful as part of your program to
actually specify things and in may in
many ways prevent arrow so anyway so
they you know that's that's the point
about strongly typed languages the idea
is that that types you know prevents
many errors you know everything is like
strict you know they like almost like
they follow a logic types now now
note that these strongly typed languages
type the concept they are semantic
concept you know they are not syntax
they are semantics like for example you
declare a variable type int so this
variable is type int integer you know
like like the compiler will understand
that it has a meaning you know
semantics you know the type concept is
semantics now what what if you can turn
that concept into sync syntax so
whenever for example you know let's go
back to Ruby you know maybe you don't
like Ruby but but in Ruby for example
whenever you see a variable name start
with the dollar sign
you know immediately that this that this
is a global variable it has global scope
so so what I'm saying is that the
semantics the meaning you know of the
type you know which is you know the
typed languages you know semantics now
it becomes syntactic Oh
which is great because you look at
things you already know what it means
you know so when you have a duck you
know when you have a s sign you know
already it's a instance variable when
you have double add sign you know it's a
class variable so by looking at things
even without compiling you know like to
humans you already know what it means
but compiler also know what it means
like compiler when a compiler sees a
dollar sign in front of variable it
knows like but because of the definition
of the language it already knows this
this is a global variable so so you see
what I mean so this so it so we with
this serial thing it kind of turns the
semantic concept of types into a
syntactic concept that and that is
critical because because in formal
language when you study formal languages
which is the basically the foundation of
theoretical computer science which is
where regular expression came from
automata you know or the regular
languages you know context-free grammar
they they are all formal languages now
what is the formal language formal
language is basically just a bunch of
characters like no meaning no no
semantic meaning a formal language you
know study of formal language is purely
just you know sequence of characters how
can they be changed you know how can
they be transformed that's that's
that's why you define your language
using you know the formal language
grammar you know that that's all from
that's what formal language is about you
know just a bunch of character sequences
or you chorus string you know a sequence
of characters so what I'm saying here is
that so
so now you turn the type concept into a
you know for example like groovy
it becomes a syntactic or concept so you
can actually treat it as a formal
language you know it so that's my idea
that's what I'm saying
so in other words for example let's say
we create we invent a new language now
every you know suppose you know every
function name start with F let's say
let's just say let's not say if let's
say lambda okay now if you create a
language where every identifier if the
identifier start with the Lamba lambda
it means a function o in other words
every time you define a function the
compiler forces you enforce that the
name must start with the lambda that's a
similar idea with the cito you know this
this idea is called cgo okay see Jo okay
so if you have that that wouldn't that
be great you know because now especially
in JavaScript you know especially many
of these flexible syntax languages like
Ruby JavaScript where a function can be
a value it can be assigned to a variable
you know you get confused because a
variable can be a function can be you
know can be lots of things then but now
if every function names start with the
lambda that kind of clarifies you know
so so that's that is why I think this
cgo idea turning semantic concept of
type into a syntactic concept or formal
languages is a great thing now actually
we have also other conventions we are
already doing that for example Ruby is a
one example another example is
let me show you naming a predicate okay
computer language predicate function
terminology and naming convention now in
Emacs Lisp
if a function ends with a P that means
the function returns either true or
false
that's a Emacs Lisp comment convention
now in closure Lisp and scheme Lisp
when when a function ends with a
question mark that means the function
always returns true or false you know
this is another idea of cg.o you know
well where where you specify the meaning
in the syntax itself and I'm giving some
examples so Emacs Lisp ending with P
scheme and closure ends with a question
sign same thing with Ruby Ruby also ends
with if you if a function ends with a
question sign it means it returns true
or false okay
in Wolfram language Mathematica it ends
with a capital Q Q stand for question
you know so here you know these are some
conventions and will be too you know
here are lists of names in Ruby
functions you know 0 question mark hard
question mark
even question mark integer question mark
you know then 0 question mark you know
you have lots of these function names so
this is another idea of the C joke where
you turn the the concept of type from
semantics to syntax so I think you know
so in my opinion I think this is great
now let me also mention that in Perl
you also have CTO but policy choice is
entirely different from this idea
because procedure depends on value so
it's it's kind of different
okay but let's not you know get into
that so this is the idea of the CEO so I
have some articles
discussing the pros and cons of CJ in
detail you know a CEO of a function
perhaps parameter names you know I won't
function functional parameters I want to
be able to we you know in a programming
language you have variables you know you
have global variables you have function
parameters and you have local variables
I want to be able to district
distinguish them syntactically you know
by by looking at it I know this can't
this variables local variable or it's a
function parameter or it's a global
variable now I know of no languages that
that that has this you know where it
distinguish functions parameter variable
by syntactically by a CEO I don't know
any of that but I did create my own
convention you know I experimented for a
while I think it's good so anyway so
that's some of the ideas about CTO so
that's that's why I I think it's a good
thing you know that that's about that
so Dec way says every time I look at
Ruby code I wrote a couple of weeks ago
I need to look up what all the symbols
mean yeah that's a valid reason you know
but but that also applies to almost
every aspect of programming language for
example input in C for example for
example in this in this everything is
parenthesis you know you don't have to
remember about the syntax but in C you
know unless you already program in C for
years but if you have new programmer you
look at the syntax index like each one
is different and and no regularity like
you have to remember oh this is loop
loop needs you know to be this this way
you know so anyone can make the same
complaint about you know C syntax which
is actually about the whole language you
know so that's okay so let's see yeah so
you are saying you know you have to
learn what the see Jose means but you
know I don't think that's you know I
don't think that's valid I mean it's
it's valid criticism but but for example
in in math you use you have plus sign
you know multiply divide you have to
learn that to again equal you know the
reason they are not confusing it's only
because you know you've been using them
for years that that is actually the
reason you don't you don't have to
remember what the plus sign means you
know and then there's the you know power
side and you know in square root and so
on so that so there's a you know
something to be said about familiarity
you know because these math symbols you
are so used to them since you are age
you know 5-2 king of kindergarten you
know that that is that is why nobody
complains but doesn't mean that this
these are actually intuitive you know
so familiarity is a great thing you know
it's a big thing in everything we do
so you see because every language is
based on see why because the moment they
create some new syntax people don't like
it because you know most people already
familiar with C that is why C syntax
grows and grows you know C C++ Java goal
and JavaScript
you know like almost every language is C
syntax and almost nobody complains only
because we are so used to it but if you
actually look from the beginner you know
point of view 16 taxes worst because
every thing is you know special every
every syntax is special there's no you
know it's not systematic in other words
it's not systematic so when it comes to
you know Ruby's CEO or you know like for
example let me show you another example
go Crozier okay you know typically in
lists we have the convention where let's
go to closure okay let's go to my
closure tutorial
you know kosher has a lot of these magic
characters very knowing okay you can
complain about Ruby wait until you code
closure you closure you know is one of
the least branch of Lisp family but but
one thing unique about closure is that
closure they created this whole bunch
you know like tens of them of this
special cryptic short operator kind of
thing like to be part of the function
name like in traditionalists emag lee's
scheme this racket you know common list
there is a convention where you avoid
you know any of the abbreviations like
typically you function name is like full
function name I traditionally you know
typically you rarely see abbreviations
but closure is like 100 degree 180
degrees turn around of that concept
closure they love you know the hijiki
they created this bunch of like things
you know with these special characters
in function name to indicate you know
different meaning you know particularly
semantics to that function name function
you know then then you have then their
function tends to be abbreviated like
four letters three characters four
characters so wait until you you do call
culture that's you know more confusing
so okay so I think that's about it for
today I because I you know it's been
like yeah so yeah an hour and 20 minutes
right so that's it for today anything
else so so thank so bad some of me so I
think there is a question I remember
what I wanted to tell you I want to be
on my own keypad half of a keyboard
basically yo s I was partly responsible
for inspiration great thank you
regarding these thank you yeah so we
let's talk about keyboard some other
time and today it's to already kind of
too long so how is your web server set
up to your website I think I talked
about that for five minutes yesterday or
the day before maybe we can talk about
that it's not much I'm old school died
just use a I just use a sink I can show
you actually so closely its for example
let's close Ruby for example my Emacs
block I can now I can sync to my web
server by going to Esha then just call a
sink okay
then that that syncs up to my server now
if you go to my web server sorry
Emacs blog you will see today's update
you know this is temporary I'm going to
remove them and stuff later so so know
you don't know what it means
so I read so you have to learn and
connect them in your head yes
okay yeah hope see you guys hope to see
you guys soon
if you like my stuff you know you can go
to my you can support me by a you know
patreon patreon Amazon gift card PayPal
and stuff by the way if you use Amazon
gift card use this link okay because
sometimes I got people there are a
couple people from from Utah do you know
from French you know they use Amazon
Italy but I cannot cash that yeah so if
you want to serve or me or buy my MX
tutorial so thank you guys for watching
see you soon