Hello guys, good morning. Welcome to
another episode of talk show. We are
going to code wam language. Let's start
wine language. We are going to draw
pattern
matching. Pattern matching like I mean
not pattern matching the titings and
patterns. Okay.
So we are going to create a drawing like
that in wuam language and uh if you
don't know introduction I did like over
100 videos on wam language just search
for it
kasari.info wuam language tutorial and
you can learn in depth about anything in
wuam language from the ground up if you
already know a programming language.
Okay. So, and you can download it free.
It's free about 3 years
ago. If you are watching offline, play
at 1.5 speed because I ramble. If you
are watching live, say hi here. Okay.
So, Wuham language uh I've got video
tutorials, best videos collected here.
uh and uh about graphics about you know
like how do you do graphics from as a
beginner there is a tutorial a video
tutorial also a text tutorial uh there
okay wam language in depth okay so let's
do today's uh thing we're going to draw
this so that is from a package I wrote
uh wam language search for it you'll
find it on
kadiinfo plane tiling package. Okay. So
this package allows you to generate any
tilings in the plane in an easy way. Uh
you know so for example you can draw
these Islamic patterns. Beautiful. Uh
and so I wrote this in
1997 and this guy
uh this guy uh okay so let's let's go to
the um uh download folder. Okay. So,
this guy
who contacted me like 20 years ago and
he actually uh he actually drew this
one. So, the package allows you to as
long as you have a motif like motif is
like that like part of the tile. So once
you have that part you can just repeat
it by mirror reflection by translation
then you generate you can generate for
example this this little part in fact
half of that is called fundamental
region. So fundamental region is a
minimal region that once you have that
you can just repeat by symmetry and have
the full uh full pattern tiding or knots
or whatever to feel the plane. So, so
but the most important thing is I mean
there are many ways to create this okay
there are many many there are several
multiple techniques to create this
geometric pattern but one of the way is
just create the minimal um fundamental
region then you just then you can just
call a command it'll just feel the plane
for you but the symmetry okay so that is
this package so like 30 years ago this
guy uh sent me uh he used my package to
to generate this beautiful uh
pattern. Okay. So, and then he sent me
about two months ago more. Okay. So,
like he he he he emailed me, hey, I'm
still using your package. Fantastic. So,
so the package he you know the pattern
he sent, let me show you. So, this is
one of the the source code. Uh so this
one is about you know this is like the
worksheet. The final
uh picture
is go down go down go down. This is the
final picture. Beautiful intricate you
see they
become linkages you know like one go
over the top of the other but so this is
kind of the fundamental
region. Yeah. So this is the final
pattern. So I'm going just to run the
code today uh to see I can duplicate it.
Of course I can should you know I should
be able to otherwise something is wrong.
Yeah. Hope hopefully it's fun. And the
he also sent another pattern. Another
one he sent is this one. This is like
um related to Celtic Celtic knots. the
decoration in used in uh Scandinavia
culture. So these are drafts and the
final image is this one.
Beautiful. Okay. So let me show you
where to get so you can get the package
package here. It's on GitHub.
Uh let's see what else I want to show.
So you got my tutorial and I'm coding
Wuam language in Emacs. You can get the
package. If you know what is Emacs then
the titing. Okay. So let's start to do
it. Let's do it slowly and easily. Okay.
If you have questions, ask me. Okay. So
remove that. Remove that. So we want to
Yeah. So let's go to uh where is my
package? Let's see if it's loaded. So I
mean just like Emacs, if you want to
load a package, you need to place it in
a special directory. So shift enter.
Let's see if it's loaded. It's loaded
there. Fantastic. So let's run. So this
one. So this one is is saying um wait I
don't know what is cap from where that
came from. So let's just run it.
Fantastic. Okay, then let's run this
one. So, he's going to
generate a bunch of lines. You see, in
order to create this beautiful uh
tiling, one of the things you you have
to know is the important
coordinates. You see, for this like
fundamental region, you need to find the
coordinate. Of course, for the star like
this one is a hexog.
uh it's called star of David David or
it's also called hex hexog I think
um you know hex hexog is more of the
mathematical name so so the to find the
point of that coordinate of that star is
easy but then you have to find the other
parts so that is
not it's not difficult but it's tedious
So that's why you see these radicals you
know these are all coordinates. Okay
let's go to the top. So he begin by you
know we begin by generating this. So you
know so you have to design what height
to put those then okay then let's try
this one. Run it. So this wallpaper plot
is for my package. Then the first
argument is a uh let's magnify. Okay. So
one so the wallpaper plot is for my
package. The first argument is a
symmetry that specifies how you the
symmetry of
the of the wallpaper. Okay. So what does
that mean? Well that means okay so you
can go to let me show you
quickly. If you go to s math blog on
sardi.info info. Then there is
um there's a section uh that teach you
about symmetry wallpaper groups. So you
know so it's kind of technical but high
school level. So if you are into
mathematics you might read this. So
you'll learn some group theory and
tiding
um kind of symmetry theory. Okay. So,
so, so the um so the interesting part is
the appendix. So, there you see the
different kind of uh let's
see you see the you can kind you you can
see the 17 possible symmetries of a
wallpaper. So you can see this one is
just simply translation you know just
move it copy move it copy and this one
is translation but you also have
rotation you see there and uh the image
on the right shows their symmetry and
generator so you can in a glance know
what type of symmetry this wallpaper is.
So what they show the symmetry and
generators. Okay. So this this image
shows the symmetry and this image shows
the generator. Generator is a concept in
group theory. Okay. So generator means
this this symmetry is generated by you
see one black line there. That's a
translation. That means you just copy
paste and move it there. Copy and move
it there. Copy. Okay. So you got another
black line that that's again
translation. So you got two translation
and you got a diamond in the middle that
means twofold rotation meaning rotating
180 degrees. So that is like for example
this point. So let's can we okay anyway
so this this this diagram shows the
generator. Okay, generator means the
fundamentals
um symmetry elements that generates the
entire symmetry of this. Then this one
is a bit different. You got translation
but you got also a mirror reflection.
Okay. So um can you see it? Is it
interesting? Hello
Hank. Can you make a nonperiodic
tiding? Yes, I can. But that is uh that
is not so easy. That is my package. You
know my package only do periodic ones.
So if you want to do
nonperiotic tiding
that's incredibly beautiful and
fantastic but it's more complicated.
Well it's well not tech you know it's
comp it's you know you have to do it in
a different way. You have to do it
either via fractals or many other
special methods.
But my package only does only do the um
symmetric. Actually, I do have some
examples of of of
um No, no, actually I don't. So anyway,
let me let me talk about that. Um non
periodic tiding. Okay, that's very
interesting. So let me show some Yeah,
let me Okay, so let me talk about that.
Uh so let's go to
um yeah so let me show you let me let me
talk about that. So let's go to the math
blog. So,
info go to math
blog increase the size then go to the
whole math section then so we want to
show about wallpaper groups we already
did we
were talking about this in the
middle okay and uh I want to talk I want
to finish this okay so there's more to
uh say so but let me
um document it here so we know
what we are talking about. So there is
that I want to talk about. So this is a
continuous groups of rotation and
translation in a plane. So that is a
math technical math oriented uh paper.
Okay. Then I want to talk about um
wallpaper gallery. So this this give you
a uh bird's eye view of kind of
beautiful tidings using the varieties of
symmetry. Okay. So that's one uh for
example go to next and see can you use
arrow? No. So you see so the diagram
shows their symmetry. You can see the
red double line that means there's a
mirror reflection. Okay. And the star is
the actual wallpaper. Okay. So that one
and that one. This one is interesting
because there is a
uh called uh flip mirror. What's the
technical name? I forgot. So you mirror
and but you have to uh you know you
mirror and you have to move a bit. So
look like footprints.
Okay. So let's go to next one. Then you
got you know this kind of more symmetry.
Okay. So you next let's just go through
them. Okay. Next, next.
Next, next. So, you can see this one is
kind of like
swastika symmetry. Okay. So, you you
know at some point you have a four-fold
rotation. That means rotate 90 degrees,
you know, like at each one of these
point somewhere here. Uh uh let's see
where
um
like like like here. Okay. Like right
here you rotate 90 degrees the whole
thing becomes itself. Then you rotate 90
degrees the whole thing become itself
again. So you got kind of the four-fold
symmetry, a four-fold rotational
symmetry or you can just say swast
swastika symmetry then but at other
points you have a two-fold rotational
symmetry that means you rotate 180
degrees. So where would that be? You
know it's kind of hard to see from this
like star but anyway so that's another
symmetry.
So another one all together there are
like um 17 of them total. Okay. So so so
far all the ones we showed before they
are all based on
uh rectangular grid. Okay. But you'll
see triangular grid. So let's see next.
Next
next. So we started to see triangular
grid here. You see triangular grid is
more beautiful. So
next
next this one is beautiful. This this
one got the most symmetry. Okay. And
that's it. So all together you have like
uh total of 17 of them. Okay. So that
shows the symmetry. Um and then let me
let me talk about Okay. So we talked
about that. We talked about that. Then
uh let's
see. Yeah.
Uh let me copy that. So back
here
copy showing
browser. So that's the things we talked
about. Okay. So we then we going to talk
uh about what about tiding. So let let
me so let's go to tidings. Okay. Uh
math. So go back to math.
So
kasi.info math blog. Go to the math
section. So we want to uh show some
titins and uh
um non periodic ones. Very
interesting. Okay. So, so some more
tiding beautiful thing.
Um, we want to go to Yeah. And Asia very
beautiful tiding gallery.
Um, okay. Let's just uh let's just
explain what is the nonperiodic.
So for periodic ones, so these are more
examples of periodic titings. All these
are generated by my package like 30
years ago
1997. Okay. So you can see you can click
of them and say random random random
random and the last one. So anyway, so
you see that that that these are p or
periodic. Periodic means you can just
repeat or reflect or rotate you know
they they have
symmetry. So that that so these are like
kaleidoscope. Uh so you got that that
that and this one is
common like
uh
um
pedestrian path
uh tiles used to be common. I don't I
don't I don't think I see this anymore
like I I remember you know I think this
pattern used to be common like like 30
years ago. So anyway that so this this
one is more like fractal tiding. It's
also periodic but fractal. Okay. And you
got the linkage um and like you got
linkage linkage linkage linkage.
Um so anyway that's some examples. Okay.
Tidings and patterns. Okay. So I wanted
to show
um Yeah. So this one is
beautiful then. Okay. So that then let's
go to the um Okay. Yeah. So let me
recommend a book.
[Music]
Um yeah. Okay. Let's talk about some of
these things. So reading notes. So there
is this is the best book most authority
book on tidings and patterns. This is
mathematics pure math. So if you really
want to get into math this is a must-h
have reference like almost the the
reference. Okay. The this book is out of
print but there's a new edition uh I
mean new reprint by do uh they made the
cover very ugly like they become this
ugly cover but anyway so you can buy the
book okay this is the reference for
titans and patterns okay uh it's a math
book okay it's not just like I mean if
you are artist you you know you can get
inspiration from it from it But it's
actually talking about mathematics the
theories what you know what kind of
tiles are possible things like that uh
and I wrote to this guy they he passed
away okay he passed away about uh seven
years ago uh but I wrote to him like in
the 1990s and he sent me his
publications like a stack of them so I
really appreciate like when so when you
when when so you guys when you are
younger you can you um you know write to
mathematicians and usually they will be
happy to help
you. Okay, comments. Okay, if you guys
comment. So, so that's a great book you
should um get.
Uh, okay. So, and it's actually this
would be one of my like let's say top
three favorite math book. This one.
Okay. I still have it somewhere. Do I
where where is it? I put away somewhere.
Wait. Where is it? Must be
somewhere. Uh, okay. So, that book.
Okay. So, let's see. Let's stop this.
Then I started to write some notes here.
Uh and but also today there's tremendous
amount of information on Wikipedia. So
if you just want to see
um tremendous okay
titings but tessellation okay so you
know so you can see tessillations
uh lots of theories and pretty pictures.
Um and uh you know math theories about
tidings. Uh and this is nonperiodic.
Okay. So Penrose tiding the most famous
nonperiodic tiding. Okay. Uh this one
they it's not beautiful. Okay. And this
is Penrose Roger Penrose uh British
mathematician who kind of created the
Penrose titing and uh this is the
precursor of Penrose titing. So they
they are actually very deep. Okay, they
relates to logic and proof theory.
Uh you know they are fairly very
deep. Okay. So uh for example in this
book in this book we were talking about
uh where did that book in this
book at the end there are like one or
two chapters about the periodic tidings.
Okay so here is the uh table of contents
one tiles that's before Penro's tiding.
So a peri a periodic tiding. Okay. So
that that
chapter actually I I haven't read
chapter chap chapter 10 and
11 I and maybe 12 I haven't read I read
the uh rest of the
book. Okay.
So so the one tiles it you know they
relates through logic like very uh
deep. Okay. So where are we? So let's
see.
Um
yeah. Yeah. Okay. So then where's the
Wikipedia? Okay. So
Wikipedia. Yeah. So you know this uh one
tiles that's where is
it? Um any but anyway so I'm saying that
Wikipedia is very rich information. you
can read for like a year just about this
topic. So before I was talking about
wallpaper groups. So now you can see
Wikipedia they have like a full article
like 20 20 years ago when Wikipedia
began they just copied my website you
know and at at the at the end there's a
reference to my website. I think it's
gun. Uh let's see. Search such folks uh
yeah they removed it but 15 years ago
it's it was there you know in the
beginning they don't have much
information. So but
anyway so the so so Wikipedia okay if
you want to learn these things you can
also use
Wikipedia okay tessellations and uh so
periodic tilings
uh yeah and you you can also go to
three-dimensional or in different
geometry like nonukidian geometry that's
what this one is about um let's shrink
you know This is non non uklidian uh
geometry
tiling.
[Music]
Uh then uh hyperbolic plane. Okay,
that's in hyperbolic plane. Then some
other things I want to uh talk about.
Yeah, I want I want to go back to work
on the code. Okay, so we're going to
write this code, but just a few more
things. So, so here is one in JavaScript
that generates this random kind of
thing. So you can click on that, click
on that 20 tiles, 10 tiles, random,
random, random. It's beautiful. Okay. So
this this tile is called trotchet tile.
Okay, let's add
that. Okay,
then. Okay. So this is my package that
does the tiding and then so and so there
are many different ways to generate
them. One way is by repeating the
fundamental region like that.
Okay. The other way is you
simply you simply draw a motif like
that. Then you just map that to all the
grid points. So this is another way to
generate the tidying. So by that
technique you can generate this one for
example this one is like Islamic
pattern. Okay. So in fact this way is
much easier because you don't have to
like you don't have to compute the exact
coordinate you know like like we like
like given like given a ting like that
you have to find out which which is like
the minimal part then you have to find
the coordinate it's not so easy but but
with this you know mapping a motif to
all the uh grid points
or lattice points. It's very easy. So
you can generate this one beautiful
one and the y square there is a
fundamental region. Okay. So anyway, so
then you can generate that uh
that that that okay then you can
generate like illustrations for the
symmetry of a tile. Okay. So then you
can like cut it. Then you get this kind
of
uh um you get this kind of church uh
tinted glass
decoration. Okay. So and then this one
is a example of fractal typing. So
this to generate this one is uh another
technique. What you do is you do line
transformation. So you see typically a
tiling is made of you know tiles. So you
have edges right you know those
edges but in this one in this uh
transformation line line transformation
basically you just for every edge of a
tile you you begin with a s simple tile
then you just apply transformation to
the line so each line becomes some other
shape so you get that then you can
repeat then you got this you know you
got this fractal titing
Beautiful. Then you can cut off the
fringes. Then you you get
that. Now this one is interesting too.
This one is also done by line
transformation. Okay. So anyway, so
that's a introduction to my uh wam
language plain tiling package. So you
can get it on GitHub you know download
Wam language and get it. So one more
thing let's cover uh one more thing
about uh yeah so algorithmic
mathematical art.
Um so let's this this is uh this is
written about 20 years ago and it's one
of my I would
say one of the essay I'm most proud of
algorithmic algorithmic mathematical art
so
I it's a exposition I explain what are
the techniques to generate all sort of
mathematical art and I also give a
definition of exactly how what is a
mathematical art. I mean different
person can have different
interpretations but I give a definition
for that and I also give a definition
for what is
algorithmic art. So together in order
you know together all these are
algorithmic and mathematical but that
does not mean anything computerenerated.
Okay. So this this one is algorithmic
mathematical art because it's defined by
a equation. This one is also because
it's defined by a equation. This is a
called Raymond surface. Okay, it should
extend extend to infinity. It only shows
part of it. Uh and I I always dreamed to
be able to have something like this in a
3D game. So, so for those of of you uh
writing 3D games or know how to use 3D
game engine engines, try to create this.
Okay. So, try to recreate this Raymond
surface in a 3D game. So that it doesn't
just show part of it. Like right now,
this picture only show part of it, but
it should be
like, you know, all the edges extend to
infinity. Okay. So, so when you have
this in a 3D game and imagine if you are
a person walking on a surface or ant or
a fly, you can kind of go through these
tunnels into a different level. So, you
go up this hole, you reach a different
level, then you go to the other side and
then you can go up.
So if anyone of you have seen anyone has
ever done this in a 3D game engine,
okay, I'm not talking about like you
know like you can go to this website.
This this is a professor Richard Palace
and Kasher who helped me a lot. Richard
Pal and Kasha okay they they they were
my
mentors. Okay. So and I helped uh like I
helped build I helped them build this
website. So you can you know see many of
these minimal surfaces
uh and for uh so this one Raymond
surface. So this one okay let's turn on
JavaScript. Um then you can see they
deform you see. So it's it's a family of
surfaces. Okay. So, but my question is
for you guys if you guys have ever seen
something like this rendered in a 3D
game engine. Let me know because I've
been wanting to do that like since 20
years ago, but I don't think I'm going
to do it. I'm too old for it. I mean,
yeah, I got other things, you know, is,
you know, so happens. So, but if you
guys have ever seen, you know, things
like that, let me know. Okay.
So fantastic. Okay. So this website uh
check it out. Okay. 3D Expo Math 3DXM
virtual math museum. Okay. Let's post
that
there. Okay. Then I wanted to Yeah.
Algorithmic. Yeah. Agorithmic
mathematical arts. Okay. Let's continue.
This is algorithmic mathematical art
because it is defined by an algorithm.
Okay. And all these two, but this is
real life. And these two because it's
defined by a mathematical equation.
These two and these two because it's
defined by a uh algorithm, you know, a
mathematical definition. This is called
um inversion of circles.
Okay. Uh and that one too and this one
too. Inversion of circles. And this one
too. Uh some of these by are by other
people, you know. So this one is from a
math
software like 30 years ago. It's gone.
It's gone now because you know like 30
years ago imagine you lived your life
and after 30 years some websites are
good things like that.
Then so then you this is a algorithmic
mathematical art because it's done via
algorithm and uh you know geometry
transformation. So typically this one is
called fish
lens and this one we've seen before but
now it becomes like one single line. So
this image is created by one single line
moving about. So very fascinating uh you
know uh it's based on uh it's based on
uh what was it based on I
forgot but it's done by line replacement
you know transformation of the line line
segment. So anyway, there's so many so
this this topic there's big topic. So
there's a building this one is called
pink wheel ting beautiful and this is
this is a building in
Australia in Australia. Uh then you got
you know so this is also mathematical
art. This one is a plot of a um complex
function. Okay. Uh something like that.
the real part of a discriminant as a
function of the of the norm Q on the
unit disk. Okay. I don't understand. So
let's see if the website is still alive.
Yeah, it's still alive. This this is old
pretty old like
2005. So anyway, so so then there's
tailings and patterns. So this is Celtic
decoration. It is mathematical art
because involves a lot algorithms.
Okay. And similar similar. Okay. So
anyway I want to get to so then we
started to have this this beautiful
thing is a nonperiodic tiding. Okay.
It's nonper nonperiodic
uh and it is algorithmic. So this is a
algorithmic mathematical art.
Okay. So there's too many to go through.
Okay. So and this one spectacular. Okay.
So um then there's fractalss because
they are a plot of a mathematical
uh recursive function. Um you know
fractalss and there's uh 3D geometry
case. Uh so
anyway so what what I want to say so
then there's you know uh one of the most
famous artist known for his mathematical
art
so transformation titings and
another's artwork
um okay but but something are not
mathematical art okay and I really hate
them. So that would be examples of
today's what's called generative art.
Okay, that's the worst possible.
Generative art. You look at them, they
are just like random, you know, random
doodling using computer programs.
There's no order. There's no structure.
It's just like random doodle. The random
doodling
popularized by the Zuma generation.
Okay. No order, no structure. You just
use computer to like do random, you
know, drawing that it's called
generative art. It's the worst
Okay. No, there's, you
know, like it's worst possible.
Okay. And it's easy because there's no
rules. You just use the computer just to
do do random and you come up, you know,
you have like a picture like that. Okay?
You know, some of them require some
creativity like this one. You know, you
got to have some some
creativity. Uh but but basically,
there's no rules, you know. On the
contrary, in
contrast, all these all these tidings,
okay, or or or this one or or this one
or uh let's go to the my article. Okay,
so
uh where is it? Okay, so
uh so all these you know all these
surfaces, they are not just like random
doodings. they have very precise
properties and
coordinates. So in order to do this you
need
to like it's not easy. Okay. Some of
these involves integrals that you have
to compute for long hours. Okay. And
they have very significant significant
properties such as this solon. Okay.
this solaton breath of solaton they
involved actually I don't understand the
mathematics but they they are about
solaton like like in physics okay in you
know in physics advanced physics you
have this kind of thing I don't really
understand it okay but it's about wave
about how you can have a wave and uh
anyway look up Wikipedia okay look look
up Wikipedia Pedia for
solit. So you have these four
solit they may not be pretty but they
have like very significant mathematical
properties you know the type of property
that get gives you like uh you know
solutions I mean solves critical
problems so you can um
have nuclear bomb something like that.
Okay. Not not exactly but something I
mean something of that
magnitude. Okay. So I but I don't
understand this. Okay. So but anyway
other things are easy to understand. For
example ellipsoid is the most easy to
understand. Uh and it has lots of
properties because earth is an
ellipoid. Okay. So so anyway back to my
point. any one of these picture and uh
let's go let's go to the minimal surface
because that's more beautiful. Any one
of these picture is very precise
uh defined by a mathematical equation
and so it is not easy to do and but they
are also beautiful. Okay, for example
this uh boy
surface. Okay, this what you know this
this one looks like a propeller
propeller. Okay, and also actually the
surface is not just a propeller. It
extends to all directions. Okay, so it's
not it's not exactly a propeller because
it extend to all directions. Okay, like
imagine you know it it intersect itself.
So what I want to see again is I want to
see someone I think it will happen down
in in the road in the new gener the new
generation somebody will have this in 3D
3D game you know create this in 3D game
engine actually 20 years ago I was in a
conference in
Tokyo I've seen people do that
mathematicians they demo you know this
in a 3D game engine but but what I want
to see is you know popular like I can
just go to a stream website and download
a game like that have these surfaces in
a game that would be fantastic. So if
you seen that let me know if you have
not you know think about it maybe do it
tell other people to do it. So these are
minimal
surfaces. So all these okay all these um
let's go back. So all these are
mathematical very very definite.
So in sharp contrast to this doodling
so-called generative
art you
know then okay so one more thing I want
to say about what is not mathematical
art
is let's go back okay so so another
example that is not algorithmic
mathematical
art that would
Uh that okay this is the worst
possible loved by the bit
diddlers you know the ray
tracing. So ray tracing they are you
know great computer techniques for
computer graphics they simulate real
world imagery right and it is
algorithmic you know but you know
because it's done you know it's created
by a computer including
um hold on a second so let me show you
so we have seen generative
odd are they algorithmic
Yes, because it's created by a computer
algorithm, but they fail to be
algorithmic, algorithmic mathematical
art because they don't have a definite
structure. They don't have, you know,
definite like symmetry or structure even
though it's algorithmic. Similarly for
this ray traced
image is it algorithmic? Yes, because
it's created by a computer. But is it
mathematical? Well, not really because
there's no structure to it. Okay, so
that is the
distinction
of you know that's that is my thesis.
Okay, in this article
uh in this article where is it here?
Okay, you want
mathematical algorithmic mathematical
artwork. All these aream the examples of
except this one except this uh this
cellular automter that's not well that's
ma that's
algorithmic but it is not mathematical.
It lacks mathematical
beauty just like just like this
generative art. It lacks mathematical
beauty. Okay, it lacks mathematical
beauty. And this one ray tracing
pictures lacks mathematical beauty. You
know for humans you might you might
think oh well this is pretty picture. Uh
oh yeah this is pretty picture is kind
of relaxing or whatever but it is
not algorithmic mathematical art okay
that that is um kind of the
point I'm making in this
article in in this article okay where is
it here okay so this this one cellular
automata that's also not mathematical
artwork but The rest the rest of the
images illustrations
are okay. I talked too for too long and
uh are we going to so it's already one
hour. Can we finish this? Let's quickly
finish this. Okay, I want to finish
this. So, so this is actual coding. Um
so this one, okay, we already run it.
And what about this one? So what is this
one?
So this one shift enter. Okay. Evaluate
it. And this one shift enter. Okay. Now
you started to add the outline. Okay. So
we can you know you starting to
see they begin with that and you want to
add the outline. So you you begin with
this motif. Then you show what it looks
like. Then you started to refine it by
adding outline. So let's see how how did
he add the outline. Okay. So fundamental
domain plate uh thing fundamental plate
cap form round join form line. So he
maps a line to this
point. Okay. So anyway that's how he
adds the outline. You see the black
lines. Okay. So blue thin
line. Okay. Anyway, then it shows how it
looks
like. Okay. It looks like that. Then he
tries to remove, you see, he tries to
remove the middle lines to make them a
path. Now, how does he do that?
Actually, I'm not it's not clear to me
how he did that. I have to look at the
code in detail. You know the code is
just just just here. I have to
like you know I have to pay attention
what exactly is going
on. Uh let's see can we quickly find
out. So here is a bunch of coordinates,
two-dimensional coordinates and he just
add line
to to each of them. But
uh but how do you
add? But but how did you add the
uh the
path blue thin
line Sean? Hey Sean, hope you are having
good day. Hello dosey. You should still
try. I don't think I have seen that in
many engines. Those tiding patterns are
awesome. Yeah, regarding you know
creating these surfaces in a game
engine.
Uh I never had experience in game engine
so I don't really know but I'm thinking
some of them the game engine will not be
able to do because the game engine is
not designed to do infinite uh surfaces
like surfaces that extends to infinity.
So let me just show you some you know
here's another beautiful uh 3D one. So
can you do this in a game engine for
example? You'll be you know I I have no
idea because I never I try to study game
engine but it's like very low level like
open openg and like you have like 100
1,000 lines if you just want a cube
rotating. Okay. 1,000 lines in Wuan
language is one single line. I've showed
this many times. Okay. So for example
uh you know cube one single line. So
let's say you want cube you know let's
say at 0000. Okay. Then you just
say graphics
3D at and that's it. Okay. Then you know
one single line you have a cube. Then
you can like tube whatever you know one
single line to do this in OpenGL is like
200 lines you know
then you know environment settings or
pipe you know whatever so I don't
know so but in gaming so so but you see
this extend to infinity you know this is
a this is like a special um
uh uniform uklidian and
honeycom. Okay. So that it you know this
is not too difficult but but some of
them for example let's see
where okay
so so some of these you know they extend
to infinity so I don't know how you know
3D games are usually not designed to to
to do that.
Um, so this one for example, yeah, this
this is not so good. So you see they
they cross each other. So you know, um,
anyway,
so anyway, so I think that's So let's
finish coding this. Okay, so where's the
code? Yeah. So let's
see, you know, I uh, so let's see. So
let's evaluate this
part.
So did we evaluate that? Yes. Okay. Now
this
one works.
Fantastic. Now this one. Okay. That's a
comment. Now this
one. Evaluate it. Okay. Now this one.
Okay. Now let's delete the graphics and
uh evaluate it ourself. Now there you
go. So let's see now this
one
evaluated.
Fantastic. Okay, we we kind of done. So
what what are these variations? I guess
evaluated. Evaluate
it. Okay, delete that. Evaluate it.
Okay. So we didn't get into
understanding exactly how he
um like for example now Yeah. So you see
first of
all you start with with simple line then
you make them into a strip then you
remove the line in the middle. You see?
Then you need to make the strip
crisscross, you know, overlap like one
on top of each other. So let's see. So
you see, so the trick is actually to
understand how did he do it because I
mean you I mean it's it's easy to do but
it's just tedious because you know it's
just tedious like so I want to find out
did he you know is there some simple
way so he's using the cap form wait is
that the new function I I haven't seen
that
function joining form is a graphics
directive that specifies what type of
join should be used to connect segment
of lines. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. So what about capform? Cap form
just means the end
point. Yeah. those that
shouldn't do it
but okay I think he manually he did it
manually so it's very tedious yeah I
think that's what he did manually let's
see why is
he you see he just did it manually like
manually created this formula each you
know each one of these is coordinate
point. Yeah, I think so. So, it turns
out, you know, you just do this
manually, you know, find out each
coordinate point, then draw a line, you
know. Okay, but still very interesting.
So, I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for
watching.
Fantastic. Bye guys. Support my work,
okay? If you love my stuff,
uh go to
kasadi.info, kasadi.info,
kasmath, and go to all the way to the
bottom. You can pay me, Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me, PayPal me, PayPal
me, or gift card me $100. That would be
good. Do it one shot. Okay, bye guys.
very off topic. Have you tried Vime
VVM
Vime C extension for your browser? No.
And I would not be interested. I know
you don't use Vim, but you get Vim key
bindings for your browser, so you won't
need to use your mouse. No. Uh, well,
that's a old topic. I like flam I I
flamed
it. I flamed it so bad you wouldn't
know. But even that that's 10 years ago.
I would
never use like a vim binding like a
bunch you know you press a key then
bunch of key like ABC D you know press B
to jump to here then you know press C to
go to this link press D to open that
link. That's
crap. That's that's not
um that's not very efficient. Okay. It's
mouse is better. But anyway, I don't
want to flame, you know. That's okay.
Bye.