good morning everyone welcome to another
top show today is June 25 25th and we're
gonna code we're gonna do a live coding
of creating a interactive CSS Radio
gradient generator so let me show you
what it is let's begin let's see that's
so I'm live that's good let me move the
browser to the position so you can see
and let's start saw log command log so
you can see all my Emacs command on the
Left panel okay right there if you are a
max user and I'm using some ficus and
I'm using black keyboard layout so the
keys on the left are actually black keys
so we are going to do a live live coding
so let me show you what we're gonna do
so let's go to our CSS okay cascading
style sheet so visual CSS this is my CSS
tutorial and it's you know it's like a
visual dictionary and you can see we
have linear gradient now CSS provides
you with these fancy features you can
create all sort of you know gradient
color gradient and we're gonna so let me
gonna show you what it is so you can you
see I I wrote a inter interactive
silkier bambo random color random color
and you can see random direction you can
adjust the direction
so what it does is that it generates
these you know random color gradient for
you and the random color and then the
code is showing up here and you can copy
it let's see let's see a copy yet so
copy it and create a new file let's save
it as s let's save render name HTML and
let's say create a HTML file and let's
say let's put a dive tag and let's say
something okay
actually let's say dive with a okay then
we put a style here CSS style and style
dive dot X loops dive dot what dive oh
yes
and this dive oh sorry
dive dot X and the style will be what we
just copied so for the style here and
show in browser oh it should be
background so background linear gradient
sar CSS mod so background-color : linear
gradient that's right
there's the okay and show in browser not
working because okay dive dot X wait
background color linear gradient class X
dive classics why is it not working
let's try to add a border for the solid
thing gray and show again okay we got a
boulder and let's say font size okay - I
am big that's good
that's walking and but why is the
background color not walking how is it
done so let's go back to look at the
linear gradient the example died have
background oh not background color but
just background okay go to browser show
there it is so this is why this linear
this generator gradient generator is
useful
let's see random okay let's let's try
this one copy it go here paste it remove
that
showing Bowser you see okay so that's
linear gradient now let's go to back to
CSS and we also have radial gradient so
is so CSS allows you to have gradient
radio Radio means you know they it's
like a circle the ripple out and what we
are going to do is we are going to
create a interactive application for
this radial gradient just like the
linear gradient so good morning everyone
say hi here and post your questions
opinions anything okay so let's let's
start to do the radial gradient now okay
now this temp file we don't need anymore
delete it now let's go to let's go to my
CSS web dev blog let's open the radial
gradient file so this is the file let's
copy the path and show in Google Chrome
okay now that's what we're gonna work on
update the date you see the date 2018
April 4th
now it's 2019 June 25th and we're gonna
start by first of all whenever you do a
interactive application what do you need
to know well you know okay so what we
need to know is what are the parameters
we need to change basically we are going
to generate this code code like this
radial gradient you know so what so
first thing to find out is what are the
parameters we need to create user input
that generates these parameters so what
are the parameters so we have Center you
know where the where is the location the
ready
gradients start so yes yep Center we
have at the corner left corner left top
corner okay that's a position then
obviously we have the color color colors
are parameters so color position of the
center then we have elliptical radio so
we have elliptical radio versus circular
radio and then there is also the color
stops meaning that how much of a color
you want the gradient to occupy for each
color so these are the parameters the
the length of the color the color stops
is actually a bit more complicated to
code so I think we're gonna skip that so
we just gonna code a basic one so I
think this will take 20 to 30 minutes
I hope let's can we can finish it in 30
minutes okay so first of all so we know
the parameters we want so first of all
create a JavaScript file okay
so I copy the file path change it to
JavaScript now should I should we do
JavaScript or typescript if you use
typescript then you can learn something
about typescript but there's a slightly
more code because you have to add types
so if you like to see typescript let me
know okay post in comment otherwise
let's just start with JavaScript so we
have created the path for JavaScript
file then we make it into a link you can
see my if you are Emacs user you can see
my command C max commands on the Left
you can find those commands on my
website so we have a JavaScript file and
open it it's empty create new yes okay
it's an empty file so we create a
JavaScript file and now okay so in a
JavaScript file let's open it
and let's put a date and let's say the
parameters let's write things out bunch
of colors then we have position produced
position of center which is Center top
center and and four corners so we have
color we have the center and we have
let's create shape of shape circle or
ellipse
okay so parameters are colors bunch of
colors then position of center Center
all four corners and the shape is circle
Elise so we know now the next thing the
first thing is determine the parameters
second thing step to create user
interface to enter the parameters okay
so create user interface so we need
let's see
lets you know it's useful to look at the
radial gradient script so let's go back
to CSS linear gradient yeah let's look
at so so the color you know each one of
the color is the color wheel you know
it's it it lets you pick a different
color you see color you see color then
you let's say this one you want to be
green
you see then let's say this one you know
that that lets you pick a color that's
color wheel okay and let's stop that so
we want to create a bunch of color
wheels then yeah I think we're gonna
pretty much follow this you know father
follow this user interface and number of
colors you can you see you can specify
number of colors to then it only uses
the first two numbers so if you can you
can increase that to three four five six
seven you know you can increase up to
seven seven so that's a good choice and
then then for the linear gradient we
have the direction but however for
radial gradient you don't have that
instead of you have the you know center
of the weight radio so you have the four
corners or the center of the box five
choices so now we want to create a user
interface we need to decide what to do
so first of all input for color color
picker okay let's start with two color
Pickers then we need random bimbo yeah
that's also a good choice
a random button then a rainbow color
button okay then we need the number of
colors yes we do need that radio boxes
those are called radio boxes you know
why they are called radio boxes radio
boxes are like in the old-fashioned
radio in cars you know you have a row of
buttons when you press one B others pops
up so at any time you can only have one
choice so this is why this is how radio
button functions and that is why they
are called radio buttons
meaning that you can only pick one out
of the many choices so we need a radio
boxes for the number of colors then we
need a choice for five choices of center
radio boxes okay so these are the
interface we need to create let's start
to do that okay so first of all color
Pickers now we go to we want to create
color Pickers so how do you do that that
is the linear gradient so let's open up
dahm dahm scripting tutorial so over
here you can see all the input boxes we
need so the first one we need color
Pickers here so that's how you you know
create a color picker and let's copy
this nice just copy the code copy and
paste is the mastery of coding okay okay
so let's do its do the color Pickers so
let's need that needs to go up here he's
a JavaScript part needs go here and so
the color picker
color picker one type color value so the
first value is red green blue okay so so
you got a color picker and this display
we don't need okay and now we need to so
color picker one this we don't need so
we have a color picker so let's do that
yeah color picker select select this
item so let me show you in browser you
see we got a color picker there and we
need a space so color picker this allows
us to pick a color that's working and
now we need to create a Java Script to
get the value of the color so first of
all you need to grab the element of the
HTML element then the value will just be
this is very simples this is actually
just value so update color picker value
actually we don't need that well update
is a function we all need to work on
later so we don't need that so we don't
need that but anyway we got a color
picker we need we need a second ones so
color picker we don't need the label
actually so color picker one and color
picker to red green let's see green so
this should be green and color picker
too so we got two colors to choose from
that's good and now in JavaScript we
need to grab them that's good now we got
a color picker what else we need a
random color button okay we'll do that
later in rainbow button we'll do that
later because you know because I'm many
I think we kind of slow we want let's
try to speed it up so we're just going
to create the application first the
simple the simplest one then we add more
features so number of colors radio boxes
let's not worry about that now five
choices of center radio let's not worry
about that now let's just get one simple
app finished so let's just have two
colors so radio box we have two colors
now let's just make that work generate a
CSS code for the two colors so the next
step is our program logic JavaScript so
how are we gonna do the goal is once you
have two colors you need to generate a
stream of particular you know string
syntax that contains these two colors so
that the string we want is basically
these
copy that so that's the string this or
the step two so step three javascript
code get user input values then generate
the CSS gradient stream code stream show
in browser okay that's what we need so
now we got okay so we need to generate
the stream so the stream is going to
look like something like that but we we
you know we need more than just
generating a string because because you
can see you know the linear gradient you
can see it actually shows an example of
you know of your choices so you also
need to show the code example so let's
go back to the HTML file we need a place
that shows the results so that's let's
let's give a dive box let's say display
okay this is a display region and we
need to also pick that up this is the
this display element okay where we want
to display the result okay
then in this toy box and and let's see
okay then display
what else so display we so we need to
generate a CSS code stream that's right
so let's do that so let's go back to our
page let's show it okay that looks like
that then we need to write now we need
to generate the stream so let's just
write a code to generate the stream so
result stream equals to now in
JavaScript 2015 you have this template
stream which is very useful when you
want the string with embedded values
variable values so here you will need
your B color to okay for example here
will be color one and okay that that is
the result string so let's console.log
let's just print it and see what happens
okay so go back to the browser
start up the JavaScript console very
useful when you are coding JavaScript so
refresh the page no okay
arrow color one is not defined you know
the arrows above those are from you know
Google trackers and others you know when
you are loading a local file for example
I'm loading a local file those Google
trackers are ignored that's why you are
getting those arrows so we don't have to
worry about that you know because on my
HTML page I have you know if you go to
the top you can see you know the bunch
of Google ads and Google trackers you
know those are ignored
so go back to the code so let's so right
now we have arrow color one is not
defined we need to define okay actually
we don't need to let's not say color one
let's just say color picker okay let's
say color 1 ok color picker 1 value ok
constant color 1 equals 2 color picker 1
value
and same thing for color picker too
okay and so right
so that should walk refresh the browser
good it's working it's printed out so
you see a princely stream this is a
stream we want now the next step is that
we need to show it you know displayed
the the radio CSS we just generate it so
what you need need to do is this display
box let's show the let's show the code
here so you see this displays box class
we don't need ok so let's read of the
class so this display box we need to add
style CSS style so we're gonna do style
dot background equals to V so stream
okay that should do it
let's refresh the browser no and no
arrow okay
why is that oh yeah because wait style
background V so stream that should work
Radio gradient yeah color one color -
yeah
wait we don't we we need to print it so
if you have any comments questions
posted okay let me know so we are so
what what's going on now so let's go
look at the browser so we got the string
correct but it is not showing the dive
box it's not showing the tie box
I've box here let's refresh
okay the dye box is certainly there but
it is not getting the style CSS style
why is that good element by ID display
box I don't know why is that but let's
do something simple let's say color
equals to read and receive exactly okay
so obviously we got the dybbuks but for
some reason the resource string is not
so what's the the syntax seems correct
so why is it not working let's try this
let's try this so instead of using
generated code let's use let's just use
the normal stream you know let's see
that should work
refresh that's working now that is
working so something is wrong with our
generated code but that couldn't be
let's try it again
gradient oh they need to be straying I
guess what
so I don't have a example using the RGB
hex
so I'm guessing what needs to be done is
that hmm I don't think so let's try it
again
refresh okay it's not working it's not
working because radio gradient so you
should walk though but let's remove
those string quotes so let's look at the
linear gradient so why is the okay so
you don't need you don't need oh yeah
you need you need a pawn sign but we do
have the pound sign here let's look at
Radio gradian let's look at this CSS
code here
something is wrong and we don't know I
don't know why let's see tests ok I'm
still going so what why what's going on
anyone know say something guys so we
have so the problem so this is a result
stream the result string we are printing
it out here and in the browser we can
see the result stream so the results
train says radio gradient you know
yeah it's correct ff0000 six digits of
hexadecimal that is correct so so
apparently the results stream seems
correct but the the result string is
correct here but when you add it to
style background it does not have any
effect you see because if we refresh it
it does not have any effect now if we
copy that and if we manually added to
heal what would happen
that works so if you add it manually it
works but
but why is it not working in browser
then well I mean why is it not working
when we use JavaScript to generate the
background value
okay don't know
now this is tea
why is it not working yes so that's it's
common that out and let's also remove
that so we go back to these oh wait what
it works now but let's seem possible
my said it works so what is oh I see why
because I added a semicolon there that
should still work though that's it's
very strange man that's a bug my friends
that's okay I see so yeah so you see the
semicolon is used in CSS to separate
different properties but however we
cannot add a semicolon here we cannot
add a semicolon here at the end because
because we are specifying a single
property background you know it's a
single property it's not a bunch of
properties so when you have a single
property and you add a semicolon that
would that you know would be wrong so
let's let's refresh what's going on okay
we understand what's going on we clean
up refactor clean up the code then we
refresh here it's correct now you see
this is too narrow we want to make it
you know nice box so to do that we add a
style at the top of this page so we go
to the top here there is already some
styles you can see those styles are used
for you know the other parts of the page
but we need a new one which we will add
here so this will be dive hoops dive
this way this way we want to create a
hate so hate will be let's say we then
hate okay so so okay let's do that let's
make it two lines within hate 400 okay
let's just say 400 no it's incorrect
because now it's an ID it's not class
that's that's good that's what we want
now let's try if this works let's change
color let's change to blue it's not
changed why because we don't have events
obviously so let's go back to the
JavaScript code open it we need to add
event listeners so that anyway the input
changes you know the thing up dates
event listeners so remove that so we add
event business to the color picker
elements that's right
color picker elements dot add event
listeners that's right so any input any
input input event we want to call a
function and this function let's call it
function update okay now we need to
write the function update so the goal of
the function update is to feel this type
box with the proper CSS change which is
the string we used here so
so we don't need this anymore yeah so
okay so let's write a function so it's
constant arrow function okay and we have
a function this is a function body and
the function name will be f update okay
F stand for function and the function
takes one argument actually we don't
need any argument the argument when you
have a eventhandler the argument is
supposed to be a event but we are not
going to need that because we work
directly with these elements we already
have picked up by element by ID so this
function update will generate the string
CSS string and attached it to the dive
box okay and the string is this you
already generated and we attach it to
the die box that so that's it so let's
it let's that's it let's refresh okay
something seems wrong here
oh yeah it's blank because you need to
call the update when you run the
JavaScript so that it actually feels
feels that you know the colors already
there so refresh that's good excellent
now the second color by default is
screen I don't like green
okay so let's change it close the
javascript file go back here let's make
it white okay
back to this oh yeah white is FF 6 FS
okay yeah let's try that
so so we got the colors why don't we add
another color okay let's let's add
another color color picker color picker
three and now let's do green okay okay
now let's open the javascript file we
got a new color picker three okay and oh
this should be moved into here so color
picker three okay and okay
refresh excellent excellent
so let's try to change let's change this
to talk blue okay and wait close it's
not updated why oh you forgot to add an
event you need to you see we haven't
finished updating the event so we need
to add event for all the color pickers
so two three okay run now let's try to
change it blue
yay red green yellow excellent
close it
okay so what that is essentially we have
done our job essentially we have now we
have a interactive application of CSS
radio gradient generator oh yeah we
forgot to show the code so what is the
code for these you know user you know
people who come to this page they need
to they need the code you know after
they play with it so we need to generate
a code that generate the code is easy so
first of all we can just print it so you
can see the code in the console logs so
this is the code but actually it would
be better if we put string in in in to
you know in a browser not in a console
log so let's do that that's easy so we
have to do is to the display type box
text content text content property will
be that okay refresh that is correct
you see you got a code here that is
excellent let's make it larger okay and
we we need to make it larger so go to
the HTML page go to the top let's add
some more properties switch to CSS mod
then let's add font size font size to
REM refresh excellent now there is a
problem let me show you what is problem
it's suppose I change this color to
something doc
oh this is beautiful this one's
beautiful
okay now there's a problem you see if
you pick a color that's very dark then
your your text becomes invisible you see
so how do you solve that problem we can
solve that problem by by adding a text
shadow so let's go back to CSS let's
open a new window let's go to text
shadow this is how you solve the problem
you add a shadow so so one use of this
text shadow is that is that copy it is
that if the text can be shown in any
background color and it will still be
legible visible so do we do it do I have
people watching now three people say
something guys say something so we're
adding a text shadow yeah so X offset
let's say let's say three okay three
pixel okay y offset three pixel blur
let's say blood five pixels and color
let's say white okay now let's see if we
solved the problem refresh now let's
pick black and let's pick this black
excellent
now you can't now we have solved the
problem now the blur is a bit too big so
let's reduce the blur so it doesn't you
know it becomes small
yeah that's that's good that's what we
want so we actually we are done we can
consider it this is done today but this
more you know this is right now so we
have like prototype up there's more
details remember now the center of the
radius can be at the corner so we need
to create a user interface you know that
user change that so let's do that that's
that's very easy so how long I been
talking 48 minutes
great we are on time so let's do maybe
10 more minutes to make this to make
this complete so linear gradient radio
grade Radio gradient yeah let's add so
for possible corners but first of all we
need to find out what's the syntax so
the syntax is you just add the okay
circle a left top okay if you want it to
be centered then you don't have to add
anything but if you want to be the
corner you have to say circle a lisp at
you know left top or right bottom okay
let's do that let's complete this so
first of all we need to add a user
interface widget so Center so we need
what we need is radio boxes we need to
pick one thing at a time radio boxes so
let's see color picker radio button
that's what we want let's copy the code
so you say here you say
Center center you have several choices
Center let's remove that okay so you
have type Center no way type radio' name
Center value you don't care okay so
Center so you have several choices
Center top left top right bottom left
bottom right
okay the value we don't care so actually
the value is let's just type it out then
okay so
Center position
okay go back to browser and refresh
refresh excellent we have these choices
top left top right bottom left bottom
right fight five choices now let's add a
break
so okay we need to add more element
shape so shape you have choices of
circle okay then you have a choice of a
lisp okay so in browser you need a break
so yeah so the shape circle or Lisp
that's the user interface excellent now
let's let's call the JavaScript open the
JavaScript file at the top first of all
select the element you want actually in
this case in a case of radio box the way
you select them is a little bit
different because the radio box boxes
you want to select
you know the chosen one not you know
so the checked let's see how long you
don't that the property checked means
you know the current selected items so
by default you want the center to be
checked you should only have one of them
checked same thing with the circle it is
okay actually there's two close together
so we need
[Music]
okay that's better
and what's the result the result delete
that results we don't need that
yeah so so we got that and now we need
to get the values so how do you get the
values of a radio box we can tell by
looking the code here
radio boxes so you see we have the code
already there for you copy the pay and
paste the mastery of coding so let's see
let's put the code here and let's see
let's look up so shad show box ok so
show box we don't need let's go back to
HTML so the so the radio box radio box
you need to get the value of the radio
box so the way you do that is this is
how you do it these these two lines so
the way you do that is selected value
equals to document query selector that
allows you to you to pick an element of
particular pattern so so the pattern
will be input tag check so thats radio
box is an info tag then you need the
name equals through pets the name should
be equals to a center position so that
so far we selected every radio box of
the center position name then you say
checked then that is the item that's
being selected so that's what we want so
then you just say that value that gives
gives gives you the value so this will
be center position let's do this
actually let's do this here okay let's
do this like this
so center position is a list of items
why is just
it doesn't make sense to put it here
because because in order to get the
selected item this code needs to be
dynamic
you know because every time you know
people selected so this code needs to be
part of the update function you know
update function here therefore it cannot
be on top like that they are so let's
let's put it back so anyway that's it's
so update paste the code here then
position value center position value is
equals to that center position value and
once you have the value then you need to
ignore that part for now okay I'm gonna
show you what that code is later but
first of all we need to get a value once
we got the value we need to put into the
gradient box code here so he over here
we there's a coma then we here center
position value that's what we want okay
now this is not going to work because
the value needs to be one of you know it
needs to be circle at left top okay so
the the value needs to be we can do this
like this
okay so let's comment out the shape well
actually I'm trying to do this one item
at a time but in this case we
we need to do both of them at the same
time I cannot just finish this because
in order to have center at the corner
you need also to specify the circle or
release parameter I think so let me just
let's just let me just quickly finish
this up if I can circle ad ad right
bottom had circle and Center I think so
this is getting tedious this is getting
tedious so so call center position value
let's just say 1 2 3 4 ok 0 1 2 3 4 ok
let's go back to JavaScript so center
position
if
and let's just Cody's of quickly like
that
oh wait
okay bottom left bottom right okay so we
got a position then we got position this
is going to try refresh the browser it's
going to be an error because let
so Center position value get a value
then that position be zero one two three
four top left top right bottom left
bottom right so then we say Circle add
position so what is wrong with that I
don't see what's wrong with that
so radio circle at undefined that is the
problem undefined so it's not getting a
value so the center position value that
is not getting it
zero one two three oh that's those are
streams wait
stupid JavaScript these are strings not
numbers and I'm using the triple equal
which does not convert type it does not
do auto casting that is why yeah yay
okay so we got top left okay now we
click top bottom you know we click one
of these it's not changing because we we
don't have event for those radio boxes
now let's add radio boxes event which is
this code so a rave foam so we have
document query select or input input
center position
center position okay so we select all
the radio boxes for center position then
we the result is in collect HTML
collection or not not least you know
that's technicalities of Dom by anyway
so usually they are not arrayed type so
you don't have array methods but we can
convert to array by using a wave form so
now we got an array then for each
element for each element we we we apply
this function which which is add an
event listener X dot add event listener
input so yeah so we add event to call
the function update now it should walk
refresh yay now it works okay
now the circle and atleast that's simple
it should be done in one minute okay so
let's go back to the HTML code shape
circle or release okay shape shape
circle it is that's right so we go back
to
open the file and open the javascript
file and now we need to so in the update
function we add Center okay we add a
center code not center shape shape code
so shape we are equals to select let's
show the HTML file shape so named shapes
select all the radio boxes with the name
shape and select the one that's checked
okay and let's see the syntax you circle
add it is head okay so we select we
select the shape and then we get value
okay so shape value okay
and now now we add this shape value into
here evaluate it dynamically so we got a
shape value either circle it is so that
should be it
refresh change way tops right circle it
is okay Elise is not working because it
is ad
what is the value Radio gradient e al
IPS e and e I up IPS Yi that spelled
correctly a lisp ad oh the reason it's
not showing it is because we have a
square box that is why I think that is
why so let's if we modify the hate to be
let's say 200 then pick a list we need
add event for the release so let's add
an event for the release ok refresh in
this it works
so okay that that should be it today for
people watching ok thank you for
watching that we we want to write this
application and it's working correctly
that we achieved our goal let's let's
let's try some some fun colors let's see
if we can get something sharp
interesting oh ok the so next thing we
need to do we need a we need to add more
colors and we need to add a random color
option you know a random option so
should we do that so if you guys like me
to see me to continue coding this to you
know add a random color option and also
a number of colors let me know you know
type in the in a box but otherwise we
are done you know today we we got this
is what we want which is good
okay thank you for watching have a good
day I