Hello, hello, good morning, good
evening, good afternoon. Welcome to
another episode of Excel talk show. We
are going to code advent of code 2025
day six part two in Wuam language.
Fantastic. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed minimum. If
you are here, say hi. love to see your
comments and uh here is my talk show on
my website kasali.info
http nos. So in the past month we did we
almost live streamed every day and uh so
day six so we're going to continue to
day six part two.
Uh wait, did we uh Okay, so we need to I
I need to update this. So this today's
part two and uh did we forgot to update
um so go to topics.
So uh
there. So let's go here. That's day six
part one. And that's the code. Yeah. So
we got part two. Okay. Let's just start
to code it. This is probably boring for
most of you. Uh and uh so but if you are
interested in functional programming and
woofam language then you might learn
something.
Okay. So let's let's begin. Let me take
off my jacket. Let's see.
This is Mickey Mouse.
Mickey Mouse Nation.
Okay. Can you see the screen? Yeah.
So, part one problem is very simple.
Okay. You got a list. You got a text
file like that. And that's just uh and
uh this text file is separated into
several columns. So, you have a bunch of
numbers. At the bottom there's a
operation plus or multiplication sign.
Your job is to sum up
or all the columns for each column
operate by that operation sign at the
bottom.
So for this column you add them
together. For this column you multiply
them together. So for each column you
got a number. Then you add up all the
numbers. That is your personal solution.
Okay, that's what it asked for. So, we
solved it uh the other day. Trivial. Uh
in fact, the shortest code actually I
have this shortest code I coded offline.
You cannot see it. I mean, I didn't do
it live. So, so let me open uh I think I
did live. I forgot. So, let's go to wam
language. Uh
let's start wuam language and let me
show you. Yeah. Okay. So there there and
just copy that. Go here. So wam language
you need to blow it up
and uh
paste the code. Shift enter to run it.
There is the answer.
Okay. Fantastic wam language. Uh so now
let's go back to the part two. Let's see
what the part two ask for.
Okay, part two.
So the first part is complete.
Oh god, this is very annoying advent
code. Uh you know you cannot read it.
Okay,
so let's copy it. Uh let's copy it to
Emacs. Okay. So,
open a new buffer.
Now, let's see R2. Okay. Uh
okay.
The big sub parts came back to check how
many how things are going. When they see
that your grand total doesn't match the
one expected by the worksheet, they
realize they forgot to explain how to
read salafod sallallow math. Safalopad
that means squid octopus
uh those kind of creatures. Sallallop
pad sallallop part. Salopod math is
written right to left in columns.
Each number is given in its own column
with the most significant digit at the
top and the least significant digit at
the bottom.
So from right to left
and each number is given in its own
column with the most significant digit
at the top
right to left. Okay, confusing problem
are still separated with a column
consisting only spaces and the symbol at
the top of the problem is still the
operator to use at and the symbol at the
bottom of the problem. Okay, so
basically you got the same input.
Now
reading the problem right to left one
column at a time. Okay, one column at a
time. the problem are now quite
different. The rightmost column is
is
the rightmost column. So it's 4 + 431
what? 4 + 43 1 + 6 2 3
Oh, 4
+ 4 3 1 + 6 23.
What the twisted
equals to that. The second problem from
the right is
175.
So it's over here
581 581
then 32. Okay.
So the numbers are
okay. I think I made sense now. You see
each column they are aligned. So first
of all they use spaces to separate the
columns. But however within each column
they are aligned
to the left instead of to the right.
Like typically if you have number let's
say 23 and you have 100 let's say 200
you align them to the right. So see 23
or 200 you align them to the right. But
in this problem
you got 64. In this column you got 64 23
314. You first of all align them to the
left. Okay. So let's let's make a uh
emac trick. So let's copy that column.
Okay. Let's uh let's do it again. So
press press.
You can see the command call is copy
rectangle to register.
Okay. Then press press
yank rectangle. Okay.
Okay. Hold on a second. Uh
press press.
What did did we not copy then to uh
register? Press press press
press.
No. Uh, what?
Okay. So,
what
yank rectangle.
Okay. So, hold on a second. Let me do
this Emac stuff correctly. If you ask
here, say hi. Okay.
What's going on? I not sure what is
going on.
Press press press.
Oh, okay. So, let's say one and uh press
press. Okay.
One. Press, press, press.
Okay, wait.
Failed.
Yeah,
I was to trying to demo a Emac trick,
but I failed. But we can do it this way.
Okay. Do okay that way. Uh so anyway
given a column of numbers they need to
be aligned on the left which they
already did. Okay. So so then you read
so given this column of numbers and each
one must be aligned on the left then you
consider a column as a digit column.
Okay. So you go from the rightmost
column you got nothing nothing you got a
four. So that is so therefore that is
four there.
And
then you then here you got 431.
That's why it is 431. Then the next is 6
23. Does it check? Yes. 623. Okay.
Remember remember each column
is a bunch of digits in each row. Now
for this bunch of digits in a column you
must align each number to the left. Then
you consider one single digit space as a
column. Then you begin from the right.
So the first column you got just one
number you know or more. then the second
column from the right then the third
column. So each so in other words each
column of this singledigit column
they create a number. So for example
here is four here is 431 here is 623.
Okay now let's check one more column. So
175 175 check
581 581 check and 32 check. Then what
about this one? That's 8 check 2 48
check 369 check. Okay. Now last one. 356
check. Then 24 check then one check.
Okay. Then the grand total you you sum
these numbers up. Then you then you sum
them up. Okay. Then you got that solve
the problem on the math worksheet again.
What is the grand total? Okay. Okay.
You got the problem. Yes.
Now commencement of solution.
Shall we?
If you are here say hi. Okay. Now this
is a commencement of solution.
Uh event of code 2025 day six. And uh
let's uh where do we begin? Uh press
press begin a new uh section. You can
see then can you see my screen? Yes.
Okay. Then start a wolf language code
and adv of code part two. Okay. So
now what is the input?
Well, let's copy from uh from the
previous day. We have the input here. In
fact, we can
uh let's copy this.
Okay.
So, paste pop it out. So, we are begin
to code this.
First turn the text block into a matrix
of strings. Okay. Yeah, that's good.
Then you
extract the last row as list of
operators. Then hold on, hold on a
second. So a matrix strings then you
rotate it.
Okay. So you can can you see can you see
we evaluate this uh evaluate this?
So you got that. Okay, that's uh that's
what you get.
Okay, then
this is input string matrix. Okay, then
you rotate. Okay, let me let me show you
X input string uh matrix rotate
right
okay you can do that but let's evaluate
this in wam language so that like we can
do this it sequentially select or paste
shift enter there it is
So you can see we rotate left. Rotate
left is just like rotate each element to
the left. So the rightmost item, the
last item now become the first. This
first become second. So you see that's a
result. Beautiful,
elegant.
So we the reason we want to move it to
the first is because we can so that we
can apply because it's a column, right?
we can apply you know uh anyway then
then then what we do is a transpose okay
let me just do it show you
transpose
at
that that okay let me just run this run
it and the result will make it clear you
see it transpose the matrix
fantastic and beautiful it is copy. So
let's show the result here
so that it is clear.
Okay. So now we got that what do you do
with this? Now for each number you want
to cons uh you want to consider it as a
remember it's a column of stuff. It's a
column
So one, two, three, four, five, six.
Let's go back here. So let's consider uh
you see this. You don't need this.
So for each number
you want to Okay. So this is h that's
interesting.
So basically
what you can do is you add zeros
to those numbers that does not have
enough dig digits. So first of all you
find out what is the maximum number of
digits.
Okay, let's say 10. Then for the rest of
the numbers you pad them to the right
until they have 10 digits.
Then
you can take this
this like digit rectangle then transpose
again.
Would that work? No, because Yeah,
because if you do that then you got 400,
not 004. So,
yeah. So, uh so you have to pad. Okay.
So
uh besides even if this works it's not a
good solution because then because then
you need need to take each of these
column of digits
they are column of strings you need to
pad zeros to the string. Then for this
list of strings then you need to turn
that into a matrix.
Then then you do transpose
then
okay so that's that's one idea let's
think about the next idea that's one
idea okay if you are here say hi hello
Amar very cool keyboard that's ultimate
hacking keyboard 80 UHK 80 I have video
reviews and unboxing each one is 1 hour
on my YouTube. So, search for it, you'll
find it. Or search on sali.info.
You will find my full
texture review and photographic review.
Lots of fine photos on each and every
detail. Okay, I recommend it. Fantastic
keyboard. Okay, back to this problem.
So,
So you got the list of numbers. What
what do you want to do with it?
Part two is more annoying problem. Okay.
Uh so ultimately you have to find out
what is the maximum number of digits in
a column. Like the question is is it
necessary is that a necessary step to
solve this problem.
I think the answer is yes. For each
column you must
whatever algorithm you do
you need to find out what is the maximum
number of digits
in each entry in the column.
Why do you need to do that? Because
uh wait, hold on a second.
So, let's just focus on one column.
Okay, for example, focus on this last
column.
So just imagine in your head you have
lot you know several numbers they are
all aligned to the left.
Now these are not real numbers because
you need a special interpretation.
These are not what it seems.
They deceive the eye.
Do you guys see what I mean?
For example, that column. Now, let's do
the EMAC trick again.
Okay. For example, this column. That's
not the numbers. The the real numbers is
4 4 31
23.
You see that's a real number. That's a
real number.
P to the mathematics real numbers
anyway.
So,
so you need to turn that into that.
Okay. So,
so you have to think about it. Okay. 446
431.
Now if you pad zero, let's think about
this. Okay. If you pad zero, what what
happened?
That's not right.
So, first of all, 446 or 644, there's a
pattern. Do you see it?
No.
So, okay. So, what what then? What if
you p to the
right
0004?
Check.
Okay. So, you have to pad it to the
right.
Tedious.
Now the problem is I think I know how to
solve the problem but the problem is
thinking about efficiency like what kind
of approach you want to do it.
So this you know you can pad it. Sure.
And also make sure does does padding
also works always work. Does it always
work? I think so. So anyway, if you pad
to the right, then you got four 0 04
then 43 1 then 6 23. Okay. Now if you
pad to the left doesn't count. Okay. So
but okay. So if you pad it to the right
then
Then you uh you can do a transpose.
Yes, you can.
So, it turns out maybe that is the best
approach.
Pad it to the right. So, first of all,
find the maximum number of digits. Then
pat it to the right,
a zero. Then turn the whole thing into a
matrix.
Then
do a transposition.
Then convert each string to a number.
Then
uh then then just add all those numbers
or whatever multiply you know according
to that. So let me think about again.
Okay.
So you given this. So but but since you
are already since we already did a
transposition let's see how does this
how does this work out. 1 2 3 4 5 6
4 4 4 6 23 314 46 23 314 So that went to
there.
Okay. So for this
you want
change 64 to 640.
Okay. Then 23 becomes 2 3 0. Then 314
becomes 314.
Okay, I think I got it.
I got the solution.
So let me think again. Then one shot
coding will solve it.
Okay, this is already transposed.
Then you just take the rest of the
least.
Then find the maximum.
Find the maximum. Count the number of
digits.
Then you pad for each and every
Then this list of strings, you change
them into a matrix and you transpose.
And then you
turn each number into a in each string
into a number. Then you
sum it up according to the operator.
then you sum it up. Okay, I got the
solution.
Let's write it up. The algorithm
description
again if you are watching this play at
twice as fast. Okay, something like
that. Okay,
I'll go description.
For each row,
find the max number.
Um, find the max length of string.
max number
which is max length of the string. Okay.
Then for each number pad pad zero
by the
max length.
Then
consider
all these numbers
turn it into a matrix.
Each
element is a single digit.
And then
Oh, tedious. Turn them then. Then you um
each is a single digit.
Yeah. So you need actually you need some
kind of illustration like here
this we remove.
So
this cut
uh
you need some illustration. Okay. So
now should you
okay
consider this column
okay then let's go into detail so that
it's slow, but
we have clarity.
We already turned it into a list
like this.
Okay. So,
We want to add it like this.
Okay.
And the read
each single digit column.
Boom. Right. And and for each single
digit column
starting
from right
turn it into a number
so that we have.
Okay. So this part is kind of the
description of the problem.
Once you get that then it becomes easy.
Okay. So let's move the description of
the problem
into the talk show.
Okay, there is the description of the
problem.
Now this now this this is kind of
tedious.
Yeah, you know to do this you have to
find
the maximum number of digits in each
column. Then you have to add all the
rest.
Tedious. Is there a better way? Is Isn't
there a better way, my friend?
Nobody's here. Okay.
Oh god. Advent of code getting tedious
every day.
solution
coffee.
This is fantastic. Rich honey and milk
and insta coffee.
Let's go back to the argo description.
Okay. Now we can code this in a single
line. This wra language we can make it
into a single line but it just takes
some time. Okay. 20 minutes. If nobody
is looking
I'm going to finish this in 20 minutes
but I need to talk. Okay. Well I'll try
to do fast. Let's try to do fast. Okay.
I'll go description
then find
wait actually
and let's just be short. Okay.
For each number pad zero
to the right.
Pad string zero to the right.
You need the explanation is tedious.
So we got that. Okay.
Then consider all this number turn it
into a matrix.
God.
So what you get is that um
Oh god. This is
very tedious.
So, let me show you what going on.
Wait.
Okay. So that's what you get.
Then we do a transpose
And what is the transpose?
You get that?
Okay.
Then
then join string
into a number. Join string and turn it
into a number. So what you get is
All right.
Then just apply
the operator
to these numbers. Okay, that is the
complete illustrated algorithm
description.
Perfect.
So, let's copy it out.
Separate
separation of concerns,
put it into
a different description instead of code.
So show in browser
go down. So here is this this
description of the problem. Fantastic
and beautiful. And then we have
algorithm description. Now this
algorithm is particular to wam language.
Um because we are using this kind of
wufam language features. But if you are
doing this in JavaScript,
if you are doing this in JavaScript,
good luck. Or Python, you don't do these
um you you don't necessarily do it like
turning into a matrix then
yeah, I don't think so. You just do
loops, lots of tedious loops.
But okay, let's push on. Okay.
Okay. Now I got the algorithm detailed
algorithm description in my brain. Now
let's let's see if we can just code it
in one shot.
Please God help me.
If you are here say hi. Okay.
Now Provident
wish me good luck. Begin coding.
Okay then. So, okay. So, we going to
do this one shot. Can we do it?
Yeah.
You you don't want that. Okay. So, let
me let me just let me try to code this
in one shot now. Give me 20 minutes.
Okay. Let me just try to code this in
one shot.
Oh god.
What language should I learn if I aim is
to flex on other people? That would be
wam language.
Okay. So operators in is that
x matrix. Let's see. Let let me just do
a lot of temp variables because that
that kind of is very helpful. Um
okay. So I got the matrix, I got the
operators. Now the matrix for each you
want to find the uh max
um
length.
Let's see the documentation for max.
Okay, that just return the largest.
Now I want a function maximum by
Okay. Maximo buy is available in 2014
about 10 years ago. Will I use it? Yes.
Okay. Max buy.
Uh
so you got a matrix then you want
maximum by
string
length.
Let's just do that. Okay,
max by
let's let's let's not do one shot.
That's, you know, otherwise, you know,
because then if I didn't, if it didn't
work, then I have to debug. Let's, you
know,
uh, run a code meanwhile. So, uh,
oh, that's not it.
Um,
what
I thought drop. You see, we already got
the arrow
drop.
Oh, you you want you don't want drop.
You want most. Okay. Uh,
wait. You want the last or most?
Uh
operator is uh drop last
what?
Let's see documentation. Drop. You want
to drop the last item, but is there a
shortcut?
Yeah, that's the most.
Okay, that's our matrix and uh
our operators are those 1 2 3 4.
Did we transpose yet? No
Uh this
okay really I need to focus. Okay.
We did not transpose.
You need to do that, my friend. You
forgot.
Oh, yeah. We did it over here. Uh but uh
Okay.
Do it again. So that's the matrix.
Yep. 1 2 3 4 5 6. So we transpose. Okay.
Let's just um
Okay, then we can execute this
that returns one, two, three. Okay. Then
then you just uh string length at
three. Okay. Uh
what?
Oh, maximal by why is it return a list
not just a number by itself.
Okay, because there might be more than
one item.
So if you say max
what is the default um
way they compute maximum if you have
bunch of strings
indeterminate rate
okay so when it's strings it consider
indeterminate
it return itself.
But if they are numbers, they they
return a number. So you don't Okay. So
you don't want the max. Okay. You want
the maximum by
okay maximum by it may it return a list
of multiple values.
Yeah, I don't want to use max spy. Okay,
let me just use um
let me just show you. Okay, what to do?
map
map length by
that's list
uh map string lengths and the max. Okay,
that's much simpler, right?
That's much simpler. I don't want the
maximum by Okay. So,
cut that.
That's an example. Okay. So, this is how
you get
max. Okay. Now,
now you simply apply.
Okay. So, now apply. You want to map a
function
to
X matrix. Okay.
Now what does the function do? The
function will do something like that.
Okay. Now the function takes X is the
argument. Then uh then here is X
Okay,
that returns the maximum
then.
Okay, let let me let me put it into a um
local variable.
Okay, max length. Then what you do? Then
you
map again
you map string pad.
Stream pad, right? That's right.
X
you want to pad by
zero
and you want to pad by
max length
of times. I mean the total should be max
length something like that
and uh
and map that to
yeah to each number which is this x.
Now
you need to find out what exactly is the
parameters for string pad. Right?
Okay. We make string to be length n
padding it on the right with spaces or
or truncating if necessary.
Okay. Okay. So we got the syntax
reversed. So this max part should be
here.
Perfect.
map this function with a local variable
of the maximum number of length in in
them. Then you just pad it to that much.
Okay. So once you do this you got
you each of these um you know you
actually you can run it. Okay. Okay.
Let's show let's run it so it's clear to
everyone what's going on. Okay. Arrow.
That's not what I wanted.
You got a problem.
Did we have our matrix correct? 1 2 3 1
2 3 4 5 0600.
So we apparently we did had. But what is
this? Uh, okay. We got an error some
some somewhere.
map to the matrix, right? Oh, right. So,
map to the matrix. Each
each x is a row,
right? So, let's name it properly. Let's
make it row. Okay. Um,
that's a row. And then
then you
then you map that to the row and oh yeah
that's right. This this part should be a
function not that. Okay. So this part
should be a function please. That's what
the function should do. And uh the x is
that number.
Let's just say numbum.
Okay. Make it simple. So this
copy.
Go back here.
Paste.
Execute.
Fantastic. And beautiful. You see how
aligned they are.
If you are here, say hi. Okay.
Beautiful. Fantastic. And beautiful. You
see how aligned they are? Now all you
have to do
is for each of these row you turn that
into a matrix.
Then you transpose it.
One two three four five zero 600.
Uh wait 1 2 3 4 5 0 600
H
tricky. You see this this first column
they are not aligned to the left. You
see this sneaky advant of code.
You see the last column is aligned to
the left. That's what we wanted. But the
first column they did not align. But
that six is become 600. Is that right?
That six is 600 somewhere.
Somewhere please. What? No. What?
God,
don't tell me I'm wrong.
Wait. So, oh, part two. What?
So, a line to the right.
Oh, wait. It's
Oh, you cannot turn that into 600. It's
just uh six.
What?
Oh, they are aligned to the
what?
Okay, our algorithm now is incorrect.
What the
623.
Now, now the Now then, then then Okay.
Then you got 175. That's this one. Then
you got 8 248 848.
Oh, you cannot pad zero.
You cannot pad zero. You you you must
pad it like um space.
You can't pad zero. You pad it with a
space.
Okay.
And the first column is what?
Then you got 356
241.
Wait.
Oh god. Our algorithm is incorrect. Even
it seems now that we don't understand
the problem. The 3,56 there.
Okay. Can you see that?
356.
So, where do they align? Wait a minute.
This alignment is funky.
Reading the problems right to left, one
column at a time.
Okay. So the problem is really tricky.
You see
these columns are separated by space.
But however
the number of spaces has significance
because what's considered a number is
dependent.
What is considered a number whether it's
you know one single digit or not is
dependent on this spacing.
Uh But I think that actually makes
the problem easier.
So we have to
remedy. So we we got it wrong.
Remedy. Realization.
Okay.
realization of previous
understanding
of the problem
is incorrect.
This needs to be a header.
Actually
the
given input text
there
spacing
between
the number of spaces between columns.
is significant
realization
the number the given input text the
number of spaces between columns is
significant.
I think this actually makes the problem
easier but I'll get to it. Okay, let me
tell you. So text
so you can see
look at the first column
and the last column.
Okay, look at the last column. In the
last column, every number must be
aligned to the left. But in the first
column,
you can't align it to the left. You I
mean, you can't do this align yourself.
You must follow what is already given.
So in the first column, they they
actually align to the right. So you got
35, six, 2, 4, then one.
Is that right? You see 3 5 6 2 4 and
one.
Okay. So, okay. So, that actually now
let's go back to think about our
algorithm. This we wasted our time doing
this already. We wasted one hour
already.
So this so so so
now the new problem
you all you have to do is you have to
you need to keep the alignment okay
now this tedious you need to keep
the alignment now let's look at this
alignment is significant
You see, if you just split a string like
usually programmers do with their
programming languages,
then you lost that information. You lost
the alignment information.
Uh should we write it out? Full
analysis.
If you just split the string like most
for each row of text, you lose the
alignment info.
Very nasty.
So, how can we keep the alignment info?
Okay, go back.
Go back.
So this at the end of a code they like
to treat you know so again you have this
kind of grid
like a grid puzzle thing
you have to move a cruiser around it.
How do you so this becomes a problem?
What kind of problem? What kind of
category of problem is this? So you see
this text file this input text you must
treat it
like
you need to find out. So all the
columns.
So first of all like you can you have a
comma separated value or space separated
value right.
Oh So you have to keep knowing.
Okay. Now let's look at our personal
input.
Okay. Uh this is becoming
a great problem. You see this is one
line. That's one single line.
Then
this is the second line. Can you see it?
Okay.
This is the first line.
Okay. That's one long line.
You see? But look at the spaces they are
significant.
So
you can So what you can do is you can
actually split by space
but
you split by a single space.
No, that won't work either. So this so
this problem is designed to screw
the industrial programmers
you see because it's treating you got a
except EMAC this coders because this you
put this text in a buffer EMAC list can
navigate it
but if you split a string
you run into problems
Unless you split and you want to keep
the splitted part that you can do in
most languages.
But then
but that means for each number you have
to look so you you got an issue. You
have to look the previous spaces or the
spaces after. For example, the number
six,
you have to look at the spaces before.
Now, the number 98, you have to look at
the spaces
after
okay.
Okay. Let's make sure we understand this
problem.
Safalo part math is written right to
left in columns.
Right to left in columns.
Each number is given in its own column.
Mhm. With the most significant digit at
the top
and the least significant digit at the
bottom.
Yeah. So this is actually becoming a
tricky problem actually not
I don't
so okay a a new approach
now you take this input text
you remove the operators
row at the bottom
then you turn it into a matrix Except
that this time
you keep all the spaces because spaces
are important.
Okay. Then then so consider this this
text. Okay. Consider this text where
each character width is a
matrix element.
Okay. So that then you can transpose the
entire matrix.
Then you just read off each row. Okay.
So So you got four 432 I mean four 431
623.
Okay. Then you got a row of empty
spaces. Fantastic. Then you got 175 581
032.
Correct? Does it check? Yes. Then you
got a row of spaces.
Every every element in that row is
spaces. Okay. Then you got 8 then 248
then 369.
Check.
Fantastic. And beautiful. Now this
algorithm
new revelation let's write it down you
know since I'm already like one hours
let's just go all the way keep my style
ching of flamio thank you very much not
a waste you learned what doesn't work
that that's true fantastic thank you
flamio
flamio I look at the problem they look
like stacks
uh uh stacks
I not in the computer computer science
sense of stacks
but I mean they they are kind of like
stack of numbers but anyway let's we got
a new we we got a solution okay
so we
realization okay so now after
realization
okay Now,
now let's write down
our thoughts.
You are fantastic
and efficient.
Consider
the
input text as
a matrix of
single
char. Okay.
turn the input text into such a matrix.
Each
element is a single char or
single digit
or single space
string. Okay. Fantastic.
Then
transpose
the matrix.
Then turn
each row
uh transpose the matrix. Then uh
okay then
remove rows
that are all empty
spaces.
Okay. Then turn each row
Each rows element
from string to number
then sum each row.
uh not sum apply the
operator
to each row
to the
corresponding
row
or each row. Apply the operator to the
corresponding row.
Then
total them.
Fantastic. Fantastic. And beautiful new
algorithm
described
here.
Okay.
So, let's do that.
Okay. Uh
Okay. Let's copy that. Let's not
destroy. So let's do that. Okay.
First turn the text block into a matrix
strings. Each element is
is a single char. Okay. So let's do
that. Do that. Okay. So then uh first of
all split string by the
line break then function line springs uh
split string by
oh we you don't want to split string you
want to turn let me show you what to do
you want to turn this into a
characters
Okay, that's it. That is a function.
Okay, you'll see what it does.
You see? Fantastic.
So, it turns a string into each
character.
Okay, those each one of these are
strings. Okay, that's what you want to
do. Okay. So instead of split string
here this function you just say
characters.
Yeah.
Okay. Uh
okay. Let's put that example
uh let's put that example here.
Okay, then go back to our code.
Okay,
so we can run it. Um,
cut, paste,
run it. Fantastic. So, you get that
V.
That's what you get. Okay, it's ugly.
Um,
then do a transpose.
Actually, let's just do transpose here.
Actually, just
Uh wait, something is wrong.
What?
The first two levels cannot be
transposed.
What?
Oh, because because you got this,
you know, that's a problem. Okay. So,
copy that.
Shift enter. What?
What? So, how many characters there?
What?
14.
Oh,
15.
You see the re? So you see
oh so you see
so you cannot truncate lines I mean you
cannot remove the empty space at the end
so let's see so if you carefully copy
this input let's see if they have spaces
at the end you see because my input I
may have already truncated because every
time I
save the file it it removes the
spaces at the end of line that's common
you know so if we paste it here and show
you see carefully this sneaky advent of
code they they do have a space at the
end
so it's not what it seems you see space
usually doesn't show but but but but
they actually include the space at the
end to like secretly show you to all to
those who know.
Okay? Because if you actually if you
don't have the ending spaces, this
puzzle won't work because then you are
um
well actually still works. You just have
to manually pad them. Yeah. So, first
job is you find you have to find the
longest length of line. Then you pass
space. Yeah. Tricky. Okay. So, you see
very tricky Okay. So, but now if
you do this, you do this um
you know, now you do this, it'll work.
So, shift enter. Okay. Then you go back
here. Then you want to transpose.
Paste.
You see now it works. Very sneaky thing.
So what we got?
Oh, you need to remove that. Uh
what does this transpose to? What is
what is this number?
Wait, let's see. Did we?
Okay. So,
okay. Select all paste. Shift enter.
Why is the uh
why is the operators got all
moved about?
Wait, wait. No, I don't understand.
Okay.
6 3 five six empty. Okay. So, every time
you have a empty. So, let's do this
again. Okay. So, every time you have a
empty
you
Okay.
And you got empty again.
Empty.
Empty. So you see
you got empty empty. So
So 1 2 4 356
1 2 4 356. Now 369 2 48 and 8.
369.
You see 369,248
and 8. Fantastic.
Then
581175.
32581175.
Fantastic. Then 623
and 4.
Check check check.
Perfect.
Okay. So, perfect.
Okay. Perfect. Now,
now that No, those are just bad. Those
those are whatever before. Let's remove
it.
Okay,
just be be careful you cannot uh let's
make a note
each trailing line in input
may be spaces.
If you remove
delete
them,
it won't work.
Very careful. Okay. Now, let's look at
the input, our text input.
I mean, our puzzle input.
You know, there may be spaces that I
might remove it. So I have to like make
sure I get the input. There is a space
uh you know the spaces at the end of
each line. You cannot remove them. If
you do then you have to find the maximum
number of characters in all these lines.
Then you need to pad space for every
line.
So
you got to be careful about that.
So now
back to this. Okay. So now so far so
good. Yes. So far this is what we get.
Okay. Copy it.
Okay. This is not showing well. Okay.
Yeah.
So now you just have to
almost done. Almost.
Now it would be nice if if you remove
the operators. You see the the operator
symbol is like where are they aligned?
They are aligned in arbitrary places. No
This is this this is closing to
two hours.
God.
So, any comments? Comments? No comments.
The operator is always the last line.
Okay. So,
so let's spare the operators. Okay.
Let's try this again. Paste. Shift
enter. And
you see I remove the space.
Is there a way? So I don't I stop
remove. You see every because
I I have I have my um
I have my code set up so that each time
you put it back they remove this
trailing spaces.
If each time you put it out they remove
the trading spaces. So that's a problem
making you
and so
what you can do this is very annoying.
Okay. So you you know you can just copy
it.
Then you got the spaces back.
Okay, very annoying. Now
copy that. Now you paste the code. Shift
enter. Fantastic. You can see now it's
much more simpler. Now all you have to
do is split
join string. Okay, hold on a second.
Join string. Um
Okay. So, operators
matrix equals to that. Fantastic.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
Then
you want to split this.
Okay. Almost done. 20 minutes max.
Then you want to um you want to like
split string or partition. Okay.
or split by.
Let's see. Split by is from
2008. That's good. Now, split is from
1996.
Okay. Now let's split by
split by a function split list into
sublist consisting of lu of successive
elements that gives the same value when
f is applied. made.
Okay.
Okay, I need to finish this quickly.
It's already It's getting too long.
Okay, I'm going to take a break. Five
minutes.
One. Uh, wait.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10. Okay, I'll be back
at 16:50. That means
like 10 minutes.
No, right now it's 6. Right now it's
4:00 40 minutes. So I'll be back at 4:00
in 50 minutes.
I'm going to try cheeky Libra office
trick on it. Please oamo I would be
happy to see you solve this problem. I'm
treating input as CSV file and then
treating as fixed length field.
Fantastic.
But
you might be careful because if you
treat it the input as CS file uh comma
space comma separate file you have to
treat it as space separated. Actually
I'm not sure Excel or Libra Office has
that feature because this you see that's
a tricky part. You can't the input
you can't just split it because when you
treat it as comma separated there's no
comma. So you have to treat it as space
separated. But if you do that the you
know you are you basically will remove
be removing the spaces
then you cannot solve the problem
because the spaces are important.
So you have to read them as kind of
like a line
without removing any space including the
space in the end trading spaces.
Yeah, I I don't know how you solve that
with Excel or Libra Office but you know
try it.
But we are almost done. Okay, let me
just take a five minutes break. I go to
a bathroom and stuff.
So, how many people are watching?
Three. Let me make a guess.
Four
of I'm treating it as neither as comma
or space nor space.
New line separated. Yeah.
you know, let's see how it goes.
Okay, I'll be right back. Let's turn off
this sneaky cam.
Okay, I'm back.
Turn on
turn on my face and let's make a
change to the input.
Okay.
Change the input
text by replacing spaces
to dots.
Okay.
That way,
that way we don't have these. Um
that way we
don't
have
this
trailing space
yace problem.
Okay.
So now it's simpler.
Now go back to
my personal input. Let's make the same
change. Okay. So let's copy the personal
input
and uh let's see where is my personal
input. Get select all.
Copy. Close. Back to Emacs. Select all.
Make a backup. Paste. Go to the
beginning. You see that's why you see
the the last character is a space.
Tricky. Now go to the beginning. Change
space to dot. Okay. Wait. Uh, change
space to dot. Okay.
Bam. To do it all. Okay. Now save it.
Okay. We made we made a change. So now
it's actually so you know now you can
clearly see the space.
Close that.
Back to our code. Okay. Now you know now
we don't have to um so now we
now we can do this. Okay. So now we go
back to wra language. Select all paste
shift enter. So now you can see
uh actual
uh spaces. Okay.
Input matrix becomes that.
Okay. And the operators become
that.
Wait,
what?
Copy.
Paste.
What? Why do we have a uh
operators
select all copy go back paste
so you got this continuation line mark
why is that I don't understand
I mean you got this back space backspace
usually means continue the line. Okay.
But uh
what?
Okay. So, okay.
Okay.
The matrix
become
why do we have the sword?
Where is the salt?
Delete that. Okay. Delete the delete. So
copy all
select all paste shift enter.
Okay. The matrix becomes this.
Okay. So it adds the
line continuation. The matrix becomes
this. Okay.
Now
split
split by
X matrix by a function.
The function will
do
string
contains.
Okay. X that's a string if it contains
0 to 9. Okay.
regular expression.
Okay, regular expression 0 to 9.
You need them in square brackets.
Okay, split by split the matrix
by the function if it contain if it
matches regular expression 0 to 9. So
that means this is true true
false true true true false true true
false you know
let's see
paste shift enter
yes fantastic
Now copy the output. Copy back to Emacs.
This is the result.
Okay.
So now we get a clear.
You can see
you get that. Okay. Now let's assign it
a uh
split matrix. Let's just say
equals true. Okay,
back to wam language. Evaluate it so
that it knows that value split matrix.
Okay, fantastic and beautiful. Then the
solution is
almost there. Then you just
delete cases.
You want to
delete cases. Um,
okay. In in this example, it's three
dots, but in personal input, it might be
more than one more than one uh more than
three dots. So you want to delete cases
by
a pattern. Okay. So
you want to apply a function
Delete cases. Cases,
right? They should be. So those elements
you want to delete have length one.
So let's say select instead
select
and then you also have discard.
Discard criteria removes all elements
of data for which criteria is true. So
you can use discard. Discard is added in
2025.
Okay, I don't want to use that. That's
uh actually I don't have that function
because I'm not using my wuam language
is like one or two years out of date. I
haven't updated
yet. I can but I just haven't done it
yet. So let's just use select. Okay.
Select split matrix. Select from that.
Now function
if
length
at x is greater than
one.
Okay,
let's do it. That will remove those dot
dot dot elements.
Shift enter.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
Now, uh,
let's go all the way. Naming long
characters. Okay.
Empty row removed matrix.
Okay. So, copy that.
Oh, what?
Copy that back here.
Select. Select. Select. Select. Paste.
Shift. Enter. Fantastic. And beautiful.
Copy that. Copy. Back to Emacs. Paste.
So this is the result.
Okay. So we have clarity each step we
show the result.
Now for the empty row removed
all you have to do is apply
map to it.
What do you want? Map a function of
course. And what you want to do with it
for each
row, you need to map again.
Map. Replace the dot by zero. Then turn
it into a number. Then just sum it.
Okay. Map. Recursive map. Nested map.
Okay. X. So this X is actually row. So
let's why don't we name it so so it's
easier to read. So what you want to map
to each row a function of course what
this function will do
uh this is string. Okay. Now it will
replace string
string replace.
There it is.
Okay. Then for the string, what do you
want to replace by? You want to replace
dot
by
zero.
Okay. Then
so this replace start by zero. Then you
so this is a row. So for the row you
replace start by zero. So you got a
list. Then you two expression
turn them into numbers.
then
then you don't want to sum because you
because you may want to multiply or sum
depending on the operator. Okay,
but let's do this now.
So this will give you a bunch of
numbers. Okay.
Number
matrix
equals to that.
First of all, let's see if it works.
Paste. Shift. Enter. Fantastic. And
beautiful.
Wait.
Oh, you want to remove the dot by empty
string.
This is tricky. Yeah, you don't want you
don't want to by replace by zero. You
want to replace by empty string.
Cut.
Paste. Shift. Enter. Is it fantastic and
beautiful? Yes, it is. 124 355
355. 369
248 and 8 369 248 and 8. Fantastic. And
the rest we don't need to check. Okay.
So this will be one single line number
matrix. Okay. Then we just
Okay. Let's copy the output so we know
so that we have clarity.
Okay. Then all you have to do is apply
the operators
to each of this row.
So the length of operator is equal to
the number of rows. Let's see 1 2 3 4.
So you can see double check
length at x operators
15.
So you need to uh
you need to do the same split
of the operators.
Yeah. Okay. So, you need to like
Okay. Operators equals to. So, actually
we can fix it there.
So, operators equals true and select
select
this thing
by a function.
Now, if
string
uh string equal
wait what so if the string contains dot
uh let's do this okay same Q
we can do is
dot
equal
it'll return true
right because it's the same string so
what we have to do here is that equals
to x
okay delete that so the operators select
we can run it and see if it works
Oh, you uh if it is not equal, so you
want to equal
ban.
Fantastic. 1 2 3 4. You got four
elements. 1 2 3 4 match. Correct.
So let's change this. This equal band
equal is the full name of that operation
is in same Q.
Okay. So just for clarity let's change
it so that you can see
clearly the wolf fully nested syntax.
Do I make sense? Do you see this line
and that line is equivalent? Okay,
this is the syntactic power of Wam
language.
Okay, so when you run this, paste it,
run, you got that.
Copy
and show result here. Okay, so now we
remove that.
Okay, now we got the operators clear.
Now
you want to
map
thread.
What do you want to map to? You want to
map to something to the number matrix
and
the operators. You map what you want to
map to these two lists in parallel.
And what do you want to map to a
function? Of course, always.
And
apply
you want to apply something to X.
Oh, this function needs two parameters X
and Y. So this is X up operators
matching that part and this is uh X num
row uh let's say num list okay fantastic
and clear so you apply the op to the num
list make it one line copy it back to
wam language paste it it and see if I
got it correct. Now wait, the Xnum
matrix, why is it
blue?
Because we forgot to assign it.
Yeah, we forgot to assign it. So, let's
assign it.
Paste.
Shift enter. Now it is no longer blue
because it's got a value. Okay.
So now you run this
paste shift enter.
Incorrect. You got something wrong here.
Uh what?
Oh, because you need to turn that you
this operator is right now a string.
You need to turn that string into plus
or
times function. Okay. So let's make a
modification to our operators here.
Okay. So before so be uh we do that
select uh input string. So that part
this part we change it by
doing a replace.
Okay.
So that
replace all
of this expression
we want to replace a list of things I
mean a list of rules. The first rule is
if it's that turn it into
times.
If it's a plus string, turn it into
plus.
Let's see. Yeah, you need to capital.
Okay, can you see that?
So, this replace all
we'll re we'll replace that and we don't
need the paren. Okay, then then
does that make sense? Am I clear? So
let's try it again.
Fantastic and beautiful
comments of Flamio.
I'm trying to figure it out from the
case with clean data by manually
removing the white space after importing
a SCSV with spaces as delimiter. We'll
figure out how to automate.
Okay. I'm not sure that will work. you
you cannot remove the space I don't
think so
but you know let us know
uh what you find out so operators
so the result of that is this thing each
of the time plus is a uh woofam language
function name okay so delete that okay
now the operators now jump to the this
part copy and let's run it.
Shift enter. Fantastic. And all you do
is now just total
uh
total
at
last output
3263827.
Is that correct? 3263827.
Correct.
Okay,
finally. Now we How long did we take?
Two hours and talking
for five. Wait, three uh when did we
start? So it's like um yeah, two hours
and 20 minutes. Not not too bad. So
anyway,
so copy the result. So copy copy back to
Emac. This this is the final result.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay. So put the code back. Cut it.
Paste.
Paste again. Now this time we're going
to try our personal input. First of all
syntax color the whole buffer showing
browser. So this is our fruit today. We
started wrong description of the
problem. We've
failed to understand it correctly
but we didn't know then we started ago
description which is incorrect
algorithm. Then realization our previous
understanding of the problem is
incorrect because the spaces are
significant.
The new algorithm fantastic in
efficient.
So we consider each input text as
characters
not as space separated list of numbers
as just each single characters. Then we
do transpose and so and and and and so
on. So we got the code correct. Now we
just need to try the personal input.
Okay.
So the personal input. So let's try it.
So go to
uh open last closed copy close. Now
pop the code out. Now this is going to
paste. So this is big and the fantastic
personal input big mega number of lines.
Okay. And we run the whole program. It
should just work. Just run it
in Emacs.
So we got a number there.
This is our new number. Is it correct? I
don't know. So copy it and back to
advant of code idiotic layout because
they do fixed layout.
Okay. Now answer paste.
Submit.
That is the right answer. Yes, of
course.
Fantastic. Solve the problem. Question.
User says, "How do you find writing on a
split keyboard versus a traditional
one?"
That's what kind of question is that?
The basic keyboard question about split
keyboard.
Well, so so split keyboard is better.
Okay. Uh well so okay here's the answer
to that question. If you do not touch
type and if you are young you don't have
any problems with your hand you don't
touch type that much or you don't have
problem with your hand then the
normal computer keyboard is just fine
okay it's fine it works fine but if you
type a lot I don't know if you are a
writer or if you are a coder you join
the startup you happen to type a lot or
you are a gamer You chat all the time or
you are a Twitter keyboard warrior. You
have to correct someone on internet. You
type a lot and you started to notice you
know after a few hours you know your
hand feels weird. That is when you want
to start to look into split keyboard.
Can you see my screen? Uh I mean you can
see my keyboard. Okay. So that is when
you want to look into split keyboard.
When you have when you feel hand
discomfort because big keyboard first of
all you don't have to like put your hand
like that it's like wide shoulder length
then they are tended like you know
instead of flat they are tended so your
wrist is more in a natural position not
like that
you know one of the torture method is
just put your hand like that on the desk
for eight hours the day you'll feel it.
Of course, you are not going to put your
hand just like that eight hours today.
But I did because I'm one of the weird
character. I for 10 years every day I
spend so much time on a flat ergonomic
keyboard. Okay, it's ergonomic. It's
also split but however it's flat. So
that started you have this kind of flat
problem. So that's called ponation.
Wait, is that called ponation? Yes, I
think so. So that's when you want a
tented keyboard like this one, ultimate
hacking keyboard 80. I have a v video
YouTube on YouTube. Okay, watch it
review.
Uh I hope that answered your question
or Flamio says the function's easy but
the input needs its own passer. The
problem says that there is a bigger data
set. That's right. So good luck. keyword
equals to enroll. Good luck or flamio.
Uh, and we finished our problem today.
Fantastic. I got a gold star. Thank you
very much.
Uh, so I'm done.
Okay. So, okay. So, I'm done. And, uh,
well, I I could take five more minutes
to compact the code because right now
you see the code. I can do it in five
minutes. Um,
you know, I can make the code into one
line. Should I do it?
Let's do it. Okay. I I feel like I, you
know, I have time. So, copy
and let's make the code into one single
line.
That is the
paste. Pop it out. Remove the comments.
I don't need all the comments anymore.
And remove and remove all. Okay. Okay.
Remove all the comments except the
answer. Okay.
Okay. Now let's start to uh like
make this whole compact. Uh
you know first of all each of the
variable is like used once. If it's used
once, you don't need it separately.
You see, uh for example, this matrix,
this uh input matrix.
So this matrix is used only once. Cut
it, paste it there. Okay? So you don't
need that. and split matrix is also used
once. So,
so if you started to compact all this
into then it becomes less readable.
Okay. You don't need that anymore. Then
this empty.
Yeah. Okay. I'm not doing this is not
the right way to shorten the code. I
mean if you are you know it's not the
right way because
because if you do that way you can make
the whole thing into one line you just
but however it becomes unreadable okay
uh for example remove that and uh the
operators you don't even need operators
the operators you know you can also
cut
it just that okay don't need that and uh
then you got now you got two. What about
this one? Uh this one is also used.
Okay. So you can cut
and
paste that there. So it becomes this
rather unreadable.
And
so you got only input the input. You see
this
input matrix string matrix or actually
there's uh more so but anyway this
variable is used three times I mean two
times okay you can remove it
by of course by pasting this code into
two of those places but that would be
inefficient because you are doing
computation twice. So what you can do is
better is to create a local variable.
Okay. So what you do is width okay then
cut then you are
creating a local variable there okay
then this whole thing
cut is the expression okay cut can it
work yes I'm pretty sure run it
you see 326 3827
correct Okay. And then so with now this
you can you know this is still
unreadable. Okay. So but um uh but the
input is used only once. So you can put
the input here you know it's only used
once. But if you paste this in wam
language
um
actually this is not too bad because in
real life I I used to code a lot like
this. The way to understand
this kind of code is that you you must
um know functional programming well. So
you focus on the function. So for
example you can see this structured this
is just total total of this expression
you see it's very structured then what
is this expression map f it just take
two arguments so the first argument is a
function there
okay and what does the function do
simple it takes two arguments and just
apply the operators to the list of
numbers very simple Okay, map thread.
Then
what what is the thing that you want to
map to? That's this one. Okay, now
because it's map thread of function of
two elements, then you know this whole
part is a list of two things. So the
first thing is a list. That's the first
list. This is the second list. Okay. Now
what what is the first list? Well, you
select. Select takes a list and a
function. You see then you see this list
you generate
that basically that's a operators.
You select from the input string the
last row of the input string which is a
bunch of plus or multiplication sign
string. Then you replace the
multiplication by times or the plus
string by plus. So they became wam
language function symbols times and
plus. Then
you select um then you know if if if
in this last input they got a bunch of
like dot you want to remove them. So if
it's it's um
if it's a dot remove it you know. So
only if it's not a dot keep it. So
basically you just have list of plus and
times. So that's the first list list of
operators
which is uh you can see which is this
you see first and times. Then the second
list is again you dive into you know you
map a function you
map takes two argument. The first one is
a function. The second one is a list. So
this is a list. So that's how you take
it apart. So this code is actually not
too bad. So let me copy that. So because
in Wufam notebook it formats it, but my
wam
uh woofam mode for Emacs does not format
it. So if you paste the formatted code,
you can kind of see
it's it's better. Okay. So let's just
delete that. Okay, let's just um input
delete and paste that there. So run it
seal works. Yes, of course. Okay, put it
back. Syntax color everything show in
browser. So that's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching. That's uh kind of
fun two hours and uh I'm lucky because
I'm energetic because when I'm tired uh
this is not going to be done. Okay, we
got an error error. This pre um
preclass
undo
undo.
Okay. So,
redo
refresh. Okay, that's fixed.
Okay, showing browser. Yes, it's valid
HTML. Good. Bye, guys.
User, thank you for the stream. Thank
you for watching.
next line of input and see if it works.
Wait for next line of input. What do you
mean?
Okay, bye guys.
Fantastic.