good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is 2019
November 17th
Sunday 1 o clock in the afternoon San
Francisco time morning but good morning
hello beautiful people and today we
don't have a topic but let me show you
Emily's watch we're gonna talk about
random stuff but I'm thinking I'm going
to do some JavaScript coding unless you
guys have some topics so if you have a
topic type in the chat box good morning
Emily
so Emily the master nerd she's got she's
we you know we were talking about
watches and she's saying she's got her
phone number system and her own writing
system but anyway so she is using a 6
based numbering system she likes it you
know she she use it that so Emily if you
have any information you know just put
in a chat so emily is using 6 spaced
numbering system and what's the name of
that and oh my god she's got this 6
based number in notation you know I was
whining wondering about what that is you
can see that this is her notes now is
this just number so is this kind of also
a writing system I mean if it's just
numbers I mean why do you have to write
so many numbers wait
yeah so there and so we were talking
about watches and so Emily started to
tell us about
her system oh my god what is this she's
got copiers notes about the system in
emacs org-mode grave structure grave
structure and design goes okay em script
Emily's script an efficient regular
writing system oh my god
design goes efficient to read continuous
forward hand movement
this means no loops that require the
hand to swap directional movement
so wait continuous forward hand movement
so this means no loops that require the
hand to swap direction of the movement
what do you mean you mean that the
strokes like no no loops like a like
going backwards yeah I think that's what
she means so we are ensure the fastest
transfer from mind to paper in the
simple regular shapes our shapes are
based off a pattern to create a simple
set of graphs that can be easily
constructed and read ok efficient to
write simple regular shapes of the
shapes can be interest inter interpreted
by pattern recognition such that a word
becomes its shape instead of its
collection of characters ok greif
structure so this is what it looks like
I guess ok graph structure each graph
consists of two or three for some cases
straight lines arranged aligning to a
3x3 grid ok imagine you have okay so
anyway this is her system
and okay this is his writing system
let's see okay let's see some yeah some
some orthography or something like that
let's see so this is okay
ABC okay oh my god mm script
Emily's writing system true nerds nerd
and she also created created a font oh
wow
she also created a fund OTF what what is
the format of that font ODF okay so
that's Emily's system if you have a
question ask Emily so good morning good
morning I already typed the topic
sohbats the parts topic is about
abstract syntax tree well I don't know
anything about that topic so yeah I
don't really know that topic because to
know that topic you have to know
compilers but anyway Emily's writing
system she's got I mean well she's got
the numbering system 2 & 6 based system
it's got a name but I don't mean I
didn't know there's a name for number 4
6 based numbering system she mentioned
it code okay and this picture let's show
this picture because because this is the
picture we talked about about last week
or so 10 days ago her you know her
keyboard and setup and she's you know
she is telling us that this you know on
the side here is her time system so she
is using you know the six based
numbering system to count
time so you can see there are six
sections and now it's like okay you have
to translate it so let's see one two
okay let me turn off the auto click so
one so here is one two three four four
times to wait six times 24
so he's so one two three four four times
four is 16 so it's about 16 o clock 16 o
clock is like 4 o'clock in the afternoon
then 1/6 of an hour
I mean her system so one-sixth of an
hour in her system will be how is it
like 20 minutes or something so anyway
so that's you know that's what she is
doing very interesting
ok so close that well actually so let me
write down
today's topic and put it there it's not
Hawk show for today
and oh I didn't start my Firefox yet so
I don't have a topic yet so type of
topic or whatever whatever you guys are
interested you know just type in the
chat so let me put this down here did I
miss anything interesting Emily so her
writing system this is amazing her own
writing system you know in in history
there are quite a few guys you know
nerds they have created their own
writing system you know and some of them
many of the famous scientists or
mathematicians they've done that too for
example for example let's keep it there
so you know we can show that later so so
ok I put this in my blog Emily in my
blog your notes and pictures I think it
would be fun I think maybe I put it in
in the page where you discuss your stuff
so so the writing system I made okay so
there are topic you don't know yeah of
course scenery okay so
the six spaced numbering system is
called scenery so let's look at that
okay scenery numbering system you know I
heard I heard that six space system has
many advantages actually I think it's
what yeah six I think so you know it's
it is possible you know if you are
really progressive then you want to
throw out the system we are using like
the decimal system like the weight out
engines just use the note six space
system now so I heard you know I haven't
read this into detail about the system
but I heard you know it's better because
it's got more the visibility things like
that you know the reasons that it is
good so but so but you know the thing is
you cannot just throw away because just
like programming backward compatibility
so we are stuck with decimal system I
think I heard duodecimal anyway so
superior higher composite number okay
six six is a superior higher composite
number anyway let's put this in the page
so you can so I can read it later and
and you guys can go read it
the scenery number ecosystem it's
pronounced scenery right not scenery yes
in re okay scenery numerical system also
base six hexam oh six some oh okay six
mo is a better name because because it
says sex well you know yeah the scenery
like what the is scenery you know
but you if you say sex Simona and people
understand what it means or even hexam
oh you know we are screwed with our
Latin and you know the English roots so
you have pie and you have die
you have you know one space from Greek
and one is based from Latin or Rome or
something like that so we have and to
this day like September like okay like
six six September October
you know October is the tenth month but
art means eight so we are pretty screwed
with all this you know the historical
naming but you know we cannot just
simply change it because backward
compatibility compatibility just like
the eunuchs
okay so hex also so you got this new
numbering system and and also remember
our is twelve paste and that is
also historical and I think it's crap
you know so but we cannot simply change
it to decimal based system so anyway
let's see what she says okay
I explained them in this course so she
explained them in this code so so
there's a lot here you can see example
of it you know yeah I saw that I was
going to ask you you know so those notes
those cryptic notes and I was thinking
you are doing some you know those are it
always very interesting because okay so
your writing system so if you know it's
kind of based on you know as far as the
the character goes it's kind of based on
combinatorics yeah right more or less
you know because you have different
positions and you you move them your PIN
to these positions but I think I think
there is a practical problem okay if if
I may say so you know because if you are
going to write this in practice you
cannot do it because it will be because
because this system
now I'm okay I'm going to criticize I'm
going to be the armchair philosopher
okay because this system if you write it
you know it's very logical but but it's
it's like the characters looks or the
same you know like some length you know
you may maybe they they differ by
changing of length so if you write this
especially in a script fashion its
eligible that's what I think
yeah right
what do you think about that okay let's
see what else here so anyway so here is
her watch and this is so cute this watch
she programmed it and it's digital so
she you know she likes the six-way
system so she has this okay so if I if
I'm going to look at this watch you know
so six space system so if you want to
translate it translate it to twelve
based system then you multiply by four
so this would be weight is your six
twelve our hour of 24-hour Emily
so use your six like equal to 12 hour
half a day of 24 hours six jism oh yeah
that's sick sea based system so let's
read let me read the comments base 12
prime decomposition for hours so she
says 24 hours let's pop the chat out so
I can see
okay so and let's magnify it a bit and
let's go back so so this is 24-hour
paste you know over a circle so if it
says so right now it says three four
okay so it says four four times four is
four times four is 16 so it's 16 o'clock
so it's 6 16 o'clock which is 4 o'clock
p.m. yeah so you know take some used to
to you know read this system and this is
Fitbit this is a digital you know she
programmed it so ok what else let's see
my number system time system and writing
system and and yeah is you know she
created entire writing system and she
has notes to you actually so do you
write the in this your system every day
in this chord
I remember you crossed it out as if you
know maybe you don't use it anymore or
something do you still use it every day
she is crazy
you know she's guys we have a crazy girl
here and you know so and she open ok so
I actually use the line on paper to
discern characters use the line on paper
to decent characters ok
yeah Korean handle combination of
characters pretty well and I really say
so you can easily see if a line starts
above or below a line okay or at least I
think so in 24 hours I do use it every
day Wow I cross eight hours I should
have been eating dinner okay
so okay that's very interesting and this
this is beautiful this is cute okay what
what else good morning George
okay so you know I you know I am also
interested in watch you know somewhat
what you know so there is this watch I
find it quite amazing this yes watch so
let's go
yes watch okay let's go through their
website open in brave okay and you know
I find this watch interesting because
it's 24 hour based watch but the gist of
it is that you can show you error
okay reload the gist of that you see you
see this you know this is digital and
also analog you look at the background
you see part of a stock part of it is
right so this this whole circle is 24
hours so you can see at a glance you
know how many daylight how much data it
remains on to your dog so that the whole
thing is full day 24 hours yeah but the
reason I mean the the the gist you know
I've been you know I so I'm a nerd so I
look at these things you know I I want
to find what's the most what's the best
system you know I didn't I didn't go
crazy like the Emily's six you know the
six based system but anyway I thought
the 24 hour clock is interesting because
because in immigrants you can see how
much daylight remains and so I really
wanted to have that kind of $445 they
are so that's one of the interesting
watch you know yes yes watch and then
there is this watch this watch this
watch is cycroid say the Cossack rose
watch
you know these these fancy watches are
expensive like either a few hundred
dollars or a few thousand dollars
I think the cycloid watch is few
thousand dollars over a thousand dollars
you know watches is a thing it's a thing
for nuts but it's also a thing for
society too it's a jewelry basically
it's a piece of jewelry to show your
status so you have many expensive
watches but it's also fascinating
because they are mechanical you know
usually you know the mechanical watches
are you know expensive and interesting
because you can see the mechanic
mechanical things has certain intrinsic
abstraction because they are technology
such that you can see kind of as opposed
to digital
you know electronics where everything
you don't see nothing okay so but but
this side cyclos watch is interesting
you see the hour hand the hour hand will
grow will shorten or lengthen as it
rotates so when it is you know the first
12 hours you'll stay inside the circle
this circle but at night it will grow
into the outer circle something like
that so that's psychos watch you know
they they wrote to me about 15 years ago
that's how I know it because let's let's
check out their website to see if how
they are doing if they are cyclo swatch
okay so let's go let's check their
website opening brave and there is
another link another link okay opening
brave
so turn on JavaScript
we fish English and Dutch okay they are
based in touch you know so okay so they
are still going well I guess this is
flash you know they this means their
website is not so active because you
know they are still using flash which
has been obsolete for a few years now so
cyclos watch you know I think actually
very few people buy these watches use
you know you 24 hour duo face watch okay
team contact so they wrote to me because
it has to do with you know math curve
okay let me show you that why this is
interesting you know when when it comes
to mechanical stuff then you have lots
of interesting math going on as opposed
to digital you know digital yeah there's
a lot math too but it becomes or it
becomes or just signal processing you
know whereas when you have mechanical
things such as mechanical watch such as
this one where you want to make the
hour-hand
grow or shrink then you you need
mechanisms to to do that any order to do
that you need to know you know these
kind of mass curves linkages so I don't
remember which curve they were emailing
about that about I forgot but anyway
this let's go look at their website I
think he's so broken refresh yeah this
so it's broken so this means they are
not that active anymore usually
so anyway that's about the cyclo swatch
and okay in 24-hour crock watch and
there's another thing that's interesting
that is I wanted to know you know so if
you have a what 24-hour watch where the
dial runs from 0 to 23 you know then you
have a question you have a question
about okay living close then you have
the question whether the zero should
start at the top or at the bottom so
here are some examples of 24-hour watch
let me show it in him brave because I
need JavaScript you cannot show okay so
sorry dot info sorry and our info in
brave you cannot toggle the JavaScript
if it is a local file so let's go to my
website so you have this wait wait is
where is my croc Oh turn on JavaScript
so I wrote a JavaScript you know to show
24 hour clock so should the 0 begin at
the bottom mode or the top so I did a
survey you know I go look you know I
looked around apparently if it's a watch
you wear on your hand typically they the
zero start at the bottom but if it's a
croc then the zero begins at the top
usually that's the case that's what I
found so that's a you know that's kind
of interesting questions if you were to
design a watch and you know shoot the
zero begin at the bottom or the top and
that question is hard to so Emily says
zero is at the top so so you prefer that
right you you think it should be on the
top let's see
and see her watch yeah okay zero
well well yo Kroc started top that makes
sense because well it's see me it's it's
six okay anyway so yeah you started top
so let's see well it would make sense
for 0 to be at the bottom such as
daytime he's at the top of the tire such
that daytime is at the top of the dial
yeah that that's the reason I found it
to be strange if the gap was at the
bottom the gap okay yeah yeah so anyway
so this I think there is no right answer
to the question because you want you
know the reason you want to start at
bottom so that the daylight appears on
the top you know it's it's more
intuitive but but on the other hand
traditionally you know they are the zero
start at the top so so you have a
conflict you kind of you know you got a
problem and also it's no good where it's
no good if you have a clock that does
one thing then watches does another so
it's a problem but anyway in real life
nobody you know nobody's gonna nobody's
going to like 24 hours watch you know
that that's that's just for nerds nerds
thing okay that's a that's a that's
about watches I think that's so let's
see what else are interesting I don't
have one I host my own get instance that
doesn't run a web GUI right so you beat
yourself to be nerdy I figure so what
what else so how long have I been
talking should we should we do some
JavaScript or we only talked for
we'll have an hour but we can't we can
stop and that'll be it for today or you
know because you know I've been doing
too long for each video so so let me
read the comments then
stenography okay so I'm interested in
making a watch face sonography that's a
interesting thing we can talk about so
George says I'm interested in making a
watch face that's twelve hours between
sunrise and sunset like most scientific
see like most ancient civilizations oh
okay so you want 12 hours for the whole
day right that's I think that's what you
sing so it's like 24-hour clock but with
only 12 hour markings you know so it's
like today's watch except it doesn't run
twice it the needles doesn't run twice
yeah that that that yeah that makes
sense that's good so the purple hand
exactly how far through the day I am the
purple hand
oh okay so she's got
okay so how do you so you got three
hands so this is the hour hand obviously
and that is the that is the minute hand
so have you seen those new ago docks
inspired keyboards that are based
entirely on chords yes I have and emily
is doing that exactly she's got you know
she's doing that I think they also
releases released a stenography speed
board
it's called Coco okay oh my god I'm
gonna do a land on that I don't like
that
gogo okay so you know actually I talked
about that in in a video before so let's
try let's see gogo keyboard
Google keyboard oh my god is Google
keyboard keyboard heavy industries okay
let's have a look
gogo keyboard so okay yeah so let's just
talk about this and that'll be it today
okay so this this is actually this is
actually the one like Emily posted her
photo and I think it looks like that he
said is that what you're doing or you
were doing your own yes by G board
industries okay yeah okay so she is
doing that oh yeah yeah that's
interesting I didn't know about this
keyboard okay
no yeah I didn't know about this one so
apparently this keyboard is designed to
be used as a steno machine you know
they're like using prova I and I and my
opinion of that is crap okay I think
it's a worst possible you use this
you type it for two hours a day and by
next month you are going to see your
doctor okay anyway so okay but this this
is very interesting I'm going to write a
blog about it yeah but let me give you
my reasons why I think it's no good okay
III don't think it's good but you know
since I I saw your you were doing that
Emily so I thought about whether whether
it's really no good or you know I you
know it's just I don't like it so here's
the thing okay so let me go into I'm
going to explain why don't I don't why I
think it's no good but you know and you
know but you know maybe depends on
perspectives okay so let me let me do
that but let me finish reading the
comments
my work for me would probably tank 2-0
okay more of the novelty okay so for
sure
the Emily says that gog is specifically
for steno and you shouldn't really use
it for no more okay so just stick with
the more standard travel keyboard okay
for me zero at the top okay so and would
be divided by three okay so what we saw
Suffolk like to get here and what is
skeet here
I forgot what is skeet here god I need
to magnify the font
so we're gonna finish talking about this
and that that they'll be here today
maybe 10 more minutes ki jiye is very
resource friendly I write on my
raspberry so what is ghiggia so past
Bart says Emily is pretty fast I think
that makes a bit so for my 15 years old
HDD so I stole my repositories yep ki
jiye is really resource effective
javascript would be nice okay so I guess
today no JavaScript today we're gonna
yeah we can you know plenty of day to do
JavaScript so Amy says I'll have a look
at okay so the longest hand is the hour
hand
okay the ways
oh the longest hand is the hour hand
okay now I'm all confused the longest
hand is the hour hand okay in a watch
face I want to be your daylight would be
divided between 12 hours okay right
smaller stenography one by the same guy
okay and okay let me let me let me give
you my reasons this is crap okay this
yeah my you know my opinion over this is
crap so so so you know you have so let
me you know talk to the general audience
because many people don't know what the
heck is they know so stay no sane steno
is a input system you know input system
device it looks like that and they are
some you know it looks pretty much like
that there is no one standard so okay so
and country let me show the videos so
let's type it here
what is this page keyboard blog let's go
here paste it and showing from showing
brave and no JavaScript okay let's just
go to sorry
keyboard
[Laughter]
snotty keyboard so stay no so you got
the steno steno is the input system okay
it looks like that there is really no
standard but pretty much all the steno
machines look similar to that and they
are extremely expensive like if you want
to buy it it costs you like a thousand
or two thousand dollars something like
that because why because there's no
market the market is very small it's it
was used to be used by court crooks you
know in court like law suit in court
what they they need to record everything
the witness said or things like that but
this technology I mean this need is
going away because today you have voice
recognition you know the machine just
record everything you you know he the
machine recorded and transcribed into
English or French or whatever so but
before you know 20 20 years ago you have
clerks typing in real-time using this
system this is this is steno type
machine so it's very expensive like
1,000 or 2,000 dollars and you can see
there are some YouTube videos they show
you how to use it how to they teach it
they teach you how to type on it and
they teach you the system how it works
basically you know they teach you how it
works
hold on a second I mean just stop that
okay so this system is very fast you
know like on a computer keyboard you can
type you know hundred watt per minute
but on a stenograph if you learn it you
spend a month or two few months to learn
it you can type typically above 200 watt
per minute so it's twice or three times
faster than typing on keyboard and the
reason it's so fast because two things
okay one it's code paste
yeah for tweeze two reasons well the
first reason is because it's phonetic
you don't actually type letters one by
one like we're okay where wher e-you
know that you know you type wher e five
five keystrokes but on a phonetic system
where where where is like two phonemes
so you just type two keystrokes
something like that okay it's a phonetic
based system that's half the reason this
is you know two or three times faster
than normal typing the other reason it's
called based system so instead of typing
one key at a time in sequence like we
usually do it on this keyboard it's like
a piano
you press multiple keys at once so why
is that faster because when you press
more of well yeah because you are
pressing motor-pod keys at one time so
each time you press one keystroke on a
normal keyboard you can press several
keys so essentially becomes parallel
someone so because these two reasons
code base system and phonetic system
combined it's typically two or three
times faster to type you know two for
input and of course you have to learn it
takes more time to learn yeah you know
the two months or three months you know
more time than typical keyboard to touch
type so that's the note system now so so
it's very fast and it's it's very good
now there are similar other systems like
that based on piano for example there is
this this mishra coded keyboard this
system you know if you look at history
so apparently you know you look at
history of inputs so they are quite a
lot systems out there we don't know
because you know we usually you are not
interested but even even if you are not
you are interested you don't come across
it
unless you actually actively try to
research it then you found you know a
lot systems you know that exist in
history and some of it still used today
in this one Michelet coded keyboard I
think it's still used today so they they
have a complete system you know invented
by this mission a guy like 200 years ago
I think it's still used in France in
court so you know you can learn that
again just like the stenograph system
it's very fast okay it's very fast for
two reasons one its code so it's
parallel you know it's code and also the
other reason it's phonetic so you don't
type each individual letter you type the
phonemes so it's very fast so anyway so
so I saw him so that's another system
and there is another system modern piano
system
this is created about four five years
ago in 2016 also yeah 2005 2015 also she
this is by a researcher who studies
input systems she is in Western Europe I
forgot we're not Scandinavia somewhere
as you know there so she created a
entire new piano based system and you
can go read her you know read the food
detail she's got PDF and all that and in
fact if you you can actually buy a MIDI
keyboard and you know use that so I
looked into this system so so what so so
so so I'm showing you several systems
they are all based on code and all based
on phonetics now it's not necessarily so
that they based on phonetic phonetics
they can you know you can make each key
on a piano to be a letter if you want to
you know but anyway a phonetic system is
usually bad faster much faster so there
is a similarity between all these three
three that is they are all code based
and they are all phonetic okay
that is why they are extremely efficient
and I love them okay I would I would
love them okay so but so so what about
what about this you know this
okay this Google or let me show you
another thing okay so let me show you
another thing let's go to PC keyboards
then let's go - lets go - Do It Yourself
keyboards let's yeah okay then let's go
to this prank keyboard the worst
possible from the program you know from
the keyboard nerds this is the worst
keyboard possible on earth well I'm not
sure it's worth then happy hacking or
not sorry guys anyway so so you have
this blank keyboard it's a
do-it-yourself keyboard a lot nerds like
it okay you gotta read it our mechanical
keyboard or you know some of the
keyboard forums a lot of people will
love this but anyway there is this lady
this woman okay she the that this is her
she's typing in real-time she is using
the plank and let me let me explain
what's she doing she's you know her
score is like 174 word per minute
she is a stenographer okay she's a
stenographer so professional
stenographer you know she she used this
stenograph but she got a problem because
stenograph you know you can't fight it
you got to buy these machines two
thousand dollars so she got idea why
don't we make you know the traditional
computer keyboard to do stenograph so
that way you don't have to you know
subject yourself to this expensive niche
market you spent two thousand dollars
for you know four
you know you shouldn't be that expensive
so she created a system called prova
okay she created a system called plover
let me explain it let me see if I have
some explanation somewhere okay so so
anyway she created this plover system
which is designed to use the stenograph
you know phonetic system on a normal
computer keyboard so you type codes on
this keyboard or any any any mechanical
keyboard one requirement that is you
need n key Yoruba meaning you need the
keyboard meet needs to be able to accept
multiple key presses at the same time
same time so anyway she invented the
prober system which allows you to use
the say nose Sinha graph typing system
on the standard mechanical keyboard and
so so this circle this google apparently
is created for this purpose I didn't
know this before and here today so you
know so so you type what you type key
codes you know you use this keyboard
keyboard like a Sinha graph but in my
opinion this is crap okay this is
this is no good this is no good at all
you use this for you know you use this
seriously for two hours a day typing
continuously you cannot get the problems
okay that's that it's my opinion but I I
think I will amend to that opinion a
little bit yielding to Emily and and
other people you know I know other nurse
who who you know we were friends you we
follow each other because they are also
experts in this another guy who is
expert in in keyboards and he's also
doing in steno okay so anyway why why do
I think it's crap because if you study
this steno keyboard or piano system
you notice that these are physical
devices now look at this this this is
actual physical device it is designed so
that you it's designed now that's a
keyword it's designed for you to press
motor keys at the same time you see each
key on this keyboard is is five times
larger than the area of a you know
computer keyboard that's a big
difference okay so this is designed for
multiple key presses same thing with
piano okay you know they are designed so
that physically if it's you know it so
you can do that you know it's like it's
designed for it but but but the the the
computer keyboard is not such a thing
it's not designed like to do that so for
example why for example it's easy its
trivial to press multiple keys on this
steno keyboard same thing with piano
okay the same thing with piano keys you
know they they have different shapes but
however they are all designed so that
you can for example on piano you know I
play piano and so so does Emily they are
designed to press multiple keys and for
the steno you can see sometimes it's
required to press both of these photo of
vertical keys together and you have this
thumb draw so it's designed for your
hands to press multiple keys not so not
so with this you know computer
keyboards that's not designed for that
and not just the size of the keys there
are multiple aspects size of a key the
arrangement of the key you know so so
the computer keyboards not just for it
so when you so when this lady okay with
my respect no she is thinking let's
let's put steno on the normal you know
computer keyboards yeah that's a great
idea but that but if but if you I think
if you take deep dive into detail is
crap you see it's a it's like it's
creating a abomination okay it's
actually going suit
create problems it creates more problems
than then the in swath that's my opinion
so that is my reason my reason is you
know you have to because we are talking
about typing machines these are hardware
devices you design the machine to you
know you have to design the machine you
don't just you know let's say you don't
just oh let's use you know this use the
ships shape for spaceships you know like
you know you have warships you know you
have you know let's let's design space
spaceships in the shape of our ocean
ships you know that's idiotic that would
be completely do attic so my opinion my
reason is the same way you don't you
know yeah you can do that but you don't
it's not good so that is my opinion but
you know as I was thinking so so let me
read the comments then then that'll be
it for today so but then I'm thinking
maybe I'm too extreme okay so so I kind
of try to you know I try to look at the
other way so so what if I mean so you
know I'm so but wouldn't it be at least
this improvement somehow you know for
example I'm using for example my my
keyboard is this Kinesis right so you
know suppose let's just say that okay so
so no more people average people you use
keyboard at but it's very slow but
wouldn't it be great if you just you
know why not if you can type stand on it
and you will increase your speed by two
times at least why not
it's not so bad an idea right and most
for most people that will walk because
you don't nobody actually type two hours
continuously a day although most
programmers like to think they do but
even I you know when you log your
keystrokes I found out if I type
continuously it's just going to be one
hour a day and and that's when I'm
typing
the most you know I know i typed far
more than most programmers so for
average programmers if you log your
keystrokes and you compute and suppose
you only type 50 words per minute then
you compute then it turns out for most
promise you your whole days typing can
be done in five minutes
in ten minutes if you type continuously
okay so that's a fact most people nobody
actually typed continuously for two
hours a day maybe once a day you
sub-average you'd you don't so if that's
the case why not you know what you know
it doesn't you know you you could just
use this you know no more keyboard and
and you know types 1000 it's it's yeah
that's what I think so that's my that's
my you know that my alternative
adjustment to my view but I wouldn't do
this I think it's crap you know because
I don't you know I do the reason I don't
like it because I don't like hacks I
don't like I don't want any hack you
know I'm like other nerds I look for
efficiency I want the most extreme
efficiency the best design I want the
most elegance but then to me if you're
gonna do stand on this that's hack
that's that's a big major hack you don't
you don't don't do that
you know if you really want to go speed
you know with efficiency and efficacy
you go you get a piano keyboard you can
buy today like that you buy one of these
then you design your system using that
that I would love okay so then that I
wouldn't get reverse if you know so so
that's that's what I think about that
yeah so what else yeah you know oh this
Mishra system I think those are very
interesting oh yeah the other thing I
want to mention is that so once you know
I I studied this moseyed I looked at
them I thought oh my god you know so why
don't we
you know we really actually we should
have a system you know we should in
entirely face out the computer keyboard
like that actually in my opinion I think
you know I started to think it is it is
actually my opinion that we should
actually have a computer keyboard like a
piano this is optimal okay this is truly
optimal so we should you know because we
are nerds we are talking about Commack
was a small rack right you know or Emacs
keybinding so if we go in that direction
then then really you know I'm using you
know for example I'm using this keyboard
I showed I showed many times you know
with my camera so so why don't we go to
the next level and in fact this is no
good okay if you really look into detail
this is no good no good you really
should have this okay you know you just
go by this okay this is like piano
digital MIDI keyboards are very cheap on
Amazon this is like hundred dollars just
Kinesis like three hundred dollars so
you buy one of these MIDI keyboard then
you learn one of these piano systems
either the Mishra or or the the steno or
the other one the piano key okay I god I
already closed that window the other one
let me show you here piano key
okay this designed by this woman you
know modern then yeah so if you truly
want
you know better systems really I think
this is the way to go then I start to
things started to think you know you
know today you have a lot Kickstarter's
right you have some a new idea you go to
Kickstarter's and you create a new
keyboard and give up buy it like like
like this one you know like this go go
but as I started to think so I'm going
to spend two years to create a
commercial system like you know the
piano based the most
vision you can type twice as fast and
easy to learn something like that easier
in fact she she researched if you learn
this piano system it takes less time to
learn then touch typing okay so if I'm
going to create that and put on
Kickstarter what what will happen then I
realized nobody will buy it because of
habit because you know it's just going
to go nowhere you know that's a sad fact
of society you know just just just like
even even like the Canisius nobody you
know he's going to buy it
he except a few of us you know me Emily
you know Emily's going for the moat romp
and you know a few of us will buy these
aqueducts or this go go maybe few you
know when when in ten thousand people
maybe so that is a problem you know most
so as a society we have the problem of
habit and problem of convention and
backward compatibility I think that's it
for today so I'm gonna read some
comments and I'll be it so if you have
some comments so some other opinions
that post it now and we talked about
that and we shoulda maybe five more
minutes so let's see comments so zoom a
good lord I can't imagine how long it
would take to get fast on that thing the
piano thing
according to her research is actually
easier to become efficient than touch
typing that is true I believe it because
you know I you I I'm a juggler you know
I also write unicycle when I was younger
so if I juggle five balls you know I can
show you you know a juggle five balls
and most to most people
if you see people write unicycles most
people will think well wow that's so
amazing it's impossible you know how can
you do that but actually writing
unicycle is very
see and you know you take one month then
you are new or know how to do it it's
not difficult at all so the the point I
want to say is that usually you know we
have no idea how something is difficult
until you actually learn it for example
writing you know have you try try write
with your left hand okay try to write
with your left hand you will find it to
be impossible okay why because you've
been you you been practicing writing for
years you know literally ten ten ten
years when you are in school you
practice every day it's so it is in fact
a very difficult thing to do
you know to write fluently and you know
you just try it with your left hand to
see how long it takes you to learn you
know it's tremendously difficult so in
the same way you know we might think oh
you're gonna you know this piano system
oh my god that's impossible that's
difficult but actually it may not be so
easy it's in fact easier than touch
typing so that's the thing so hello
beautiful people says according to Mira
by night yeah that's a that's a woman
who designed plover stay no typos okay
the school for sonography is many many
years long two or three or four if I
remember correctly and most of the
people are not able to reach 225 word
per minute Oh as he requires speed -
okay - 25 word per minute is required to
be certified as a stenographer okay
she is also proponent of programming
using steno okay yeah yeah he hugging
here oh isn't that bad so I don't think
phonetic system would be good for
programming phonetic yeah
the problem with phonetic system is that
first of all English lang
which is not very phonetic okay because
you got lots of variations in spelling
and things like that you you don't act
you know English like the Latin alphabet
is not a phonetic alphabet it's not you
know in linguistics they call that
alphabet principle meaning that if you
have a language where the pronunciation
corresponds to how things are spelled
hundred percent that's called alphabetic
principle like Spanish is more much more
than English English is not so much a
large bank the artificial language is
hundred percent you know correspondence
even down to punctuation in lowest round
you pronounce the pronunciations so
anyway so so phonetic system then when
you do programming with you know which
includes parentheses and punctuation so
that's that's not part of phonetic so
but if you actually use these kind of
systems of course you have to it's not
pure purely phonetic because you also
need to type punctuation so I think they
they do have ways you know to type I
think you know I think so I mean even if
not it's not difficult to create them so
anyway so my god try to vote 40% and
didn't last more than a day so say no
works with the dictionary in background
so you can just set a key code to put
some program in test yeah yeah so like
you could could you know so actually so
you know I object to the idea using
using a normal keyboard for the prover
system because you know because the very
idea is a hack but I think partly I
object so much because of nuts because
it's a pop you know it's a pop nerd
thing it's a gig you know it's just
it's not truly good you know the truly
good the true not we or if you do this
okay if you sir some of you if you do
this then I will like it much better the
piano system but strong language about
boards with buttons good morning Alan
okay so what else
Wow there's more comments okay so
I think that's about it for today but
let me finish the comments the piano is
more efficient but it would be seriously
heard the Ries after a while yeah I
thought about that because the piano you
don't have tanking so today's economic
keyboards you have tenting so you this
is more natural the piano keyboard will
be like that but you can always you know
you can always be creative for example
if you actually if you actually adopt a
piano system you could have for example
you also have you could have thinking
you know you just killed it you know you
know so that's not inch in intrinsic
problem that's not a problem that you
cannot overcome
unique Sarko why not EEG keyboard and
also in when it comes to input you know
today as technology progresses you have
you know we have voice systems which for
common speech is actually quite more
efficient you know faster you know you
and you don't have to learn just like
like I noticed in my youtube they
actually today compared to as opposed to
ten years ago today all the captions
come out correctly less even I don't you
know I don't have no I don't have the
best english pronunciation but all the
captions just come out fine so at least
for normal you know everyday speech you
know the speech system beats or these
infant and that is true the speech
system is you know his is making the
stay no absolute in court mostly my
apparently me by unicycle in learn to
ride is not so bad so yes sighs mumbling
many transhumanist thoughts today now
that is endgame so how is much how how
am i doing transhumanist I don't see the
connection now that's in game efficiency
oh yeah engine happy is the enemy why
not be right out for a fee we we wire
for efficiency beep I always said I
would love to set to get a USB port as a
sidewalk enhancement y'all connect to
your brain the computer directly
into your brain yeah that'd be nice
adapter that is ok so but like the
information output of human body is so
limited that's so true wait why did it
jump
where was I this common system
likes trained to read the comments need
to magnify so stream players like
guitarist often retune their instrument
to be more efficient for certain type of
play oh okay
Louis bong I I've learned that oh my god
you have learned that too oh my god
Emily I've been outdated my frenemy are
learning is slowly okay I can help
okay I think that's it for today so
today your own writing system sorry what
Emily think we are you start the next
stream with I I don't know if she's got
she is my she's a source of my my
information
she's got a lot keyboard stuff I'm
pretty sure we you see that
good morning Kathy you maximizing us how
to use but it's nothing compared to even
entry-level piano playing so did I miss
anything according to okay so yeah so
thank you guys for watching that's it
for today bye
so Joy's discord if you have not already
okay so discord let me type the key let
me type the code okay you invite people
30 new 39 more messages well so hi guys
I spelled it wrong
one hour and 10 minutes