good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is 2019
December 22nd sunday 6 o clock p.m. San
Francisco time hello guys and we are
going to talk about technical topics
today lots of technical topics on
programming on in Linux or sync so let's
begin so this is gonna be I think I hope
it's gonna be a tense talk so you go to
the YouTube description and you can find
a link and then you can see my you can
see my wait am I going yes so there's
this so let's see what are people saying
so we're gonna talk about technical
topics today and and morning guys Pedro
is there anything planned for today yes
I'm upgrading my PC why I want your
stream ok why when when you upgrade your
so wait those veggies looks oily yes
so ok so we're gonna do technical topics
we're gonna talk about Linux we're gonna
talk about our sink I'm gonna tell you
what it is and how to use it and give
you a demo and we're gonna do goal and
and and I'm going to tell you what is
the best way to learn :
go line is a very simple language you
can learn it in a few days ok you can
learn almost all of it in a few days now
let's see where is my pen yeah now I
cannot find my pen oh there so I need I
need two pens I require two pins so that
I can talk for them at any time
so the morning James Stewart so we are
going to do and I'm going to explain
then then I'm going to explain number
system okay the history of mathematics
numbers without numbers number notations
and Guggenheim growing expand number
base what does it mean number base 16
base 10 base night Bay 7 have you ever
heard of number of base 7 you can do
that you can have a number of any base
ok and so and we are going to write a
program that converts number from one
place to another
this is continuation from yesterday from
Emily crock
good morning Kathy to UK okay so well I
was a member of Mensa like in 1991
because means I is pretty CV okay yeah
it's supposed to be top top 10% of IQ
people but it's it's pretty it's kind of
like a code Mensa and you know if you
want to meet smart people they are a lot
quite a lot people smarter than minced
meat i and by the way there is another
Club which is one in 10,000 or 100,000
something you know intelligence club so
anyway so so so I'm going to show you so
let's begin okay practical you go to
Saudi practical UNIX tutorial Casali
mean Linux ok just search for Kali Linux
hold on a second let me get this correct
stop that and check one more time okay
so so you go to Saudi Linux you go to
practical Linux tutorial then you find
my Linux tutorial okay so this is this
tutorials command based tutorial so you
you want to learn all the most practical
Linux commands that are used daily you
go to this tutorial it's helpful
so if you are new to Linux Nabby or
anyone of you check it out okay this is
my tutorial and I'm going to show you
today a sink because we happen to we
were talking about it and I think I need
you know I think is pretty basic command
and very practical very useful so if you
don't know you might learn it so a sink
what is it what does it do it allows you
to sync your computer a directory from
one computer to a remote computer the
remote computer can be your work
computer can be a server or can be
anything so it's sink
you know it's remote sink what is that's
what our sinks stand for Limor sink so
you just run one command and all your
directory structure will be mirrored
almost I didn't identically basically
identically to the remote machine so so
that's the a sink our sink is building
in Linux you don't have to install it
it's building and it's also I it's
building on a Mac ok I'm pretty sure so
let's see let's see which heart sink
user being a sink so it is also part of
Mac so I think so
so illa allows you to sink one directory
on your machine from one machine to be
more machine but also this can be done
on any two directory so the the
directory needs not to be a remote
server so you can for example you have
one directory on your machine and
directory a and you have another term to
EB you want them to be synchronized like
exactly the same so you can run a sync
which is which is a sync is basically a
advanced version of SCP SCP is a oder
command on UNIX called remote copy
you know CQ or copy okay SCP so I think
is a
advanced version of it you have lots of
options so for example so let's see so
my terminal let me show you my terminal
ok so a sink for example you can type
man man our sink and you got this huge
amount of page down page down a huge
amount of documentation ok a huge amount
of arguments the options you know like
the typical Linux huge so so that's our
sink very complex you know if you
haven't used it before it's very
difficult to understand what are all
these options but so it's like endless
ok endless the main page is like 10 10
20 to 30 pages ok so that's a sink now
of course you can also call the man
command in Emacs let me do it ok
our sink so you see now I'm in my Emacs
and here is the documentation of our
sink and you know in Emacs you can see
the score bar on the right and you can
see it's gonna go over so that's our
sink and I'm going to show you how to do
it ok how well how to do it so you go to
my Linux tutorial you click on our sink
and the base so it's just a bunch of
options okay like like right now and I
think uses SSH so you can see there's an
option SSH
so it's secure and and also one thing
important to remember is that our sink
is one way it's not two-way sync ok so
it's just one way like you want one
directory to go or out to the other
directory so how do you use it there's
not much to it except just the options
you just have to know what all the
options - so the easiest way to do is
just like copy my code here you know you
read you know
copy so basically the syntax is like
this okay so you got a sink a bunch of
options Z means Z means Z means like
compress it first something like that so
it saves bandwidth a means archive mod V
means verbal verbose so that when the
command bruins it shows you what it's
doing and team is used timestamp which
means that it based on the modified time
so that it doesn't have to check on
files that's that has the same timestamp
anyway so so those are the options okay
so you just just use them those are the
common typical so this line is the
typical way you use a sink then after
those options then you say - - is H
equals true then your SSH login you know
SSH - L means logging then your name
toward remote server you don't have to
have you don't have to use SSH if you
don't want to then okay so those are the
options then the last two parts are the
directory for example I have here a
local directory tilde web which is home
home directory web directory then here
is the remote directory so in this
command that means I want to sync
oh the directory in my home directory
named the web and and all this directory
into a remote server located at
example.org and the login name is Joe
and sync it to a with the remote
directory also on that machine the home
directory of Joe so that's a basic
syntax and that's that's it that's about
it
now our sink has many many options like
we showed before so you so for example
this one
let me copy it okay let me show you in
Emacs okay so so that's an example so
for example let let me let me rephrase
space by bio return so it you can eat so
it's clear so so this a crew exclude
means you don't want to include any file
ending in Tilda typically those are
Emacs back up and then you exclude
Tiesto which is a temp file Mac created
on a Mac then you also exclude bash
history you know before sometimes in my
case I don't want to include that I
don't want to overwrite the bash history
on the remote machine then you can say
this this a crew excludes all
directories that that contains this
directory name and all the PNG files
that's what this liming then you exclude
logs okay so so this is so you have some
exclude commands then you have delete
option delete option means if on the
remote destination if some fire or
directory is not in my current directory
is not in my source directory then
simply deleted okay so that's the option
for that so if you have if you include
DD that means you basically you want the
two directories to be exactly the same
if you don't include the delete that
means whatever it's there it doesn't
delete them okay then then I have this
okay that option our SSH then at the end
this is source directory this is a
destination so that's our thing
now let me show you an example okay
example of a sink in real life for
example let's begin sorry
command log mod
okay and let's so on the left window you
see all my Emacs command and let's sit
background color set background color th
I okay three so one okay that's a
background color that's good okay let me
show you a demonstration of a sink now
you can see right now I'm on this HTML
page that is a talk show today so I'm
going to delete the first paragraph
livestreaming one hour I don't need that
anymore so delete showing browser you
see that that line is good now go back
to Emacs I start easier then I call this
command okay this is Satya brief so let
me show you that let's keep that let me
just show you a command okay so here is
our sink you see I type a key let me
show you again so close it go to each
shall magnify then I call a deviation so
there it is that's my awesome command to
sink my web website to the server so you
can see you know you can see a sink then
delete then change mod that change mod
means you can change the you know that's
a UNIX directory permission thing if you
don't know that that takes some time to
explain so change much you know UNIX
directory has permissions so I I want to
change them out to those mod so let me
show you what what what what UNIX file
and directory permissions are so for
example I'm in a let's go to directory
so this is my talkshow directory let's
delete the files we don't need okay so
now for example this file topic notes so
you can see these kind of things those
are you
makes file permission mods okay now
that's another topic if you don't know
that you have to go to go to my web you
go to my Linux tutorial you can
understand them by reading one of this
page this admin so Linux shall basics
Linux system in then file permission on
this page I explain what all those means
it's it's it's UNIX ok UNIX is fairly
compact complicated and it's not good in
my point of view in my in my opinion so
anyway so back to a sink then I say you
exclude something something something
then then SSH then from my web directory
to my server directory my website is
hosted on this web server so as I say
enter ok ok it asked me to type a
password so let me type a password ok
and now it's building of our list so
it's it's done it's so what what it does
is see it's it has updated this
directory and it has updated that file
you know I have I have about 6000 files
in well I have like 20 or 15 thousand 20
thousand files in this in this web
directory so you see it's very fast you
know back then like 10 20 years ago when
a sink came up it's one of the greatest
tool because it has new technology you
know in algorithms so anyway so we have
we have just shown I have like twenty
thousand thirty thousand files and it's
updated and only you updated those this
one single file because it knows which
file needs to update so now if you go to
my website let's see sorry dot info
okay ma'am Paige is one of the worst
thing okay that's another topic that's
your eunuchs pestilence
you know eunuchs is full eunuchs the
technology of eunuchs in my opinion is
the worst possible now I know many
of you don't think like that way like Oh
what what are you talking about you you
know like many of your you guys mind
that eunuchs is the best operating
system technically at least you know
because this or that no well you know
opinion is one of the worst in fact we
have just shown some of them some aspect
of them for example the a sink the man
pages which is in incomprehensible the
worst garbage possible in a computing
industry and we have and and and and
well anyway we are digressing a lot so
you go back you go to sorry
sorry dot info click on talk show and go
down and click on saw talk show today
you can see it's updated you see because
our sink is successful okay I think
that's about a sink that's it about a
sink close that close that and close
that and open this in browser okay let's
let's go through practical Linux okay
let me copy the path and paste it here
I'm bad at math James Stewart says I'm
bad at math I'm bad at reading man pages
and bad at reading file diffs
hello ticket ticket cheater kick okay
that is about a sink so that concludes
one of the topic show a sink show my
awesome tutorial and demo asking to my
server and now let me show you this
thing I just bought it today now I have
money if this is $70 okay you know what
this is this is a external drive to
terabytes now this is going to be good
for me for for good let's see if I can
show that to terabytes and usb3
okay it's got so it's so it's so new
that I just opened it and I have not
plugged in yet you see so let's see what
is this so let's take it out so you got
you got a USB cable USB okay so this is
a normal USB this is some funky I don't
know what okay so you plug in one side
this is very light actually so this is
very small it's like palm-sized so what
is the so what is the other side of the
plug
it looks like a proprietary kind of
thing is it is it proprietary kind of a
thing so you for being here then you
plug in the other side to the computer
and then you have it and you go PI okay
you like my stuff and go buy it so you
there it is the Amazon Inc so see Kate
they have one like for two
terabyte okay so hold on second let me
copy that
okay copy and go here and paste it and
you can go and see and meanwhile let's
wave shoaling King brave and you click
on that so you on Amazon you have this
version that this is five terabytes ok
$110 see gates very small ok very small
nice so finally now I can do backup okay
that's about that now let's go - oops
what did I just closed by mistake
reopened discord we cannot we don't want
to cross discord
so go back so next topic goal add an avi
yo I'm a super speed connector what do
you so what
Tara what what but what Tara so what do
you call that microUSB with the thing on
this side
it's a SuperSpeed connector Oh I lost my
when I wanted to buy a new one but
couldn't find it I was super speed
connector ok
is that a standard or he said prepared
everything so anyway so that's about my
the backup driver I just bought so you
guys buy it now let me explain the next
thing how to learn :
ok let me give you three minutes guide
how to learn : : is my favorite
industrial language is super fast it's
it's great ok I talked about this many
times terabyte oh not tetra Oh Tara ok
terabyte Tara it's like terrible
terrible
so : ok Holly :
you go to my Golan tutorial
I'm gonna give you a three-minute guide
on how to learn :
okay this is gonna be great guy okay
listen to me and you'll be good you go
wander on your own I know many of you
like to do that because I'm that type of
person and see you know then so many of
you like to oh yeah because I said that
but I'm just going to go and do extra
for myself well but I can give you a
guide for how to learn : okay first you
learn
oh my screen is back thank you
Nabby so you go to : tutorial right so
you go to : you know go to Sally's such
folks sorry : tutorial so you go to my
tutorial and the first thing you do is
read my tutorial okay just read it there
are 34 pages : is very simple okay you
can learn it in few days you can this is
opposed as opposed to Python JavaScript
closure
supposed to Haskell Haskell is the most
difficult to learn as opposed to Java
although some more difficult okay : is
extremely easy simple to learn and it is
the most use in industry you learn it
you get a job you got money money coming
in then stop easily okay so I recommend
: now I know many of you nerds like you
I go I want to learn scheme this I want
to learn you know some of the esoteric
languages no no no don't go then okay
unless you well you know what you are
doing so I highly recommend you learn :
: is all powerful all powerful highly
practical industrial why do we use you
know use everywhere like like C C++ Java
use everywhere and the language is very
good okay the documentation is the best
in the industry I can tell you for sure
because I've read all documentation in
the past 30 years
so : I highly recommend it now how do
you learn it here's how okay
you so i recommend of course i'd
recommend my own tutorial you just start
with my own tutorial but of course the
first thing you need to do is you need
to download : on the Mac all you have to
do is okay let me show you on the Mac
what do you do on the Mac on the Mac all
you have to do is brew install : I think
that's all you have to do okay that
that's all you have to do on Linux it's
kind of similar so again on Linux so let
me show you my Linux tutorial close that
so you go up Linux tutorial let's go
back to Linux tutorial so where is it
the big penguin by the way you know do
you guys know I'm pretty sure many of
you don't know because I'm getting old
do you know the story of the origin of
the Linux logo
why Linux has this logo probably you
guys don't know he because you guys are
younger but back then 20 years ago
everyone knows so leanness Linux Scott
got this logo because Lena's the guy
Lena's who created Linux he you know
when he created Linux back in 1991 okay
he when you know when they become
popular people want to know again so
what logo do you want you know and his
idea is that he wants a penguin that is
fat and satisfied like just had just had
a meal Thank You Alan for the super chat
for the money
Thank You Alan so Lena's towboats
you know he he's a big nerd and his idea
of logo like he's imagining he's
thinking okay I want the penguin that's
phat just had meal and just had sex like
a Content penguin that is how we got
this they not Linux penguin logo okay
that's a little Side Story
okay so so back to so so back to Linux
so if you want to know how to install
Linux of course I have a tutorial I have
an article on that you read this one by
one okay you read them one or two a day
so let's see where install packages now
I tell you all about how to install
packages and by the way have I mentioned
already that oh these are command line
based tutorial that is you don't go to
GUI so Kay you don't oh I'm gonna let's
do mouse and no this is hardcore Linux
tutorial everything is command line
command line only well actually I do
have a section on on Linux desktop you
can see there but but most of this is
about comma command line so you go
install packages this direct this page
will tell you all about the most used
the commands that you need to use
everyday for you know the most practical
ones so you follow that you will know so
anyway so let's go back to : so go to
learn : first of all you install : : o
you go to the go line of official site
then you can you know you find you they
they have like they tell you how to
install it so go the go programming
language and there is a let's see
documentation package the project
whatever where is the download go okay
let's see download go now am I on brave
okay so I'm on brave I need to turn on
JavaScript okay I talked a lot already
and actually we have more important
topics I think I talked about lots of
other things so you see go line you can
download for Apple yeah i po it's very
easy to download you just download this
package and you just and then this Linux
Linux is probably problems all the time
problem you'd you know because I how do
I know I know because I use it for four
years
Microsoft Windows MSI you CMS is also
very easy microsoft stop I don't want to
download because I already downloaded so
you have you know download Microsoft MSI
is the Microsoft's official installation
mechanism basically you download that
you double-click then it pops up you
know a graphical GUI ok then you follow
you know where do you want to install a
quick quick and it said Apple you
downloaded double-click it pops up you
drag it to your app for the or drag it
to your anywhere then you have it Linux
you download it then it's fact and you
are
ok that's Linux that tar.gz ok so you
don't if you don't know what
what are those start at Jeezy I have an
article on that there it is
Todd gzip bzip2 XD 7-zip rah zip one
complicated thing ok so anyway so you
download :
so the first step you download then you
just go through my tutorial ok then
after you go through my tutorial you
spent like two days three days okay you
you know you can work it out like just
like for example the first lesson
compiled and run you just copy it copy
it you paste in your editor let's see
paste in your editor then save it as you
know xxxx not go why because I I told
you so you know like I have the
instructions here then you just run it
okay then then for example we have this
okay then let's go to the directory this
is a file xx not go then you go to a
shower or terminal then you say go oh
you can run it okay go run code run xx
go
okay let's double check indeed so you
see you run it and it gives you the
result I love cats
which is from here that's how easy it is
and you can compile go programs you can
compile like go biota start go okay so
go field xx go that will compile it you
know go can be run as a script just like
Python Ruby pearl or JavaScript or you
can compare it like C C++ when it's
compiled you send it to your friends and
they can run it without having to
install Co so that's one of the great
advantage of going superfast
okay for example we have created the
code here a binary code xx here you see
this line so I can open it you see
that's a binary and we can run it for
example let's go back in shell again and
let's just run xx okay run it it trains
I love cats so you send this binary to
your friends and they can read they they
can run it you know they don't have to
oh you need to install Python verse or
you have to install Ruby verse no you
don't have to just run it so that's one
of the great advantage of code so that's
how you learned go okay I'm not done yet
okay so hold on a second let's delete
that we don't need that okay close it
close it we are back in our actual page
now so go so how do you go how do you
learn go so first you download it then
you read my tutorial you follow
everything you you code it you know you
actually have to do it that's best way
to like oh you can just read it for for
the first time then then okay here is
two things you want to do I'm going to
fit which which is I'm going to give you
a introduction to the go website okay so
you go to go website there are two
things you want to do after you read my
tutorial shut up okay so you go to so
after you read my tutorial then you go
to the go website
you can exploit okay so that you for
example they they also have a tutorial
interactively but I don't think that's
as good okay well if you ask me in my
opinion Michael tutorial is better than
this tutorial
of course I've tried it when I started
to learn go I don't like I didn't find
this tutorial to be great so anyway so
after you read my tutorial you go to the
goal page okay then let me tell you what
to do there are two things you want to
do okay one is that they have a go SPECT
which is a specification of the language
okay so you go the to the documentation
and actually they have a lot you know
language SPECT so you can you can read
that if you want if you are the type of
person who are interested in programming
language I mean yeah if you are
interested in programming language
details I mean if you have experience of
reading SPECT before then this is a good
one to read however this is not a
practical thing to do so if you have
never read a programming language
specification before then you don't want
to then don't do it okay but if you have
this is very good okay this is the best
language SPECT
of all the others I've seen for example
bit far better than Java JavaScript
suspect far better than closure spec
well closure it doesn't have a spec far
better than eMac this menu eMac this
manual eMac this doesn't respect but you
have a Mac this menu and then you have
Java Java language SPECT which is huge
okay anyway so the go spec Co language
spec is very good and it's not very long
okay for example I'm scrolling around it
the whole thing is one page
well it's it's like 50 feet or something
or 100 pages but it's not long and it's
comprehensible you read it you can
actually understand it that is if you
have some experience in reading spec
because I know because I've read quite a
lot so : spec is one of the best written
language spec and and and pretty easy to
understand you know it's not as in
contrast the JavaScript the Xmas script
2015-2016 you try to read it it's it's
about 10 or 20 or 30 times larger than
the goal-line spec and it's
incomprehensible it's one up
the JavaScript SPECT and because also
because the language is far more
complicated than goal and okay so anyway
here is goal as spec you can read in
fact on my tutorial I have included the
goal inspect if you just go to the
bottom you see I have a my local copy of
the goal inspect there it is okay so
I've read I've read I didn't read like
20 percent of it I plan to read them
more but I haven't done so so cold
inspecting is good to read okay but you
don't have to okay but now let me show
you the other thing which is the most
important thing so after you read my
tutorial then you can read the goal
inspect if you want to or if you have
experience in reading specs then the
next important thing is to go to the
packages now these packages is the
documentation of all the Bo Deen
packages now go is a low-level language
just like CC phosphors
so everything you do you kind of need a
package because they divided the
language into several you know pack
different parts so that if you don't
need something you don't include that so
the the binary is small so that is why
you have these
packages building these are or building
packages now on this page is the
documentation for all these packages for
example let me show a general example
for example standard library okay you
click on that you have the standard
library you have tah-tah zip for
archives io before i/o you have bytes
you have compressions you know all the
compression we mentioned you have you
know you have quick quick cryptanalysis
crypt cryptography database debug SQL
database and hash hash HTML image
manipulation I all lock math you know
these are networking this old these are
the fundamental building packages and
you are looking at the documentation
it's fantastic ok it's a once you read a
few you get you get a sense of what you
know it's writing style then you can
just write them you can just read them
like like a book it's it's the best
documentation written now there's one
more thing so so this page is the
documentation of building functions
building packages but there's one more
thing you see there is this thing built
in this line okay let me magnify
okay this this line this line this this
one is a spear in this one is actually
not a package the reason it's here it's
a special the reason this thing this
piolin thing is here among the packages
is because this is actually all the
building functions about the core
language for example in inko language
you have all these key words they are
part of the go language is not a package
is it's part of the core for example in
Golan you have these types you have int
sixteen in 32 in 64 then you have stream
type you know so on this page
it explains it's it's basically a
documentation about the spewing things
okay building functions part of the
colon and they happen to put the
spilling documentation among the
packages you know so you just they just
find a place you know it just it's just
the way they do it you know you may
think okay so this is not consistent
because package is this page supposed to
be the documentation for all the
packages so if you put a documentation
for the building keywords it seems
inconsistent but you know go line is
very practical it doesn't you know it
doesn't like have to stick to some
artificial structure or something as
opposed to Python Python Python people
Python Kaido
you know they like to they like to
create a big you know like computer
science structure and and they think
they are doing good Python talk is one
of the worst you cannot find what you
need you don't understand what they are
saying the documentation is imprecise
ambiguous everywhere badly organized
that's and badly written to let's Python
documentation but meanwhile they tried
like they do get us they try to be like
we are computer science you know Python
is crap Python is the worst one of the
worst so goal and doc is very good
okay that concludes my my guide to how
to learn go lad
in summary you download colon then you
read my tutorial all of it okay we did
like spend two days so more if you
depends on you
you read my tutorial then you go through
the goal and packages then you start to
read one or two packages for example a
stream
let me show you a stream because colon
is a very basic I mean very low level
language so when you want to call stream
functions such as get a substring or
something you require package and you
require this speeding package so this
stream package it's gonna be used all
the time you know
like almost every one of your goal and
program we all need we all need to
import this stream package so you're
gonna be reading this you're gonna need
to read this often so you can start to
you know you can choose this package to
to begin to get familiar with the goal
and documentation for for its packages
so that's it that's it about how to
learn : okay you know read the packages
and oh and also last thing you know on
Cola inside you you could just explore
them they got lots of other informations
interesting and useful informations but
what I've given the guide above is what
I I do okay that's my recommendation
what you the steps to follow okay
that is about a guide to how to learn :
okay so what is the next thing
are we okay so I've been talking for too
long actually now the main topic the
main dish today I was planning to talk
about number notation history of numbers
number notation and number base where
does the concept came from you know most
programmers you know you know you might
be familiar with Oh hexadecimal Oh octo
Oh decimal you think you know but you
don't know okay and I can give you I can
explain what's the background what's the
number base what do you need a base in
the first place and that that traces to
the history of
number notations and also the history of
numbers the concept so that is what I
was planning to do that the main thing
so and I'm going to talk about yeah so
some history about numbers number
notations then we're gonna write a
function in goal and to convert from
base X to base Y the x and y can be
anything so you can have a base seven
number system you can have a base 17
number notation and you can convert
between them but I I think I talked for
too long on other things so how long I'm
having F yeah 46 minutes so comments
okay comments guys then let me know
where to go and and maybe there'll be a
today comments and I'm gonna read the
comments and let's see where we go okay
it's so quiet on discord and today's
Sunday and now it's the holidays I don't
you know my day every day is the same I
don't know what is Wayne's Christmas I
don't know Wayne's New Year until I
learned oh today oh now it's now
holidays okay let me get a drink and
let's read the comments please to base
6000 yay good morning George hold on a
second
that's rockstar Rockstar Energy Drink so
I think what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
talk some random 40 minutes about number
base and but we are now going to get
into details about how to write a
function in : to convert the algorithm
the algorithm to convert from one number
base to the other and you know that's
fairly technical and it's tasking you
know like I mentioned this many times
before when you do a YouTube tutorial if
I do some technical like live coding
that really takes our time and that
really takes a lot of me of my know-how
like I really have to know it very well
and in order to do it but the funny
thing is that that usually you don't get
much people to watch that neither
because most people they don't they want
to watch the drama the for entertainment
you know that's why most people are
watching YouTube not you know the the
the so the the the interesting thing is
that the most the more difficult subject
you try to do even if you are if even if
you do it well you the less people you
have the less audience you have GTA
what does GTA mean gotta go all the the
game what is GTA so what blood says
there is an advantage Minh tuck umpire
language nothing that is go specified
what oh that is any advantage of
compared language yeah
so let me go to and Thank You Alan again
great
Alan money money talks of course you
guys love open source due money okay
open source is going nowhere it's it's a
it's so bad it damages people it damages
yourself sure screen okay so let's see
so Pedro says why I find : useful and
easy
I am never being able to fully
understand how the dependencies work and
how the prod and the project structure
what do you mean dependency dependency
is just import libraries and about the
project structure the goal and has a
website that they talked about it but
I've not I've actually never got into
well you need that only when you started
to write bigger programs but if you are
just writing you know one file script
you know I I showed this many times for
example I have lots of go for example
let's go let me show you one okay let's
show you one go language okay this
script this script in : now this script
is 220 lines this script will go through
all my website files like 20 30 thousand
files among them is like seven thousand
HTML files it will go through all of
them and find any link any broken link
that is link that goes nowhere links
that goes to a non-existent fire that's
this for graph so for for example let me
show you okay so so for example this is
the input directory so right now this
program is going to try to check
sorry info site just that site okay that
side has has like 3000 HTML files but
before we do that lets go to my
programming block okay so this is my
programming block I'm sorry that info
and you know I'm blogging about
something about olan olan
Emily's language and you know and I have
several links for example this link goes
to click these links to go to goes to my
talk show a few days ago okay so let's
let's say let's go back to the
programming language so let's go to so
here is a link okay
now let's say we we add something there
tget so the link no longer works okay
now back to the browser refresh now I
click on that it's a dead link because
it's pointing to a non-existent file you
see but now I go to my goal and script
you see this script will check will find
all bad links so I run it I just run it
and you know in two seconds also you
show me or tell me which think are bad
everyone takes a shot everyone takes a
shot sabe turns on JavaScript Pedro says
for Linux you should use the package
manager having my ass off yeah you mean
the package manager I showed him a
tutorial
you see package managers you know if we
are going to talk about that then I'm
going to start a rant one hour event
don't be Knox package managers it's it's
it's crap well it's not let's not begin
that so bar says it seems like you were
drunk when you last time Linux this is
how I install stuff install YPG and what
done know what you don't know well
windows only make trouble like lots of
modern Linux is not so bad ok
programming stuff what was way easier to
get up speed ok anyway let's go back to
my goal script now as you see it's done
now let's go saw find output mod this is
a Emacs mod that highlight highlight the
stuff so it tells me this file this pink
file has a broken link and this is the
link content so I press ENTER to go to
go to that file position you see so that
so you see that that's that's how useful
it is this is a ghost script that checks
checks you know thousands of files in
fine-a fine spoken links basically why
it does is that it kind it kind of
passes the HTML and find any of the link
structure then get the file path then
try to see if that file exists so if thy
foul doesn't exist print it out that's
you know that's the essence of that
I'm sold so he walked so let's fix it
okay done so here so that so this is the
: script you know only only 200 lines
yeah so go read my tutorial okay : I may
be Alan maybe you'll be your next
language other than JavaScript so bosses
that is okay so let's see keychain dot
exe keygen keychain is a UNIX command I
think in my humble opinion does that say
hello world hello world okay yes
oh wait nevermind I thought you were
asking George they do that to them or
unit colons unicode abilities they kick
in they yeah and they are you know
marketing you know the things on Colin's
website is half of it is marketing and
the way you know that that that's
typical for any programming language
homepage because they want to attract
you they want to lure you into using the
language they want to that's what every
programming website programming language
website wants to do you know so they
have a video this this sky creator of
goal and this Rob Pike talking about it
Rob Rob Pike is kind of a dramatic
colorful people you know he's one of
those UNIX philosophy type of people
he's very found of Unix but anyway but
but you know I also I didn't like him
however about seven years ago since I
started to learn :
actually by actually you know digging
into actually started to code then I
love Golan yeah I find every design I
talked about this before in my previous
video like three
month s month ESCO so I started to dig
into : I then I discovered all the
design decisions and well first of all
it's so simple
the documentation is best okay best of
them all it's super fast and easy you
know it's pretty clean it's simple clean
easy to learn
so I find it great okay and suppose
functional programming and then you know
so I started to learn more and more and
I find that every design decision I like
okay by this rap I can friends you know
he's got a bunch of his friends who
co-designed the cola so I started to you
know so I like you know the Rob Pikes
opinion at least for his language design
Goren's KN Kaena are you a member of the
Society's smarter than Mensa no please
to base 60 okay number positions we rank
drama and entertainment overnight this
is much stuff when I'm working on
something else and washing the dishes
one King and yanking text you know Nabby
like wherever I see people especially
people who follow me you know most
people who follow me because because of
my Emacs stuff my Emacs - oh me oh my
Emacs anniemac based knowledge most
people follow me because of my Emacs
stuff but whenever I see them when they
learn Emacs they started to post some
other tutorial like they started to say
oh I like that video oh I like this this
website about Emacs I get I get pissed I
get I get it I get in how do you say I
get
indignant I get indignant like I I have
this entire tower of tutorial the most
easy to read the most logical the most
the the great greatest writing the style
and the most poke you know the tech like
in quantity and quality there's nothing
out there that's that's comparable to my
Emacs tutorial and eMac this tutorial
but then I see my followers I mean these
are people who actually follow me and I
talk to them being friends okay
some of them are closer you know then I
see them the post is I was thinking to
myself oh my god what's the problem okay
so is there a problem with my tutorial
somewhere that that that makes you go to
somewhere else to read or Algeria like
what's the deal so every time I see that
I get indignant okay so with I don't
know something I guess I guess sometimes
you know other people they got they got
video tutorials that suits them or on
occasion or something so anyway so I'm
gonna do random chat for five minutes on
number systems name we're gonna shut
down okay
so what's up guys anything else good
morning so George George says okay first
of all I'm gonna show
showcase sorry unicode you go to my
únicos web site I'm gonna showcase some
of the number systems used in history
okay so we are on sorry you know sorry
dot info Unicode Unicode search so we're
gonna type we're gonna type
and you m p e.e
all Unicode characters that contains the
word number in their name so you can see
here we are seeing quite a lot agent
okay so actually it doesn't show too
much because because I have a limit of
how many characters to show because
otherwise you're gonna show thousands of
thousands of characters anyway we are
seeing we are seeing some of the some of
the numbered systems in different
languages so so I can show you here so
you can see here's information so we
have a Rea big number sign or a big
number mark above Tamayo number ten Tama
number 100 tamio number 1000 okay then
here is number sign here is Mallory alum
number ten here is mariana num number
100 so then you have 1000 then you have
Ethier pic number 10
Ethier pic number 20 30 40 50 and so on
80 90 100 then you have this Ethiopia
number 10,000 you see these are some of
the you know different languages they
how they represent numbers then you have
these circled numbers parenthesized
numbers characters then and the number
with the . with a period that's the UK
UK style of calling the period full stop
okay then you have okay those are not
interesting so anyway let's scroll down
then you have Aegean number for Aegean
number five agent number six seven eight
then my agent number 10 okay then you
have Aegean 2030
40 and so on 60 and 90 and agen 100 okay
now it's getting interesting so agent
number 200 300 400
so when hundred is represented by a dot
okay then you have okay then you have a
thousand represented by this kind of a
Diamont odd shape explain number versus
numero how do you explain that well
number is a concept of mass number oh I
think numeral describes number the
number of number of the word number
means it's a it's it describes the
writing system to represent numbers
that's what I think okay I'm not sure
for example we can look up dictionary
okay so yeah so okay so number o number
oh it's just a number of system okay so
so let's go to dictionary a word letter
symbol or figure expressing or number
yeah that's I'm correct guys I'm correct
number oh now a word letter symbol or
figure expressing a number so you know
it's just you know it's indicator number
yeah basically so and so anyway so we
have other number systems so we have
Copic Copic number 40 10 20 30 40 you
know they're very interesting so in some
and then okay so then we have person
okay look look guys person owed first
your number one two and this is number
ten and this is number twenty and this
is number 100 per cm okay then we have
in
p vo aram ik number okay I don't have a
font okay so then we have you me we have
cut out a lot of others and we have old
Hungarian number system then we have
pasta
Pallavi number system then we have
inscription on our inscriptional Pallavi
number system so anyway these are you
know then we have Remi and we have
sodium number system so we have we are
looking at lots of number systems in
history so that that is my point
you know just to show you just to show
you that that's a number notation you
see today we are familiar with array big
numbers numero Arabic numerals like one
two three you know you so 1 0 is 10 1 0
0 is 100 1 0 1 is 100 and what and what
that's Arabic you know to me to us it's
like it's like basic so basic what's
what's more to it you know it's like we
learnt because it's not that basic ok
the reason we think it's so basic it's
because we learned it since we were five
literally you know since we went to
kindergarten but that that the Arabia
notation that's there is not the
beginning notation the Arabic note in
the beginning we don't use that ok for
example in I don't know what year year
500 or something the Western Europe they
are using Roman numerals
ok Roman numerals
there we have it these are the Roman
numerals okay so in the I don't know
what what year they changed to a Rea big
number system you can look up on
Wikipedia you look at you know you use
such for Roman numerals and then you'll
see the history of it
anyway doing some time I year 500 or
year 1000 I don't know so Europe was
using you know these Roman numerals
which is very cumbersome you know very
fairly calm you know it's hard to read
how to understand eventually we adopted
adopted the Arabic is so called Arabia
number system now so when on the subject
of numbers now we we are talking about
the context here is about notation
numerical notation to represent numbers
so that is the problem
so for example let me ask you a problem
what what are the ways to represent
numbers okay now most of us know well we
have decimal numbers right yeah that's
that's we know it because we were taught
from when we were child but suppose if
you don't know that or let me ask you
what what's what's some other way what's
some other way to to have a notation
system that represent numbers can you
can you name the name one well yeah you
can for example Roman number us ok these
these Roman numerals but that's that's
not the only alternative so so the
problem is what what are the like what
are the possible ways to represent
numbers to have a written system three
percent numbers so so we have quite a
lot ways you know in history how do I
know because I'm a math history
enthusiastic me most of 1990 I read I've
showed you my books I can show you right
now several you know I have quite a lot
books on the
history of mathematics actually let me
show you okay
books and books I'm just going to show
you a few okay so I'm showing you my
some of my history of mathematics book I
read them mostly in 1990s that's why I
know about these things the men of
mathematics okay this is this is
actually not a accurate historical book
but it's pretty dramatic and fun to read
it covers some of the most famous
mathematicians the man of mathematics
then you have these three volumes of
okay three volumes let's see if I can
read it
mathematical thought through Asian to
modern times
Volume one by Morris crying he is a
famous math historian and also
mathematician now there are three
volumes of it okay one two three
you see so I read lots of it in 1990s
and by the way you guys need to go buy
it
okay then then there is this book number
theory and its history okay this this
this is by this guy he is also kind of
well-known mathematician only in OS 10
oh you can find his name in Wikipedia
then this is another way of no math
history book very thick very thick a
history of mathematics by car boy Oh
boyo he is also very famous you came for
example you'll find his name on
Wikipedia
so I read I read you know I read a few
and there's a there's more there's also
another math history book by Howard Yves
Howard Yves ok I mean actually so let me
show you okay so let me so you guys go
by the book for Christmas if you need to
give someone a gift or something to your
friends or to your mom hey mom I got you
a math history history of math book ok
Sokka sorry math block you go to Mike
sorry math blog okay so we digressed
into math books but let me get back to
the numbers numbers and how do you
create a writing system to represent
numbers and by the way the number we
know the Arabic number system that is
classified as the positional number
system I'll talk about that okay so you
go to my math blog then you go through
math books math textbooks okay now these
are a bunch of three math books okay and
I recommend I actually looked through
them I recommend them but you want to go
to this one ok so here is a photo of
some of the books I showed you and let
me paste it so you guys can go to Amazon
so let's go back to talk show where is
it go yeah books so math books so first
of all so Alan says do you think that
reading of math history requires
understanding lots of mathematics not
really well yes in some well yes yes and
no okay
for example when I read all these books
in the 1990s I don't know of that much
math so so okay let me explain this for
example there is another book I it's
called the history of PI's okay let me
show you some Amazon okay let's go to
Amazon remind me to answer that question
if I digressed okay and remind me to go
back to number systems history of Pi now
this is one of the very popular book
okay a history of Pi I read it in 1990s
but I think I threw the book away I oh I
gave it away or something so here here's
a book by by Peter Beckman way not this
one no a history of Pi okay they change
the color design you know the the this
is kind of annoying the books they
change color design every few years
every 10 years anyways this this book
very very popular extremely popular a
history of Pi by the way this book is
also not very accurate like when you
study the history of mathematics there
are some books that's that's for the for
the masses okay like kind of like
popularization of Sciences so they are
easy to read but their story
you know what they talk about is not
very historically accurate as opposed to
some other history of math books they
are read and referenced by historians
who study the math history you know so
they are there's kind of this
distinction so you know so you know what
I'm saying so on one hand for example
for example the history of Pi this book
and also this one the men of mathematics
they are a little bit dramatic okay they
are kind of you know dramatic not really
that historically accurate they are not
because they are designed for the the
you know general crowd on the other hand
on the other hand the other book I
showed for example this one the oh I III
this cry Morris okay on the other hand
this book now these are for
mathematicians history of mathematics
this history of mathematics for you know
they refer reference this book and
others okay anyway so the question about
do you need to know mathematics in order
to read history history of math that yes
or no that depends if you are reading
this comment for you know for the
general audience you don't need to for
example this history of Pi you don't
need to be a mathematician to to to
appreciate this book you can you know
just for fun you can read a lot history
of Pi more or less accurate okay but if
you are reading for example some of the
for example these these three volumes
I'm talking about the moral moral sky
then they talk about you know
differential
a tree topology differential manifolds
differential equations some some
equations in physics you read it but if
you don't know those subject you don't
get it
okay because because for example if you
are reading that the history of
chopstick but if you don't know what is
a chopstick then you don't get it
you know so for the advanced history you
have to know the math of it in order to
really fully appreciate the history of
it okay so that's it for today so
actually yeah I think that's it for
today the number systems the number
systems I think that's basically all I
have to say I mean so maybe next day we
will do a number based like okay so I
haven't explained the positional number
system which is a decimal number system
it's positional why is it called
positional this class of notations is
called positional number system why
positional because when you say one zero
that's ten the position is critical
because one to the left of zero is
different from zero to the left of one
or on top or whatever so it must be
positioned away it's you see the the
meaning of a sequence of digits depends
on their position that's that's why it's
called positional notation system okay I
think that's it for today so let's see
I've been talking for one hour oh my god
1 hour and 20 it's so young okay so my
screen is still off okay I'm back okay
so
shaving of the unfulfillment so try to
answer questions about reading math I
think it is similar with computer
programming stuff thank you okay thank
you for answer yeah so if you know more
about computing stuff you can access to
much more stuff yeah so I guess that's a
yeah it's a similar to reading history
of computing or history of computer
languages that would be yes exactly
okay Alan well Alan Alan Alan was
talking about 60 based system that's
very interesting but I think that's it
for today so many interesting things in
Chinese every form makes every form
makes more sense yeah that's that's
another topic to go into I was always
confused when I want to convert between
Chinese and English
anything else explained number versus
number okay so so what different based
spaces be about different numbers for
these numbers okay we're gonna shut down
in one minute but I can kind of I can
explain okay
so positional number system right you
know so you just type positional number
system like number notation you can
actually you can read on Wikipedia you
know it's like oh this thing are there
so based and so first of all the Arabic
system we use the decimals you know
notation is spaced 10 Y 10 it means we
use 10 symbols that's it because we use
10 different symbols 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 different symbols
you know the symbol can be anything can
be ABCD efg or whatever we are using 10
of the
different you know symbols and we place
the symbols you know you know how the
horizontal way and we position them to
make sense what they mean so the easiest
way you know I started to explain this
but I should stop today I should stop
today anyway so you you go to Wikipedia
it's you can it's not how to understand
okay so you have positional systems so
Wikipedia actually you you go there it's
gonna be a black hole you know do you
have a history of number notations
history of numbers history of number
concepts and so on and you know and and
the number base and so on so anyway so
so yeah that's it for today so I think
bye guys bye guys have a happy happy
holiday Merry Christmas Christmas is is
you know ho today today is 22nd oh my
god
Christmas is like the day after tomorrow
let's see who is wrong who is on discord
so guys join discord if you haven't
already okay we had fun chatting today
on this chord our voice by Mott bibot
Merry Christmas