good morning guys
so I'm going to talk about actually I
don't know what is today's topic I'm
waiting for people to come out hey boo
but hey guys Wow two people both the
pets jack and jack so what should I talk
about today so I said a vote aunt Rita
just three hours ago so it's either
gonna be about Emacs or Emacs Lisp which
is a technical topic where I'm going to
teach some subject you know I can it can
be any specific thing about Emacs or
Emacs Lisp oh I'm gonna talk about
something about YouTube many interesting
things channels on YouTube you know just
I just talked randomly like like a talk
show or I can talk about some other
things like programming languages so you
know just just random stuff like none
technical well okay
programming languages that's your
technical but random ish so so what do
you guys like to hear let me know
so I was going to so again my Emacs blog
and let's get the command log going okay
I'm probably gonna I'm gonna show a
random stuff okay I want to know more
about Elise bloop okay is Thai I can
cover both Factory let me start by Emacs
by the way but pet do you use Emacs at
all so anyway let me start by just going
to this mod dot Emacs helper command log
mod and command log mod magnify and I'm
going to start this mod but you see this
mod is probably well let me start it run
run run so so what this mod does does is
that it shows all my commands including
typing for example you see you can see
you know whatever
I even the text I insert will show up
here but actually I'm thinking of
modifying the mod so that it does not
show the text okay let's do that okay
let's see that command command mod
you know every few minutes every five
minutes I'm gonna look at the chat so
you know keep the chat keep the chat
comments coming so let me type it it's
not okay so I'm what I'm going to do is
you see this this mod is on ALP is our
mapper but however the fire you are
seeing is modified a little bit so and
this mod is problematic in that you see
these two sections I added myself if you
download from Maya you won't see these
two sections the instruction to start
the mud is is bugs so the way you
actually want to start started is to
coke man lock mod and if you wanted
global you have to cook global command
loud mod then you have to call this
command CRM open command log buffer in
order to show this buffer all the
commands you are using your calling so
and it must be in this specific order
you cannot simply just call you know
global command mod lock mod because that
doesn't work it's kind of a bug you have
to call command log mod first to turn it
on so you know this mod you know is
problematic so if you want you can
actually copy this you know download the
file for male power copy it put in the
file you know make like make a push
request you know so it's better okay the
other thing is that in this mod when you
download it actually it has a filter
like over here so so basically this
filter is used so there are some command
we are not show commands such as
backward char like like this you know or
backward elite are like
oops like this okay I have different
command but anyway so these commands I
feel that filtered out he won't show on
here however I want everything to show
so I commented route I commented them
out except the mouse tracked region in
Mouse set point which is basically Mouse
quick and but now I want let's say self
I want this I also want to filter
ourself insert command because you know
when you are typing something typing you
know people already see what you are
typing it needs not to be sure there so
I I'm gonna close that so I'm gonna
comment it it you know I'm gonna filter
out the self insert command so let's
just run it so I'm gonna call this so
it's it's done so now if I type
something you see it does not show on
the left side so that's it for the
command log mod let's go let's close
these make a backup close it okay
new framing
okay so Emacs Lisp loop okay let's talk
about that so email is basically the
only general the most basic loop is wire
loop eMac list eMac list does not have
for loop you know for loop like in C or
Java JavaScript you know Python it only
has quiet so what you do is let's see
once we switch to again so switch to my
email is smart type W enter when that's
not what I want so while that's how you
do a loop for example let's do this set
one equal to let's say print messages so
I'm gonna print I i from 1 to 9 okay and
not now I'm going to show my message
Mart it's gonna be the result is gonna
be shown here okay so I'd run a command
avoid variable I yeah of course so
that's a problem with wire so what you
have to do is to set I to 0 you can do
that or you can do let let hi wait hi 0
so you can do this so let's run it you
see another wizard is here now this is
the most basic the most fundamental loop
in Emacs and that's it there is that's
the only one there's an as far as loop
goes okay so that's the only one but
there are several others for example
there is if you have
a okay if you have a list for example
let's just sit
let's delete that okay let's just say X
list for example doing it then you can
you there is a command code two times
okay and that's the syntax and you say
one from the variable I is all already
local that's just part of the syntax
let's put this in let's put it this way
so two times high from I from let's say
ten let's save let's say 10 okay okay in
two times it's a it's a loop you don't
need a list so let's forget about that
so it's just it's like a wire loop so I
is from 1 to 10
forget about the result for now you can
always look up describe function two
times to see the full syntax so so the
body is gonna be just that let's say
that okay let's try it move it down run
it you see 1 2 3 4 5 2 now let's try to
learn to find you see 0 1 2 3 4 so it
start with start at 0 and the last the
last expression in the body is returned
for example we can do for example set X
okay xx equals 2
so we can do that turn it and show eggs
vennett
oh not X but X X because we have X X
here so show xxx O'Neill okay so the
result of two x is just Neal it it just
does it it does a loop and it doesn't
return anything it's just loop by side
effect yeah we're loop is like four in
not like fully in JavaScript because
javascript is very complicated it's
up you know JavaScript 14 is not
what do you think it's doing should I
talk about it okay
let me repeat you know we got five
people watching you know I'm going to
talk about you know let me know what you
want to talk about you Emacs or you make
this technical subject where I just you
know you ask a question I focus on oh oh
I focus on particular topic you know I
just teach it oh I can talk about like
South talk-show which is more random you
know about society about future about
technology about programming in general
about philosophy and I was planning to
show YouTube there's many so many
interesting things going on YouTube you
know they are literally like billions
billions yeah I think something like
that billions of big videos on YouTube
like every hour every minute there are
hundreds of new videos and this has been
so since since you know five or 10 years
ago
okay general stuff okay it seems like
that you know yeah so keep the comment
going so doesn't matter what subject I'm
talking about you know keep the comment
going because when you you know your
comment direct me to you know the
direction I'm going to talk about you
know you can ask the question note
something so okay here we have Emacs
loop we covered Emacs loop let me talk
about javascript javascript just a
little bit okay not taking about
javascript loop
javascript is a very complicated
language and it's pretty up it's
because originally you know JavaScript
started in 1995 and originally it's not
it's not much of a language it's just
for people who don't have programming
experience you know like designers you
know they you know it's designed for
them to you know maybe trick something
on a web page that's our engine of
JavaScript and it's literally created
and implemented designed in like ten
days you know this is javascript is
created by Brent Brent and I think he's
Brendan opened up Brendan Eich so he
invented javascript in night around 1995
and it's it's the whole thing instant in
10 days and the Brendan went on egg he
is a lisp
fan so he is a scheme list to be exact
he's a scheme list fan so he's a
language fan you know like me very
interesting languages very interested in
elegance of languages design of
languages know you know so he got hired
to buy Netscape and he is to you know he
what the plan was he he was going to
implement scheme he netscape browser but
you know but it's not up to him because
you know this
society you know because companies they
have their own goals you know so back
then 1995 Sun Microsystems created Java
you know Java the the most bloated
language it's supposed to be like have
you know you must have heard the slogan
write once run everywhere run anywhere
you know that was a slogan you know if
you if you were not there you can not
imagine how crazy it was it was in every
magazine every magazine including non
programming magazine like scientific
America in you know pop magazines
everyman everywhere you see it every day
every website you know they they'd run
ads you know write Java run write once
run everywhere and the thought you know
among programmers or at least according
to the marketing and very popular woman
programmers as well is that the Java is
going to be the last language you know
no more Java is the final one right was
maybe everywhere
so anyway Java came along and so micro
system puts million millions dollars you
marketing's
you know and then but in browser at the
time they need some kind of a scripting
language you know scripting is kind of
hot at that time you know just it kind
of just began scripting you know and
Perl was also very popular so Java and
Perl extremely popular back then
okay back then the most popular language
is not much you know not like today you
have so many different languages
languages you know Python Ruby pearl you
know Haskell or camo you know many
different functional languages you know
so many but back then there's only few
actually used widely in the industry so
there's C C++ Perl Java and
and that's about it let's see did I miss
anything so so you know keep the
comments going coming you know so I know
where I'm going you know I'm going too
fast or too slow I or should I change
subject so anyway so back then there's
only just these few languages and then
so Java is very popular because some
some I go systems and and Linux was just
on the scene Linux is kind of not there
yet but anyway so so Java is you know I
you know widely marketed everyone knows
so when when JavaScript came into the
scene the Netscape company want the
syntax to be Java so that is why today
when use the JavaScript syntax syntax is
see like it's not like scheme Lisp it's
see like however the semantics you know
the how JavaScript works it's more like
scheme okay it's and it's worse
functional programming in fact
JavaScript I JavaScript is one of a
language that propelled functional
programming that introduced popularized
functional functional programming to the
industrial programmers not Haskell okay
no it's not as it's JavaScript and also
I would say PHP is also a very
fundamental in introducing functional
programming now however that my opinion
is controversial okay you probably don't
agree many you know that's just my
opinion because PHP is very it's also
very lousy and screwed screwed up
language it's just started by a teenager
who who original name of PHP is pretty
homepage something like that okay it's
like my pretty homepage and PHP in the
beginning is just Perl it's just you
know a copy
you know just code written in Perl
that tries to do something HTML that's
it so it's a perl script running in
browsers along with Apache you know the
you know to compile it so PHP in the
beginning is just power the the
essential idea that makes made PHP
widely popular is because templates you
know in Perl or Python or Ruby when you
want to run up huge page HTML page
basically whenever you want to print
something you have to say print you know
something
but however PHP is the reverse so
basically everything you type is gonna
be printed out so everything you type in
PHP is just you know it's just like as
if you have a print statement in front
it's just gonna print it out it's just
dump it so the whole thing is like a
template template but when you want code
to actually run then you have to put
special brackets you know you know and
that's code so let's see okay so let's
not PHP let me show you some syntax so
this is PHP for example yeah you see
this nummy magnify you see this bracket
left angle bracket question mark PHP and
end by question mark PHP so if you want
code you have to put inside this bracket
but otherwise any text is just gonna be
printed out
it's just dumped out so this is you know
kind of the reverse of you know normal
programming languages you know you print
something you have to say print but here
everything is printed you have to you
know for code to run you have to put
them in special diliman to delimiters so
this way so what's good about this way
this way is very useful for HTML because
in HTML you know like over here the math
vast majority of your text is actually
needs to be printed out so that's how
so PHP is very simple extremely simple
it just have the basic idea of functions
that's it in the beginning just
functions everything is just a function
it doesn't have object-oriented system
because it's just a you know teenager
who wants to create a pretty homepage so
everything is just function so there's
no any fancy programming language
concepts for example when you talk to
Python heads or Haskell heads or dis
heads they want to talk about Oh tail
recursion Oh monads Oh currying Oh
transparency of what what's the code you
know you know variable transparency Oh
Marcus you know like like those hacker
types elite programmers they want to
like keep telling you those important
you know things and if you don't use
them visit you you are stupid you know
you you need to do you know you need to
coded in idioms you know what they are
fancy references and stuff so PHP is is
not like that because it's just this th
guy he wants to create a pretty homepage
and you know writing script on top of
Perl and so everything is just a
function function meaning just simple
function you know you give this argument
it returns something so and so anyway so
because of this it's it's extremely
simple and because it's you know
suitable for HTML it becomes huge I mean
it because basically the number one the
most popular language in a world into
meme in much of 2000's like most of 2000
even still today so for example
wikipedia is written in PHP and so so
PHP is like drastically different from
the other languages may be academic or
an industrial because the academic
languages like Haskell scheme they have
their own you know like code of
philosophy they want to tell you what
should be done you know according to
computers
and so on the industrial programmers
like the C and C++
in Java you know they they have
different ideas they have a code there
their ideas to tell you like you should
do this way because it's the most
efficient you know they need they talk
about compilers references references
you know with medics and you know memory
you know stacks and overflow and they
want to talk about that so PHP is just
entirely you know it isn't it's not from
that environment so you know it's just
simple guy created thing practical
things so that becomes extremely popular
so so and because PHP is mostly just
simple functions that's why I say you
know that's that's my opinion I say in
fact PHP is the programming language
that actually helped propel the idea of
functional programming now if you are if
you are a functional programming fan you
know maybe has cow or Lisp oh okay moe
you probably don't agree because that's
not you know everyone every program
professional programmer likes to dis
JavaScript and PHP you know but anyway
PHP so there's PHP and JavaScript
so yeah JavaScript in the beginning it's
designed just for you know common people
like like web designers CSS writers CSS
wasn't there yet CSS was invented
sometimes in 1998 or something and it
became kind of somewhat widely used it's
slow it became somewhat wider is used in
2000 by 2002 I would say somewhat why do
you use okay so anyway but JavaScript
today you know it there's a tremendous
change in tremendous shift you you know
you guys already know this front and
front end became became a thing by
itself it's extremely complex in
JavaScript today since since 2005 you
know yes
my script 2015 they introduced basically
they introduced like tens of new
features you know new semantics for the
language so basically say it's a
completely different language than
JavaScript before that okay in since
so the ACMA script 15 you know the since
2015 javascript has all the features in
perl python or you know p8 Python Ruby
you know whatever you know Ruby people
of Python people you know they they
might say you know advanced things like
oh you know decorators for example in
Python you can do that I mean well you
can do that in JavaScript actually I
don't think JavaScript has taken raters
but I think it's it's coming or omok or
something like that you know nowadays
like today every year there's a new
version of JavaScript so anyway however
you know JavaScript since 2015 is very
new I mean it's a new language kind of
however it's 100% compatible with you
know the JavaScript before that's that's
by their design that's their decision
they want to make it 100% compatible so
the advantage is that of course all the
old website we will still run well
mostly you know all the website you know
millions of website they will still run
however all the bad designs in the world
see you know the history of javascript
is still there so so today javascript
you know it's pretty very complex you
know very complex perhaps comparable to
C++
so let me talk about quickly about the
okay for example let me give you an
example of for loop in Java Script let's
magnify this let's see JavaScript object
inheritance properties functions loop
okay so the most basic photo peas you
know for well actually I'm using yes
2015 now so it's you know it's late but
there's a wire loop there's two wire
loop there's continued loop the okay so
there are these loops but the the four
in is actually something entirely
different
let me show you
so yeah let me show you quickly again
you know if you have comments you know
just say it you know because your
comment no questions direct which way
I'm going what I'm going to talk about
let's see
so yeah new people keep coming keep the
comment coming such an escape is to baby
language interactive okay I'll talk
about that a little bit wasn't Jabba the
one that popularized Opie yeah well I
was you know
yes Java Java is one of the program mean
language that popularized or P to the
top that that's that's like the hate of
Opie grace I would say around around
2002 2005 I would say but however I
don't know see first for us but I think
C++ introduced Opie to the general
population
but I don't know I don't know see first
press and you know I'm not in C+ first
communities I don't really know but
anyway sleepers trust introduced what we
the way we understand our he to the
industry
so yeah let me just go I was going to
talk about JavaScript the for in loop
it's very it's not what you think it's
very up so quickly okay for you
loop where do I find it for in loop
that's actually for looping through
objects but it's not what you think
it's snooping through object however it
also checks out the inheritance so you
know it's so you have object object in
JavaScript is simply a collection of key
value pairs so for example like pearls
hash table like rubies hash table like
pythons dictionary so in JavaScript when
you see the word object it actually it's
not what you think it's it's okay the
object in JavaScript is entirely
different from object in object oriented
programming of Java or Python or Ruby
okay so Java Ruby Python C++ they have
one concept of object in object oriented
programming but in JavaScript it's
entirely different so whatever you know
about olp in Java or Python or Ruby or
C++ is entirely wrong in JavaScript okay
entirely I mean if you want to
understand JavaScript first of all
eliminate forget about all you know
about all being in those languages in
those languages they are all P is kind
of similar so they have the same model
Java or Python or Ruby old or new C
press press or even PHP PHP added okay
sometimes in in the 2000s but javascript
is entirely entirely different so an
object whenever you see the word object
in any anywhere any tutorial or
reference you know the object means
think think of this way it's just a
collection of lists and value pairs like
hash table or dictionary okay
however there's one more thing added to
it every every hash table it will every
you know collection of key value pairs
they may have a parent which is another
object so you have a u so you have a
object that object usually have a parent
which is another object key value pairs
and each object can also have a children
can also have children you said one
children or more than one children god
but anyway any every every object key
value pairs can have a parent or K of
children now it's not necessarily they
have parents they can have no parent but
that's rare you can you can create an
object with our parent but however
almost all building object has a parent
so once you so so so what does a parent
mean it means whenever you want to look
about a key you know you want to see if
a key exists in a JavaScript object
javascript will check you know if it
exists if it does not exist exist if we
are look up you know it will check the
keys in that object's parent and if it's
not there it will keep checking you know
keep going up to the parents until there
is no parent then it returns you know
okay there's no such key and it returns
undefined so that so that's the nutshell
of JavaScript objects in JavaScript
object inheritance okay so it's it's not
like the Java you know object class or
you know there is no concept of class
but it's complicated because after 2015
they introduced the key world class
which kind of emulate you know the OB
model in Java
so it's you know entire the whole thing
entire thing is very complicated
very complicated if you ask a a ver
ajoomma script programmer they don't
know what the they are doing that's
true actually Adam you know I would say
more than 50 let's put it this way
precisely I would say more than 50% of
programmers who are programming
JavaScript as their main programming
language in a company you know it's the
way they make money you know
professional JavaScript programmers more
than 50% they they do not know much of
JavaScript you quantify it they do not
know what what percentage of German what
you know let's just say they don't know
you know they don't know the details so
what they do is that they just you know
they just copy what other people do like
simple syntax you know so when they when
they write for something in something
they think it's a loop but they don't
know it's actually checking their
parents so usually often you'll have
lots of bugs you know and that's just
one of the problems with javascript
javascript has lots of problems you know
because let me just okay let me show the
object chase functions object property
okay object property now let's forget
about that for example I mean it's going
to into detail so what I'll yeah maybe
that's it for JavaScript interactive xxx
so you know keep keep the comment
comments keep comments so I know you
know what
why was XML ever popular oh that's a big
story I like to talk about that okay so
let me cover the interactive India at
least let me show you jack
so interactive actually so okay so go
eMac please you know the best thing
actually is just to read this article
because interactive is not something
that's simple and I don't it's not that
useful for beginners okay so if you are
just beginning to program a program eMac
lists for those first few months or even
half a year I would say don't worry
about interactive you know don't you
know but if you want to know the details
I mean you can you can begin to
understand it by reading this page you
know so this is just my website you can
just search for sorry it is interactive
okay let's go here
so you go to practically Maglis and
you'll see here interactive foam you
know just just read it there because
it's not for begin it's you know you
have to understand several of the things
that's more useful than the interactive
so let's get back to okay XM XML so why
is XML popular so so XML you know in the
beginning there's in in a big in the
beginning there's HTML HTML began around
1990 okay it became along with web it
become became very popular beginning
around 1995 in 1995 they are not many
websites there may be 100 okay maybe -
let's say - 200 below 1000 is for sure
like the entire world there is only few
hundred websites and you use HTML but
before HTML there is a there is
something called sgml it stands for
semantic general markup language okay so
something like that so we have HTML we
have sgml sgml stand for you know I'll
look it up so so anyway HTML is a markup
language where you have hyperlinks you
know just like links you can click and I
was like told a totally new idea
that's like a innovation like you know I
remember reading on Time magazine you
know remember you know Time magazine is
not a programmers magazine but I
remember reading are on it and you know
all the magazines like every magazine or
newspapers they are telling people about
oh there's a new thing called
web you know worldwide web www
created by cyber punks you know
cyberspace and then there is the thing
called hyperlink meaning you know just
link you can click so you know all the
magazines they are trying they are
turning people about is you know how it
is a phenomenon you know like back then
like you know just like any new
technology today AI or whatever you
don't know if it's going to be popular
like you just hear it oh there's like oh
these crazy guys are creating that thing
and you go on with your life like you
have no idea what it's going to be
become so you know so this HTML there's
sgml G HTML is kind of a simplified
version of sgml I never really
understand the tech detail of sgml it's
very complex okay it's just one thing
you can be sure it's fairly complex but
basically the syntax looks exactly the
same as HTML HTML is like a subset of
sgml okay now back in 1995 each browser
is very competitive you know in the
beginning there's a mosaic from NCSA I
think NC ANCSA which stands for national
super computing Center I think NSC C
okay no that's wrong so anyway look up
mosaic let's do that mosaic is is the
first browser one of the first not
it's kind of slow disambiguation okay
most mosaic it's one of the first
browser I remember he using this browser
in 1993 and it's created by the
university NCSA here NCSA is National
Center for supercomputing applications
that's a fancy name but basic basically
it's I think it's a branch or something
of University of Illinois at
urbana-champaign and that is also the
headquarter of Wolfen research so
there's a affiliation between a
university and roof and research you
found research you know that's a guy who
makes Mathematica they often hire people
from you know University of Illinois and
actually I lived there you know I worked
for them for half a year in 1995 so I
lived in Illinois urbana-champaign do
every day you wake up you would smell
cow done well that's like kind of a
small country what they call university
town anyway so so okay in the beginning
there's a mosaic then Netscape took over
you know
mosaic mosaic is the NC you know the
National Center for supercomputing
applications is that's kind of an
academic organization it's not
commercial its kind of academic so
Netscape is the one who wants to
commercialize it so Netscape he they
created an escape as I think part of the
code is based on mosaic but then they
escaped then they okay so so Netscape
introduced a lot tax into the HTML and
for example one of the most famous is
blink like this
so if you have this code in HTML that
that text will just flash and to the
programmers
that's the worst feature the most lousy
and you know we don't like it and anyway
back then the the way attack HTML tags
are created is just by the company just
by ok so this a Netscape the Microsoft
introduced IE browser you know to
compete with Netscape you know and each
browser basically they are there are a
few other browsers but they are not
popular these two are the most popular
in each browser they create their own
tags like they invent like they invent a
new tag like you know for example one of
the popular ways is let me show you
this thing you see if you read some old
page you will still see DS so how does
this work
it basically Microsoft introduced this
invented this Microsoft ie introduced
this so you just so they created this
tag much code marquee tag so back then
every browser they just invent their own
tag you know they just amend it so that
you know you as a developer you know you
might think this is a great feature so
that means you use only their browser
and you tell your people you know this
this website is best viewed in netscape
browser or this space this website is
best viewed in IE browser you know you
tell people to use that browser so every
browser is you know they just invent
their tags so so at the time there is
already a standard kind of there's no
standard you know this HTML you know so
there's a HTML 2 standard coming up
because you know people start to think
oh then we need we actually need a
standard so that to prevent you know
each browser
you know just create their own tags you
know in you know to compete but still
you know you know you remember back this
is like a Wild West you know there's no
actual rules or governing body or you
know or you know law that says you know
this should be this way everyone just do
whatever you know see what happens you
know you can copy other people's website
you can do you know it's like today
there's a copy of you know pirated
movies you know that's that's all came
from like these you know so so nobody
knows you know so so anyway we have like
many years of these after ten years like
around 2002 Netscape so there's a
browser war but around 2002 Netscape
lost so Netscape went from like 99%
market
- like 10% of 0 you know so you know
Microsoft won't and Microsoft is but by
the way from my memory I the Internet
Explorer is in every way better than
Netscape technically ok it uses it uses
less memory it's faster it's more robust
it doesn't crash it it it also conforms
to HTML standard more and it conforms to
the CS CSS just created CSS you know so
in every aspect
Netscape is technically was so so you
know a lot of people you hear they hate
Microsoft you know they hate ie
I don't agree that said that's all
that's all a lie ok they lie
because they many of these people are
they like UNIX you know they like the
UNIX actually I think some Microsystems
the guy who started Java and UNIX the
Solaris is the worst in my opinion okay
in the back in those days I think it's a
worst ethically you know morally with
respect to ethical morality some
Microsystems is worse far worse also the
other thing about some micro system is
that they love creating jargons like
they just create jargons out of the blue
from their marketing department so you
know you have java one you have java
beans you have geni you have Java
Enterprise Edition you have Java you
know a bunch of just jargons format from
their marketing so actually I have a
article let me show you again let's go
to
jargons of software industry okay there
is a particular article I wrote about
the Java situation where the Sumiko
system created huge amount of
incomprehensible joggins purely for the
purpose of marketing I mean some micro
system is a scumbag you know and you
know from all the companies like every
every commercial company they do kind of
unethical things to advance themselves
you know but if you rank them you know
as far as I know job some micro system
is one of the worst I don't know if they
are worse than Microsoft to me some
micro system is worst that that's is
worse that's just my personal opinion
but of course today Google is far more
worse then they over them combined
Google Google and Facebook you know it's
interesting how you know history you
know how things change you know because
then today's you know generation they
don't know then I realize you know how
come you don't know because well they
wasn't born you know 10 20 years ago so
when you when I start to talk about
these things you know to them it's oh
he's talking about history like who
cares like history you know when I was
young you know you mentioned some
history about 1960s 1960s or 1970s you
know ideas operating system or whatever
you know this machines I think that's
interesting okay you know I don't care
like how do I know I mean I don't know
you know what what are they you know and
it's hard to know so today it's the same
thing I find you know it happens you
know so I when I talk about these things
Wow okay he's talking about history and
you know this you cannot so dislike that
that's why generation gap happens and
and also that's too
the natural happening you know every
generation things just move on you know
so so you have the same you know history
is important that's in the sense that
you actually you do want to understand
some histories because that's how you
can see you know why things are that way
and you can kind of guide your future
you have to you know
no of course history is not it's not
everything
anyway let's back to back to the Sun
Microsystems job ins J okay jargons of
software interest industry this one so
you go to my website and on the left
side you have this anti hack year 2k
panel you know index so here is a
collection of all the old rants wrote
they are written around 2000 2002 yeah
mm mostly around early 2000s so this
article jargons of software industry
this is written in 2002 and you can see
here the Java you know how they create
you know they'd love jargons like mock
you know marketing marketing job
ins so here's the jargons they create
oak jdk j sdk j2ee j2se Enterprise
Edition Java one Java 2 then they
changed so you have Java 1 point
something in Java 1.2 something then
they change the version so it's like
Java 2
so Java 1.2 is actually Java 2 then then
you know then there's another jargon
called Java one like oh and ye I think
that means that that means the
conference then then they have JFC they
have geni they have Java beans
entity beans oak swing you know you know
those you know they just came out from
some microsystem marking development but
by the way this is what's during the
time you know 2002 when people are suing
Microsoft because people accused
Microsoft of monopolies and of course
Sun micro system is one of them you know
they jumped onto the bank bandwagon in
Apple basically every enemy of Microsoft
they band together to you know trying to
get Microsoft ads you know it doesn't I
mean they okay didn't work because
Microsoft you know look at today
Microsoft is still around in fact it's
it's far more powerful than before you
know you go to LinkedIn that's owned by
Microsoft you could go to github that's
owned by Microsoft yeah you know
everything you Skype is on my Microsoft
then you have you know Xbox games and
stuff so what I'm saying you know a lot
of people still hate Microsoft at least
in the hacker community I am kind of
around I think and yeah you know I think
they are just wrong you know when you
want to like or dislike something you
want to be you don't want to just follow
ideology you know the UNIX philosophy
ideology you don't want to do that
because if you do that in the end it
does not help your go you know what is
your goal okay Michael you know almost
you know hacker types we want we want
companies to be you know not lie you
know they we don't want them to lie we
don't want to be devious we want them to
to be transparent about you know
whatever whatever data format they use
we want them to be open source if they
can although I don't you know I don't
particularly require them to be open
source but the data must be open and
whenever I want a data I must be able to
get it so I can switch I bring
systems or you know programming
languages you know so on so there are
these things we want and but most people
they just follow ideology they just you
know oh you must be open source we only
saw them as open source
oh oh oh they want people to you know
free software or they want you know oh
you have a manhattan monopoly we want
you know we don't want you that's wrong
because you don't consider all things
and you know and also most people they
want things to be free that's why all
the web sites are free you know Twitter
Google Facebook LinkedIn or are free and
what do you get in return well you get
it for free then but the side effect is
that you now have this entire you know
global evoke entire Google Facebook
Twitter they control everything they
know everything about you they they
monitor your every movement your photo
and cell phone Rosa the cloud computing
Rosa what's cloud that just you know put
your data into their computer so what
why does cloud Rosa because obviously if
you only want open source and if they -
open source they'll have no business
they cannot make a you know living day
because somebody will just copy it and
put a different name so they cannot do
that so they people find a way to
survive so they oh man let's do service
then then they're dead then you have
crowd you know and the force is so
powerful they and all the companies you
know keep lying they say whatever to to
make them more popular so they say oh we
provide crowd you know you don't have to
worry about your photos it's everywhere
you go doesn't matter it work at home so
you got crowd and what you're gonna you
know if you are you know the P open
source there's nothing you can do you
know because because you you were
pushing for something you know it's like
a balloon water balloon you squeeze here
it pops out
there you know you cannot just force
your ideology onto society it doesn't
work it you get worse you know things
it's not what you want okay so I
remembered a lot so it's back to okay so
how long I've been telling you Wow one
hour already so let's let me check the
comments so okay back to XML so why why
did xmlpk map Euler so let's go back to
mmm so we have s sgml and HTML and back
them every browser is inventing their
own tags so we started to have standard
bodies like you know the w3c stand the
bodies and then back then people
subscribe the idea that when you code
HTML sometimes you have syntax errors
right for example for example let's
create HTML okay so this is a HTML but
suppose you forgot the button so that's
an HTML but suppose sometimes two people
for god sometimes they okay so let's say
so this is HTML but sometimes people
forgot you know for example what if they
forgot that by mistake you know they
forgot a tag oh maybe they they they
typed something wrong here so what
happens so the common idea popular among
programmers you know the hackers geeks
is that you should there's a quote like
every one every programmer you can see
in their signature
they have this quote let me show
you everywhere
okay you don't know how popular that is
it's like every ten every year see it
almost every day every other day every
program like today like today on Twitter
or you know some blog you know this
quotes you know program I like to put
little quotes discourse signatures
doesn't happen much today be anymore but
but back then there is the one of the
the tremendously popular quote is this I
have a article that shows that somewhere
let me find it
so HTML history okay so the story of XML
so actually I have an article written
here already yeah that covers part of it
but let's find
okay give me I'll try to find it in few
more seconds if not let's try to
okay I don't remember where it is but
that's just such it okay the the quote
the saying goes like this be lenient in
what you accept be strict and what you
send out okay so I guess today it's even
hard to find okay here your bet
robustness principle okay here's a
famous quote it's created by a
Jon Postel
so it's called Pascal's law so here's a
quote we can be conservative in what you
do be liberal in what you accept from
others okay so it's often rewarded us be
conservative in what you send be liberal
in what you accept so what does that
mean so you will see this code every
other day in in around mm for for over
ten years okay so what does it mean that
means when you write HTML when you have
an error like that if you have a browser
implement implementer you know so when
you see an error like that you don't
want to stop the world you don't want to
say hey you got a error instead you just
quietly accept it you know like maybe
you can guess okay he probably means oh
I hear you know quietly fix that fix the
arrow and show show in a browser so
what's that they mean the other part you
know be be liberal in what you accept
that that's what it means because be
conservative in what you saying that
means you try to be you know you try to
create correct HTML but anyway because
of this quote what happens is that
99.9999% of web pages they are all
garbage the
or badly more foamed syntax so every
browser when you pass a HTML you have to
do 100 guesses that's why people that's
why people start to focus on browsers
like instead of creating a page you know
that's valid HTML people start to see
which browser is the most popular okay
so that's IE so everyone check their
website with IE and tell people to use
IE
that's it that's what happens because
each browser behaves differently and
because of this quote so people don't
people in general don't care about
correctness of the I mean because
doesn't matter the end result is that if
you show it in I it works so there is no
incentive you know there's no emphasis
on you know that it's correct syntax so
anyway so this went on for 10 years
ok so then people realized that's really
bad we need to fix this you know we
actually need the correctness concept to
be there so people want to have a HTML
that is very strict like that for
example if you have error if you missed
a character you mistyped something then
the browser will immediately tell you
you gotta arrow and refuse to render
that is xml so that is the origin of xml
and that is also the popularity of xml
so xml begin to become popular around
2002 and it's it's a craze i mean it's
it's it's like it's this it's one of the
greatest craze you know before we have
java that's a crazy you know write once
run everywhere then Perl you know the
the swiss army of programming languages
and then OB is one of them xml is one of
them back then once you so you started
to have xml which is very strict to this
day so ever
streak if you even missed a character in
your bracket it won't render in browser
so XML you know so people start to
understand and believe that the concept
that you know at least for HTML you want
to focus on correctness because that way
every browser will behave the same and
also you don't create you don't create a
situation where every page is invalid
syntax basically just like just random
soup there's no way to know exactly what
it means you know but every browser
accepted because they want to make them
browser look better you know like my web
page this displays okay in this browser
but not in that browser therefore I'm
going to use you know the IE browser but
in fact my HTML page is full of garbage
you know so people want to prevent that
so X XML concept the idea of correct
syntax becomes hugely popular and not
only that you start to have XML
databases XML programming languages
based on XML meaning that the whole
language the entire language programming
languages syntax is XML you know nest
nested bracket so so you have this whole
thing for like for basically ten years
okay for maybe eight years until the
html5 people came along which is which
is another very colorful political story
html5
Vinod Khosla
as far as ethnic you know with respect
to s thick is Google better or Apple is
better I think Apple is better but they
are both very bad they are both
extremely bad honey to say one is better
than the other that's that's would be
that would be misleading but if he I
think you know if you ask me if I have
to choose one I would I think now I
wouldn't even put it that way
Google is extremely and corrupted and
Apple is - Apple
you know what Apple do they so they they
have you know Apple is one of the comply
kever ething is green Oh Google - you
know they they they want they want
health healthy planet every day they say
they are machine use the least amount of
energy the factories or their buildings
uses you know green energy you know wind
power solar power everything they make
it you know they they market you know
they they make it beautiful and Apple in
even Apple operating system you can see
here let me show you you see
they even have a energy panel energy
panel showing that which process is
using you know is actually eating the
more energy actually this is kind of
popular now because from phone from
smartphone but anyway they they paint
this pretty picture but actually you
know Apple Apple Apple's iPhone or iPod
Co whatever I have a product they didn't
want to you to repair like they
intentionally design their battery
everything such that it's not
replaceable and there's not replacing
parts even if you go back to Apple to
have them fix it officially there's no
there's no they don't create parts to
replace you know parts they just want to
you buy the new one so what do you do
with the old one just
way extremely wasteful so you know why
they do that because money that way they
can you know get more money you know so
an apple you know Google on the on the
on the surface they are like poor
open-source you know Mac OS you have Mac
in the beginning of Darwin operating
system which is basically the source
code of Mac without the graphics layer
in others so you know in the beginning
like all the open source the the
programmers you know the hacker types
you see today on Hacker News you know
that the the type of programmers that
tells you what to do what should be done
you know they are like elite and they
work in big companies and they have you
know created you know they have a team
or they you know they are like
influences you know these these are
you know they so they so for example
back then we Apple have you know Darwin
always they say oh yeah we you know we
should support our Apple you know
because you know it's open source
yeah let's you know open source is so
great and also Google you know Google
you see Linux why because it's free it's
not because you know they they really
actually care about you know the you
know things well a little bit you know
for Google at least in the beginning in
the first ten years but anyway so Apple
and Google they are the they are one
they are the earlier companies that
really supported open source but you
know look at what they do do they really
care like each apple and and Google they
have thousands of patents you know
patents little things like trivial
things they have thousands of them so so
you know that's the thing
do you write all of your Emacs code what
do you mean do you mean I use everything
I use is written by myself no I use a
few packages but yes in general I I tend
to use just my packages
so anyway I think that's that's it for
today so that's a loan talk we are over
an hour and 15 now so any any other
questions any questions I missed
so any any more questions type it so I
think so that's it for today I've been
doing a lot videos you know when you do
videos you learn a lot of things and you
also get better so I can now I'm pretty
much you know I I still have a lot of
things to learn you know but I like
everything in life you know it's like
the old saying practice practice
practice
if you want to be really good at tennis
you practice tennis if you want really
be really good at programming you
practice that and so I've been doing
videos I've so I've learned you know the
have learned the software to use I
learned you know how to YouTube stream
and you know I'm getting better you know
I'm knowing better about technical
details you know I'm also better at
talking you know I want to say what I
feel comfortable in saying you know what
to talk about or what subject to talk
about or what kind of style you know and
and still there are many things I'm you
know I want to learn and improve I
probably may be one of the things you
know I'm thinking you know like today
like every time I talk about these
topics I get excited because I have so
much grant I want to get out but I'm I'm
thinking you know maybe I've felt that
you know perhaps I should not do it you
know in such a you know too much like as
almost like anger okay so maybe that
maybe I should not do that me but maybe
not but I mean maybe it's okay because
you know you know so you know because
I'm running a talk show and I don't you
know it's like I don't have exact idea
what exactly you know where to go
there's so many directions so you know
just do and see what happens so I hope
so I hope you guys liked video like the
talk show if you liked it you know
let other people know and comment in the
YouTube comments so let me know what do
you like to see next I should have I
like to invite more people like
especially Emacs people to come and I'm
working that out and so yeah let me know
what what do you like to see any
opinions put in the comments and see you
guys next time thanks bye