good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show
today we are going to do wufang language
mathematica so this is the about an hour
and i'm going to just called wufam
language and
before we begin let me mention so
we have this uh from a friend in
satisf carbena so here is xr tv in
virtual life
okay that's interesting
you know so virtual life is becoming um
becoming more popular again and i'm
going to
i'm probably going to start to get into
second life again so second life it's a
wonderful it's amazing uh world second
life
you have all sort of uh
things going on in second life okay so
but today we are going to code wufang
language okay so
and today we are going to code wolfram
language we are going to do find and
replace so let me show you
so let's see uh what what else here so
you are looking at my keyboard this is
kinesis advantage 2
and
then above it is ultimate hacking
keyboard so i have reviews here detailed
reviews
go buy them
so today we are going to code wufang
language so let's start
woofam desktop
okay and where is it
so wolfram desktop new
new um
notebooks so one plus one plus one
evaluate two fantastic
okay so let's magnify and put it here
and we also we are going to write a find
and replace script in wufang language or
woofam script
uh
okay so you know
if you don't know
so i have a full tutorial just go to
search for sal lee wufang
sardi wufang language
so here i give you an introduction where
to download it for free what is the
difference between wufam language
you know download it for free or you can
buy a raspberry pi it comes with it free
it's free for personal use you know read
their you know agreement in and whatever
and then i tell you what's the
difference between wolf and language
mathematica will from engine will from
script you know the
what's the difference is
what it's kind of confusing so here
then
and then
you know i have a wolfram language emacs
woofer mark saw mod for coding wolfen
language in emacs you can pay me and buy
it get it
okay
so
then i tell you i give you a tutorial
the best tutorial one of the best
tutorial about wolfram language syntax
and wu from language tutorial i've done
about 10 or more than 10 videos on
wolfen language so you should check it
out
so
uh then wufram script you know so this
is one of my video on wufam script so
today we are going to write
um
find and replace script so let me show
you what that is so if you have common
questions post it okay about wolfram
language
uh welcome guys
so we so i have written you know find
and replace is the one of the things i
do
uh all the time like doing you know
uh thousands of files about
ten thousand twenty thousand html files
find replays every day because about
few times a week for the past
15 years
find replace find and replace for a few
thousand ten thousand files
about two or three times a week
for the past 15 years that's what i do
so i have find replace script written in
python
so and i have a tutorial and code you
can find on my website
so um
you know in python
and several you know in python in golan
in perl
in emac lisp and i i did a video about
these uh
several times in the past just search
for it on youtube
and
you know so find replays
so there's uh you know
when you know i have a script for my own
use for example so you know these
different languages but i also have a
tutorial so what does what does it
involve when you want to write a find
replay script by the way these are all
practical practical for me so i wrote
them because
for one thing
when i started to learn the language i
write the tool
the second reason is that
since i use these tools so much so i
have uh different versions in different
languages you know so and i can also
explore because since i'm interested in
programming language
features design how they you know how
how they it feels and um
you know so i have uh in different
languages
so what does it take to write the find
with replace script so you need to know
how to traverse a directory
that is list all files in your directory
and its subdirectory you want to uh and
also you need to know
so let's go back to talk show and i
forgot to mention you also to know you
need to know so i have i have it written
out here
how to filter
by
file
extension file name extension okay so
that's another thing you need to know
how to list directories how to filter
files by
by a file name extension for example you
want to to find replace on all html
files only or css files only or
javascript files or whatever java
whatever
and you need to know how to make
how to copy file you know in in a
language say python go land perl or lisp
how do you copy a file because you need
to do that
if you want to do backup you know you
usually before you
do thousands of files you want to
do a backup before you do the find
replace just in case you made a mistake
so you need to know how to copy file
then you need to know how to open a file
how to write to a file and then you also
need to know open file for read open
file for right and you also need to know
how to
um
find and replace a string given a string
how to replace certain regular
expressions
so each of these are the individual
tasks you need to know when when writing
or find replace script in a new language
and that is
exactly what i'm going to show you today
in wufang language
i did a video before uh but it's uh but
you know uh like a few months ago about
this but let's do it again because each
time it's different
okay so if you have a questions and
comments posted okay so let's begin so
first of all how to list directories in
subdirectories okay
so
for that question
let's go to um
because i have already
written a tutorial
so
let's use you know that's what i
typically do use my own tutorial to
to remember you know as a reference
so list files so this is how you list
files okay so let's let's begin to code
wufang language
um
[Music]
let's see how we're gonna do this
so i'm going to start buffing language
then so you are looking at wufam
language and you are looking at my um
let's see 17 okay magnify the found even
more so
so this this is you are looking at my
buffer language mod kusawu from language
mod wait wait where is it okay it's
hidden the file name is too long so the
mod
the mode line is
is like hidden there so this is someone
from language mods so for example you
can
uh let me demonstrate a few things okay
so
expand okay
uh
x
squared plus x
y third
power
and
raise the whole thing to the third power
comment this out and run the script
okay so actually you need to print it
you need to run and print so look at
lookup um
okay f9p f9p
so you see the result at the bottom so
uh you know over here you can see so
let's go to the message slide so close
that yeah
so you can see here's a result
and if we do this in
in the notebook you see that there's a
result nicely formatted so that's wu
from language free
get it today
okay so we demonstrated that uh and you
know notebook and the wolfram language
casa will find mod in emacs so what so
we're gonna do so first of all so let's
focus let's get back to
list directories and subdirectory files
so this is how you do it
so we are going to write find replace be
sub but before we do let's create a
directory with a thousand files okay
uh emacs okay so let's i'm just going to
create a directory so
so here's the emax manual so there are
two directories lisp and emacs in this
directory there are
a thousand files this is emacs manual
you can download it from the glue emacs
website so emacs directory you have also
about 700 files so this
so let's copy the
okay so let's go to talk show
go here
and
copy
this lisp directory recursively yes
so we are going to use this as a
now let's rename the file rename it to
xtest okay
so here's the directory so close that
okay
so here's a directory with a thousand
files
so you can see
we are going to do find replace on this
directory
okay so copy the file path
okay close it close it um then go back
to our code
where's our code
okay here yeah go back to our code so in
this directory okay
uh that's kind of big directory um
let's hold on a second so let's remove
let's move them up
sorry info
okay so
move it here
so rename it xx test okay so here's it
okay copy the file path close close
close
and paste it now it's shorter it's
better so this is how you get the file
names you you want to find all files in
all html files in
this file path directory path okay run
it
it's yeah it's a thousand files okay you
need to show the output so let's call
different commands so there it is that's
all the files
um
so now it's hard to read because
everything is in a single line so let's
call a command
subspace to new line
okay so that makes
you know each space you separate it into
a new line so this
this is how you
so you can see a thousand files
so let's turn on global high line mod so
you can see where my cursor is so you
see
a thousand files so this is how you
list all files in your directory okay
and you want to know the documentation
just press the key in casa emacs because
i will find mod you can press the key
you can see the here's the documentation
for
uh
the file names function of wufam
language let's turn on javascript
okay so that's how you list all
directories oh and you want to give
another option
you want to give another option that is
the depth so so usually you say infinity
okay
in
infinity okay
so that uh
that you know so that means like in in
unix jargon it's called recurse
recursion okay
so okay so all directories okay so
that's one thing so next next
what is the next task we want to solve
okay so this is how you traverse
directory
uh so let's
let's it's um
let's move that up let's put that
so there is our code and let's add
syntax coloring go back to browser
refresh there it is this is how you
traverse directory what's the next
how to filter file by name
by file name extension there it is we
know how to do that how to copy your
file okay
how do we copy your file so
so
i don't know off hand but we can just
try it here
copy file there it is
okay so file copy so this is how you do
it
okay so let's look at the documentation
this is how you copy your file copy file
file path one file path two
okay and the file path can be remote as
well that's the power of language
okay and it and and the file path can
also be a url you know on online website
so
you know instead of the unix cp
then you have to use
uh you know uh
what is it scp and other you know
commands or or rsync or whatever so
muffin language
what one of the design of wolfram
language is that a function
maximizes
what the function name
all possible thinks the function name
is fit to do for example copy file
so any url is also considered file you
know that's what anyway that's the
digression that's one of the wolfram
language design principle so a function
you usually have options to do all
possible things related to the function
name copy file
so it's not just
copy file for the current you know local
machine but it can be url and so on
so anyway so for our purposes all we
need is
um let's remove the syntax coloring and
by the way the pink window shows all my
emacs command line command cores and the
key
stroke i press
okay so
so copy file so yeah so okay so we want
to copy file copy file so
let's uh
create a new one
copy file okay so you need to give a to
give to path so let's um
let's for example let's go to the lisp
sample file
so copy file needs two arguments so this
is one
this is the second so let's say name it
two okay so if we run it
then we will see a new file here we
should okay
run it
okay
a warning comma encountered with no
adjacent expression oh
error so wolfram language does not allow
the
you know the last comma so if we refresh
yeah copy fail okay let's do it again
okay done
shell success now refresh
you can see we got a new file or copy of
the file okay
so so that's how you do copy file
so now next step
get date in iso format
for backup okay so why we why do we need
to get a date because when we copy
usually i i want the
um
the copied file to be named something
like
something like um
like this okay let me show you what
so okay um
okay the the file path is kind of long
but you can see i wanted you know to
have a date like that and with a tl dot
so that's a emax convention for backup
file
so
so you need to
generate today's state and usually your
time time
in second as well
so because after a while you have lots
of backup files you don't know which one
is from by what task
so
the next thing we need to do is how do
you get the date and in a particular
format okay
for that question i already have an
answer here wu fam script
tutorial so
let's see delete the directory
uh check file existence
date okay
get file date okay that's a file date
but we want date time so
so here is how we get date time
okay
but which format we want
we want
[Music]
let's just say let's pick a simple one
okay
so
so the date will be let's let's let's do
in uh
some of the mod okay so get date now i
also so let's say
now date equals to
that okay
so we don't need that
okay
run it
so you can see the date is at the bottom
output okay can you see it actually and
see what
yeah
[Music]
okay so
this is how you get the date
now
now let me show you some other uh
variations okay so actually
copy the tutorial
go to the talk show open today's talk
show
paste the reference link here
um
shown in browser
okay so we have a link here
and we want to now we want to
date yeah work on the date so how do you
what is this emacs blog
okay so yeah date about date um
okay
let's let's
let's try that one
okay run it
okay you can see
you know the the second one returns that
result now usually i want the backup
name to have
time as well
but however i don't want the
i don't want the
colon because colon is usually a problem
in file name systems on the mac for
example colon is actually allowed
but it's
you know but underneath it has to to do
a lots of complicated file name
conversions because the unix file system
wait
you know in the old mac file system hfs
plus it does not
it allows
the you know okay so
let me explain this so in the unix in in
the unix tradition
okay okay so in the mac in in mac os
tradition the colon is used as a file
separator you know analogous to the unix
slash okay so on the mac mac os you know
in the 1990s
micro is classic
the colon is not allowed in the file
name
now mac as far as file system you know
allowed characters is concerned mac is
the best
between unix mac and
and windows mac is just best it allows
the most possible number of characters
anyway so i have lots of articles on
that you know that's kind of history now
anyway so max switched to unix
with starting around 2001 with mac os x
that's mac os 10. so now you have the
issue where
you know so mac before allows the
backslash but now if you are in unix you
know you gotta you're gonna have
problems with backslash so there's so
what the apple people did is that they
did a lot engineering behind the file
name system so that
so that essentially you get the best of
both worlds words
but however so it's there's some
complexity anyway so this is related to
um
file name okay so let's let's let's
digress and show it
you know when it comes to unix i have 1
000 rents okay so and i'm not going to
turn today's talk show to into a unix
strength any comments
questions and comments
okay i'm gonna read that read them in a
bit
okay so i have several articles
on file name okay because this is one of
my concern
okay so let me show you one by one so
unix file name character problem unix
file name characters problem
this is written in 2006 unixes
problems okay that's
so
go to talk show and just log what we
talked about so i'm just gonna paste the
link here so unix file name characters
problem okay unix is the worst
and then and linux linux inherited it
and here is rob pike
on the origin of unix start file names
dot file names is another
crap you know it liters elites your
directory with a bunch of
file files your files irrelevant to you
the
and it turns out it's a mistake okay rob
pike explains the history of it rob pike
is one of the
um one one of the pioneer
which did a lot contribution to unix
operating system and he also wrote other
operating systems
plan 9 and so on and he also he's also
one of the creator of the golan
which turns out my favorite language one
of the
one of my favorite languages so rob pike
on the range of unix file name okay
then unique star problem
file length truncation unicode name
support
one
you know it is it's it's
worst possible you know unix
first of all unix truncate silently
truncate your file names
your your files for example you have if
you have a directory you need to move it
to another machine for example or you
need to travel to china or something so
you tie it
but if your file name is too long more
than 120 characters
it silently truncates your files
in the tar
so when you expand you're missing your
file name is no longer the same it's got
truncated unix
that's not that's not the only problem
then you have the unicode support
problem so if your file name is chinese
characters for example you are
okay
you you tie it up
and you put it on usb or whatever back
then you you know
you put it on a you know portable disk
you know back then back then you don't
have a usb
disk yet around 2000 around year 2000
okay so you type your directory
then you're gonna you know send it to
someone or as a backup when you untie it
your file names all have gibbyish names
you know
because they are chinese characters or
they contains a
arrow or something you know
as unix
the worst
up in the computing industry
so this article is written in 2011 okay
so you got the detail about
uh
about the you know why and how
that's a unique star problem
glue top most specific it uh happened to
a few tasks okay it's it's uh the
problem is over
uh
you know it happened to data a truncated
file name because i remember in
1996 around 1996 i was moving a file
from 1998 maybe i was moving a file on
i-rex
you know the
irix operating system of the sgi fame
silicon graphics
you know computer one of the big names
in unix and
when you untie it it truncated your
files i i didn't know i just found out
you know it up my files
and and
unicode is another reason okay that's uh
that's about that
then
uh so this article is a tutorial on the
unix file permission system another it's
another
hair it you know pain in the ass
you know root wheel you know unix file
name permission system pseudo
it's a
hack of the hacks okay
but this article is just a tutorial
telling you what what it is
and and here is an article
this is a perl code
that
check
bad file names you know file names
containing characters that's not allowed
typically we'll up your unix
commands
you know for example you have these
um yeah typically you don't want files
using these characters
uh so this is a perl script that checks
your directory your file names okay this
i so this is written actually this is
written in 2009
but i put it up on this page in 2021 so
uh and this article on unix file systems
case sensitivity another
giant
perpetual
controversial topic
you don't see it much today
but back in 90s or early 2000s it's a
perpetual perennial topic
you know whether file name should be
case sensitive or not and unix is the
worst okay just about everything when
you look into detail the unix way is
just the worst
was
possible
because why because unix
unix people the unix philosophy the c
language they don't think you know they
just oh this this works that's it
this works and it's simple it's fast
that's it they don't they never think
about
about problems
unix file name system case sensitivity
issue this one is written by this guy
okay who is that guy that guy is from
yeah that guy is an expert of bos okay
which was killed by open source linux
around the year 2000 bos
okay so
so that okay so we have that
and okay that's these that's the
articles okay
so showing browser we have a log of what
we talked about
so file name so we are talking about
file name issues
um
so let's go back to yeah so
okay so yeah that's a digression about
using slash or colon in file names
so what i was saying is that
we want to
you know i want the back file name
backup file name hold on a second
okay sorry
no sound
okay so
so okay so we we know how to do
string replays okay the next thing we
need to do is how to write to a file and
read to a file okay so here already so
let's just copy it right to a file
and read to a file so read and write
okay showing browser
so
we have all the things we need to do all
the you know individual tasks on how to
write a script to find and replace a
thousands of files now let's put them
together so let's now
let's
put them together
on how to do this okay
so is the audio back i think it's the
audio back
uh sound is fixed yeah so
you can hear okay chocolate is used
for lots of recipes okay
okay i'm
i'm good now
um so now
let's
find and replace strings
in uh so this is the wolfram languages
comment syntax so
we are beginning to write this script so
input okay so
input wheel equals to
okay so wait
there it is
okay input directory and backup
make backup
true
okay
um
the
the depth
infinity okay
so these are the parameters
date
so input directory
uh make backup the depth
find replace pairs okay so this is going
to be a list
of find and replace pairs so we're just
going to have one pair so what what kind
of word do you want to find so let's see
let's open one with a file
let's say we want to find um
this string okay
okay let's let's say let's say we want
to find this string so
that
and replace it by x y z just for testing
purposes okay
so
this find replace pairs we should this
script should be able to
to find replace on multiple pairs in one
shot okay not just not just the unix set
crap
so this is one pair
okay so wait
this is one pair let's add another pair
okay
so let's add another pair let's
let's say
let's uh expanding okay let's
let's let's pick some words okay
commands let's
replace all the word
commands by
x commands okay something like that
and let's do another pair
and
this will be something
not there okay like a string you will
not find it you know just for testing
purposes okay so multiple pairs of find
replace pairs and and this can be a
regular expression but we haven't
showed how to do that yet
okay
so let's see what else so file names uh
so
files okay
file list
equals to
file names
html
so file this equals to get file name
file name extension okay file name
that's another let's add another
variable
okay
so this is the extension we need to do
the find replace
with
okay
okay so now we got the fire file list
uh
input.depth okay then what else
then we want to make backup okay
we need to open file so wait
so
for each file so we want to map okay so
map
map function
to file list okay
and level one okay so
so we want to map a function to all
these files and what this function do it
will
first of all backup the file make a copy
back up the file then open the file then
do the string replacement then save the
file okay so this is uh
the function
let's call it
process file okay so map this function
to the to this list okay so we have to
define process file okay so
uh we have to define process file okay
so
let me show you how to write a function
okay so
so process file okay so let's write it
in the most simple way you know wufam
language has a lot of ways to do things
but for
for our purposes let's write it in the
most
plain
simple way
you know it means it doesn't look fancy
you know
if you are doing a demo
you know in some conference so you want
to
something cryptic like the unix and see
people would love something cryptic you
don't you you can't understand the thing
like all the shortcuts you know
but let's not do that for now
let's just use the most simple anyone
who never programmed before can read it
and can see what is going on can
understand it that's one of the power of
wufam language
as a choice you can also do it the other
way you can write the wolfram language
using
methods such that the result code is
more incomprehensible than perl
i'm telling you that okay because i have
i can show you examples but how long
have i been talking 44 minutes let's not
so wufam language you can write in a way
you can code it in a way because of the
flexibility of the syntax you can code
it in a way
such that
everything everything the entire
language is just a nested expression
just like lisp like that
like that you see
purely nested and just function names so
you can understand the whole program by
just reading the function names
okay or you can write it in a cryptic
way such such as this this is not even
cryptic enough there's small there's
more you can write it in a cryptic way
that's even more incomprehensible than
perl
and
the the thing is that you can press the
button to convert either one of these to
the other for example let me show you
okay let's copy that by the way i talked
about this in one of my videos the full
hour is about the syntax
wolfen language syntax so you see i i
you know if i evaluate this what do we
get okay this is a bunch of you know a
list of lines okay so now if i press the
button uh let's remove this
you see i press a button
i have a shortcut but you know this this
is just uh
shift
okay shift ctrl t okay so
so that's that's these shortcuts okay
input you know so i can just press the
button and look look at how they change
okay so
traditional form and
okay
uh
but you you
you know you can convert them back to
this form all you have to do is um
oh okay so you want to actually hold
there it is
did we get it right
now because you have to hold the set
okay anyway i talked about this single
uh in one of my video before
so that's a bit digression so let's get
back to what are we doing so we need to
write a process file function okay
so
what does this function do
the first argument is a list of
variables okay
the second argument is what the function
will actually do
so
the function
what we will do is we will take one
argument file name okay
then do whatever okay let's save three
for now
so you take your file name
okay then it will
open the file okay
it's
backup first
open the file
do stream
replacement
save file okay
that's what the function will do so
we're gonna need we're gonna write that
so first of all backup okay so backup is
easy that line
so backup so you just
file name
so this is actually file path so let's
just change it better
reflect what we are actually doing so
file path
the new file path will need a date okay
so you need the date
okay so but before we give a date let's
we need a we we want a constant we want
to assign this to a date okay so
so what we can do is um so actually so
let's let me show you okay
so uh wait not modular
module okay so what this do
the function module
is analogous to lisps
let
okay so the function module is analogous
to this
let so i can so now
i can put this here so
the second argument is what is the body
okay so the body will be
joined string okay
uh string join
okay string join two arguments
uh
so the first argument will be the file
path
the second argument will be the date
okay so you can see
can you see these
these together
is the backup name
backup file path name so
before we join we need we also want um
let's look up the documentation for
joining string
yeah so you can have multiple arguments
correct
okay so multiple arguments so now you
need
i
want a tilde
and another tioda here
okay so
you know for example we can run this and
you'll see
what it does
uh string join
what string join string expected oh we
don't yeah the file path of course the
file path is something slash some
xyz okay
there it is you see that's a
module is a let
like a lisp sled it defines local
variables
then here's a list of local variables
here's the actual body okay
so that's that part then
yeah so
then
then this this copies the file okay so
that's the backup
now once you do the backup
now you want to open the file okay how
do you open the file open the file is
read stream here
okay now
this is getting um
[Music]
big so
so actually i need a module here so let
me i mean put the
put the
let here
so
let me show you
what's going on okay
okay so this is the body
move the whole body to
here
okay
and move the date module
i mean the date variable local variable
there so you don't need the module here
anymore
so module takes two arguments
one is a list of variables
so we have a date there then first of
all we do backup
uh yeah so actually this is shrink okay
so backup then open the file okay so
open opening the file
will be
so you need opening file uh content okay
content equals true
so you need a variable content let's put
it here
so content is actually we can put the
whole content
here
so content reader string file path
that's right
opening file is already open so now we
need to do string replacement okay how
do you do that how do you do that here
string replacement
so we want to replace
uh we want to replace the string will be
here for our content and
and what string we want to replace well
we need to do a loop because remember
we have a list of strings okay
so let's just remove that and make it
simpler so
so find replace pairs we need to loop
through these
pairs of strings so how do we do that we
need
another
um okay we need a loop
okay so
you know before we do loop let's make it
let's
make it simpler okay let's just say
should we
what's up guys
so am i doing good
so
55 minutes okay it's already an hour so
okay we're gonna go fast okay so it's
so now we need to do a loop through so
usually you use map
okay so
find replace pairs
that's your list
okay and you need to map a function so
the function is going to be replaced be
this function okay
so the function will do that
[Music]
uh
so the the the
string replacement okay string
replacement
so
each one
the first element in the find replace
pairs okay the
so this needs to be a function actually
so
okay let's write it in
let's write it in a cryptic way and it's
not
so map the function the function takes
one argument let's call it x okay
so x
x
is
a pair in the find and replace
okay so
x
one
that means the first part of x that is
the find string okay
and replace by
x two
that is a replacement string okay
so map this function
let's say pair instead of a
pair okay
actually
you don't want a map because you want a
loop
because once you
wait do you want the map or loop
okay so this is actually getting complex
because there's an issue
where once you replaced it
should the new replacement
should should the next find replace pair
be based on
anything
anything of the previous new replacement
text or not
usually you shouldn't
but so you okay so it's getting complex
so find replace pair so
so first pair let's play a function so
we
if we do a map no we don't want the map
because map it just returns a
you know a list of the new contents for
each of the replacements so you you want
a recursion instead
you want a recursion or a loop
so that okay so let's just
let's just do recursion then
so
so let's okay so nest okay
so nest is the
nest is the function to call when you
want recursion so next
two arguments the first argument is a
function okay so let's grab it
okay the first argument is a function
then the second argument is the
is the beginning
argument
uh okay so
if we do nest then we have a problem of
how do you get
the pairs
okay it's more and more problems
um
yeah okay so
so for example i can show you what nest
does okay so if you say nest f
then 10 it will just nest f
with the first argument of x
you know then 10 times for example you
know that's what happens with next
so
next
i mean nest so nest is
is kind of what we want but however
in this nesting we need to get the pairs
for each iteration we need to
get that and how do you
so actually so what you want is um
okay so let's think about this issue so
you want a function that essentially
recurses
but each time
you want to get one of the pairs
so
so some sort of
map and nest together so you know you
know there's a lot there's a tons of
functions in from language for this kind
of thing
that's why
um
and there are so many ways to write it
you know we can you know we can do it
the
dummy way or
fold okay fold is what we want
that's right fold is what we want okay
fold
now fold in
in in javascript for example it's called
reduce you know in javascript in python
it's called reduce you are familiar with
that okay let's write fold so forth
three argument f
x
list okay so the list is just
find replace pairs
and the starting argument
is
we don't need the starting argument just
take it from the pairs okay
then
then the function
right the function is this one okay
so you see wufang language is kind of
you know you can you can see it's all
nesting so it's a bit hard to read
but however for example if you paste
this for example let's make this one
line if you paste this in
the notebook
it formatted for you automatically you
see the truncation and syntax going and
all that you see
and it's this is intelligent formatting
you see how they wrap the lines
at the proper place
so you can see you are calling fold and
you have two arguments
so the first argument is a function
now the function is again break broken
into two lines now depending on how wide
is your screen
you know it it format them in a sensible
way
you see
okay so and and this
not just work for plain text it also
works for complicated um
expression such as this one
well including when there's a radicals
you know anyway square roots and so on
so anyway so let's get back to this so
fold is what we want okay so fold the
function
the function okay so here the function
takes the one argument which is pair
and
yeah that should do it oh the function
also each time
now this is incorrect each time it needs
to write the new content to
um to you know
after it does a replacement it needs to
write to the content
okay so this is the do string
replacement part then save the file okay
save the file is simple
save the file it's just that
so right string
so why is there two arguments so what's
the second argument for
file and string oh file path and string
okay easy so the
uh
the
the string is the content the file path
is just
that okay
okay so i believe this is a complete
program to do this
now let's let's remove these comments um
okay so let's
copy the whole thing i mean like we can
run this we can try to run this
in emacs or we can run it in the wolfram
notebook
so let's try to run a ufo notebook copy
or
paste
because it looks
good here
so here's a whole program
praise to god it works
let's put some comma here
comma so once we do this so process file
is a function then here is the main map
process file to the file list
okay file list is here
place to look the load it works this is
the demo the mother of all demo
part spec is longer than depth of object
that means here
no string replace okay we got some kind
of we got a
we we got a empty
comma something oh here yeah so
yeah you see it's it's it's trying to
you know it's in
interpret in um interpret
these two lines as a multiplication you
see because we are missing you see
we are missing a semicolon here
semicolon okay there it is
do it cannot override existing
file uh copy file cannot overwrite
existing files so what's going on so
copy file file path
wait which part is destination which
part is the target
copies from the local remote or cloud
file file 1 to the remote cloud file 2
okay so
the first is a source
the second is the destination target
and here we have
string join file path
yeah string join and now date
and that should be right
so copy file cannot
overwrite existing file oh i think
that's a windows problem
you know because in windows once you
have a file open
okay what is this
yeah that's right
that's what happened
i think you know in windows once you
have a file open
it doesn't let you
delete the file yeah so we need to close
this in emacs i think that's what
happens so let's try it again
do it
okay cannot override the existing file
construct dot html okay what's going on
let's look at the file
construct
oh okay so this file
what's going on open it
refresh
so you see it made it made backup
already you see all these are backup we
made
but why is it cannot override or
whatever
and switch to html mod
why does it say cannot overwrite
copy file cannot overwrite existing file
that
okay i don't understand
then part specification
is longer than depth of object okay so
function pair
so we got do we have the pair right
so we got three pairs in need this one
that one
and that one three pairs okay
um
[Music]
string replace pairs
replace
replace the content
by this
pair
[Music]
wait we are doing fold okay wait fold
oh remember we are doing fold okay so
fold takes the first pair
[Music]
wait fold takes two arguments okay so we
are
okay yeah fold remember fold takes two
arguments
[Music]
yeah the problem is somewhere here
v-o-r-n-g-o what does that mean
[Music]
so
question the dude how hard would it be
to use fulfillment language to create
geometric patterns like the one found in
persian architecture and actually export
the geometry for using other 3d it's
extremely easy
if you have watched my previous video
you might know
but i can show you if you just search
for sally
you know math blog star math blog in
fact i have written a package which
one time i demonstrated so this is the
wolfram language package i wrote in 1997
[Music]
why is it so slow so this package i
wrote it does geometric patterns
probably you know
similar to what you were saying these
were islamic patterns
by mathematical categorization so
so you call a function
and you it can generate these patterns
then you can export to all
possible
3d or 2d software format
in existence
like all pi like like
you know if you want to
ask the question which
programming language or application that
supports the most extensive
3d or 2d formats or movie formats
of all software
which software that supports the most
that would be wufam language
okay so
um you know and you can easily
verify that you know just search for
3d format okay it will show you tons
like things you never heard of
you know this so there's a format
building symbol date format so
stream format number format
so you want to
you know the easiest way is actually you
go to the wolfram language
visualization and graphics
um
[Music]
import and export okay
so you can see
import and export so click on export so
you got this export function
and you can see export format
you can
import export data or sound or files or
there's so many uh so but
what we want to know is okay so this
multimedia formats
this raster image formats
there is um you know you are looking for
3d formats right something like that 3d
or 2d like autocad and things like that
um
you know this is just so many so you
know for example here's the multimedia
formats okay
mp4 avi falv quicktime
matraska ogg and so on
um
actually i think there's more the i
think you know there's more
raster image format okay so for example
click on that
you know so here is you know raster
image format
all possible formats in human history is
here
um but we are looking for
okay so this is again so this is my
package that does what you are
asking this is you know but
you don't have to you know
if you are doing you know this package
has many features but you can just
code it
using building functions for the basic
things
so you are looking for so there's a
vector and graphics format
oh there it is so svgdxf
autocad eps
postscript pdf but there's more okay so
i mean you are looking for for example
3d print
3d printing format okay so there it is
3d geometry
open that 3d geometry and modeling
format so p l y d a e o f f i don't you
know i don't know colada
there there you have it so you can
export to them
just call the export function
okay so i kind of digressed and we have
we you know we actually haven't finished
this problem
right now the problem is this
fold and we are already
over 80 minutes
70 minutes so
does that answer your question the dude
so how many people are watching probably
yeah fantastic
uh so
you know so we haven't actually finished
this
task you know and and i wanna
i'm gonna chicken out you know they
always
didn't finish the problem but
so
so there's a little problem
that's not working so
the problem is
fold
so
you know the problem is really because i
didn't think
through so fold
you take the first element
so fold takes
default takes two arguments yeah so
so that is
why i'm wrong fold takes the function
takes two arguments
yeah because each time you need to yeah
you know that's why they it's called
reduce kind of
so
so the argument yeah so true argument
the first argument would be
the second argument would be content
okay
wait the content should be the first
argument
okay so we need to add
this is the first argument we need add
content here
okay
i think
yep
let's try it
okay it's uh it's got problems now i
don't understand why cannot override
existing file
what's what
why is this
refresh
open it
open all these backup files we made
first of all delete them okay
let's just delete them
now
cancel
okay it's still running
uh
cancer evaluation
old
dots okay so
do it
cannot assign to raw object
string replace okay
alt dot
so we got
cannot assign
so we got the function
we got the function that
takes two argument content in
pair and
the function
so this is the body of the function
now
oh okay so you don't want to assign it
that's right
okay so let's just try it okay
okay for some reason once you
once the wolfram language generates the
backup
somehow it creates a permission so that
you cannot override it again
and this is actually screwed up this is
not what you see this is oh this is
error so
wait it's open original
you know i think okay so
cancel so actually i think i screwed up
the file
let's open a small one it's you know
yeah because you see
it wasn't it doesn't look like this
before somehow it got screwed up you see
it
i think it just
repeated the content so actually we're
gonna do this again so
close that
go up a directory actually open it
delete all
backup
delete all files in this directory okay
delete yes
but
deletion failed
okay
why is that failed
do it
yes
permission denied okay
so i know what's the problem so if you
open the directory
so somehow
somehow when wu film language writes to
the file
it
changed the permission so that it cannot
be written to again
for some reason
so
for example now
can we delete them
you see the action cannot be completed
because the file is opening wolfram
kernel okay that's why
okay so let's restart wolfram
quit kernel local
quit yes
okay
then go back to emacs
d this file yes okay done select all
delete delete
yes delete all
done
okay
and it's
wait what
permission denied what
why is permission denied i don't get it
delete yes
yes
select or
delete yes
oh it works it worked
okay now
now you go to emacs blog
and copy the manual here again open this
select all copy
so now we have a fresh copy of emac this
menu okay
and now we can
try our find replace again
okay so now let's run this code
do it
okay i think we uh this error we are
it up
oh okay no so okay
so now let's look
let's look
okay so
let's check if our code
works correctly so initial
there shouldn't be any word
containing initial
but however there it is so it's not
correct
what about the word command
search for the word command in this
directory
okay so
there's a lot of currencies of the word
command
so our script actually
is not working correctly
so debug more debug
okay but i think that's it for today
so you are my inspiration in idol thank
you
okay but so if you guys like my stuff
pay me okay that
that is actually you know what makes
you know that that you know that
that's how
that's what makes the world go around so
if you like my you know video buy me a
drink okay and that's it for today so
you russian people what is this
abbreviation
please show here sir what kind of okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
bye
shutting down in two minutes two minutes
so this
yeah but we didn't do it successfully
that's obama that's not
right so
we need to fix this
oh right that's right we didn't actually
write to content that's right we didn't
write to the content that's right
so so okay so let's try this so the
function
okay so
content equals to
content
equals true
that's
there
do it
i cannot override the existing again
so
so basically once wolfram language
writes to the file there's a permission
problem so let's look at let's look at
let's solve this problem
once the wolfram language writes through
the file somehow it made it
so that you cannot modify it again
oh you have to close file
let's see
bye guys bye
so
delete
and
cannot write to file so
stop kernel create kernel
local
quit
delete them
okay
now
this time let's just
let's not copy the whole thing let's
just copy some of them okay
so
now if
now let's
redo this over again
okay now this time it should work
refresh
open
search for init yeah it worked
so this is great so finally
we are successful you see because
you see in our code we want to replace
any initial word initial to x y z
so there it is x y z
and we want to replace the word commands
by x commands okay so let's search for
for the word commands in this directory
let's see if it's there
you see now we have x commands you see
open it you can see right there
so
fantastic success
thank you guys for watching bye
so now we just
copy this um
copy this
make it plain text
okay
uh
copy it
go back to talk show
and
add the code there and that's it we are
successful so
yeah open this file
put it here
you see wolfham language formatted for
you so this actually
yeah i don't want that okay so there it
is
there it is
color it
show in browser
and here is today's result
find replace strings multiple pairs in
wufang language
bye guys