hello welcome to another episode of
sound talk show
so today we are going to talk about
uh
walking a directory programming language
comparison of
of the task of working a directory or
list of file names in your directory
okay and we are going to compare python
Golan emac lisp and wufam land and I'm
going to tell you a fundamental
difference between industrial languages
such as python Golan CC plus plus Java
and Ruby you know basically all the
popular languages you heard of versus
math oriented languages that would be
lisp and wufam language there's a
fundamental difference in how they
approach the task okay let's see let's
see video check audio check okay
so let's begin okay
the programming language design python
golang emac this wufam land and
Powershell Powershell is a special case
because it's a shell language in English
language is specifically designed to
list file names in your directory so
that's the easiest okay so I'm going to
do all these languages and demonstrate
how do you how to do that okay hello
hello immortality and hello 3DS
okay so so you know you know as a
programmer you have the question which
language is the most should you learn
you know like how easy how complex it is
how powerful how how fast it is how
elegant it is you know you are hitting
the right spot we are going to do
comparison how you know of the language
language Design This is language design
I issue uh an issue of language design
of the you know this python Golan this
language differences in Powershell okay
so the in in terms of easy you know
which one is the most easy to do for
programmers that would be Powershell
that's a special case because it's a
shell it's designed to list directory
file names okay so for example duh you
are looking at Powershell okay
uh so you are looking at Power just so
let's magnify okay let's do it again
clear screen duh okay that's you know
list all file names uh yeah and let's go
to web okay let's go to
um
study info okay and let's go to
emacs directory okay so let's do it
again the you know and and now the
recursive and uh files okay we only want
files no directories okay so huge number
of things now let's let's so this is
um this is how you
Walker directory
you know meaning that you want to for
example you want to change five uh you
want to refactor your code you want to
find some pattern in each and every file
JavaScript or c-sharp or whatever C plus
plus you know you want to refactor it so
you want to find the pattern and you
want to do replacement so in order to do
that you need to walk directly or get
the list of all file names in your
directory same concept but but different
names so you see the here comes the
conceptual differences between
mathematical approach versus algorithmic
approach which is most in the industrial
languages because from a mathematical
point of view what you want is list of
file names that's all you want a list of
file names then you can have a function
to Loop through each and every one and
do something to it
this is mathematical approach what you
want is a list of file names on the
other hand Golan JavaScript Java they
don't do it that way they don't have a
function these file names okay
inclusible
so in this industrial the mathematical
languages their approaches walk the
directory or Traverse the directory that
is you have a function named walk then
you it's fairly complex then you know
then you have to provide a function that
each time the work you know function
finds a file it passes arguments through
your function
you know this complex okay but let me
finish demonstrating the Powershell okay
so Powershell
recurse file and let's say uh filter so
we
filter okay most of the time you want
the filter HTML so this is a list of all
just HTML files okay now let's try PNG
so all PNG files or JPEG files
okay and let's say you want the full
name you know the full path so what you
do is you
um
pipe it to
full path okay
for each that percentage percentage sign
is an alias for for each object okay so
that's what we do here then
dollar sign underscore means the current
object dot full name full name is the
property okay so now you are looking at
the output that's familiar to most Unix
people you know just the full path you
know the Powershell this is annoying you
know it is the directory name then in
that directory that is that's kind of
annoying because every time you need to
go through
you know anyways that's another detail
so you this is how you do it okay
so so this is in Powershell how you list
all files in your directory or how you
walk a directory you know once you got
once you got you know this is the syntax
then you can pipe it to whatever and do
something for example we pipe it to for
each let's let's use the full name
instead of the
um percentage you know you can just say
for each
uh
object you know that's a that's a full
name same thing okay
so let's let's expand this yeah so
so this is how you walk a directory in
Powershell now let me show you another
thing okay so
now this this command
the the is a Alias to the full name
get child item you know that's the style
of Powershell instead of Ls or the you
you have the full name get child item so
for example we can say get
child it's exactly the same okay so this
command get child item because file
filter you know it returns
it returns a collection okay actually so
technically speaking if you want to turn
this into array you put a
at sine then parenthesis so now
now it actually Returns the arrays how
do you know well
for example now you can
okay so this is getting technical detail
so you can say get member and the input
object to be that then it'll return and
it will tell you you see it is a array
of system.object type okay so anyway so
the this this operator at sign is called
splatter operator in Powershell it turns
a collection of things which is these
sketch out Children returns it turns
them into array so this is you so you
know once you got the array then you can
call you know whatever function you know
in Powershell you don't actually need to
change it into array you just
you know like we did before you just
directly pipe into something then start
to do core function on it but sometimes
you if you do need an array then this is
how you do it okay splatter operator
okay let me let me show let me show you
uh because I just updated in my blog
Powershell array collection 2 array so
this is this page explains how you how
these syntaxes okay so anyway we are
digressing a little bit let me let's get
back to uh
Traverse the directory okay
so Powershell you know
one single line does it okay now next
let's look at wolfam language okay
wolfam language uh this is the second
easiest okay
simple in concept now pay attention to
the to how simple they are you know
compare we are comparing language design
pay attention to what approach and how
easy they are okay now we'll find
language here is wufan language okay so
basically you have the function file
names that will list all files in the
current directory okay then you can pass
a argument which is a pattern the
pattern can be a regular expression or
wirecard then it will filter out you
know by those patterns in the current
directory then you can give a list of
patterns you know for example you want
JPEG files plus jpg jpg or jpeg or PNG
you know you you have a several
so you can give a list of patterns that
will filter them up
and then you can give two arguments one
is a pattern or at least a pattern the
second argument is the directory for a
specific directory okay
and then you can also give a list of a
directory now this now this part or the
languages cannot do in Powershell you
cannot do in in Unix bash LS you cannot
do if you want two different directories
you have to actually
do a you know do a for each on different
input directory but in Wolfram language
it's one single function so you can have
list the patterns and you can also have
a list of directories I'm gonna
demonstrate okay then you can have n the
add another argument that's the depth
okay so the depth can be Infinity so
typically in other languages you just
say recurse
you know because you know in in bash in
Unix in Linux it's Dash uh so but in
Wolfram language it doesn't it's not
like that you you know the third
argument is just the level the depth
okay so you can actually say infinity
okay let's demonstrate um
let's demonstrate wolf and language okay
let's go to
um
go to uh let's go to emacs okay so wait
so let's let's start move from
okay and let's pop it out and file names
okay completion okay then let's say a
pattern Wild Card HTML okay then which
directory let's say I want to go I want
to list just like in Powershell emacs I
want to go this emacs directory so where
is my emacs directory copy the name
there it is okay
emacs directory then the third argument
is a level Okay so
let's say infinity
uh
Okay so
so this is this is how you do it okay so
we can run it
I'm right now in Wolfram mod Okay so
this is open source you are looking at
the source code
and here's a URL open it show in browser
so you can go there you can download it
this allows you to run Wolfram language
in
um emacs okay and it's on GitHub so you
can just download it it's free okay it's
sponsored by wolf and research
okay so so so so so let's demonstrate
okay so so close that close like
subwoofer mod let's run this okay run it
oh it's gonna be huge
um when you have you know so here uh the
negative of infinity expected oh I got a
syntax error let's do it again
this is going to be huge uh you see here
is a result you know it's one huge long
line because
and when you have you know this huge
long line emacs cannot handle it becomes
very slow okay so let's close that
uh okay so let's so anyway let's run
this in
in uh
in Wolfram script okay so same thing
magnify
so let's start Wolfram script
okay
now do it uh oh okay so
paste
okay so in
Ctrl shift V okay in Microsoft oh there
it is huh
Ctrl shift V
what
control V
now how do you paste in terminal I
forgot I don't have the insert key
usually shift insert I think or control
insert
oh yeah okay right click so there it is
so you do it so you you got you know oh
HTML files let's try again now let's try
let's change the pattern
let's say
uh PNG okay so you got all PNG files now
let's say we want a
um
yeah we want a it's modified here it's
much easier so we want a
okay so we want a list of
um
let's say TS and TS is typescript in
JavaScript okay copy that
uh paste it here oh you cannot paste
right click okay there it is
this JavaScript files and typescript
files
okay so let's let's do them here let's
do them
so if you want a list of JavaScript or
um typescript you have to do include
this time
so
star JS comma star typescript
there it is so that's how you do in
Powershell Powershell and Wolfram
language fantastic okay so this wufan
language also provide a directory level
so you can Traverse you know depending
on how you know the depth
um okay
that's Powershell and that's full fun
language now notice notice their command
name you know file names
and in Powershell it's get children so
for example help
you can see the full name is scared
children get child item get child item
and in Wolfram language find file names
so they basically essentially returned a
array of
file path okay
now what do you um so these are math
oriented Concepts
so you see they do not involve a timing
a Time concept
so get children you know it just return
a list of things and same thing with the
file names now let's look at let's go
let's look at python okay
so let's today's talk show now let's
start to look at Python and Golan now
this will be very complex okay now so in
Python when you want to get a list of
directories so you have to call Os walk
okay
uh
so how do you I you know I haven't coded
this for a while so wait let me see
uh
wait where does it path pass the
function
for each the visit so os.walk for each
the visit starting with input path OS
dot work returns a generator
at least like thing or generator where
each element is a turbo of this format
okay so so you have the full path of the
directory sub the name list and file
name list okay then
wait where is the
where is the function you actually call
Okay so
so in Python yeah so this is how you do
okay so you know it it's a bit complex
because it
it returns a list
it returns a generator which is like
at least but unevaluate at least again
again that's a concept from algorithm
not mathematical
because basically when you have
algorithm algorithmic type of Concepts
you have the concept of time so
generator is such example
which is a very popular Ms you're going
say hi okay say hi guys so generator is
again
the concept of generator is very typical
in industrial languages such as CC plus
plus Java C sharp Pearl Ruby python you
know they
in JavaScript they you know generate us
so what is a generator generator is
actually just a list but it's like
unevaluated list so you see it involves
a Time concept it's not mathematical for
example so what is mathematical in
contrast for example if you want to do
sine sine cosine you know assign
something you know you don't say you
don't say sign
some number you know you don't say
well return return something
you know return a time series then then
you have to call another function to get
each term you know you don't do that you
it simply returns an answer okay as
something Returns the answer a function
function always return something so
that's mathematical but generator is
a prototypical a classic example of this
industrial language is no good okay it's
it's
not good in many ways
so so it Returns the generator at least
kind of thing where each element is a is
a tuple is three things okay so okay
let's demonstrate the python Okay so
let's let's do it okay it's same thing
so
python let's see Python 3 paste the code
here pop it out
and let's
end the Ping window shows all my command
cores and keystrokes in emacs okay so uh
let's I want the emacs directory so
so emacs directory
Okay so
yeah so the python um
well so this is how you do it okay let's
run it
there it is so there it is there is all
the files in that directory
so you have JPEG files you have PNG
files you have HTML files
okay close now what what if we want to
filter you know let's say we want
JavaScript files so
and so you so you have to uh
so you have to code you have to code it
so how do you do it
um full path OS join okay the file name
so you have to check if the file name
match a particular pattern you know so
the point is you see it's starting to
get tedious this is not as easy okay do
I have an example here no
[Music]
so
okay the easiest way is just look at my
existing script okay so let's let's do
that
so basically we want to get just the
you know uh
file with a particular file name
extension
okay so let's go to
replace so this is my goal and replace
command let's drop to the directory so
this is the so let's search for python
so yeah Python and here is my script to
Traverse the directory and do find okay
this is like grip
uh so
so we want the file name pattern so
where is it uh
level file name is no change
wait who is the
hell I don't have the pattern separated
out yeah I have the pattern here so yeah
oh God I have to do that
so here is here is the filter here you
know you filter out by a regular
expression you want all HTML files so
what we need is we need to copy this
these lines and put it here and the
python is okay for for file name
for fname for so um
oh we already have it here okay so hold
on a second
full path
so for file name in the list okay so we
don't need that
and how do we how tab is not defined
okay in in emacs I redefine tabs so I
don't have the
Tab Key
oh
okay
so anyway so let's see let's just say
that python very annoying you know
because the indentation
and it's just a one
one okay so
that
that okay
then what is check file uh
don't don't check fire just print it
I think that will do okay let's just
let's run it
run it error
memory is not yet defined okay so you
need to import read that's okay let's do
it okay now we got all HTML files now
let's change the regular expression to
JavaScript run it okay so we got all the
JavaScript files now we want a
JavaScript or typescript okay so copy
that so we want a alternative
uh
TS
or JavaScript okay so actually let's try
that
the 80s so that's how you do it in
Python
Okay so
pop it back
syntax color it show in browser
so we have the code Wolfram language and
python okay and Powershell
so you can see so
so there it is so my point being that
you know in Python you have this walk
concept work directory
which is no actually in Python you don't
you don't have the
yeah so python work OS start work also
returns a list basically but it's more
complex okay
so now let's move on to go land okay now
Golan is Golan is actually the most
complex golden is quite complex and it
actually involves a
time concept and actually in Python
it also does I think because in both in
Python in Gola and they changed their
work directory function so you are
looking at python 2's work directory
which is different
yeah so there it is so that's my point
so this is a good example so python 2 so
let me let me go let me explain okay so
python 2
sometimes around
2018 or so python changed python created
a new work directory function so in
Python 2 you have
os.path.walk okay in Python 3
and also python 2 right basically they
created created a new function OS start
work and these two are completely
different design okay so in in the old
one
os.path.walk you give a base directory
then you have to give a function
then argument okay so so this is the
this is the actual the concept of
walking a directory so once you call it
you know then then it will call the
function f every time you know it
gets a new file or directory then your
function f you have to write a function
f then to determine what to do whether
to quit you know whether to abort quit
or do something so this so this design
of worker directory involves
a Time concept
because
every you know it doesn't just return a
thing it every time it does something it
calls your function
while the Python 3 version doesn't do
that it's simply this OS dot walk it
doesn't actually work it simply returns
a whole list okay so this is better this
is much better okay python three so two
designs
now this OS start work is also in Python
too you know they added to python too so
so in the in the python 2 version it's
more complex but the Python 3 version is
much better now let's look at Golan now
Golan is similar to the design of
golan's world directory is similar to
the python 2 version
such that you know it takes a directory
but it also takes a function and every
time it sees a new file or directory or
call your function so
a much more complex okay
so
so Golan you know in Golan version one
you have the path slash firepath.walk
okay so you can see example here uh
fairly complex okay
so here is a full code so in order to do
that this is a full code to to run it
now in about two years ago Golan 1.16
they created a new function to work
directory which is walk the you know the
the name they added and this version is
basically the same as the old version
except it's faster okay so they they try
to improve it so they create a new
version so this version is faster but
the design is essentially basically the
same as the old version so the new
version they just improved speed
basically
so again so let me so so Golan is more
difficult not fairly more complex so the
water it takes two arguments okay the
directory path the starting directory
you want to dive into and a second
argument for the function the function
you have to write and because Scotland
is a typed statically typed language so
you so that the function has
has a spect you know it takes three
things and returns a a error object
so okay I'm getting I'm getting
um probably boring so
so let's let's what we do now let's
let's run it okay so let's just run a
demo
so copy the code
yeah let's demonstrate the Golan version
so here's uh our versions
paste the code pop it out so we can
actually code it and we need the we need
the Emax
directory so here is the directory
okay
then go through the directory and print
all file name and extension okay so if
we just run it
okay so there's a lot it prints lots of
things it prints the directory prints
the file name and prints the file
extension okay so we just want let's
let's start printing all these let's
just print the file name okay run it
okay so it yeah so it prints
uh uh the full path and then also prints
the file name okay redundant so let's
even not print that
your net
okay now it's just a list of full paths
now suppose I want to filter them out
okay
uh so he said don't print nothing can we
run it
okay good so now we want to filter the
name
okay so we have to filter the name
okay so now we need a regular expression
uh
we need a regular expression you know
rejects here if
match
dot t s or dot JS then print it
okay you need a regular expression so
how do you do that let's go to Golan and
let's go to uh regular expression
Okay so
okay here is a tutorial
now Goliath's regular expression is
fairly you know golang is a low level
language so every time you need to do
something it's
tedious
uh
so regular expression must compile
uh what is this high
replace string we don't need
now I
pretty good expression let's say
backslash dot t s or
whole chat or JS okay so that that
creates a regular expression object
now
yeah no I don't now I don't need to
replace I need to check if it matches
so
okay so I don't know what's the function
for
match so let's look at goal and
documentation
turn JavaScript
match
Golem back to the 80s
Golan golang is pretty good though
golang is simple and fast I mean for low
level programming languages I think
goliathan is great
so
so you have so many functions you know
gold and
there's a bad point about Golan is that
you have a rejects function for you know
for string or four
byte slice
ho for run slice which is Unicode size
characters so so you have like a variant
for each one of them so anyway so which
one we want we want the match
you know so if you look at the Golan
functions for radio expression it's
small it's like four times five times
more than than Python's regular
expression functions python has maybe
five five or six
Cola has like 30 of them
so okay which one is the one we want
basically we just want match okay so
match string match reader match okay
let's try so it takes a bite uh
okay anyway this is too complex you know
that's easy the easiest way again is to
look at my goal line script I have
already written here golden okay so so
file name regular expression there it is
just search for that
and no yeah so that is the function we
want okay so let's copy that
and let's paste it here
so what what is the rejects
uh rejects is the
rejects is the
okay so we need a rejects package
do we have it no okay so we need to load
it
God
tedious
so now we have the rejects package so
this is our regular expression
and then
match
file name rejects Okay so
let's
that's the file name rejects okay we
want to match that then we want to match
the file
path X path okay which is the X path
yeah so
base no we don't care about pace
okay so if that returns
true
then if x is true then to that
Maybe
it's
compact that's a pretty print our code
let's hope it runs okay
red
okay uh declared in not used Golan
what
I have a brief let's see
now I have a brief for Arrow so let's
see
I.E okay if error so this is yeah so so
you need to add that okay if Arrow Panic
let's run it
ah cannot use file name Rejects
variable of type as a type string
yeah okay so it's gotten so instead of
that let's just say a string okay
comment that uh instead of a regular
expression object let's just pass the
string because this function requires a
string type let's run it
undefined result so where did we okay so
we here we need to print X path run it
okay so remove this
okay then it
fantastic Okay so
there it is it got extraneous results
because we forgot in the pattern we need
to say it must match at the end of the
string okay do it again
fantastic so that that's
how you use skolan
to this or JavaScript or typescript
files in your directory so let's do it
again Powershell
clear
Powershell
there it is okay Powershell Wu fam
language okay so pop this back
Now wolfam language
there okay so let's let's go to Wolfram
language
pop it out
I don't know
uh basically that's the code copy it
you can download wufam language free
okay just you know go to my website
Saudi Wu fan language you can find the
download location okay so this is how
you do it in boofam language a list of
JavaScript or typescript files
python
run it fantastic okay this is how you do
in Python now what if I want the full
name okay so let's see I want the full
path okay maybe that
do it there it is okay python
10 lines five six one two how many how
many lines one two uh seven lines okay
now go land
oh God
[Laughter]
let's remove the comments and stuff
uh that's and what is his spot we don't
need
let's remove the things we don't need
okay so basically this is Scotland 40
lines basically
clean the code yeah 40 lines run it
there it is there it is okay
so I think that's it for that today yeah
hold on a second so
color syntax color it show in browser so
this is today's talk show we went over
these languages in language design and
we talked about the difference between
math oriented language and Industrial
languages so oh oh we missed one thing
we missed emacs list now emac this is
another method oriented language just
just like a wolfam language
so
so how do you do it here okay this
directory and also directory okay let's
just copy it let's do it here
uh
so we have Wolfram land let's put uh
let's put emac beasts here okay
now
we need the directory okay so pop it out
so the directory will be there okay
and uh
let's let's make this okay so let's run
it so oh
yeah so
okay so we don't want to insert so
basically here is here is here is the
code Okay so
and the regular expression should be
typescript
or
that's how that's what you have to do in
emac this backslash toothpick syndrome
tso.js okay
run it
done okay so
yeah it just returns it doesn't do
anything so you have to actually
um
run it there it is so
I mean so okay so it Returns the list
so if you copy the list new buffer paste
it and uh
and uh let me break the line into each
you know break the loan line then you
got
that that's how you do it
so okay close that close that no save
pop it back
back to browser syntax colored showing
browser so we showed several so you see
here is emac Beast one single line and
here is wufam language one single line
okay you know they are very similar
let's remove the comment
uh
emac this one sync online we'll find
language one single line and very
similar in design these are math
oriented languages where you do a
function it returns results okay there's
no concept about time okay function
return result there's no time involved
or how you know how the Traverse you are
traversing something nothing now in
Python 3
it you know so you have the walk the you
know this is uh where is the function
name walk the function so again it just
return a list but in in Python 2
it's more complex
and in so in then we have the Golan then
you involves you know you involves a
work function that cause your function
each time it gets a path it calls your
function
so walked or traversed this involves a
Time concept okay I think that's it
that's what I want to say about
um this the important thing I want to
say is you know the like the math
oriented design concept versus the
algorithmic concept because math
mathematics is about how is about what
is you know there's no concept of time
there's no concept of how to do it
there's no concept of you know step by
steps algorithm you know it's just what
it is you know you want the list of file
names you get these two file names by a
function
While most industrial languages python
Golan
see you know Java you have a worked and
each time it runs you know each time it
finds a new file or directory it calls
your function so you know that's my
point in language design okay
module okay so that's um
yeah okay that's I you know I don't know
about that module but I suppose that's
you know
it's it's you know you always have you
you you you you could also write this
function in
you know in Golan you can write a
wrapper so that you can have a single
line that returns a list of files but
you know it's just it's not the standard
normal way
so new inversion 3.4 this module offers
classes representing file system path
okay
uh whatever you know I thought python
documentation is always pretentious and
so how do you do these subdirectories so
path equals to path dot so this is
abstract representation of a path then
you have a then you have a um
list comprehension edsc which is a
special minus you know special syntax
within the Python language that
generates a list then you have the
concept of generators and iterators that
deeply you know that's a prototypical
example of time based you know Concept
in programming languages
um you know so for X in that iterator if
x is a duh so okay
so what if you want to list a match by a
regular expression so I suppose you just
if you know if
match
okay anyway that's interesting so that's
it that's it for today I think that's it
okay bye guys who who you guys watching
say hi okay so if you like my stuff buy
my stuff okay buy my stuff
you can so I have this Kinesis Advantage
keyboard it's fantastic let's go to I'm
gonna shut down in one minute in two
minutes okay so what is the latest
writing about keyboard yeah that's it
I'm gonna have a drink
so 15 minutes so
so keyboards so again my keyboard is
this one that's the one I'm using
and the one on top here is this ultimate
hacking this one is great for key
markers the best interface
the best interface uh where is it
for keyboard markers expensive though
this one is expensive you know I
wouldn't say so I wouldn't say this one
is so great for you know if you just buy
it for typing and also you know this
seems you know also if you just want a
keypad there there are programmable
keypads around so you can buy one of
those but I happen to have happy cacking
so you know so I'm I'm using it for as a
key macro and there's a separate you
know there's the other side over there
you cannot see
so anyway this so and my recommendation
you know best best keyboards are these
so Kinesis advantage to and expose and
Kinesis freestyle Edge
very good all the Mr baroco all these
are good I mean others others are good
too but if you are gonna ask me what's
which are my favorite that would be
those depending on different needs you
know
for example this one I think it's great
but it's over five hundred dollars you
know too expensive and also
it's hard to buy it's only it's from
Japan
uh ultimate hacking it's a bit expensive
you know you know and also I want I want
full function keys it doesn't you know
it
you know so I mean compared to price and
all the things considered
um you make different choices and
keyboard IO is you know not sure I want
to spend you know 350 for this one if
I'm gonna spend 350 dollars
and the small Lander there's this one is
pretty cheap you know and pretty
functional practical you know so
different piece
and okay so if you like them you know
buy buy for my Amazon and support me
from patreon patreon me Amazon gift card
me and PayPal okay and buy my emacs
tutorial
pay me basically
emacs
and my emacs tutorial
and the JavaScript tutorial
where is it these these two are my best
tutorials
uh okay so that's it
so
anything else
let's close that
okay that's it
so keyboard block was close so today we
covered all these
fantastic okay that's it
bye