good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show today we're going to do a pure
javascript live coding uh
i'm going to do i'm going to show you
what i'm going to do
so you see this uh
uh two-letter sequence spygram
counts so given a text any text
i'm going to write a interactive java
javascript
application that draws the
diagram chart uh dynamic dynamically
dynamically
as you type so basically reproduce this
uh bitmap image but uh in real time
so i'm going to do it quickly so let's
start
good morning
[Music]
good morning russian link 2050
okay so javascript coding uh so today is
april 10th welcome to another episode of
talk show okay so javascript coding so
let's
do um
so we are going to begin
now and on the left window i'm using
emacs
with soft like keys and on the pink
window you can see all my emacs commands
and keystrokes
so move forward move backward move
forward by char move backward by char
and up and down go up by paragraph
go down by paragraph and you can also
see
the keystrokes on the pink window
so if you find if you are emacs user and
you don't know what i'm doing
you can always you can actually search
uh search the command and usually you'll
find the code on my website
okay so javascript so first of all
we need to yeah let me show you okay so
let me show you what it looks like
at the end so you just search for xari
keyboard
okay i'm gonna do this quickly today so
any comments questions
uh said okay hi guo
um so i'm gonna show you how it looks
like
uh basically um
i i did a video talk about
um
about about this kind of key mapping i
mean keyboard layout
and uh project a few days ago you you
might want to watch that
so for example this page this is how
it's going to look like
so delete it start typing here
and you can see that the graph
the chart is updated in real time
so we're going to write this in um
for the diagram okay so let's begin okay
so first of all
we need to we and i'm going to do this
from the ground up
uh without any libraries pure javascript
and the dom and stuff okay so
first of all we need this input box okay
so how do you do that
you check out my javascript in depth
just search for
exactly javascript in depth and go to
dome
first of all we need the input box
so how do you do that i have examples
here text field so technically
it's called text field actually it's
called text area okay
so here's the code here's html code and
here's the javascript code so you can
see you start to type and
you know use results so let's copy that
copy it go back to emacs paste it here
and we are going to create a web page
for it okay so
okay so let's do this okay uh open a new
buffer
paste go to the top magnify
and this is gonna be javascript
uh diagram
background app okay updated
and let's let's let's move this google
uh thing
the google tracker away so it's gonna
let's
remove the add remove remove let's see
remove remove footer we don't want
uh we don't want highlight link so uh
save okay javascript we need to save it
lowercase it and
dot html so save it and show in browser
okay we got it we got empty html page
so we're gonna start to add stuff here
copy the link
paste it here so this is our app and uh
before we remember the text area so copy
that
copy that go back
paste it here so text area so show so
you see we got a text area so how
so here's a html uh
text area row five column forty okay i
need to go faster than
these otherwise we cannot finish um
okay then we're going to need a
javascript file so let's create a
javascript file
of this name open it
create yes okay so here is a javascript
file javascript app
to draw
diagram of
a given text okay that's our javascript
file
and this is the file path and press the
command
to link to it so we got that
and now so this result we don't need so
here's the javascript code copy it
wait copy it yeah
open the javascript file paste it here
let's see refresh
select all something yeah
it works okay so let me explain how
how this works so first of all so
javascript
uh let's let's copy that put it here
okay so
text area creates this
this uh text box and the default text
type something here
okay then
span show box um
right this is uh we don't need that p
okay so okay so let's let's make it
simple okay expansion box
id that okay so we got two
uh html elements one is the text area
with an id
and with a spam with id
okay and now look at the javascript code
so javascript code says first of all get
the text area element
by this id you know get element by id
then do the same thing for the show box
do we need the show box actually we
don't need a show box but
actually leave it so now we define a
function constant
f update here is the arrow function
sharebox.textcontent equals to
textarea.value
so so here's a function that gets the
gets in the in the uh
text area so when
when this function runs it it
sets the show box you know it sets
it sets this span elements
you know inner area to be the value of
the
typed text so
so that's the function grabs
the text area text and put it in the
show box
so that's that then we need to uh create
events
so what does that mean so that means
whenever user type something
you call the function so so text area
this event will be created for the text
area so whenever
user type something there you add a
event listener
so input is a event that means whenever
the text change here
then you call the function f update
which basically just grab the text and
and insert into the show box okay
then lastly we call f update so
so when the app begins it also
shows there okay so that is that is the
uh
that but what we need to do is actually
let's see so we need to
yeah we need to do this fast so uh let
me i
have to think about so given the text
we need to compute the diagram okay we
need to
kind of
let me show you okay sorry keyboard
okay so we go to layout
we go to yeah so we need to
draw this diagram so first of all
you know um so given a text we grab
the text then we
we find okay so we find all possible
diagrams okay
then we count it so how to do that
basically you create a hash table or map
or
called dictionary and each
element each key is going to be a
diagram
okay and the value of the key
is going to be count you know the number
of occurrences of the background so okay
so that's the
that's what we're gonna do so let me add
some comments so you go
you guys can see clearly what's going on
so
uh if update let's let's make my
code a bit more you know let's make the
code
the code formatting a bit more
traditional okay
uh
if update the i mean let's add
the documentation for update uh
grab text area text
and insert into show box
okay that's what it does okay so but
what we need to do
so algorithm
uh actually i don't like this common
style so let me try these
always in decisions that's uh
uh what we need to do is to
grab the given text
then then we need to find
all possible diagrams how do you do that
okay let's see a b c d
e f g so if that's a given text
we need to get a b
b c d e f
g okay um
how do you do that so
d e wait a b b c
a b b c and it's not
a b c d e okay then you the diagrams are
a b
b c c d
d e yeah so
if the character length i mean if the
string length is one
uh con words five characters
then the diagram is gonna be one less
you know one less background so that's
how it works right
let's see a b b c a b b c
c d d e yeah um
let me write it out so because when you
do a video
uh people can see later on okay
example input text and that's a
background okay so
we need to do this uh computationally so
input text
so once we have input text so how how do
you write this
let's see you can
do a map
let's see how you do this um
you can so input text is a string
you can do a map or a loop
okay uh let's do you know
let's do a loop yeah let's do a loop
okay
let's for example for simplicity let's
um
uh
so so for for simplicity let's create a
new javascript okay let's just test
okay
so input constant
x x equals to let's say
string
so that's the
that's the input
okay then
diagram will be equals to so uh we
so we map okay now
let's go to my javascript tutorial
because i
i have tutorials there
javascript in depth uh
wait so we need to
[Music]
so string we are we are going to work on
string string overview
now remember in javascript 2015 string
is
a
create string string constructor string
drawing string method string
is a how do you say
let's see um map object iterable yeah
so in javascript string is an iterable
so that means we can use for a loop
okay
for of loop so so for
k of iterable
k is a char x char okay
i prefer to have variable names that are
unique
okay so for x char of x input
for example let's say we can do console
log x char
okay run it there it is our result so
this is correct
now for each x chart of
input we need to
okay we need the index because we need
find we need to find
the char that's next to the
how do you okay let's try to
i'll do okay so i need to
um
so another way obviously is you to use
a for loop for loop is uh is actually
going to be
simpler okay let's let's forget about
let's forget about the the you know
that's
pretty fine wait what's going on
formatting line tango unexpected token
what
yeah for loop oh yeah so the length here
is wrong
yeah so you need x input
okay so so let's do a for loop for i
equals to one uh two islands
uh less than
x input.length okay
then we
got now is there a way in a string
to um i forgot you know uh wait
is you know anyway let's let's just push
on with this
it's not waste time so uh
you know because but however this way
might be
less efficient okay but let's not worry
about it x input
so you need to create a diagram okay so
how do you create a bigram first of all
we need a map we need to create a map
so basically this is going to be
x input i that's a string
plus x input i plus
one okay and this is going to
be uh minus one yeah i think so
so this we're gonna add this to the map
so how do you do javascript map
so let's look at that map
create map so
map object tutorial map in javascript is
a key value pair
better than object i talked about that
in my last
javascript video so uh
oh so we can just make it a iterable
okay
create a map from values in each of
our objects so the iterable can be a
string
but if you do that what's gonna be the
value
i don't know
let's let's just try okay
so comment is all coming out this out
console.log new map
okay let's see what it get
okay uh uncaught type error let's
x input is a iterable then
iterator value a is not an entry object
oh yeah so i guess it needs to be you
cannot
you cannot create a map out of a
string even though string is iterable
because
the to the argument to a map must be
pairs
okay so forget that
uh but however we need a map anyway
so new map
okay so this map is going to be
by grams
okay so this map is going to be diagrams
now let's continue with our for loop
so we now for each
occurrence i mean for each happenstance
we need to add to the new map so how do
you add to the new map
let's see create map
parent of map object size of map add
entries so
here is how you add to the map okay
so map objects
set key is going to
be
that's the key okay
okay then value is going to
be basically if it
exists already then add
one to it otherwise
create a new key okay so
so check existence
has key
so we can do that if
has the key if it has the key
then uh
then we add one to the
um yeah we then we add one to it
so how do you get the key size check
existence get value get okay
okay let me show you how how to
do this so if it has the key
then set
plus one
okay otherwise
that okay now let's prettify the code
okay
so if background has the key then
basically add one to it okay now
otherwise
otherwise um otherwise create a new key
and the value is going to be
one okay i think that's
that's um that's right let's see what
happens
finished okay no output so now we can
console.log
x by grand printed okay let's see
yay let's see uh what
so a b b c a b b
c c d d e let's see check a b
b c yeah so so that is uh
correct now we can
now we can uh we can just make a
function
out of it okay constant arrow function
uh string two
diagram okay function
okay uh the string is going to be
i mean the argument is that
then the value is
basically this okay
and you need to return
so here is a function
here's a function it takes a string so
that let's rename this
returns a map object
where keys are the diagrams
and var is the count okay
so that's a function so now let's just
test
if it works so comment this out
comment this out and
to do that so now we want to
call the function on
input okay run it fantastic
now let's try now since it works now
let's try something
fancy okay let's just copy let's try the
input string to be something fancy wait
abcde let's repeat this okay repeat this
okay run it run it
let's see a b okay
a b is two b c is two c d is two d
is two e space is
one
e space is one then
space a is one correct so our diagram
function now works
fantastic
so now we can put this uh function back
to copy it
back to our code
you can see now we have a function
okay now let's drop the you know
usually in my javascript the whole
script i put a
curly braces around it so that
so that all the variables and constants
does not escape
this script uh does not interfere with
other scripts you load on the webpage
but it's not neces
you know it's not that necessary so
let's remove it
and reformat so so our code is easier to
see
okay uh
this is grab okay grab text area text
and insert into show box okay now this
is a string to diagram function
now
now these comments this
this is what we need to do let's put it
here
uh input abcd diagram okay
give a text
compute the diagram and
print the stud
the count of them okay that's the first
thing
second part of the
of the problem
given a map of the map
object of the diagram
plot generate a svg
object
draw a chart okay draw a
chart draw a bar chart
by generating a svg
object okay
first part of the problem grab the given
text computer diagram
and print the count of them okay now we
almost already did the first part now
but we need to update it
so let's modify the update code
so so update code show box
text content equals to
equals to this
is what it will be okay copy let me show
you how
so we compute the diagram yeah that's
how
it is okay
now actually comment that out now
if we now let's try our code if it works
refresh
oh it's just say object map okay
something all right it
it okay we need to convert the object
map to text so
so this part will be two string two
string
okay refresh
something yeah
okay debug now let's see
let's do a console log here let's print
it
so text areas this is the input text
which is a string and feed it to
feed it to the diagram function oh
wait yeah i think i know what's wrong
the function needs to be
at the top okay because if you define a
function using arrow function by
assigning it to a constant
you cannot call the function until it's
defined
so so here we are calling the function
here so that's why
okay so now back to the browser
refresh something okay that's still not
working
refresh close it close it
let's go back to the let's see
some okay that's not working okay so
what's going on let's see
the code
okay so we need to debug show
show log string to diagram
and tostring okay that should print that
should print the log
morning bot okay now let's
press f12 to show the javascript console
and refresh it prints object
map that's wrong that is wrong
okay so you can see can we magnify this
can we magnify this console log
oh you can yeah okay
okay so it's it shows object map
wait but i thought i
so okay here's a problem why can't we
print two string okay so let's
go back to our test script
wait
close that let's print let's put
the yeah
so here's the text test script
by say sometimes you need to make sure
the browser is not
caching the website okay i
uh
in yeah in which case you keep the uh
offset version in the browser yeah but i
think
i think that's not the case refresh okay
uh return refresh
wait uh i hate firefox
let's show let's let's do this in um in
chrome okay
yeah it's the same thing console
yeah i don't think that's a problem okay
let's back to
the drawing board
console.log f string to diagram
x input it really should
be closer
he really should um
uh that's pretty fine okay
let's
yeah i'm just fuzzing you know like i do
i do
fuzzing a lot when i'm stuck uh
second part of the problem okay the
first part of the problem second part
about the problem
constants um what's going on so this
returns this function returns a
a diagram which is a map object
and now the update function
the update function first of all it
console
it what what that rack let's let's try
this okay
let's just print console.log i mean
let's just
print
the whatever is in the text area value
okay refresh
something here okay that is working okay
so so the text area value is
good
okay then
let's try to define okay
and what's going on
why is it not formatting correctly
what's going on
it's let's try the browser again refresh
oh there it is so now we are seeing the
map
now we are seeing
the diagram update
in real time
yeah it works yes
yeah so this is actually this is indeed
the diagram
it returns a object but not
but let's see two string to string
okay now it should
what happens if you to string a map
that's a question
refresh
when a map okay that's a problem we the
tostring is a problem
it does does not convert a map to
kind of the printed values it just
when you tostring a map object it just
prints
object map that's a that's a book that's
a problem
okay so we found the problem
um
okay we found the problem but uh
okay we found the problem
uh that's okay
we don't need this okay so
so actually so anyway so we we we
already completed the first part of the
job
which is uh which is given
an input text create a diagram of it
and their count of occurrence
now we can actually start to code the
second part to start to generate svg
images now that's actually more complex
but first of all what do we do about
these
i would like to print it here actually
okay so let's
uh so let's complete let's actually have
the background printed here
so so okay we can we can we can
we can print uh now we need to print the
diagram
okay so wait that is why wait
okay so we need to print the diagram
by grab map so for each
it needs to become a string
uh how do you print them i forgot
map object delete object check existence
clear map iterate map okay so we can
you know the whole thing needs to be a
string that's uh
issue
but i thought two string should do the
job okay so let's see so let's
yeah i'm pretty sure two string should
do the job
the reason it's not working before
where you just see the object mapped
the reason that's like that is maybe
because
we are calling to string of the string
object not the map object so let's go to
javascript reference
go to the map object let's see if it has
a method
about two string okay
for each entries iterator keys values
has size constructor
symbol tostring tag that's not it that's
not
it i know
prototype
uh parent purpose okay constructor size
get set has delete clear for each
entries key values
entries return the iterator
for the map okay maybe we need to
convert it to an array so
so dot entries will convert a map object
to
array then
then maybe let's do this
okay then maybe
okay background map entries
it becomes a array where each element
is a pair key and value then you do
two string maybe that work
okay so back to
[Music]
firefox refresh
try something yeah now it becomes object
map iterator how do you
okay yeah okay i i think maybe i know
now let's go to look at the stream
functions
string object object reference let's go
to string
maybe there is a
method that
converts any iterable to a string
representation okay
now string object has lots of uh methods
concat repeat trim path slice substring
index of last index of
search map imagine okay to lower case
char charcoal okay there is no such
wait i'm i'm i'm very sure i'm pretty
sure there's a simple way
because i'm trying not to write it
myself
given a string i mean given a map object
the problem is to create a string that
represents the map objects
uh wait i'm
very i'm pretty sure that two string
of array does that what uh
what the i think you need to do
some json.string file
oh okay that's uh json string5 that's a
great
solution let's do that okay
jason
stream five yeah so jason stream
five okay so how do you
okay so i guess uh
yeah maybe that okay let's try it
refresh select
all delete maybe
this work no damn it
what the
no okay let's look at jason
uh object reference
jason
okay stream fi
converts a javascript object to json
string format so what the hell
why is it not working json stream file
okay i don't know why is it
let's cancel log it okay
refresh what
the hell now i just print empty
brackets
console.log diagram
map okay
console.log diagram entries let's see
what the hell they are
refresh now oh
it returns a iterator yeah
right so when you um
yeah so when you use the entries method
of a map it returns a iterator
you need to turn that iterator into a
actual um yeah exactly
the dot dot dot the the spread
operator okay let's let's let's go to um
the spread operate operator okay so
so if you go to iterables
uh go to e3 iterables which is a
new kind of more advanced
e-trade over map
you can use for a bloop or where is the
dot operator let's let's search for
spread
okay spread operator here iterable yeah
spread operator yeah okay so let's
try that entries dot dot dot
okay let's hope it all works
now yeah oh yeah okay we need
that that seems to work you need to add
it here i mean
dot dot
refresh select all delete
now let's see okay it's working but
uh you know it's just printing it once
so that's something we can fix
so let's remove remove remove that
we don't we may not even need stream
five
so maybe that okay and maybe we don't
even need entries
if we convert it to
you know um wait do we
okay let's show box content okay i don't
know
refresh what happened now okay
uncalled expected expression
dot dot okay and
add the parenthesis refresh
uncode syntax zero expect
expected closing parenthesis got dots
what okay so let's follow
pancreas news suggestion
just follow just follow what i said okay
let's do that
jason streamfire
okay jason streamfight then
then what uh then then
my map okay so he suggests that
it better work
it's better work ah what's going on
no
oh yeah wait uh i'm missing dot dot dot
here okay hold on a second
he says yeah turn the map into
um yeah okay
this is not exactly i mean i mean i
wouldn't do that
oh yeah yeah this it works great great
suggestion
great suggestion now we
got the diagram computation
working
fantastic okay so we got the diagram
computation yeah so fantastic
now you can like like now we can like
copy the whole thing here
and just this you know let's have some
fun doing diagram computation oh
wait what copy it
uh paste what uh what's going on okay
copy it paste
oh yes okay the next thing we need to do
is
to sort the diagram obviously
yeah that's what we need to do before
before we started to do
um to do the svg because we need them
sorted
okay let's do that okay but
i need to figure out how this you know
how
i need to think about this a little bit
so
this spygram map
so this diagram map now is
convert the map you know maybe you don't
need
you don't need the outer bracket right
i think
let's try it
wait yeah yeah it should work
why okay
why is it not i don't understand
background map is a iterable it's a map
object iterable but
um
do we actually it's it's iterable right
and yeah i'm being stubborn
you know i wanted to start
entries
okay so so why is it
uh i mean i don't see why
why do you need
extra uh square bracket there
okay rocket it's just not gonna it's not
working okay let's ignore that
okay let's just
okay now we need to sort okay now let's
now
now let's write a function
to sort a map object okay
now do we have do i already have that
somewhere i might have
straight operate a spread operator
object reference
map get
set clear uh keys so
now god i don't have did i
e-trade over map convert to for
map reverse key value map constructor
map filter
convert to format object to map
map to object okay now we need to
sort map it's always more code
go only sit
okay how long have i been talking we
haven't
uh it's almost an hour but i need to
okay we need to we do need to write a
function to sort a map object
then then we need to
start to draw the svg
so i'm thinking let's just continue
whenever
you know i have some time let's finish
this
let me drink
there it is take a break
milk and coffee and honey
okay let let's push on let's get let's
get the um
yeah let's finish this so now we need to
write a function to
sort a map object how do you
how do you do that yeah okay
i need to then
you are looking at my keyboard now you
look at me
okay so now we need to um
sort a map object i mean let me think
map object so map is got key
key and value pairs you want to sort it
by the
by the value okay
so one of the easiest way
is to first of all turn the map into
array
using entries
using the entries function then you just
saw that okay let's just do it
yeah so now i want to know if the array
function
if the array
if the array uh sort method
does it take a iterable or not
sort
return a new array array so no it does
not take the iterable but i think it
will work
array like object yeah there's a crap
javascript array like object okay
so so let let's go to the
test script do we have the text
test script okay
run this so this thing returns a map
object
now we can sort it but before we do
let's change
some random input okay
run it yeah so now you got different
okay you need some
more text so that some bar
is more than others okay let's say
t-h-t-h-t-h run it
yeah okay so you can see
you know some of the yeah so we can now
sort it so let's see
my map okay
my map is that now
function sort map so so my map
dot entries
then dot sort
comparison function okay arrow function
uh
a and b let's say x and y okay
x y it should return
negative number
uh just number comparison okay so
entries
so wait so how do you so entries
which is entries which is an array
where each element has the form
key value okay that's an
entry so we want to compare the v so
what we do
is we want
we what we do is
x
the first one
let's let's just do that okay i
think
wait yeah i think that
yeah the so the one is the
the value part okay so it just returned
that
okay so we don't need
so that should be our sorting function
let's try it
console.log sorted
run it arrow uncode type error
map entries sort is not a function
what
it's not functional yeah because well i
think that's because of the iterable
thing again
let's just try the
yeah now wait did it sort
what
no it didn't sort what
console.log that magnify
run it
so the biggest value should be e space
that's seven okay
okay let's let's uh let me reduce the
input
okay run it
okay so th th let's do that run it
so thth occurs three times okay
ht occurs two times okay
then we can actually reduce it more
so for simplicity
th occurs three times and the
ht occurs two times okay
now sorted
okay our sort function is wrong f is a
ordering function the function should
takes two arguments
x and y
takes two arguments x and y and return
oh okay so it it shouldn't return true
or false it should return
a stupid javascript you know
uh should it should returns um
it's it's just let's just say minus okay
run our code run our code
okay now we need to reverse order okay
so
reverse the x and y here
run it what
oh yeah correct you see
th count three then
ht2 so so that is our function basically
that
so we have our function
uh let's see so so this is a function
let's let's clear it uh constant
constant arrow function sort map
okay
my map okay
so they are a map object and returns
a array of array
sorted
sorted by the vowel
okay so this is the function and it
can
adjust this single line okay so
yeah so now we can see
okay i think i'm taking more time than
necessary here
run it
no what's going on soda map
so here is a function sorted equals to
sort map
my map run it
oh yeah it works yeah so it works
so now we grab this function copy it
okay copy it go back to our code
and here's our function
okay now put this function on top
put it here okay now we got a function
to sort map
now we can we can call it
we can call it here so
stream file sort map
okay back to javascript back to browser
refresh
now we should see sorted
but this something seems
wrong
okay i think this is getting this is
dragging on i need to move on to the
svg
you should call this in fortran the
language is hipster
like right yeah
um okay so
so what is going on
oh yeah so sort map sword map doesn't
take that
anymore that's right
okay obviously i know what is going on
yeah that's what we need
refresh
now it seems to be working
and we going to add
a lot t-h-t-h-t-h-t-h-t-h
yeah the more th so th
comes on top
yeah so now we got the sorting function
work okay now the sort function worked
the next thing we need to do is
plot the svg okay
i feel like
one hour and nine minutes i
feel like i want to go
okay now we need to do svg
okay so so now we got um
we got the sorted diagram
we got the sorted diagram now we
we want to plot something like that so
now we have to think about svg
so given
basically given a map object
where keys are the diagrams and values
of the count
you want to draw svg
so that um
you know so that the bar length
represents the count the frequency of it
so in order to do this first thing you
need to do is
instead of showing the count
like we have here we need to show a
we need to make them a percentage
instead
so what that means is that you have to
you know you have to sum all the numbers
then for each value divided by that sum
so you get a percentage with re
you know that's a percentage of this
diagram
with respect to
with respect to all diagrams
but that is not necessarily what you
want
because there potentially
there i mean there are a lot of diagrams
the number of diagrams in english
language
you know you have 26 characters you have
upper case then you have punctuations
so you if you add them all together you
might have 100 characters you know the
like the characters on your keyboard so
you have 100 characters
and every pair of them forms
a diagram and a different order
creates two different diagrams so
essentially you would have
uh how so what's the total number
background
quite a lot so that's
um how do you compute that
so does anyone know comment it okay if
you think you
find you know so the question is
assume you have 100 distinct characters
the question is how many possible
diagrams are there
so 100 times 99
100 100 times that would be 100 times 99
times 99 i think okay
i think
so which is about wow big number
nine hundred eighty thousand
so they are positive
wait not times 99 times 2 wait
yeah so they are about 1900 big grams
1900 big grams right
so
let me write it out okay
assume you have 100
this think charts
how many possible diagrams
are there
probably this number
yeah 100
you have 100 possible first character
then you have
oh you have actually 100 possible second
character
yeah that okay just 100 times 100 i
think
so the possible bi-grams is 10
000 okay
so so back to our problem
that you know you don't want
the percentage
you know so what what does the
percentage what do you want to measure
against
uh all possible biograms yeah i think
maybe that's
yeah and also the issue gets complex
because typically when you measure when
you count diagrams you only want to
count
letters you want to ignore
you know diagrams that contains a space
or punctuation
so that means our diagram we need to
filter out
you know results such as this space
t and any other things
involving comma so comma comma for
example
comma
you know comma comma or comma space
you know comma space or period space
that's probably going to be very
frequent
diagram so but traditionally you want to
uh you don't want to include that so you
need to write a
filter function first so you want to
write a field
filter function for your map okay let's
maybe we can do that
then after that after that then you need
to compute
the percentage okay let's write it
so that write a field function of a
given map so that backgrounds containing
diagrams contains um
contains space or punctuation
should be removed okay that's the first
thing
then then we need to write
a then we need to write a function
given a diagram map object
return a map object
where the value is percentage
instead of count okay okay let's work on
that
write a filter function of a given map
um
okay you know if we cannot finish
wherever we are let's let that be
you know just so be it so
now we have so what is this now now this
sorts the function i mean this sorts
um i mean this is a test script uh
that now we have the sort function now
we want to write the filter function
so how do i do how do we do
uh for example this one
you see this contains this
contains c space right so we want to
filter that out
so we're gonna write a function we can
can we write this
this in one shot yes i think so
it's constant arrow function
filter map okay
takes a map object
filter remove
return a map object
with key keys where
that keys that contains a
space or contains a char
that's not english letter okay
so xmap
so input is a map object output is
okay now we need to work on map objects
so back to javascript
uh convert object so let's go back to
the map
map filter i have written this before
copy it
yeah so you just give a function okay so
so i'm not going to go over this all i
have to do is to
uh give a error function
wait so you
call the map filter
and here is arrow function
the arrow function
return a new map where that returns true
okay so
the arrow function will say
f so
key value the arrow function takes two
values
key and value okay
uh we want to know if the key contains a
punctuation
okay so we want some kind of mat
match string so let's search for
string functions string
string object let's go to let's just
open a new one
so far so good
so far so good so stream function we
want to map
string start with end with
match okay
ah this gets complex
start with search string return true if
string start with search string else
force
so the start string does not
does not take a regular expression we
need one that takes
regular expression uh
let's see includes return true if string
contains
such string else return force okay
that's not what we want
okay we apparently
we need some sort of regular expression
function
okay match or is not what we want match
basically matches what we want
oh god no actually that's not what we
want let's
so let's go to the regular expression
okay
so let's go to regular expression object
yeah we want something that returns true
and false
so start test then given a string
returns true if rejects matched part of
whole of string
yeah yep that's what we want so
copy that
so regular expression is going to be
a to b a to z
and a to z
now there's a shortcut for that syntax
and see
no there is no shortcut for that
okay so here's what we need to do
so the regular expression will be that
and dollar sign so correct in the
beginning means the beginning of regular
expression actually
needs to be here
okay and dollar sign needs to be here
and
the whole thing needs to be like that
so that's a regular expression
that means okay
this needs to repeat
so the first letter is a afternoon
alphabet you know english letter the
second character is also
english letter then we test
key so see if that returns true or false
if it returns true then the element
should stay
so yeah
okay predefine the code yeah so that
should work okay let's let's try
now console.log filter map
filter map sorted okay
run it undefined
oh yeah because wait yeah
because when you use a braces here you
you need a return statement we don't
need we need a
return statement but we
there there it is let's try again run it
yeah it worked one
shot coding success
so you see the space c the c space
and space t are removed fantastic
okay so copy these two code
copy these two code okay hold on a
second what
uh copy those two code and back to our
function here
and paste the function here
okay so we got filter map function
then we also got i mean we got our
filter map function here
okay then we can call off
a filter map here so
copy string file sort map and filter map
okay
okay prettify the code
go to the browser magnify
refresh
something is wrong okay something went
wrong
oh now you need to again
[Music]
filter map now
again you need to make it into a
you know i really hate the iterable crap
you know they created iterable things
for
iterable is a let me say this again
iterable the concept of iterables in
programming languages
which exists in javascript in python
okay i'm claiming this is my
my opinion okay itrobo is a
computer engineering byproduct just like
int float long double
uh code stack you know those kind of
thing
you know the the concept arrived
right arose because you kind of need it
in order to implement
them or for efficiency reasons
but however it's not truly a
programming concept or algorithm so in
other words
for a programmer you don't really want
you know you don't
really need the concept concept of
iterable
you know what so what is the iterable it
basically is just a list
or vector okay it's just so that a
iterable
just doesn't compute the whole thing you
just you know you can
you don't have to compute the whole
thing so that it consumes a lot of
memory
but to a programmer that's that's your
problem that's your compiler writer's
problem that's not my problem
you know you figure you figure it out
whether i'm going to use the old values
or not you know
but you know but it's a difficult
problem in com
compilation optimization right so these
compilers or these programming language
designers they just throw it up
to the programming language so
the problem you know they avoid the
problem be
by by throwing this
optimization problem into the
programming language
so now the programmer has to worry about
it like when i use a
you know list or array i have to think
about oh
whether i should want to where am i
going to
be needing to add elements to it
if not oh i need to use array because
it's sufficient
am i going to have lots of element oh if
so oh and then i need to use declare
it verbal you know this kind of crap
computer engineering side effect
and i'm dealing you know the the the
reason i spent
time you see today is a is a concrete
example it's wasting programmers time
uh you know and especially javascript
you have the you know spread
operators and crap so anyway so let's
try this again
let's go to the browser refresh
see if this works and it's not working
yeah
and i'm getting i wanna i wanna go take
a break
alpha beta says why don't you use
next.js what the crap
what what is next.js
okay so um what are we doing now so
should we
oh yeah fig yeah of course i need i
forgot the
dot dot refresh
there it is okay
now finally it works t h t h
t h t h t edge it works
and now we have sorted them and also we
have filtered
out anything that's that's not just
uh letters we filtered
out uh punctuations that's great
so we this you know take
so now we can actually start to
to draw the svg i i think i take um
i'm thinking uh maybe starting to
let's do it next time because
yeah i you know i should create my own
programming language because i've been
bitching about them
for 20 years where is your own
programming language i haven't done so
and right now you know i i studied
compilers for
for a while three years ago three or
four
i really i need to finish that then i
can actually create a
my own language you know it's not
you know it's not that easy uh and i
have lots of other things to do you know
so it you know it's really it's not that
difficult
to create your own language like you
know you learn for example most college
students in in uh majoring in computer
science
if you are a good student when you
graduate you probably have
studied compilers and you know and you
might actually have
already written your small language so
it's not
too difficult but however to create one
that becomes very practical and
efficient
that quickly becomes immensely difficult
uh besides that if you want to
um you know if
i mean even if you create a very elegant
and efficient programming language
super efficient practical can be used by
google for example
even suppose you created that that is
not
easy but even suppose you did such as
julia
you know we already have examples julia
the programming language
so even you are a genius you created
such a great
programming language nobody is going to
use it
you run into a problem of how do you get
people to use it nobody
you know so right now we have you know
julia and lots of other languages they
are just
hanging there uh not much used
so
so actually you know creating a
programming language
is actually not a practical
thing to do you know and nobody will pay
you
you know you know you're gonna waste
your time basically it's like
painting or philosophy you know yeah
it's fun to do but
you don't get paid for that that's the
thing
uh starting on this screen in real life
you converted with requirement to create
a
well yeah yeah of course in real life
you
are confronted with the requirement to
create a new language
no that almost never happens what you
are talking about is a small
uh uh what they called you know uh
you know small language like a few lines
you know
what they call um application specific
language
a s
l uh or no
there's a there's a word you know it's
like a niche
just for your um
company just for your um and
generator functions okay so okay so i
think i think maybe
that's it for today so we finished
you know we finished the part
you know we we kind of finished the
first part of
of you know creating
you know statistics for the diagram
actually there's another thing we need
to do we should finish
we need to write a function that
computes the percentage
instead of the count yeah that's easy
that's not too difficult
but we'll probably take another 10 or 20
minutes
actually i already have written it
so but the the second part we have not
completed
is svg is actually creating
um you know the svg for the chart
this is the this is the important part
actually
because people you know you need a
visual diagram
so i'm thinking but however coding this
svg will be
entirely different separate uh
tasks almost having nothing to do with
what we have done
now because for the task of drawing svg
what you need you consider the input
given the input is a map of key value
pairs the keys are diagram
the values are the percentage of
occurrence
of that diagram then you just draw a
chart okay okay i think that's i need to
go
i need to take a break uh
let's do it so next time javascript
you know yeah nick let's do it next time
i have a lot um okay i
actually i have a lot talk show uh
coming up
you know i want to do so i'm gonna do
maybe
almost one every day um
i like usually 10 o'clock in the morning
san francisco time so for example let me
tell you what
are the things that i plan to do for for
example
here you see internet speed growth
rate okay and there's a chart
now this chart is done in mathematica
okay
it's done like 10 years ago
and here you are seeing mathematica code
to
you know anyway so i need to update this
chart because this is up to
2012. so i'm going to show you how
how to use mathematica to draw this like
one single line we'll do it actually i
can do it now
so anyway this article is about internet
speed growth rate
uh it basically doubles every two years
in theory
so that's one thing uh one i want to do
then there's
also so that's about wufam language
then there's also quite a few
uh emac emacs list i can talk about
i i you know i have to do i can talk
about you know
live coding tutorial then there
is uh oh there's my food
uh then there is
javascript yeah we i talked about a lot
last time there's quite a few and there
is
also this unicode um
i want to do i want to
you know for example let me show you
this one
let's see this fun program
it lets you type something
and convert them to upside
down characters okay
so i want to write one you know kind of
a tutorial for the
for the full width characters for with
characters
are characters in unicode that
just like english alphabets but however
each character
by specification is like uh
is the same with as a chinese character
and it's basically mono space
and white width so i want to create an
interactive app for that
okay that's that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
they put they put you through
exercise and a lot of training in
particular discipline but when you enter
practice your life a lot of learning
skills quickly become unlearned yeah
okay so you if you like my stuff buy my
javascript tutorials okay
you just go to javascript
in depth then you'll find it you know
you can you then you can just
buy it and thank you guys paypal me and
patreon me
bye guys okay bye guys
i'm shutting down let me just um
i'm shutting down now let's see
close
uh trust me background
uh yeah live coding you know live coding
is always
much slower than i would expect because
we actually start to code lots of issues
like
minor details that um
you know because but i'm doing this kind
of for fun you know i need to do this
for my website right
because i like i need
you know i need this i i want to have
this dynamic
diagram and also i need trigram as well
but once you start to code you know you
have the structure
then it's pretty easy to add a trigram
or
quadrogram or you know
uh and you know then
you know i need to create this dynamic
chart
so this is for my own website
so even if i'm not doing live stream i
will have to code this
usually that's a bit much more faster
because i don't have to expand and i can
stop and read something in detail
um yeah so
then i need to add svg i'm gonna
schedule that
i don't know when but uh just check out
my youtube okay
the next one on javascript is probably
going to be
creating svg from scratch you know
then um
yeah so this is one of the things to do
and there's quite a few other javascript
ones
so where's the yeah
i'm shutting down okay
i'm shutting down in i'm shutting down
now this
is i'm done today
uh and golden okay math keyboard
okay bye guys
you