Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Tsaw Talk
Show.
Today is 2020
May 26th,
Tuesday,
San Francisco time,
11:30
minutes
in the afternoon.
So,
hi guys. So, what are we going to talk
about? Show today's topic. So, I was
going to
thinking Good morning, Green Deck.
I was thinking so we are either we
talked about we had some discussions
today
in in our Tsaw Dee Discord
about tiling windows manager.
Tiling windows manager, that's a big
topic and we actually I talked about
that a few times
in the past on my YouTube. So, tiling
windows manager, keyboard efficiency,
those type of questions. So, we can talk
about that. I did a giant rant today in
Discord about that topic.
So, that's one topic. Uh then are we
going to talk about Hey, good morning,
Emily.
Glad to see you here.
Good morning to UK and Green Deck. Good
morning to Russia. And good morning, uh
Vanya, to India. And good morning,
Andrew. Andrew is you are in USA.
Uh and uh
uh
Everyman.
Oh, do we have like
is Vanya Vanya is Everyman? Oh, or I got
it wrong.
So, anyway, um type the topics, okay?
Type with my name on it. So, one topic
is tiling windows manager and the other
topic is syntax coloring. So, we've been
talking about debating about syntax
coloring. I have quite a few articles on
that.
Syntax coloring, a very interesting
topic.
So, syntax coloring
tiling windows manager or syntax
coloring or you guys have some questions
um
you know, regarding my life.
Uh
we can talk about that. So, anyway, ask
me questions, okay? You guys need to
type. You need to type with my name, you
know, set set the topic and we're going
to talk.
So, let me let me begin random then. So,
here's here's my Emacs as usual and you
can see all my keyboard commands on the
on the right.
So, today's topic is going to be Let me
show you, okay? Syntax coloring or
tiling windows manager
or syntax coloring or other things,
okay? Showing browser. But, first of
all, let me show you about this today's
background image, the Gmail man.
The Gmail man.
Okay.
What about the Gmail man? Let's see if I
have it here.
Yes, the Gmail man.
So, the Gmail man, you have to go to
this link. Wait.
Uh
Oh. Uh okay. So, you have to go to
Yeah, where's my link?
Search. Search the most useful feature,
Exapedi
Gmail
man. Let's see if we can find it.
Uh
no.
Sorry, what?
Google
ice
cream.
Okay.
Google ice cream in the Gmail man, okay.
I'm trying to find the link to my
article.
Ah, okay, saw odds.
There it is. Google ice cream, can
Google be trusted? Now, this is back in
[ __ ] I don't have a date here. This is
about 2010.
So, beginning around 2010
uh,
you know, big Google is becoming a
superpower and a lot people are starting
to criticize Google and this is one of
them.
Okay, don't be evil video.
This is criticizing Eric Schmidt
the CEO of Google at the time. So, let's
get the date.
And actually, let me copy.
So, this this video is um,
started in 2010 September.
Someone, I don't know who is the group
Consumer Watchdog.
They are uh, criticizing Google severely
back in 2010.
I my in my opinion, I still believe
Google is pretty good.
So, anyway, I collected video. So,
anyway, let me show you.
Uh,
you see, so you can see my Emacs work
workflow.
Emacs workflow, here is how I add a
video.
Okay.
So, you need to actually uh
I need to
go back here.
Copy the URL.
Paste it here. Make a link.
And cut that we just did.
And now go to open that URL.
Magnify.
And uh
the video is on top. Let me put it here.
So, here is the description of the video
I just copied. I didn't have that
before, but now let's put it here.
So, showing browser.
So, there it is. So, that is my page uh
Google ice cream soap.
That's an interesting video you might
watch. But, today's uh background image
is this one.
The Gmail man. This this is this one is
uh very funny.
So, am I doing okay?
Okay, so that's a very funny video. You
can go watch that. So, that is today's
background. I'm talking in quiet quietly
ASMR stream because
you know, right now it's close to
midnight here. So, I have roommates, so
I have to uh
be quieter. So, what is today's topics,
guys? Type a topic. So, good morning,
Jagan.
And Jagan, you are in USA, right? What
state?
So, let's see what's questions, okay?
So, type your questions, okay?
The talk show is going to depend on your
questions.
Tiling Windows Manager, or let me show
you the topic again.
Close that. Close Close that.
Okay, so we have today's topic.
Okay, since you guys don't have a topic
here yet, I'm going to
Uh good morning, Animal Killer. An- An-
Animal Killer, where you from? You know,
don't
Don't um
type things that like that, okay?
Because Google censorship, you know,
it's Google, it's not me. Because I show
that, I'm going to get banned.
Uh
Okay, so since you guys
You guys You You guys need to type a
topic, okay?
So, tell us about tiling window
managers, okay? Eastern Supremist. East
New York East Standard Time, okay?
Okay, tiling Windows Manager. So, I'm
going to talk about that, but first of
all,
let me show you
something you need to buy. Now, this is
Elgato Stream Deck Keypad. Now, this is
a programmable keypad.
And uh each key comes with a LCD
display.
You know, like a little TV. So, you got
like 1 2 3 24 of them. 24
TVs.
Uh so, this is fantastic. And uh guess
how much is it? It's not too expensive.
It is only
only $150.
peanuts for you for you guys
programmers, you wonderful programmers.
So, the news So, this is pretty old.
This is actually um
3 years old. Now, they have a newer
version
with 32 little TV screens. So, you can
check it out.
So, this is one of them. There are a few
others. Let me show you.
Keyboard with a TV display.
So, here's another one. And this one is
based on
uh display ink. So, this is not using
the LCD technology. It's actually, you
know, display ink such as
like Amazon's
Amazon's, what you call them.
Uh
you know, it display ink.
So, this one is also not too expensive.
It's a full keyboard.
And if you want to buy them, let's see.
Let's see if they are still in
operation. I think they are. Let's
check.
So, this is Sonder Design Keyboard.
Each key has a
display ink.
Uh pre-order. I think they
I'm not sure what's the deal. They've
been around for like 5 years now.
And I
say yes, anyway. Anyway, check that
check it out yourself.
So, this is another one. Not too
expensive. This is only 100 something.
Uh apparently, display ink is uh not is
less expensive to make than LCD
displays. So, then we have the other
one, the Optimus Popularis keyboard.
Now, this is actually the earliest. This
one
Let me show you. This one, okay?
Actually, uh this one.
Optimus Maximus keyboard was announced
around 2001. Yes, 2001
on slashdot.
slashdot.org.
This is the the very first online forum
for programmers, for nerds.
So, when they announced this keyboard,
it didn't came out until three or five
years later. And it's like $4,000.
So, each key is a little TV display. You
can see a video here,
even.
Anyway, there's a video. Eventually, it
came out.
And then later on,
this one, for example, this one is also
pretty old. By now, it's like uh
10 years old. So, they have a different
model and with improvements in
technology. This is This is kind of the
first one with the display keys.
Okay, so that's about that.
So,
so some of the keyboard programmable
keyboard. Now, programmable keyboard is
very useful. Let me explain.
Okay, so
tiling windows manager, why why they
suck, okay? Let's talk about that. One
more thing.
One more thing. Let me show you one more
thing before we go into that. Actually,
this is related because programmable
keypads, I highly recommend them.
For example, you can
For example, every one of you do web
browsing, right? When When you do web
browsing, you need to switch tabs. How
do you do it? Usually, you go there with
your mouse slowly and you click
and you go here and slowly and click.
This is Art Deco.
Let me magnify. For example, then you go
here slowly, click. And if you want to
close this tab, you have to go there
slowly and wait for that cross, close
it. To reopen, you have to move your
hand back to the keyboard.
Command shift T to reopen it. You see,
that's tedious. That's no good. But,
usually you also have a keyboard
shortcut.
For example, on Windows, it's control
one.
Go to the
Go to the first tab. On on the Mac, it's
command one.
You see, command one goes to the
the first tab. So, you have command two
can command three and so on. Those are
no good.
You see, for me,
I have programmed into my mouse. So, if
I want to You see, left, left, left,
left. Right, right, right, right. Left,
left, left. Close it.
Press a key. Close it. Press a key. I
don't have to move my hands to the
keyboard or to the mouse.
Let's reopen them.
So, because, you know, so I I have
programmed them into my mouse.
Into this, you know, mouse. You can You
can find it on my website.
But, I have a mouse
you know, if you have a programmable
keypad
which does similar function
and
which is fantastic.
You know, so you can
switch to previous tab, next tab, or
previous window. You know, typically you
do like this.
And let me show you. Command tab, okay.
This you know, command tab or the alt
tab is the most idiotic [ __ ]
people do.
You know, so I command tab or which one
I want to
switch or I want to go to you know
Cisco.
Let's say let's switch back.
Oops, I passed. I [ __ ] passed. Now
shift.
It's the most idiotic
inefficient. So you don't want So if you
want to switch to the previous window,
by the way,
when you use this functionality,
the
90% of the time
what you are doing is is switching to
the last app. You know, almost always
90% of the time you want to switch to
the last app or last window.
So you don't need, you know, you don't
need to hold down command, press tab,
and release it, then tab, you know, you
don't need that. You want single button
press like one one single button.
So do I have it? I don't have it. You
know, the reason I don't have it right
now is, you know, I'm moving, as you
know.
Um let me show you my
As you know, recently, you know, there's
some changes in my life, so I'm moving,
so I'm, you know, right now with this
keyboard.
And this ultimate hacking keyboard does
not have that many keys.
For example, it does not even have
function keys. If I need to press
function, for example, F2, actually I I
switched.
Let's look at this one, F6.
If I want to press F6, I have to hold.
I have to hold this and press that.
[ __ ] no good. You know, this
keyboard, I don't like this sort of, you
know, 60% this
nerds 60% [ __ ]
You You want You want real function
keys, okay? Single key press function
keys. So, because I'm on this keyboard,
therefore I don't have my
usual optimal setup. By the way, I don't
have it on Kinesis either. Let me show
you.
I I have showed this a thousand times,
but a lot of people have not seen it.
So, on the Kinesis keyboard, as you can
see,
or maybe you cannot see. Let's see if I
can see. So, you see, they don't have
function keys neither. You have these
tiny
tiny buttons. You see these tiny
buttons? That's function keys.
So, I end up
I end up
not having my optimal setup.
So, what you need is a keypad. Again, I
don't have it now because I
I was moving.
So, I don't have my usual optimal setup.
But, this my current setup is good
enough. But, normally I would have a
keypad, programmable keypad. So, if I
want to switch
previous tab, next tab, close tab, copy,
cut, paste,
uh previous window, just one key,
or switch the window
uh within the current app, just one key
press. So, that's So, that is why it's
You see? That's why you need a
programmable keypad, single key press,
because, you know, people complain, "Oh,
you got RSI."
You want a single press, you know, key
press, because the chord combination,
that's one of the reason people get RSI,
especially on a standard normal
normal mechanical keyboard, so you have
to control control
alt [ __ ] you know, this [ __ ] up your
hands.
So, we are talking about efficiency
here. We are also talking about hand
health.
Uh
so, that is why I recommend I highly
recommend a programmable keypad. First
of all, you get you know, you get a
programmable mouse with 10 buttons, you
know, five is not enough.
You want 10 or more.
In fact, I have this mouse.
You know, I talked I talked about these
topics quite many times. I have this
mouse and I showed it before.
But, the problem with this mouse is that
the
you know, you got all these buttons.
They actually work, you know, you might
think, oh, they are too small and
cramped. Actually, they work fine. But,
however, they are the buttons is not as
easy to press compared to a mechanical
key on a mechanical keyboard. So,
you if you
work with computers for 10 hours a day
with this mouse,
you know, although it saves you from
control alt [ __ ] however, if you keep
switching windows or stuff with that
with that mouse, copy, cut, paste, and
so on,
you have other problems, you know, with
your thumb because it requires pressure.
Again, all these are related to what we
are going to talk about tiling windows
manager.
Okay, so if now now here is a time if
you have disagreement with my arguments
about the tiling windows manager, say
it, okay,
say it and I'll shoot it down.
So, let's go to tiling windows manager.
Now, we have talked about programmable
keyboards.
Uh now this is Rick and Rick and Morty.
Fascinating topic.
Rick and Rick Rick and Morty is the
cosmic horror show.
And you can see that there's a
philosophy, the philosophy of Rick and
Morty.
Uh I love this show. I watched tons of
them on YouTube, you know, the clips.
Since I don't have
a TV or Netflix or whatever.
Okay, so let's see. Let's go back to
tiling windows manager, today's main
topic, I guess.
Programmable keypads, okay, tiling
windows manager. Now, so I wrote this
article
back in 2012.
Uh
and uh somehow it becomes
uh extremely popular. It It's been on
Reddit
uh
two or three times. It's on the It It's
been on Hacker News two or three times.
And uh you know, I used to have Disqus,
you know, comments, you know, you have
tens, you know, lots of comments.
Most of Most of them are idiotic.
Idiot- idiotic Linux nerds.
So,
post your reasons, okay? Post post
George George and uh some of the others.
You have disagreements, so who who was
it? You know, we uh argue today.
So, you have disagreements, say it, so I
can address it.
You know, I'm just giving
uh my view to you. I'm just presenting
my view. It's not
usually it's not necessarily um
you know, your opinion is no good.
Half of the time it is.
Okay, so let me go over the comments,
okay? Comment, guys.
Uh
So, are you Chinese? Yes, I'm Chinese
animal killer and animal killer, where
you from?
Tiling window managers, okay. Are you
Chinese? I never understood them, but it
seems they are very popular among more
vocal Linux users, yeah.
You know, tiling window managers, it's
one of the
uh
what you might call a dramatic thing.
It's like Emacs and Vim.
Uh you know,
uh
people talk about all the time.
I have bunch of the window from
disappear.
Uh
okay, so any questions about tiling
window managers because otherwise, you
know,
I'm just going to talk about it maybe a
little bit because I'm kind of tired of
this topic. You know, I'm
So, let's see what's the comments.
Do you use Vim? No, I don't use Vim.
Well, I I use occasionally, you know, so
let me tell you the story, okay?
There is a hum. Wait, do you hear Yeah,
another question I want to ask you guys.
Do you So, do you guys hear hum?
Like
you know, if you put on headphones, do
you hear
when I'm not talking, do you hear some
like my machine humming?
Because that happened
when I started to do video here
and today I changed the search
suppressor. So, does it still happen?
Do you still hear it, Emily?
Okay, well that reminds me Emily's
setup.
Emily's workflow. I want to criticize
it.
Now, okay, so wait
Loud humming. Oh, [ __ ]
I I don't know what's going on. I
Maybe I unplug.
So, let's see what I can do.
Yeah, electric hum. [ __ ]
Uh
I I I don't I don't want to unplug it
now because
then
Yeah, I don't know.
Uh anyway, so
let it be today.
Next time I'll try to plug it into my
Mac.
The headset. So,
tiling windows managers. So, in this
article, I'm talking about the op-
optimal setup. You know, so I'm doing a
flame on the tiling windows managers. I
think it sucks.
Now, there are two aspects to tiling
windows managers.
One, the you know, tiling windows
managers it's a tool on Linux. It allows
you to
it it has many commands to rearrange
your windows. For example, you can have
your windows side by side.
For example, this window, you sometimes
you want them side by side, exactly. So,
I I do it manually. You know, I move it
here.
But, in the tiling window manager, you
know, that a tool on Linux, you can
press a key and have them side side by
side and things like that.
You know, they so-called tile the
window. So, anyway, the tiling windows
managers, these tools, there are several
of them. They are like seven seven or 10
of them.
Uh the Linux nerds are crazy about it.
So, there are two two aspects about
that. One is that these tools, they
usually provides many commands and the
keyboard configuration shortcuts
that
that, you know, these commands
rearrange your windows that is more
powerful and flexible than
than what your
the default Linux provide. So,
so tiling windows managers is actually
gives you lots of commands plus
key configuration. And their key
configuration is usually very powerful.
You can set your keys to do, you know,
what you want much more powerful than
uh let's say directly dealing with X11's
keys.
So, it's a very flexible and powerful
tool.
And uh
Every run, oh, thank you. So, it you
know, let me let me finish that. So,
tiling windows manager, two aspects.
One, it's it's it's very flexible tool,
powerful tool because it gives you many
commands to manipulate your windows
which otherwise you don't have these
commands. Then, it provides very
powerful configuration for shortcuts to
call the those commands. So, that's one
thing. Okay. The other thing
is
tile windows. Okay, let me show you
what's the example. So, here is what
tile windows looks like. So, you have a
screen, you
basically you don't want gaps, you know,
for example,
right now in my screen I have several
gaps, you know, this, you know, I have
gaps in between, you know,
like each window is in a some
irregular position. But with tiling
windows manager, the ideal, you know,
the name tiling windows is that the
ideal is that
you don't have gaps between windows so
that every window is um
in the size and position optimal, you
know, optimal size and position, which
is, you know, this.
So, that's why they are called tiling
window managers. Now, now this part,
this is the most idiotic [ __ ] in the
universe.
You know, tiling windows managers. So,
the idea is that you don't, you know, so
you don't have gaps between windows
anymore. But, however,
you see,
what happens if you have
if all your windows is just terminals,
text text files, then maybe that's okay.
But, as soon as you have graphics, you
know, maybe you have, you know, YouTube,
for example, streaming, or if you are
doing gaming, Twitch.
Imagine.
Imagine you are gamer, you are playing
uh you know, Fortress or some 3D game or
Minecraft, then then you need tiling
windows managers. So, so it must tile
with other windows. So, [ __ ] the [ __ ]
idiot. [ __ ] these nuts.
They don't understand. So, so, you know,
to these nuts, they are thinking, "Oh,
when you are playing games, it's that's
an exception." You know, so they don't
they don't consider gameplay as part of,
you know,
part of using the computer. That is like
that's an exception.
Or, for example, when you are watch
movie,
uh watching movies on YouTube, you are
watching my
YouTube live stream, right? Sometimes
you full screen.
So,
what what's with the tiling windows
managers? Well, you don't use it. You
know, you just full screen it. You don't
use it.
So, anyway, so my point my point here is
that the idea the idea the the very idea
of tiling window manager, you know, so
that you have efficient arrangement
without gaps, that's idiotic. Because
once you have different programs,
applications, calculator, scientific,
graphics system. You know, you plot
differential equations or you watch
movies in another screen. So, one one
screen display YouTube, one screen
scientific, you know.
When you tile them together, you get
situations like this this scratched
clock. You know, I I cannot
I cannot possibly imagine these Linux
idiots like you know, I cannot possibly
you know, I have arguments with these
Linux you know, these tech nerds, [ __ ]
heads for over 20 years. And sometimes
in our arguments, I just can I I cannot
possibly imagine who the [ __ ] head like
do you have do they have a brain to
show? Look at this example. Now, this is
this example is from D D I M dream,
okay?
Do what I mean? That's what it stand
for. Do I what I mean? That's you know,
that's part of the Unix philosophy. They
love these puns, you know, do I mean? Do
what I mean? Things things like that.
So, I cannot possibly imagine. So,
you see this one someone in you know, so
so someone
wrote a library to have this so-called
Fibonacci arrangement. The Fibonacci
arrangement is that
you know,
to simplify so you have a rectangle, you
cut it in half. Then the other half you
cut it in half. The other half you cut
it in half. So, you have this
arrangement. It's like a Fibonacci
spiral. So, someone wrote code to tile
Windows tile your Windows into this
Fibonacci
arrangement. And they they you know,
they they you know, it's open source.
They put it up so it shows up on the
DWM DWM my mistake.
Uh dynamic window manager, you know, so
they put up on the DWM website as kind
of like you know exemplary
example of the power of it. But you
know, so I cannot possibly imagine
someone would actually show you know
their work as a you know my work to have
a window that's a squashed clock. These
[ __ ] Linux idiots.
You know when you watch a you know this
happens on Linux all the time.
Like you know back in let's say 2000s
you know there are tons of video DVD
players for Linux. Often very often
almost all of them half of them at least
when you play a DVD
it shows like squashed.
How how does how does that happen? I
mean what what
do you like to watch a movie where it's
squashed vertically or horizontally? Do
do you do you do you like do you find
that interesting? I cannot imagine you
know someone would show this code to to
actually show
show a squashed clock.
So this is what I don't understand with
these tech geeks.
So anyway back to tiling windows
manager. Let me summarize. So two things
okay two things. What
what these tools do is that it provides
many powerful commands for manipulating
your windows or work space. Okay that's
one thing. Now this part this part is
very good. I would love it okay. I and
especially you will be able to configure
keyboard shortcuts you know to rearrange
windows the way you like.
That part is fantastic.
The other part the tiling windows it's
it's almost useless. Let me explain why
is it useless okay.
You know many Linux people they like
virtual work space know, the idiotic
virtual workspace. Mac actually have it,
too.
I'm not going to show you uh because I
don't use it. It takes time to uh
actually I can
I can show you the
Yeah, you see I can add a uh virtual
workspace. Let me show you. You see? Now
I have two.
Now I have
I have a second virtual desktop. The
[ __ ] [ __ ] idiots, these people.
So, let me show you again. So, I can add
I can add another one. Now I have three
virtual space. Oh, look. Fantastic. Oh,
look. I can I can I can like um
I can open the Firefox.
You see? New window Firefox.
So, that's
So, So, that's virtual workspace, okay?
Where am I going? Let me get back. Okay,
hold on a second.
I don't want [ __ ] virtual workspace.
You see? Yeah, okay. Let me get back to
So, tiling windows So, Linux people,
they love this concept of virtual
workspace.
The purpose, you know, the most people
they love it because you can group your
work,
uh categorize your work in different
workspaces. For example, one workspace
you are doing coding, compiling. The
other workspace, you are uh browsing the
web, you know, let's say works related
works related browsing the web.
Then you have another workspace, you are
doing online shopping, you know, you're
looking at keyboards or clothing or
whatever, you know. So, virtual space.
Now, you have to realize So, you
You You have to realize, doesn't matter
how many virtual workspaces you have.
It It's not like you are increasing the
workspace. You are not increasing any
screen. You are not increasing your
screen
uh space.
Actually, if you like me, if you have
single one only one workspace, it is
itself is already virtual because you
can move windows, you know, this
all these windows are virtual in a sense
virtual. You know, it's not like it's
not like when you have virtual space,
you have more virtuality. It's the same
virtualness.
My point is My point is that
So So, what does this workspace uh
doing? Essentially, they are doing is
that they provides a some sort of uh
grouping structure, okay? Grouping
structure.
I'm kind of digressing and I'm not on
the
So anyway, I want to get back to So,
that's kind of a digression about
workspace.
Why do I not like them?
It It It doesn't really It It has a
little to do with tiling windows
manager, but
it's related, but I'm talking about
virtual workspace. I'm not doing a good
job. So, why is it not good? Well, it's
not good because virtual workspace
the essence of virtual workspace, what
they they do is that they provide a kind
of a grouping
categorization. So, you you know,
um
for your
uh work, you know, kind of categorize
your work. And in order to
use that feature, you have to put effort
to it. For example, you know, multiple
virtual space does not automatically
give you uh let's see.
You know, it doesn't automatically group
your windows into, you know, work
related or compiler related. It doesn't.
You have to do it yourself. You have to
manage it. So, when you actually use,
you know, these workspaces, multiple
workspaces, you have to sometimes
move this window to this workspace
because this workspace is for works
related things. You have to move movies
to, you know, it's more work. It's
actually more work.
I would claim, okay? And also,
you don't need it because what why you
see why why do you need to categorize
it? There are some situations, you know,
you could use that.
But in general, no, because why do you
need to categorize, you know, for
example,
alternatively, you know,
for example, let's say desktop one,
okay?
Uh what virtual space one. For example,
my workflow,
if I want Emacs, you know, if I want to,
let's say, coding related, I just switch
to Emacs, okay?
I switch
Let me turn it off. I just switch to
Emacs, you know, press one single key, I
have my Emacs. If I want a new window,
you know, a new window,
uh full screen um
if I want full screen, I press the key,
full screen, you know, if I want to
Google,
uh I go to Firefox or Google, you know,
s-
you can set up your keys so that same
amount keys, you know, what what
what's the point of
categorizing your work? It's actually
kind of categorizing your windows. It
actually takes
a lot more effort, a lot more keystrokes
to do that. You have to, you know,
a lot of digression, okay? Let me get
back to tiling window manager, okay? So,
actually it's related because tiling
windows manager also help you, you know,
manage the virtual workspace. So, you
you you can have a command that sends a
window to space know,
two or three, you know, things like
that. Too much work, you know, more
keystrokes and control meta [ __ ]
control meta alt [ __ ]
No good. You know, when you
when you install Linux, for example,
let's say Ubuntu, let's say Ubuntu XFCE,
one of the most simplest one, XFCE. You
have like 20 by default. You have 20
keys.
20 keys, like control alt,
right arrow, control alt up arrow, you
know, you have like 20 keys dealing with
the workspace
virtual workspace [ __ ]
You don't you don't want that. You want
simplicity, okay?
So, that's about virtual workspace.
Now, let me get back to tiling windows
manager. So, when we talk about and let
me
and I'm and I'm going to talk about
Emacs, okay?
Emacs Emacs way.
So, when So, we are talking about the
optimal workflow or optimal
Yeah,
optimal workflow, you know.
Uh So, when we talk when we talk about
this subject, there are several things
we actually need to agree upon. For
example, for example,
what is your monitor size? You know,
what is your monitor size?
Do you work with a laptop, you know,
laptop? Usually, you don't have a big
screen. Is that
if you work on your laptop or you have
a, you know, typical what
uh
17-in screen, like I have 24-in
you know, one single monitor, 24-in
screen diagonal.
Or
like in Emacs, you have three giant, you
know, three huge screens. These days
it's fairly popular, you know. You have
a 24-in 24-in screen here, then you have
a vertical screen here, then you have
another one, you know, or sometimes on,
you know, it's fairly popular. So,
when we talk when when if we are talking
about the optimal, you know, the
utmost optimal
workflow, you have to consider which
screen are you dealing with, you know,
tiny tiny little screen or
or a normal, you know, 24-in screen or
three monitors.
That's the questions. That's one of
thing you have to decide because for the
different systems, you actually have
different choices that's that would be
considered optimal, okay? So, that's one
thing. So, besides screen size, you you
also, you know, for example,
should you use, you know, the tiling the
tiling window manager, the tiling
feature?
How useful is that? Depends on, you
know, how big is your screen or how many
screens do you have, you know, the
answer will be different, okay? So,
that's one thing. How many, you know,
what's the size of your screen? The
other thing you have to consider is
um
The other thing you have to consider is
your
um
What's the other
keyboard. Yes, keyboard. Okay.
What What keyboard are you using? Are we
talking about, you know, we are talking
about the optimal
uh workflow, which, you know, whether to
use tiling windows manager, which
includes key binding, you know, what key
binding to use.
So, if you are going to talk about key
binding, keyboard, you know, the optimal
choices of keys or things like that or
whether you should use code keys or
function keys like me, single key press,
which is better? Single key press
function keys, it's a bit far, you have
to reach, or control, you know, control
G, for example, it's closer. You don't
have to reach, but you it's a code,
which one is better?
That depends at
all these questions, so it depends on
what keyboard are we assuming? Are you
using a stupid laptop keyboard, or using
a normal 100 key, you know, external
keyboard?
Or you use something like me, you know,
some some sort of admin keyboard.
Programmable keyboard, so
I think I
drew along too much. Let me read the
comments, okay? Let's see what you guys
saying.
Hold on a second, let me see. Am I still
How long I've been talking? 47 minutes,
I think I talked too slow.
Anyway.
So, let me just quickly mention one
thing about tiling window manager. I
haven't speaking yet.
Speaking yet.
So, what So, Emily, okay, so, you know,
tiling windows managers, if you have a
laptop screen, a small screen, basically
tiling window manager is is
not much useful, because for a laptop
screen, you you almost always want it
full screen, okay? You want it full
screen. You don't want You don't want
you know, because if you split into two,
it becomes too small, you you know, you
cannot see a video, things like that.
You almost always want your full screen.
So, tiling windows manager is not that
useful if you have a laptop, if
laptop is what we talking about.
But on the other extreme, if you have,
you know, three giant screens, then
then again, you don't really need tiling
windows managers. That's
That's my opinion, but I will also say
that is the scientifically valid
conclusion. Okay, if you have three
giant monitors or or two giant monitor
or or one single 30-in giant monitors,
you don't need tiling windows either
because
because you have so much screen space,
you don't need to arrange them, you
know, to be proper. You know, you can
you doesn't matter if it has gaps. It's
fine. You have lots of space, you know,
it's fine.
So, screen size matters, okay? And
So, you have two scenarios here where we
can see tiling window manager is not
that useful.
You don't need you don't you don't need
it.
Um
Okay, so what am I So, let's see what's
the comments.
And maybe that's it for today. So,
So, there's a lot of things here I want
to say. Let me read the comments, okay?
Okay, Avery Ran says, "What are pros and
cons of joining a startup after college?
What's the truth?"
Okay,
you know, there's no truth about it, you
know, it depends on your personality.
So, for me, if if I were you, I
you know, it depends on personality and
your personal situations. If you just
graduated college
and suppose you have two choices. One is
to join a, you know, big corporation,
Apple, Google, IBM, or
you also got, you know,
offer to join a startup. Which one would
you choose? Let's say
you know, let's say the benefits are
somewhat comparable. Of course, which
know, depends on depends on how much
they pay.
But if they are about the same,
I myself would
typically join a startup. In fact, most
of my life it's been with the startup
because startup
you have more freedom to do what you
want. You have more control, you know,
usually startup, you know, only five
people, three people. You are the boss.
Like you can be creative, you know.
And also to join a startup, usually that
also means you you need to be a good
programmer. You know, you you know, you
can write programs from the ground up
without, you know, without basing on
some existing code or how to you must do
it, you know.
You you need to do something this your
startup need to do something. You have
to do it
from scratch, from nothing. As opposed
to if you're working a company, usually
it's, you know, some given project in,
you know,
and you have mentors and stuff. So
that's that's my answer. I don't know if
um
that answers your question or where does
that
make sense or
because these kind of questions there's
a lot of um
uh depends on you, you know, what's the
situation.
There's no right answer. So let me read
the comments, okay?
Uh
immaterial whether I use V mode Emacs T
months there's a different job they have
in coming uh home is
bearable, okay. Harmonize with it.
Can fix it another time, okay, it's not
that bad.
2000 something.
Connect uh you can pick this or George's
topic in Discord.
What's going on on Discord?
Uh
you know,
when it's live, it's better to post on
YouTube because
Uh so, what are the questions for me?
Anyway, just repeat it, okay? If
something you if you want to ask, repeat
it.
Uh let me read
Let me turn it around.
Good thing about tiling window manager,
what would be good things? Yeah, so the
good things about tiling window managers
is to use
purely for its
commands to manipulate windows, you
know, that would be useful. For example,
right now,
if I want to move this window to the to
the left a bit,
there's no way to do it on a Mac,
except, you know, manually drag it.
But on Linux, you can
Uh
if you have a tiling windows manager,
you can somewhat control it with a key.
You know, suppose I want to have this
window.
The only way I do it on the Mac is, you
know, go here and make carefully and
drag it.
You know, there's no Oh, if I No, if I
want it
to span vertically,
there is no um
easy way other than
manually do it. But if you have tiling
windows manager,
you can do it you can do it fast and
also with a key of your choice. So,
that's a good thing about tiling window
managers. You know, most people
these users, when they respond, when
they see an article, you know, why why
this article is popular? I can tell you
why because
drama.
Because
my clickbait is successful.
You know, I start the article by saying,
"Try it
today for real. Currently 1 hour into
it."
Tiling windows is unusable and
inefficient.
I say
You know, I started to use Xmonad, which
is the Haskell [ __ ] You know, Haskell
is the you know, the hacker's something.
You know, when you mention Haskell,
everyone is oh, Haskell is monad and you
know
It's like like advanced. So, I said you
know, I said, "Oh, I tried it for 1 hour
and it's uh it's stupid."
And that
when the this Linux nerds see that, "Oh
my god, what's going on? This guy, who
is this guy?" You know, they then then
become popular.
Well, part of that
part of the reason this article is
popular is because that, you know,
clickbait, but in order to be
popular, you it's not just the clickbait
title. You have to have some some at
least some substance. So,
let me be polite and say I'm lucky.
Okay. So, I got some substance here. You
know, I tell you, I explain in detail my
reasons and I give you a challenge. Try
this workflow. You know, I give you an
alternative.
And and the littered with tens of other
links to my own website that tells you
how to like
like for example, how do you set up
mouse to single click to open file? I
have an article on that.
How do you
why should you ban code keys? I have an
article on that. Each of these article
is you know, written
days yeah, usually years of research.
You know, what about keyboards? Oh, I
have an article on that all of the
keyboards, you know.
So, um key binding. Oh, you know, some
of you know, these Linux people, they
You know, they Linux people, this Linux
typically Linux nerds, these techies,
they are competitive. And they are male
they are male, you know, usually they
are young males. Young males are very
competitive. That's nature, okay? That's
the nature of human animals, not women.
Not girls. They don't need to be
competitive. They will have children.
Uh but males, yes, you do. You know,
because you are if you are not the alpha
male, you get no girlfriends, okay?
That's why all you know, in thousands of
fairy tales and stories, you want to get
a girl. Get girl is your goal.
Males has to be competitive and
especially young
males. Young males, you know, like in
societies, you have rituals. Or in
military, you have, you know,
you have rituals to get the boys to,
you know, fight and
and to, you know, you you want to be
uh competitive.
Otherwise, you end up like me,
a failure.
So, you know, when Linux people in in
this nerds community, they talk, they
debate, you know, they argue all the
time. You know, you are idiot because
this that. No, no, you are actually
because Emacs or Vim this that.
Half of it is actually just the it's
just the um
they're actually, you know, it's just
the
competitiveness.
One-upmanship.
That's part of it. That's the most part
of it.
You know, they they are they are in a
debate not because some subject is
important. It's just because let's see
who who knows better, who is better, you
know, you know, I'm let's see who is the
alpha male. That's what happens.
So,
so let's get back to part of the reason
why this article is popular and you
know, the way I have all these links
about all the technical details of Linux
in particular. For example, Linux, this
article is about how to set a key to
switch to browser. So, I have Mac OS,
Windows, how to AutoHotkey, and Linux.
So, I have a article to show you what to
do.
So, this So, you know,
I do my homework. I did my homework. So,
So, this is part of the reason,
you know, these Linux nerds, they see
some substance at least. So, they they
find um
value to um
I guess spread this article.
So, anyway, I have lots of comments on
this article and actually I did I kind
of mentioned, you know, talk about this
article in two previous videos.
Most of the comments, you know, again,
let me
get back to the point about these, you
know,
people, you know, it's like, you know,
the debate about VI versus Emacs.
It's not really a important question.
However, VI versus Emacs,
you know, so-called religious war.
They, you know, why do why do geeks do
that? Mostly, half of the reason is
because they are young males, okay? They
are doing it is a spot of the ritual,
you know, to be one up manship, to see
who is better, who knows better, who is
a better programmer, who is, you know,
they talk about that, not because the
topic is really important, VI versus
Emacs.
But these people, you know, these nerds,
they don't they don't realize it. They
don't know. They don't they think they
are actually debating reasons, okay?
So, in the same way,
uh what I was going to say. Yeah, so a
lot people
when they debate, you know, they comment
or so-called criticize, you know,
they're not really criticizing.
Vast majority of the response I get
is without content, you know, they
they haven't spent 10 minutes to really
think about the issues. They just
glanced over. For example, they see they
see the clickbait. Oh, this guy he tried
XMonad Haskell for 1 hour and he think
it's idiotic.
You know, they saw that and immediately,
you know, without reading
you know, the whole thing. Immediately
they they have to something to say. You
know, they say, "Oh, actually this guy
is an idiot. Look, he only tried uh
XMonad for 1 hour. How How can he
possibly say that it's idiotic, you
know? This guy must be a troll." That's
what they say, you know.
But beyond that, you have to, you know,
if you really if you are really
concerned about the efficiency of key
binding, you have to think, you know,
you have to actually think for 10
minutes, for 1 hour, for 10 hours, you
know.
You have to think about it. Then when
you reply, you have something
of substance. Then I when I read your
reply, I can see, "Oh, this guy actually
has a valid reason why, you know, some
parts of my article or the whole thing
is wrong. It's you know, it's actually
incorrect or
bad reasoning, something like that.
You know, you have to you
you know, the effort how much you spend
the effort you put into something shows,
okay? It will show.
Doesn't matter what thing.
When you put subs you know, good effort
into a lot effort, whatever you say or
the result
will show. It will show.
So,
so most of my replies on Hacker News on
Reddit, they are just brainless. They
are just oh, this guy is a troll or or
oh, actually, no, he's wrong because um
because I do it this way. I use Vim and
I do it this way. You know, it's like
what's the point of telling me your
habit? Yeah.
Okay, so that's it. So, anyway,
another thing about this kind of thing
is habit. Habit plays the most important
part
about
what you think is the best workflow,
things like that. Because for vast
majority of people, vast majority of
programmers,
they never actually experimented with
different workflow.
You know, whatever they think typically
when they say, oh, this is best way or
you should rebind key this way or that
way.
Their opinions is just a happenstance.
You know, they happen to do it that way
and for years. You know, they just used,
you know, habit. They developed
developed a habit into a particular way.
And they think that's the best way
because, you know, habit. They actually
never,
you know, like a logician, you know, you
sit down, think about what are the
possible all possible ways, you know,
about key binding or
workflow. You you think about all the
possible ways. Then you systematically
explore or logically eliminate which way
is the best way.
You know, they they never do that. It's
like this idea never never ever come up
with, you know, from these idiot this
Linux fanatics nut nuts heads.
Okay, that's it for that. And maybe
that's it for today.
It's it's hot. Today is super hot in
California here.
So, am I still
uh
Okay.
So, what's up, guys? That's it for
today, right? Any more questions? Any
more questions? You're last chance to
reply.
Okay, let's see what
So, what level should typing
be at?
So, what level should typing be at? Oh
my god, the Fibonacci culture.
Tim
Edissa
Edi yes, Edi yes, Jami.
So far, we have EMT Max tapping on us.
Daniel Diaz
Fernandez. Hey, Daniel, I haven't seen
you for a while. Now, you are from
uh Spain, that's right.
So, Daniel says
Are you Aren't you the one who studied
at scale, like the homotopy type theory?
I think Yeah, I remember. I think
Do you have research anything about the
biomechanics of typing?
No, not really. I do have an article to
It's an amazing topic that would be
interesting for a future talk show.
Uh so, if you want to know the
Uh
so, there are some
You know, okay, let me talk about this.
So, repetitive strain injury, you know,
repetitive strain injury, you know, hand
pain when you type too much.
That actually we do not know as far as I
know. Yeah, I know.
So far, our science
uh medical science do not fully
understand what's going on.
Okay, we do not fully understand what
what's causing it. Why How do I know?
Let me show you, okay?
So, you go to my keyboard blog and you
go to where is the article?
So, there it is. Typing Habits Hand
Injury.
Okay?
Then, we go to
um
you know
There are some scientific papers.
You know, the RSI experts, basically
they they will tell you
that
the medical science do not fully
understand exactly what's going on.
Okay?
Um and in fact, for example, you see
this
This is a common
suggestion about ergonomics.
Everything is 90°. Your legs, your knees
bend 90°, your hip
bent 90°, your elbow is supposed to be
90°, your head, you know. In general,
it's a good good um
suggestion, but there is no
very
scientific um validation of this. You
know, I think in general, this is good
because
but there is For example, there are many
people who don't sit this way.
You know, most people don't sit this
way, but they they are fine. They type a
lot, they are fine.
Uh anyway, so let me try to find the
scientific um
article I want to show you because I
have a few.
I have a couple at least
about keyboard, about ergonomic
keyboard, the science of ergonomic
ergonomic keyboards by
by, you know, by these uh researchers.
Okay, I don't know where is it. It's uh
it's I have to think about.
their research on keyboard ergonomics.
So, here you can see a PDF, which is by
this UC Berkeley professor,
David Rempel.
Uh he is a professor of um
ergonomics, okay? So, he wrote an
article about that.
The split keyboard and ergonomic success
story.
So, he wrote an article about that. You
know, he tells you about different
angles,
you know?
Uh
and then
there's another article by
by a different uh ergonomics researcher,
biomechanics of upper limbs.
Um you know, you can go read it. I I I
have an excerpt of it.
It's a book, actually. So, go there, buy
the book.
The biomechanics of the upper limbs,
okay?
So, I'm going to copy the URL. So, so
this is, you know, search for the title
scientific research on keyboard
ergonomics.
Put my name in front of it, you'll find
this article.
So, let me copy that.
Okay, I think that actually that's about
it today. Let me put it here.
And uh later on you'll show up on my
video YouTube links.
Um
so, there's two articles, but there's
more. So, for example, there's another
article, the latest thinking on
computer-related pain.
This This is again by David uh
Rempel.
Uh and he you know, this is a interview,
a question and answer
session. You know, they interview him.
You know, and he talked about for
example, they talked about
this posture.
And basically, he says
you know, this posture and he says
there's no
you know, this is
this is not medically um
like we don't we don't really understand
why this works, you know.
Like you usually you see these, they all
say, "Oh, lumbar support, you know, for
your lower back." And it's you know,
that's semi [ __ ]
But however, you know,
however, you know,
I do recommend this in general, you
know, especially the monitor height, it
matters. And you know,
because you can you know, if you can
feel it. If you sit on the wrong chair,
you can feel it because I used to even
when I was 18 when when I was 18 years
old before before I even used a
computer, there's this chair I sit that
to watch TV and that gave me back pain.
Okay, so tiny window is okay. You can
found you can found amazing and
interesting info in
common approach piano techniques
about biomechanics and easily
transferable to typing. You know,
usually I'm um
um
I question all those, you know, piano
thing. Like often when we talk about
typing, you know, the proper
typing related to hand pain hand pain,
things like that. Many people
programmers they all say, "Oh, I'm also
a pianist. Uh You know, I'm trained as a
pianist. Therefore, you should do this
or that." That's all [ __ ] okay?
I also play piano, okay? I play
I play scale.
Anyway, I love piano, you know, I
Um I I have articles on piano
key actions. Anyway,
you know, with many of these nerds, they
all say, "Oh, it's really, you know,
it's because they play piano, therefore,
you should be this way or that way."
That's usually [ __ ]
I do miss something. Okay, I think
that's it for today.
Float to the max today because your
roommates are asleep. Sleep. I think you
are not able to float to the max.
Uh-huh,
big Kobe so deaf, okay? That makes me
sad. Be sure to tell Asian.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for coming.
Uh
listening to my rant for 70 minutes.
Good night, guys.
And uh thank you. Thank Thank you. Um
Let's see. Every Ren. Thank you, Every
Ren, for the
donation.
Bye, guys.
Bye, guys. One more minutes. Bye, guys.
And there's some question about my
my biography, some sort of biography.
Let's talk about that next time.
Some question about biography.
Internship at Wolfram. Yeah, some people
ask me about that.
I did talk about that one time. Okay, so
one
you know, you search for Sal Khan
Wolfram, okay, on YouTube. Find a
YouTube that's Sal
Khan Wolfram. You might see it.
Yeah,
I had Yeah, I did a lot videos. By now
it's like 200 or 300. So, I don't
I don't know.
Noise in the back.
Okay, bye guys.