And good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Kasan Talk Show. We
are going to deep dive into the source
code of YouTube
download. YouTube download because I'm
concerned I don't want to see anything
nasty, you know, like virus or phone
home. So this is open source. Uh but
nobody really checks the source code. uh
and I am going to do
it. So let me show you. So today's talk
show you can see so there's a command to
download YouTube or videos on Twitter uh
you know you so you know any videos on
Twitter YouTube or other websites Rumble
or uh or
others and uh it's you know it's has a
kind of long history so you know
originally YouTube DL then some someone
forked it because at one time few years
ago ago uh they removed Stack Overflow I
think. I mean uh
GitHub removed the account or something
like that. Okay, so there's a lot of
things you don't know what's going on.
So if you're going to use this command,
you better you have to check the source
code. Okay, a few weeks ago, two weeks
ago, we did uh maybe three weeks ago, we
did a video talking about this thing.
But today we're gonna actually look into
the source code because I really want to
use it and I don't want to just you know
uh for example
uh
wait YouTube download.
Okay. Okay. So this you know I don't I
don't want just to run a command. I want
to I want to see exactly what is what is
the code doing. Okay. To make sure it's
safe, then I can use the command. So, if
you are watching this offline, play at
1.5 speed and and skip, okay? Because I
ramble. If you are here, say hi, okay?
Love to see your comments. So, let's
begin. YouTube download. So, here's a
command. So, uh the latest version fork
is
yt-dlp. Okay. And here is the webs uh
the GitHub page. Let's turn on
JavaScript so Google knows where you
are, what you're doing. And Microsoft
will also
know.
So, okay. So, there is the code. Am I am
I am I all
good? Uh let's
see. Okay. Hold on a second.
Check. Check one more time. Video check.
Audio check. Okay, I'm good to
go. Um, wait. There is
um Okay, that's good. Uh,
so yeah, let's put this here so I can
see. So,
Okay. So, so first first of all I want
to download some um of my uh Twitter
live stream I did on Twitter. So for
example this one you know Twitter is
getting you know they used to show a
thumbnail but now it's hidden so you
don't see it. So this is about Tik Tok
red book China and racial tensions in
USA. I did this one in January. So, but
you know, I didn't find a way on Twitter
like I think you are supposed to be able
to make your video downloadable, but I
checked the options. I didn't find a
way. But anyway, so this one is already
uploaded and there's no options to to
download the video. So, I want to
download
it. So first of all I'm going to do try
to check this manually to see if you
know look at the source code then we are
going to look at the uh source code of
the YouTube download. Okay so get
YouTube download I already you know the
a month ago I did
um uh get clone the project so you can
see all the source code here. So that's
what we're going to look into uh this
um dev script. So this source code like
you know we're going to go as far as I
can and there are like few thousands
lines of code or something. Okay. So
first of all I want my goal is to
download this video. So how does it how
can I do it? So let's see shift control
I. Okay. Uh wait. Okay. So, shift
control I that's a source code. No,
let's control U. Let's get the HTML
source code first. Okay.
Close. Uh,
so, okay. So, let's new and let's save
this XX today's
date you uh Twitter. Okay.
HTML. Copy. Go back here.
Uh, paste the link. So, we got the link.
That's a raw source code. Let's see.
Wow, it's
actually this this page doesn't
exist, you know. So, so here's the
source code. We're going to Okay, make a
backup. Let's look at what um so you see
it's a long HTML. So I'm I'm just going
to explore the way I usually do. Okay.
So I'm not like directly focused on
getting that video. But that's what I
want to do. But meanwhile I'm going to
you know look at the code find anything
interesting. Uh you know that's what I
how I usually go about.
So you see so you know first you know
because this way I mean that's just my
habit okay so you you can observe what
is a you know what people are doing with
the technology the style you know like
they they are using all kind of
frameworks so you got this
incomprehensive [ __ ] so you know so I
I'm just going to look into okay so
first of all so you got this so let's do
format okay format them uh error
formatting. Why is that? Uh expect
expected close tag. Okay, this is a
bad it's obviously invalid HTML. Most of
them are. So, but why can I but um why
cannot I format
it? Syntax error expected close tag at
uh line 342.
So,
oh, so you just got this script
now.
Okay. This
this
obsticated [ __ ] created by late Malay
gen [ __ ] with the frameworks and
all that [ __ ]
And uh they sometimes I mean often times
they are
intentionally done so because not
because they need to you know they what
they they what what they want to do is
like track where you are looking track
how much you scroll on a page how many
how much time you stay on there track
your location you know your IP of course
obviously track your whole browser's uh
fingerprint soal like what what kind of
font you support, what operating system
you are on, what window size, what
browser you are using, so they can
identify you. That's why you see this
crap. Okay? And the opensource [ __ ]
and the open source idiots, they just
the the tech nerds, you know, they just
follow it. They say they say, "Oh, look
at the latest uh framework. Oh, this is
so cool and it's open source. We need to
use that." and the CSS templates. That's
that's how you get this. Okay.
So like even if you are top expert on in
HTML in CSS in JavaScript you know you
or or see you know you look at the code
that that million lines that like you
cannot understand the thing that's
intentional kind of indirectly
intentional that's why we get this
situation.
Okay. Now, okay. So, let's uh so I have
a command kasar html uh format buffer
format to multi-lines. So, that will
make it readable. You see this is
written in eag
uh did I? Okay. So, let me show
you. So you got HTML format buffer and
you got HTML format to
multi-lines. So you see now it's
readable. Now if you undo go to the top
it's unreadable. Okay. Now go back. So
now it's readable. Now that command
is that is this uh in eagisp. Okay. So
that is the command that makes it
readable then but there is another
command let's uh let me show you uh in
HTML mod this command we are actually
called the deno
okay deno which is uh the javascript
engine fantastic I highly recommend it
it's created by the same guy who created
njs he created you know Ryan Da
He created NJS about 15 years ago around
2008. Uh then after two years he he let
it go you know he let the other the
other guy a
scum to run it. Okay. Then it got
corrupted. That's why every time you run
notjs 1,000 libraries you know you
install one library 1000 comes in. That
guy is a [ __ ] He's a scum. Okay. uh
in my opinion a serious gun. So let me
digress. Let's just ask Gro. So AI is
being super powerful. Grog now is on um
so if you go to Okay, let me show you a
few things.
Okay, go to Linux tutorial. Uh wait.
Okay. So, go to uh
search AI chat bots. So, Gro today is
free. There's a website gawk.com. So,
you can go there and ask it things. It's
one of the best. So, we going to ask
uh but I'm just going to use the Grog in
Twitter.
So who is the leader of notjs? Okay,
there's this
guy a
skun operates under the governance of
something blah blah blah. No, I want the
guy. So Ryan D is the creator. Okay.
Then there is this
Isaac Schilutter. Okay. That guy is a
scumbag. Now, I don't have much detail
about that, but that's just my
impression. Okay. Uh, by the way, this
is just my
opinion. Okay, back to So, I highly
recommend
uh Deno. Okay, Deno is a new
thing. So, hold on. Okay, so let me
copy.
Um so you AI chart bots this is all the
AI chart bots you can use free uh you
know there are so many today and and do
not use whatever bundle with Microsoft
okay I uninstall it like the
Microsoft okay I I'm going to digress
all over so
So, Windows sucks. Why use uh Windows
sucks? This is a collection of every
problem of Microsoft Windows. And then
one of them is
um is this yeah Windows copilot you know
you un uninstall it and by next month it
came back. So I uninstall it right away.
Don't use it. So if you want AI bots Gro
I recommend I highly recommend. However
the Gro image generation is no good. for
image generation. You want to download
Flux. Okay. I I'm I haven't done so, but
that's going to
be I'm gonna live stream it in, you
know, tomorrow or next, you know,
coming. So, I'm going to in in the next
live stream also. I'm going to uh
install Flux and I'm going to also
install Deep
uh Deep Seek from China. That's a good
one.
So you want to install them locally on
your machine because you don't you you
don't want to rely on the server because
especially for deepseek when you install
it on your local machine it doesn't have
censorship but if you use the website
you know usually there's lots of
censorship so deepseek uh
deepseek flux
Great for image generation. Okay. Uh
actually we digress so much I need to go
faster. Okay. AI bots and Microsoft
Windows Copilot sucks. Unin uninstall it
right
away. This commercial you know like
usually you know they are very bad. So
we back to Yeah. So we back to looking
at the source code. So there is a deno
format. So HTML HTML format buffer and
it's calling deno. Okay. So you can see
but deno failed because I just tried to
you know press the key. It says syntax
error expected closing tax.
So, so the deno formatter somewhat
expect at least somewhat valid HTML. So,
this you know this HTML from Twitter is
completely
[ __ ] I don't think they actually have
a body. Let's see all the script tags,
you know, like everything is generated
dynamically. Okay, there's so many so
much script tags. script script. Okay,
then
SVG. Uh, let's
see. So, let's look at the source
code. Link link link. What are these
link cross origin? this uh this uh
JavaScript like one 10,000 JavaScript
files by these
frameworks late Malay genen zoomer
[ __ ] Why do they do that? Because
these corporations they do it for money.
They don't care about nothing else. But
meanwhile they say, "Oh, it's open
source." They they make you guys they
deceive you guys so you guys promote it.
So like the entire you know this is
technology this programming you know all
this code is technology but is it
necessary to for them to become this
unreadable no it's not really necessary
it became this way because these money
greedy [ __ ] doing it doing it and
create deception so that you Zuma idiots
and late Men you hackers you you think
you know open source open source you
know that you so you promote it you you
help them spread you know they they are
open source this this is you know these
frameworks is open source but the
corporation is not open source at all
they have 1,000 patents 1,000 lawyers
Facebook Google you know Amazon
Microsoft so they create this lies for
you guys you know you think you are the
great hacker you ethical you are open
source only but you you help them spread
the entire infrastructure of programming
you know
coding to to the you know programming
industry. So anyway let's go back to um
yeah so I want to let's go back to how
do I get the video? Okay so click on
that hello guys I don't want to copy
video so click on that
inspect. Okay, let's see if I
can get the
video. Oh, so so many comments. Okay, so
I'll read the comments
later. So you can see this is
um basically ultimately you want to
find the you want to find the source URL
of the video.
Okay.
So, so this
incomprehensible, you see this CSS?
Okay. That's not big enough. Let me
magnify. Okay. You see this CSS? They
are, let me tell you what they they are.
They are called Atom
style.
Um, okay. That's not big enough. Okay.
So, what's new? Shut the [ __ ] up.
You see this incomprehensible machine
generated
uh
names. Okay. React root react from
Facebook
opensource nuncript. Okay. So background
color black.
Uh so
body. So I want to know where is
[Music]
the where is the video
um source. Okay. Then you got keyboard
shortcuts. Okay. Then you got what the
[ __ ] is
this? Play selected video. Okay. Space.
What is this? area hidden area is for
supposedly the disabled people which is
a complete [ __ ] you know they they
don't actually help
nothing but the again the tech geekers
the open source says oh you need to
support that because for the blind or
the hearing disabled but they are
actually [ __ ] up in so many ways you
know they they create this you
know muk
So data at data at shortcut keys n is
new. So send post delete. Okay. So what
is so this is
dive the equals to
ltr. What is the the attribute? I didn't
know there's a the attribute in
dive. Okay. So let's ask
what is there
a is there a attribute in HTML dive tag
dive
element. Yes the the attribute is a
valid attribute for the dive element. It
is a global attribute. Oh meaning it can
be used by on any HTML. The the
attribute specifies the text directory
of the elements
content. What is particularly useful for
supporting
languages? Oh, direction. Okay. The for
direction. Okay. Uh funny they have to
add left to right. Okay.
Direction.
Uh so this is dive and class a bunch of
class
area hidden force data at shortcut keys
that that's custom attribute data at
shortcut keys. Okay. So if you if this
element is focused then this these
shortcut keys are available. Okay. So uh
x IO more. So let's
see okay that dive element but but what
okay
then then you have a header so they are
embedding so I suppose each
treat is actually a
um you know each each treat is actually
a like HTML page. So you got a header,
you got
um you got D. You know, we need to move
faster otherwise we we because we never
going to dive into the YouTube
download. Okay. So what are we doing?
So
go H1 row
heading. So what exactly? Then heading
then link
home. What is the actual value? My god.
Jesus. SVG view box. So you got a SVG.
Now what is this?
SVG4. Then you got span class span.
Okay.
Yeah. Okay. Let's try go back to here.
go back to this Tik Tok and uh let's
search
for Wait, let's
actually So click on that. I want to go
here.
Okay, so there it is. Tik Tok, Red Book,
China, and racial tensions in USA.
That's a
header. So before that is a video. Okay.
So let's just uh let's
see. So this is the header and it's got
the dive treat text.
Okay. Then above that that's another
wrapper class. Above
that another wrapper. above
that class above that. Okay. So this
thing
expand.
Okay.
Expand.
Expand. Padding butt. Padding bottom.
Okay.
Expand. Jesus. Placement
track. Data test ID. Placement track.
Expand. Data. Test ID. Video player.
There it is. We getting close.
Expand. Data. Video player.
Expand. Padding. Bottom. Okay. data
video player.
So
expand video component. Okay. Style
height
position translate Z. Okay. With video
component
expand
then height position. Okay.
Then go 1,00 nesting dive. Then position
relative. Okay. Overflow hidden. Then
video. Okay. They they actually use a
video tag. There it
is. Okay. Now, right click to copy this
element. Okay.
So,
copy. Copy element. Let's see what we
get. Now, back to this. Open a new paste
and uh save it. xx date
vid.html. Okay. Copy it back to Kasar
talk
show and we're going to paste that here.
Link list. Okay. Open it. So now we call
a command
to make it each word by a line so it's
easier to read. So video preload none
tab index play place in line empty area
label embedded video.
Okay then poster. Okay. So this is the
this is the you know the thumbnail.
Okay. Okay, the video tag got this
thumbnail. So
this so you can let's see if this URL
pro fastly US west one video
PSCP.tv
transcoding thumbnail periscope play
redirect. Okay, now this is a long URL.
Now there's a question mark that means
after that is a query. So you got
token, you got
token, token quite long. Then you got
this, this, this, this, and then service
equals to
proxy e and the just equals to that.
Okay.
Now let's open this URL in Braay browser
because in Brave browser I have I'm
logged in because if you open this in in
a browser that's not logged in. You are
not going to get it. So let's try. So
but this is just a poster. So that that
is just a picture of the thumbnail. It's
not an actual video. So let's try it
anyway. So, tab
O B for
brave. Let's see if it
works. No.
What? Tap
[Music]
OB. Open in Brave. Okay.
So, why is it not? Because it's too
long. Let's select
it. Tab. O B doesn't work. Probably be
too long.
So HTML
open
URL.
Um open in
Brave. Yeah, it's not working for some
reason. Let's do it manually. New tab.
Paste.
Go. Oh, it downloaded. It became a
JPEG. It became a JPEG and it is just a
blank image. What the [ __ ] You see
this? This nasty things they are doing.
You see all this
trouble get you a thumbnail of a blank
thumbnail. It is not blank, you know.
It's not supposed to be blank. It's
supposed to be like that. Let's
refresh it. You know, it used to have a
thumbnail, but but maybe because this is
political issue, so Twitter, you know,
kind
of censored it somewhat. You you never
know exactly what's going on. It used to
have a
thumbnail. So anyway, this this poster,
okay, that's not what we need anyway. So
now, let's continue.
style type source. Okay, here is the
source. Now the source says blob. Now I
don't understand why does the source
what is
the you see you see there is the the
blob. I don't understand what is that
for. I don't think that's valid. So
let's ask
Gork what
is the word
blob in a
HTML video
elements src
attribute in the context of an HTML
video elements src attribute the term
term blob typically refers to a blob
URL. Oh, binary large object URL. I
didn't know that
before. Blob
URL. This is a special type of URL that
start with blob colon. Wow, I didn't
know
that. And points to a binary object
stored in memory.
Okay. Rather than a file hosted on a
server, I see blob URLs are often used
to dynamically load media content. Okay.
Such as
video. Okay. So, let's try now. Copy
that. Go to Brave. Now, let's try
this. Tap
OB. There it is.
Okay. So, if you try this blob URL,
that's a video
object. Can you play? No. Can you save
it? No. You see, it's not the
actual video. It generated a
HTML. Is that
right? No. Wait.
No, never mind. That's just Never mind.
So, new tab, paste this blob URL. Enter.
Your file couldn't be
accessed. Okay, it's nasty
trickery.
So, it does not allow you to get that
unless maybe you need to have a referral
and stuff.
Okay. So, but if you use we
get well you need referrals and stuff
maybe.
So, so okay. So, so far this video
tag Yeah. So, let's try this again.
Inspect. Yeah, I
cannot find the video. Let's shrink.
Where where are
we? So this is the header Tik Tok in
China. Okay. Then then you go up
And don't know where did that video tag
gun. So can we search
VO search again
video meta name? So what is
this? Okay. So
maybe there meta name Twitter image
broadcast thumbnail
original. So
content.
Yeah. So search
again. Search
again. Oh yeah. So this is the search
again. Now what? What is this
one? Style. So that's just the
style. Image embedded video. Okay.
So maybe that
is Oh, that's the empty, you know.
[ __ ] Yeah.
So, next next embedded
video
buttons, SVG circle. You see that's why
you know it's almost impossible these
days if you are trying to find a
video. Uh so I think I give up on this
manual
thing. So you know there's a lot you
know so I you know it takes a lot of
time to go through all these.
Now I still don't have a clear
understanding of of this
um
structure. Okay. So video video let's
see one two three four five 6 7
8 9
11 12. Okay. Now this time search
for tag
video. Okay. No, it doesn't find
anything.
Um tag video.
No. So it doesn't search the tag, I
suppose. So now search video again.
video
space and
uh
src.
No, you know, before we found the video
tag. So, where did that
go? Yeah, very annoying.
So, okay. So, that's that's the manual.
I'm trying to download this video
manually,
but apparently you can. It's very hard
to do today. You know, 10 years ago, you
can still do that because I' I've done
that on YouTube videos or stuff. Uh but
I guess now it's becoming even
harder. So that is why we need to use
close that. That is why we need to use
this uh YouTube
download. Okay. So let's
see. Close
that. Show. Okay. Um, and also the deno
format doesn't work because this is not
a valid HTML at all. They, you know,
let's double check one more time. So
they So
body wait, I didn't get the full source
code. So let's try
again. Control U. Okay, that's supposed
to be the full source code, right? But
no, it ends at
script. Oh, I see. Right. So, the HTML
is not valid. But however, if you run
it, the JavaScript inserts the HTML.
That's this is the real actual source
code you want. So, can we get Yeah. So,
let's copy this entire
source
code and can
we copy out HTML? Let's
see. Okay, close
that. Open this. This is a uh No, not
that one. This is the video. This is the
source code. Now this is the raw HTML.
Go to the button. Okay. Now select or
paste. Now this is the actual generated
HTML. Okay. Save
it. Yeah, this is the actual generated
HTML. And
uh okay. So you got So now let's try the
demo format again. Tap
F.
Successful. Fantastic. Now it's
readable.
Okay. So we are looking at the generated
code for this video on
Twitter. Yeah. So now it's much more re
uh readable. Fantastic. Now just search
for video. Now in Emacs it's everything
is fantastic. So you can clearly see
what's going on. Video. Video. Okay.
Uh let's magnify this. Let's so you can
see. So now it's very clear what's going
on. Now where is the video
tag? Now is there any actual video tag?
Because we s we saw it
before. Close that. Search again. Video
less than the video tag. Oh, there's no
video
tag. Wait, I saw that before. We didn't
we? Yeah. So, we saw this video tag.
What's going on? Let's search for
preload. Okay. Search for preload.
So there's uh these
occurrences
but you see very interesting. You do not
see a video tag at all but we saw it
before. That's probably because we
didn't click play. So now let's try
click play. play.
Hello guys, just random chat. I I'm on
my smoking break. Can you see me? Okay,
so now we
played. They probably changed, you know,
the JavaScript probably changed the
source code. So now we need to
uh do the source code
again. So right click, inspect. Okay.
Now go to the top and copy this entire
thing. Let's see. Copy outer HTML. I
never know exactly what's the
difference. So now select all delete
paste. Okay. So
now we got it. Save it. Now search for
the uh
preload looks very different than
before. Okay. Now search for
video.
Exactly. So now exactly they are
different. Now
uh now let's do deno format.
Okay. Tap
F. So now it's easier to read. Deno
format is very industrial. So doesn't
matter how
complicated, how obst
um obstacated HTML and CSS and
JavaScript it is. It will format it.
Well, this is so this is
um tab
ftml format buffer. If you want this
code, you go to this URL show in
browser. There's a source code. You need
to have deeno installed. Okay. So that's
uh for you Emacs users. This could be
useful. Okay. So Nick, hello. Hi Nick.
So Nick explained what is the blob. Blob
is any binary objects. It's so you don't
necessarily try to read the whole thing
in
memory.
Okay. So, so anyway, that's deno format.
I mean, yeah, fantastic. Okay. So, you
can So, now, so now let's look at
video. Search for all video
uh word.
Okay, we started to see video
player and
uh there it is the video tag. You see
this nasty [ __ ] So only when you play
click the play then the HTML changed
then the video is actually
there. So you got the video tag um you
see. So you see
um okay you see the word here that's the
end tag. Where's the beginning
tag? There. Okay. So jump to that
line. There is the video. Okay. So now
add a new line. There's the video.
So this
poster and source there like before. So
we found this
source but if you open it it won't
work. New tab paste. No. Okay.
Um so what we
do you know now we can try to get this
thing. I don't think it'll work. So
that's why. So okay. So now we know we
are at the dead end. Okay. So now close
this. Close this. We try to manually get
this URL. It won't work eventually. But
we learned the blob URL. We learned a
few things. The blob the and also only
when you click play then the video tag
showed
up. Okay. So now that's that. Okay. It's
already 50 minutes. Uh
okay. So now we need to start to look
into the um the source code of
the git directory YouTube download.
Okay. Now we need to look at the source
code. Okay. Okay. Let's continue.
Okay. Why not? Let's just continue. So
take a break.
It was a big controversy when GitHub
banned the original project. Yes. For
some reason, you know, many reasons in
the deep state, you know, like maybe
someone in the deep state told GitHub,
you know, they told Microsoft. Micros
GitHub is owned by Microsoft today, of
course. So they told you know then you
know you need to remove this
thing then there's some resistance of
course you know some you know some
workers at GitHub maybe they are poor
open source you know but eventually they
they they will fail of course because
this opensource idiots they don't know a
thing how society
works so but then it got removed then of
of course there are other open source
fanatics They're going to they make a
fork they already have. So they you know
so it's like a perpetual
fight a perpetual fight the tech geekers
can never win
basically.
Um so ACP says I usually first play the
video and observe the network tab. Oh
that's a nice
tip. Oh that's a nice tip. Okay. So
maybe we can try
that. He polarized JavaScript on the
back end. Site
crime. Uh hello bra left to right. Emacs
on Windows is so slow. No, I don't think
so.
Uh you trying to rewrite? No, I'm not
trying to rewrite. I'm just trying to uh
understand. I I'm just trying to make
sure the code doesn't have any nasty
things. But this this is going to take
an hour or two. Okay. So, let's take a
break and continue. But before we do
that, let's try the network tab. Okay.
Control
shift I to turn on the JavaScript
console and then click on the network.
Okay. And
complicated. Okay. Now you let's try
refresh. Refresh
it. 1,000 objects. You know, it's
downloading 1 million
objects. JavaScript.
[ __ ] Okay.
Then then go back here, click play, and
let's see what is doing what what you
know. Chunk chunk random chat. I I'm on
my smoking break. You see me?
You see this chunk chunk chunk? I should
stop smoking. But anyway, let me just
talk about something random because I
want to start to do live stream on uh X.
You see instead of a video source code
you got this chunk chunk chunk
typescript very interesting it's
actually typescript so is it I mean ts
is
typescript so how do
they so they they
embed request URL so they embed the
video like a fraction of the video in
Typescript Is
that what it is? Let's see what is this
TTS. Oh, it downloaded chunk. Okay,
let's look
at Go to download directory.
Refresh.ts. So, this chunk is part of
the
video.ts. It is not TypeScript. It's a
binary blob. Okay. But why do they name
it.ts? I don't
know. Okay.
So, you know, this is a binary
blob. It's probably something you can
just
play, you know. So, that's one of the,
you know, that's how they prevent you
from downloading
anything. Okay. So, anyway, so let's go
back. Let's
see. So, you got this.ts ts chunk and
client event JSON, you know, one
complete [ __ ] up
[ __ ] Okay, so that's why, you know,
that's why this this this YouTube
download is so
complex. Um,
get YouTube download. Okay. So, yeah.
So, we we we need to look into
that. This this chunk is
not
helpful. Oh, so Z says YouTube download
not working.
Okay. Thank you. Thank you for trying
that for me because I didn't try it.
Okay. So if you I you know I think I
trust what you are saying. YouTube
download on Twitter is not
working. So you see it's a perpetual
fight. You know they they trick the code
to prevent you from downloading and the
open source guys try to you know fix it.
I guess it right now it's not
working. So but okay. So since you said
that, let me try it because I don't want
to try it because before I look at a
code, I don't want to try it. But uh
but you know, it's like there's one
0.1% is something nasty because very few
people like almost nobody actually look
at the source code. You just do YouTube
download update then the new version
comes to your computer then you just run
it you know trying to download something
then you who knows what it's doing
uh so yeah well I I don't want to try it
so you guys so you guys try it okay
you put the virus in your computer let
me show you the URL okay let me show you
the command
so
Uh
wait wait wait that's YouTube download
uh that's the old one you know so it
become very complicated
uh so what you want is this one okay cyt
uh c stand for
command
cyt cyt TD okay so
that
YouTube-d okay so ID keep video extract
uh something and the video is this one
okay so
that's that's a command you guys can try
uh or you know the original I
mean another complexity is that uh let
me show you the the treat. Okay. The
treat of that
video is this one. Okay. Copy. You know,
it used to show a thumbnail, but now it
doesn't. I don't know why. You know, I
was afraid I'm afraid it's censorship
because it's kind of, you know, politics
related. So, that's
why I decided to not to talk about
politics too much. you know because um
so anyway this you know you can try the
video directly the URL or the Twitter
post. Uh I suppose it won't work. Uh
should I try
it? No, I'm not going
to I'm not going to try it without
looking at the source code first. Okay.
Now to look at the source code means
it'll take like two
hours. Uh let's see what Okay. So
uh okay. So now let's
um Okay. So which one is the
main suppose this one?
Okay.
Uh okay.
You don't even know which one it begins.
Okay. So, yeah. So, look at to look at
this will take actually few
hours. Uh download the extractor. So,
and I'm not familiar with the Python
framework.
So, so you you kind of also need to look
up the structure the you know
um okay so but what but what is it uh
originally like the first question
is when you run this command you yt-dlp
key. Well, first of all, that's a
Windows
binary. So, I don't know how do you
build a Windows binary from Python. So,
that's something you look
into.
Um, so that's the first question. But I
mean the first question is you want to
know how you know where does the program
start to call? So, which
file then? But then you need to know how
does Python makes a Windows binary.
Okay. Then the other thing you want to
know is can we run this YouTube download
directly as a Python code? You know
since it's Python can you do that or you
can you not
because because the tech gets very
complicated. So sometimes you may not be
able to do it without some sort of
building it
first. Uh so if you need to build it
then the question is how do you build it
like what what is involved? So that's
why you need to know all these
configurations and project
[ __ ] Okay. So that so that's um so
today I think that's it for today. Today
we just explored the videos on Twitter
source
code. Okay maybe.
Yeah. So Twitter working but YouTube
gives
error. Oh okay. So it it
works.
So, Zo says, "Why not use e-glots and
LSP server? Much easier to go to
definition." We talked about that
yesterday.
Okay.
Uh, it says Twitter working. Okay. So,
um, so let me just try
it. Should I just try
it?
No, I don't want to try
it. Yeah. So, there's a, you know, so
that's it for today. Uh, we haven't
looked into YouTube DLT DLP
YTLP.
Um, oh so there is a instruction. So
this you you this is what you do.
Uh so what is the option
M dash M in Python
3. The M option is a command line flag
used when running the Python
interpreter. It stand for module.
Okay. Allows you to execute a Python
module as a script directly from the
command command line.
Okay. Oh, okay. So, yeah. So it's, you
know, but this won't
work because Python wouldn't
know this module
exist. So in order for Python to know
that, you have to do
something. Okay. So I think that's it
for today.
in. So, what do you guys think? You
know, do you guys So, so, you know,
let's just talk random for for a
while. So, do you guys when you guys
need to download a video, what do you
do? I suppose most of you just, you
know, just download YouTube download and
just just run it without worrying too
much. Most people just do that,
right? Okay. You do not need those
special files for modules anymore. Thank
you. Yeah. So, I'm kind of out of date
of, you know, Python, especially the
Zumas, you know, these frameworks, you
know, these config files, the YAML and
stuff. But I've been coding Python since
like 15 years ago.
Oh, okay. So, yeah. So, you guys just
run the code, but are you So, my
question is, do you are you guys not
afraid something
nasty went into that YouTube download?
Like, how do you know? Because usually
when you download YouTube or some
something it doesn't work, it asks you
to update. So, you
update. So, so how do you how can you be
sure that there's no something nasty in
the code some virus because when you run
it just you know just install virus to
your computer you never know.
So in the old days in the '9s the
hackers we
usually you you know you look at the
source code or you run a um you know
network trafficking uh program
uh wired sha sha shock you know
shockwired or something.
Yeah. So but you but do you actually do
it Nick? I don't think you do because I
think you I think you are comfortable
with the
establishment
right so you know you either you run a
network sniffing stuff which is very
complicated you know then you need to
know uh IP you know the the the whole
TCP IP
infrastructure so that's another thing
you know that's another thing like
looking at the source code you because
you need to understand the whole packets
and stuff
um to know what what it is actually
trying to do to know if it actually you
know downloaded some virus to your pro
to your computer or send your photos to
Microsoft. Uh the other option is use
other website you know like the zquas
suggest that that sucks. Okay. Never go
to a website that says download Twitter
video, download YouTube video.
Um, actually you can do that. But but if
you do that, that
means that means somebody else this
YouTube download or Twitter download
website knows what you are downloading.
Okay. So normally that doesn't matter
you know. So what you know so you know
so but but but the thing is they know
you are downloading they know what
videos you try to download which
means well I mean it doesn't mean much
because when you watch your video on
Twitter Twitter already knows you are
watching it
right but I mean that you know so it
just means you know someone else then
knows that you downloaded video And also
when you when you use these other you
know web services to download video you
never know what they embed into the
video. You see, you cannot be
sure whatever you know little things you
know like like especially today the
video format is very
complicated unless
you have been a video format
professional then you know you know you
know but you know you never know what's
going on. So there's lots of these
issues.
[Music]
Uh okay, that's it for
today. Use a immutable DRO so nothing
can mess up the
roots. Oh, that's interesting. I haven't
heard of that. So which for example,
what what what is a immutable DRO?
Let's ask
Gro
immutable Linux
distro. Okay. Is a type of Linux
operating system designed with a core
system that is read only and cannot be
modified during normal use. This
immutability means that base operating
systems such as directories user being
li boot are locked. Okay. Now, okay.
Yeah. Okay. So, you just lock those
directories and what else? Key benefit
trade off. Okay. Now, examples. That's
what I want to know. Examples of
immutable Linux distro fedora silver
blue. Okay.
Uh, open susi micros Ubuntu core.
Okay. Okay. Nix OS. Okay. That's the one
I heard recommended. Nix
oxos. My if I going to switch to Linux
anytime soon. Okay. Maybe it'll be Linux
OS. Yeah. So I don't want, you know. So
yeah, that's good. But basically, it's
just locking up this being, you know,
being user directory. So that's not too
much. It's not something like new
technology, you know. So yeah.
So okay, Rudolph Rudy says, "No, that's
what I'm not that's not what I'm saying.
that what I'm saying is that you have to
check, okay? Because you can never be
sure. Oh, god damn. Why not full screen
window? I use Nyx. Okay, Nyx is good.
San Francisco
uh GIX. Well, that's a new version of
Nyx. Okay, that's it. I don't know much
about that. Okay, so that's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching.
Uh, another option,
Mingic. I record the screen with my
phone.
That's That's poor man's technology to
download the video.
Okay. Okay, that's it. Bye, guys. Bye.
We shut down
now.
So, you know, I got so many to-dos. So,
for my next live stream, there's so
many. So, I still haven't looked
at the YouTube download. So, I still
need to do that. So, maybe that'll be
another video live stream. Okay. Today,
we just look at the, you know, the the
video code. Um, yes. So, a lot to
do. Donate. Okay. Go to cassadi.info.
Uh oh, it has to do it has to execute
Google JavaScript. I didn't know. So
let's look at the you know what kind of
files it include. Okay. Uh so let's demo
the power of Emacs.
So we are in YouTube download directory.
Now let's start
uh PowerShell. Okay. Not eman shell
powershell. Now uh casar powershell the
interactive a brief because I have 100
200 a briefs. I don't remember. So
I call kasar interactive a brief. If you
want that code it's on the web. Okay. So
now we let's search for uh
JavaScript files. Let's see what we
found. Okay. None. Uh why
not? Wait, there's no JavaScript file.
So let's try ts. No. Uh let's try
py. Yeah, lot of Python files.
So So why is it calling uh Google JS? Do
you mean dynamically? I don't know. But
anyway, there's no JavaScript
files. So, there's there are about 1,000
files or Python. Okay. So, you got this
uh let's you know some you know we can
look at
Twitter extractors. So, extractors for
100 different websites. Okay. So, what
else? Uh, then you got downloader. So,
what's the difference between downloader
and
extractor? Okay, so let's search for
Twitter. Okay, there is Twitter. Open
it.
Twitter.py. That's the
extractor. Okay, so you got you need
math. Okay. So, let's see. So, today we
just look at the Twitter video code.
Now, let's look at the extractor and see
if something we can
recognize. How many how many lines of
code? 1,800.
[ __ ] Uh,
Jesus. Yeah, they cannot
Oh,
really? That's another nasty thing. So,
it it it calls a Google JavaScript
dynamically. That's really nasty. Yeah,
that's that's why I that's what I'm
saying. You have
to you have to read the source code to
know exactly what it is doing. You don't
know what it is
doing, you know. And also you know the
YouTube download and all this open
source you don't know who they wrote it
you know who wrote them
like you just can't be sure like you
know these
days you know they think they make you
think you open source fanatics [ __ ]
you know you recommend all this to your
friends but but but nobody actually know
who is like creating this like usually
they hide you know like usually
they you know like 10 years ago they
pretend they are nice people you know
they they they don't want to be [ __ ]
they want to be like um humble you know
so they don't put their name up there
you know they just create a kind of
YouTube download and you know they don't
they don't create a name and usually
it's hard to find the
author like you it'll take you 10
minutes if you possibly can find who who
actually who is original who faked this
this YouTube download
thing like you don't know so many things
you don't know you know then you know
that's that's what happens so you can
look at the um commits like who is
committing to the
project and most of them are announced
these opensource [ __ ] announce
announce So you can because why? Because
they believe you know meanwhile they are
open source fanatics like you got you
guys but meanwhile they are also a non
fanatic because they are afraid of the
deep state. Each one of you is like this
tiny you know you think you are freedom
fighter. You know you are afraid of the
deep state. So you are you are
contributing to this anonymous fox that
makes everything incomprehensible. You
know you think you are doing good but
but who how do you know these people are
actually good you you don't
know you know that's why sometimes you
have big news like this this project got
hacked or you know like uh there's a
secret virus there you you don't know
and these days those news are actually
they don't spread much anymore like you
never know what the what is going
now. Okay, bye guys.
Uh,
well, yeah, but
[Music]