Testing, testing. Sorry for the delay.
Testing. I got some I think my audio is
low. So, anyway, we're going to do Emacs
Lisp coding today.
And hello, Huang Zhao. Are you the Huang
I know? Are you Are you on a different
account? So, anyway, so OBS, I mean,
Emacs Lisp
coding. Okay, let's see I'm alive. So,
is my audio low?
Is that Is my audio low?
So, let's go to Windows. Yeah, Windows
11, you know, you got this audio
enhancement. Anyway, so let's let's just
code Emacs Lisp. That's all we're going
to do today. So, let's show in browser.
If you are here, say hi. You are
watching Saw Talk Show. Hello, Huang.
I'm Huang Bro.
Hey, Huang.
So,
Huang from Germany. Okay, so what you up
to? What you How are you doing?
Huang is also a Emacs Lisp coder.
So, we're going to do Yeah, so okay, so
today we're going to Okay, I'm going to
have some drink, too. So, I'm just going
to do random. Okay, this video
you probably don't want to watch this
video. And you probably want to pay me.
Okay, go to my PayPal and pay me.
And I'm just going to drink some
Okay. So,
Emacs Lisp coding. Okay, the most
advanced fantastic coding you'll see.
But I'm going to do it slowly, okay?
Have some red wine first.
Can you talk about what you normally eat
nowadays?
Okay, that's going to ruin my talk show
today because I'm I'm then I'm going to
talk about that for an hour.
What Okay, what do I eat nowadays?
I I eat whatever my wife cooks.
Fantastic wife.
Huang, you need to get your wife. Grab
her quite quickly.
You better a her. Grab your girlfriend,
that China girlfriend. You need to grab
her fast and have children, okay?
So that is my advice to you.
Now don't don't don't worry about what
will happen, you know, in a few years.
Maybe you'll get, you know, maybe you
don't get along or something, whatever,
you know, but grab her, have a baby now,
okay?
That's my recommendation. So what do I
eat these days? I eat whatever my wife
cooks.
Most delicious
Chinese food.
Okay?
So remember we going to do Emacs Lisp
coding.
Am I alive and well?
Yeah, I'm hanging hanging on.
She's doing internship at ByteDance.
Wow, that's nice.
That's nice.
China is taking over.
While the United States of America
is collapsing.
Collapsing badly.
Collapsing
very badly.
Uh pretty sad.
Okay, so I Okay, we going to finish this
for sure, okay? Let me Let me tell you
Let me start to do what we want to do
today, okay?
Yeah. So
mark the time. So we going to do Emacs
Lisp coding beginning now, okay? So the
problem is you see Let me Let me tell
you. You see you go to a website This is
about uh website design for web dev.
Okay, so you go to website xahlee.info,
okay? xahlee.info. For example, you can
go to the keyboard
page, let's say keyboard. That's a
popular topic.
Okay, then you got ergonomic keyboards.
You see, you can click there. Then you
see a lot ergonomic keyboards. You see?
You see, they are made
I have these icon links. Each link is
icon, you know, each one of these I've
been using live for like
several years. I've been using this live
for like 2 3 years.
I've been using this one live for like
uh 3 years, you know.
Uh I've been using um
and I've been using this one for several
months live stream. You can watch my
previous live stream. You will see. See,
I've been using uh this one
for a week, I think, or a few days.
I've been using uh what is this one?
This one I don't have. I think it's
great.
But um you know, but things have
changed. Okay, we need to stop. So
anyway, because
otherwise this video's going to be about
keyboards. So this is I've been using
this one for like um
live for maybe a few months.
But off live, you know, I've been using
them half a year or something. Each one
is different. Anyway, so and this one is
what I am using right now you are
seeing, okay? Ultimate hacking keyboard,
okay?
I recommend Glove80.
I highly recommend Glove80. Very
expensive. Um
Kinesis 360 I
also recommend. Better than better than
Kinesis Advantage 2.
Anyway, I'm not going to talk about
keyboards because otherwise this video's
going to be keyboards. I talked enough
about keyboards You know, 100 videos.
So, this XBone is exposed is very also
superb. Ultimate [snorts] Hacking is
also supreme, but it's kind of very
expensive, okay? This This one I'm
using.
Uh so, anyway, so so what So, okay, back
to the topic. So, I have these icons.
So, these icons let me show you, okay?
So, you open them. So, you can see um
So, for example, uh one piece split
sections dish surface keyboards, okay?
So, you go down, so you can see Go down.
Go down. Go down. There. Dish surface
keyboards that correspond to that.
Can you see my screen?
No, you cannot. You got a problem.
So, this needs to be like that. Okay.
Well.
Okay.
And increase the height, okay?
So, you see this correspond to that, and
this one piece split sections co-
correspond to
there. You see? Now, let's go here. So,
you see each one of them is a list. You
see this is a UL stand for unordered
list, okay? And each list item
You see? And each item this item then
you got a
anchor tag that's link. Then inside the
anchor tag you got this image. So, let's
open the image. You see that's a
thumbnail, okay?
Now,
pay attention. Notice, in thumbnail
there is no width and height.
Why is that? Because I removed it
a few years ago because, you know, let
me show you how this, you know, for how
do I
write my webpage? Let me show you, okay?
So, for example, I want to add a new
link. So, so okay, watch my commands,
okay? So, the commands on the pink
window, you will see all my command
calls and keystrokes. For example,
uh delete forward, delete backward,
undo, undo, okay? So, you can see all
the command names and their keystroke on
the left.
The keystroke is Dvorak keyboard layout,
okay? So, let me just go slowly. I
repeated this a thousand times in all my
videos. So, for those people don't know,
okay? So, I'm using a Dvorak keyboard
layout, which is one of the advanced
keyboard layout. So, you can find the
information
on
Mike Sadi web
keyboard blog.
Okay, so what is Dvorak keyboard layout?
So, you just go to the layout section,
design layout there there.
Keyboard layout design. Then, you go to
ergonomic keyboard layout. So, you can
see the layout diagram, a heat map.
The bigger the circle means that letter
is that key is more frequently used,
okay? So, this is QWERTY, QWERTY,
everyone is familiar with. That's your
keyboard. You can see it. That's what
the keyboard you use, which is idiotic.
Okay? Then, you can switch to Dvorak,
and all of a sudden, you can see the
most frequently used keys are now in a
home row.
You see the aligned. You see back to
QWERTY, you see QWERTY is all over.
idiocy.
Dvorak, you see? Then, people
later on has a lot variations. So, you
got Colemak, you got QFM, you got
Workman, you got Norman. There's so
there's a science, there's an entire
science and culture
dedicated to the keyboard layout. For
example, you go to Reddit, there's a
community about all these different
keyboard layouts like these nerds. Like
they design their layout and and talk
about which one is more efficient, okay?
So, I [snorts] have 10,000 articles
about them.
Like you'll find, you know, you you you
you you need to go through my articles
like links are so many so many because
I've been I wrote them, you know, for
Well, the beginning of my keyboard
journey is 1990
uh two, okay? So, I read read read read
all these things before the internet
began. So, anyway, so so you got the
keyboard layout, okay? So, you can see
the QWERTY. So, let's do it again.
QWERTY, Dvorak, Colemak, then others and
then you got other fancy ones. Uh BÉPO,
BÉPO 15, BÉPO 15. Colemak. These are
new. This this
BÉPO is like 10 years old, okay? Only
10.
Uh Colemak is
Okay, QWERTY is like 100 years old. 150
years old, QWERTY.
Cole uh Dvorak is uh
is a 80 years old, something like that,
okay? Colemak is 20 years old. Colemak
began around 2006
by a
whose name is Colemak. That's his name.
You know, he he got a vision.
Uh Dvorak is not good enough. We can do
better. Colemak and he push for it. He's
got e- you know, he's very pushy.
You know, he want to replace Dvorak. So,
I dis- I don't like this the guy, okay?
But he's good, okay? I think he's a good
guy. He didn't He did not do nothing
wrong. Unlike some other
you know, people in programming
community. He didn't do anything wrong.
But he's just like promoting a lot of
his
uh keyboard layout. You you he think
it's superior than Dvorak and a lot
people fell for it.
In some ways better but not in other
ways. I have a article on that. Okay,
you you know, I have a article on that
in diving in depth.
So anyway, that you got Colemak, you got
then you got this QFMLWY.
What what a name, you see?
Because there's another guy who is a
biologist who is a um
you know, anyway, a scientist, you know,
on his spare time he studied efficiency
of so he came up by computer came up
with a
this layout supposedly the most the most
efficient, you see.
And this this one is like also
by now 15 years old, okay? Like 2010 or
something.
And you have Workman. Workman is, you
know, the guy who studied
Dvorak and he used it and he studied
Colemak, the newcomer, the new new kid
in town, Colemak. And this Workman
thought,
"They got problems, okay? They got
problems." So so I created Workman.
Solve their problems, okay? So Workman
is also like
10 years old something, okay?
Norman is another new one, okay? So
anyway, each one's got stories, okay?
Each one's got history.
So anyway, that's about layout. So let's
go back because I want to do a Emacs
coding. Is there anyone watching? If you
are watching, say hi, okay? And PayPal
me, go to PayPal, donate to me, okay?
Huh, Jesus. Looks like we going to never
start to code if because I start to talk
about layout and stuff in random.
Do you guys like it?
But actually
I'll make a promise. Actually, I'm going
to actually code this because
because
because it happens so often that I start
to do live stream and I just talked
about stuff for an hour or even two
without actually doing what I wanted to
do. So, it became delayed and next, you
know, late
live stream and so on.
Uh wordy blog, uh so okay, so are you
guys here? So, say hi, okay? Hey, yes.
Okay, who else is here? Like three
people, something like that.
So, we were talking about keyboard
layout, okay? That's a good topic, but
So, Neo is for designed for German
language.
And there's alternative ADNW also for
German and there's a Bepo or Bepo for
French
designed for French, the most efficient
for French and there's French AZERTY.
And there's PT Nativ Nativo for Brazil
Brazil Portuguese.
Okay, then there's Russian. Dzhonken
Dzhonken is not official layout, but
it's
but there's a official one for Russian.
Anyway, so this are about keyboard
layouts, okay?
So,
why are we talking about it? Because I
was telling you I'm using Dvorak. I've
been using Dvorak since 1994.
Before you were born.
Okay?
1994 because, you know, anyway.
Uh [snorts]
you know, I had to create the layout on
the Mac using ResEdit. Anyway, I talked
about that before. Anyway, so I was
using I'm I am using the Dvorak keyboard
layout. So, the keystroke you see when
whenever I press a key, you see it shows
on the pink window, those are from
Dvorak layout, okay?
Okay?
And I'm using soft light keys.
Now, if you don't know what that is,
that's the most efficient key binding
system on
on Emacs and you can look at the
website. Okay, so here's the source
code. 4,000 lines of code. Go to the top
and go to the Xah Fly Keys homepage
showing browser. So, this is Xah Fly
Keys homepage for Emacs. It is the most
efficient key binding system for Emacs,
okay? In the universe, in fact, not just
for Emacs. The most efficient key
binding system, meaning that if you are
a programmer or if you need to writer,
you write a lot, you need to edit text
pro- profusely, you know.
Uh, this is the most efficient way.
Saves you keystrokes, okay?
It's kind of like modal, it's like Vim
VI modal, but
the keystrokes, the key choices are
based on
frequency of the command. So, there's a
science behind it. Unlike VI or Vim,
which is like historical, okay? The Vim
VI keys are just historical. It so
happens that back in 40 years ago,
50 years ago, 1970s, they
do it that way. Therefore, it's that
way. That's how VI or Vim or NeoVim
are like, okay? Like the the you know,
it's got HJKL for arrow movement, okay?
But, Xah Fly Keys is designed from the
ground up
with the goal of efficiency in mind,
okay? It's also like modal, just like
VI, but the efficient, okay?
So, anyway, that is what I'm using.
Okay, that and in fact, this is probably
my
uh, best achievement in my life. When
I'm dead, I will be remembered for this
thing.
Probably, something like that. A little
bit, okay?
>> [sighs]
>> What heavy What heavy talk.
I switch to Colemak. Okay, that's not
too bad. Enjoy.
Do you have something like expand
region? I really like using that.
Well, in HTML I have, you know, I'm
using side HTML mode. So, you can see
there. So, you can expand. Of course,
you can expand.
For example, right now I just expanded
to select the entire body.
Uh so, it expand by the nesting of the
HTML, right? So, but in um
in uh in Emacs Lisp you can also There's
also a command. So, for example, let's
say you
your cursor is on a paren
and you press this key I, it will select
the whole parenthesized expression.
What the Lispers would call sexp.
Sexp with a P. That's what Lisp
Lisper Lisp phonetics would call it
sexp.
Which stand for
uh symbolic expression, okay?
S E X P.
So, anyway, you put So, put your cursor
on a paren and press the key
I
or on QWERTY press the key G if you are
using software keys, then we will select
the entire
parenthesized expression, okay? Now,
press it again
to expand it.
You see, that's what you are asking.
You see? Press it again to expand. You
see, now it became the whole function,
right?
Now, press again. It It stops because
there's no more expansion for Lisp.
So, that is the case when you are in
Lisp code. I'm using
Emacs Lisp mode. You see?
I'm using all my modes all my own.
Because I'm too old, I don't use any
other people's code.
All the code I use is my own.
And you have to And for 10 years, they
are free.
They are open source, but the open
source
they grabbed it, you know, they don't
pay, you know, they you don't get
nothing. You just become tech support
for them.
So, now they are not They are still open
source, but you have to pay me to get
them, okay? So, except stuff like keys
is still
free on the web, okay? The others like
Emacs Lisp mode because uh
HTML mode uh because uh Emacs Lisp mode,
you have to pay because uh CSS mode and
uh and the most um
complicated, like the most feature-rich
is actually the
because uh HTML mode that take me the
most time to do.
Because this very feature-rich. Uh
anyway.
So, you were asking about the expansion
feature of Lisp Fly Keys, okay? It's
limited because it can only do in Lisp
code. For example,
put your cursor on a paren or you know,
your cursor can be on anywhere. Press a
key, it will select the current
word, okay?
Or function name. Press again,
it select the current line, and press
again, okay, that doesn't expand. So, if
you want to expand on the parentheses,
you have to put the
um
you have to put on the beginning paren,
so that will you see's that will expand
selection
by the syntactic unit of parenthesis.
You see? Very nice.
But, the limitation is that it's only in
Emacs Lisp. So, for example, let's see.
If I copy this
uh paste it.
Now, this is let's say fundamental mode.
Does it still work? Let's see. Do it. Do
it. Do it. Yes, you see? Still works.
So, it does not matter which mode you
are in.
As long as you have nested parenthesis
and as long as you put your cursor in a
beginning
opening parent
then you press a key
which is called C-x extend selection.
That's the command name. Then it will
add it will like expand the selection
to the syntactic unit of parenthesis.
Okay?
And you don't have to be in Lisp mode.
You can be anywhere.
So, that answered your question on this
is part of the C-x fly keys. Okay?
So, um
Do you have something like expand
region? Okay, so anyway.
So, in if you have parent that works,
but if you are in
dealing with Python code or C code or
whatever new other language, no.
Uh
Yeah, so I don't have a feature up for
that.
Uh
you know, because um anyway, no
basically no, okay?
I think you could improve that feature
then as a video as a video um
Well, um
I'm not sure I'm going to work on that.
Uh so, if you you know, if you code it
well
and you can make a uh push uh they call
on GitHub, so you can
you know, if you want to, you can help
me uh then we can
I might commit your code, okay?
Uh I think you improve that feature as a
video. Well,
Now, that's you see this extend feature
is uh fairly complex, okay? Because if I
do it live,
yeah, some of you says it's interesting,
but actually I don't think so because
it's very technical. So, let me show you
the command, okay? So, describe key,
press I, so you can see the the command
is sa-extend-selection, okay? Now, jump
to the source code.
So, here is a source code. So, press a
key, copy it, new buffer, paste it,
okay? So, this function is 124 lines.
You can see 20 124 lines of code.
Now, let's make it Emacs Lisp mode, so
press press
uh press press press press, okay? That's
now in sa-emacs-lisp-mode,
okay? Now, syn- syntax colored.
So, this function, what it does is you
see you have to know, you know, whether
um you are already in a selection. So,
it is like First first of all, you check
if you are you already have a selection.
If so, then you try to expand the
selection, okay? So, you see that's what
this code does.
Now, if you don't have a selection, so
then if you don't have a selection, then
then this is what you do. If you don't
have a selection, meaning that you are
calling this command for the first time,
then
this is what you do, okay? So,
that, okay? It is kind of complicated
code.
But, if you already have a selection,
then this then this is what you do,
okay? So, then then this
So, you you you guys are saying that um
you know, it would be interesting to
watch. You're not really, because it
It is it's like you cannot take 30
minutes just to explain what you
actually wanted to do, because then in
Python, in in C or C++,
for example, or Golang in in JavaScript,
you you really like the the
there's lots of things to explain, and
people don't understand. People don't
like it, you know, people like people
like quickly sh- drama. That's what
people like. If you actually go into
detail, people don't understand. Nobody
watches.
Okay, we digress so much um
so much.
Now, I want to explain back to So, back
to this, okay? Back to this keyboard.
Um
I wanted to Let me show you, okay? So,
So, press a key to select to extract the
URL. Now, open the Oh,
open new lines. Paste it, you can see I
extracted the URL. So, now I call a
command called Tsar
uh
icon linkify, okay? That's the command.
So, do it.
So, you see, those two lines becomes
this, okay? Undo.
So, you see, I begin with two lines. One
of the line is a file path.
The other line is a image file path.
Open uh let's see.
Open that. You can see it's a image file
path. Close it, okay? Now, I call the
command Tsar HTML icon linkify. Do it.
You see, it became
it became
kind of linkified, okay? Now, show in
browser. Now, refresh, you see you see
we get repeated, you see we just added
that.
Can you see?
Now, notice
notice this image link, there's no
height and width.
Uh because I few years ago because
Okay, let's delete it, okay? Because if
if you add height and width to all the
image
then the page become more cumbersome,
you know, it becomes like lots of height
and
height and width width and height width
and height for all these um
image tags. So, I find it
confusing. So, I actually
changed my command so it doesn't add
width and height.
So, anyway, so the width and height and
many of them are actually in part a part
of the uh file name. You can see.
Uh it's actually uh part of the file
name.
Okay, I don't know where am I going. So,
this is getting uh I need to code
this um
Jesus.
>> [laughter]
>> Now, I'm I think I'm half I'm 30% drunk.
I need to do this, okay? I need
So, let me
So, let's go back, okay? So, let's let's
do it, okay?
So, this page, right? I want to add
width and height. So, let's um
describe function uh what is a function
we just called? So, describe um
this uh view lossage. So, view lossage
command lets you
shows what keys you just pressed
in the in the last minute or so.
And what's their name, the function
actually you called. So, let's go back.
So,
So, we can see what's a what's a
Oh god, we did a lot.
You see execute extended command HTML
select element and what did we do?
I can't find I write. I can't find link.
Why is it not there? It's not there
because the I can't find link is not a
key.
This view logic lossage only shows keys.
That's another interesting
thing. Okay, so you guys don't know. So,
you see I press this key it calls the
command view lossage and that is a Emacs
jargon. That's kind of a Emacs jargon
view lossage. Like what the does
lossage mean?
That's so that's a
That's not history. Okay, that's not
history. So,
So, what does lossage mean? So, let's
actually I don't actually know the
technical detail, but we can ask AI.
Okay.
What does lossage mean in Emacs? Okay,
that's like
It's like a hacker culture. Okay,
lossage. In Emacs lossage lossage refers
to the record of your recent keystrokes
and the commands they invoked. It's an
old school Emacs term from loss as in
what did I just loss break loose break
for the input history purpose. So,
magnify magnify magnify magnify magnify.
Okay.
So, that's what lossage is. So, a little
bit like hacker history.
Anyway.
So, close that. Uh
uh so, the command
describe function
uh xah icon linkify. So, there is a
function xah icon linkify. Let's jump to
the source code. We want to do this,
okay?
So, here's the source code. We want to
make it add the width and height of
images, okay?
Uh God, I'm 30% drink drunk, and I
can't do this.
Damn sick
Damn sick try. Thank you. Thank you,
damn sick try.
You could be interesting to watch. Thank
you. So, do you have a question?
Uh
Fantastic. Fantastic. Okay, so So, what
are we doing? So, what um
God, I'm 30% drink drunk. You know,
actually, so drinking is actually not
very good.
When you When you drink, you cannot
code.
Uh
So, what are we doing? So, what do I
want really want to do?
Well, originally, what I want to
what I want to do is for my all all my
website, like 3,000 um
about 20,000 uh well, actually, about
12,000 web HTML pages
for all occurrences of the image tag
that does not have width and height, I
want to add them, okay? That is
what I wanted to do for this video.
I can do it, but we didn't
begin it. So, now it's 40 minutes
uh and uh
So, anyway, so you see 12,000 for 12,000
HTML pages
for each occurrence of the image tag in
them where there is no width and height,
basically where you got the alt
thumbnail, okay?
You want to add an uh width and height
like attribute. Okay, that's what I want
to do.
And the way to do that is in Emacs. So,
um but
but now
I have to figure out what do I going to
do now. So,
because now I'm like incapacitated by
the red wine.
>> [gasps]
>> So, again, anyway, here is the key
command. Okay, there are many ways to do
this.
One way is just to fix it. So, you do
basically grep.
So, you search for all HTML files. You
find any image tag. Okay, whose
uh
whose alt value is thumbnail.
Then you check if it got width and
height.
So, typically, usually if it the if the
alt value is thumbnail, it will not have
width and height because I removed it.
Which is a mistake a few years ago,
okay? Because I want to I want my HTML
source code to be simplified, you know,
not not with width and height.
Uh but it turns out that that width and
height is very important, okay? I
haven't explained why. Um
Jesus.
The the reason width and height is
important is that
when you load this on a website HTTP,
you know,
if you don't have the width and height
information, the browser is going to
load each image, then
realize what is the width and height,
then it will like
re-render your HTML. So, basically, to
the user, the effect is that when you
load a page, when you go to a website,
you'll see the text like jump around.
You'll see like after a second, you'll
like move.
That's That's not a good experience,
okay? You don't want that.
That is called
uh that is called cumu- cumulative
layout shift, okay?
That's a jargon from from the web dev,
okay? So, if you do web dev, you'll know
this, okay?
So, how do you know you got this
situation? Well, you can know by
Okay, go to uh
a browser, then control shift I to
launch to open the
console, the dev console. Very
complicated today. Then you need to go
to the networking tab, okay? Here,
networking tab.
Then you reload the page, okay? So, you
can see So, let's F5 to reload, so you
go back to the
uh browser dev.
So, you can see
So, this this is very complicated, okay?
You know, web dev today is fairly
complicated. So, you can see it loads,
it shows you the network tab.
So, you see
uh
s-
uh 975
kilobytes.
That is the size of this page including
all the images you see
including all the images for the
keyboards. So altogether it's close to 1
megabyte.
But then it says zero byte transferred.
That's because cash. Because right now
I'm accessing this website via locally
via my you know it's local.
So it's using cash. So if you reload
it's instantaneous. You don't see you
know you don't see the layout shift.
But if you
are on a slow network if you actually
visit my
my website http then you you
for the first time you will you will see
the layout shift. Okay. So that's that's
some of the complications of web dev.
So you use this web dev tools so you can
find out. So let's see.
So you go down. So
where do I see if I have cumulative
layout shift?
>> [sighs]
>> God.
Is it performance
cumulative layout shift? Is it
performance? Jesus.
Storage accessibility.
Jesus.
Okay.
Okay. Drinking is a mistake
because now I'm like 30% drunk.
I can't really
>> [laughter]
[snorts]
>> can't really do any code properly.
But
is my explanation clear?
But why add width height to the image
tag? So
is my explanation I think I just
explained that.
It's you see again this issue is is
called cumulative shift layout shift,
okay?
I cannot demonstrate it. Well, actually
I can. So, if you for example
So, that's my local file path, okay?
Copy it, paste it. Now make it HTTP, so
press press press press
it became a
fully qualified URL.
You see?
By this command start site.
Okay? So, now if you go to that page, I
can press a key or just go to a browser.
So, now I'm going to press a key
Emacs will go to the browser and launch
that URL.
And if you observe quickly, I don't know
if you can see it via the live stream,
but
in the next minute observe quickly,
okay? Carefully. You will you will kind
of see layout shift in half a second,
okay? Because my images you know, all
these image
uh
thumbnails are pretty small. So, they
load very fast. So, even the entire
you know, the thumbnail all of them all
of them together is just 1 MB.
So, 1 MB will network, you know,
download within a second.
So, you won't see you know, it will be
very very brief.
So, you will you will see within half a
second there's a some kind of shift
going on, okay? Now watch, okay? I'm
going to press the key it will go to the
browser.
It will load this
um
Actually, you won't see it because
because
you won't see it until you know, until
on the second screen fold.
Only here you will see the layout shift.
You won't see it at the top. So,
so if I show it, you will see then I
need to quickly
page down first. Okay, let's try.
Okay.
So, I need to
open this URL and quickly do a page
down. Then maybe you will see
a layout shift in half a second. Okay,
let's do it.
Do it.
Uh what?
Wait.
What?
Wait, what happened?
Okay, let's try again.
Do it. What?
Uh oh, okay, wait. Now, that doesn't
work because actually I my my program
actually just look at the file.
Just
the command I'm trying to call
we will just open a file locally in
Emacs when the file when the URL is
actually
my own website. So, we will just go to
the browser and do it, okay? So, open a
new tab, paste the link. Now, I'm going
to press enter, okay? I'm going to press
enter.
Then I'm going to press space to page
down. So, you can so hopefully you can
see the
layout shift, okay?
Enter and
and space down. Okay, you cannot see it.
You see?
You know, it's too fast. So, you cannot
see the layout shift, but it happens.
You Sometimes you I can see it on the
phone, you know, when especially um
Okay, so anyway,
that's called uh cumulative layout
shift, okay? You can ask AI today
uh to explain. So, you know, for
example, let's try.
It's always fun to ask AI.
Jesus, taking longer than usual.
quirk. On the phone, it responds right
away.
But, when you are on desktop, the quirk
is taking forever.
Uh,
Jesus, connecting.
Can you explain cumulative layout shift?
>> Sure. Cumulative layout shift, or CLS,
measures how much a web page
unexpectedly jumps around while it's
loading. It's part of Google's Core Web
Vitals and a key metric for user
experience. A high CLS score, say above
0.1, frustrates users because things
shift under their fingers while they're
trying to read or tap. Low CLS, under
0.05,
means the page feels stable. Common
causes are images without dimensions,
ads, or fonts that load late. You fix it
by setting
>> Okay, thank you. What's your name?
>> [clears throat]
>> What's your name? Tell me what's your
name.
>> My name's Aura.
>> You are lovely. I love you.
>> Oh, that's so sweet. You're making me
blush. I love chatting with you, too.
What can I help you with today?
>> [laughter]
>> AI is fantastic, amazing.
So, that's a layout shift, okay?
Uh, I love AI. So,
and by the way, there is, uh, you know,
Annie is not available on desktop, but
only on the phone and only on iPhone.
Anyway,
um
Okay, what we Okay, so you see
So you see that's a layout shift,
cumulative layout shift. Actually, you
can show it in browser
by
uh somewhere they will show uh
performance. Okay, here.
So you see, but
Firefox profiler is now integrated into
developer tools.
Uh what?
Learn more about this powerful new
feature.
Anyway, so you you can see uh one of
these they will show they will tell you
about whether you have this cumulative
layout shift, CLS.
It will say.
But you need to, you know, it's getting
complicated because this this this um
web dev is really getting fairly
complicated.
So it's loading because I don't have
JavaScript on. You need to turn
JavaScript on, okay?
So Jesus, look at this complicated
User guide, capture a performance
profile, analyze it, share it, make the
web faster. You see? So you see, if you
use this tool
I believe it's actually um
it's not local. It It's actually, you
know, using the Firefox servers.
So I don't want to do that. I don't like
that.
I want things local. I don't like to
like connect to a to a server like phone
home.
Um anyway, but I've tried it before.
It'll It'll It'll tell you about if you
have
if you have cumulative layout shift. In
fact, you can ask AI how to do how to
get that information. I did before.
So, anyway, that's the issue. That's why
that is the you know, that's why we
wanted to I wanted to
Oh god, I'm Are we going anywhere? So,
do you guys understand? At least you
guys understand me. What's What is this
example like? He's
How's it?
What's What are we doing? So,
Yeah, I can linkify. That's a command
now, but I want to go to Okay, you don't
even have a web page. So,
So, let's go to let's open that
keyboard. So, you see that's a
So, you need a width and height, okay?
So, how do you get that? Let me show
you, okay? For example, let's I just
extract the link and paste it, okay? So,
you can close that. Okay, wait.
Close that. Let's go to the top, okay?
So, there are two two pieces split.
There, okay?
Now, go back here. So, the first one,
press a key to extract the URL.
Then,
paste it. So, you can see there is the
article
URL file path. There's a
image
file path. Okay, close it, okay? Now,
delete the article. So, the image file
path, now if you press a key,
press
You see it became a figure
image. Then, you can see there is width
and there's height. Open it. Can you
see? So, if you now show in browser,
you can see we just added um
Oh, we we we we went here, but anyway.
So, you see, we just added this image.
So, you can clearly see there is width
and height.
Now, okay, now delete that. Now,
extract the URL again.
Extract the file
path. Paste it here. Now, if I call
icon link a file,
do it. Now, you see there's no width and
height. Why is that? Because I
intentionally removed removed it few
years ago.
Because I don't want it
I don't want the source code to be cur-
cluttered, you know, with lots of width
and height.
And that's a mistake.
Because there's no way I,
you know, I I learned there's no way for
the
there's no way in CSS to make them
not have this cumulative shift.
Provided that if
you want each thumbnail to have
different height height.
Okay, that's the key.
Now, if you do not care
for each thumbnail to have different
height,
so, in other words, you want all of them
to be the same width and height,
then
you don't need the width and height
attribute.
You don't need it.
But, if you do want each
icon to have
variable
height,
especially height, for example, in this
case, for
you know, I can show you some other
example and you'll see.
You see, some some some thumbnails are
more rectangular, some more square. So,
they actually need different height.
Okay, for example, you see,
this this this scam
this one is actually a scam, you see?
So, you see some of them require
in in in short,
you want them to have different height
depending on the thumbnail, okay?
So, if you do want different icon to
have different height, then
then you want the width and height
attribute because there's no way
the the the CS cascading style sheet,
there's no um system to know
to do that.
Okay, if you don't if if all the height
if you don't care, if you want all of
them to have the same height, then you
don't need that, okay? So, anyway,
that's what I found out. So, therefore,
therefore, I need to retro uh
fit, you know, I need to process my
13,000 or 12,000 HTML files to add the
width and height to all these.
Okay, and how do you do that? There are
several ways, okay? The first way is
that um
that um uh
>> [laughter]
>> I think I'm
you know, I'm making all these
explanations which are in progress,
which are solid.
But, it's going to take forever for me
to um
do anything. So, you see? So, how do you
fix it?
You want to process about 12,000 HTML
files. So, for each one, check if
there's a image tag,
and check if there's width uh alt, you
know, if there's no width and height.
If that's the case, add it, okay?
So, so how do you do? There are many
ways, okay? One way is you just
use eMagLibs. This Okay, you open the
file like right now, open the file.
Search for the image tag, okay, found
it. Then you um
you search the tag if it contain width
and height, okay? If it doesn't, you
want to add them. How do you do that?
Well,
then there are several ways. One way is
you simply delete this
Okay, so you search for the image tag
that does not have width and height, but
just by find just by, you know, text
search, okay? If you found it,
you extract the URL. Let me show you,
okay? So, extract the URL, you know,
just grab for the inside the H so H the
source, okay? So, you got the URL there.
Then, I mean, the source um path.
Then you just do a image you call the
command to do the image. So, let's do
it, okay? So, let's go and
um
Xah image
uh wait.
There, okay, Xah HTML image link. You
call that command so that it come uh
that's incorrect, okay? So, actually
What is the command?
Mm,
Xah image link.
There, okay, so I think that's the one.
Tab e h
No.
Uh
>> image to image image to image tag.
I think that's the one.
Yeah, okay. So,
and do so, let me show you again. So,
you got the image file path,
then you press tab e i, that will turn
that into a image tag with
width and height. You see?
So, what one way you can fix this by
search for image tag that does not have
width and height, then
then delete it.
I mean, well, extract it. Extract the
file path, then delete it. Then you just
call uh that command.
Okay, that's one way to do it.
The other way to do it is that
Let's undo and do, okay? The other way
to do that is once you found it,
you
you find out what is the width and
height of the image tag, then you go to
after the old and then you just insert
it. Okay?
Anyway,
do I make sense? Like I I can't code, so
um
So, I'm going to I think I'm going to
code it offline. Or should I push on?
God, this is
Um but do you guys understand what I'm
saying? Okay.
No more why.
So, I'm going to I think I'm going to
take a nap or something.
If you zoom out and max the site max max
the browser, okay? Let's try it, okay?
Oh, yeah, that makes sense. So, so, we
first of all, we need to go to So, let's
try, okay? solid.info.
Let's go to a um
ksadi.info. Let's go to keyboard.
Okay, then you go to
I'll go. Let's see. No, let's do it as
You see, okay, that doesn't show the
cumulative layout shift. Let's click
normal.
Watch. Click.
No, okay. Then click laptop. Yeah, it's
too fast. Okay, click keypads.
Click. No, not here.
Uh click fun.
Okay, a little bit. You see.
So, anyway, my You see
So, this is not a really a big issue for
my Okay, there's a little bit image, you
know, like here because there are so
many uh icons. But, they are like very
small file size, so that's So, for my
side, it's pretty good. It's You know, I
don't have this problem.
But, it's nice to
add back the
uh width and height.
But,
I don't think I can do it now. But,
well, I can actually, but I'm like half
drunk.
30%.
Uh
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> What am I doing here? So, what is this?
So, that is that.
Okay, but do you guys see? Yeah, I guess
you guys see what I'm doing. So, I think
that's it for today.
Okay, I already explained two ways to go
about. Okay, so you open a file for for
12,000 HTML files. You open each one,
then you search for image tag without
width and height. Then, there are two
ways to fix it. Either you extract the
URL, then delete the whole tag, and
paste the URL, then call a command to
which I have written to
to to create a new image tag with the
width and height. Or, you just go to the
bottom and add width and height. Okay,
that's two ways, two
different approach. There's more.
Another approach is you first of all,
you just go through the directory, okay?
You find First of all, you do is that
you find all image files
and find their width and height and
create a hash table, a database.
So, you can use You can use Emacs Lisp
to do that, or you can use F# to do
that. I've been thinking of doing using
F# because I'm using I'm learning F#.
So, this way you can learn F#. So, I can
also ask AI how to do it. So,
in a directory, go through all image
files, PNG or JPEG files, or other There
are There are some Apple
format files. But, it's basically you
want to go through all image files,
okay? They are They are not just PNG and
JPEG. There's more.
Um So, you want to go through all of
them,
build a hash table of their width and
height
given a file path. So, given a file
path, you know the width and height hash
table, okay?
You can do this in Emacs Lisp, and you
can do it in F#.
Then, uh
in either language, then you go Then,
you open all HTML files. Then, you
search for the um
image,
you know, without width and height.
Then, you query the um
hash table to find the width and height.
Then, you insert them, okay? And this
you can do in F#, or you can do in Emacs
Lisp.
I can do the whole thing in Emacs Lisp
in in 30 minutes, okay? In 30 minutes,
which was what I'm going to do,
but
>> [laughter]
>> but I up. I can't do it now.
But in F# it's going to take few hours
because then I'm learning F#. Okay.
I think that's it for today. Bye, guys.
Uh,
>> [sighs]
>> God, what am I even doing? Okay, so what
is this?
I got link a file. Okay, one of the
thing I need to do is actually
Huh.
Hello, sister Tom. I don't remember who
you are.
>> [sighs]
>> Actually, so there is a width and
height. I removed it a few years ago,
actually.
So, silly me.
Uh,
okay.
Okay.
ACP, hello ACP. Okay, bye.
Yeah, bye, guys. I think that's it for
today.
Uh.
>> [sighs]
Didn't actually code any Lisp.
Just like explained the
Okay.
That's it.
>> Mhm.