welcome to another episode of Star Talk
Show today is 2021 April
April 20th
and today we are going to continue our
journey yesterday doing emacs lisp we
are going to look at the source code of
Helm mod and see how it uh
implements First Imagine okay
so that is what we are going to do so
it's going to be very technical uh it's
all about emac this code it's probably
going to be boring
unless you want to if you are already a
emac this programmer and also if you
want to see kind of actual real life
workflow
uh you know coding emac Beast
so otherwise it's probably going to be
boring for you so I'm going I'm going to
go pretty fast uh and uh if you have
questions about emacs related to what
I'm doing uh just post in the comments
okay so on the on the left window the
pink window is uh my oh my emacs
commands I call such as moving closer
down up or by paragraph and so on
or delete delete or undo undo and you
can also see the keystrokes and I'm
using some fly keys and I'm using a
vorac keyboard okay let me begin then
okay video good audio good check
so let's begin let's begin to code this
okay so last time uh what's going on
okay hold on a second
so show uh this is today's uh yeah talk
show so
uh let me show you so last time we did
uh so there's two episodes you know uh
yesterday and the day before so we wrote
this function select choices it when you
call it it has a bunch of predefined
sentences these are academic phrases
potentially there are thousands of them
so here is just a short example so when
you call this command you can type uh
you know show a few characters then you
will narrow down you know the the
sentence you want uh speed up writing
academic papers so here is a one simple
implementation uh very simple
just uh 10 lines
so you can see so if we call it so I'm
gonna evaluate it call it select choices
enter Then you can see I have several
choices so I if I type uh
for example if I type e let's say e e o
e e o
okay so there's a lot of sentences that
matches these
so I'm looking at this one e e o e let's
type another E okay and let's type P so
it Narrows down
uh so this so narrow down so I press
enter and it inserts that sentence now
this first Imaging is based on I do so I
do completing read which is a character
based fuzzy imagine that is whatever you
type it's considered a sequence of
characters now in order okay older
sequence of characters and if any of
these candidate sentences
contains that sequence of characters in
order then that's a potential candidate
so this is Idol's Version of First
Imagine but however uh Helm is using a
different way it's a word based uh first
Imaging and order does not matter for
example we can call
Helm MX okay call Helm MX enter
so we you know we got a bunch of uh
uh candidates for emacs commands and as
you know you know we Define so one of
our Command is Select choices we just
defined so we can type
for example if we type
s
C okay the first character of each word
SC
then you don't see you know then it
eliminates this candidate because
Helms first Imaging is based on words so
this command name does not contain the
word s c so that doesn't work okay so
but it's word based okay but so try it
again how meta X so if we type
uh if we type
choices you see now we have we actually
got what we want now we type choices
then we type space then we type select
SEL
again so so you see uh
enter
so now it calls our Command now I can
you know I can now I can make a choice
type to make a choice so so Helms
firstly matching is word based and and
order does not matter now our job today
is to continue to look at the helm
source code to see how it is done and so
that at the end we we want to modify our
code to use Helms first Imaging system
if we are successful
okay so here so we we start from where
we left off yesterday uh
so we trace the core stack you know we
trace the function Helm MX you know we
look at the source code uh and Helm MX
turns out course Helm MX read extended
command to do the job then that in turn
calls Helm to do the job uh it's called
like that
and that in turn cause Helm internal to
do the job
and the helm internal has this syntax
okay then
then at that point it seems to you know
it cause Helm read for mini buffer
but
from what I know uh you know since we
looked at yesterday it also sets up a
bunch of variables or uh yeah variables
that
that contains information about what's
the current state like what like what
what is the current uh string user has
typed and what is the current
um
pattern and current uh
choices narrow down choices I think
that's how it works so I don't know yet
so that's how that's where we were
yesterday
okay so we I'm going to continue okay so
this is mostly just me working on this
um it's gonna I I suspect it's going to
be long for an hour or more
uh tedious job okay so I mean yeah we
are looking at the emac source code to
yeah so okay so so first of all okay
let's describe function Helm for mini
buffer let's go to the
uh the source code okay now
now let's look at the Helms package
structure okay so you see
so Helm has a package called a directory
called helmco and it contains let's see
basically we can ignore the first two
because those are Auto created package
info so the main code is one two three
four four
um
files and the primary primary one is the
helm.el so we open helm.el and that is
7 000 lines of code
and we yesterday we looked at all the
functions in it so we call describe
matching I mean these matching lines
type defund
and you see it returns 290 functions
and we looked at this so we have uh we
yesterday we got the idea of what are
these functions are this is a Helm core
okay
uh helmco and part of it
let's see where part of it contains the
first Imaging
I mean we determined part of it I mean
many of these functions are related to
uh first imagine so you see starting
here so firstly Helm firstly matching
maybe something helpful image help fuzzy
search Helms score candidate for pattern
and so on they are like 15 or 10 or 15.
functions related to matching string
so anyway let I'm giving you I'm I'm
trying to uh you know
two cons two two two to know the
structure of Helm uh at this moment so
you have Helm core directory but
actually
there's more so we go up one directory
we go up one directory you can see Helm
that's the okay so that's the helm code
wait
yeah so helmco is this one so in fact
there is another directory just named
helm
so Helm the package Helm apparently you
know contains two directories one is
helmcor which I suppose is the the heart
of the engine Helm uh you know firstly
matching engine
then you have uh the helm directory
which contains let's see you know uh
Helm adaptive Helm Auto load Helm
bookmark help buffers Helm color
Helm commit
uh Helm command Helm config Helm dab a
brief
how easy manual Helm it is
so I suppose so so these are commands
uh for various for example if you want
to open a file or if you want to open a
you know call him to if you want to call
external command or if you are in emac
based shell you want to call some
English shell functions
or if you are you know and some of them
create menus so these are a bunch of
commands and uh
that
that user actually call help so I so I
imagine these commands you know content
in these files they ultimately will call
some functioning Helm code to do the
work okay so I haven't looked at this
what are these uh uh so there's also
Helm semantic so what uh hell is Helm
semantic author Danielle Hackney
uh okay I know so these people are
developers of helm
okay so now I'm going to put on my egg
eye patch
because I have a little bit quasi so uh
since I was young so I put a eye patch
I'm wearing two glasses because one is
near-sightedness one is the old age
reading glasses
I need to get better classes
so okay so so back to the structure of
Helm uh two directories okay two
directories one is Helm core and one is
a bunch of Helm commands
uh and utilities and stuff so what is
how semantic just for curiosity let's
see
uh requires semantic okay I don't know
what package is semantic Helm help Helm
I menu
uh you see a documentation no no so I'm
also wondering
um if there is a documentation for
programmers for help you know for people
who wants to you know contribute to him
so you know we are just you know this is
part of process of looking studying you
know the source code
so if I you know it's always a gamble
which direction you go if I spend the
next 10 minutes to look to look search
for the documentation
you know whether if there's one for
programmers then
maybe it's a dead end maybe not
uh so it's you know you don't know
so anyway let's look at how I'm call
okay so so uh yeah so helmco and this is
the main file so what are the others
so here I'm call this is a engine
helm.el then Helm lib I'm not sure what
what's in Helm lib
so it's coded by Theory
uh
Bo piatto
uh Italian or something
okay so there is no
documentation for programmers okay
common commentary or Helm functions that
don't require specific Helm code should
go go here okay so this file helm lib.el
is all harm functions that don't require
specific Helm code
okay it doesn't require specific Helm
code
in helm.el I suppose
okay so let's see declare functions
declare functions and see color declare
functions uh
and Define VA
okay Helm sources Now sources mean just
a list of candidates
how many initial frame Helm current
position helm
uh
right diode marks
okay Helm has um you know Helm is trying
to change the user interface of emacs
which I don't I don't really use
okay so so so okay let's continue uh
let's not get distracted so continue the
source codes so Helm buffer in new frame
Helm completion style Helm completion
style at least a list Associated
persistent action window buffer position
action window buffer
completion flex no space okay so that's
a uh kind of a settings so because
otherwise space functions as a separator
of words in user input I believe
so how big is this uh file
okay
1700 lines okay uh now okay now let's
let's uh search for different so let's
see so there are these matching lines
they are 92 functions defined in this
file
so let's look at them Helm help
you know I actually never used Helm
before
so another option is for me actually to
to kind of read up the helm
documentation for users to see
uh to see if there is kind you know to
to become
to have a solid uh
knowledge about how
how you use Helm in general I I I think
I do know
basically you open a file or you want to
call any command or you want to search
string helm
you know pops up two buffers in a mini
buffer is where you type but Helm
updates another buffer which is the
candidate as you type it narrow Downs
the candidate so I believe this is the
general pattern of using help
so so therefore
the code there must be some code that
update the you know so we are looking at
we are seeing I believe some of these
variables you see for example Helm
sources is continuously updated as user
types that's the list of candidate IBD
and then you have you know Helm buffer
is the interface buffer that contains
the candidates
yeah because I believe so I don't know
for sure yet okay
so
so we have a lot to do you know I can
try to
scan the Helms user documentation just
to get idea you know do that for a few
minutes and also try to look for if
there's a documentation for Helm
programmers
so that would be if there exists
that would be good because then I I can
instead of guessing I can know how Helm
is done the whole structure
okay helmandib
or I mean or we just continue with we uh
where I am you know look at the source
code so let's start let's keep looking
at the source code so helmdib is um
ly is still
part of the helm core
but not the essence of the core I
believe
uh
let's see what is Helm window
Helm window Okay window of Helm buffer
okay yeah so so
yeah so in emacs terminology a window
basically just a split pen exactly so
Helm window is the is the pen that shows
the Helms candidates okay so this
function Helm window get both a window
Helm buffer get okay so it Returns the
helm buffer
and and Helm buffer is you know is the
candidates
list of candidates so Helm action window
window of Helm action buffer okay I
don't know what that is
okay so these are a bunch of
um
helper functions so you also have helped
describe function which is Helms
basically helmets wrapper version of
emacs describe function
let's try it out how that works okay so
let's call
Helm describe function
oh actually so it's not a command it's
not a interactive command it's a
function
only called by Helm you cannot call it
yourself okay
so I think
you know so far I have not turned hell
mod on so the easier command called hell
mod yes
so if I turn it on you know I never
turned it on before not yesterday or the
day before so if I turn it on I presume
what that means is that it it's going to
change all the typical emacs commands
such as describe function or meta X you
know execute extended command
and open file you know find file
it will
automatically create a wrapper or Alias
to those functions so whenever you call
those functions you are because you know
you use helm
s uh function command instead so I
suppose that's what
so before we do you know before we turn
on helmet let's have a look at the
uh dark stream
so how mod is a auto loaded interactive
compile this function okay it's bound to
a menu bar two or something something
okay how much optional so do we have a
menu bar let's see hold on shrink
uh yes we do we have a menu bar help mod
no you have to turn on Helm first okay I
think so anyway it's it's bound to this
this uh hell mod toggle generic Helm
completion right
if code interactively enable Helm mod if
argument is positive yeah uh all
functions in emacs that use that use
completing read
or read file name or completion in
region and friends you know and others
will use Helm interface when this mod is
turned on exactly
however you can modify this behavior for
function of your choice blah blah blah
okay customization
code we okay so should I turn it on
um so wait there's a something about I
do mod
do not enable I do everywhere when using
Helm mod okay instead of using I do mod
add the commands where you want to use I
do to okay
okay so so okay
so how mod if I turn it on then
everything is gonna be held but I can
turn it off I think
uh
let's try to turn it on okay so let's
just see what's going on with help let's
turn on Hell mod so I can get a some
sort of experience user experience and
see how Helm you know
is used okay helmet
now meta X let's see
okay now it's getting complex because
I'm using stuff like Keys which has its
own
um yeah so it's not calling helm
let's call find file okay let's call
actually let's call execute extended
uh command
okay
so this is the meta X okay
do I need to explain that okay because
it's a bit confusing oh actually maybe I
should just um
uh okay so so so so so
you see I'm using some fly keys so when
I press a key which is actually a
uh it's cancel okay cancel let me
explain what's going on so you see I'm
I'm when I press the key a it will call
the command subfly meta X
which
which will then which will then call one
of the version of meta X
you know the default first of all
execute extended mod that's the command
that's a default gunu emacs then you
also have Helm metax that's a Helm
version then you also have
uh smex smex which is another
package smex is a package as a
replacement
for meta X so it contains uh you know
another fuzzy matching way
So currently if I press a it is actually
using smex I like this you know I I like
the smax feature I do actually doesn't
support meta X so when I press a
you know it's actually coding the smex
version
but since I turned on Hell mod I want to
use the Helms Minix so I so actually I
have to call
I don't know if this works execute
extended command okay let's try that
okay it's not using Helms version but
let's try something else okay so let's
try find file okay
meta X find file okay that's a command
to open the file
okay it's not
it's not calling helmet's version
neither
so we know from these
experimentation we know that Helm is not
actually creating an alias to these
emacs commands
so
what is it doing probably it's just
remapping the keystrokes so for example
in emacs in glue emacs to open a file is
Ctrl X control F that wheel that is
mapped let's find bound to find file
so now if I type Ctrl X control F it's
probably bound to helm find file
probably let's try it okay describe key
control X control F
okay actually it's bound to I do find
file so what's um
it's calling Idols version yeah because
I have I do on
uh okay so
now remember Helm documentation say it
said that
um you know you should
turn off
and okay what
uh you should turn off I do
you know it says do not enable I do
everywhere now I don't know if I have
that enabled or not so let's describe
variable to see if there is a variable
the value is new
but however I do have I do mod on
I do have I do mod on so does that
interfere with Helm I don't know maybe
it does not mention it here
however
you know it's it's a there's a
possibility that you know it does
interfere
so so so so so let so let's go to my
settings
and let's this uh this matching lines
let's see if I do have I do
um
everywhere
okay so here this section is my emacs
setting for I do mod so I turn it on
and uh
so should I turn it off
because I want to try the Helms without
interference so let's turn it off okay
it's called I do mod
okay now it's disabled now let's call
helmet to turn Helm on now let's
describe key control X control F
okay so it runs the command find file
which is not which which is uh glue
emacs fine file so let's actually try it
Ctrl X control F
yeah so it's not calling Helms version
so what does how mod mean when it says
you know just use Helms
um
describe function
oh okay so here is where Helm kicks in
when you describe function when you call
the command describe function it it
calls the helmets version okay but how
does it work let's see
so normally the key is
Ctrl H F okay so now let's call describe
key Ctrl H
f
okay so it says runs the command
describe function okay
so let's do that Ctrl H F
okay
There's Something Fishy going on okay
cancel okay so cancel okay so
when you say describe key and you type
CHF
emacs says that key
runs the command describe function
but but however that's not true I mean
you know when you call describe function
let's try it again uh describe function
okay you see
this is not this is a Helm's Behavior
the helm interface this is not a gnomax
behavior so
somehow for you know somehow or
somewhere
describe function you know that command
is actually calling Helms version
uh and uh and so I don't know how that
is done possibly by your advice
you know so in emacs there's this thing
called advice where it lets you change
behavior of a functional command
it you know it's a kind of it's a little
bit more complex way of changing things
which I don't like I never use
you know advice Define advice because it
confused things because right now we are
running into this issue the very issue
you know because when I say describe key
control h
k
then I type Ctrl H F
then emacs tell me tells me Ctrl HF runs
the command describe function but
actually it's not because I press Ctrl H
F this is not the behavior of describe
function this is the behavior of Helms
version
okay let's do one more trick okay Ctrl H
L
it will tell me all the commands I typed
in the past
so you see clearly I am coding describe
function
but however somehow
by what mechanism I do not know
overrides it
yeah this is the reason I don't like
this
you know I don't like this complex I
don't know how it's done I don't know
you know I don't
I don't you know it's not
done by a simple mechanism so what is a
simple mechanism a simple mechanism
to
to do that you know to launch Helms
version of things is two ways one is you
change the key binding so all emacs key
binding that's bound to describe
function is automatically changed
remapped to Helms version you know a
function name Helm describe function
so this way is simple because if user
type you know
CHF see what that is you'll say oh it
calls Helm describe function
but it's not doing that the other way
simple way is to do an alias
so basically you create the areas of
to described function so when when
people call describe function it
actually the documentation will say
actually it's you know coding you know
it's a Alias to help describe function
so this way is also simple because you
can query it you'll see but but right
now it's not doing anywhere you know
it's not doing uh it's not remapping
Keys No is it an alias
and nor is it a advice which is a way to
change your function's behavior
because if it is you will see it in the
documentation but I'm not seeing it so
let's do it again okay
describe key control h f you see so
here's what comes up
uh
uh it does not mention Alias it does not
mention advice
and it does not mention any change of
key binding you know it's you know it's
so um
so unless I'm missing something there's
something some other simple way I don't
understand
you know I don't like
you know I don't like these complex ways
to achieve things
so what what do we do now let's see
describe let's search for
yeah you see it has so let's search for
describe okay in this helm Dash lib
these matching lines describe
so you do have you see Helms version
Helm describe function function help
describe variable function
help describe class Helm describe
function yeah so so you do have so
Define custom
uh okay let's jump to it
help describe function function describe
function okay
Define custom
uh what what is the second argument of
describe function because you see
describe function here so let's describe
function
Define custom okay let's see
symbol in standard okay yeah
okay okay that that doesn't matter okay
so
Define custom so so so Helm describe
function function is actually a variable
whose value should be a function okay
now where is this set
advice function called Help describe
function function help describe function
okay so here is wait uh one
okay so here it is
so you do have a Helm described function
D you know that's a function
you do have that and uh
and then it calls help describe function
function okay uh it's going round about
okay I mean not I don't mean that in a
bad way it's just uh how Helm works
I guess so far I see the source code is
pretty clear
um
just since gossip skyfi good morning
good morning to mathematician are you a
professor or maybe you are a professor
already right
at some University of Vancouver or
something
my eyes okay I talked about this a
million times I have a little bit
cross-eyed that's why I put this patch
on so I easier for me to read the
computer screen
so describe so so so so I'm I'm stuck in
this so anyway this is a side question
about how helm
how Helm wraps around emacs default
functions okay that's a another
different question we are
getting off track
so anyway now back to the helm structure
okay so we are looking at so back to
helm
structure so Helm
so we look at we looked at helm.el we
looked a little bit at Helm Dash lib
let's see how multi-match okay let's
open
author Ruby kitchen
original author okay then
theory for piatto okay
uh so this guy who spent a lot of time
like full time
working on Helm
you know because I read one time I read
a you know announcement on Reddit or
blog you know he's saying that's really
a lot work
and this guy doesn't really do blogs or
video interview I think maybe there's a
few yeah I think there's a few
but he he doesn't
like he's not in public too much
uh so he you know he's saying
which I don't agree because you know
every emacs lisp
coder or user once you use emacs for a
few years you have your own way and you
think it is the best way
so I you know I use stuff like Keys then
there's two me Max the space space emacs
then there's helm
uh you know besides Helm there's also
you know this I do this Helm there's IV
IV of a bunch of things ivy so you then
there's icicles icicles is one of the
oldest you know so each person have
different ideas about which is the best
interface or best way to operate emacs
but I remember I read this guy says you
know he he you know he wants help to be
the you know he likes him he you know
and he mentioned there's a lot work he
mentioned something about you know it's
gonna be five more years
uh something like that until he
find him to be perfect you know then so
there's a lot of work
uh and I don't think he get paid
sufficiently so donate
you know that's probably one of the
problem with open source
I don't know because last time I read
he's like he's gonna stop working on it
because he is too busy with life and the
real you know work where he gets money
but I don't I don't remember if if
that's still the case or he went back to
work on Helm I forgot
so anyway so so okay A bit digression so
at this point I think we should
have a look at Helm's homepage you know
see what um
you know so we get familiar what what
what what it is doing
so here is a Helm home page
Helm let's see uh
yeah I think he's still the primary code
that I'm guessing
uh so we look at the commits
merge pull request multiple request
okay yeah it's almost all he's done by
him so he's stuck
he's stuck working on helm
yeah old uh
yeah he's still very busy working on
Helm you know almost like every day lots
of code
uh yeah looks like he he's almost the
I mean he's the only leader as opposed
to having another guy because all the
comments are basically by him you know
uh managing the project
you know merging pull request things
like that
okay so so today
we already talked for 43 minutes okay
this is gonna be a long one so we're
gonna do two hours maybe two hours
I kind of digressed but anyway I we we I
do need to look at Helm so here's a home
home page
uh
Helm home page documentation
what is the documentation okay these are
PNG files
uh what
yeah PNG files okay
okay now let's go back now let's see
all these Helm files Helm tag Helm type
okay
so
so Helm has this icon this is not a good
icon because it
fails the criteria of being simple
because the hell icon is based on
photograph
they you know
it should simplify into a actual
symbolic icon you'll be so that's my
okay that's my offline suggestion to
help people you need this is not a good
logo
so you can one way to fix that is two
things
simplify symbolic you know make this
Photograph symbolic okay
you know I believe this photo is from
some kind of 3D uh
uh movie I think about robot robots or
so I think I forgot
anyway
so Helm is an emacs framework exactly
framework for incremental completions in
narrowing narrowing instructions it
provides an easy to use API
for developers wishing to build their
own Helm applications in emacs oh okay
so it does have a API now where do I
where can I read the documentation for
that because
that solves our problem
okay so it contains easy to it provides
easy to use API for programmers
and Powerful search Tools in dozens of
already built-in commands providing
completion to almost anything
yeah because the original name of Helm
is anything okay let me give you a bit
history the original name of the helm
package is just called anything.el
and that is inspired by a mac program
called
um
Quicksilver okay okay digression
uh I close my browser by mistake
okay reopen okay new window
so Quicksilver began sometimes in 2004
okay let me open that uh and is there a
Wikipedia Power Mac
um
I want to I want to show you okay here
so you can see yeah this is the one so
Quicksilver began in uh 2003 or
something okay
and that
basically it provides the interface
a Zeo type you know things show up the
things can be application to launch can
be a files that contains whatever you
typed can be your file name or can be
you know like anything you know so it
changes so this becomes this began on
the Mac a third-party software which is
which was fantastic well you know
greatest it led a revolution in user
interface across Mac Linux and windows
so because of quicksilver then someone
in emacs developed anything.el which is
the father of helm okay they because
anything is too confusing they change
the name
so so quick server is a granddaddy and
also
in Linux you started to have you know
Ubuntu started to have their user
interface I I forgot what's it called
and also in Microsoft Windows for
example again I can just uh
uh Power you know I can just type a few
words and it pops up
applications or file names or you know
condensing like or you know you know any
you know
so it revolutionized
revolutionized nice the kind of the user
interface
okay that's a bit history Okay so
uh and uh you know so here's a quick
silver home page okay now back to helm
uh so it says it is a must-have for
anything for anyone using emacs as a
main work environment you know that's
his opinion I don't like I actually do
not like
the
tool to rely on this kind of searching
on the Fly
user interface for all my things I don't
like that actually because I want
precise control for example I want to go
to the task manager I press one key test
manager if I want to go around the bus I
mean the tabs I press one key
okay I want to go to my um
Powershell I press one key tab manager
Powershell or any browser okay
uh you see it's all one key operation
so I don't want to type you know for
example I want to go to Firefox I press
one key uh wait which key this key wait
yeah that that key okay so for example I
mean here I want to go to Five Firefox
one key okay I can show you my keyboard
okay let me show you my keyboard okay
no I have you know okay it's hard to see
but anyway
task manager this uh okay I need to
okay so so this keyboard you are looking
at uh this one is kinesis advantage two
you just search for Sardi Kinesis
Advantage keyboard you will find my
reviews and video reviews I recommend it
this is a linear switch
and this
this is Ultimate hacking keyboard so
task manager
uh Powershell
Firefox
that is a chrome
you know it it disappears because I have
actually two Chrome Windows okay so
anyway Chrome and and Bray browser and
emacs you see one single key press I
don't need to type f i r e you know to
then then I have to look oh is it 5x
then press enter I don't need to do that
okay let's go back to OBS let's
go back to
so this is my a little bit you know
philosophy or style about using the helm
interface you know this this
type to search anything to launch
anything interface I don't want that so
I disagree with the Helms claim
you know this is the must-have
and similarly in emacs I don't want to
just start to type anything to for file
so for you know I have precise
yeah I know exactly what I want I want
to go to my for example a talk show page
one two three three keys t-a-l-k okay
and this is just this is book smart
bookmarks I've made myself I don't want
it to if I start to type talk I don't
want it to to search my whole drive and
pop up all kind of files that contains
the world talk okay everything is
tightly controlled that's what I want
you know uh bookmark or things or
anything and also commands you know
so the helm sway
you know different person have different
preferences I don't like I don't you
know helmsway is not my what I want
so anyway so Helm is pretty good you
know but it's uh you know for a lot you
know it's very useful okay different
people have different
um you know workflow Helm has been
widely adopted by many emacs power users
that's true uh it is available in melpa
and okay okay great documentation this
you know if you are a software developer
especially if you are a nerd a hacker
type very technical you know you dive
into Linux or emac this you want your
document documentation to be like the
helm one very great fantastic
introduction in one paragraph you know
what it what it does exactly okay and
very well written this cannot be said
for for vast majority of emacs uh
packages usually they are very nerdy
like you read it you have no idea what
they're talking about they don't give
you the context or things like that the
helm ones is excellent
documentation okay home page download
get started this is also fantastic you
know you can you know home page okay
home page download get started Helm Wiki
FAQ so we need to read a few
let's open home page and also this
picture is fantastic you know it gives
people immediately an idea what this
Helm is doing the interface you know
why almost emacs project packages they
are like you don't know what they are
what exactly what they are but they have
full of jargons you know to impress
other hackers okay let's be a typical
typically the case
anyway we we I have digressed so much uh
I need to actually get back to the main
point about
finding out how the First Dimension
Works in hell but
okay but but we need we do need to look
at the documentation so this is part of
the process of coding
uh and you know since I'm doing live
talk show I might as well tell you
something interesting
uh good morning people and greetings
from Cheer chili Daniel garrido I think
I we talked before right
uh join Discord guys if you guys haven't
Okay saw this excited scored
uh join there and we
can um you know so I can know you you
can you know we can have fun chatting
okay okay back to
Helm okay let's let's go back to focus
on help
so you have home page open a home page
okay home page you have get started then
you have Helm Wiki open Helm FAQ that's
I want to read them all
okay
this
so what is a home page so what am I
fireworks home page okay
okay table accountants
intro features Alternatives requirements
getting started okay Helm applications
uh recommended recommended Helm
extensions okay intro
okay okay Helm is a fork of anything.el
oh it's a fork which was originally
written by
Thomas Petrovic okay
uh
yeah features okay Alternatives okay
[Laughter]
this is a
not historically historically true it
says there are several alternatives to
help nowadays
they are all providing incremental
completion but they lack all the helm
features due to due to their wrong
implementation abusing meaning
quite a damaging remark and dramatic
this is incorrect
you know it says they are there are
several alternatives to him nowaday
implying that Helm is the first no
before Helm existed there are quite a
few there are three or four
uh
before help even before anything okay
before anything so Helm is derived from
anything that year before anything there
is already I do there's already uh not
just I do there's quite a few I have an
article on that
uh
okay search for
yeah so there is I do there is I
complete there was there is they are
still any emacs okay there's also I
switch these are all before far before
Helm ever existed if
10 years before Helm existed
so this statement by Helm is
you know it's it's a bit you know
marketing which is all right everyone
does that you know I don't have a
complaint but this is incorrect there
are several alternative to help nowadays
no there are several
you know existed before help
and then it claims they are all
providing something something abusing
mini buffer
what what a remark no you you Helm is
going way over engineered you know I
don't like him
Helm is you know one of the actual
common complaint about Helm is it's slow
noticeably you know if I call M smex
okay smex smex actually came before him
I think
you know helmets by now like you know
depending on whether you count anything
that El which is its father
you know if you count anything dot ER
then Helm is like uh
uh 15 years old something like that okay
but
but there okay maybe smacks come after
help after anything that yeah okay so
anyway anyway
so back to reading the helm
documentation you know I making some
criticisms of my own
uh dramatic dramatic remarks of my own
just as he is doing it there
marketing statements uh requirements
okay getting started uh in store from
straight okay straight is another you
know newish thing
uh not sanctioned by ignou emacs by the
way I want to mention that
because they are good anyway I'm I'm
starting to digress into kind of a rant
let's go back to focus focusing on the
code
okay so so yeah so install just the
helmcorp package okay helmcor which we
uh studied warning about alternative
warning about alternate install methods
configuration
um
basic usage okay basic basic usage helm
MX okay
and important in any Helm session as
soon as there is candidates in the helm
buffer
chm pops an org buffer which detailed
with detailed documentation about
current command okay that's a useful
feature
by the way a Max also does that smex not
a mix smex
but the key is CHF which is more
standard with glue emacs
okay so uh use it with no moderation use
this embedded info screens first before
reporting bugs okay
so helmet to enable Helm completion 2
for for E for common emacs commands note
that the helm functionality enabled
through how mod comes from generic
implementation and does not include all
Helm features available through
equivalent Helm specific commands Okay
so that's uh you know that's uh issue
that's a kind of a
implementation issue or emacs structural
issue
because one would likely ideally one
would like to turn on this mod then you
just have everything
you know work using the helm interface
but due to the way emac
this is or emac structure you don't have
that
you know you if you turn on Hell mod it
just gives you kind of
some of that
feature if you want a fully integrated
Helm experience you need to You Know
download the helm specific
mods like that's why you see you know if
you look at the packages there's a lot
of tons of Helm packages
okay hell mod okay so so Advanced usage
okay Helm contains many features some of
which are easier to follow visually
here's a demo of Helm buffer list
okay which uses
helmutai occur I guess demon will start
with okay
okay I'm not sure where are we and where
am I going with this
okay those questions you know you watch
my
you you know in many of my videos
I talked about those issues about things
like why is emacs not popular why is the
emac this is not popular I talked
so many times about that
uh in the past you know uh watch in the
past few months you know you can begin
there
so
so here okay important matching methods
help support by default multi-patter
matching okay it is the standard way of
matching in helm
multi-pattern matching okay for example
you can use patterns like full bar to
match your line containing four and bar
or bar in Foo each pattern can be a
regular expression okay in addition Helm
supports First Imagine okay
okay I need to look at what exactly how
it defines how you know Helms fuzzing
First Imagine uh capabilities
Helms you know this is what we want to
do uh Helms building firstly Macho is
activated for some commands Helms First
Imagine is disabled by default okay
disabled by default currently these
commands support fuzzy matching okay now
I get it
so
by default if you do not do any
configuration then if you call Helm MX
it is actually not using First Imagine
okay
but rather I'm not sure there's a term
it's using a kind of matching where it's
word based and order does not matter
okay but but Helm does support firstly
matching which is kind of more I guess
complex
but you have to turn them on so you have
you can turn them on for recent app for
mini for buffer list for fine files for
locale for you know mid hacks for
semantic yeah so
okay
Okay so
so on this page first imagine it does
not explain
exactly what is the definition of first
imagining
used by hell
rather it just gives you gives you a
list of help functions that does you
know this kind of match it doesn't
actually explain
or specify exactly what is the first
imagine
Helm is using
you know but that is what
I want to know I I'm interested that's
what I want to know
you know I want to
you know I don't think there is a
specific definition for First Imagine
but rather
it's just some kind of matching you know
different programs defined you have
different ideas of first imagine that I
don't think there's one universal
definition of First Imagine
okay
okay but still it's good to know so
the default way
how matches when you when you call Helm
MX is
uh word matching orderless World
matching let's just say let's put it
that way odorless
matching by words
okay
and which is what I want you know I want
to try I want that
so okay so that that gives us a clue in
source code so ins you know we remember
we saw a lot of functions
so these matching lines you know
uh
wait what is this
so Helm leads the file Helm lib
open it
called this matching lines different
then search for
search for match okay only three
occurrences
search for
okay it's not in this file so go back to
the directory open the helm.el now this
matching line is different then search
for f u z z y so you can see
so this uh you know you have six or
seven functions that the first first
imagine so these are the these functions
implement the first imagine but however
for my purposes I do not need to look at
them because
because I am interested first you know
at at first I'm only interested in the
world
orderless word matching not first
imagine okay now that
reading the documentation clarify that
part
okay
so creating custom Helm sources okay
sources
in Helm means like list of candidates so
it may be commands or file names or
whatever
so you can create custom Helm sources
okay
yeah okay
so Helm applications okay now it costs
okay now it now they help you know this
is another marketing term applications
which is basically your list of
different Helm commands that does you
know that uses Helm interface they are
not exactly
well they are not apps but they are well
they are applications you know that that
where Helm is useful
so these are popular applications
developed using Helm completion and
narrow narrowing framework they are
available for individual installs
through the emacs package manager this
list is not exhaustive okay
so are they saying this up not part of
the helm package
so let's say help find files okay one
command that handles all the files
related command Okay so that no wonder
so let's see if that is building so
describe function
paste help find files enter it's not
there
oh okay so okay that's another thing I
learned
when you install the helm package it
does not actually contains a
you know find file
okay that's interesting I thought that's
so fundamental it's part of it
wait wait wait why does it not what
about this buffer list
right so
uh
oh so pounds Buffer's list is there
but Helm fine files is not that's that's
wait
control
h f
Helm
find
oh God this is slow
yeah
God I have like a half a second delay
what's what's going on helm f-i-n
yeah this is you know this is why this
is a practical issue with help
great interface but slow
so you have helped find but you don't
have him fight find fire
so what is Helm fine Helm find is a uh
okay it's bound to something something
uh recursively find files whose name are
matched by all specified grabbing
patterns you know
you know it's slow because it's probably
I don't know where is it looking at my
files I hope it's not my whole disk
that's you know that's that's you know
that's why
I don't want this anything thing
uh
okay so anyway these are commands that
use this Helm interface
some of them are building I guess
some of them
you know are external packages you have
to install
so then you have extensions recommended
Helm extensions normally all hell
modules coming from emacs Helm
organization
are safe to use otherwise it is
mentioned in there read me if they are
broken or earned unmented and maintained
here some of them I'm using okay
okay so please besides besides you know
so-called Home applications then you
have another level called Helm
extensions
uh
uh so I I guess these are more
kind of more exotic
so I'm supposing the the
differentiate differentiating line is
that these Helm applications merely
Supply helm by a source you know
while
these Helm extensions are
more involved you know like Helm Firefox
like like what what does it do Helm
Firefox
emacs Helm interface to Firefox to
bookmarks oh interesting so it actually
grabbed the Firefox books bookmarks so
you can open them in
because potentially you can control
Firefox launch bookmarks in Helm within
emacs okay
yeah so you have some of that then other
emacs extensions recommended with helm
okay the external programs recommended
with Helm rip grab okay known issues
okay
contributors
so uh the helm documentation is superb I
want to make that
comment okay the
the
helm documentation of all let's say just
within emacs of all emacs packages
documentation I've seen
is the one of the best let's say top
five superb
clarity
fantastic introduction
uh you know organization Clarity detail
well we haven't looked at we I mean I
don't know about that yet but
superb okay Helm stock documentation and
also the user interface you know
you can view on GitHub download right
away and you know yeah
so Helm documentation
a great job great job uh Helm people
so then it says uh created by Helm is
implemented by Helm emacs Helm Helm team
so who are the emacs helm team
okay it doesn't really say people okay
okay these people are
mostly contributors I think
okay D Wong I recognize
okay
now I don't know if they are actually
your team or are they just
major contributors
from what we've seen before mostly just
just this guy Theory you know in the
past month or so it's all him
okay so it's actually members okay so
these are actually members okay
so if you want to join Helm you know if
you love him join them
uh you probably you know start to
contribute some code in
and join them
okay let's help okay so I have finished
reading the helm home page now
uh where I mean at least I've I we have
scanned it well we we basically finished
reading them
now
let's look at
the now okay here's the helm Wiki
potentially it should contain lots of
miscellaneous information okay
upgrade or recompile or configure
General General concept okay I want to
read that quick try with emacs Helm okay
General Helm commands and so on
okay
okay so next
Wiki why is the wiki repeated Okay so
delete that it's the same page okay now
frequently asked questions
area with Helm adaptive pod Arrow when
running make
I installed Helm with straight and emacs
helm.sh is not working okay uh
as a bad one you shouldn't require
people to run make in my opinion when
you have a Emax this package you should
never require people to run make or
shell script just let it be emacs disp
keep things simple so people don't have
to install oh I need to install make or
what which version oh is it groom make
or BSD make
you know especially on Windows it's a
more problem just use emacs this you
know that's that's the thing we are
pushing that's the thing we love make it
make it all emacs this even if that
means you have to do a bit more work
that's my opinion
and especially shout like don't don't
don't don't make people run bash to ins
as a required step to install your
package
um
okay so FAQ uh why does mailpa update
give an arrow using prefix okay function
okay this FAQ we are not concerned
okay yeah a bunch of uh
you know small errors when running Helms
okay next okay Quicksilver Quicksilver
uh okay
so we finished reading the FAQ kind of
and we finished reading
okay the home page of Helm then there's
uh Helm Wiki now where is the
programmers API for help let's be
somewhere
I'm getting tired let's see oh seat Abby
five dollars USD thank you so much
uh
fantastic
do you have a question special question
for me
Max when okay I talked about that a
thousand times in my in my past videos
okay
uh unless you are trolling me so why
this never took off okay again I talked
about that about that a million times do
you reckon Windows is better what what
kind of a bunch of trolling questions
I talked about that
a thousand times Windows which one
should you use Windows Omega or Linux I
talked about that
several attempts in South talk show just
search it you should find it
okay but says the embar says okay so
something how do you Auto Import modules
in emacs
how do you Auto Import you know you use
you call use package are you a newbie
are you a new Emax users
anyway I'm not going to talk about that
today because today is you know the
you know for what I'm doing today it's
more for people who already know emac
Beast it's actually for
you know Vape fairly Advanced emacs
users who already know emac based I'm
coding
I'm trying to find out about how Helm
implements fuzzy matching
and in fact
I have discovered you know just now we
discovered firstly matching is not the
thing we want to look for we want to
look for our helm
implements odorless World matching
and that's part of the default helm uh
Helm meta X
okay I have been talking for
one hour and uh 20 minutes basically
uh and I'm kind of tired
um
for the past hour I've been rambling
about Helm documentation anyway
so
so back to emac this code in order to do
really do this I actually I need to
just do it myself I cannot
um
uh any I actually I do need to take a
break been sitting here you know I need
to take a walk
uh so
so we have not
made progress well we made some progress
but we are far away
from the goal of understanding how Helm
does word orderless world matching
so but we made some crop progress okay
let's let's write them down okay close
close all these close close
okay
so
so here is what we know so far we have
the helm
code stack
helmetics course Helm meta X read
extended command
then that calls Helm function then that
cause Helm internal
then
then that course Helm read from mini
buffer and and also probably setting up
a bunch of patterns or candidates or
sources things like that
and basically that's it and uh
so in Helm
they use the word fuzzy matching
to mean some sort of fuzzy imagine okay
now again
we have not found
how it is defined you know we want to
find a documentation possibly if there's
one how Helm defines first imagine we I
don't know yet
so but we do know that
but
the
Helm meta X thing
is
actually not using
Helms fuzzy match
but
let's call it
all the less word based matching
okay
okay that's what we learned today
um
okay
and uh the next thing to do
where is the dog for Helm API
so I thought I thought we saw that
mentioned somewhere
a documentation for API for programmers
API
search search
okay not it's not here
okay go back to
uh
so go through the helm full Home Page
search for wait what is this this is a
Helm home page
search for API okay so it's not here
now go to this one
this is the Helms
documentation I think search for API
where does it look oh there wait let's
GitHub API
oh okay
so now okay okay actually this is the
wiki
now let's go to FAQ search for API
okay not here
let's open a new browser let's say emacs
Helm API
I hope I can find the
Helm API documentation if it exists
it would be fantastic
not here because we've already looked at
here
Helm web API
okay that's that's uh that's a different
thing that's not emacs
well actually it's probably related to
um Helm but it's for other things it's
kubernetes cluster to programmatically
install Helm charts and expose them
through a single public phasing public
facing IP what the is this fund
edisp where to find emacs Helm
documentation let's see now that's a
stack Overflow question
where to find emacs Helm documentation
yeah
Helm is a great so this is written in
2018 okay
still pretty good come it's a great
framework
okay but provided no instruction on how
to do so
this page advises user to update
extension okay Helm Wiki doesn't provide
any helpful information on writing
extensions using Helm framework okay
this is a question we want it's not even
user editable containing grammatical
errors if that no one fixes or pull
requests are not accepted which I find
really young welcome okay so this is
probably a Vietnamese
he's rather criticizing help so he is
looking for Helms API documentation for
programmers just like I am
okay so he says I've been extensively
using Helm recently and like it a lot
and I want to write a cheat sheet
to serve my workflow better so my
questions are is there is the outdated
anything documentation applicable to him
okay is there any useful documentation
about Helm which explains how it works
and how to write extension using it yes
I want to know that
I've been Googling for a while but I
couldn't find anything okay
so let's see if there's answer there's
no answer but you have a bunch of
comments
as far as writing your new extension for
Helm I would recommend the 16 minute
video video
okay a very good tutorial was written by
John Kitchen okay I know that guy John
Kitchen we
met face to face he came he came to my
place one day
uh great he you know a great he's a
professor
of
uh chemistry I think Material Science I
think
uh at
Cornish melon you know one of the famous
university
and here were the emacs uh distribution
called Psi Psi Emax or something it's
for basically for academics
for professors you know for for
I could yeah research
uh to for
researchers to write academic papers so
he you can you know John kitchen so just
search for for his name John Kitchen
emacs
it's a very
big useful you know package
so anyway so let's see so John kitchen
so a very good tutorial was written by
John Kitchen okay so here
how to write Helm extensions okay
and the the documentation was initiated
thanks to John kitchen's article on his
blog okay so he has a article
okay fantastic I'm going to so this is
written in 2015 I suppose it's still
uh good I'm going to read this
okay this is great resource
and then I guess this Wiki uh emacs Wiki
version Wiki emacs version is kind of
you know kind of more cleaned up or
general
okay so I'm going to read this
okay they are updated you know 2015. I
think Wiki emacs is kind of
dead nobody's actually using it but
anyway
so here's one thing to read and here is
another okay
first of the three original post block
okay so so so so he introduces okay
okay so I'm gonna read that John
kitchen's documentation
so and also
then the Vietnamese complained
uh what 2014
he says what's going on
the documentation is badly written okay
he's referring to some other
documentation
not the one by John Kitchen
Okay so
so what about the wiki
so I need to explore more about Wiki
yeah okay developing I should yeah so
there is
okay there is developing in this First
Dimension okay so here is the
documentation
yeah so let's see let's look at
developing
introduction creating a hamburger Helm
attributes customizing action list
creating a source creating a class
creating creating actions okay
developing with Helm framework fantastic
okay this is uh
this is what I'm looking for
so I'm gonna have to spend
you know a few hours God
I didn't expect it to be this you know
big of framework so I'm actually good
I'm actually getting into a the helm
framework
and apis uh
then there's the first imagine
yeah okay it doesn't
we've seen this before it doesn't Define
what exactly is there first imagine it's
just this a bunch of functions that does
it
okay but okay so that's it
so it's you know judging from these you
know kind of short basically that's all
you get that's all I like that's
basically
oh I get you know the useful information
I don't think there's much more
on the wiki
so okay so at this point I just gonna
dive you know into source code and
and I don't think I'm going to create
another part for this series of videos
of exploring Helm source code
because it's not proper it's not gonna
be very interesting it's gonna be you
know
for people already know this
so I think that's it for today
okay that's it for today I let me just
mention so if you like my stuff
go buy my emacs tutorial okay so I have
a emacs this tutorial that contains also
I did the video I did several videos by
now that teaches you emacs lisp so you
can learn emac this from the ground up
the most practical way uh you can learn
it quickly in a week or two you can
become fairly self-sufficient in you
know coding images
okay so buy it or PayPal me you know but
you can buy it you know here the link
or you can PayPal me or patreon
thank you
okay that's it for today thank you guys
I'm gonna shut down uh in one minute
okay so you so Alpha Beta you started to
use emacs yesterday yeah so
congratulations you have a long way to
go indeed
you know I mean you you'll be
it will be fun exploration you know you
you know you can launch emacs and you'll
be already useful but if then you might
explore you know you want some better
ways you you as you go as you go
whatever you I don't know if you are a
student or if you are already a coder or
a researcher or whatever
you can customize emacs to find to make
it better for your needs
and that is kind of a journey you know
some people say it's a lifestyle so I've
been using emacs for 20 years so you
just go you know it becomes also a part
of that is a code you welcome to the
emacs code or emacs church as Richard
snowman would say
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching uh and thank you Sid Ali bye
guys