good morning guys welcome to another
episode of excel talk show
so today we are going to do emacs list
coding and the emac this coding and
especially focusing on passing URL you
know uh so what's what's a URL that's
you know that's a URL so passing URL and
I'm gonna demo several emac Visa
commands and also some JavaScript so the
topic is passing URL in emac list okay
so thank you guys for coming uh let's
begin
so okay so so let's see uh today's talk
show so I'm gonna uh first of all demo
some of the
um
Saudi website features okay so you go to
casady.info
that's my website and turn on JavaScript
okay and the video check audio check
okay and we good
so
saudi.info and click topic search and
and now there's a new feature whatever
you typed you can the URL will update
with parameters so you can bookmark it
or you can share it on Twitter and
whatever then it'll show the results so
let's uh let's try
uh
Emax okay 900 results lisp
okay 300 results let's say emac this
okay 12 results so here are all the
tutorials about emac beasts and now you
can copy the the URL copy it then go
back here and let's open a new buffer
paste it you can see
the there's a parameters now if you copy
that and let's see let's switch to a
different browser open it paste the URL
enter
uh and you you need to turn on
JavaScript of course
then you see the result shows so that
means you can share
um you know the the results of such
okay so that is the Sadi web search okay
let me show you
um so okay so let's copy that let's put
it in in talk show so we have a record
of what we talked about today so paste
that there okay and that's Saudi uh
website kasari.info website search
now let's go to Unicode let me
demonstrate Unicode search similar okay
so here's the Unicode search term
JavaScript it's already on
uh let's search for fire
okay so you got all Unicode characters
whose name contains the word fire okay
this slide is in my eyes
okay so now let's do it again let's see
water okay okay that's all Unicode
Cactus whose name contains water let's
try gram
okay now there's a lot Unicode with the
uh word gram in it so this is
post your grandma whatever that is this
character Greek capital letter Alpha
with
Philly and Pastor Grandma okay that's
new for me okay that's a that's a
apostrophe under the character that's
interesting
you know so Unicode so you know they are
hundreds of thousands characters
so these are interesting so many of them
black parallelogram uh trigram for
heaven this one
uh then then so lots of trigrams then
you have left-handed interlaced
pentagram
right-handed interlaced pentagram you
have pentagram you know many interesting
characters then you have hexagram
hexagram is just like trigram but it's
by the way these trigrams you can see in
Korean flag you know that's the taiji
Chinese philosophy but you also have
hexagram made out of six
bars you know this is combination
combinatorial actually this is very
interesting because you know what let me
show you this is very interesting this
about trigrams okay so let's go to the
page
uh
okay so let's go to the cultural let's
search for culture
yeah so let's open that page
so you can see here
is the collection of monogram which is
just one single bar but
a common you know a single bar can break
into two bars or break into three bars
so you have monogram then you have
diagram these characters in Unicode then
you have a trigram now these are the
most popular you can see it in Chinese
Tai Chi you know bakwa
if you know what that is uh and you know
and there's pagua palm which is a Kung
Fu style uh and you can see these
characters in Korean flag let's show
each of the trigram actually has a
meaning
so you see you see those uh trigrams in
Korean flag so there are total of eight
possibilities when you have three bars
and each bar has two variations either
of a continuous bar or cut in the middle
so you have six you have eight
possibilities the Korean flag shows only
four of them and each one actually has a
meaning so for example this one is
trigram for Earth or broken and and this
one all connected by this trigram for
heaven heaven and earth that's that's
Chinese philosophy Buddhism concept
Heaven and Earth
Heaven is kind of equivalent to God to
the Western Society
Earth basically means anything that's
none God you know human Affairs Earth
Heaven Earth then you have Lake trigram
for Lake Fire and so on but
interestingly this is uh rarely seen is
you have the hexagram made out of uh six
characters
and then you have tetragram made out of
four uh four bars okay so hexagram and
tetragram uh you don't see them often
but let me yeah let me show you how they
connect to mathematics this is you can
consider them as binary
numbering system okay that's a that's an
interesting part for you programmers
binary numbers numbering system in fact
um Lebanese you know one of the greatest
mathematician Lebanese the the inventor
of calculus uh and also Newton lebanes
has commented let me let me find it okay
so now
let's go to uh back to Unicode search
let's go to so a bit digression and
today is random say hi okay uh whoever
you are so let's topic search and uh
let's see
trigram there it is okay so
uh actually where's the article
okay so the article is inside the DOT
org so I have two websites saudi.info
and another one is saudi.org but okay
let's search for it
saudi.org trigram
uh JavaScript now
okay uh Grand Master let's try that one
so I'll ask some music uh and stuff
let's see
so this is a kung fu movie uh you know
Kung Fu movie they are not realistic
uh so there is uh you know Tai Chi and
Ian stuff and there it is
so this is a verse from you know the
here's the verse describing the bhagwat
bhagwa means eight
eight extremities you know these eight
trigrams represents the kind of the
eight extremities and here's the English
translation
so let me let me read it okay the
Limitless produces the delimited and
this is the absolute the taiji produces
two forms named Ing and Young
the two forms produces four phenomena
named lesson greater in lesser young and
greater young okay I think these four
characters are the uh what's in the
Korean flag I'm I'm guessing
you you can you can check you know you
can verify then the full phenomenon act
on the eight trigrams eight eight or 64
hexagrams okay so they mentioned
trigrams and hexagrams you know so they
derived from you know the
absolute which is like I I suppose one
bar or something but anyway from one bar
to trigram to uh to a hexagram
okay so know that the trigram is
inherently inherited to your binary
system you have three lines each line
has two states so two raised to the
power of three is eight possible
combination combinatorics okay that's a
combinatorics is a field in mathematics
okay so for you programmers I recommend
you study this subject very interesting
for example Lottery you know if you want
to know what's a possibility of winning
lottery you know the formula how do you
deserve that from formula and things
like that that's combinatorics okay
combinatorics has quite a lot
interesting applications for example
three the possible binary tree you know
how many number you know basically
combinatorics is about counting Counting
the number of possibilities enumeration
okay combinatorics is you can code uh
you know in other words is enumeration
the problem of enumeration so for
example if you have
you know Lottery 50 numbers you pick six
what are the possibilities of six unique
numbers that's common and torics that's
the most basic fundamental combinatorics
you know pick six numbers out of uh 50
or whatever
Pick N numbers out of M numbers so the
total number of binary tree given n
number of nods that's also combinatorics
you know and there's a partician part
partition Theory there's a okay this
poly uh poly Cube uh what's the exact
exact name
polyaminos you know like how many shapes
is it possible to be formed by let's say
four cubes you know that's combinatorics
and you can have the same problem with
triangles how many total possible number
of shapes can be formed by let's say
five triangles you know you you put them
side by side or squares so combinatorics
and you know there's many different
um approach to find the solution
analytic combinatorics that's using
calculus to trying to find a solution
you know partition Theory graph Theory
you guys probably uh hood of
design Theory I don't know what that is
a finite geometry you know so these are
combinatorics so for example this one is
another very interesting thing for
example this you can think of it as a
maze you know creation of Mace you can
write a program to do it and the problem
here in particular is how many possible
uh let's see self-avoiding work like you
know how many possible
you know self-avoiding walk in a square
on a grid you know so algebraic
combinatorics uh and and there's a
geometric combinatorics uh
okay so combinatorics and and uh what is
this combinatorial optimization you know
here is a sphere packing I suppose
that's the most uh famous
um problem in math very difficult
problem
okay so we went into combinatorics and
let's quote
um
okay
Lebanese you know bong knight uh 1646 to
1716. inventor of calculus and father of
computer
said that hexagrams
a base for claiming the universality of
the binary number system
so I happen to found that quote you know
I'm not sure exactly what's the contact
context so he says hexagrams
a base for claiming the universality of
the binary number system very
interesting okay digression digression
into combinatorics so now let's go back
to our URL problem that's what we wanted
to talk about today
so I was showing I was demonstrating the
Unicode search okay so we happened to
search on uh gram okay so Unicode search
uh let's see something else hot okay hot
so you got all possible hearts in
unicode
uh okay so now the point is now the URL
you can see the URL
um
you can see let's let's post it here
okay so the URL contains a query stream
so so you can uh you know bookmark it
and you you uh have the same result okay
that's my that's a new feature on my
website
so okay so we demonstrated that we
demonstrate the my website search and
unicode search let's uh let me
demonstrate some uh this emac these
commands emacs commands Okay so for
example I copy this URL you know often I
want to tweet
Twitter you know treat uh or post on
anxiety scored you know on social media
so I want to post a link to my website
so usually you need the title so here I
got a file path
but you know how do you get the title
usually you open the file uh wait you
open the file which is this file
let's try another file okay let's go to
Kasa you know programming blog so copy
the URL back to emacs close it paste the
UI so you see that's a URL you you need
a title so usually what you do is you
open the file then you go to the top
then you go to where the title is you
copy it close it then you paste it here
and also you this is a local file path
you see that
um local file path you needed to change
it to the
you know fully qualified domain name the
final path so I have a command in emacs
so so look look I copy that paste it
here so I'm gonna do it here
so I think this key you see so let's do
it again delete that line so I got a
local file path
three keys and there it is so
programming blog with the uir so this is
very convenient for for me
so let me show you what that command uh
the source code okay
okay so the command is site this is my
personal command and it's the let's look
at the source code so the source code is
here uh let's narrow to region so there
are a total of 35 lines
so that's a demonstration of this
command let me demonstrate another and
let me tell you what's the point uh
yeah site okay so hold on a second so
let's see
so that's demonstration of exhaust site
as a citation and let me demonstrate
open URL open file from clipboard okay
so now let's go back to this programming
blog let's copy the file path
copy it
and paste it you can see you know it's
that file so I want to open that file so
what do you do usually so usually
you know what I usually do is you open a
buffer you paste it then you call
usually ffap ffap stand for find file at
Point that's a pod emacs command so we
can try it ffap okay
then you'll ask you are you sure this is
the file you want to open yeah shut up
you know then it opens then you can show
in browser okay so go back here close it
but anyway that's too many steps okay
what I want is that you see you see what
I want is usually let's go to some other
um
some other files so for example this is
my
that's not a good example okay
so you for example this is one of my
page I copy the URL I want to open this
local file in emacs so I copy the URL go
to emacs and I just press three keys
it'll open this page for example now I
show in browser it's exactly the same
page
so what is that command okay that
command is first of all let's paste the
path that command is
this one open file from clipboard okay
so basically when you copy your file
path into the clipboard you then you
call this command you will open whatever
the path
so I don't have to you know create a new
buffer paste the path then call a
command to open that path you know so
very convenient
so once I you know as I work on my
website I copy some UI out there I can
just outside and it becomes this you
know I can then I can treat treat it and
so on very convenient so they are these
are two commands Okay hold on a second
it's um
okay show today's talk show
so that command is open file from
clipboard now let's see if I if I have
the source code
uh somewhere no I don't I you know it's
I don't have a page showing the source
code
so anyway but now there's a problem with
these two commands why because now my
website now has the um
uh has the
has the parameters okay let me show you
so for example let's let me let me
demonstrate okay so let me demonstrate
here uh wait here
so paste it and paste it again so you
see
now normally you know before today my
website is usually static you know I
don't have the these parameters so if I
want to
um cite you know
this path I just do and it becomes this
you know the title Unicode search
no but if I do it here
it doesn't work you know it says error
sound site error file doesn't exist you
see it's trying to consider this
parameters part of the file path so I
need to fix that
so let's fix that
hey guys so uh any questions for me
so uh you know
so okay so so
and let's now code emac bisp
um okay so now
we can start to code emac this let's see
okay let's see where do we go now we
demonstrated that we demonstrate that we
demonstrate these two emac basis
commands uh oh okay so let me show you
the JavaScript
so the JavaScript you know how do you
implement this uh you know parameters
you know the trick about these
parameters this URL
get a URL parameters so here is the
dissection of the
URL okay so let's magnify dissection
naming of the URL parts so here is the
protocol here is the host okay that's a
host name then part of the host name is
Dom domain name then you have sub domain
name then this number is the port number
uh
and then you have this part is the
resource path technically it's called
resource path then you have a question
mark what comes after the question mark
is called query stream okay that's a
proper word not parameter it's called
query stream now given a query stream
is separated by a ampersand
uh character then
each part is a pair uh
um
a query string name and a value okay
key value pairs yeah you can say that
okay so anyway this is Chris query
stream then after that is a fragment URL
fragment
so
so one the thing we want to do today is
write a emac these two parts this uh URL
so anyway here's a JavaScript
and uh
okay so let me let me let me talk about
um
so when you do when you want to have a
interactive search website
you know you see if you look at the URL
you know look at the URL carefully as I
type let's say
um
t
H you can see the URL gets updated i n g
so
so this is a unical character contains
the word thing I don't know what that is
let's say m o n
mono okay all these are Unicode
characters containing the word mono
okay and you we have a interesting
character kimono a Japanese traditional
uh attire
and face with face with Monaco that's
also interesting and we have monorail
okay so the point is the URL gets
updated so when you whenever you have a
page like that in JavaScript the
question the problem is when you have a
search box how do you do this
okay
uh that is easy that is not difficult so
I have a new blog on how to how to do
that so you go to you know start
programming blog and you can see a new
page update URL parameters
okay so here is um how you do it okay
I don't I am now going to go over
JavaScript let's go back to
um
okay passing URL so
so next thing we want to do
is to pass URL to fix my commands Okay
okay so let me show you how to do that
pass URL so first of all let's try let's
copy the URL let's let's demo let's
start to do emac this okay
let's start the emac this paste it and
and start code here so here is emac this
Emax this mod okay so here is a stream
and we want to pass it into separate
separate parts
so let's write a function okay
Define
has a x pass okay let's just say that
version
okay so let's say the input so
input is a URL let's just name X URL I
put X in front so that we know it's a
local variable just um
uh so so let's here's a example URL
let's quote it let's comment that out
and we want to pass the URL right so
given a URL
so
so there are several parts okay so there
is the the parts are
protocol
host
port number
path
let's say resource
resource path
then frag fragment okay so let's add a x
in front so that
just for my convention so they stand out
the variable names become Spode
or we can put a dollar sign that's just
my convention I started to use x
so so anyway so
we want to pass the URL into those parts
so how do you do well
you can do it with a regular expression
okay let's do it this is not the most
efficient but and also it's not the most
robust robust
but let's you know for the sake of this
emac this tutorial it's just code it
okay comments keep them coming okay so
let's
we want to pass the URL now so how do
you uh yeah make your expression so
okay so how do you um
yeah the regular expression so
uh
so what's the function to match a
regular expression in here in this case
um
string match okay so you know I just
know it because I've been coding emac
this for over 10 years
string match is the command you want
given a regular expression you want to
match your stream and in this case the
string is the X URL okay so let's go
back here
and optional start we don't care okay so
what what is the regular expression okay
let's do the regular expression
the regular expression will be HTT so
first of all we need a so let's see the
hostname does Does it include the colon
it I don't think so so right so
this part will be
I'm I'm just gonna work on this okay so
we want to capture that's why we need a
parenthesis
okay
uh and the parenthesis in emacs string
needs a backslash
I mean a parenthesis in emacs regular
expression is literal okay so in order
in Python in Pearl in PHP in JavaScript
in Java in Gola and all the you know the
regular expression parenthesis means
capture however in emacs this regular
expression parenthesis is literal so if
you want to capture you have to
backslash you have to you need one
backslash in front however
in emac this stream
there's no special regular expression
string it's just normal string so in a
normal string a backslash is a Escape
character so if you actually want a
backslash you need to put a backslash in
front so two back backslash so this is
actually how you do capture you know a
toothpick syndrome very severe in emac
this okay so anyway the first part is
gonna capture
so we want to
start with that that means start of the
actually
you know so that correct sign means the
beginning of the string okay
uh but but actually in emacs you what
you need is not that what you actually
the correct way is
again backslash backslash
that okay
because
that tick that back tick you know at
grave accent I think that what's the
official Unicode name so official
Unicode name for this character is grave
accent okay so this scrape accent in
emac this means the beginning
in emacs regular expression it means the
beginning of the
of the Matched text the beginning of
match text okay
the
correct character means means two things
either the beginning of the match text
or the beginning of a line so it has two
meanings
you know this is some special you know
this is a special case in emac regular
expression because in other languages
you just have this but in emac this if
you really want to do it properly you
should use this the
the grave accent character okay so I I I
suppose this is uh too esoteric hello
reason
so anyway so but let's just use that
it's more familiar to most people and
similarly for the end you need a dollar
sign okay
uh
so let's so let's continue with the
regular expression so you want to match
the protocol so the protocol will be
A to Z and O A to Z and zero to nine
okay let's say 0 to 9 okay
okay that's a protocol name so the first
capture is that then then you got a
domain name okay so now we can just copy
that then we got the domain name okay
then you got the port number
okay domain name includes a DOT so you
need to put a dot here actually we need
one or more characters one or more of
any of these characters okay so that's
why you need a plus plus means one or
more so now here is a domain name I mean
the hostname we capture that part
then the port number okay so let's copy
that again
port number
port number and here is just zero to
nine okay
okay let's try this okay so port number
then after the port number you have a
slash then you have
after port number you have the path
resource path does that include the
first slash no it does not include the
first stash so this is a technical
detail you know actually you have to pay
attention if you if you are actually
working on some code
so the first slash doesn't count so
let's
um actually let's turn the mono spaced
font let's go back to Mono space font so
so now you need to capture the path so
that would be that
okay so anything
path will be
okay so path the path part will be more
complex because you also need the
percentage sign that capture because
it gets into encoding because if you
have a Unicode character in The Path
it's not allowed you have to encode it
and encoded for example space becomes
percentage sign 20.
space a literal space is not allowed so
that's why you need the percentage sign
okay that's called URL encoding okay let
me let me show you
since we are I'm gonna just show you my
stuff so study code you know xadi dot
info search
you type percent then you can see so
e-macb UIL percent in code decode that
shows you how and uh and you can also
code
emac this command to do that but calling
JavaScript okay let's open that uh and
here is the article about
let's open them you know so and there's
a complexities when it involves a
Ampersand character because Ampersand
character in HTML also needs to be
encoded so this is complexity extreme
very very
uh
okay this 40 is about 40 keyboard
okay so let's open them so so here this
is a tutorial on emac this viewer
percent encoding so you can see uh
example if you have a Unicode like that
it needs to become you know
percentage C3 and so on it needs to be
you know anyway
you can read the article so and this
article is about
okay writing a emacs command to do
percent percent encoding and decoding
but coding a JavaScript to do it because
in JavaScript there's a building uh a
building function to do it this one the
code URI component
or we can do it in pure emac list so
here is how you do actually there is a
building command in the URL uto Library
okay so let me move on quickly so
so here's another this is article
explaining the percent encoding decode
so anyway let's go back to the
to the passing URL so that's why we need
the percentage sign and we need other
things but but let's not let's not let's
just you know
um
do this quickly so now you need the
parameter part so what is the
oh God this is never gonna end
so we already talked for 46 minutes uh
okay the parameter part will be
so you need uh let's see okay so
so you need also the
Ampersand let's just say that okay let's
forget about and also you need the
equality okay so that gives you the
parameters what's the proper name query
string okay then the last part is
fragment notation okay the fragmentation
is
let's say anything
let's just say anything
one or more till the end actually
the fact mentation is actually may not
exist so we need to
have regular expression that checks the
possibility there's no fragmentation and
also you need a regular expression to
to check the possibility there is no
parameters so this gets complex and also
the absolute path may be maybe empty
and also port number so this is this is
not a robot's robust solution robust you
know the regular expression will get
more complex in fact I think to do this
properly
you don't use a regular expression but
anyway let's just
um let's just push on okay so this is
too long let's make it into two lines
so okay so delete that delete that
shrink let's look at our whole command
now let's cut predify okay so let's just
let's just do that for now okay so now
we got first part two part three four
five six okay so you need to set them
okay
uh
God this is this is gonna take a long
time
set
protocol
to be
match string match string is
match string is a function that gets the
Matched groups okay so the in this case
is the first match okay so match string
one that's right and the string is this
you need to add it here
uh so okay let's just do it this way
X host
export
X resource path
extract
okay
and now
now let's see one two three four
four
five okay
that should do it all right let's hope
um
okay and now let's print them
let's just return
a list
return a list of these things that's
right okay purify the code
okay I maybe that's it maybe that's it
that's our code that's our whole code
okay
x-pass URL let's name it something
better okay Xbox URL and the
documentation
return a list
of Parts okay now let's call the command
let's copy that let's call it and that's
and that would be way
the argument would be this example
okay evaluate
the code okay you can see I called uh
evaluate so emacs now know this function
now we are going to evaluate this line
okay and see what's the result
do it okay debugger enter this error
invalid regular expression oh God
expected a new you know you almost never
gonna succeed on regular expression
oh there it is okay so we forgot the uh
backslash
backslash backslash okay now
evaluate this code again call it again
there it is but we got Neo Neo Neo
that means the code the regular
expression failed let's double check
okay
so
ah God why is uh
you can see here's the result it's
O'Neill that means we captured none of
it uh is correct
you know I'm writing this because just
to demonstrate emac disp
but the proper way to do it there is a
library already building in images
because emacs has a browser building you
know so you know if if you if you don't
know emacs already has a browser
uh building so but uh hold on a second
let me copy
copy the URL let's let's open
let's log what we talked about into uh
today's talk show okay so we copied we
we did that
we did that and we searched for
percentage sign okay
okay so now we want to
what what is it that we want to do uh
emacs it is regular expression we want
to
uh this is taking a long time so we want
yeah there should be a building function
to do this yeah yeah I was going to show
you emacs browser okay so let's search
for Saudi code search
emacs browser
so you can see
emac this view view URL in web browser
browse URL okay so there is a pod
browser
or this is uh okay close that
so there is a building emacs browser
let's show it let's demo okay today is
randomish let's demo Okay so
www
browse okay
and the wrong argument type what
I haven't
now the first time when you use the
emacs browser you got Arrow
uh run type argument Emax 28 what's
going on
yeah you know I haven't used emacs
browser building browser but now I got
an arrow but it would work if I start
Emax 27. but I don't I don't know okay
let's try to make it work okay so let's
open Emax 28 let's open beam yeah I do
have emacs 27
okay start
uh Windows terminal okay that's a new
application Windows terminal better than
the command.exe the better than Windows
console so I recommend you download
Windows terminal okay so now
CD Bing
duh so we want to start emacs 27 I'm
using emacs 28 so emacs you know
possibly my distro yeah my e-max 28
broke broke the building emacs web
browser so let's try emacs 27 okay
do it
okay here is the Emax 27 now let's call
let's magnify
called www
uh what
what is the browser command
eww okay
you browser eww main IX eww Brown
okay just eww
and enter URL let's say sorry dot info
so there it is a browser within emacs
including Graphics so here is uh
including including Graphics but it does
not support SVG
um
I don't think so so anyway here's my
website in emacs browser
but if you go to my website let's see
sunny.info
you can see apparently it doesn't
support YouTube you know
embedded YouTube videos but there is a
SVG JavaScript clock
so and that is also not showing up here
so let's search for
SVG there there it is it doesn't show
you know it doesn't show the
JavaScript anyway so emacs browser okay
so let's close this we don't need it
anymore
uh okay emacs 27 we demonstrated the EU
browser uh
we what we want to do yeah so
emacs has a browser build in that means
you know return in emac this entirely
because you know I can let's let's show
the source code
oh I think uh
enter URL actually
oh actually emacs 28 works you know I
was calling the wrong command before so
so emacs has a
browser building written entirely in
images so let's see the source code
describe function eww okay
there it is okay so
and jump to the source code so here is a
source code and you jump to diet jump
you jump to diagram to the to the
directory so you can see the source code
for the you browser
okay so 2000 lines is more than that
they split into you know it's it's more
than ten thousand lines so but basically
my point is that it has a browser
building so it has lots of you know URL
passing uh passing HTML already in in
emac Beast so there's a code for to pass
URL
okay that is my point
now okay so now let's close the browser
now let's
um get back to our
code let's see where where is it
um what's wrong
then that's it for today you know I was
going to find the library for passing
URL I can yeah I can probably find it
let's let's find it now okay so describe
function let's let's show the pink
window
and close this okay describe function
eww okay go to the source code
then
find color command to search all
dot El files for pass URL that's
probably the name okay so such that this
directory search for El files there it
is
URL there it is URL generic past URL so
there is the that's probably the correct
function so let's just open it
any one of them so there is that that is
a function so now describe function URL
generic pass URL there it is the source
code so it's in the file UIL pass okay
fantastic
fantastic so it has written you know so
it has written for us
so let's try to call call this command
Okay so let's see how many lines is that
so this command by itself is 100 lines
okay so you can see it's not using just
one regular expression
because that would be very complex
so anyway so let's try the use so it
says return on UI are struct of the
parts of the URL UIL struct so it's
using a struct data structure the CL
style struct contains the following
Fields okay I
okay let's copy it close it close it
close it let's try to
uh call this command and see if that
works okay run it
fantastic now show the output show the
message buffer so you can see
it passed correctly so you got we got
the protocol and Neo Neo that's some
other field you got the hostname you got
port number port number you got
okay so they they join the path and the
parameter into one then fragment okay
okay that works so I think that's it for
today or we can try to get a regular
expression to work
we we should be able to okay let me try
so the hostname
host them
let's see
so we got the
we got a protocol then we got the
hostname
including a DOT examples okay then we
got the port number zero to nine one or
more then slash then this is the path
resource path okay that should work
one or more plus and then here is the
parameters okay the
query string okay
so why is our
um
why is a regular expression returning
new all the time so
match string one
yeah so so let's let's do some debug
okay
it's just message
protocol okay
about the buffer Eva this Neo so why is
it Neo
so if we
okay let's uh
let's try that
eval the code Eva that's your Neo so is
it because
let's remove that okay
wow
Neo
protocol what's wrong A to Z a to O the
yeah so this is this part is wrong the Z
needs three capital uh
there it is okay eval the code
this part that's still Neo so A2Z a2z029
one or more
I don't know why is that stream match
okay so that is incorrect for some
reason it's common it out let's make it
simpler Okay so
here let's just do that okay
Eva the function and Eva this part there
it is HTTP so you can see in there it is
we got it correct
so that means our regular expression
this long one is incorrect
so but we before we go to anything let's
add back the beginning of string okay
Eva
that's still correct okay so now let's
add
so that part is correct so
that part is correct then the second
part
the second part colon colon is literal
then slash slash slash is literal in
e-max vehicle expression then we want
this part so why is it not working so
let's
copy that okay let's
do it
port number
okay let's just try this simple
expression okay comment this out okay
eval the code
evaluate then run this it still works
http
okay so now we made some progress now
now we got the
protocol and we got the host okay that's
that's also put the host there
okay so hold on a second
Okay so
you have the code internet there it is
correct
now we let's add another part
so we got a hostname correct then
oh I know what's going on because the
this part you need a slash but we don't
have a slash there so we need uh that's
a resource path part so we add a slash
render code
and actually make that
run the code now eval
now it's only again so actually
so the S part is fragments okay the
fragment and let's see
it's a fragment
so there is something
oh the question mark there it is the
question mark in regular expression
means
um
means any character wait it means zero
or one occurrence so you need to escape
it
backslash to escape it backslash to
escape the backslash okay
now
blend the code and run this code
fantastic now we got
http
the hostname
then
okay Neo Neo Neo then we got the port
number okay the port number we need to
work on the port number
the port number is zero to nine
slash
why why is support number oh yeah port
number we have we forgot to
there do it
minute fantastic here is the output
fantastic so that's
okay that's it for today so we completed
we
we completed our code this is how you
pass so let's clean up remove that this
is how you pass a
uh URL in emails and so hold on a second
let's clean up so here's a code and
there's a building function that's how
you do that there okay so now let's put
them back
color it show in browser
so that's
how you do it in emac this that's it for
today thank you guys for watching that's
70 minutes
now if you like my stuff you know buy my
emacs tutorial Okay so
so you go to you know emacs of uemax
fans you go through my website just
search for Saudi emacs you have emacs
tutorial and you have emac this tutorial
um
you know then you buy it pay me okay or
patreon me or PayPal me thank you guys
so we shut down in two minutes
awesome guy Leons thank you
so let me read some comments we shut
down in two minutes
uh dizziness says it would be great to
get the H1 tag from the source code via
curl we get
and get the title of the article from it
and combine it for a quick browser
browser to emacs link
yeah that would be useful but not for me
because that you know you are going to
call curl and we get so that means
you're gonna make a internet trip you
know for me I don't want the internet
trip you know I copy some local file for
example today's talk show here's a URL I
copy it I go to emacs I paste it this is
not a fully qualified URL it's just a
local file so but I can press the key
and it becomes you know start talk show
the title I don't have to make a
internet trip
I don't need to I don't and I don't want
to uh so but
but for example if I if the URL is study
I can also do it because you know
because I know this is you know my
website so I can I know how this file
path maps to my local file so I can
actually open the file that's what the
code actually do open the file and go to
the top and find the title you know
title of which one you know and copy
that
then then paste the title there so
that's the that's what my command do but
yeah but
of course for remote for example if I
copy some for example this combinatorics
I copy it it doesn't work right because
I you know I I can't get a title you
know you have to make a internet trip
then in that case you have to uh you
know use call or we get
yeah but usually I just post my own
website you know so I don't
um I don't really need it
uh
crazy sloth I think you are a troll
don't post political crap okay
thank you guys okay and thank you gayash
bye guys
we have we have 10 people a bit busy
today
shutting down by