Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Sand Talk Show.
Today, we are going to cover Emacs Lisp
from the ground up for beginners.
Okay, so this is going to be 1 hour.
Uh let's check video video check audio
check. I I'm good to go.
So, it's going to be 1 hour and uh
and the the prerequisite. So, this is
for people I assume you have already
used Emacs for a month or two. So, you
are familiar with Emacs a little bit at
least because Emacs Lisp is is going to
be used in Emacs. So, if you don't do
Emacs, then it's useless for you. Okay,
so
uh I assume you already used Emacs for a
month or two. And I also assume you
already you are familiar with
programming languages at least one of
them. You know, some familiarity. So, I
don't have to explain what's a variable,
what's a function, uh you know, what's
what's the data type, you know, what's a
string, you know, so you I assume you
already know that. So, that's the
prerequisite. So, this is for beginners.
You never know any Lisp before.
Okay? And so, we're going to
uh
Uh yeah, so let's go to my website. So,
everything I talk about today is already
written as a tutorial. Xahlee.info. So,
you just go to Xahlee.info or just
search my name
Xahlee Emacs
you'll find my Emacs Lisp tutorial. So,
that's my website. So, you go down and
you can find Emacs Lisp.
Okay? So, Emacs Lisp, that's what we're
going to cover.
And uh let me tell you the So, what So,
let me tell you some background about
Emacs Lisp the language. So, what you're
going to get, you know, so
if you are Emacs user and if if
programming is your profession or any
kind of technical
uh security, you know, uh computer
computing is your profession
and and if you choose to use Emacs,
which is very powerful, you know, you
want to
you want to master a editor, text
editor, because that's that's that's
your life, you know.
And Emacs is a good choice. And if you
use Emacs, Emacs Lisp is great to know
because it allows you to for example,
this is a HTML
you are looking at HTML file and showing
browser. That's today's talk show. So, I
can do a lot editing for example, here
is the Google Ads, you know, I can
select them by by, you know, matching a
tag and delete them if I want to, you
know, and
uh for example, I can for example, here
this block of code, you see, I just
press one key. Okay, hold on a second.
Let me magnify. I forgot to
uh
do some preparation. I need to magnify
my buffer. So, for example, this command
I'm calling
you see, it allows me to change my font
size.
Let's say 20.
Okay, so now it's easier to see. I
forgot to
uh do the preparation. So, let's also
magnify the browser.
Okay, so now it's uh easier to see.
Uh okay, I forgot to
Okay, so hold on a second. So,
So, but anyway, so that command I just
called to magnify uh to enlarge the font
is the one of the command I wrote. So,
if you are Emacs So, if you know Lisp
uh it's going to be uh
great benefit to you. Okay? So, showing
browser and let me uh enlarge this
window.
Uh I forgot to do do preparation. So, I
need to make sure nothing is blocked.
Okay? So, hold on a second. So, let me
also um
start my command log mod so you can see
all the keystrokes I type and all the
command I call. So, for example, you see
this text, I can make it a
paragraph. You see, that added the P
tags there there. You see, undo. Do it.
You see? So, that command I just called
is
Xah HTML blocks to paragraph. You see,
so this is the power of knowing Emacs
Lisp. And especially if you are
programmer, you can do, you know, you
can do your refactoring your code in any
language, you know, it's very powerful.
Okay? So, that's the benefit you get for
Emac Emacs. Of course, you know, there
are thousands of packages already, but
you can enhance them. You know, knowing
a little bit Emacs Lisp will help you
understand lots of things in Emacs
because the whole Emacs is actually just
a Emacs Lisp environment. For example,
all your init files.
For example, I have uh lots of init
files. For example, all your init files
all all all those all those are just
Emacs Lisp code, you know, it's just
programming language code.
Okay? So, that's the benefit of Emacs
Lisp. So, let's make this one line. Uh
so,
Okay, prerequisite.
And uh okay, I showed you my Emacs
website. We're going to go through uh
some of them. And let me tell you there
are two major parts to Emacs Lisp the
language. Okay? One part is that Emacs
Lisp you have all the things every other
language have such as string, variable,
how do you do how do you define a
function,
how do you define local variable, global
variable, how do you do a loop, for
loop, while loop, things like that, you
know, those are the basic concepts in
every programming language, Perl,
Python, Java, Ruby, JavaScript, C, C#,
Golang, you know, and so on.
So,
and and uh okay, variable, functions,
string, comments, how do you do a
comments in in Emacs Lisp? So, all these
things uh formatting string, arithmetic,
how do you do 1 + 1, uh converting
string to int or float to to or string,
two different types of the language,
uh and variables and loop, if then else,
and then you have data structures. In
the Emacs Lisp case, you have list and
vector. Vector is just like a tuple
tuple in Python.
Uh then you have, you know, sequence
types getting technical detail,
association list, property list. So,
that's the data structure, you know,
built-in data types in the language. And
then you have functions. How do you
define them? How do you
you know, define very various forms of
function parameters. For example, named
parameters, optional parameters, default
values for parameter.
In this, you know, in in the Emacs Lisp
case, you actually don't have that. But
anyway, this uh function, what's a
lambda function, and uh
then in the Emacs Lisp you have the
concept of symbol, you know, maybe I'll
go uh we'll go over that. Then Okay, so
these elements all these elements are
basic concepts in every programming
language. Okay? So, this is one part of
learning Emacs Lisp.
Okay? So, this is the Emacs Lisp, you
know, I I call Lisp basics. Lisp basics
because these are concepts available in
every Lisp, Common Lisp, Scheme Lisp,
Racket Scheme Lisp, or Closure, you
know, those are the major Lisps today.
So, uh
yeah, so this is one part of Lisp
concepts that's available in every
language. So, once you learn this, you
can just, you know,
do uh programming with it. Now, the
other part, which is more practical and
more important to Emacs Lisp, is
uh is Emacs specific
Emacs Lisp. So, what are those? Those
are things like how do you um
uh how do you manipulate the buffer, you
know, so in Emacs Lisp, you know, in in
Emacs we have the buffer, we have the
window, we have the frame, we have the
background color, we have the syntax
coloring, you see the current line is
colored. How do you do that? You have
also uh cuz you have also
buttons, you know, how for example, this
is uh you know, one of the feature of
Emacs that lets you customize
Emacs without, you know, knowing uh much
Emacs Lisp code. So, you know, you see
those are buttons that allows you to
search. For example, let's say
uh
You know, anyway, so buttons, you know,
syntax coloring, and major mod Let's
close it, you know, close buffer, how do
you do that? You see, these concepts,
buffer buffer cursor position, um
deleting deleting text, inserting text.
For example, I copy that and copy and
paste. All these concepts are not
available in a general general purpose
languages such as Python, Java, C,
because, you know, so these these are
concept these are Emacs specific Emacs
Lisp. Okay? And this part is the most
practical.
Uh and in my past videos, I've done a
lot of that, quite a lot, more than 10
videos. So,
but I've never done
uh I never done a tutorial of Emacs Lisp
fundamentals from the ground up. That's
So, that that's what we are going to do
do today.
So, Emacs specific Emacs Lisp, you know,
and how do you write a major mod? So,
maybe you have, you know, cursor uh
cursor text editing. How do you insert
and what is the interactive? How do you
query user? For example,
let's say I want to
you know, in Emacs control X control F,
open a new file.
How do you prompt user to get user to,
you know, enter some path? You know,
that's a prompt. So, how do you do that?
You know, usually these things are not
available in other languages. You know,
how do you do prompt? How do you ask,
you know, user to input
uh
file path, file names, or regular
expressions for searching, or or what a
number or whatever.
And so, Emacs specific things. Then, how
do you run Emac Lisp code in a shell run
Emac Lisp script in a shell? So, Emac
Lisp can also allow you to run
For example, in Python, you can type
Python A
uh
Python script.
Something like that, py, right? You'll
run it. You can also do that in Emac
Lisp.
Okay, so
So, all these
So, this concept is more specific to
Emacs. Okay, so
uh
we're going to cover some of that. So,
let's move on because we have a lot to
do. We already talked for 10 minutes.
Okay, so let's let's let's let's try to
move on.
Uh we have a lot people today.
So, if you have a question for me
related to this talk, just ask me and
post my name there, okay, so I can
easily see it.
So, two parts of Emac Lisp, one is
generic,
uh similar to every language. The other
part is Emacs specific, such as cursor,
text manipulation, cursor buffer, major
minor mode, syntax coloring, GUI, how do
you create a new window, uh you know,
new frame, or you know, things like
that. That's Emacs specific.
Okay. Now,
Now, they actually Okay, so for the
Emacs specific Emac Lisp,
they are also kind of two parts. One is
all about text processing. And this is
the most practical. This is the most
practical. Because, for example, every
every time you see me using Emacs, all
these, you know, selection,
uh delete, or cut, paste,
uh let me show the pink window so you
can see my command. You see, I want to
select the whole list.
You know, so that command is such HTML
select element. So, let me show you the
code, okay? So, for example, let me show
you some Emac Lisp source code.
Okay, so you jump to it. So, there it
is. This This is what
does that. So, it's not too big, okay?
So, copy that. So, copy new buffer,
paste, only 60 lines, okay?
And make it syntax color. So,
So, anyway, so
uh So, okay, close that. So, let's let's
let's go on, okay?
Two parts to Emac Lisp. So, yeah, so the
for the Emac Lisp Emacs specific
Lisp,
they are again, you can divide it into
two parts. One is text manipulation,
which is the most
uh common commonly needed, the most
practical. For example, everything I do
today. And
uh you know, that's for example, delete,
or
that's related to that's that's part of
text processing. Now, the other
part is about how do you control font?
How do you
uh How do you For example, you see the
color here is purple. How does that
How is it How does it work? How do you
make Emacs to color part of text purple,
for example? And you see here is a line.
How do you do that? So, so these are not
text processing. These are related to
syntax coloring, font,
minor mode, which is Emacs specific
concept, minor mode, major mode. How do
you create a major mode? How do you
manipulate window frame size? How do you
write a directory viewer, for example?
You see,
uh let me shrink the You see, here's a
directory. So, Emacs can be used for
directory. For example, I can make a
backup list of this file. Do it. You
see, there it is. Here's a backup. And
the command I just called is that. So,
So, this is not text processing, but
rather more
Emacs specific. For example, and how do
you write a image viewer? For example,
let's go to some image directory so I
can actually view
some images. You know, this is our
study forum.
Uh
view image, PDF viewer, and so on, okay?
So, okay, so let's begin the the Emacs
fundamentals, the general purpose Emacs,
okay?
Uh let's see. Okay, so let's begin to do
that.
So, in Emacs So, what do you do is
in any Emacs buffer,
we
you can start to write Emacs code
anywhere, okay? But, typically, you open
a new buffer
you open a new empty buffer. That's too
big, okay? That's
Hold on a second.
So, in general, let's let's just do
this. Plus two three, okay? Evaluate it.
You can see
that's the answer, five. So, we just
typed some Emac Lisp code and evaluated
it. And you can also do it here in any
buffer. Any buffer you can you can just
type start to type Emac Lisp code, and
you call a function, and you can see the
bottom is your your result, okay? So,
you can see the command I called is eval
last sex.
Okay, sex stand for
this word S-E-X-P stand for symbolic
expression, okay? That's that's a
tradition of Lisp name. Symbolic
expression, that's what this syntax is
called, okay? So, you can you can start
to type, you know, just usually you open
a new file and you can do it.
Okay, so what
Okay, so the Yeah, so that's how you
start to
type Emac Lisp. And now, let me show
you. So, Emac Lisp the whole language
syntax is uniform, okay? Unlike Python,
C, Java, JavaScript, or Ruby, or PHP,
any other languages. You know, the
syntax like each each construct have a
different syntax. You have to learn it
learn it. So, for loop has a particular
syntax, while loop,
you know, you have a different syntax.
You have parenthesis in somewhere else.
Then, variable assignment, you have a
different syntax. You know, that's most
languages are like that, but in Lisp
languages,
everything you see everything you see is
basically parenthesized form, okay? Like
that.
Okay, I need to go faster because this
way we're going to not going to
go anywhere. So, for example, you have a
Now, you have a nested expression, okay?
So, if you evaluate this one, you see
the answer is six because you are doing
three plus one, then plus two, okay? So,
in Emac Lisp, everything is an
expression.
Okay, so maybe actually should we write
it down? Okay, so maybe let's write it
down.
Everything is a expression.
No
statements, okay? In other languages,
you have things like statements, and
sometimes you have statements,
expressions different. Sometimes you
have directives, which is another thing.
For example, in JavaScript,
in JavaScript, you have
you have this string use strict. That's
That's a directive that's called a
directive because that changes the
language's interpretation, you know? So,
no
In Emac Lisp, everything is an
expression. No exceptions, and no
statements, no directives,
no anything else, okay? So, that makes
it simple, uniform. So, So, Emac Lisp
Lisp family of languages is such that
you learn one concept, it applies to the
whole language. So, there are only, you
know,
uh handful of concept you have to learn,
then you already know the entirety of
the
of the language, okay? That's a Lisp,
including Emac Lisp, okay?
So, everything is an expression. So,
what does that mean? That means
everything returns a value. So, for
example, this two is an expression, this
three is an expression, this whole thing
is an expression. You can call it
compound expression, you know? So,
everything is an expression. Okay, then
So, let me tell you about atomic
expression. So, this two, for example,
that's an expression, too.
That's This expression is called atomic
expression because it's an expression
that cannot be taken apart. That's
the kind of the smallest expression
possible. So, you can also evaluate this
one. For example, I can call just like
before eval last sex. So, you can see
the answer in the mini buffer, too,
okay? Now, let me tell you in Emacs
Lisp, everything is
you know, for beginners, everything is
printed into the a buffer. Every output
is printed into a buffer called the
messages buffer. So, you can see the
name here. So, you can switch to that
the messages buffer by
by control H E. Okay? That's how we do
it. So, for example, let's do it again.
Control H E. So, that pops up this
messages buffer, and you can expand it.
So, every output will be there. Okay?
So, you have to know this.
Okay, so everything is an expression.
Then, you have atomic
expression, which is expressions that
cannot that cannot be taken apart. Then,
you have more compound. Compound
expression is always nested parenthesis,
okay?
Now, that's it. That's essentially all
syntax you need to know about Emacs
Lisp.
So, again, let me show you some
uh let me show you some Emacs Lisp Lisp
source code. For example, you see this
this
uh my HTML mode, okay? So, HTML mode,
which is 5,000 lines. You see all the
parenthesis. All those are expressions.
So, what does the expression mean?
Expression, again, it means it returns a
value.
You know, unlike some other languages,
Python, you know, X maybe not Python in
other many in C, for example,
X equals to three, that's a statement,
and it doesn't return anything. You
know, or maybe you call it void. You
know, there's nothing like that in you
know, in Emacs Lisp, everything is
expression, okay?
So, make sure I'm
on the page with you guys. So,
everything is good.
Okay, so everything is expression. So,
let's go back to next we we need to go
much faster.
Um
Okay, so but they are
they are like a five exceptions.
Okay, so how do you do comment in Emacs
Lisp? Comment is
uh wait.
Comment is that, okay? Comment is the
semicolon to the end of the line. This
is a comment, okay?
So,
so now there's a question. Now, this
apparently this syntax for comment is
not
parenthesized.
So, you know, it's like, "Oh, this is a
new syntax I have to learn." Yeah,
that's true. So, but so there are few,
you know, maybe five a total of five or
so
uh special syntax. Comment is one of
them. And but usually you don't have to
worry about it. For example, another
another one is this uh apostrophe,
which stand for
uh let me just go over, okay? So, this
is not
uh critical, you know, you you will know
it once you get to know Emacs Lisp.
So, for example, this line is equivalent
to that
to this line, okay? Quote something
something.
But, however, this you have a special
syntax of a quote in front, you know,
that's a special syntax. They are only
five or so of them.
But, the all the rest are just either
parenthesis or just atomic, okay?
Okay,
so let me so let's move on. So,
text Okay, so text processing,
everything is expression.
Syntax shortcuts, yeah, so there are a
few exceptions, but you don't have to
worry about them, you know, when you
start to learn Emacs Lisp. You you know,
okay. So,
um
yeah, so let me cover how to evaluate
code.
Actually, we did before. So,
there are many ways, okay? You can also
evaluate a file, you know, you can say,
for example, load. You know, meta X load
load file, okay? Then, Emacs will ask
you to
uh type of file path for Emacs Lisp
file, you know, a script.
So, cancel that. So, there are many
ways. So, again, in my tutorial, it's
everything is covered here, okay?
How to evaluate Emacs Lisp code.
And the two most important thing you
want to know is this one,
eval-last-sexp.
That's the most convenient.
Uh and what you do is you move the
cursor to the end of the expression,
then just call it. For example, let's
let's say I want to evaluate that. I can
put the cursor here or here or anywhere
here, you know, just after it. So, I
just do it.
Uh control X E, that's the default key.
Oh, okay, I removed it. Okay, so let me
just use C-a I'm using C-a by key. So,
anyway, let me do it. So, you see five.
So, show the messages buffer, you see
five. That's the result.
Okay, and uh the and again, the you see
the command is that, eval-last-sexp.
Okay, that's one of the most important
command to evaluate
Emacs Lisp code. The other one is called
uh
eval-region. So, for example, if you
want to evaluate this part and this
part, you select select them first, then
you meta X eval
region, okay? Do it.
Then, you can go to the messages buffer,
and when you eval-region, it doesn't
show the output. I don't think so. So,
let's
yeah, I don't think so. So, eval-region
again, yeah, when you eval the region,
it doesn't show the output.
But, you told Emacs, you know, Emacs has
already evaluated them, okay? So, that's
how you evaluate Emacs Lisp code.
Uh okay, so let's go let's see next
what's next.
Okay, so basically that's you know,
that's the beginners introduction.
So, we covered So, we covered comments
and let me show you So, you know, I hope
you guys, you know, after so far, I hope
you guys already know you can start to
code Emacs Lisp already, you know, like
you know, I hope you guys, you know,
take this seriously. So, you can start
to code it.
You can already
from what we covered, you can already
start to code Emacs Lisp, you know, try
try
try to do some arithmetics, okay?
And uh we covered comments, we covered
how to evaluate Emacs Lisp code, we
covered the basic syntax of Emacs Lisp,
okay? That's that's a lot, you know. We
are already beginning
uh Emacs
experts.
I power drink with some lime soda.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, it's very hot today. It's uh
California
heat wave today. Okay, so what we going
to do for the rest of about the rest of
the um another 30 minutes is cover all
the language details, like
Okay, so we covered comments. How do you
print? So,
okay, let me show you. How do you print?
So, the again, there are many ways to
print. There's insert, there's messages
function, there's print.
Okay?
Before we go further, let me tell you,
you know, so syntax is all parenthesis,
right? And with the way you evaluate
something is always always a function
call.
So, in Lisp,
when you you know, the syntax is always
F um
F
A B C. Uh
something like that. And the way you do
computation, the computational model of
Lisp is always a function call. So,
there is no
for loop, you know, you know, for loop
in C, in JavaScript, you have a special
syntax, and it does it's not a function,
you know, but in Emacs Lisp, everything
is of this form, parenthesis, function
name, and arguments, okay? Parameters. A
function call. That's how you do
computation. That's the computation
model of Lisp languages in general.
Okay, so this is So, you the input are
the parameters, the the arguments. You
pass whatever data you want to change,
then you call the function. The function
you know, outputs some value,
a new value. So, this is how you do
computation in Lisp, okay?
In Emacs Lisp, in Common Lisp, in Scheme
Lisp, in Racket, in Closure, this is the
computational model. Very simple.
There's nothing else. There's no special
thing. There's no iterators, you know,
there's no generators that return
something mysterious that
you know,
no such thing. Everything is just a
value, function call, input, output,
okay?
So, function. Okay, so now
So, how do you print? The you know, most
important thing every language, okay?
So, so there are many ways. Again, a
function call. So, you call messages,
okay? A string, okay?
Hello hello world.
Factorial, okay? You can function of a I
mean,
so this is how you print. So, let's
evaluate it. Let's show the pink window.
Evaluate it, you can see the bottom.
That's the output, okay? So, let me show
you.
You see there.
So, this is um
how you print. The most frequently
uh used version, okay? There are other
ways, but we are not going to go over.
Okay, let me go show you another one.
The other way is insert, Okay.
Insert when you call it, it will just
insert the string into the buffer.
Wherever it is. Okay, so for example,
let's evaluate this. Okay, there it is.
Okay, let's try let's try something
something more fancy.
And uh
backslash n for new line.
Okay. Okay, now let's delete that
evaluate this. Okay, let's insert. So
this is how you print message and insert
most important.
Okay.
Now let's go back. Okay, so now string
string very simple in Emacs Lisp.
Uh again in Python, in Ruby, in you
know, in in other languages you have
double quote, you might have single
quote.
Uh
you know, and and uh in in in Python for
example, you have triple quote. And in
Python you have
Okay, let's
let's go over these. Then you have a
triple single quote. You know, that's
the Python case. In JavaScript, then in
JavaScript you have these
template quote.
Okay,
different syntax. So in Emacs Lisp,
there's only one
uh quote creating string quote syntax,
double quote. Okay, nothing else. Okay.
So let's see that. Okay, let's leave
them there. So for um
Okay, just just just double quote. Okay,
and uh here is how you get the length of
the string. So let's magnify. So this is
again, remember everything is a value,
everything is a expression in Lisp.
Everything is a expression, and the only
way you do computation, the
computational model of this is call a
function.
Give it input and get output to change
the value. That's how you do
computation. So right now we want to um
get the length of a string. What to do?
A function.
Okay, there for example, length ABC.
Now show the pink window and evaluate
it. You can see three at the bottom.
Okay, because you got three characters.
And uh okay, and this can be
can have Unicode characters. Okay, let's
you know, for example,
let's say that one. Okay.
Can Okay, so evaluate it, you can see
character one because you have one
character. So you can have Unicode, too.
It work. In JavaScript, in Java, you'll
get two. You know, that's because
very complicated Unicode UTF-16
encoding, you know, because you are not
actually
Anyway, so
Emacs Lisp. Okay.
String. So
So now you know how to create a string.
And uh everything and because everything
you do, everything is a expression, and
the any time you do want to do some
computation, it's always a function
call. So now you already know everything
you need to know about manipulating
string.
Almost in in this.
That's that's that's basically
everything. Okay.
So everything so so then of course that
yeah, so you have some escape. For
example, how do you have a double quote
inside the string? So you need to escape
it. You know, that's that's a
fundamental. So you and how do you uh
include a new line?
So that's how you do them. Okay.
But other than that, so there's you
know, there are there are some detailed
complexities. For example, how do you
how do you include a Unicode or emoji,
but without literal emoji? Sometimes
that's needed because for some
characters that's invisible. For
example, uh
uh unbreakable line break.
Uh for example, there's this character
in Unicode called
uh
non-breaking space. Okay, for let me
show you. Okay, so you can see
you cannot see it. You know, in Emacs it
shows a tiny underbar to indicate
there's a character. But now you can
call describe-char. Okay, let's call
describe-char. So you can see
So you can see the code the the name is
no-breaking space. So So that is used as
a space, but it indicates to the editor
or browser or whatever to not
not have a line wrap. You know, anyway,
so that's a invisible kind of invisible
Unicode. So for those characters,
sometimes you need to
um
you need to uh
use a you know, the ID for the character
instead instead of the literal. But
anyway, that's a detail. Okay, you won't
most of the time you won't need need
this. Anyway, let's get back to string.
So
So string so string so string functions,
that's the most important. So you know,
you we already showed length. You here's
how you get substring.
Here is how you join string, concat.
Here is how you split string, uh turn a
string into a list. Okay.
And and there are many others. There are
also regular expressions and so on.
Okay. But the thing I want to say again
everything is a expression.
And in this there's only one way to
quote string, double quote. Okay.
So
So anything everything you need to do
with string is just a function call. So
we have a list of all string functions
here. That's this page contains them
all. That's there there are about 20 of
them. Okay.
So let me show you a few. Let's show a
few. Okay, so
so length so
um
Let's let's comment it out those those
Python and JavaScript things.
Uh let's write it out. This is
JavaScript
template quote. Okay, there's something
like that.
I have a tutorial on that. I have By the
way, I also Okay, let me mention I have
um
So if you are new to my videos, I have
you know, I write tutorials. That's my
hobby. That's my obsession. Programming
languages, study of design of
programming languages is my hobby. In
particular, the syntax of programming
language design. So I have tutorials for
beginners or even for advanced people,
advanced programmers. Uh all the
tutorials for different languages. You
know, Lisp full form language, HTML,
CSS, JavaScript, SVG, and so on.
PowerShell and Python and Go lang.
Um and uh so
So yeah, so I have a um tutorial on all
of these in detail if you want to read
them.
Uh so Okay, so here are some uh example
of strings in different languages. So
here is how you print. Uh what's next?
Okay, so let's go let's move on to uh
next. So string substring. Let me show
you how to do substring example. Okay.
Substring.
Uh move the comment and and print to the
top. Okay, so so some evaluations there.
Okay, let's go here and save this file.
Let's save it xx today's date.el.
By the way, the Emacs Lisp file name
extension is .el.
So if you want to save it, name it
something something.el.
Okay.
Okay, so now we save this file. Yeah,
substring. So
substring.
Uh
Uh I have a shortcut.
Okay, yeah, there. So substring. So here
is the syntax.
Okay.
What about how do you look up the
documentation for a function? For
example, substring. For if you are not,
you know, right now I'm using Emacs Lisp
mode, my own customized
major mode in Emacs for coding Emacs
Lisp. But there's a building Emacs Lisp
modes. Okay. So if you want to So I want
to So you know, I learned yeah, I can
use substring, but what is the syntax?
What is the argument? So you can So So
what you want to do is
describe-function.
Meta-x describe-function. So the
shortcut is control h.
f.
Okay, so it asks you for
describe-function and default to
substring because the cursor is on it.
So enter. So here is the in the
documentation for and the syntax for
this function. Uh let me shut down my
phone alarm. Okay. Okay.
Okay, never mind. My phone alarm is uh
on.
Uh okay, so we have a lot to cover. Uh
if you are on Saturday Discord, I can
send you. Okay, yeah.
Uh thank you, guys. So
Okay, so so substring. So So how do you
use it? So let let's demo. Okay,
substring a string. Okay, let's say
ABCDEFG.
From let's say from the first character
uh two is optional, so we don't need it.
That means from the first character to
the end. Evaluate it.
What? Wrong type argument integer one.
Okay, the second argument Sorry. Okay,
so here is a example of syntax error or
some error. So,
you you So, when you see it next time,
you know, okay? So, you all you have to
do is just,
you know,
type Q to
to uh cancel that. So, because the
second second argument here should be a
number, not a string, okay? So, let's uh
give it a number.
One, okay? Now, let's evaluate it.
Okay, so you can see in the mini buffer
that's a So, let's go show. You see?
It's It says b c d e f. So, the one is
gone. So, that's how you do it, okay?
Let's do another example.
Let's say three.
And let's eval. So, you can see now it
is d e f g. And let's do another
example.
This time,
uh you know, just to show some Emacs
Lisp coding. So, we want to check if
they are equal. So,
uh
d e f g. So, now we are checking if this
two this evaluate to that. Okay,
evaluate it.
T, okay? So, you can see to go to the
mini buffer, you can see T means true,
okay?
So, we covered string we covered string
and uh format string we're going to
skip, okay? Okay, format string
format string is a very frequently used
function. So, actually So, let's show
it.
So, hello, we already showed this. So,
you know, that prints hello. But, you
can If you have some arguments,
uh let's say 34, okay? So, hello, I have
something as cats.
Evaluate it. You can see the output is
hello, I have 34 cats. So, this is how
you
So, this is a uh template kind of. So,
this means you have a
you want to turn something into a string
and you put the argument there, okay?
So, that's the
that's the format function. Okay? And
And if you want to see the doc, again,
describe function, okay?
There it is.
Describe function. So, it shows uh it
shows what
uh
Hold on a second.
Yeah, so it shows the inline
documentation for this function with
full explanation
of what S means, you know, percentage S,
percentage, you know.
Okay.
So, that's format string important. So,
arithmetics, let's skip. So, it's you
know, very simple. Plus for addition,
minus for subtraction, okay? And then
you have multiplication and division.
Okay, that's uh
arithmetics.
Now, now let me uh pay attention to this
one, okay? So, um yeah, here. So, if you
divide two integers, 7 / 2, you'll get
three because
not 3.5 because integer, you know,
because
when both of them are integers, it
returns the integer, okay? So, this is
something you might have to watch out.
You know, in Python 2, it's similar.
But, in Python 3,
they changed it.
You know, they change it to
automatically return a
floating point, you know, 3.5, 7 / 2.
Because this default behavior is quite
quite uh unintuitive, you know, and uh
two people.
So, anyway, arithmetics in Emacs Lisp,
okay? Converting int to float.
Okay, this is how you convert a number a
integer or floating number, decimal
number to
uh a string. So, this is how you do it.
So, you call the function string to
number and number to string.
Okay, we can
you know, we don't need to demo it, but
Okay, so let's show the message buffer.
Watch it here. So, I evaluated you can
see it's three. You see? Now, originally
it's a string. Now, it's a number. Now,
in this case, I evaluated you can see
now it's a string. Okay, so
string to number, number to string. That
That converts string to number. Or, you
can use format. Format will convert a
Let me show you, okay?
Format will let you convert a number to
string, you know, do it. Same thing. You
see? 34 is a number. The output is a
string, okay?
So, let's So, we covered string um then
Okay, boolean. Boolean.
Now, boo
boolean uh
Yeah, okay, let's talk about boolean.
But, let let me first of all talk about
the types in Lisp, okay?
For example, many uh languages such as
Java, C,
C++,
C#, you know, and Haskell,
each
value has a strict type, you know, for
you know, typically int, float, double,
long, things like that.
Now, in Emacs Lisp, you also have those
types, but they are not so significant.
So, like if you For the first year
coding Emacs Lisp, like you don't have
to really know about them, okay? You
just just be aware that
that integer int and float are different
types. For example, we have
demonstrated. For For example, let's
let's do it.
7 / 2, okay? Evaluate it.
It's three.
Okay? Now, let's try again. 7 7 / 2.
Evaluate it.
Okay, you have to
point is not enough. You have to say
2.0. That makes it a
uh
float type, okay? So, if you do it,
evaluate it. 3.5, you see? So, why is it
different? Because Emacs Lisp actually
have a data type concept. So, because
the two is in int type and the 2.0
is a float type. So,
So, that's why you get different
results. So, Emacs So, the point is that
Emacs Lisp do have the concept of types.
But, it's not
you know, other than knowing int and
float and other than knowing these
cases, almost just one or two cases like
I just showed you.
You usually don't have to worry about
it, okay?
Like converting string to number two.
Yeah, so usually you don't have to worry
about it.
So, I'm going I'm not going I'm not
covering them because usually
you know, it's not something you have to
specifically specifically to spend time
to learn it.
You will just come to You will just know
it, okay? Then, when you need to, you
can uh always go to the Lisp reference.
For example, let's click on arithmetics.
Then, there's a
uh
link to the Emacs Lisp manual, which is
1,000 pages, okay? More than 1,000 pages
if you print it out, you know, it's a
thick book.
So, here they will tell you uh
the details about the number types and
whatever types. Usually, it's uh hard to
understand.
So, you have integer basics, you know,
you can see, you know, lots of um
So, you have integer basics, you have
floating point basics, you know, then
you it mentions IEEE standard 754-2019.
Then, you have
types like double and you know, it
mentions C data type double and yeah.
You know, don't worry about them. You
know, if you want to get get on, you
know. So, my goal I hope to show you
that is that you can learn Emacs Lisp
and be productive be productive.
You know, you could learn Emacs Lisp for
the sake of programming language study.
Yeah, that's one thing. That's good.
But,
if you want to do that, your time is
better spent on Haskell, okay? Haskell
or Camel.
Uh
Erlang.
Uh you know, those kind of languages or
Common Lisp or or Racket Lisp, okay? You
don't You don't do that in
For Emacs Lisp, your goal is to
be able to start to write your own
custom functions for Emacs Lisp. So,
you'll enhance your
uh Emacs using capabilities. You can do
lots of things custom, you know, only to
you is useful.
That's the goal, okay? So, don't worry
about the little details. You You will
learn them uh
eventually.
If you uh keep at it. Okay? So far, so
good? Am I doing good? Give me a high.
Give me a high five or something. Seven
people watching.
I hope I'm not too slow, okay? So, 50
minutes. Um okay, let's go on. So,
there's few more things we're going to
1 hour today.
Okay, so uh string arithmetics uh
So, boolean. So, boolean type. So, in
Emacs Lisp, you don't actually have a
type that's boolean. You know, boolean
means true and false.
So, instead So, you don't have a
dedicated type of that. Instead,
in Emacs Lisp, just remember
this value, there's a special value
literal called nil, okay?
This value is false.
Anything else is true. But, also this
value is equivalent to a empty list,
okay?
Uh empty list. We we haven't covered
list yet, but we are covered. But
anyway, just remember these two are
same, okay? So, for example, we can type
equal empty list.
You know, versus nil and evaluated, you
can see it returns T. T means true. So,
remember nil is false.
And empty list is equivalent to nil. So,
empty list is also false. And by the
way, another way
to write the syntax for empty list is
this, okay? It's apostrophe parentheses.
That's equivalent to this
empty list, okay? So, if you evaluate if
we evaluate this,
it's also true. You can see in the mini
you can see in the mini buffer, okay?
It's also true. So, so nil and empty
list, that's false.
Anything else is true, okay? Just
remember that.
There's no delegate dedicated boolean
type in the Emacs Lisp, but you know,
true or false is determined this way,
okay?
That's about it. So, but what So,
and so, let me tell you what is nil,
okay? So, nil
nil is a variable and the value of this
it's a building variable, meaning that
by default it's already there.
And the value of this variable is a
symbol called nil, okay?
Now,
symbol is a special thing in Emacs Lisp.
Again, for beginners,
uh you don't have don't worry about it
too much, okay? Just just know that
there's a thing called symbol. Maybe
we'll cover it today.
So, nil is a building variable.
Sometimes it's called automatic
variable. Anyway, it's building it's
it's it's already there. And the value
of nil is the
the symbol nil.
Essentially, it just means false, okay?
That's that's all it matters, okay? It
just false.
So, you can use either one of them. So,
for example, we can also do
nil equals to nil. Is that true or not?
True, you see? It's just the same thing.
Okay? And the
So, nil is false, okay? That's just a
building variable. And true, anything
else is true. So, how do you represent
true? For example, one is true. For
let's say
uh let's say two, okay?
Uh let's say and, okay? So, in Emacs,
and is a logical and, okay? So, for
example,
nil and three
returns true because one of them is
true. So, let's evaluate it.
Wait.
Oh, yeah. Oh, so you have to say or
uh
or
Okay, evaluate it. You can you can see
the result is three, meaning it's true.
So, um
Anyway, nil is false. Anything else is
true, okay? Nil and the empty
list is false, okay?
Now, so
but by by convention,
when you want something to be true,
usually you use a symbol T, okay? Again,
T let me show you, okay? T or T so,
okay? Let me show you this.
Okay? This thing, okay?
T
is a building variable and the value of
that building variable is just a symbol
apostrophe T. You know, it's just a
symbol T. So,
it just means true, okay? That's it.
That's all. That's all. That So, by
convention, this T is used for true.
Okay, that's that's all about it.
So, empty empty vector, empty string
and the value is zero, they are they all
return true, okay? Let me show you.
Uh actually uh we should go faster,
okay? So, for example, evaluate it, you
know, so
evaluate that one, yes. Evaluate that
one, yes. Evaluate that one, so we got a
bunch of yes yes four times, you see?
Okay, so that's true and false. And then
and then you have comparison of numbers
greater than uh less than, that's how
you do it. And greater or equal,
okay?
Uh
then test equality.
Okay, this is also
slightly tricky, okay? There are many
functions that test equality.
So, if you have two numbers,
you want to use a equal sign to compare
them, okay? So, if they are
the same, it returns T. T means true.
So, you can also use them to compare to
test equality between an integer type
and a float type, you know, three and
3.0.
It's also true.
Uh and if you have strings, you can use
string equal to test equality.
Uh and otherwise, you can use equal to
test equality. That
So, this is the most frequently used
function to test equality is the equal
function, okay?
Um because it covers various different
types of data.
Then you have something more
uh advanced, EQ and EQL.
We are not going to cover them today.
Usually you you know, you almost never
need to use it
until after maybe, you know, um
until 1 year of Emacs Lisp coding or
something.
Okay, so anyway,
for numbers, use the equal sign. For
strings, use string equal. And for
anything else, generic generic, just use
equal to test equality.
Okay?
Uh variables, okay? So,
uh God, it's already 1 hour. It's kind
of too slow. I think we are going too
slow.
Um
So, we covered equality. We covered um
Okay,
let's talk about if then else, okay? So,
here's a basic syntax for if expression.
Uh so, yeah, we already, you know,
showed many of them.
So, uh let me talk about so
let's talk about variables, okay?
Variables, so
So, in very uh in Emacs Lisp, you do not
have to declare a variable. You can use
uh a variable right away. And to assign
a variable, just say setq x 3, okay?
Evaluate it. Okay, that's three. That's
good. Now, if you type x and evaluate
it, three. So, we got
x.
You know, x value is now three. And now
we can do equal x three. Evaluate it,
true.
Okay? So, this is how you set a
variable. And
and variables by default, if you do it
this way, it's always global, okay?
That's always global. Know, you know,
globally known in every buffer.
Okay, let's close that. Let's go back
here.
Uh
Yeah, so let's do it here.
Okay, so what else? So, that's variable.
Let's move on. So, what about local
variables, okay? Local variable, the way
you do it is you use the
let function, okay? So, that this is the
syntax. So, if you want x to be a local
variable, you put here. Then here you
put something something body, okay?
That's the
whatever this code here.
So, this variable x will be local to to
this parenthesized expression, okay? So,
for example, let's say message
x, okay? That will print x.
Do it.
Uh let's go to the mini buffer. Wait,
nil. Okay, nil because
Yeah, it's nil because globally x is
three, but locally,
you know, that's the local variable.
There's no value to it yet. So, that's
why it's
nil. But now you can set let's set x
equals to four, okay? Now, let's
evaluate this
block of expression. Do it.
You can see
it's four.
Now, but globally, it's still three.
Let's evaluate this expression, okay? Do
it.
You see? True.
So, that's local variable and global
variable. So, this is how you do local
variable. Let,
okay?
So, let's move on. So, there are some
variations of the syntax I won't cover
here, but not not now
uh because we got other things to do.
So, let me show you about this uh
a block of expressions.
So, if I have if
let's say if, okay?
Uh
let's say if x is greater than two,
okay? Then do something here. Else do
something here. You know,
so if x is equal than two, let's say
message
yes, bigger than two, okay?
Otherwise,
otherwise, let's say
no,
not bigger than two, okay?
Let's say no.
No, it
is smaller than two, okay?
Now, let's evaluate that.
You can see the answer is yes, it's
bigger than two.
Now, what if
if it's true, I want to do more than
more than that. I want to
I want to print something and I want to
insert
insert a text into my buffer, okay? So,
let's say
so I let's say insert, okay? insert
world
You know that we will insert
the world to my buffer. If we do it
here,
it doesn't work. Why? Because the first
expression is taken to be true, then do
this expression. Otherwise, this is
this will be done only when it's false.
You know, that's how the if statement
works.
Where is it?
You see, that's how if statement works.
It only basically only takes
uh three arguments, test, true body, and
false body.
So, if you So, well, my what I want to
do is that actually I just want to show
you this
p r o g n, okay? p r o g n construct,
okay? So, that will
cut that, put it here. Let's prettify,
okay? Now, you can see.
So, this p r o g n will group a bunch of
expressions into one as one single unit.
So, now, if I evaluate this if
expression, it works, okay? Let's do it.
You see? You see? It inserted world
here. You see? Because it evaluated this
whole expression, okay? So, this is that
is why you need this p r o g n grouping
of expressions.
Okay, so that is explained
block of expressions here.
So,
this p r o g n is most useful when you
have a expression. It's almost always
used inside
used inside the if statement if
expression, okay?
Okay, so
actually we got more to cover. So, let's
do 15 more minutes. We haven't covered
defining functions and we have to cover
some
uh some basic basic data Emacs Lisp data
structure. We're going to cover list and
vector, and that's it, okay? The others,
you don't have to worry about it. You
know, you can worry about them later.
So, we're going to cover list
and vector, then we're going to cover
defining a function, okay? Then lambda.
And that will be it. That That would be
it. That's all you need to know to begin
coding to be you know,
to you already know a lot. That's you
know, the fundamentals.
After we covered function and list,
okay? Let me have a drink. Have a minute
break.
Um
So, so far so good? Any questions?
Okay, there's a question. Can you say
about differences between lexical and
dynamic scope in Emacs Lisp?
Um
that question Okay, that question is
actually hard to explain. Um
but let me Okay, so let me explain. So,
So, let me put it here. So, um
that's lexical scope versus
Okay?
So,
let me explain that. Um this is actually
a little bit difficult to demonstrate.
But, I have some
thing interesting to tell you
that I think you will find it useful
because there's a lot misconceptions in
the
in the in particular in particularly in
the Lisp community about these things.
Okay, so first of all, let me tell you
that's an impractical question.
Useless.
Fairly impractical question, okay? It's
like this is one of the dramatic
question in programming languages. Very
dramatic. You'll see this thing, this
question, you know, why are they how do
are they different? What's the benefit?
What's the pros and cons? You know,
dynamic scope versus lexical scope
scope. You know, this is one of the one
one of the dramatic thing among
programming languages.
All the people will talk about it. But
actually, in practice, it's not a
question, okay? Either you your language
has one way, you stick with it, things
will be fine. Or your language doesn't
support one or the other, it things are
totally fine. I mean, it's not a
question
where
as a practical programmer or
professional programmer, you have to
ask about it. Like the the question
never comes up. Almost never come never
comes up.
Okay, so it's not it's not a practical
question, you know? I hope this is
something new
you know, I'm telling you. Because you
hear you If you are a beginner
programmer, you'll hear this all the
time. And then you'll hear people debate
debate about it. It's a dramatic
question. Why is it dramatic? Defined by
because it's a question that actually
never
comes up, okay? Unless when you are
designing the language.
Unless you are designing a programming
language, okay?
Now, the second the other thing I want
to talk about is that the um
If you are a functional programmer,
you'll never actually see any difference
between these two uh scopes. You'll
never actually see any difference at
all. If you are a functional If you
stick to a functional programming
principles, that means if you every your
function has no side effect, okay? And
you do not use closure, okay? Because
when you have a closure, your function
is no longer a function. Your function
has the possibility of side effects,
okay? So, don't use closure. You know,
closure is another dramatic thing. So,
anyway, I'm getting very
I'm getting quite um
out of out of scope for today's talk
because this is a fairly advanced topic,
okay? Let me get get back to practical.
So,
in Emacs Lisp,
before 2015 or so, everything is dynamic
scope, okay? But after 2015, they
introduced a
They introduced actually a directive,
okay? So, I made a mistake before. There
is a directive in Emacs Lisp, okay? So,
let me show you, okay?
Uh
So,
about 2015, in Emacs Lisp, every
variable is dynamic scope. But after
2015, I think it's 2000 maybe 2010,
okay? Then they introduced lexical
scope, but you have to specify it by
Let's go to the E Lisp file, okay? So,
you have to specify
what's the variable? Um Okay, let's go
to one of my packages. That's the
easiest way to find out, okay? Go to the
top, you can see. Close it. There it is.
There it is. You see that keyword? Um
There it is. You see? Lexical binding
true. So, that is a variable, okay? So,
let's put it here. So,
There. So, that's a variable. So, you
can now describe variable,
okay? Enter, then you'll see the
documentation for the variable lexical
binding, okay? So, basically this line
as a comma as as a comment at the
beginning of a Emacs Lisp file will tell
Emacs Lisp that for this whole file or
the Lisp code, they should be lexical
binding, not dynamic, okay? But
Okay, mostly. There are still some
exceptions that's always dynamic
binding, okay? Anyway, so you can see
the documentation. So,
so it says, you know, the value is nil
globally, you know, whether to use
lexical binding when evalu- evaluating
code. And then nil means that the code
in the current buffer should be
evaluated with lexical binding, okay?
This variable is a automatically set
from the file variables of an
interpreted Lisp file, blah blah blah.
Okay? So, anyway, you know, it doesn't
even explain it. But it's hard to
explain it because
uh basically lexical binding is
text-based
variable. So, that is what I like to
say, what you see is what you get.
That's lexical binding, and that's the
proper language design.
It is so. It speak It began the language
that began this lexical binding is
Scheme Lisp, okay?
Then other languages adopted Common
Lisp,
Emacs Lisp today eventually, you know?
But you have to say you have to put this
line at the beginning of your Lisp file,
okay? You Actually, I recommend it,
okay? Put this line in the beginning of
your file.
And so anyway, so
basically lexical binding Okay, let me
explain. Okay.
Uh you know, it's best if we actually
demonstrate their differences in code,
but it's
it's it's really hard to do. It's fairly
advanced. Okay.
Lex- lex- lexical scope
basically means
text-based variable scope.
Meaning
what you see is what you get. Okay.
that a variable scope is inside a
paren
inside a syntactic
unit of the language
such as paren
or bracket in C or JavaScript, you know,
so So, that's lexical binding. What you
see is what you get. Okay. So, for
example, let
So, for example, we have defined a
variable let here
that is
you know, if it's lexical scope, that
means whatever this X is does not escape
this parenthesis. Okay. That's lexical
scope.
Uh but
dynamic scope
is basically
a time-based scope. Okay. So, this this
is a time-based scope. Meaning that
the value of X a variable the value of X
a variable depends on
when it is wh- when when the value
changed last time. You know, it doesn't
depend on your
how your code looks
or the order of the text in your buffer.
It doesn't depend on that.
The order of you know, all the brackets,
the scope, the nesting of your source
code.
But rather it just depends on time. When
is something last
changed, you know, that value remains.
Okay.
So, that's what dynamic scope means.
And
um
you know, it it would be best to
actually demonstrate code to show their
difference, but that's difficult because
because that will involve some you know,
you you have to define a function, then
you have to let it leak.
So, basically, it's not a practical
question. Okay. So, if if you always
write your function, you should always
write your function such that it doesn't
have any side effect. That That is In
other words, your function the input
the output always depends on the input,
nothing else. The same input will
generate the same output. That's a
function without side effects.
For those functions, it is impossible
to have these dynamic scope or lexical
scope differences. It's impossible to to
have those differences. Okay. Always
just do that.
Okay, I'm not going to go through
uh it's hard to do so.
Okay.
Uh fantastic. Thank you.
Okay, so so so
So, okay. Another 10 minutes. So, we
kind of digressed. Let Let me show you
uh
list and vector. That's the most
important. Okay. So, So, now we covered
if then else. Okay, there's one more
thing, loop. Okay, this is This is how
you do a loop. In every language, you
have a loop construct. Okay.
Uh Okay, so how do you do a loop? Okay.
So, loop. So, the most common is while
loop. Okay. So
uh I have templates. Just don't Okay, so
here's test. Here's body. Okay, that's
how you do a loop.
So, let's test if uh let's say if
while
uh
while uh while let's put it here
less than while X
is less than
three.
Okay. Then body message
X. Okay. Then but we also want to
increase X. So, we can say set
X equals to
plus X one. Okay. That's one easy way to
do it.
Simple way to do it. Okay. So, we test
if X is less than three. If If so,
we print the value of X, then we add one
to X. Okay.
And uh we want to know what is the
current value of X. So, we can do that
by moving the cursor here and call eval
last expression. Okay, let's do it.
Three.
So, right now X is three.
Okay, so if we run this, it won't print
anything. Do it. Nil. Okay. So, we have
to say let's say nine. Okay.
Now, let's do it.
Okay, now let's look at the message
buffer. There it is. It print It prints
3 4 5 6 7 8. Okay.
So, this is the most fundamental loop
construct in Emacs Lisp. Okay. This is
the most basic one. There is no for loop
in Emacs Lisp. Basically, this is
it. Okay.
When you want a loop in Emacs Lisp.
Now
of course, there are other kind of kind
of equivalent uh ways to do a loop. Loop
for such as for map um and you can also
do uh two times.
Uh but we are not going to cover it.
Yeah, do listen two times. Okay, so
let's not let's let's skip them. Okay,
let's Now, let's talk about list. Okay,
list is a fundamental structure. So,
Lisp
uh stand for list processor. Okay.
The Lisp language.
Originally stand for
list
processor. Okay, that's what
L I S P stand for. So, that's why So,
all these are a list. So, that's why the
whole syntax is all parentheses. That's
That's a list or everything is a list.
So, the list is the most fundamental
data structure in Lisp. Okay. And the
way you do a you generate made a list is
this. Okay. This is a syntax.
Okay. That's a list. Simple enough.
Again, remember let me emphasize what we
covered before. Everything is a
expression. And the only way you do
computation
in Lisp the computational model of Lisp
is by calling a function.
So, we call a function. So, again, we
call a function um and uh
and you got 3 4 5. That's a list. That's
how you generate the list.
So, this is the syntax for list. Okay.
And you can you can nest them. For
example,
uh
that. Okay. Evaluated, you see, you got
a nested list. You can
you can nest them in any way.
Okay, so
So, that's the
Okay, I'm going to skip some other
things. Okay, so if you want to you
know, you can read my tutorial later for
for a bit more information, but I'm
going to skip lots of these things. So,
So, get a link So, the length
the count of elements is length. Okay.
So, for example, let's count this list.
Okay.
So, you see the result is three.
Um So, that's list. Okay. Now, once you
So, you already know how to do a list.
The the syntax. And then
then you again you call a function to
get
to do anything with it. So, for example,
you can get a sublist. You can get um
And here are examples. You can get You
can prepend. You can append. You can
join list. Okay, let me show you a a
few. Okay.
Uh
Okay, so here is a list. And here is
another list.
Uh let's say
A
B.
Okay. Now, let's say you want to join
them. Okay. So, you say concat.
I believe that's the function.
Uh append. Okay.
Okay, copy that.
Okay, so there. So, evaluated, you can
see here's the result. Okay, that's how
you join two lists. And then you can
take a sublist and other things. You can
take the first elements, the last
elements, and so on.
Uh and to check equality
Yeah, you can Okay, so you can use equal
to check if two lists have the same
number of element same items. Okay.
So, for example, um
Okay, let's copy that.
Uh E Q A L. Okay. Evaluated, you see, it
returns t for true.
Uh, and it can be nested, okay? So, for
example, let's see.
You see?
You see? The result is also true. Now,
this is not so for JavaScript.
When you have a nested list, there's no
way actually there's no way to test the
content of a list in JavaScript.
You have to write a function to do that.
So, uh, then you have other functions
like push, pop, okay? I'm not going to
cover Okay, so that's list, okay? Now,
let me tell you how to map a function to
list because this is important.
Uh, okay, so that's how you do it, okay?
So, so if you want to let's say you want
to add a number
add one to this list, okay? So, what you
do is you say map car
Okay?
You know, never mind the name. The name
is a bit weird because history.
Um,
but anyway, so you say map car
and the
and the the map car takes two arguments.
One is a function, one is the list,
okay? So, this part is the list and this
part is uh
let's say add one, okay? So, lambda is a
function.
And the now we want to add one. So, how
do you
So, we can say
uh
Okay? First x
one, okay? Now, if we evaluate this,
we're going to get
4 5 6, okay?
Do it. Uh,
do it.
You see?
Okay, that's that's how you map a
function to every element in a list.
Okay? So, that's it for that. Let's, you
know,
uh, I'm going to skip vector for now.
Now, vector is just like a list, okay?
Except that
the number of items is fixed. You cannot
add to it. So, it's similar to the
concept of tuple in Python. Okay, that's
that's what vector is.
Um,
Okay, so
So, let's Let me show you how to define
a function and that's it for today. Uh,
that's it for today.
Okay, I'm not going to cover symbols.
Okay, let let let's see. Any other
questions?
We're going to shut down in 5 minutes, I
think, okay? So, define a function. So,
you can
to define a function, you say defun,
okay? So, you say defun
Uh, basically, here is a basic template,
okay?
So, here first of all, you have a
function name, let's say ff, okay? Then
you have a parameter, let's say x.
Okay? Then you have docstring, excuse
me. Let's say uh,
let's say add one to
x, okay? Then let is again a local
variable definition we covered before.
And here, let's say x +
x one.
Uh, let's say add two to x, okay? So,
that's how you define a function. So,
now we have to evaluate this.
Do it.
Okay, so now Emacs knows about this
function. Now, we can call this function
ff
uh
three, okay? Let's evaluate it.
You can see the result is five.
Okay, I think that's that's how you
define a function.
And uh, I think you know, we have
covered all the fundamental elements of
Lisp, the language. And now you can, you
know, we covered Now, you can put them
together to create however arbitrarily
complex programs
because we already know how to do so. We
covered, you know, the
the comments, how do you add a comments,
how the basics of printing something, we
covered how to how to create a string,
and all the functions that manipulate
string.
Uh, we covered uh
then we have covered arithmetics.
We covered, you know, some basics of
value type in Emacs Lisp.
In particular, we have int, float, and
string.
Uh, then we covered boolean, you know,
nil is false, everything else is true.
We covered test equality.
We covered how to you how do you define
a variable, global variable, setq, and
local variable, let.
And we covered a block of expressions to
group them together
for the purpose
of if then else. This is uh,
conditional, you know, flow control, if
then else.
Critical in every programming language.
The most this this part, the if
statement or if expression
is the most fundamental
uh, construct and the most fundamental
concept in any programming language.
This This is prob- This
is the most because without this
basically, you fail Turing machine.
You don't have a transistor in a CPU.
So, if statement, okay? This that's
that's how you do.
And uh, okay, so then we also covered
how to do loop. The most basic in this
is while loop in Emacs Lisp, okay?
Then you have variations like do list
and do times.
Then we covered we covered list.
You know, the most fundamental data
structure in Emacs Lisp or any Lisp.
It's most fundamental because the very
name, programming language Lisp, means
list processing. So, in Lisp
everything you you're basically you are
just processing lists, okay? And
everything is a expression. Everything
has a value. And the only computation
the only way you do computation is by
calling a function, you know, a head of
a list to
to get its return value, okay? So, list
we covered the most fundamental data
structure.
Then you can have a lot of
you know, these are kind of details.
Then you can have lots of
functions
that manipulate list such as get a
sublist, get the first item, get the nth
item
uh, push an item to it
or take one item from the last from the
first element and remove it, things like
that, push and pop, very uh, frequently
used construct.
Uh, and lots of more, lots of, you know,
reverse a list, reverse list elements,
and check if a element exist, a value
exist in a list, things like that.
So, all these are list functions, okay?
Then uh, so we covered some of these. I
mean, well we covered the list concept.
Then we covered how to define a
function.
Okay? So, we, you know, this is the
skeleton of a function. The most
fundamental basic template. Then in the
body, you can put any code we covered
before, you know, the let variable
scope, you know, and you know
to create
arbitrary programs, okay?
That's defining a function.
Uh, we showed some, you know, we
demonstrated the use of lambda.
Then Okay, I think that's it for today.
Uh, so thank you guys for watching.
So,
So, when you use uh So, there's a
question. So, when you use um
when you use setq
uh, local variable inside a let
expression, does that create a global
variable? No. Okay, so let's go to it
and see, okay?
So, variable. So, when you have a let,
you know, whatever variable you declare
there, it's going to be local. So,
inside that So, the set the set
function just sets the value. It doesn't
actually create a variable. Well, I mean
I mean, tech- technically, it does not
actually create a variable.
Um,
yeah. The variable is created Let's see.
Let me try something.
Yeah, well
Anyway, that's kind of you know, the
some of the technical details, it takes
some time to explain. It's and it's hard
to explain, but in practice, you don't
have to worry about it. So, anyway, set
the you know, set just set the value,
but if if you use it outside of the let,
then it does create a variable.
Yeah, but it's not really the purpose,
you know, for example, it's not really
the purpose of set. For example, let's
look at the
uh, documentation for setq to see if it
actually
say uh, to see if it actually mention
it actually create a variable. Um
set
each symbol to the value. The symbols
seem are variables. They are literal,
okay? The value, yeah, they don't they
don't mention anything about creating a
global variable. That's just a side
effect. That's
Uh
Yeah.
Yeah, they don't they they didn't
mention about
about it creating a global variable, but
it actually does.
But that's not
its job.
Okay, so um
That's it. I think that's it.
Okay, so everything we talked about
today is already, you know, in my
tutorial, of course. If you like my
stuff, sponsor me, okay? Pay me. Buy my
tutorial as a donation. You get the
whole
you know, 7,000 700 pages of tutorial,
you know, on your hard drive, so.
Okay, that's it for today. 90 minutes.
Bye, guys.
Okay, there's a question about byte
compile list.
Okay, let me let me talk about that.
So So, let's look at our list code,
okay? So, we got a bunch of list code
here. That's what we talked talked
today. Some of them are just
not actually valid, for example, that
one because F is not defined. So, let's
comment those out
and comment those out. So, we are going
to create a valid Emacs Lisp file here.
Okay?
So, we're going to So, this is
this is a valid Emacs Lisp file. All
those are valid Emacs Lisp
code.
And all that all that all that all that,
okay? So, here's a valid
Lisp file. So, you can see
that's a file. We can compile it. So, in
Dired
So, let me let me show you. So,
you know, if you know Emacs, this is
Dired, okay? So, I can press capital B.
Then Emacs ask me, do you want to byte
compile it?
Yes. Yes. Type Y for yes, okay?
Then it gives gives me a bunch of
warnings.
Um
Okay.
Warning, value returned is not used.
Yeah, value returned is not used is not
used. Something something is not used is
not Yeah, because this this is kind of
silly
examples of tutorial. You we are not
actually
you know, the the code does not actually
do anything. It just return a value
that's never used. So, it gives you a
bunch of warnings
when you compile. Press B to compile in
Dired, okay? Or you can meta X and say
byte compile file, okay? Call that
command. Then you'll ask you to type a
file path.
Then you'll com- compile it, okay?
So, Emacs Lisp So, you have a byte you
can byte compile
the Emacs Lisp code. So, why do you need
to do that? You don't need to do that,
but if you do that, Emacs you can load
the byte byte compiled version.
And it will be faster, okay? Emacs will
be able to run it faster and also load
it faster.
Um
That's basically the only advantage,
okay? Other than that So, if you we can
open it, this is how it looks like.
It's, you know, it's a sequence of
bytes. So, this is intermediate code,
you know, the
in compu-
in computer science, you know, it's part
of it in in in in in in in in in in in
in in essence
the byte compiled file is a side effect
of computer
engineering, okay?
Mathematically
practically, you know, it's useless,
okay? Technically, you don't need it.
But however, it's because engineering
you have lots of technicalities and
details and the way to make things fast,
use less memory and so on. That's why
you have this intermediate concept of
byte compiled thing.
Which is a hindrance.
Technically, it's a hindrance. You
shouldn't have it.
But because of
you know, reality, the real world
situation, so you have the byte compiled
thing. So, you can byte compile any
Emacs Lisp source code to create a byte
compiled file and it will load faster
and run faster. Okay, that's it.
I think about five times, you know,
according to Emacs Lisp manual, which
haven't been updated for a long time, it
says like six times faster or something.
Um but um
Anyway, I'm not Yeah, anyway, that's it.
Bye, guys.
Buy my tutorial, okay?