Hello guys, good morning, good evening.
Welcome
uh to episode another episode of Star
Talk Show. Uh this is my keyboard
ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80
NIA trackboard. Okay, so let's start. We
we just going to code wam language
today. Okay. So, you're just going to
this is my work session on woofam
language and I'm just going to work on
my visual dictionary of special plane
curves uh elementary geometry. Okay,
this is like high school level geometry.
Uh so I created this 30 years ago and
I'm just going to update some of it
today. So my walking session okay if you
have questions about W language ask me
post your questions here if you are
watching this offline play 1.5 speed
okay so I want so let's go to so so I
got this I got this project so you can
see here is the this is the project lots
of plank curves very interesting lots of
animations illustration on how they work
and let's go to directory. Uh let's go
to the directory. So I wanted to find
all the old notebooks out there. Okay.
So let's see
PowerShell does. So I want to find all
the MB files, my old notebook files.
Um
yeah, let's see.
So again, this is my walking session.
Okay. So you probably get bored with it.
So this is just me doing random things.
So let's see. Okay.
So here are
here are the files of all the notebooks.
Um,
so I want them. Okay, so they are
actually all inside this MMA directory.
Fantastic. Okay, that's good to know.
So go to MMA directory. Okay, not
packages, but MMA. So they are all here.
So you can actually order them
uh by file size.
Uh
let's see what directory am I in. CD
MNA.
Duh. How do you order them by file size?
Actually I don't know.
Uh P shell. Can you actually do that?
list file by size
where object length. Okay. Yeah. So
that's how you do it.
Paste it.
Paste anyway.
Yeah, let's do it. No.
Okay. where object length less than 100.
Uh that's not
less than m bytes. Okay. So I want
actually sort by file size.
Uh so it is very annoying that in
powershell you don't have a easy way to
sort file. Uh this is how you do it.
Okay.
So actually so okay so you can do that.
Yeah you can do that.
So
okay. So anyway, so go here. Uh power
shall close. Uh so actually I can do
this in Emacs.
Yeah. Okay. So
let's see. Let's open one of them.
Continue with updated style. Okay. So
that's continue with updated style. So
let's say 150. So this is what is this
about costics.
So this this one is about creating
generating a movie of that in parallel.
So this is all the okay.
What do you want to do?
So you have Okay. So you have
uh
Okay. So they are not
Okay, we can do this one by one. Okay,
so let's uh let's just do that. You know
there's like so many to do. So you have
to just focus on something and start
somewhere. Hello Faren. Why you learn so
much stuff? Emac this wam JavaScript
Python if not even programmer. What are
you talking about? I am a programmer.
They've been programming professionally
since 1997
1998. Well, since actually 1995.
So anyway, so um
next next question. Okay. So uh so so we
we want to focus on
Okay. So so first of all, let's update
this image. Okay. So that cardiod image
that's a special plane curve
that's special case of the roulette
which is a special case of the
cyclloid curve. Okay. So, and which is a
uh this one. Uh
okay. So, so first of all, let's just
generate a better
um resolution picture of this. So, this
one is done 30 years ago. So, let's do
just that, which is from here. Okay. So,
you need
Okay. So, let's let's just start to do
it. Okay.
Go to talk show. Let's see. Okay. Go to
uh today's talk show and showing
browser. Okay. Go to section. Uh create
a new section link file at the bottom.
Okay. And uh let's go to uh it and uh
PNG. So here that is a picture. We want
a newer version of it. Uh so can we do
that? Yeah. Okay.
Uh you're going to start to put the code
here. And the wam language you don't
have um
well so this is the code. Okay. So let's
copy that.
I'm not sure I got the package loaded.
So we'll have to see. Uh
so let's see.
Uh
okay. So let's go to get uh curve plank
curve formulas plane curve generator. So
plank curve plot
that is the package and uh you can get
this package
just go to my website. Okay.
Uh,
for example, you go to uh sardi.info
and uh and go down. You go to you
there's a woofam language tutorial and
here is where you download wam language
and uh complete tutorial for
programmers. Okay. And uh you can get
all my packages. Uh just follow wam
language tutorials by video. I have over
100 videos open language mode that's for
Emacs. Uh and let's go back and open
package by XR. So all those images you
see they are all in these packages.
Okay. So you can download and they are
on GitHub. So if you click them you see
download on GitHub. Okay. So you can
download Wam language. can download my
packages and you can you you will have
all these uh all these you know easy
code to plot all these. So anyway so
plinker plot so this is called plur
plot. Okay so I wanted to go back to um
lots of things to do. Yeah. So
and then you need also a formula there.
So that is from uh the other package
planker formulas. Okay. But here you
just want to um
actually let's just try it here
if that works.
Uh
shift enter.
No, it does not because
um
do I have power plot loaded? Hip enter.
No,
I thought I have. Okay.
Okay. Let's go to my git. Let's go to
Wait, put it back. Let's go to my g
directory. Go up curve formulas. So, we
need one of these formulas and we need a
generator.
But um so let's go to my wam language um
tutorial. I want to know where is the
wam language init file because I thought
I have um wam language init file. So you
look at wam language tutorial function
comment string. So wam language for
programmers you want to let's search for
init file init
library. So you need to uh use a base
directory directory path for user files.
That's what you want. Let's see what you
get.
Okay. Shift enter. Okay. So, it's on
Windows. It's in this wrong main
directory. So, magnify. Let's save this
in the untitled one desktop. Okay.
Untitled uh
X
whatever.
So app data roaming wam desktop. So
let's go to there
and you can just um
stupid windows. So you got this app data
roaming. Okay. and wam.
Well, okay. So, let's just go there.
Okay, it's not that warm desktop. So,
there is your init file just like Emacs.
Okay, so then you need to go to
autoload. Okay, let's see package
manager config front end. No, no, no,
no, no. Close applications packages. Uh,
yeah. So, those are my packages. So you
can see we got planker
plot and planker formulas. So we have
both of them. So why is that?
Why is that? Like my wolf language is
not loading them.
[ __ ]
Okay. Did I have um
let's see plank curve plot?
Yeah, maybe I didn't have the alias.
No,
that's
Oh, because you didn't load them.
Is it because you didn't? Yeah, you
did they do they autoload or not? Maybe
not. Okay, so you need to say you need
to like load them.
So how do you load them? Load the
package get. Okay, so check here. You
can use get or you can use needs context
name. Okay, let's use the needs context
name. Yeah, that's what I want. So go
back here. Uh
paste needs plank plot. Shift enter.
Okay. In multiple contexts. Yeah, that's
right. Because we already loaded, you
know, by mistake. Uh I mean,
you know, the what the message means is
is that we run this code before and so
this name parplot is already part of the
global name. So but now you load a
package which contains the power plot.
So so the global name will shadow uh
actually so you know one of them will
shadow the other.
So planker plot and global you see so
this name plank plot is in both the
context plank plot and also in global
context. Context is just name space.
Okay. in in in Java you have like
like something com something something
you know that's a name space um
in common list you have similar okay so
so basically anyway
so let's just try this let's see which
name space is this okay pl so that is
that works but except now except this
cardioid
you see now this works Now, but now we
need to load the formula. Okay. So, you
need to uh load the plank of formula.
So,
close close.
Do do we have it? Applications. Yeah,
planker formulas. Okay. So, you just
need to say,
do I make sense? You know, this is like
just coding. So, you guys probably don't
know. um needs
uh that okay so
that is what we need okay so here needs
planker plot so paste that shift enter
appear in multiple context that's right
now we go back here and shift enter now
it's Beautiful.
Finally takes a you know I because I
haven't I haven't worked on this for a
while. So we run into the issue of
loading the package then eventually we
load it. So so now this is a high
resolution quality 30 years difference
uh from from this little image. You
know, back then you don't want big
images because then people have to wait
for for the internet. Uh but today the
internet is like 100 times faster than
30 years ago something like that.
So like before you you can't have you
know set more than few images on a web
page. So we want this. So you know we
can uh actually just uh uh save this um
save graphic as PDF. No, we want to save
as PNG. Okay. Uh what
there are many ways. Okay. Save graphics
as uh
yeah, you can do that. Okay. So, you can
you you can save that as PNG.
Uh, let's see. Where is this X?
Stupid Windows
X.png. Okay.
Uh,
that's one way to do it. Another uh and
you go to desktop.
Um,
you go to desktop x.png.
There it is. Okay. Uh, okay. So, let's
just copy that. Close. Close. And go to
here. Paste it. Linkify showing browser.
Fantastic. We got the picture. But now
error. Um yeah there's error because
because because all these uh you need to
encode those ampers greater than sign.
So you need to do that. Okay but anyway
so we need to change the file path. Move
this image file into the current
directory. So let's do that.
Press press press.
Okay. Yeah. Move that into the current
directory. And uh let's name it cardio
by tangent. Okay. Rename the file cardio
by tangent. There is naming convention
changes after 30 years. So let's just
rename the full
um
like that. Okay. So
okay. So now show in browser. So that's
much better. Then we need to delete this
old um this this old. So
copy the file path, search for it,
search all directory in si info. Let's
see if it shows up somewhere. Then if
not, then you can safely delete it. So
we basically update it in one image.
Okay. So ACP says so today is a Super
Bowl. Oh,
I didn't know today Super Bowl is is
today's Super Bowl. I, you know,
[laughter]
I never watched football in my life. The
American, you know, the American Rambo,
you know, the like the American is like
the the Super Bowl, the the
uh Super Bowl. Oh, there it is. Super
Bowl.
You know the Super Bowl of American is
represents the like the brainless wrong
uh sports like whoever is the bigger
monkey, the bigger bamboo wins. That's
basically that's like the spirit of the
Super Bowl. Okay. Oh, you don't want my
name there.
So, I'm sorry. Uh I never you know I I I
find this this uh this this American
call it football which [laughter]
is not football. Football is what
American would call soccer. Okay. But
American has you know has this kind of
thing. Um, Rambo. This is like whoever
who can who is the bigger
uh what?
So they have like like halftime show.
Another quite idiotic and very American
uh thing that they call it halftime
show.
[laughter]
Any anyway?
Yeah. The Super Bowl NFL. Okay. So it's
an American tradition. So what what the
[ __ ] are they? you know, on Twitter,
then you're going to have like a bunch
of uh oh, oh, there, you know, like
random political things using the
opportunity of Super Bowl, you know,
they get a bunch of random political
things. But this is something, okay,
this is this is about the files.
Very bad situation. Uh trouble, you
know, tr troubled USA.
Uh anyway, so [ __ ] you know, I I'm I
was going to look at some of the Super
Bowl, but then you got this like [ __ ]
that's a that's a that's a nature of
Twitter. Okay, that's a state of USA
American brand today like on social
media, you know. I'm looking for Super
Bowl and then you got Okay, you got
[laughter]
you got tits, you got politics. Yeah,
you got whatever. What is this? Uh then
you got Okay.
Uh then you got what is this? Another
like drama or something.
And then tits. Okay.
Okay. Anyway, and there it is. Michael
Jackson and the guys posting Michael
Jackson is because something something.
Anyway, so I was looking for some
pictures of the ramble, you know.
Oh god. Oh god. What is this?
Oh, okay. [ __ ] [laughter]
Anyway, so that's a American thing.
Okay.
Um,
Super Bowl. Okay. Please give a
prediction. I have no idea. I don't know
who whatever is Seattle or New England,
but you know the but the the interesting
names. New England. You see, I learned
um that's, you know, that's about US
history. New England, that's England,
but it's new. That's like somewhere near
the eastern side of USA.
Hi, Buken.
Can wan be um let's see can woof be
substitute
for ticks or IP for pictures
combinatorics and geometry.
Yes of course. But what is Tik KZ or IP?
Can it embed Latte in pictures? Of
course.
If you want um
Okay, hold on a second. So, so
apparently there is no in my 10,000
files, HTML files, the only occurrence
of this picture is on this page. So, we
can delete it safely. Okay. Actually,
let me just delete just just just um
just paste that that that and actually
we can I don't want to I don't want to
delete it yet. I can Anyway, so we
updated that this is cardiode formed by
its tangent and here is a code. So I'll
get to the question. Okay, so here's the
code. We need to like clean up the code.
So this part we don't delete it. Okay,
we don't need um so delete that.
Delete that.
Delete that. Save it. Okay. Now I want
to see if we um
if the file got saved larger or smaller.
Refresh.
So we made a backup. Uh wait what?
Okay there it is. Oh yeah, because we
were
uh sizing it by uh size.
So actually we actually we made the file
much bigger.
Let's see. Uh
that's 7 megabyte. Yeah, we made it much
bigger because
well anyway so I was just in in
interesting you know anyway so
so what I'm saying you know in case so
this is very old notebook this old book
this notebook is like 20 years old so I
just saved it I I just removed one image
and saved it and it turns out much
larger
I mean the result is like seven times
larger. Uh why we I I can I can kind of
tell you why. In part because you know
um you know it's after 20 years so you
allow much larger file size. So for
convenience and tradeoff wuam language
they they made it um they choose to have
you know like larger file size.
Anyway by the way you are looking at the
source code. I mean the actual notebook.
So it's all text. Okay. So it's all
text. We talked about this before.
Notebook is like it's actually all text.
It's not binary file. Okay. So images
are represent for example. Okay. Oh, I
can tell you why. You see the images in
this notebook some of them are bit map.
Uh actually they are not. Oh they are
they are actually postcript. You can you
see they have a bit map version when you
open it. But if you resize it a a little
bit, you can see actually it's a post
script. So it's very high resolution. So
let's show some example. So for example,
that's bit map. Okay, initially. But if
you just enlarge it, you see this is the
real picture. So the real picture is
actually a postcript. So you can see in
the notebook file,
this is the postcript data. Okay. You
see this this you see this these are the
postcript data
postcript is a uh scalable image format
okay that's when you you know very very
popular postcript
um
and it's actually also a programming
language anyway so so the notebook
technology um
and uh so if you actually now if you
make them now if you save it I believe
it'll become smaller m maybe I don't
know anyway that's like a lot technical
detail okay so let's close this reopen
it refresh let's say let's see
oh no look no I got a confused you see
the new version is seven times smaller
than the old version you see this is the
old version this version is like 20
years ago So, but the new version you
save it, it's like 10 seven times
smaller. Okay.
Uh anyway,
so but anyway, today we did this code.
So, uh fantastic. We did this code that
now we need to like clean up the code.
Okay. So, let me let me do that and
that'll be it for today. So, close that.
Uh let's go to where is my code?
Yeah. So instead of um
you know you don't want you want the
actual formula. So let's go to get
uh search for formula. Okay. Formula PL
formulas. Okay. Now WL
open the source code and search for
cardioid there. Okay. Search for it. So
here is the actual formula. So search
search search search search search
search search search. Okay. Okay. So
it's actually uses that. Oh god. So I
don't I don't like this um dependency.
So you see cardioid is a special case of
epotrocoid
with parameters 111. Okay. Now so so
what you have to do is just uh Okay.
Let's see what what it actually is.
Okay. Paste it. Shift enter. Okay. So,
you need to you need to like uh two
parameters, right? No, just t.
Okay. So, here is the uh
formula for cardioid. Okay. Copy that.
Copy that.
Okay. Let's just close close. Okay.
So let's copy that, paste it there and
uh plank curve
and uh and
I want to say plank curve plot. Okay,
plank curve plot then cardiode is
actually that. So replace that by that.
Okay, delete that. So now it's more
explicit. Okay. Then then add that that
that that. Okay. Now make it one line.
Copy it back here.
Paste.
Do it. Fantastic. Okay. So let's see.
Axis true.
Okay. Let's say axis false.
Uh
press enter. Okay. Now let's put a
cursor here and control shift N. So now
they become type set. You can see.
Fantastic. You see this fraction. Okay.
So anyway this is the formula. Okay. I
mean this is the code. So go back here.
You can paste it. uh except that I don't
want this uh back slashpi that that that
is the special symbol for pi. Okay. But
if you work with Wuam language in in in
text like in um in Wuam script, you
don't want you know usually this
backslash
bracket special symbol is annoying.
Okay. So you don't want so that's not
that just this is a code. Okay. Try it
again.
Paste it there. Shift enter. Now this
red, you know, this thing, they
shouldn't be red. They became red for
some reason. That's because uh probably
because I something is not totally
proper in my code.
They shouldn't be read. Okay. Tangent
size. Oh, maybe it could be because I
loaded. Remember, we loaded previously
by mistake. Anyway, so here's a code.
Uh, and you need to say,
okay, so you need to say that. Okay,
delete that. Uh, then you need to say
plank curve. Okay, needs plink plug.
Copy that. Go back. Okay, kind of do
that. Put it back. Syntax curette
showing browser. So that is much better.
Okay. So you got a code here. Yeah.
Okay, that's like update for today. Um,
now let's check one more time how how
how much what's the image size? So, this
one is PNG
is 166K.
166.
What about this old one? That's 4K.
Okay. Yeah. So, we increased a lot.
Now, another thing I want to do is I
want this to be SVG. So,
uh can we wait? Actually, we did we uh
did we
did we uh optimize it?
What?
Optimize PNG. Okay. Uh,
okay. I Oh, yeah. So, tab I do.
Okay. So, now So, yeah, the new file
size is 81. Okay.
Okay.
Now, what's the um
Okay, here's
new
old new okay
close
and here's a code fantastic okay that's
it for that so you were saying uh
substitute
so you know if you want um tech or
formulas inside graphics you just all
you have to say is for example we can we
can we can do it here uh eper log
Okay. So, epilogue you want like what
kind of thing you want? Let's say text.
Okay. Let's say integral that you you
want some kind of formula, right? So, uh
let's say integral.
Let's say integrate. Now, I haven't done
integrate for like 20 30 years. So, what
you know 1 /x 2 overx
what do you get? Okay. So you got well
so let's make it more complicated. Okay.
So
square root uh x + y something. Okay. So
that they don't Okay. Well, how do you
um we want you know we want the integral
sign.
Okay. So actually so that will make it
wow they evaluate okay so what uh what
is
what what is the integral so that
prevent it from um
yeah if you add a sign and then you you
this will take okay so there is an
integral okay so we got an integral so
you so you are like you want the so
suppose you have a image you want some
kind of formula inside it. Okay. So you
have to say is you you can put that into
um
uh Okay. So let's let's just say hold.
Can we do that? Yeah. Okay.
[clears throat]
Wait. Uh hold. Okay. Something like
that.
Uh
yeah. So what how do you uh text what
coordinate you want the text be? Uh
yeah I don't I don't know. So let's say
something. Okay. Let's just try that
now. So there it is. You can see
something in the middle. So now you just
paste the integration
uh formula shift. There it is. You got
your integral
in hold there. So you say hold form uh
fo l fo r m.
Okay. So that's how you get a
type set uh mathematics in in a image.
So and if you are want you know of you
can you can I think you can do it this
in latt
you know you can type the latt way to
for the for this uh expression then wuam
will translate it
anyway but nobody does that because lat
is a very bad design lat tech latt of
the Donald Groot is one of the worst
design
in part the reason it's worse is in part
partly because when it was invented he
it was the first type setting. It was
before it was before the idea of um of
um auto automatic mathematics. It was
the before the idea of
uh
symbolic math algebra system you know
like kind of before. So Donald on so
latt
pestilence I have a written an article a
rant about it and this is well known
this is this article is well known and
this is from 2004 I wrote it in 2004 so
tech is like a disease okay latte it was
very popular because it's free because
basically that's the only reason well
that's the predominant reason it it was
popular if it's not free nobody would
use it. Okay. So, but it became like
like Unix, you know, disease. So,
people, you know, because you you it's
free. So, then it forced people to type
this crap. Okay? You see to type these
simple formulas. This these are the most
used type set formulas in mathematics.
You know you have summation integral uh
you know infinite sum summation definite
integral uh and derivative and limit
okay and and matrix and square root okay
that's the most and fraction that's the
most basically the whole math type
setting is almost that's all you need
okay and and also power okay so
summation integral power you know power
at little corner fraction
limit
uh square root and the matrix. That's
all you basically that's all you need.
Okay. So in Latte you got to you to type
those you you have this crap this
syntactic disease.
Okay. Now in Wuan language you type this
instead. So some so for example I can
show you. So copy so copy that
uh
paste it. Okay. So let's see if we
evaluate it would it work? Actually no
because um
because you well but you know because
this are not exactly valid uh
expressions
but
but you know for example you uh for
example you can do them one by one. So
because the first part becames log one 1
+ uh
invalid integration variable or limit.
Okay. So you got
yeah because you know this is
traditional math. This is not valid. You
can say that equals to that you know or
you have to say double equal if you want
to ask the question if they are equal.
So, and also this this preceding
succeeding symbol you see that's like
curved greater than that's not a valid
um character in Wuan language but over
here I'm just showing how it is done.
So, but basically this formula but we
can we can break it apart. So, wait.
Uh so, copy that. Okay. So delete
control shift D to separate it. Okay.
And go here. Delete that. Control shift
D. So you can evaluate each one of them.
Okay. That become harmonic number. Okay.
But you can shift CtrlN to make it a
formula. Okay. Same thing here. Shift
CtrlN to make it. Okay. You are actually
you want um
can you integrate this? Okay. Invalid
integration. Oh, you forgot x there.
[ __ ]
Yeah. So, so that's the actual the
result. Okay. So, so I need to correct
something here.
Yeah. You need the X. You need the X
there. Okay.
So anyway,
so in wen language if you want to type
something it's you know the the syntax
is very simple as opposed to the latte
you know this crap and plus in wen
language you can evaluate them you see
it's not just type setting it's actually
meaningful for example this thing
so for example that part that part if we
paste it there uh you can say you have
to say double or equal to to if you want
if you want to uh mean that they are
actual equal. So it will return false
because they are not actual equal. But
copy it control shift n control shift t
to format it in traditional type set you
see you got matrix okay [snorts]
uh and similarly for for all these other
um anyway that's about tech latte.
So so
okay I think that's it. Let me just
quickly answer some of these questions.
Uh today okay uh Super Bowl I don't know
anything about it can wan be substitute
okay when you decide when you decide
write your own model mode isn't hard to
write it what does what does what does
that mean
what are you talking about
uh fuka American football
hand egg yeah that's Uh that's a better
name. Hand egg seems to require no skill
but only brute strength. Yeah, that's
the point, [laughter]
you know, actually. So I think
technically there there is some kind of
uh tactic or orchestrating skill like
the
centered on this uh so-called
quarterback
you know I don't even know the rules but
the quarter the guy in the in the back
like in the middle and back they he must
be some kind of like very smart and
director kind of a guy. He must know
where to pass the ball. I think that's
the most important thing. But but it's
kind of idiotic, you know, American
football game.
It it's kind of funny because it
represents the American
mentality some somewhat, you know, big
and bet, you know, big is better, you
know, it's just like everything crash
and burn, you know, they just there's no
sensibility.
He's just like, you know, we, you know,
big, let's have, you know, big trucks
and and that all that.
And the other idiotic sport to go with
it in America is basketball. It's
another like the most brainless
game. You know, in basketball, the the
the key is whoever is taller is wins.
Okay, that's like it. Whoever is taller
wins basketball.
Uh,
if today you wake up as 20 years Zoomer,
you choose MVM or steel Emacs? Emacs, of
course, that's easy to answer. Okay. Vim
is Vim is like this Unix hack. The Vim
VI or engine is VI. Okay, it's a Unix
disease. The way Vim came to be it's not
because someone thought about oh the you
know we should you know this way would
be most efficient what you know what
what is the most efficient way to edit
text you know you know after you know
they think about it for a month or two
they decide they eventually oh I realize
you got to have this model system so you
have like you switch in a in in a in a
context where you everything you type is
a command then you can switch to insert
mode you know no it didn't happen like
that okay vi was like that because 50
years ago computers you can't you cannot
do interactive editing you must tell the
computer okay right now I want to run a
command to insert some text okay so you
say let me insert some text then okay
the you you type the command then and
then the screen says, "Okay, ready."
Then you type the text. Then you press
enter. Then it shows up, you know. Then
okay, I want to now I want to delete
them. Now you have to tell the computer.
Okay. Now I want to go to I want to
delete something. Okay. Then you give
the command to delete. It asks you from
from which point to which point you you
give a number, you know, like that's how
vim became. That's what vim vi is. Okay.
It's a it's just the way things are. The
idiocy passed on and evolved. That's how
VI and C and Unix are. Okay. They they
they are just like brainless.
And the newer generation of course newer
generation didn't know that you know
even when I was like in computers like
in 199 actually I got into Unix in 1996.
I never seen you know like like before
VI there's Ed okay Ed is the father of
VI I mean even at that time in the 1990s
people have never seen a computer where
you have to like switch modes like
people are used to you know interactive
editing you know you just type what you
you know whatever that's natural
so people have not seen that you know
that's from 1970s that's where VI came
VI. So that's like a disease. Okay.
Uh basically everything Unix and C
related is like all disease. Where is
the SWAT board? Swabboard is here. Okay.
No, not I'm not using it yet, but I
still plan to, but it's just not. Uh
and doesn't light theme cause a lot
glare? No. I did like one hour talk
about dark theme. Dark theme is a
disease. Dark theme is bad for your
eyes. Search for my YouTube, you'll find
it. Okay. Uh by scientific research, by
lots of reasons, dark theme is just bad.
And I have like over, you know, several
articles on my website. Search for it,
you'll find it.
Uh
Tik KZ and IP are two most popular
programs for making images to include in
Latte. Okay. Okay. That's like
well if you are using wam language you
don't you know they you don't you don't
need them. They are like
uh d i kz. I don't I don't even have to
look. I know they are like the worst
[ __ ] Okay. pair of languages for
producing vector graphics from a
geometric of a algebraic description.
Oh, okay.
So, what uh so what do they um
it's a pair of languages for producing
vector graphics from a geometric
algebraic description with standard
features including the drawing of
points, lines, arrow, path, circle and
so on. PGF is a lower level language
like T I KZ is a set of higher level
language you know god complicated the
top level something like what like what
the [ __ ] is it
commands are invoked as tech macros but
in contrast with PS tricks the PGF tick
you know this con this this is like
complicated [ __ ] [laughter]
like you have no idea what the [ __ ] is
they talking about but
okay but it's some kind of like what
what kind of language is it? So, so it's
like um veto graphics languages. So it's
so it's like SVG is it like tech is like
postcript like what the [ __ ] is it
you know I have no idea like like you
know just like what the [ __ ] is it
stupid I I you know I think it's
reasonable valid simply reading this
introduction
uh I think it's reasonable valid to say
This introduction is idiotic. Okay. Some
idiots wrote wrote it like they anyway I
don't want to go too extreme
export you know so so but what but like
what like like this people you know like
either you describe it in a technical
way or you can describe it in a user
oriented way like what like who who why
do I want to use it what is this for for
users. Is this for users or is this for
programmers? Like if I'm I'm creating a
you know math programming language, I
need some kind of library to embed tech.
Is that for the programmers or is this
for a user? Like what the [ __ ] is it? It
failed to describe you know in in
failed to describe it fast written in
tech and lua repository okay stable
release so when did it begin I don't
know original author tanto
uh tanto Christian something okay so
when did it start I didn't say okay so
Uh
so we are just digressing into this for
curiosity sake. Uh the PGF tick
interpreter can be used from a popular
tech
confer
packages also directly from original
tech.
Uh since tech itself is not concerned
with graphics the interpreter supports
multiple tech output. Like who the [ __ ]
cares? like this is written by the
people themselves, you know, overview.
That's not overview. That's like a
technical description on on what the
[ __ ] you doing.
I want to overview like I'm a programmer
for 40 years. I want to know what the
[ __ ] is this for? Who is the audience?
They didn't say, you know, it a bunch of
jargon. This is like Unix, okay? This is
like the VI and Unix people. They they
they are like this. Okay. Like they are
going nowhere anytime.
The entire VI and Unix things and see
things are like this. You know, you you
you read it for like you like no what
the [ __ ] is it? But to these people like
to to these people who are already in
this mind mindset, you know, tech they
they wanted to do something like they
they find it oh this is so precise. This
is you know that that that that's that's
these people.
Okay. The project has been under
constant development since 2005. Okay.
It's pretty old. Most of the development
until 2018 was done by Tio Tanu since
the since the then Henry Mankey has been
the main contributor. Okay. Uh something
something Lua Tech support for direct
SVG output via via something or another
something cryptic [ __ ]
Uh okay. And another thing by the way
another the one of the worst [ __ ] is gnu
plot. Okay gnu plot and I think matt
plot lip too.
No not no wait not not that but the gnu
plot. Okay they are the worst [ __ ]
possible.
Okay.
No. [laughter]
Unix pestilence,
the Unix scumbags, the Unix [ __ ]
Unix haters handbook. Okay, so on my
website you will find a link to that.
That's what you're talking about. So let
me explain for people who don't know.
Okay. The Unix the the Unix people the
the people who put you know basically
what the Unix people are they they are
like a code okay from the most um
you know I want to give the most
scientificbased
opinion okay they are not stupid they
are not uh you know scumbags they they
are basically like a kind of a code
phenomenon okay in the computing
industry
That's a Unix people. Unix and C
including C people.
Okay. So, so the the article you are
talking about. So, I wrote this like
long ago 2003. You know, that's like
it's my like my entire life
by now I'm I'm old, you know, I I'm
pretty old. So, my entire life basically
has been like uh fighting the Unix code
almost, you know, basically. So, so and
and and by the way, so there is this
famous book written by computer
scientist that's called the Unix haters
handbook. Okay, this is written in um
1994.
Okay, 1994. In fact, I have not read it.
Okay, actually I have like read, you
know, so I have so there's one chapter.
So, let me first let me go slowly. Okay,
let me introduce you guys who have not
heard of this. So Unix haters handbook
is very well known at least back in
1990s written in 1994 by three computer
scientists
Simon Garfinko, Daniel Weiss and Steven
Strosman and Don Hopkins. Okay, now now
some of them they pretty old. Okay, Don
Hopkin is still around. Don Hopkins is
kind of uh a friend, not exactly a
friend, acquaintance. Okay. But we
haven't ever met we but we I've seen you
know but Don Hopkins is on hacker news
often. Okay. [snorts] Uh Don Hopkins is
created the Simpsons. He ported the Sim
City not Simpsons Sim City to Unix X
Windows system. Okay. And this is long
ago like in the 1990s. Okay. And Don
Hopkin or 1980s even. So, and Don
Hopkins is also uh a wuam language
coder. Okay, he's you know wam language
coder. So, anyway, these are computer
scientists but but they are pretty old
like you don't hear them. I'm Simon
Garfinko they uh you don't hear them
okay but they are like the in the 1970s
80s computer you know operating system
researchers or whatever
okay so this this famous book 1994
and uh actually I have not read it
except one chapter so one of the most
most famous chapter is by by the way
today it's free okay you can read it
it's free one of the most famous chapter
is by uh is on X11 the [ __ ] idiotic
[ __ ] [ __ ] the Unix people okay like you
guys have no idea
what's going on like you guys trival I
mean you guys are too young you guys
don't know but but even back in the
1990s okay so so so in the Unix um so
I'm talking about history okay I'm
talking about a non- mainstream view of
history of important chapter in
computing history of Unix operating
system. Okay. So there's this book 1994
and one of the most popular chapter is
about X11. I have a link in fact my
website is the one of the earliest
mirror. Okay. So uh let's see where is
the X11 there. This chapter name is
named the X windows disaster. Okay. It's
written by Don Hopkins. Okay. 1994 I
have read read this this chapter okay
it's online it's online free
back then in in the 1990s but today the
entire Unix haters handbook is free okay
uh you can you can read it now I have so
I have read that chapter but but I have
not actually read the whole book you
know the but I have skimmed part of it
okay
so some of you Guys, I I forgot what you
know are you guys saying like suggested
I get I got influenced by it or
something. Okay.
Well, not exactly. Okay. Because the
Unix the Unix the Unix operating system.
Okay. If you have a brand any person use
it, you'll know it's like the most
[ __ ] idiotic [ __ ] Okay. You don't
need like you don't need to read. Oh,
oh, you got you got brainwashed by this
book Unix haters handbook. You know, you
don't need that.
Any person who are into design who think
about things, think is a key word. Okay,
if you ever you know doesn't matter if
you are a programmer or you know if you
ever you know well you have to be a
programmer you know like you have to do
work related to computers.
If you
have even slightly like this thinking
type of guy and if you work with
computers, you know the Unix is the one
of the most [ __ ] idiotic
crap.
Okay. But most people don't know because
the Unix, you know, partly because it's
free and it has this rebellious
uh kind of code, you know, it's
associate associated with hackers
rebellion and then you know small, you
know, like a bunch of jarens like uh
small is um beautiful like like you know
like the Unix philosophy.
It doesn't doesn't doesn't constitute us
philosophy. no design it's just it's
just like this code okay like garbage
lie that's what Unix are
but they are successful just like
Microsoft do you guys understand because
Microsoft for many reasons in society
there are many reasons bad people become
successful become popular one good
example you guys may agree those of you
loving Unix [ __ ] may agree is
Microsoft like every one of you the Unix
[ __ ] will say oh yeah of course
Microsoft is so evil but anyways my
point is that in society many you know
for lots of reasons something become
very successful but not necessarily good
in fact in fact might be harmful and
evil okay so and my claim is that Unix
is one of them a big one in computing
history and the C programming language.
Okay, that is my claim. That is just
that is my opinion.
You don't have to believe it. You might
you might think, okay, that's a bit
extreme. Okay, that's up to you. But
that is my opinion. That is my honest
opinion I'm giving out to you guys.
Okay, so that is my rant about Unix. You
know, this is like my lifelong rant. my
like my life almost is revolving around
the Unix and and a few other things like
lisp uh programming language and and few
other things. Okay, the Unix the worst.
So, so what I'm saying again overall I I
would say it's the Unix phenomenon in
computing history is kind of uh quote a
little you know uh
you know uh overall broadly speaking
it's uh it's a bit it's a bit of a code
phenomenon okay and in the computing
industry okay it's a bit of code
phenomenon
so so you got you know today for example
vi you The VI is one of them and you
know the Unix philosophy lots of okay
Okay, thank you guys um for you know the
comments. Lots of comments today. Uh
very enjoyable. Read Unix handbook. Um
haters handbook seems like a biggest
influence. Okay, expand your page. I
don't I don't have much to add you know
they and also it's history you know it's
history like you don't really it's it's
it's really history like even all the
Unix things like we don't really do it
today you know the you know because like
the Unix people the Unix uh handbook
they were talking about command line but
but you know people still think you know
command line is a issue but actually no
you browse the web most people browse
the web it's long time past command
command line it's not about command line
and programming language is not command
line anymore Python Ruby in you know we
long time past that but you have but
it's like you see that's why I say uni
Unix is a code you have kind of this
lingering thing like whenever you think
about Unix like people still mention
command line command line command line
like where the [ __ ] do they think they
are they why are they talking about
command line because Unix
Okay. In reality, the command line is l
like doesn't matter anymore. You have
GUI, you have web browsers. Okay. You
got you got your iPhone, you you you
don't like every day living in command
line anymore. But you can still, of
course, but why are people still like
command line command line vi you know
that's because Unix Unix made you think
that that that that you know command
line is a thing.
So that's why.
Okay. Bye guys. How long have I been
like this is like 90 minutes rant or is
it um 10 concurrent viewers? Okay. So
but that's it. That's it by oh 70
minutes. Not too bad. So we did wolfen
language. Not too bad. And we ran it on
tech latte and not too bad. Okay. Bye
guys.
Uh, if you like my stuff, okay, support
me. So, just like go to my website, go
to, you know, go to go to it,
kxani.info, okay? Go to it. There's lots
of uh tutorials and, you know, and go
to.info
all the way to the homepage.
Uh, and at the bottom, at the bottom,
PayPal, Patreon, Amazon, me. Okay.
$100 would be nice if you have a job.
Bye.