good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today's 2020 June third Wednesday night
o'clock in the afternoon San Francisco
time so what is today's topic post your
questions okay if you have a questions
to me instead of a topic not topics
suggestion just post whatever you want
to ask me something you want to ask me
then post it don't give me suggestions
about topic okay so 2020 journal third
time passed fast so let's see what's
going on so what what is today time
today's topic because if there's no
topic and I'm going to just do random
and usually if I do random the easiest
one is I'm just going to work on my
website so it's gonna be something like
Emacs demo because that's the easiest
topic comes to mind I just
Emacs them all Liam golf the idiotic vim
golf so okay so let's read the questions
okay the morning Ripper I saw your name
first
hello Tim Shaw good morning George to
Australia Ripper in United States of
America Stoker quo I don't know where
you from Chinese China tell us about the
riots okay that's a big one the riots
okay let me talk about that a little bit
you know then it may be a long rant yeah
but I try not to I don't feel like doing
a political topic because you know
that's because it's controversial then
you know so so there's all these riots
going on and you know polity politic
political issues and you have to see the
videos the video footage by common
people you can easily see that on
Twitter as they happen you know people
are burning buildings and
looting stores you know they just break
the window and do in stores and black
life matters group but also also antifa
and you know is fairly complex okay I
don't like it of course nobody nobody
likes it but today so what I want to say
my opinion about that is that
hold on a second so do you do you hear a
like electric hum how do I fix that how
do I fix the electric hum do anyone
knows about that I noticed that there's
a Wikipedia about that Electric hum but
it's quite detailed detailed takes an
hour to read it so anyway so you know
the riots because if you don't know
because a cop accidentally killed a
black man you know some people you know
they are very angry people are very
angry now so if I do not agree if I say
your opinion that is what is you know
they are angry it's not what they think
I'm going to have problems you know they
are going to start to you know look me
up or beat me something like that so
it's a troubled time you know when that
happens you know in chaos when the
situation is not stable you cannot say
you cannot reason you say something
you think it's reasonable but you got
beaten up so so this cop you know the
white cop he technically it's I think
it's you know in my opinion it's
accurate to say accidentally killed a
black man but of course all these angry
people they don't you know they would
say the cops murdered the black men or
things like that in fact I think it's
being accused I mean in Inked there you
know the cop is being arrested and in
jail now and they are accusing him of
murder you know I'm going to say my
opinion I don't think he's you know I
think it's you know it's actually
accurate to say accidental kill in a
Beautif
you know because you know I saw the
video I watched the video you know the
the black guy is already already under
control and and there is no it's not a
violent thug you know the bad guy he
doesn't have guns or anything like that
he's are totally under control and they
are bystanders by standards saying that
you know let him breathe you know he's
saying you know I cannot breathe so the
cop is is essentially abusing his power
however I wouldn't say it's it's
intentional models like some of these
black life matters actives activists say
because when you are a cop you know this
you know violent thugs you know they
sometimes they have guns you know
you know things happened they can you
know they can you know if if I'm a like
if I'm against the cop has me down but I
can pretend to say you know I cannot
rest you know then suddenly I you know I
I pick up my gun or something and shoot
a cop so that happens you know that's
that happens but overall I want to say
you know the the cop abused his power
and you know unless seeing there are
several cops there's another cop you
know trying to fend off the the
bystanders you know and I think he's
unfortunate you know because now he's he
didn't do anything to the bad guy but
now he is part of these associated with
murder so that's unfortunate you know
you look at this situation you you think
if you are that if you are the other cop
you what you're gonna do are you going
to support the bystander that's but you
know the the crowd no obviously not
because you know you you have to help
your co-workers you know anyway I'm not
sure I want what I want to say about
that so and and also this situation now
this riot all over its highly political
because the America is you know America
the white countries in my point in my
opinion is falling apart because partner
you know partly because the corruption
the I don't like the democratic today
you know they are doing fake news all
over and anything Trump says they
and they do fake news that's my opinion
so it's a controversial topic to talk
about so anyway let's let's read how now
second I got been smoking too much in
the past two days
so let me cough
okay so let's let's go let me read the
topics and let's see what we're gonna
talk about today are we gonna talk about
technical programming stuff so George
says have you heard about the pallets of
bricks being left everywhere for testers
to use yes indeed yes indeed because you
know so there is this antifa group who
wants to overthrow the US government
basically and they are you know it's
it's been going on since the past three
four years but news you see all the
mainstream media they don't cover it
much or they spin they are basically
prod antifa they are sponsored by the
left-wing politicians higher-ups you
know for example or the tech corporation
you know take white people you know so
they do fake news they the for for
example Firefox actually donated to aunt
Eva and the and all the news media
report fake news you know they say they
say the antifa is there to fight the
white supremist okay
that's not what I see from what I see in
a past let's say at these five years in
the past five years the white supremist
essentially almost doesn't exist okay
they they are essentially no way it
doesn't exist they have no power
meanwhile the left people the the the
social justice people so to speak they
are the most powerful they are the me
all the media corporations or the tech
corporations Google Apple you know
Facebook Twitter and so on and most
programmers in the Silicon Valley's you
know in California we are very
democratic people so very powerful and
you know the thing is you want to fight
power and does and they lie you know
they die or this super elite in
Hollywood Superstars they they are so
rich and they are sponsoring this
terrorist group including you know Apple
Google they all did that in one way or
another and they are spinning you know
they are putting out these fake news
this fake story about how the rise of
white supremist therefore we need to
take it down you know
and and create anger you know a whole
bunch of and good but that's not what I
see from what I see the white supremist
people they almost essentially doesn't
exist there are a few you know like like
the you know the the the training
teenager girls blue what what's the name
they you know here and there and because
I'm looking because I have been paying
attention to these kind of things you
know white supremist they are
essentially they have no power they
didn't need it didn't exist well however
the the left-wing people the politician
the elite they they push fake news so
much
that's how President Trump got elected
okay and on Twitter you know all these
you know the black life matters and all
these groups they you know fake news
they lie all the time and so in my in my
view I started to see the right-wingers
the you know the cop believers the the
right-wingers the consulted
conservatives they used to empower a lot
of power the rural America you know in
mm you know george w bush which is come
back but they fear out of power but
anyway so the left politicians they rule
and the elite people so the this i
started to see in the past three years
the the the smaller right wing people
start to resist and they start to come
up so that's what i see total totally
different from the mainstream media
so okay so let me read the comments okay
George
hello team saw George called legacy show
your photos from Las Vegas my photos
from Las Vegas I talked about that in
two of my videos I believe at least one
of them there is a YouTube you know
search for Saudi Las Vegas you'll find
it free though ultra finite ISM in math
now what is ultra finite ISM I know I
don't know what that is
otra finite ISM there it is Wikipedia
let's see what it says
in philosophy in philosophy of math
ultra finite ISM also known as ultra
intuition ISM strict formalism strict
finite ISM actual ISM predicatively
vision and strong finite ISM is a form
of finite ISM okay [ __ ] Wikipedia in
this academic way of talking now what is
a form of finite ISM now I can tell you
the finite ISM or whatever this ultra
fanatism is kind of new concept okay
let's say it doesn't exist before year
2000 you know or it exists as a small
niche you nobody knows because in
philosophy of math this is new so so I
have to read about what is finite ISM
you know that that's how you read
Wikipedia you link after link after link
so anyway
ultra finite ISM is a philosophy of math
is a form of finite ISM ok we cannot
read about that and it says there are
various philosophies of math that are
called ultra feminism a major
identifying property common among most
of these philosophies is their
objections to totality of number of
theoretic functions
like exponentiation over natural numbers
okay so a major identifying property
common among these ultraviolent ISM is
there objection to totality of number of
theoretical functions objection to
totality of number okay
ok it's a bit complicated their
objections to totality of number of
theoretic functions ok totality is some
property you know it's a class of
functions and they are objecting to
totality of numbers of number theoretic
functions ok ok I don't know what that
is let's read about finite ism finite is
amis of philosophy of math that accepts
the existence only of finite
mathematical objects it is best
understood in comparison to the
mainstream philosophy of math where
infinite mathematical objects accepted
as legitimate okay so that's finite ism
but ok finite isn't basically limit I
you know I can you explain what finite
ism is basically it's this is related to
computer proof proof systems and prove
theory using computers that is if you
want to use computers to to to do
mathematical proofs the most fitting
approach turns out to be one branch of
philosophy of math that is today you
call it finite ism before you call
before you know let's say before year
2000 it's called into intuition easel
anyway I talked about this before let me
give you a summary of my understanding
so let's say before 1990s the classic
philosophy of math you have essentially
three big philosophies of math one is
largest ism logic you know largest ISM
they say that mathematics is nothing but
logic so they in their opinion all
mathematics can be reduced to logic pure
logic you know and the the foundational
work is Bertrand Russell and something
Whitehead they wrote principia
mathematica they want to reduce entire
math into logic so that's one of the one
flaw one school philosophy of math then
the other one is formalism formal from
as informality formalism from the main
guy is David Hilbert he proposes that
math is nothing but symbol manipulation
essentially you have a bunch of symbols
for example in high school algebra you
have x squared equals 2 let's say for
you want to solve for x you
manipulator symbols then you get x
equals two to the principal square root
you know you move you know you add a
number to both sides things like that
manipulate manipulation of a string of
sequence of symbols that is called
formalism and in the formalism school of
mathematics they believe that all these
you know that's that's math okay they
believe that math is nothing but eggs
but purely manipulation formulas okay
formulas and inherently they they don't
have any meaning you have to interpret
in interpret it so manipulate important
concept a pure manipulation of a
sequence of symbols according to certain
rules from this idea that's what we
that's how we have symbolic pattern
magic for example in Mathematica
symbolic pattern matching or you can say
Lisp Marcos okay a lot of you this was
you know you talk about this Marco's
every date Marcos Marcos [ __ ] these
these idiots
okay so lease Marcos is a form of
symbolic pattern matching basically you
have a bunch of rules that says when you
have a sequence of symbols when they
have a certain pattern you replace it
with another sequence of symbols like
when you if you are a compiler if you
write compilers
passes okay grandma formal grandma you
know what that means
you know you you have a bunch of rules
that tells you patterns of sequence of
symbols they should be replaced to
another form and you have you know this
is a generative linguistics then from
this grammar you have a language
computer programming language so anyway
pattern matching okay simple symbolic
pad imagined so formalism school math
says that entire math entire math is
simply just manipulation of sequence of
symbols that's formalism so you have
largest system you have formalism then
you this is classic philosophy of math
then there is another school called into
intuition isn't okay keep your comments
going okay I'm gonna read them am i
doing okay so lottery system formalism
lottery system of Bertrand Russell and
and whitehead formalism of David Hilbert
then you have intuition ISM by led by
the guy prove or something like that you
know a German guy
and and and intuition you know intuition
ISM is kind of odd you know so you know
III you know I study math when I really
read about into you know I understand
largest ISM very logical you know you
want to reduce the entire math into
logic you know like they're you know
this is something something therefore
this implies that you know things like
that or formalism everything is just you
know formulas simple manipulation
according to certain rules then there's
intuition ISM now into you know so I
read about that it's kind of strange
very odd okay intuition ISM they they
say things like they do not accept
infinity okay so in math it's almost
fundamental you have the concept of
infinity especially essentially that's
what calculus studies you have infinity
or you have infant estamos which is you
know infinity is infinitely large in
fatty small is something so small
smaller than then the smallest infinity
is small but not zero okay that's that
that's essentially what calculus is
about calculus is the formal study of
infinity or in fortissimo infinity and
the infinitesimal is related because
they are the inverse of each other you
know 1 1 over infinity is invitees mode
so anyway so so in math infinity is very
common and even you know you could say
it's intuitive so you know 1 2 3 that
you have infinity does in this but the
intuition is a school of philosophy of
math they say they don't accept that
they say ok they don't accept infinity
there is no such thing show me you know
this that's their thinking show me show
me an infinity of course we cannot show
infinity because that's a conceptual
therefore so they don't accept that and
there's another thing standing out from
the intuition nist
school of thought that is they don't
accept what's the named of divided meter
watson you know there's an named let's
look up intuition is Amagi int UI
intuition
okay there it is so there are two things
standing out about this intuition isn't
school of philosophy of math one is that
they don't accept infinity the other one
is that they they don't they don't
accept the excluded middle okay let me
explain what that is then we're gonna
read it so excluded middle in logic you
know in logic usually you have a
situation that's either A or B for
example is is this is this color white
you know it's either white or it's not
white there is no in-between you know am
i human you know yes or no there is no
in-between but the you know the I'm kind
of I'm kind of simplifying the details
and I don't know the details myself so
I'm not a you know professional logician
Dutch - I'm not qualified to talk about
this but however I can give you I can
give you a simple ideas or you go you go
study there okay so the intuition is
some school of math they don't accept
infinity they don't accept excluded
middle like they for example whether it
either this is a pen oh it's not a pen
you know so in traditional math you can
prove so if you can prove that it is not
a pen
then then you say you you have proven
that this is actually a pen because you
are proving it's not a pen therefore
it's a pen but the intuition missed they
don't accept that okay
they don't accept that they say that if
you want to prove this in Spain you have
to construct it you have to you have to
show an actual example like you know
show an actual example something like
that so when I read about the intuition
you know I'm not doing a very good
explanation because it's quite
complicated okay these kind of things
you have to study for years okay - and
to really understand what's going on so
so you know when I studied math you know
I I'd read about intuition in some I I
don't get it yeah like this guy these
people are crazy these people they don't
accept infinity then then they don't
accept the excluded meter what the [ __ ]
so I don't I don't like this intuition
nation now that here now here's an
interesting thing now you see Haskell
you know now it's being you know 40
years 50 years peoples trying to do
automated theorem prover I talked about
this in my past videos basically you
know since not since we have computers
we want to do AI
you know this AI artificial intelligence
and so on and one of the you know big
thing is we want to have a automated
theory improver so you don't need
instant to to have a theory of
relativity you don't need that because
since we have computers why don't we
automate it you know the computer will
just chunk out theories new theories for
us so people in order to do that that
goes into the heart of mathematics you
know the essence in fact the mathematics
is the essence of all you know physics
all the sciences and even philosophy
and logic you know you dive into the
deepest heart of mathematics and one
concrete example that requires that is
to create a automated theory improver
because now you are dealing with the
essence you know if you can create
automatic clear improver then it answers
almost everything you know what's the
meaning life you know just let the
computer tell you the computer we wrote
you know it's automatic theorem proved
I'll tell you what it life means so so
mathematicians and logicians you know
and in computer science scientist most
you know started to study automate
automate a theorem prover and it's
extremely hard they find out they cannot
do it but the the you know but however
now by now especially this giant you
know we have a lot understanding we try
to do it just like AI you know we have
to take a decade we find out what's
wrong you know we have the progress but
in theory improving systems we also
learnt a whole bunch of things we
developed many branches branches of
computer math you know computer algebra
systems and so on that can you know two
integrals and derivatives and
differential equations or sobbing you
know matrices equations and so on so we
made a huge progress
in practical you know for practical
needs such as computational
computational number crunching like you
know Fortran or you know you want to
calculate the ballistic missiles the
path of missile going to the moon
practical things to fear you know or
computer algebra system sobbing
equations or theory theoretical we made
a lot of progress in theoretical
Holland's again about progress in
theoretical proof proof theory systems
to okay but but then I don't know if I'm
talking too slow and know something but
let me get to the point okay so so so
much messages has been piled up let me
get back to where we began so screw of
math classic schools in philosophy of
math largest ism by Bertrand Russell
that every oh math is reduced can be
reduced to math math is simply simply
logic okay that's largely seasoned
formalism led by David Hilbert which
says mathematics is nothing but simple
symbol manipulation okay formulas it
doesn't have any meaning it just rules
for manipulating symbols if you have
different rules you have a different
math system okay Ruhlman information
then the other school is intuition ISM
okay they say which I didn't understand
before but they say they don't accept
infinity and they don't ask accept
excluded middle in some detail part of
logic okay
and this okay so so but now we have made
so much progress in the past 20 years
especially in the past 20 years because
you know computer power we understand a
lot more about theory your theories of
proof systems and theories you know for
example we started to have homotopy type
theory there's a book and we have [ __ ]
you know we have a lot of programs that
okay hold on a second
so Hamato P type theory I want to learn
okay I talked about this last year you
know hopefully I can learn this subject
matter what before I'm dead
for good homotopy type theory which is a
new foundation of math okay there's a
free book so this is a new foundation of
math that's designed for computation of
proof systems that is using computers to
do math proofs you know it takes us
tremendous time and in the genius this
guy's a genius okay he died two years
ago you can read on my website he so he
essentially created a new brand new
branch of math to do proof you know to
do proofs proofs by computer brand new
because before we have a lot you know
logicians that we all try to do this and
we run into also the problems but
eventually we have today this is a new
thing homotopy type theory which is
related to some you know then we have
category theory which is different
things okay I don't like category theory
and I talked about this many times I
don't like category theory I died in the
Fast and the Haskell [ __ ] idiots fad
you know the Haskell people monad [ __ ]
[ __ ] idiots they they tell you Oh
monad unit every day Oh category theory
you need to know you don't need to learn
category theory it's a [ __ ] I talked
about this many times if you want to
learn real stuff advanced in practical
try to learn homotopy type theory okay
in anyway so let me back get back to
into a Nissen you know my understanding
of you know so three school of math so
what about so this is a very interesting
as thing you know since we started to do
computer proof systems then we realized
here's a interesting story that had a
major impact on me
we realized that that intuition
intuition ISM is actually the Lee
philosophy for computer computer
mathematics that is using computer to
prove math because when you use computer
to math you want to throw away kind of
okay okay kind of okay you want to throw
away the infinity and you also want to
throw away the the excluded middle you
know the the either this or that you
know yes something is either yes or no
that's instead you want to construct it
okay you want to actually construct the
example so that's so intuition ISM after
a while you know this is packed packing
you know 1900 so what early eight
eighteen hundred's
anyway then you have construction nism
then you have let's see
they are you know mathematical
constructivism so intuition ISM became
somewhat of a branch of became
constructivism that is you know when you
use a you know especially suitable for
computers like you want to actual
construct things then I suppose it
become today's fine nineties you know
you know we refine and we find you know
then we have you know finite ISM then I
suppose you have ultra finite ISM so
let's read about finite ISM a little bit
let's read intuition Nissim okay so so
you get a more accurate understanding
what it is so in a philosophy of math
intuition ISM or neo intuition ISM is an
approach where math is considered to be
purely the result of the constructive
mental activity of humans rather than
the discovery of fundamental principles
claimed to exist in an objective reality
okay that is logic and mathematics are
not considered analytic activities we're
in deep properties of objective reality
are revealed and applied but are instead
considered the application of internally
consistent methods used to realize more
complex mental construct regardless of
their possible independence independence
existence in an objective reality okay
that's a that's a bit a lot too many
words okay that's too many words and and
you have to realize intuition ISM this
is back in 1800s and see ya 1800 sigh
you know you have to read so
you know backing 1800s we don't have
computers so much of that you know these
classic philosophy of math much of these
their content what they talk about is
related much more to the domain of
philosophy so you they are talking about
philosophy as opposed to something
concrete an actual that you can do
something with so into is intuition ism
or engine you know is about philosophy
about what you know the question of what
math really is so intuition ISM you know
they focus on construction then they
then you have constructivism okay so in
philosophy of math constructivism
asserts that it is necessary to find a
math object to prove that it exists
okay so this is a more or less a branch
of intuition ISM okay so let me then
then I suppose you have finite ISM and
ultrafine elitism I suppose ultrafine
artisan is let's see the main idea like
under finite hist autre fernandes deny
the existence of the infinite set of
natural numbers in addition some
ultrafine artists are concerned with
with acceptance of objects in math that
no one can construct in practice because
of physical restrictions and so on
you know so we have covered you know
what laymen you know I'm giving you a
layman's understanding kind of what
these philosophy of math are but you
have to remember that's just layman's
approach I don't know these subjects
well I hope to study a homotopy type
theory one day so what I mean is that if
you really want to understand this in
detail you have to dive into them you
know spend a year or two to actually you
know study them or an hour a day every
day because when I say for example when
you read about excluded excluded middle
of the intuition you know there are
there are so many fine details like you
cannot understand it by just listening
to one youtube explanation so that okay
that's about that
Raven paradox okay freedo okay so that's
about that how long have I been talking
it's getting very hot in California for
game for 44 minutes so sensor good
morning so some of you might already
left
how to recognize propaganda someone was
asking that the other day okay how do
you recognize propaganda okay that's
that's not hard to do but mostly takes
some experience proportional so
proportional to your knowledge the more
you know about things general things you
in the more you can easily recognize but
anyway propaganda has certain traits you
can I can I think it's fairly easy to
recognize propaganda okay first of all
so let me just you know tell you of the
top of my head what I think of course
you can go read Wikipedia I'm pretty
sure they will give you characteristics
of propaganda but but anyway you know
it's something something that basically
propaganda is created to so that you
know it make make belief they say
something that they tickle emotion okay
and they want the you know by a short
passage or a picture they tickles
emotion they make you want to believe or
they make may a lot of people want to
believe that's basically propaganda
propaganda by definition is some
information that is intentionally
purposefully designed to spread spread
certain idea that is for political
purposes and that is in generally
generally force
okay fake fake news that's what
propaganda is by definition intentional
spread of force or misleading
information
remember the key here is intentional so
some someone some party some group
created it okay when if it's
misinformation that arose naturally
that's not called propaganda propaganda
is someone some group intentionally
created for the explicit purpose of
misleading the public of particular
target audience and usually the
techniques used in propaganda is emotion
and you know ignorant okay
ignores ignorance is big part of it and
and that's easy to do because most
majority of people including me vast
majority majority of people don't know
mass vast majority of things in a world
for example I know about programming
okay I know nothing about law like a
typical nerd okay I don't know nothing
about I don't know that much about
history okay
but compared to vast majority of other
programmers I know a lot about history
and propaganda and this kind of thing
anyway the point my point is you each
human animals in this world basically
you can practically speaking knows
nothing about nothing okay we are
touching upon infinity and info testimo
so realistic realistic please speaking
each human animal on this earth knows
nothing including me okay so propaganda
is relatively easy you know you could
just say something and you know because
racial bias racist you know ratio is
very natural you know you we have human
bias in our brain that's how we can
survive and we propagate we become the
most dominant animal on earth we cured
control breed other animals you know
that's what we what we do and we have
racism that's why we have nations
definitions fighting each other we have
political groups you know for example
the social justice
cats that is my enemy and I am their
enemy
you know you know if we if we don't have
these biases then they hey hey let's all
be peaceful you know you you don't you
know you don't you no longer hate me for
whatever I say I think you are idiot and
you'll love me still that is a true
equality okay that's a true ultimate
equality but if we become that that
there will be no more human animals on
earth because you are just tired
so we exist you know we have evolution
that's how we are so we have you know
these things so back to the topic so we
have you know bias is speeding you know
some of us can't believe that and we
have culture you know the left the the
Democratic Party you know that these
people they they say Oh multicultural
multi culture but what they are doing is
they cure pure they want pure white
culture they want pure white culture
plus different skin color and different
funny hats and different faces that's
what this social justice people ah you
know you know recently we've been talked
about what does it mean what what do you
say everything in social justice well
you know I'm using that term because
that's the most fitting thing term I'm
giving you the highest level description
in one sentence what I see what's going
on what's wrong okay of course social
happen is there are very complex complex
reasons for for why things are the way
they are
and I you know I I'm not expert on these
things you know these social issues but
I can I would claim you know I'm pretty
I'm pretty accurate you know if you
don't agree chances are you are wrong at
least things happening in America you
know America is very bad now because the
you know the you know corruption and and
mostly the fight between the left and
right you know the constant whatever you
want to name them you know in my weight
in my style of expression I'll just say
the social justice can versus the
Conservatives or God believers you know
they are fighting they are not they are
not being reasonable to each other and
why does this happen this happened
because all the tech corporations
Twitter Facebook Google they you know
they they created social networks you
know they just want to make money but as
a consequence you know we talked about
this sometimes as a consequence because
they want traffic they want people they
want traffic therefore they created
blinders they create little you know
reality hosts so each group only see
what they like to see so it becomes more
and more you know you perceive word the
world differently and all you know
because creep aid you know all the news
websites you know New York Times they
want to make money that's you know in
capitalism in USA you make money
and and in order to do that you want
people to read you know go to your
website
you know ads people don't want to pay
but also because the open source
ideology people don't want to pay if you
start just have a subscription system
nobody you know you have much more fewer
people so so they want more people you
know so they more and more quick paid
big and also Twitter they want more
traffic they force you they want you to
post every day just post whatever post
post post that I get they they design
you know they have mounted monitoring
systems you know Anna analytics logs you
know they they know what kind of things
can encourage more people posting they
want they want people just post every
day so you no longer can write something
once for over solid information doesn't
matter it's good writing or good you
know you spend days or years research
you know he wants you post them on
Twitter after one hour or day it's gone
you think you have to do it again you
know that's what Twitter do so so after
10 years of these we we have AG major
chaos small you know the tech
corporations is responsible for this
it's not like they they are evil you
know they want to see it that way it's
just a consequence because they need
more posts you know so you have you know
you have division
you know the people don't perceive the
same reality the same way anymore
and getting very bad you know worse and
worse over the past 10 years and then
fake news encouraged by Twitter you know
the you know fake news they want to make
money if fake news sensational reason
you know anger you know anger anger is
the the primary element that makes your
postcode viral then you think you have
then then you know then you have more
and more social justice you know things
like that so answer the original
question how do you tell propaganda yeah
you know like I said before corporations
they are very concerned about this
because marketing you know propaganda
actually propaganda psychological
warfare doing washing marketing
and memes or something go viral they are
all related and also persuasion they are
all related the same essence about them
is that you want to change other
people's opinion so for example you can
sell you want to buy you know cause you
know you maybe you want to buy Toyota
you know that's marketing important what
how do you convince people to buy your
things your brand Apple you know Apple
whatever you know think different you
know that's a great marketing very
successful think different guys think
different by Apple in propaganda
brainwashing and coats you know
Scientology I was very involved kind of
not very when I was a team you know so I
was very interested in all these or
these so I know a thing or two about
them so propaganda yeah you know how can
you tell propaganda so anyway so let's
see what else I'm thinking I think I'm
going to wrap up
it's getting so hot here now some
hello Lindy an Indian where you from
Santana Lindy and Sundance and Ana
okay so let's see
so I think that's about it anything else
so I've been talking for 55 minutes so
so free though asks about ultrafine item
so you know a thing or two about that
are you like a student or are you a
vanya so guys joined this code okay it's
showing sorry discord man yeah say
Sylvania so I
venya are you are you the every ran are
you very maybe ran Oh a beer ends friend
because I got confused but I think you
are not but so who rules the word today
oh yeah you are Arry right so is it
China is a USO eh eh
or is it old Empire Brits Japan or
engine shadow
or is it technology companies food
producers energy producers or is it one
with military might I think that
question the obvious answer from these
choices is the one with military might
that is you know given these choices
easily that one is the answer the one
with the greatest power rules the world
that's that's the fundamental theory of
the universe formation time you know who
whoever got the most muscle power the
bro who rules you know so today it's
basically USA you know because you got
more military power you win that's still
USA by a bit you know by quite far by a
bit of distance so the second country is
whatever you know China is certainly
climbing up but as far as military power
goes USA is still the world number one
by quite quite a distance so who rules
the world the one with the most military
power yeah
but if you yeah so your question you
know if you put that option there that's
the answer but if we remove that option
then who rules the world is it China is
it old Empire Brits no breathe in Japan
no the old Empire they are they out of
the question
not certainly not Brits in not Japan
technology companies yeah food producers
yeah energy producers among these three
tech companies okay you know it depends
on the context what are you talking
about because for example depending on
how you how you throw the question for
example take what users or energy
producers who rules the world if you can
only choose one of them depends on I
mean you know let me ask you back a
question so I would claim tech companies
rule because for example Google Google
is the most you know the is the the most
powerful organization organization in
the entire human history that's probably
true even more powerful than US
government ok so again it depends on
your question so is the u.s. US
government more powerful or Google
that's the question it depends you know
how how you how you judge they are
actually tight they are intertwined
together Google and US government they
are intertwined inseparable even because
first of all you have you need US
government the infrastructure the system
in order to have Google and Google is
actually part of you know Google is US
citizens mostly in intertwined you is
not it's not
you know it's not separate entities in
many aspects so so Google is a tech
company plus Facebook you know Twitter
and in lots of you know entire website
entire every time you go to a website
that's a tech comm company mostly in USA
so if you think about that that's
communication every cell phone is tech
company obviously tech company is more
important more powerful than food
producers thank but you might say oh but
food is actually more elementary yeah
that's true but the tech hub company can
just by pay you you know you are food
punk company I own you you make food
yeah okay so do you allow this exchange
of you know trade between you know tech
companies to do a lot of that you know
this kind of CD to compare whether you
know tech company is more powerful or
the food company right that depends on
food producers or any energy producers
yeah I think you know I think that
depends on the question so it depends on
you know what's your context how you how
are you asking that question I think
okay so come on in Chico Chico from Hong
Kong
good morning to Hong Kong rioters Ripper
Ripper Grimm says law second time epic x
rose before I get to casaya epic time
epic times you know politics is very
complex at epic times is from follow
valium Kong you know this coat
you know they teach that you can
levitate yourself you know if you end
and they teach you that what miss
Western medicine is no good you should
trust you know the Kung Fu de Qi you
know for long gone that's you know they
and the guy is very rich median
multi-million billion you know air from
donation just like the the lead the head
from Scientology you know they they
teach you coat you know the they also
follow him going also his anti-gay okay
in Fallon Gong in the you know it they
are you know and so they've been kicked
out of China why because they are they
are you know they are threatening the
stability of cha-chang you know China
the country and I can also tell you why
you know I you know these things I can
tell you a few things you know
Thank You Reaper for $1 okay actually
Reaper has a question so we're gonna
answer that question or we being already
talking for one hour so okay let's let's
wrap up about Falun Gong and epic times
and let's talk about Marquess okay
mark was actually that will take one
hour to talk about yeah you know I mark
was this mark was because in in actually
I've talked about it in two of my videos
two or three he should watch it if you
have not already just such folks sorry
lisp sorry
you know such youtube colleague least
you will find you know quite a few and
three of them I would say is fairly good
okay relative to all my other videos so
a mum IV or spirit you know those on
this is pretty good one of us in
particular one of them about about
symbolic I think about symbolic
pattern-matching or something you'll
find it so probably watch that
yeah because that's that's the essence
of Marcus you need symbols symbols in
transformation of rules and many people
say markers are a big strength of lists
you know they are lists phonetics I
don't you know the markers in this in my
opinion is the most useless
one of the most useless [ __ ] as far as
computer programming language feature
goes not not the you okay that's that's
clickbait okay that's it's not true okay
but it is not one of the worst but it's
it's it's relatively not that useful
okay
and in fact in Lisp languages you need
it because without lists Marcus you
cannot even have if statements you
cannot have if you know if something do
this you know they rely on Marcus
therefore to list languages Marko is all
is the the most important because
without you cannot even have leaf if you
know expression and without if
expression your language is like fact
that's why list Marcus in Lisp is the
most important feature I would say but
if you compare to other languages where
they have if statements but they don't
have markers for example Java or Python
then you don't need Marcos you know
Haskell has Co Java C c plus first they
are doing just fine okay well C C++ you
have you know pre processes which is
kind of similar anyway so the least mark
was is
decided by these phonetics all the time
but it's compared to other languages
it's not that useful feature yeah you
read if statements you know you have
building give statements and others but
it's not that useful you rather you want
symbolic pattern matching like
Mathematica or you rather you want a
building library for parcel okay that is
my opinion now now I want to say I'm not
expert on this relatively okay compared
to most lispers these fanatics who been
coding this for 10 years or 20 years I
know better than them okay idiots but I
haven't but I am NOT a compiler writer
these kind of things you have to have
you know if you been writing compilers
or passes for 14 years
then you really understand the full
details ok that's about that because
when this first talk about mark was the
mass majority of these people you know
the average programmers you know every
every almost everyone you know once you
you know programming industry after ten
years you are open you have opinions
about languages python this you know
Java or whatever suppose you have
opinions every [ __ ] Joe have [ __ ]
idiot video like opinions and they all
say oh this Marco is this or that idiots
but you have to type into it then you
have somewhere okay that's that's that's
that's about you know Marco's the back
to Falun Gong okay the Ferran Gong is
very powerful about you know so they've
been kicked out of China because they
are they threaten the stability of
Chinese government why there's a
president to it okay I talked about this
before to in my video there's
you know in human history if you think
about the number of people dead you know
massive killing or you compare all wars
massive number of deaths the top five on
tap the top five one of them happened in
China type in tango okay that's a how do
you call it in English you know I have a
lot to say about that but anyway it's a
coat okay it's a coat by a Chinese guy
who believed that he is Jesus brother
you know the Christian ality he's the
brother of Jesus he created this code
and that code killed hundred millions
something people you know the top five
in human history that massive number of
death created a civil war in China
that's a code heavenly kingdom okay that
look for it you'll find a Chinese
heavenly heavenly kingdom that's the
English name
so resulted in a hundred million deaths
death was something so that guy is you
know he's Jesus he's his brother of
Jesus and Andy my biased view we are
seeing you know the the hum of the white
people's region you know Christianity
you in Scientology to end moments you
know there they are o brothers of Jesus
or son son of God or things like that
they created coat
so anyway that's a giant death so you
know so Chinese in Chinese city you know
this happened in 1800 or something 1,700
1,700 or 1,800 look up heaven have
heavenly kingdom China okay so so then
then you have Falun Gong obviously you
want to stop them you know you want to
stop you know before you have these
medians you know in my book in my view
certainly biased Chinese because I'm
Chinese but so anyway they you know
Chinese the China the government kicked
out Falun Gong so the guy escaped to USA
USA democracies oh oh my god you are a
leader you know of the web oh you know
you are anti child Chinese government
come over come over we'll help you
we hope you fight the evil China of
course that's what that's what people
think so they come over to you know us
embrace or other countries rebels you
know to fight the other countries us
enemies so so this guy is very rich you
know by donation and he says you can fly
you know don't trust Western medicine
you know if I don't go and they are
sponsored by who pays them US government
tax tax dollars sponsored a but the
thing is in the past three years they
become the Falun Gong becomes far more
powerful and it's very interesting they
become before you know they are saying
they are anti China communist government
every day you know they say oh they
steal organs you know they imprison you
and take yoga and sell you organ Hogan
things like that yeah but but then but
in the past three years they become a
right wing Pro Trump supporters with
their epic times you know they spend
advertisement on Facebook more than any
US politician combined so they become so
extremely powerful you know like over
sudden I see Epoch Times or everywhere
the interview you
you politicians for Trump people and I
was like what the [ __ ] is going on
because I hate you know I don't like the
left the social justice can and I don't
like the Falun Gong either because
that's garbage you know but now the
Falun Gong is supporting Trump and
fighting the socials is justice guy so
should I support the van Gogh it's gets
complex as politics you know because you
have different parties each one has
different costs and interest then they
are intertwined in the Hong Kong people
I don't like
okay the Hong Kong riot riots speaking
of Hong Kong is a Britain the [ __ ]
British Empire
why why why is Hong Kong belong to you
know what why why do I have the right
because the British [ __ ] with a white
people British Empire [ __ ]
they took Hong Kong by war you know the
fighting with China
that's my biased you know that's from a
Chinese person view so they they took
China Hong Kong then they you know 100
years for 100 years and they'd be turn'd
and return'd oh oh by the way I have a
condition within ten years you cannot do
this or that fact for the white people
the brita yeah but you know American you
if you are white people you are American
right you don't know you know you you
think oh oh Hong Kong is great democracy
one country two systems we should stick
to that no we don't we should not stick
to that [ __ ] [ __ ] in the first place
your British Empire you know you should
return channel the Browns China so I
understand you know you're 14 years or
something from studying in 1997 because
things happens you know so you return
you don't you don't just take over and
you know you have to give people you
know because Hong Kong people have under
they being lived they were born in Hong
Kong for the past hundred years they are
continues to the British rule right you
know you don't
so you you it's it's reasonable to have
you know a period that that you know for
this period of time ten years you hung
on people you stay the way you are used
to right I understand but then but of
course USA for political reasons you
know they they pay that they put you
know millions millions millions start
billions by now together to the rebels
in Hong Kong you know they want to make
sure so you si can you know staying home
going if I change fight fight us enemies
control China in essence it so that's my
opinion
yeah you know the opinions I'm giving
here you know you might believe it or
you may not believe it you know you you
know you might take it or not
you might agree or you men may not agree
but my opinion given here is a very
simple natural natural
analysis from a fundamental human
interest point of view so I'm not you
know so I would say I would claim that
I'm not actually introducing some kind
of political bias even though I admit
I'm biased but you can see the point I
want to say is that if you assume there
are biases among all human and most
every one of us okay if you simply
assume that then you can see my point
okay
why is Hong Kong a riot why is us
supported of course because you in China
is you know becoming powerful Hong Kong
you know and you know you we have to
group people a and B they are enemies
they are different race okay and B is
becoming powerful a of course naturally
want to control it on the other hand you
know you know and vice versa vice versa
you know through our history
so obviously you just want to you know
help Hong Kong right saying that it's
you know the it's the right thing to do
and I you know and their reason is
democracy whatever that means
okay that's about Hong Kong okay so
that's right that's it for today so let
me just read finish the comments and
that's it for today
Thank You Ripper for the money I'm going
to enjoy a dinner with that money I'm
out of food you see I need to go to
store
okay I'm gonna finish reading the
comments but essentially we are done
night concurrent viewers
how many riots have I seen no not many I
don't how many riots have I seen in real
life riots I don't think I've even seen
one oh well I've seen you maybe one or
two when I was in
you might say you know when I was in
1985 when I was in El Salvador you know
where they are warming but I didn't
actually see riot man you know in front
of me yeah I don't think I've seen riot
yeah you know I don't join them I think
activists I despise actually I despise
activists this is even before 2010
before the rise of social justice you
know we are often see protesters you
know specifically in America you know
this is American thing protest you know
you have people protest and it becomes
worse was in since let's say 2010 now
become now with this activist you know
becomes a common daily thing especially
because social networks Twitter you know
they have activists but before you have
protesters like hippies you know hippies
they protest Vietnam war but I usually I
always despised activists or protest
because they
well I guess why because you know I can
I cannot say it's good or bad from the
US American tradition perspective
protest is fundamental because America
is fun is a country it so happened okay
it so happened you know because of human
history American is a country it so
happened that the foundation the the the
the founding principle of America USA
his focus on democracy and personal
freedom okay that's it so happened and
and the religious freedom and free
speech gathering because they let me put
some other controversial you know a
point okay because they are the traitor
of United of the British Empire you know
they are going to be beheaded but they
they be voted and successfully anyway so
US US history that's of course a bit
more complex than that anyway so from US
point of view for test is fundamental
that's in the heart of every American
which is a good thing and I would also
say democracy is a good thing okay it's
but not the way you know typical
American think when when it comes to
China but anyway democracy is a good
system the way US democracy I would
claim you know it's pretty good system
and but it's but I would also add it is
not the only system okay but it's a
pretty good system it's a system in
capitalism it's a system that made us a
we so rich and powerful and prosperous
now we have cars everyone has you know
cars well
cars happen because capitalism because
they don't want public transit the car
companies anyway so but anyway they
become reaching comforts you know
capitalism where was I going let's go
back to yeah so freedom personal freedom
it's a big thing and democracy that's
that's good but how did I come to this
but but the
anyway so that that's revamp our Docs
okay so
that's it that's it for today
okay I don't have time to read all let's
see yes they are intertwined
okay write computation singer ma cross
we write computations in our markers our
compiler can run
jaqen now we have a jaqen in our group
and Jagan and Jagan is also in our
discord okay fantastic people
now Jagan is a lisp expert i respect
okay shall I say you know I I want to
highlight some of the people I know by
chance okay I don't want to like give a
overview of all the people who is good
or who is you know the who knows who
doesn't know that's not good anyway
jkerner happens to know he's at least
expert he because he explained one of
the thing I have about symbolic pattern
matching that is why ok this touch on is
the question so my I have this question
since 20 years ago since year 2000 okay
because I in my career I happen to be a
mathematical expert in 1990s I worked
for Wolfram for half a year you know
because I read the entire Mathematica
book three times from cover to cover so
I'm an expert of the symbolic pattern
matching of Mathematica so then I
started to learn this in 1999 so it
puzzled me you know it doesn't mean this
is although it's kind of similar to
Mathematica but why didn't they have you
know pattern matching you know so it's
trivial to do because they are almost
the same language why why this doesn't
do the Mathematica way so why why you
have this Marco's but not fully powerful
why not it's not you know the proper
symbolic data matching from my point of
view this Marco's is simply just a
trivial you know para matching system
like the most simple way why don't they
you know they can trivially extend
and meanwhile all these lists phonetics
they are talking about Marcos all day
but they when I talk about Pat imagine
you know the foof and imagine they is
there their brains like they what they
don't know but they refuse they they
deny you know they refuse to accept you
know they keep talking about this
idiotic Pat imagine you know the list
mark of [ __ ]
jaqen okay no Jay can explain to me why
so so I was you know telling Jake about
semantic panama dream so why didn't this
Marco you simply extend it then you have
the full smelling para magic okay so
basically the issue is that there is at
least one of the issue is that when you
have a symbolic pattern matching system
which which means you write rules you
write rule replacements like formal
grammar okay you define a rule that's
how you define function you'd a function
in pattern matching way is a you define
a rule that transform a sequence of
symbols into another sequence of symbols
so your program works by by this kind of
transformation
of sequence of symbols similar to
symbolic similar to beasts Marcos this
Marco's is like you can think of us of
it as a trivial transformation of a
trivial pattern to another pattern okay
expression cover the expanded form in
this
okay that's transformation but but if
you have full pattern matching system
then you have the issue of which order
of rules to e to apply the the order of
application of your transformation rules
so if you have a real for symbolic
pattern matching system you have bunch
of rules there is a question about which
one you apply first and they can become
very complex because when you have a
very powerful pattern that is at least
you know elements inside and they are
type you know and you want to transform
in some other way your pattern you know
it gets very complex so you have a
situation where are many patterns match
you know so if you have a expression and
you have a bunch of rules you defined
they all match they all match so you can
use either one of them to transform so
the order you use will create different
results so that's a big question when
you have that situation let's a full
symbolic pattern matching in Mathematica
so lease doesn't have that they only
have just one this mark alright once you
you can you you know so it's not a full
pattern where you can define simple
patterns where they all match then you
have a choice which one to apply they
don't have that this idiotic [ __ ]
this phonetic [ __ ] idiots they just
have one simple mark
but I'd yeah that's that's my opinion
so I just want to add I don't know that
you know I haven't implemented passes or
this you know if you actually implement
then if I actually implement these
things then that we all know the obvious
reason you know I have this question for
20 years because precisely because I'm
kind of just like mouthing about it I
don't actually haven't really spent you
really need to spend time to implement
you know then you know a lot then I
would know that my question about why
the lispers they didn't extend this into
the full symbolic pata magic well part
of that reason is also because social
reasons you know there are many social
reasons they don't need it you know the
you know okay that that's it for today
I'm getting hot and hungry so that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
bye guys
we've been talking for one hour and 26
minutes that's a big one n stream
okay and streaming in one minute okay so
you guys can you can you can say your
last words your last words she called
psycho psycho psycho psycho says civil
protesters are followed a friendship
illusion what food do you wanna eat with
skele-toes money money you know the
skele-toes money I can buy a burrito I'm
going I'm going to go out there nearby
this burrito but I'll pay ya that's I
can get a burrito I haven't been eating
well for the past few days the past few
days I'm out of food
you know I'm eating let me show you okay
these mixed nuts which is very good okay
and they're very good for you but you
don't want to eat it every day like you
don't want to eat this like all day
every day nothing else and there's
orange juice okay orange juice 100%
juice concentrate I am tired and hungry
that's it
Chico Chico Chico says Boxer Rebellion
exactly that's the heaven heavenly
kingdom of China
oh wait wait not that not that's a
different thing
Chico Chico parcel rebellion is yeah
it's separating Boxer Rebellion happen
after typing rebellion yes Alan said it
Taiping rebellion yeah that's the
heavenly kingdom thing killed you know
tens of millions or hundreds of millions
you know actually I have an article that
I haven't you know I have I have
articles that it's not sure then that's
it for today thank you guys bye