good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is 2019
August 16th 10 o clock a.m. San
Francisco time this is California
mountain view today is hot and sunny
it's being hot in the past few days and
today we are going to talk about
probably you know it's in a description
there is some technical subject you know
look at the description and type you
know type it out in a chat box let me
know what you like to hear ok so let's
see I forgot to you know now I know how
to create in the scheduled live stream
with a URL so that you just go to my
youtube channel if I have a live stream
schedule you will see it thanks to John
Lewis told me to do that yesterday but
today I forgot to do that until half an
hour before so so anyway a lot of people
has been asking me to about scheduling
my live stream like englidh vents few
days in advance
hi I try to do it it's kind of
problematic because I don't have a
regular schedule and well I'll try to do
it ok so we got one guy watching and so
let me know what topic you like to see
just type in the chat ok
pick a number in the description box
ok so meanwhile let's let's see you know
maybe your house I all start by talking
about so I got two guys watching type
what you like to see ok type it in a
description box you know type in a chat
pick
and okay so today what I like to talk
about Emma hi good morning
Isaac number four okay so good morning
Isaac Isaac is from Isaac is from
Australia well either Australia or
Southern California which one is it I
forgot number four okay Emax tired set
up okay let's let's begin talking about
that then okay so since we are doing
Emacs let's do let's do this okay I'm
gonna show you I create a new window and
I'm gonna cook sauce start command lock
mod okay then shrink the window and now
in this window you can see all my Emacs
commands for word word backup word next
line previous line forward child back
watch our every command we use you will
see it on this window so that's so if
you I'm doing something you can see what
command it is and you can look it up
usually my commands are also on my
website so you can get source code and
use it for yourself
okay so that okay so nothing nothing oh
oh yeah I said so you are in Northern
California now okay we're in Northern
California by the way if you pass by San
Francisco Mountain View you know let me
know and we can have a coffee together
you know just have coffee together you
know sometimes so so tired okay let's go
to my Emacs blog Emacs tired we're gonna
talk about diet yeah so let's so today
we're gonna talk about Emacs related
things practical Emacs not emag Lee's
but let's just focus on some tips about
Emacs
so diet you know let's see what we say
comment oh okay oh yeah Sacramento are
you
Sacramento did we have a chat on Twitter
about that how was it on math students
someone I remember recently someone you
know because I don't remember because I
have a lot of followers so sometimes I
don't remember who so let's go to let's
look at E max okay Emacs tired what do
we want to talk about so let's go to the
my talk show and it's meanwhile write
down what are we talking so we have a
like index what we covered today and
today okay so here is today today is
again look at the left panel okay so you
can see all the commands I call for
example right now I press a key space EU
and that's insert date and I have today
state and I press command control you
then call that command then it wants me
to ask what date format do I want for
example number three I get that
let's try it again for example number
five then I get Friday okay so today is
Friday August 16th
now I want to delete these two lines so
I can press a key look so I press I and
that caused the command CD current text
block and then you can just go to my you
know go to your web search engine and
just search for it
and you will find the Emacs Lisp code
for that so there it is and you can copy
the code put in your in init file and
you have it it's fantastic it deletes
any kind of for example like code it
deletes that I coded each side
I call it again
see you can like delete the whole thing
very quickly so now I don't want to save
it we close the file
don't say we open it you see we are back
here and you can see the command I code
is stopped open last closed
you see that's also very convenient
extremely convenient I close it I press
one key close it close it you know press
another key we open last closed person
of the key we open last curves super
convenient in order for that to happen
you need to use this command so close
current buffer because when you close a
buffer you need to tell Emacs you know
which you know you need to make a record
of what buffer you just closed otherwise
it's impossible to find out you know
whatever you closed so you need to use
the command closed current buffer it's
also on my website so let's talk about
Emacs now I wonder if I just should
directly start to you know come out
whatever in my brain in my head you know
or should I should we follow a fellow
kind of my tutorial so this is my
tutorial you can you can find it by just
search my name in Emacs and there is a
section devoted to tired so let's see
basic functions writing commands writing
scripts data structure oh this is eMac
list so let's go to practical Emacs
let's see if you can see the window oh
okay so it's hidden
yeah okay so this is good so okay so
some practical Emax there's a section
devoted to fire topic you know anything
related to file opening file closed file
tired copy file delete file manipulating
files everything is in this section fire
topic and usually I give you know first
of all I give the standard normal way to
do those things then I usually talk
about efficient way to do those things
so first of all the most important thing
is tired okay let's see the comments hi
guys so Isaac Sacramento home can zoo
hey honking sooo good morning as I don't
think okay good afternoon
not J naught J and SZ okay not J ok
tired so today we you know we're not
talking about Emacs stuff
Emacs tips so diet you know tired tired
stand for directory edit you know that
say Asian 1980s named dir you did
Stanford directory edit you know it's
kind of old-fashioned name basically it
means you know it's like in Mac OS you
have this this application code finder
you know this for example let me show
you
you can view file by oops
where did they change the oh yeah you
can use view file by you know by name or
by let's see icon Oh by you know there
are several ways to to look at the file
so let's do that again
and again you know right now I'm Emacs I
want to open the finder you know in Mac
it's called find
so let's do that so I can press a key
wait not this one okay
so I can press a key you see on the Left
panel you can see on the Left panel you
can see I call this command because I'll
open the external app Oh No this command
because I'm showing desktop so this is a
easy way to for Emacs to open whatever
is the current directory I mean this
file the file I mean it will just open
it and on Windows the application is
called Explorer you know that's windows
name
so you know it shows the window where
all the files you know you can view as a
picture so let's see view by picture so
or a bunch of files so let's go to the
high directory high directory is a bunch
of pictures you can see oh there's not
many pictures there so wait oh so let's
go to Emacs go to my Emacs blog go to
tired again look at the left hand left
panel you see all the commands and
hegemon in green deck so let's go to the
next directory now notice the the key
address that's the greater than sign
that will jump to the next directory
subdirectory you see you see address
again you see press again you see press
again then right now we are in these I
director you it's press ENTER to open it
a bunch of files now I directory is my
image files now let's look at let's look
at them go to the desktop you see cuz
I'll show you in desktop ok I don't want
that actually so I move the cursor to
somewhere else and showing this top you
see so this directory is full of images
so that's a command good to know
tired you know I wonder if I should like
make a
you know list of commands that what we
talked about where is it
section so today some talk show that
actually this should go to Emacs blog
anyway so the commands we talked about
so many commands okay so I'm a little
bit lost on what to cover exactly let's
go back to focus on tired then okay yeah
let's just you know focus on tired stuff
okay so tired tired stand for directory
edit you know I just pronounce it diet
so you can
so there's a great commands there's a
great command you want to know so this
command is called this way
tired jump okay so this is a great
command this command will go to the
directory where the current file is so
I'm going to call this command so this
is a good to know so I call this command
oops I call this command and I'm at the
directory of the current file this you
know you know kusa will be placed on the
current file so this this is the file so
I go to that directory so you can see
I'm in this directory and a bunch of
files so let me show you the commands
okay I'm going to so I call show in
desktop it shows the files in desktop
okay this this is some custom commands
you can have and they are several of
them okay let's go to diet so go to diet
let's go through the pictures directory
now show in desktop you see a bunch of
pictures but also you can close that you
can for example packing Emacs so for
example this is a picture let's see
another one
so for example this is a picture if if
you want to view it in a image dedicated
image application you can do that it's
very useful because in Emacs viewing
images doesn't work so well because
sometimes the image is huge and you
cannot shrink it you know it's it's not
so good so you can press another key you
see I'm viewing it in the preview which
is Mac's default application for viewing
the image so for example I go to this
one I press the key I'm doing this file
in preview and that command is called
you can see it here opening external
apps so that's another great command
let me put it here any of this command
you can just give it your own key you
know it's up to you because each person
is different depending on your keyboard
and so on so you can just assign a key
to to it for example I mean my keyboard
blog I go to I open this file and I go
to the directory now again look at the
left window you can see all my commands
let's see yeah it shows right yeah so
you see this is my image directory I
show in desktop you see I can now easily
see them and on the Mac you can also you
can do this in Windows you can like
magnify them you know so you you know
you get overview of all the pictures or
oh you know potentially thousands of
files so you can shrink them like that
close it packing Emacs
now for example I show this file let's
see let's show lets open someone okay
for example this picture it's so huge
now let's magnify the window it's so
huge and you cannot see the whole thing
now now this is this buffer is in image
mode so I think there is is some
commands to shrink the image image
decrease size so you press the minus
sign so let's try it
so emacs's cannot rescale image without
image mask magic you know so that is you
know it's painful then you have to
actually I have image magic installed
but you have to set it up you know
config so you usually unless you are
Emacs phonetic you know you really want
to do everything in Emacs but otherwise
it's more efficient if you just let me
show hold on so again if you just view
it you know I call the command opening
external
you can just view it in a dedicated
image viewer it's much more efficient
because then you can edit it you can
stuff okay so that command so the
command we just called is viewing
external app do we have it written down
here oh yeah open in external app okay
yeah so that's that's there okay let me
show you another another one so reopen
last closed reopen as close okay we are
back in this fire hold on a second so
let me show you the command let's write
it down so we open last close okay so
that sees a command close let's put it
here make a tag okay so reopen last
close reopen last goes okay this image
now suppose you want to edit in so
I can call command I don't have a
shortcut for that but the command name
is so opening I press ENTER then
is firing up you know you'll take
like 10 seconds for it to walk you know
is firing up by the way do you see
is my lip synced to my speech is a or
delay do you see your delay
is there delay between my video and my
lip you know my voice okay no TV a great
thank you
hey good morning in bathroom you so you
see I can open this image in and I
can they you know start to edit it you
know close it
discard changes actually quit games so I
save memory okay so that is opening get
can close it okay let me show you the
command sound opening get game okay oh
these are on my website you can find a
source code on my website okay so there
that's few commands now let's go back to
diet remember the topic is tired we're
gonna cover it slowly because because
there are so many things useful commands
so greens do you customize every mod to
use stuff like ease for example if you
view PDF in Emacs so do I cut so I'm
using stuff like ease the question is do
I customize every major mod so that
supplies keys will work smoothly in them
the the answer is no I
I only customized some of the major mod
I really use very much
then I customize you know I I may create
a keys for that yeah let me talk about
that maybe later okay so let me see
let's copy that let's maybe let's talk
about that after we discuss you know
tired so but there's another interesting
coming up you see let me magnify the
screen you see I just copied from the
chat box to Emacs but you see my cursor
it's rectangular now I I move the my
cursor now it becomes that thing it
becomes a things vertical i wide
that happened you see when that happens
that means there is a invisible
character this is very annoying when you
copy things from Twitter or from from
you know some some of the websites
usually you know they are they are using
invisible characters for example right
now there's an invisible character I can
tell because the cursor becomes a thing
vertical line you can find out by moving
the cursor to that character and call
describe cha okay let me show you the
name encode that so you can see now it
tells me so this is 0 with space okay
that's no good tipping so like when you
are writing your blog you know you copy
you know you copy some stuff you know
discuss that in your block then where to
you it it has this invisible invisible
characters which is typically annoying
so one way to find out so you want to
call the command let me show you the
command okay describe cha ok here is a
command so this is another command good
to know let me put it here so you can
see
so describe Chow is a great command that
command lets you find out for example
echo it it tells me the kusa position it
tells me you know what character it is
the code point and also in hexadecimal
it also tells me what font I'm using to
display that character which is here you
see you know so whenever you want to
find out what fund is used you can do
that describe Chao
and it also tells me what is a unicorn
name for this character
so this one is latin small letter C so
it's very useful describe ciao ok now
let's go back to the Unicode this
invisible car chart you see now now I
call echo describe cha it tells me it's
a 0 with space ok
don't want that I can just delete it for
example I can press the Delete key you
know now it's good but another way but
sometimes like hold on second sometimes
you have many of them like you cannot
tell maybe there's another one over here
so I actually created a command let me
tell you what the command the command is
this sod replays invisible ciao okay let
me put it here so that oops
so this sub replace invisible child let
me call it okay I call it you see it
moves the cursor to those invisible
chars and you see the mini mini prompt
it asked me whether I want to delete it
so I press Yes to replace yes and it
tells me we face one occurrence there's
no more so you know this is very useful
so we're gonna talk about do you
customize yeah let's talk about that
later let's go back to Emacs tired let's
see how long I've been talking okay
night people watching so okay so yeah
how long have I been talking 25 minutes
okay
so let's go back to diet okay we're
gonna we gonna talk about diet and and
what's the O then green deck says you
mean J ijkl no I almost never I never
modify a major mod for that no when I
mean a major mod for for example magic
magic is nasty because you know it has a
lot of problems with a soft I keys and
so basically I just switched to insert
mods so you know and use the physical
arrow keys you know so I don't I don't
want to mess with you know because yeah
I don't I don't do that
but if there is a major mod you use
really often you know like you know an
hour a day and and you are using stuff
like he's that is when then you probably
do want to fix that in some somehow to
get that fixed because you know moving
the arrow you know moving closer is
incredibly useful you don't want to use
the arrow keys or the ctrl P control and
you know those are no good but as far as
how to do that you know it songs off
like his page unless you know if you
actually have a question about that
green deck posted okay then we discuss
the details about that so let's go back
to Emacs tired so so the basics okay the
Emacs tired you know Emacs is tired is
tremendous tremendously useful because
once you get used to tired you never you
know go to the shell you know like no I
mean shell let's let's see ICD - can you
guys see it let me put these up yeah
yeah you can see the shell right yeah so
so ICD - one second okay so
okay ICD to ICD to my let's go to ogle
Emacs okay so you see I mean my web you
know my Emacs directory so I can do LS
and at least you know all my files
actually this is no good
and what else so you know I can do a iOS
and I can I can copy files you know like
I can you know a CP copy some files
that's no good okay because you know
back in you from 1993 to like 2004
2002 i working you know with you know a
most UNIX server Solaris you know
operating system sis at me and that's
what you do you know you have to CD you
know the UNIX to backs grab and so on
and top and stuff the good old UNIX days
you know I remember but but once you are
in tired you don't you know CP or move
or make the anymore like you know this
command move which is rename a file this
make you know create a new directory you
don't you don't use that anymore
everything is in tired for example let's
say I want to copy this file to a new
name okay I just press capital C and I
type a new name let's let's say xxx okay
enter it's created it's copied you see
this this is the new file you know this
this is new file this to file have the
exactly the same content okay okay well
anyway so so you see now I want to
delete this file so what I do i press
capital D wait so I press capital D D
ask me to do I want to delete I can say
yes or no okay I say no let's say so
capital D is one way to delete a file
another way is lowercase T
so I pressed lowercase T now again
observe the left window you can see all
the commands okay so now I press
lowercase T it marked the file to delete
okay you can you can mark several files
so example you can you know you can mark
all these files the capital T is for
delete now if I press X X means execute
so I press X it says td7 files yes or no
you see and on the left window you can
see the actual command name tire to flag
delete that's actual command name when
you press X so you ask me to delete them
no I don't want to because those are I
don't want to delete so actually I want
to delete only this xxx file so I need
to mark them type you to a mark look you
you you you you you you see on the left
you see the name is tired a mark so now
I just have one marked file to delete I
press X email semi asked me to delete
them I press Yes the is good and I can
this I don't want to DV okay so and I
can make a directory so you press + I
you see on the left you see tired create
directory then he asked me your name
let's say T DT wait wait so I I press T
DT okay enter you see this new directory
is created so if you compare to the
shell the keystrokes the number of
keystrokes you use for creating a new
directory copy fire out DVD fire is less
than if you actually type you know make
the copy move you know and also in a
shell it's error-prone because you don't
have a visual clue you know you you
might type the name your name and the
share will just overwrite the existing
files
well maybe you typed RM you know - f
delete a whole directory by mistake that
happened that is the hallmark that is me
you know they say rite of passage when
you use UNIX you delete a whole
directory of critical files that you
don't have backup this happened to me
begging you know in the company its
disaster you know it's gonna you could
not be fired but it happened to us to me
too so once you do
uuugh that stun you you know you gotta
be very very careful when you are in
unix and you know unix shell has a huge
bag of problems sometimes for example
you copy you know so is you know you
copy the whole buffer content and you
want to paste it but sometimes by
mistake you you pasted the hope of a
company shell and is it just start to
execute all of them like a command is
this a disaster you don't know what's
going on you know that's so when you use
you you know Linux or UNIX shell you
gotta be very careful that's the thing
but so with the tired you know
everything is visual for example right
now I mean in this new directory we just
created let's go up a directory so you
want to go up a directory you press the
correct size so let's do that
you see I'm up one directory now I want
to delete this directory we just created
so I press capital D yes it's deleted
and Emacs asked me you know do you also
want to delete that buffer yes you know
we don't need any because you know so
that is some of the example of
usefulness of tired you know once you
use tired you you get you know so much
in you know you don't you don't use
these shell commands anymore plus it's
visual you know you can mark for example
you can mock files you want you know you
can see it you know oh this you know
instead of you know
like if you want to copy a bunch of
files you say CP and share CP and you
know you you forgot the name you have to
you know command completion the name you
know it's no good but here for example
let me show you okay I split the buffer
I marked several file names I split the
buffer now I create a new buffer a new
directory let's say t2 okay create open
this is a new buffer now I want to copy
these files into that buffer so I just
say cat OC then yes it's all there you
see you see you see now let's look at
let's call let's look at in finder you
know in the windows they're in a you
know so you see you see I just created
this directory and copy those files and
but now let's say I want to delete the
hole I don't want that anymore
let's close this so I want to mark let's
say I want to amok all these so capital
you a mark okay now I want to delete
this new directory we just created so
capital D yes it's good so it's super
can be convenient now these are just
some of the basic these are the some of
the the most basic use of Emacs and by
the way if you forgot what's the key or
command you can always look up when you
are in tired you know once you switch to
diet there is the menu for example they
are like Emacs creates for for new menus
for it
which are you know the operate the mark
and the rejects and immediate so I and
also actually subset to the subdirectory
sir so Emacs creates like a bunch of new
new menu for it
so you can always just look at the menu
when you start to learn him about diet
you know not like it so has so many
commands not everyone remember or use
all of them you know but you pick the
one you know you just learn what you
need and and and keep coming for 10
years 20 years infinite learning that's
what Emacs is like so tired okay that's
the basic some of the basic example sub
tired let's close it wait
refresh what is this close it don't save
okay so let's shrink it shrink it okay
so some of the tired basics so describe
cha so so okay yeah so we covered the
basic tired operations now and there is
about mark in the mark which is you know
critical you know very useful if you
want to learn tired and also by the way
you can also mark by regular expression
for example let's go to my JavaScript
blog
okay this is my JavaScript web Dave
block okay now I go to diet
remember the command tired jump you know
it gets me into diet with the cursor on
the file okay let me cover another
command very useful suppose you want to
get the fire path of this file so in
Emacs the command is that the command
now look at the left window so in Emacs
the command is this okay
tired copy file name as kill now the
shortcut I have is W now I don't
remember if that's my custom key or the
if that's default but anyway when you
are entired you call this square
function and you will tell you what is
the default key for that so so so we
just act we just copied this file name
so
open a new buffer paste you see there it
is now suppose you want the full path
okay suppose you want to the full path
so what you do is control you which is a
universal argument then you press 0 ok
then you okay in hold on a second so
let's do it again control u 0 W ok now
let's go to the buffer paste you see now
we get you know you know that's the way
to copy the full file path they very
useful okay when you wherever you need a
file path so let me let me put the
commands in here so you can okay tired
copy file name is key oh that's very
useful but but for myself I have another
command to copy file name and that is
called sock copy file path ok now this
now this is the command ok this is my
custom command I have some improvements
so you might use it it you might it
might be preferable to the Emacs one for
example I can call it right now with you
know right now I mean I'm not in tired
but I can call the command return paste
you see this is the full path for the
current buffer so let's use useful
command but of course I can do it in
with the the tired way Emacs default way
by for example they mean let's
demonstrate
okay let's tired jump to the file to
diet now now I control you
0 W ok it's done now I close the diet
and paste you see exactly the same thing
but you know so
you know I have my own commands because
it has several improvements useful to me
okay so you know it's up to you which
one you like so we covered basic tired
oh and we are talking about mark files
by regular expression let's do a demo so
so I have this directory let's let's say
I want to mark all files ending in Jas
JavaScript okay so I press i press the
percentage sign or hold on percentage
sign em then II must ask me to enter a
regular expression let's say so I say
let's say Jas let's say Jarius dollar
sign okay Jarius dollar sign it says 68
matching files marked you don't see it
right now because it's it's it's a few
pages down so let's scroll down you see
those are JavaScript files we just
marked it you see now we can copy the
whole thing to another directory for
example you know we have showed that
before we can delete them or things like
that and by the way another command is
least not matching files for example I
can do this you know it shows me all the
JavaScript files
you know least matching oils so anyway
so let's go back to my
so that's the command and another
command is lease matching lines okay Oh
extremely useful commands these are used
almost every day okay let me show you
another diet command okay so another
basic of diary this navigation you know
G press G to refresh buffer like reload
okay
press the caret sign to go up a
directory press the greater than sign to
go next sub directory and press less
than sign to go to previous sub
directory so that that is the basics
that the most basics of diet and see any
questions type it okay let's then we're
gonna cover some tire customer
customization because they are some
customer a custard customization that's
super useful everyone should have it
done then there is let's talk about
batch rename files there's a great
command for batch rename by the way am I
to basics like you know some of you
Emacs users you already you know
probably already know these and if you
have any questions or you know you have
questions about what's your workflow in
this or that you know it's a great time
to ask so we can talk about that and so
yeah let me read the comments now let's
take a break and read the comments
hey Derek good morning
Bethlem you say is greetings Derek okay
[Laughter]
c3 yeah I should get habit to start to
announce my schedule yeah a lot of
people we asked me for that
let's okay so let me make a impromptu
decision like right now you know this is
like I'm typical like that like like my
life is no schedule yeah I'm a free man
you know I do is not scheduled but let
me make let's say I'm going to so after
today I'm going to make a schedule for
the next seven days you know so today is
what Friday okay so I yeah I make a
schedule so I'm going to post on the I'm
going to post on my Emacs
what should I post it I'm going to I'm
going to post my Emacs blog or okay
another problem you know where do am I
going to post it because if I just you
know because again you know like my
YouTube the the topics are diverse you
know some like some people just they
only are interested in Emacs and
sometimes I talk about JavaScript
programming languages and they are all
technical so that's still good but
sometimes I talk about non technical
stuff like social issues YouTube music
you know that's when some people really
don't want to see it you know they it's
like you know especially today in our
society like you know you don't like
something you don't really want to see
so so if I post my schedule on my Emacs
blog then that means a lot of my Emacs
will follows we will see oxides gonna
talk about some of these things they
don't really they don't really want to
see things like that and
yeah so so I'm thinking so anyway I'm
trying to make a schedule but where am I
going to post it because I can also I
post on Twitter often but I know a lot
of you don't use Twitter which is
actually a good thing you know Twitter
is these hell anger hell sucks your time
it's like a TV makes you angry about
everything and anyway let's focus on
Emacs okay so anyway I'm going to make
great schedule I'm gonna post somewhere
I don't know where now but I'm gonna so
so in the next seven days also I'm going
to have like I give a time for each day
and what topic we're gonna talk about
some of them is going to be a technical
tutorial on JavaScript and some will be
Emacs tips back today and some will be
in Emacs Lisp live coding and I'm gonna
also explain and teach about eMac this
coding okay then some of some of them
will be probably be : and some will be
non-technical then yeah so let's do that
so let's say I'm going to post on my
Emacs blog okay yeah so today before
midnight you know basically in within 10
hours we think yeah twelve hours I'm
going to post that huh you'll find it on
my Amex block let's say that so that so
that's one that's that let me read
comments then then we're gonna talk
about Emacs some of the critical very
extremely useful Emacs customers
customizations okay by the way I know
it's missus interesting I know a lot of
people say you know I know people who
don't use tired in Emacs this is very
strange especially I know a guy who is a
great program my boss my
expos you know back to the 20 years ago
Edna Tapia okay he doesn't use diet and
in fact the way he used Emacs is that in
shell you know when he wants to edit
some file he says you know he says you
know he start Emacs then file name okay
like index dot HTML okay that's what he
do
this is extremely EDI so he start Emacs
okay and then you know so now Emacs is
launched then he added it then he quit
let's see command control seek control X
control C okay save desktop no okay then
he quit that's that's the way he used
Emacs it's incredibly inefficient you
know but so he's a Emacs user and he is
a master code it's not like he doesn't
know things he you know he he wrote he
wrote the one of the first web ecommerce
system in Java and Perl back into the
year 2000 okay so that's you know very
funny and a lot of people I know from
reddit you know Emacs community I know
that they don't use the diet for some
reason you know then some people use the
Sun some there's a ones things called
something sunshine or something
commanded by the way anyone remember the
name you know like very famous the end
you know there's also note and commanded
but anyway there is a major mod you know
Emacs mob that emulates that so they use
that you know so but anyway I use tired
I just you know I have been using diet
you know for 20 years and I don't
basically I only use tired I don't use
you know there's also tree you know some
tired tree or things like that I don't
use them
so let's let me read the comments
so Beth Lemieux says respect the privacy
of others think before you type with
great power comes great with smallest
responsibilities that's not a good thing
to say okay well that's my personal
thing you know whenever you hear people
that says with great power comes great
responsibility you know that's one of
the famous line from spider-man
you read anyway that's another topic in
bathroom you you are in Germany right
how did you pick up that line
it's no good like green deck says so you
are again it's living in emacs oh ok so
regarding the question about living in
emacs wait let me clean my eyes so you
know my grass is I need to change my
glasses now I use this glass my eye gets
tired this is very bad quality so anyway
so about living in emacs you know so let
me explain that a lot people they live
in well I also living in emacs but not
to not not like the extremists you know
like there are some people who really
wants to do everything in like a Mac so
example viewing image image files you
know they they rather they don't want to
open external viewers they you know
whatever Emacs you know they and also
they want to view PDF files in Emacs
that's not good ok let me show you some
examples let me show you examples ok so
let's go to my math block ok open it now
go to the math textbooks so these are
great math textbooks I have collected
open it
so let's go to for example let's see
calculus okay so so let's open so for
example there is this calculus textbook
could calculates textbook you know you
don't see the PDF here because I have
JavaScript off but you can okay let me
show you another thing I have this
command so cool so you see on Firefox
I have JavaScript off that's why the PDF
is not showing but in chrome I have it
on so it will show if I you know display
this page in chrome so there here is
that here is a great command okay so I
call the command saw okay so let's try
view in Safari okay let's just call
Safari Safari okay so open link in
Safari okay
I call it your launch safari in Safari I
have JavaScript on so let's wait it to
load to launch what is that close that
right
let's try it again Oh I called the wrong
command
I was calling open link in Safari you
know my cursor needs to be only linked
but rather they are rather what I want
is opening Safari not open linking
Safari so open in Safari you see now it
shows you know it opens this buffer in
Safari so I can see it
and there's another command open link in
Safari for example if I put the cursor
on this PDF link line and I call open
link in Safari enter you see now the PDF
is showing in Safari this is great you
know today in browsers you can view PDF
in Chrome in Safari in Firefox too but
you have to have I think you have to
have the yeah you need Java Script on in
order to do so but and there's but of
course there's also dedicated let me
show you so again let's call diet diet
you know let's go diet if I actually
just open this PDF file diet jump now we
are in tired in that directory you see
this is the file PDF now show in finder
you see this is a PDF now if I open it
double click now this is preview which
is max default PDF viewer you see very
convenient you know this PDF viewer okay
so we have showed several things
let me type it and show you close close
close okay hold on a second let me show
you okay let's close all that
okay
okay here those are the comments okay
open link in Safari open Safari and what
is it and by the way there is also open
linking brave and there's also opening
brave okay all these hakama my custom
commands you can find it you can find it
on my website I think okay so it's not
on my website but it's in my Emacs in it
on github so you just search for sorry
github you will find the source code for
these four commands now this so what the
point I want to mention is that the PDF
okay yeah PDF so so we have seen you
know you can view them in browser and
you can view them in dedicated dedicated
PDF viewer but you can also view them in
Emacs but however is sucks it sucks
donkey ass because when you try to I
cannot do it on the Mac I don't think I
mean let's try so open open eyes closed
open eyes closed open eyes closed we are
back into the fact in this file that has
the PDF link here see so open so let's
open it so this is a PDF file let's
let's let's call the command PDF mod
this is the Emacs default way to view
PDF files it's not coop IDF file
it's not called PDF not mod what what is
the name for that mod yeah sunrise
commander that's the another thing for
diet you know similar to tired utility
by the way so what what what is the
command for for viewing
EF files I know the guy who wrote that
it's basically it's just no good okay
let me talk about that anyone so it's
such okay so another problem with Emacs
he said usually they don't name the
commands in an intuitive way you know
they try to name it in some kind of
generalized way so the command to view
PDF is called view something view does
anyone know am I still going so you must
you're alive yes what what is a command
naming Emacs that view PDF
okay so this let's digress and let's get
into another general solution to how do
you find a command name when you when
you don't know you know exactly what is
the name so let's you know let's see
what we can do so right now I want to
find the building
Emacs command name that view PDF now I
don't remember what it is definitely
it's not definitely the name does not
contain PDF so in general the command
yuko is this apropos command okay let's
hold on a second so wait wait yes I'm
still alive so although I've been
talking so you guys so you guys don't
know what's a command name to open PDF
files who is asking that question you
should know come on great green deck you
you are spouses living in Emacs you
should know that commands write PDF so
okay so a proposed command so let's try
a propos command view okay let's so
right now we call a proper command then
we type view then at least all Emacs
commands that contains the name view and
we can just go through them to see if we
can spot the command that view PDF
okay we're getting I need to finish this
because I think we are getting Wow Oh
one hour already so they mean yes let's
go back to Emacs then finish Oh doc doc
okay there it is doc view but this
idiotic me max command I think that is
it
so you see talk of you mod so we have
covered so we you know talk to you mod
okay so it's press enter let's see what
it says that view mod is an interactive
function blah blah blah so major mark in
Park View buffer stock view Mahdi's and
Emacs yeah it displays PDF PostScript
and so on there it is okay we have found
it so so okay a proper command okay that
is the name to locate the command you
you forgot okay and then we talk about
this PDF let me show you let me finish
the topic about PDF so doctor you mod
okay so now let's go back to that PDF
file okay so we open a scope and we open
reopen there it is okay wait open the
PDF now let's call doc view mod
Oh God you see only it says unable to
render file view extracted text instead
no because PDF is a very complicated
file usually it's not text you know it's
binary so anyway we cannot do it on the
Mac but on Linux typically it's set up
so you can actually view PDF file but
what it actually does is that it tries
to convert every PDF file it try to
render it then convert that page into a
PNG file then open the PNG file so is it
is extremely inefficient idiotic
basically ok so you know you is how to
understand some people like that you
know so I do so this is no good so I do
not recommend using a building command
to view PDF because you open it if you
know even if it works on Linux you wait
for you know you you wait for half half
a minute or one minute you know to
render each page as PNG you know it
actually convert into an image file and
then show PNG it's it's basically
unusable but in Emacs merely it's you
know it's incredible it's like one plus
one equals two three you will hear
people say oh this is great oh yeah max
you know you can view PDF you know it's
utterly impossible incredible so anyway
that's a situation with PDF view PDF now
so we are talking about living in Emacs
concept you know some people they they
want to read emails in Emacs they want
to play music in Emacs like mp3 music
you know you can you can do that they
want to view kaki you know two calendars
calculators calendars everything they I
asked each at you know IRC chat Twitter
Amy max you can do that but in general
you know I've tried to do that you know
I've been using Emacs for 20 years you
know I've used you know I've tried all
that basically here's my conclusion okay
you could do that but
generally in general it's no good
because one you will take tremendous
effort to set them off set them up for
example if you want to read emails you
know you're gonna take hours in your
days to set it up okay now if you want
to for example right now I'm I'm only a
Mac I want to set up you know viewing
PDF within Emacs you know what I need to
do is you know I need to start to config
the path you know it's it's it's you
know this is gonna be our at this one a
half an hour at least you know you
cannot start to read the table you know
how does you know how to do that and so
on then you know so it's going to take
tremendous time and effort to convict
them and also it's not like do it once
and it's good for ever no because
especially things like email things
change the server Google server and
whatever server and Technology HTTPS
encryption you know they change all the
time so every year every two years
you're gonna spend you know our out days
to change your config you know things
like that so it's tremendous and the
same thing with IRC you know Twitter you
know the network the server changed you
know then next day there's new protocol
you know it's headache you know so
tremendous time to configure them that's
one thing to let me write it down okay
leaving in Emacs some go to extremes
such as to everything in Emacs including
email view PDF music player control IRC
Twitter
and stuff okay lots lots of stuff my
conclusion it's no good because two
reasons one tremendous time to set up
okay
to to it is actually extremely it is
typically extremely inefficient and
impractical in emacs
okay for example I we have just showed
the example with PDF it actually convert
each page you know it tries to render it
and convert each page to an image file
then display that image just that page
on imaginary it's extremely inefficient
that's PDF example now for emails in IRC
and also even though I all see like
twenty ten years ago I tried it you know
in IRC in Emacs pure text no images
compared to a dated dedicated IRC chat
program on the Mac then you look at the
past you know process you know the CPU
usage Emacs actually uses momentum more
memory and more process usage then the
dedicated IRC chat program that that
features you know images you know
profile photos images and all the nice
things and also you max it see when
things you could do those things in
emaddix eMac this is not actually a
general language so you have all these
inefficiencies okay
I have compared you know you can try it
you know if you are using IRC email Siri
and compare it to
located you know chat program and you
can look at the process and see which
one uses more memory you know Emacs
typically uses actually actually it's
you know you don't have much features
and then it actually consumes more
memory and stuff but of course in living
in max you have many advantage because I
can control like my windows my you know
my Maya breathe you know everything is
so nice but there are so many flaws and
problems as well so in general I don't
do that I still living in max but but I
don't go you know I don't push it to to
do anything that Emacs is not you know
deeds designed to do which is in general
I you only use Emacs for programming in
text stuff not for music or images or
email or IRC you know I don't use that
anymore
so that's about living in Emacs
so actually we we are we have been
talking Frank let's let's do five five
minutes or ten for let's cover this
hey hey hey Scott good morning there is
some more one more thing I want to cover
I should really finish today is five
five minutes we are we need to cover
this topic about some of the very basic
tired setup let me just talk about that
then we're gonna read the comments okay
now some very fundamental diet set up
okay this one tired hide detail by mod
this command tired hide detail smart
okay let me show you okay so this is
tired notice on the left side it shows
the permission and the owner's name this
UNIX stuff okay and bite you know size
and stuff you can hide them by calling
what's the command by tired hide details
Mon okay tired hide details one okay so
you can you know now you only see file
names so that's one thing you can set up
and if you want that you know you can
put it in your in it this code oops I
clicked by mistake
so this there's this in it you put it in
your unit and you know then you have
that so that's one useful setup now this
one now this delete are actually copy
directory this is extremely useful
because you know let me show you okay in
tired I straight window then let's go to
go to the previous directory parent
directory let's say I go to this
directory symbols now I can okay let's
go up directory okay split now for
example I can copy this directory I can
press C hold on so let's go to the talk
show okay suppose I want to copy this
directory to this
over here I can just press C capital C
to do that but however by default you
cannot do that because Emacs Emacs is
set up to prevent you from accidentally
copy or delete a directory
you know the whole directory so but if
you want to do that you want to set put
this in your in it you know tired
recursive copies you know quote always
things like that so that's what you want
to do okay now there's another thing
useful to you want to do for example
when I want to copy this directory
typically email okay typically I say a
press capital C okay then Emacs is going
to ask me to type a directory name where
I want to copy to now with completion
you know of course you can do completion
but but still is typically very tedious
so instead you can have you can speed a
window you can navigate navigate to a
different directory never navigate to a
destination directory then now if you
say copy the destination will be
automatically be the the directory in a
split pane so in order for this to
happen you want to set up this this
variable tired tired dream target true
okay so put that in your unit then
whenever you want to copy from you know
source and destination you just split
pane into two and put one of the pen to
the destination and that way it's a this
is great
okay man tired
mock tired use the same buffer full view
now okay so there are some other tips
you can read I'm not going to talk about
them
okay this one tired X also tremendous
use tremendously useful I recommend it
yeah so just put required eye attacks in
your in it I think by now it's it's
probably already loaded by default I am
Not sure we can find out by actually we
can find out by you know launch Emacs
with dash Q that we are you know so this
is the default Emacs without any in it
then we can find out by calling you know
we want to find out if tired X is
already loaded we can find out by what
needs to come and I forgot I'm getting a
bit tired now
we've been talking for 80 minutes I
forgot what's a command but features
okay so so we want to find out whether
the tired X tired a sex symbol is
already already loaded so to do that you
can look up the value for the symbol
features okay let's do that
so describe let's call describe
describe variable okay enter now type
the variable name featured fe80 you are
e features okay
t you are yes okay now you can see it
shows me the value of the variable
features okay and now you just have to
search whether it contains tired X so
let's try that control ex dir IDI no
okay so this is how you find out you
know now we know the answer Emacs
version 26 by default does not load
tired X so you actually if you want that
you want to put this in your in it you
know we are doing some extra you know
some tips you know on the fly you know
practical you know day-to-day use issues
and how to get the answers so that's
that's about that so let's close that so
we we talked about describe ba okay very
useful and we talked about features okay
so feed the variable features okay
okay so actually so let me read the
comments and we'll be we are done today
check if I'm still alive
correct
so Barrios asked can use sometimes
evaporate on the priority of key
bindings between minor and major mods I
saw the page on your website but it's
not quite clear okay we can talk about
that oops
copy okay so basically okay so let's go
to my website let me tell you
so basically minor mods all minor ones
any minor mod has priority over well
actually it's more complicated than that
in general in general any minor mods key
binding has priority over any major mods
key binding however there are there are
other things also because in Emacs you
can define a key binding depending on
where where your text where your cursor
is that is for example if I eat for
example on this text for example on this
line in this slide specifically I can
define a key binding specific to this
line for example when if my cursor is on
this line then I if I pressed ctrl K for
example you know do some commands but if
my cursor is outside this line then you
do some other general commands you see
so this is called text properties so in
short ensure that means you can define
your key binding that is specific to a
particularly particular text now that is
why
for example when you do let's see
you see in this you know forward word
this this is the documentation for
forward you see all these links I press
ENTER you see these links those are
highly highlighted in blue you press
ENTER then you go up to them you see
let's try it again okay now how is that
do you know so if I press ENTER on this
on this word on this particular word it
will actually call the command that
actually jump to that that you know
whatever that command is supposed to do
that is implemented by what's called
text properties meaning basically means
in eMac base view assigning a property
to this this specific text and one of
the property is key binding you know so
that means when you when your cursor is
on this text when you press the key that
key binding whatever it is has priority
nope you know on top it before anything
else you know this so and in any mod
image your mod or my nama they can do
that so when you have this happens so so
it's not it's not just like oh my no mod
comes before major mod no because you
can have this you know text specific you
know key bindings that can be you know
that can be defined in any minor mod or
major mod so you know so you have to
first of all you have to find out when
you press the key something happens you
have to find out exactly you know
whether it's text property key binding
or with where it came from
oh it's came from minor motto it's came
from major mark so it's a little bit
more complicated so in order to when you
have problems like that first of all you
when you encounter problem you want to
call describe key okay which is this
command
describe key okay let me put it here
this are all the important default I
mean you know building in Emacs command
describe key so you could describe key
to see what command it is actually code
then you look at you you look up that
command describe you know describe
function to look up that command to see
exactly what it does and where it came
from
now this is when you know you know
whether that command comes comes from a
major mod or minor mom so that's a bit
complicated complicated I think that's
it for today I kind of you know okay so
one more two more questions because I'm
getting hot here and you know I'm Guinea
I've been talking for like almost 90
minutes
I read my email just I just go to a
browser that's that's what I do so
[Music]
hey good morning scarce marks car sales
I've tried that it's best to that the
best tour speed the best tours yeah yeah
that's what I do as well
yeah so Scott says for instance I have
an oak link that will open our look to a
specific email message yeah yeah that's
what I do
so you customize you acts so you can
like open the external apps or open
specific things like that yeah so so
Scott has given up using Usenet an email
oh you're always giving up using Emacs
for those things yeah so well for me
better amuses what about the RSS thing I
proposed you're talking about my youtube
schedules I don't know about YouTube I
think on YouTube by default they have
says right bathroom you are you still
there
I could type it type it you're like let
me I'm hot let me get my fat ok type
type it ok yes YouTube schedule on a
second so this is Chinese so anyway this
is about to end this is we are thankful
we have done Muse Christian ISS ISS well
RSS on YouTube you know you can this RSS
for YouTube channels I think but I don't
know how do you get that I don't know
you have to go to youtube but I think
this you know that I'm sure that this
ISS link to my channels but however that
is not for scheduling I mean that's like
whenever I have a video that's already
done like after I finished today after
one hour it will be you know uploaded to
my web you know my McSally channel
YouTube channel and then I think it's OB
ISS so but ISS is not for live
scheduling you know like for the next 10
days I'm going to I don't think ISS will
have that
so okay so you are talking about
announcement over ISS yeah but I don't I
I cannot do that over YouTube I mean I
don't think YouTube allows you to it's
all generated it's all automatic I don't
think there is a way to actually you see
YouTube is you know it's Google stuff
you know they control the their RSS I
don't and this tastes you don't have
anything you know you don't have much
things like documentation or spec
because they change all the time like
use the interface instead of the
experiment and change all the time
you know RSS used to be popular today
it's like few people actually use it so
as far as announcement I'll just make
announcement yeah I'll make us
announcement on my Emacs blog and my
Emacs block is has ISS so you will you
will also see it yeah so yeah so my
Emacs block okay and you know like my
stuff support me I have like links to my
patreon or by my Emacs tutorial or by a
keyboard on my website you know stuff
like that
that's it for today thank you for
watching and have a good day bye