hello guys good morning everyone welcome
to another episode of talk show we are
going to code Advent of
code this year so today Advent code
2024 um problem problem
one okay let's have some
eggnog eggnog 14% alcohol something
so this is going to be eggnog coding and
I'm coding in wolam
language let's see how it goes I heard
the day one problem is not too
hard okay that's not too
much fantastic amazing Advent of
code I hope you guys had a good holiday
I mean the
Thanksgiving um and
uh here's me my keyboards glove 80
fantastic you should go buy it or give
it to to your friend glove 80 this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard also fantastic
I have reviews on my website and there
is the um small board sorry I I haven't
got to it yet so I'll get on to it so
the code let's do it today uh yeah so
let's see yeah so emx ready wam language
ready and if you have not already join s
Discord you can find the invitation link
ons.info
apparently we have three people who are
doing Advent of
code uh we are doing it so one is C++
one is um
something go
land okay let's let's begin let's
see uh if you are here say hi if you are
not here skip around play at 1.5 speed
speed so we got this x I solved it
already it was pretty easy okay let's
see yeah I heard it it is easy okay so
this needs to be moved
here
um
here okay big
one the chief
historian is always present for the big
Christmas slide launch but nobody has
seen him in months last anyone heard he
was visiting locations that are
historically significant to the North
Pole so you got the Chief historian a
group of senior historians has asked you
to accompany them as they check the
places they think he was most likely to
visit as each location is checked they
will mark it on their list with a
star okay mark it on a list with a star
they figure the chief historian must be
in one of the first 50 places they look
so in order to save Christmas you need
to help them get 50 stars on their list
before santar takes off on December
25th collect Stars by solving puzzles
two puzzles will be made available on
each day in the Advent calendar the
second puzzle is unlocked when you
complete the first each puzzle grants
one star good Lu okay that's not even a
problem that's just introduction to
Advent of code so you you haven't even
left yet and the group of Elish Senor
historians has already hit a problem
their list of locations to check is
currently empty okay eventually someone
decide decides that the best place to
check first would be the chief
historian's office okay upon pouring
into the office everyone confirms that
the chief historian is indeed nowhere to
be found instead the eles discover an
assortment of notes and lists of
historically significant locations this
seems to be the planning the chief
historian was doing before he
left okay so there is some um uh
assortment of notes okay and list of
locations okay
so perhaps these notes can be used to
determine which location to search
through out the chief's office the his
the historically significant locations
are listed not by name but by a unique
number called the location ID to make
sure they don't miss anything the
historians split into two groups each
searching the office and trying to
create their own complete list of
location IDs
okay so you're going to be working with
uh there's just one problem by holding
the two lists up side by side your puzz
input it quickly became clear that the
lists aren't very similar maybe you can
help the historians reconcile their
lists okay so you got two columns of
numbers each number is supposed to be a
location ID okay so maybe the list so
can you see it yes so maybe the lists
are only off by a small amount to find
out pair of the numbers and measure how
far apart they are so you check the
difference pair up the smallest number
in the left list with the smallest
number in the right list okay then the
second smallest left number with the
second smallest right number and so on
so essentially you order them first then
you pay then you compute the difference
in each pair within each pair figure out
how far apart the two numbers are you
need to add up all of those distances
okay the difference they call a distance
for example if you pair up a three from
the left list with a seven from the
right list okay let's see three on the
left so there are three
threes uh and uh what there's no seven
on the right
what with a seven from the right is the
distance apart is four
um okay if you pair up nine with three
the distance apart is six okay so in the
example listed above the pairs and
distance would be as follows the
smallest number in the left list is one
check uh and the smallest number in the
right is three
check the distance between them is two
okay check
the second smallest and blah blah blah
well let's go through the second
smallest is two uh then then the second
smallest three so two three yeah
check um then the third smallest is
three and uh in both are three so let's
say 3 three 3 3 three one two yeah okay
so uh
third yeah it's three two so 3 three is
zero this difference is zero next number
pair is 38 four distance one fifth
number something something uh these are
distance of five apart uh
weight finally the largest number in the
left is four while the largest in the
right is nine four and nine okay let's
check four and nine by the way I heard
there are people who finish this problem
in 5 seconds
like in 5 seconds and the second problem
in 4 seconds so you know see was looking
into so if you even if they are cheating
that's incredible speed 9 seconds total
solving this
problem so anyway to find the total
distance between the left list and the
right list at the distances between all
the pairs you found okay then you you
know then there's a sum okay you your
actual left and right list contain many
location IDs what is a total distance
okay and it seems so it's easy problem
many people have said so so there it is
let's
begin uh by the way this image is
generated by gr AI bot and uh that's on
x.com and what is interesting about this
AI generated image is that you ask G to
draw you based on your
uh based on your post so it's
interesting so you know it becames a
fashionable thing for people to do a
meane you know so you just type in G uh
where is it let me show you okay
beautiful girl amazing beautiful the
center of humanity
this we have quite a lot uh and so you
know I talked about the AI generation so
here is you know so here is the image
Draw Me based on my treats and go came
up with that that's very interesting
because uh and by the way says ask ask
chat GPD to draw me so apparently this
is apparently this is based on uh for my
website because I do have a photo of me
using this
iMac uh so anyway so that's interesting
anyway let's not talk about this
um we did the episode about three month
ago or four uh about AI image
generation so anyway let's go back let's
work on this problem so okay so there is
your input let's begin uh yeah so let's
begin wam language we can finish this in
an hour in maybe maybe 30 minutes
actually so wolam language if you don't
know I'm using S wolam mod that allows
you to uh code wolam language in emac uh
and here is a wam language we're going
to use it too this is a wolam notepad
you it's free just search for S wolam
Language tutorial you'll find the link
to download it's officially free um
uh
okay okay so the input is let's just say
that uh okay so that's that's input so
you have to pause it okay so
uh oh I haven't haven't coded wam
language for a while string split okay
now string
split X input let's just name that
uh by default it will input um I forgot
but let's just say
X2
uh
X2 equals to that and X3
uh X3 you know by now some of these
people already finished the
problem uh let's see let's see what we
got okay
so tap e to Eva region no that's not the
command tap control h what is the
key from EV region tab R okay tab R
let's see what is the
result okay so you got the list mhm
so you got a flat list so now you can
just partition
it okay
um 5% drunk not
yet so you got at least like two like
that so let's say X3 equals to uh what
what
what that that key okay equal so uh
partition okay
partition uh not partial D okay
partition partition that that will split
the list into Su lists of each n
elements okay so partition X2 by two so
that you get pairs okay eval the whole
thing let's
see there it is so how beautiful this is
this is wam language is the most
advanced high level the highest level
langu language one wol from language
equals to 10 to a thousand python lines
of
code uh you know if you don't count the
math functions it's it's about one
language one lines like 100 lines of
python okay so there it is so you got so
now you just need to find the difference
okay now let me just do it uh
transpose transpose X3
then just um then you just apply minus
okay substract uh what is the I forgot
what is the
um keyword for minus I mean the full
function name for the minus
operator I forgot so let's ask wam
language okay so you just say full form
okay full form and what I want is uh
x minus y okay let's see what it tells
you shift
enter oh okay so it does uh what does it
do it does so yeah so you see minus
operation in in formal mathematics is
considered the inverse operation of
addition so minus became just addition
addition of a
number you know so minus a number means
The Addictive inverse of that number so
in in other
words when you have a number say let's
say3 in mathematics you can consider it
as a formal way you consider that as as
a number whose addictive
inverse is three
okay you know that's that's how you
think about this that I mean that that
is why so anyway so we transpose and we
just want to find the difference
so uh uh
what so how do
we what is the I mean I want a single
functional operation for substract
I I think it's just minus CD
me yeah there it is yeah so I was see
anyway so anyway let's just do M so you
transpose this then you apply minus okay
uh you can just do this okay now you
don't you won't understand this but let
me just run it you'll see It'll show the
differences okay now uh you
wait okay so actually you don't even
transpose uh okay so you can just apply
minus uh let's map okay so
map
minus okay map the minus function
2x3 so actually we don't want to map
minus so because
um uh let me just work it out okay
function
X
um what are we doing
so that will work okay so let's just run
it you uh okay no
[Music]
um map the function the function and the
apply the
minus cod with two arguments oh so
actually not
minus and do we have
substract
no interesting let's look
and annoying uh yeah oh there there is
substract there it is this is very old I
believe let's see the function 1988
right yeah subtract is what we want not
minus
okay substract
what
subract why don't I have the substract
symbol
completion wait uh maybe there's a bug
in WFAN mod let's say 32 okay let's
evaluate this
line
what oh subtract not substract substra
Idiot me yeah there it is okay so
yeah evaluate
that is one that's correct okay so you
just want that evaluate the whole
buffer there it is that that gives you
the difference now except that these are
you see it doesn't evaluate the reason
is that because those are actually
strings so we forgot to convert this
string into a number so you need to
convert it to a number so let's do that
here okay so
um two
expression that's how you convert a
string to uh number Okay add that okay
now evaluate the whole
thing you see fantastic now all you have
to do is just say
total at evaluate the whole
buffer negative 11 oh and you forgot to
order them you need you are supposed to
order them okay so yeah yeah so if you
want to order them then let's do a
transpose okay
then
transpose okay transpose
X3 then you got then you got a row of
the columns the
second uh part is the right column the
first part is the left column okay once
you trans post you just sort
them uh actually we can run it so you
can see the intermediate
result uh no okay no is not correct
what what X3 run
it no no is not correct
uh why can this be a
string okay
problem
problem okay so you need to see exactly
what is this output so let's try it
here shift enter not control enter shift
enter
so
X2 post fix
notation take the
first okay shift enter three then um but
is that is that a string or number
so okay so percentage sign means the
last output then postfix not ation then
string q q stand for question enter so
it's a string
so um so now you do two
expression at
X2 now those are numbers now shift
control L to copy it these are numbers
that's right now if you do this shift
control L those are strings you see
that's a
difference um okay so two expression is
right so why is
that so when U2 expression that turns
actually that's why don't we put it here
okay so
now R
it oh no yeah no because well because
you got a semicolon there so if you put
X2
there uh it's still new so what the
is going on
spring split two expression so that's
not supposed to be new my
friend what
oh okay yeah that's right because of
this you got a I got a no in emac wam
language because I got commented stuff
there because otherwise if I put this
bottom then it would not be noral that's
right you see so actually our code is
all correct so now these are numbers now
then you partition the number
numbers uh then you print X3 let's print
it here run
it so that's right so that's right you
got group then you transpose it um and
uh you transpose it and run
it you see so 3
42133 that's the First Column yeah and
now all you have have to do is sort them
so you just say
map
sort and uh the second argument is just
going to be
that so you got 1 2 3 3 3 4 that's
correct okay now copy this so that we
can see what's going on so and uh so
after you saw them you just make the
difference okay so then you just um
subtract okay so you just
apply
apply uh uh there's a English issue for
some reason I always thought of as
substract okay instead of
subtract uh yeah it should be subtract
so apply subtract to so let's put this
X4
okay uh so subtract
X4 then you just got a list of
differences okay then you just
total hello guys s Sia do you prefer
wolam land or emac
this wam language of course by a
magnitude
uh there's subtleties about that let me
explain so anyway the solution to this
toy problem is negative 11 okay let's
check uh is
11 okay so how does it deal with
the let's
see do they how do they take the
difference okay so the smallest number
in the first left is one then the
smallest number uh they only want okay
so they want the absolute value of the
distance that is why they don't call it
they don't call it the difference they
just call it distance okay
tricky uh you see they they they don't
want you
know why don't they want it negative
because
um because when you have a distance the
problem is slightly more complicated
because then you have to either find out
which which one is the bigger number
then you can minus or you minus then
take the absolute value okay so we can
do that okay so apply
substract then then uh just absolute
value okay
so
um absolute value is ABS okay let's look
up documentation
uh why is it taking long time so turn on
JavaScript ABS gives the absolute
value of real complex number so that's
right so you give the apps yeah so so
that is it let's run
it 11
fantastic now we can combine this all
two one single line but let's not bother
okay so let's uh try the get my personal
input okay big numbers big numbers big
big
Lotus put it
there and uh let's just overwrite it
it's ugly but nobody cares because the
Advent of code I really you I noticed
you know it doesn't care if your
solution is elegant or not
all it car if is that it just want the
number okay now so the number is that so
this problem is easy we solved it um
fairly certain paste it do I double
check no submit that's the right answer
now you got to go start continue to part
two okay let's see okay intermission
let's talk about the emac Lis versus wam
language and versus other languages
because language perving computer
language perving is my
expertise this looks like a Lambda
expression which
one so I also solved using
C++ okay so this guy are you which one
which qu guys are you are you on Discord
so anyway this a easy problem okay so
the the the question emac this versus R
language okay you see there's no
comparison and it's not fair because EAC
dis is the language that you can only
use in
emac and the
area it's actually so-called um domain
specific language so emac LP is not
really a general purpose language
what's a general P purpose language
Pearl python Ruby JavaScript C C++ goand
c f
hascal and so on those are general
purpose okay that you can use them to
write just about
anything
uh EAC L is not because you can you can
only run it in emac this I mean in emac
that's I mean you could run it as a
script but you know it's not it's it's
not feasible okay because in any of
those language I just mentioned they
need in order to be Industrial Level
like not just one man's hobby like a lot
of people has you know I'm going to
write a compiler you know that's you
know greatest language I designed it but
that's one man's Hobby in order to be
really truly useful you need you need
lots of Library libraries to access
database and they need to be efficient
okay to access database to access to in
in interconnection with other systems to
uh talk to uh Unix pipes to uh talk to
uh or or do HTTP uh go through you know
libraries for various
protocols you know so you need to have
that then and to be able to do them in a
efficient way and massive scale then you
can code your language a general purpose
language so Pearl python Ruby
JavaScript Java C C++
C they are they are all they are general
purpose goand and
rust
okay
now of course among them there's also
there are still differences for example
python Ruby Pearl you don't really use
them to write the operating system
anyway so that that's getting into
different thing but anyway so they are
general purpose and in each of these
language you have very efficient
libraries to um access database you know
like billions B Petra petas something
exra numbers you know uh massive scale
and um so what about emag LEP well you
you know so you cannot do that okay so
besides you need these libraries you you
also of course you need a system to call
them you know you need name space you
need name space because your code is
going to be millions of lines emac
cannot do that okay I love emac but you
know among the emac Fanatics you got
these people they saying that oh I love
emac emac is best language but actually
in reality speaking of reality emac
compared to all these python PE Ruby
emac is okay it's worth worth less
than you know you you don't have
name space you don't have a library
system you just well you do but yeah
it's for like efficient you know you
know for editing deleting text and
things like that you know you cannot can
Google use emac dis to access their pet
pety database no but can Google do do
that with Java JavaScript C C+ uh or
even python yes okay so emac is like in
comparison is you know is you
you'll never hear people talk about
things like like this like the way I
talk because most most of the talking
online is just
cheers
but however emac does that doesn't mean
emac is like useless EAC disp emac disp
there's one thing EAC disp does great
and no other language does it better is
text processing because it is designed
to do so and the real reason why no
other language including wam language
okay Pearl py on Ruby including Pearl
Pearl is known as the best text
processing language no not really all
any of these language including my
favorite wam language when it when you
compare to emac this for doing the task
of test processing all the all the all
the other become nothing beats Emax
why because emac this got this um perfer
structure which is like
a glorified string it's it's basically
it's a data structure designed for man
manipulating
text okay so so anyway so if you are
doing small scale text processing
nothing beats emac
disp okay which is what I'm doing uh and
you know which which is what I'm doing
for the past you know 15 years uh by the
way recently I worked a lot on my
packages and stuff and if you like my
stuff just pay me okay now my python mod
is no good because it's just um small
and but anyway so go to my website
search for S emac this packages you'll
find them if you like it pay me I'm not
going to ped it now so emac disp is a
domain specific language
so generally speaking it cannot compare
to any of these PE python Ruby or C C
Java
C++ you know you cannot compare okay no
comparison at
all um but I like it you know for text
but for text processing emx this speeds
them all okay now wolam language is the
highest language of them all doesn't
matter if it's hascal or it's fancy
hascal or it's fop or it's abta or it's
you know like next Generation has got
you know nothing nothing comes even
close not even close not even a little
bit close in terms of expressibility
like one line you know like one line of
wolam language Mathematica is like 10 20
100 lines of
hascal well let me let me say it again
one line of wolfen language is like 10
lines of hascal let's say
20 lines of python to or 50 or 100
depends on I mean depends on whether you
count mathematical functions if you do
count mathematical functions such as a
function returning derivatives integrals
Sol differential equations or difference
equations or you know or physics
equations there like hundreds of them in
wol language each one of those function
is like equals to 100,000 lines of
python Okay so
so if you count those then one line of
WF language is equals to 100,000 lines
of python or JavaScript or whatever or a
billion a billion lines of
C but normally programmers you know the
for that the the most vast majority of
programing jobs we don't do math we
don't need to do solve differential
equations so so you know let's say we
don't count them we just count you know
about manipul manipulating list or
strings okay so for that one line of
language is like uh 10 or 100 lines of
python okay and and similarly for hascal
you can you can kind kind of just F
factor in okay so that's about the
differences between the uh you know
these languages and do I prefer woan
language or emag this
well I would prefer woan because
because it's just general you know emag
is is just for text
processing okay so that's that uh shall
we continue to problem two okay so let's
do so uh so far 40 minutes let's have
more some more
drink let's see who else is watching
five people
fantastic your analysis only confirmed
what everyone feared the two lists of
location IDs are in indeed very
different or are they the historians can
agree on which group the mistake or how
how to me it comment you notice
interesting you know this idiotic driel
Advent of code drivel they just drivo
and
diling lousy specification of the maybe
the other number on location I mean
handwriting this time you need to figure
out exactly how often each number from
the left list appears in the right list
how often the left appears on the
right
okay calculate so immediately that gets
you think about you know subsets which
set is larger and so on calculate a
total similarity score
by adding up each number in the left
list either in the left list after
multiplying it by the number of times
that number appears in the right this
okay it's counting problem it's
trivial but they choke it up to
similarity score okay and how is
similarity score defined well it's you
can't um you know so
adding up each number in the left list
after multiplying it by the number of
times that number appears in the right
list
okay so you take the left column for
each number you need to multiply it by
multiplicity and this multiplicity is
defined by you know the number of times
it appears on the right
column so three the first number three
appears three times on the right so you
need to times three the number four
appears one time on the right okay the
number two appears uh zero times so two
* 0o is zero okay number one appears
zero times so one is also zero is that
right so let's
see uh first number three so second
number is four appears in the rightest
ones okay third number is two it does
not appear therefore 2 * 0 is zero okay
so we got it so let's let's do let's go
back to the
code yeah so this
time let's put the input the toy input
back okay so that's a problem one okay
so let's let part
two so part two cut okay okay part two
this is the input um and we need to what
let's just copy some of these copy okay
part two so two expression correct then
what you need to
do you need to partition it uh three
four okay then then you need to
transpose okay so let's see uh
okay
so do you need to sort this time you
don't need to sort okay so it just
transpose and meanwhile let's make
it into one line Okay so
okay so actually so this is still pretty
simple
okay run
it yeah we got that okay so what what is
next
thing 3 42
13 uh wait three yeah so okay so you got
3 42 1 yeah
so you got these are columns okay so you
got that and that and uh for each one on
the left you need to check how many
times it occurs on the right
okay so you this is so easy okay so but
what's the best
way so first of all how many times it
happens um
you there's a buing function in wam
language okay
so okay that function is Count I
believe okay let's check the
documentation count give the number of
elements in this that match
pattern uh give the number of elements
of in the list that match pattern okay
yeah so list in pattern
so list and pattern okay
so this is so easy so let's
uh first of all we stop by map a
function okay the what we want to map
the function to map the function to
X2 okay
okay now but the question is what is the
function now the function is going to
be
um okay let's create some local
variables okay so
module module takes two argument the
first argument is a list of local
variables
okay so column two let's say column two
equals to
equals to x to the second part
okay
then then column one is
um X2 uh first part
okay that's kind of um does that make
sense so you got a module then then you
just want to map okay so then you map
function to to column
one okay and the function what does the
function do the function takes the okay
so this is the element in the column one
this is one the
element you take it then you do
count okay so I mean you do x
times
count okay then what is the count the
count is
the uh the pattern is X itself and the
list is column two
okay that's what you do so so what you
end up is uh yeah x times that then you
just you just
total I believe that's the answer shall
we do it yeah let's just run
it 31
uh let's to be
sure
uh yeah so you don't actually don't you
don't need well I mean okay 31 yeah I
think I'm pretty sure there it is 31
there it is 31 okay so now you just need
the user input so let's copy the giant
big thing let's copy it
again put this here right
okay are you sure
yeah
paste
submit that's the right answer fantastic
so we are
done so does that make sense you
[Music]
see you see um you know so you know let
let me let me run this in move language
so you can kind of
see okay so that's the huge input you
know go
uh let's the user input two columns of
numbers
then then the code is just two lines you
can make it one line of course shift
enter okay shift enter so
230 4 6 913
2304 6913 that's
correct fantastic
beautiful anything
else who else is
watching uh I think that's it so
tomorrow at noon let's you know continue
let's get this going this is a I'm sure
it's a warm up
problem the band of cold
nasty warm up
problem
okay nobody comments comments that's it
I think that's it for today let's see 50
minutes
okay yeah let I think that's it uh let's
see if we put it back syntax color it sh
browser and uh there it is
today's
okay it's a big numbers
but bye guys
okay pay me okay pay me you can buy my C
go to CAD doino you can buy my
emac tutorial and emac this tutorial
they are I think you know like 800 Pages
or a thousand
pages and uh you know lots of stuffff
the
best tutorial for emac and emac disp on
the web and also in any printed
books in my opinion okay so emac this
you can buy you can buy it you know so I
have done a lot huge amount of update
every day um you know so
busy by the way by the way if you read
my emac blog every time you see this too
that means I'm currently like reviewing
and reworking on this page for example
this page started in 2022 in fact you
know so this is about everything the
complete documentation about emac
regular expression so for emx regular
expression this is this page covers the
syntax like complete account of it but
this is only one out of like 15 one
another 15 pages on emac regular
expression so you got introduction you
got uh okay emac commands using regular
expression okay that introduces you the
commands that uses regular expression
then this section is about regular
expression itself so you got emx regular
expression then how do you do that in
EAC LP and EAC L regular expression
function you see this is when you use
emac this to do programming and how do
you extract the captures and so on you
know and any or unit code unit code or
escape unic code and so on and how do
you test so anyway so you know in total
I think this like 900 or a th000
emac pages in my emac
tutorial uh let's go back n yeah 900 70
plus you know plus you got miscellaneous
articles which
is 250 240 miscellaneous articles plus
the complete emac and emac list manual
each one is like like 900 pages so you
will get that if you pay
me uh so you can find the link of course
by emac tutorial okay um uh actually I
need to increase the price but you know
consider it's a donation you know you
are just donating because this is um I'm
not sitting
that much you know and I don't want to
make it like a real commercial stuff
because when you do that then it
became you know lots of marketing and uh
also the quality degrades and you become
you know it's usually it's not going
I like the genuine hardcore
stuff and you like if you benefit you
like my stuff you can buy it that's what
I'm saying so there is that then of
course JavaScript in depth that's also
you know the one of the best JavaScript
tutorial uh you know you
got anyway I talked about this many
times okay so lots of programming
tutorials just go to the bottom and pay
me
okay bye