hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we are going to talk
about this device okay so uh show you so
this newa tracko fantastic track tracko
if you are watching this offline I mean
not live uh feel free to skip around
okay so this is fantastic we I'm going
to cover it and I'm going to talk about
ergonomics if you have hand pen using a
mouse or track Boo and which one is uh
better and things like that what is the
best way to set up your uh mouse or
track board and the
workflow okay to avoid repetitive strain
injury okay so let's go so let me have a
drink first let me introduce my
keyboards this is glove 80 fantastic
keyboard This is Ultimate hacking
keyboard too Fant fantastic it's got a
um you know a functional lighting system
so if you you can see the color changes
depending on the keys function ultimate
hacking keyboard I use it as a key Mark
or key pad so I have like 60 keyboard
marals and this is pre-made Margarita
something like that yeah have let's have
a drink so new tracko and the other one
the mouse my Mouse is the Logitech
g504 I believe so let's have a
drink this is 13% alcohol I think
cheers pretty good though I'm not a
drinker so I don't know
exactly what is a fine te
uh taste for
wine for boo okay let's begin so this is
fantastic let me tell you know this this
is uh one of the is actually cheap too
uh it's China chipo so it's made in
China China in the past few you know
five or 10 years has been producing
massively you know reasonably good
product and cheap so this is
uh so let's see what's the best camera
so that that that okay so here so this
this track B it's got this button is the
thumb button this is the left
click and this is the back and forward
click fourth and fifth button and this
is the right click and the wheel is also
fantastic the wheel feels very good to
roll and uh it's you and it also
functions a middle click so you can
click it but it does there's no tilt so
you cannot you know til it t is not that
much useful but anyway you can click it
and the action so it's fairly light so
you know it's very good it's fairly good
so and this is Wireless so it's got you
got two Bluetooth connections you can
see in the middle so you got two uh
okay so let me let me get off that so
let me try
again so you got the middle button is
switch between two Bluetooth settings
and all and the other one is USB Dongo
Wireless so you got a USB Dongo socket
here I I'm using it so it's not here so
you can switch wirelessly between three
devices and uh this button is for
switching track Bard speed you have five
speed and this is on and off in case you
want to save the battery so it's
rechargeable you just plug in USB and
you'll charge uh but when you are
charging it you cannot use it so that's
one of the issue one of the flaw so
overall it's very smooth so I can
recommend it it's uh super smooth
fantastic I'm using it right now so I'm
going to show you my desktop uh so the
other Mouse I've been using for the past
10 years is this
one this one this is a Logitech
g502
g502 and uh you know it's also fantastic
and the most fantastic thing about this
mouse is the spin
wheel so you can see okay so I need to
it's programmable so I have set it to
Linux uh button marus uh Windows and Mac
so blue is Windows so this spin wheel
you can push it and it'll spin for 20 or
30 seconds so this is truly fantastic so
I had this I've been using it for 10
years comments and questions if you have
comments post it okay so am I going am I
doing well uh in my videos yeah so
comment comments and questions okay
so so let me let me let me let me talk
about these two devices the track B
so you know on my
desktop I use you know I've been using
this mouse for 10 years by now something
like that more than 10 and the most
great feature is uh the the spin
wheel so but I forced myself to use this
one whenever you buy a device when you
first use it you you may not like it
because habit okay so you always want to
try if some device you think it's welld
designed or things like that you have to
try to force yourself to use it for a
week or two or month so I've been
forcing myself to use this you know when
I first tried it you know I don't want
to change I just you know go back to my
H habit of this uh but I forced myself
to use it and and it's pretty good so I
can
I can recommend it and I can actually
just use this instead of that but now
you know you see I have too many devices
it's not good to have you know two
pointing devices on right I I also have
a track B here you can see there's a
tiny track B here so I have too many
devices I have I have to use just
one in my case you know if I have to
choose only one of them uh can I can I
like show you this over here okay so in
my case I have to choose one of I have
to it's a tie it's kind of a tie but I
slightly prefer this uh large the mouse
with because the sing wheel because the
sing wheel is just
fantastic with this you have to squirr
it you know like that you know that that
that that that you know it's much better
with a sing wheel because you just you
know you don't it's like the least
effort you have to put you have to put
in using it you just you know push it
and you spin fantastic and when whenever
you want to
stop you know push it and just just tap
it and it'll stop you see
so if I have to make a choice between
these two I I would go but but with the
I would go with the Logitech the sping
wheel but I would say this track boo is
just fantastic okay let me switch to my
uh desktop screen so you can see uh
actually so you can see I'm using the
track B on the lower left corner you can
see my screen and I can move the track B
around you know I'm using the track B so
it's fantastic now let's so talk show
let's go to today's talk show page and
let me show you tell you what are the
features smooth ball One USB wireless to
Bluetooth uh and similar okay so one you
know there was this track B Microsoft
track B explorer that is considered the
best track B you go to Amazon sometimes
they sell for $500
this it's made around 2000 year 2000
2001 so this new is actually very
similar to this so some people say this
new is a you know like replacement for
this um I actually never use this
Microsoft uh Explorer though but anyway
so you can see on Amazon some people
sell it for like
$500 uh let's see
there there
579 hello to Jack hello Nostalgia what
do you think about litech MX MX vertical
range okay I'll talk about
that uh yeah what can t tablet yeah
tablet is also fantastic you know you
have different devices okay you cannot
see my
tablet uh okay by the way I got a new
camera so that no you know so so so
here's my
tablet you see I have a stack of papers
on top of it you know it and it still
works
fine
uh okay so let me let me answer the
question one one at a time what do you
think about the Logitech MX vertical so
the Logitech
cheers so if you go to just search for S
keyboard
I have 1,000 pages about track boards
about Mouse okay so um yeah Logitech so
let's go to the mouse section and
there's also track boo
history so these are the all the track
boo currently you can buy these are the
considered the best you know consider
you know well some of them so anyway so
let's talk about the mouse yeah the your
question log uh the MX
vertical uh Mouse okay okay so Mouse
section so you know so this one is what
I have right now and uh I also have this
one it's right there uh why don't I show
it so you see this is my other track
ball I use it while I'm lying in bed for
my Mac so afterday today I'm going to
use that one this one for lying in bed
on my Windows tablet the Surface Book
this one uh and this this track B I use
it on on my Mac is also superb okay so
both of them I can recommend but which
one you like depends on whether you
prefer the thumb of or the index
finger so this one is great too so this
one is uh oh God they don't have name on
it but anyway you can easily find it
search for on Amazon you'll find it so I
also have this one this one is Wireless
it's got six buttons for the thumb on
the side so it's fantastic this one is
Logitech uh 54 604 okay so this one is
also fantastic and it's also got a spin
wheel fantastic you know the you know
the swing wheel is just you know just
fantastic by the way both of them you
can you can press a button here and then
it become notched wheel it no longer
spins if you sometimes you prefer that
but I almost never switch to notched mod
okay so that's about the you know the
track boards and mouse so your question
about uh let's switch back to my audio
check video check uh switch back to my
screen so you were talking about the uh
can you see my hand yeah so let me show
you since today we are talking about
track B so let me show you kind of so
you can see my hand using the track boo
one of the great things you want to turn
on is Hoover click so you see I never
make a click oh there's one issue with
with this track B okay let me show you
let me let me talk about
it there's one issue about this tracko
which is this thumb button at the bottom
is kind of far because I'm asan so my
hand is not huge so I I felt
that well I mean if you always put your
hand like that then it's okay but
usually I don't so that's one of the
technique to avoid repetitive strangury
when you are not using it don't don't
fix your hand on the mouse or track B
okay don't always put your hand there
just leave it you know when when
whenever you are not actively using it
just you know leave it by so anyway I I
feel this button uh that's a left button
it's a
bit I fa it's a bit you know it's
actually it's not a reach it's right
there but I fa it's taking some effort
to P push it so a remedy for that is let
me switch back to my screen so a remedy
for that you can swap the buttons you
can you know in operating system you can
swap the left left and right
click or turn on Hover click like right
now you see I'm using I'm switching
Windows you see switch Windows no old
tab because old tab is one of the worst
ergonomic thing you don't want to do old
tab so you just arrange your windows so
that every you know about five or six
Windows you use most often for example
this is my Brave browser this is my
Firefox if I want to go to emac I just
nudge the track board there
go to my Chrome browser or go to the OBS
so it's all just track boo I don't I
don't click there's no click at all so
this is what you want to do to avoid Ri
so with this setup I don't even have to
play press the left click like almost
almost never so that solves that problem
same thing with the m with the mouse by
the way if you can see let's see you see
this is a mouse I don't click I just
move it around and it can switch Windows
you know whatever windows I want with
almost without any effort at all you
know for people who use a mouse or track
B some people have hand pin due to the
mouse or track B because you you know
that click is actually very uh takes a
lot effort so if you click like normally
you have to click a lot like click click
click click you know so with Hoover
click you don't have that problem you
solve that problem okay now in order to
turn on Hoover click I have uh tutorials
you know if you just go to S Talk Show
today uh I have lots of tutorials about
how to set
up uh just search for Kar keyboard block
you know so you can set up hover click
on Windows on Linux or on the Mac so
switch you know so Hoover Mouse Hoover
to activate activate Windows this is for
Microsoft Windows this is for
Linux uh and this is for Mac okay so you
follow these instructions and you can uh
do it you can find just search for SAR
talk show today I have a link at the
bottom of the description and you you
can find all the links uh you know I
talked about okay so you are talking
about so let's go back to the mouse so
you are talking about the Logitech
vertical
okay I I don't have that one okay so
let's go to Logitech ver go check check
so logic uh Logitech vertical Mouse MX
vertical do I have a actually do I
actually have a page about that uh no so
actually I don't know any I cannot give
you opinions about that yeah I don't
know I don't have it and I really but I
do have a page on vertical Mouse and uh
ergonomic Mouse so that would
let's go there have a look and also
there's leftand
Mouse so if you have hand pen due to
Mouse there are several Solutions one
is uh one is of course get a track ball
or track pad or a vertical Mouse Okay so
let's see where's the vertical
Mouse uh okay Mouse Hoover to raise
window single click to open file that's
a good thing swap Mouse buttons uh set
Mouse wheel spe need uh swap Mouse right
button with left middle
click uh okay so where is
the how to choose a mouse Apple Mouse
okay how to choose a mouse okay so lots
of Articles so Apple Mouse ergonomic
Mouse there so this is uh Apple Mouse
history and here's ergonomic Mouse so
you have quite a few choices so there it
is Logitech m x uh by the way this girl
has a video she's a great you know she's
a YouTuber so she has a great video you
can go check it out just search for S
ergonomic Mouse so there are all these
ergonomic Mouse especially in the past
five years there's tons of them from
China originally there's just a handful
like this one is one of the original you
know vertical Mouse the idea of of
vertical Mouse is that typically when
you use a mouse
yeah your hand is like that flat this is
called pation your natural hand position
is like that so if your hand is always
like that there's some kind of a stress
on your attendance so that's not good
which actually is
true I know because I you I type so much
on flat keyboard that and that's causes
problem so the idea of vertical Mouse is
that they you know you don't have to to
put your hand like that rather it's like
that so there's a tons of them today
hundreds of them but this one evolute
evolent um is the
first uh first in what year uh very
early like
2000 uh do I have a date I don't have a
date but this is this was the first
vertical Mouse you know it introduced
idea so anyway so there's a lot for
example this is the China chipo you know
one of the China cheap one of my uh on
my YouTube friend kind of a friend he
had it so you know so anyway the so I
don't know I don't have this one
Logitech so Logitech came out with a
vertical Mouse about uh
2018 four years
ago I suppose it's pretty good uh but I
never use vertical Mouse myself why
because
because like I said you know you have to
develop a habit like for example this
track ball if you look at you see it's
slanted you see it's it's not flat you
know it it it's not flat but it's like
that so you can
see so which is good now but if you use
a mouse you see
it's it's flat you see especially gaming
mouse but what I do is that I do not put
my my mouse like that all the time I
don't so I always just my hand is always
just like that I just nudge the mouse
around if I need to know I grab this
side so my hand is not like that so that
is a important trick for ergonomics when
you if you have hand pan with the mouse
okay so since I don't you know always
like whatever claw style or Palm style I
don't do that so my hand is always just
like that
so so vertical Mouse is not that uh
useful to me I mean well it's useful but
you know but it's not
critical but anyway so that's idea so
that's about
that and the other thing with vertical
Mouse I actually never used it so I
cannot say for sure but but if you do
have a vertical Mouse then you then
whenever you need to press the buttons
you have to exert effort that is you
have to use finger M finger muscles as
opposed
to a flat mouse because of a flat mouse
you can always press it by like for
example put your finger in in that
position in this style pressing the
button you do not act
actually uh cause you of any kind of
muscle strength because you are first of
all using gravity
okay but with vertical Mouse it's hard
to do that so you you kind of you you
have to exit you know you have to start
to like use the finger muscles a lot
that's what I imagine I never use it so
I don't I can say for sure okay that's
my opinion about the vertical Mouse
okay what's next Let's uh let's see okay
so we covered that let's go back to my
page and let's see what uh next thing
it's been a while since I uh did the
talk show so I'm going to start to do
often again sorry about that oh I forgot
to mention for those of you still
watching you know waiting for my review
of this sorry I don't have it ready yet
so this is SW board SV a l SV a l b o a
r d so let let me show it again so this
is the most advanced keyboard it cost
about $800 or $900 okay so you can
search it online and you'll find it and
you will also find my review and also my
my review of IT s v a l b o a r d on my
YouTube okay it's magnetic switch but
I'm not ready to demo it yet so you have
to
wait okay that's so smart so that's
Smartboard and let's go back to um yeah
so what else I want to talk about so let
me show you so vertical Mouse uh yeah so
let me uh so just search for keyboard
blog so you can see my review of
IT lots of stuff uh so now next let's
see what what else okay keyboard
shortcut tutorial okay so let's discover
that so when you need to program your
keyboard on Linux or on Windows or on
Mac or on emac this is my resource so it
has a collection of basically everything
you need to
know the best thing is always to buy a
programmable keyboard or programmable
Mouse by the way so this one for example
this one is not programmable but what if
you want to program it let's say I want
to swap the left button with the right
then you go to the operating system so
that's when when this page page you know
this
helpful but this one for example this is
programmable so programmable means that
the key maros whatever you set is is in
the memory is in the device itself so
you can plug it in any device and all
the keys you set is going to be the way
they are
instead of you know you have to start to
program on whenever you bring a mouse or
track board to another machine you have
to you know re you know to configure you
know operating system you know swap swap
the mouse buttons and things like that
so first of all you want a programmable
keyboard or
Mouse so other than that then but you
can program you know this you know remap
keys so Mouse so this is Windows for
everything you need to know on Windows
and everything you need to know on Linux
okay all kind of software I show you uh
what they are for example Linux keyboard
software so all these all these are the
greatest software for remapping keys or
creating key markers on
Linux uh so you have you know many of
these are new new in the past five years
you have have Hawk you have X monad you
have X key snail you have key D key
demon you have canata this is also new
new in
2022 uh you have y do tool this is new
in
2018 then you have classic classic ones
like you know like 20 years ago you have
xine keys and WM CTL and others so
everything you need to know about Linux
and everything every key map key Mar or
software you need to know on the Mac how
do you swap cap lock how do you swap
control key and and command key or
whatever Escape key so uh that's all you
need to know here and of course there's
emac
okay so what is my next thing I want to
talk about okay so let's see Smartboard
uh okay let's see what uh
yeah that's I think that's about it okay
so that's about it any any other
questions that's it for I think that's
it for this one for today 30 minutes not
bad so I'm going to start to do more uh
continue to do live stream so I think
one after you
know you know just watch my YouTube okay
I'll start to do emag this coding I've
been coding a lot in the past month uh
my last video is about three weeks ago
so I've been doing tons of coding on
keyboard on tons of writing on keyboard
on python on emac LP on wolam language
so expect my live stream to become more
frequent okay any other
questions talk about lat latch XMS
office Libra office okay
uh I don't like Thum breast I don't like
thumb rest what do you mean by thumb
rest Logitech um okay so is it true that
track BS are never as precise as M even
when you get familiar with them that's
not true okay so you have a question
about basically about track Boo versus
mouse there's article on that okay so
here's track boo reviews so you want to
know about track Bard versus mouse so
so there it is track uh track Ball
versus mouse how to choose track ball so
on this page you search it you'll find
it so I give you a detail about tracko
versus mouse what is the advantage what
is the disadvantage what is a common
consensus okay so your question
specifically about tracko is not precise
as much that's false okay because as far
as prec iion
goes that that just comes down to the
DPI which is basically means the
sensitivity of the of the registering uh
mechanism in a track B Mouse today they
are all Optical so basically it's the
same okay you know if you buy a track
board that's 20 years old obviously then
it's not good but for example many of
these but today's tracko or you know if
you buy today's track B many of these
are with today's technology
so and for example let me show you for
for example let me change the resolution
for this one to very low okay so let me
one two three yeah so now you can
see it taking me a long time to you know
I I have to uh roll a lot to move a
little you see
but if I change it again press and
press now I roll a little and let's
change it again one more time so now I
roll a little and it it goes all the way
so that's about Precision you just set
it to low then you have the finest
Precision possible same thing with the
mouse the DPI socalled okay so let me
set it change it back okay
okay you see now it's like very slow
super slow like like I have to spin the
mouse I mean I have to like
spin spin the uh
ball what press the wrong
button okay so
that
so track ball is not less pre size than
a mouse however your question is about
you know it it does make sense because
usually a track B I mean a mouse let's
see
um how to choose a track B so a mouse is
actually kind
of how shall we say so if you are
playing first person shooter where you
need very fast movement to precise
locations in a straight line then Mouse
is better okay so you know first that's
precisely what first person shooter
games are is
about so you know so I mean watch the
way I use the mouse okay so you see I
don't I don't do that that's no good
that's going to get you
RSI I'm kind of like fingertip you know
I don't even touch M so let me me show
you see I don't I don't this is no good
okay and this is no good so I don't I I
the way I use the mouse is like that
okay so that's the benefit of you know
if you are playing first person shootter
games then Mouse is better so why should
you use a track B many reasons if you
are using a 3D card software if you need
to do anything with 3D modeling usually
track B is better it's more intuitive
okay and how do you choose choose a
track B for example there's thumb ones
there's there's you know fingertip ones
you know you
know the thumb track ball uh
so but so depends on person Some people
prefer Thum thumb track B Some people
prefer the fingertip track B but in both
cases you want to avoid moving the
finger okay so let me show you so let's
turn this off so for example uh let me
show that so when you use a track B do
not do things like that okay so for
example normally you put it you know you
just R the
finger you try to not do that too much
instead you want to move your hand like
that okay like that so you don't move
your fingers same thing that's same
principle with uh with uh typing you
don't want for example all these thumb
Keys you don't want to constantly move
your uh tdle your thumb like you know
that gets you thumb pin a lot of people
has that thumb pen so instead try to
move your whole hand you know so your
hand think of it as a dummy so you just
move your whole hand and and do things
that way you avoid
Ri so let's go back to uh yeah so oh God
where is
this uh where am I
so yeah okay so let's switch back to my
and let's put the track B
back so yeah so so one of the uh issue
about how you know the track B is
thumb track B versus fingertip track B
it's your preference
okay uh and uh and there are other tips
okay I think that answered your question
and uh that's I think that's it for
today I mean not only for window Hoover
but on any
Hoover is there a way to enable auto
click Dr in Windows as far as I know no
so you can in over you know so on
Windows you can you know I can move my
mouse and it will automatically
automatically switch windows but it
won't
click you know because otherwise I go
this is my Twitter so I move move the
cruiser here I stop the cruiser it
should do a click that's auto
click but on Windows you don't have that
I'm not sure there is a uh software you
can install to have that feature I don't
know but on the
Mac that's what you have okay auto click
and on Linux you can choose one or the
other you can have auto click or just
Hoover to activate window so so okay so
I think that's it for today thank you
guys for watching if you like my stuff
you know go to my website uh go to my
website go go to
it.info and then you scroll down all the
way you can see my patreon my Amazon
gift card my PayPal pay me
okay okay I think that's it for today
anything else we're going to shut down
in a minute or
two one more drink
[Music]
Margarita then I'm going to have dinner
with
wife been coding so much in the past
month a lot huge amount of
emac you know work on my emac tutorial
and all my packages
fantastic Thiago Hello
by nostal Nostalgia Nostalgia something
next time can we discuss the most
beautiful Mouse track boo not including
functionality possible
the most beautiful one the most
beautiful by appearance like
girls uh we can talk about that right
now so what is the most beautiful Mouse
I haven't actually thought about it you
know if we go purely by appearance uh
but I can
immediately say some of them apply for
example this
one the appearance I like it pretty much
pretty well but this this one is
actually not that good because the
ergonomic and all but judged purely by
Aesthetics I think this one looks pretty
good uh then then you have others okay
for for examp let me show you some funky
ones for example this one I have it
there in the
Box uh Mouse with keyboard switches okay
uh not not bad and oh this one is
beautiful China another thing made by
China you know China makes a lot of
China and
Japan their style is very different from
American you know Americans usually
don't care about cuteness what American
want is Big the bigger the better power
the more power the better trucks you
know big trucks that's American American
taste so when you want to buy a a mouse
or a pen or whatever devices you don't
you don't find these you know pretty
ones but in Asia Japan taian China oh my
God is everything is like so cute cute
so for example you can buy this mouse
very cute so you
know in women's fashion and okay so low
fre and also this
keyboard um okay so that's you know the
beauty of my so then you have this funky
one from Japan but they don't make it
anymore uh funky one from Japan this
it's it's a more kind of a tech looking
one and then you have this one this from
a company from Taiwan okay you know they
name it bloody a brand so you got this
Commando
Mouse with buttons on top so and oh okay
then this one by Microsoft it's pretty
this this this mouse is by touch okay so
it's like a touch pad
Mouse uh I'm not sure they still make it
it's still available wow so it's still
available this one touch
mouse uh what else what are some other
candidates this one I think it's
ugly uh and this funky one two mouse
wheel which is fantastic functionality
because Mouse wheel is one of the you
know the mechanism the touch feeli
mechanism how you know how you operate
with the device the the interface of the
wheel for human hand
is particularly great for any kind of
function that involves previous or next
for example forward word backward word
page page down scroll up uh scroll up
scroll down volume up volume down and
next tab previous tab you want a wheel
wheel is the best thing you you know so
this mouse got two wheels it's really
great
um and then you have the thumb wheel
Mouse Okay this this one is
pretty uh okay so yeah so then you got
the DJ Mouse it's got the DJ wheel I you
know it's very interesting I don't have
it uh
okay uh and then this one is very fancy
looking it's also I don't think they
make it anymore so you know it's like a
turtle uh you know interesting uh
mouses oh and this one this one is kind
of pretty you know it's like a Shar you
know with a instead of a squore wheel
it's got a squore ball for your
thumb so I don't have it uh it's made by
jelly comp which is pretty cheap I think
a German
company okay that's it bye guys