good morning guys
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show and today we are going to talk
about some technical subject
okay so technical subject what are we
going to cover we are going to cover
some random stuff but you know such as
eMac eMac c-max this JavaScript you know
programming languages go land and stuff
so let me show you okay where do we
begin let's begin with JavaScript so I
go through my JavaScript blog okay so I
have this JavaScript in-depth tutorial
let me just a window position so you can
see and okay so I have this JavaScript
tutorial JavaScript in-depth and then
there is JavaScript object references
then there is Dom scripting you know the
JavaScript in-depth covers JavaScript
the language in-depth then the
JavaScript object references obviously
they are references for JavaScript
objects now JavaScript objects are like
they are analogous to the standard
libraries in Python or in : you know so
in JavaScript the standard library
meaning part of the language is not you
know they are they are code you know
they are basically just building objects
so that's this page then I have dumb
scripting now dumb scripting is what you
actually do when you use JavaScript to
program websites that's called you know
sometimes it's called web scripting
sometimes it's called Dom scripting
sometimes it's called single page web
application you know so anyway and they
are quite different I mean they are not
just JavaScript but using javascript to
script you know to create applications
so let's go here let's go to Google
Chrome browser showed their you you can
just web search dump scripting sorry and
you'll see my page and dumb scripting
let's see some examples I have some kind
of fancy user interface examples let's
see web scripting examples okay so let's
see image rollover now this is like this
is 1999 era you know like when you move
over a button or some areas in on the
page the image changes so I'm showing
you how do you do that in you know
modern way but this this exists exists
backing is very popular back in 1999 so
image rollover pop-up window this is you
know a pops up window let's see digital
clock stopwatch fade element fade on
element using CSS transition you know
some kind of fancy kind of thing so when
you program Java when you when you write
a web application you need to know
JavaScript well you also need to know
the Dom well and you also actually need
to know CSS well in HTML of course
and actually I cover the basics of HTML
and CSS it's all here you have the CSS
transitions animations transform and so
on anyway so Dom scripting it's let's
show some more examples shake element
create to tip now to tip is very
interesting it's very extremely useful
like when you move to some some area
then some information or image will pop
up now this is used in for example sorry
Unicode
I can show you unicode characters so
let's go to Unicode sports for example
then I move my browser to anywhere then
you can see that you know a pop-up shows
up showing information now there's this
annoying thing I need to fix yeah that
thing I need to fix any anyway so that's
the pop-up you know this also if you go
to saw the Emacs in my Emacs tutorial
this is also used in a practical way
it's really extremely useful so you go
through sorry
Emacs tutorial and go to let's say
practical Emacs Lisp you make these
basics then you can see all these red
Brownlee brownish red text
those are image based functions and if
you mouse over them you will see the
inline documentation so this is actually
you know extremely useful and you can
also move the mouse to any code that
will also work string equal and so on so
that is the use of JavaScript to tip or
balloon you know pop-up balloon on
Windows it's usually called to tip you
know it's rather the common name is to
tip but on a Mac it's it's at various
times it's called a balloon popper
balloon you know it's usually called
pop-up balloon so that's so let me go
back to my video let's see how many
people are watching
let's pop up the chat so if you have any
comments questions just type it okay now
let's go back to so you got you see two
tips you know and I show you how to do
that in JavaScript you know this two tip
is it this is actually very interesting
first of all let me tell you you know
like 10 years ago this is this is this
this tool tip on a web is extremely
popular okay you know so many people
want to use it including big
corporations like real estate companies
or whatever you know or they say our
cars or whatever you know usually
usually commercial organizations they
need to tape you know they want to tape
this is a great feature but but back
then packing let's say in 2006 not many
people know how to do that okay it's
kind of a mystery and and then you know
there are some guys they actually one or
two guys who created you know a library
JavaScript like library that allows you
to use two tips and that became
extremely popular
you know like today when we talk about
JavaScript there's something comes to
everyone's mind you know frameworks and
libraries such as react you know angular
we had react.js angularjs you know
jquery you know so on so that so that's
today but back then
jQuery is I think in 2006 jQuery it just
just began I think jQuery just began so
but if you do web dev at a time you know
everyone would know this library that
does the two tips but eventually as time
goes on there's more browser
you know browser support like the
browser's support for CSS or JavaScript
becomes more and more consistent you
know
browsers so tooltips becomes easier to
implement so as time goes on of course
that job that library that to tip
library died you know like nobody heard
of it today actually you can still find
out that library the name of that by
using wayback machine for example you
copy my URL actually this is my local
URL so let's so this is a local URL
let's change it to my full URL and let's
go to wayback machine way back machine
wayback machine is a Internet Archive so
we go there turn on JavaScript because
it requires JavaScript oh it's already
on so place it here go to my website
javascript - tip okay so I think I wrote
this page new in 2011 however I have a
older page at a different URL that talks
about how to use this to tip library but
anyway let's have a look at this page
let me see what we see
oh yeah so there it is so I wrote this
in 2011 so this library is called over
Lib this library is called over Lib it's
extremely popular you know back then you
don't like github is not that popular
yet or doesn't even exist
you see you can see your tooltip there
and let's go to let's go to the website
and let's see if they still exist just
for curiosity's sake so this is the URL
over Lib okay this is wayback machine
version but let's see if that page is
still up it's good huh Philippe so so
who is let's see who is this guy if he
still maintain a website probably not
you know so we you know as you get old
you observe all these people and web
site you know web software or you know
technology they you know as time goes by
they just go away you know I you know a
lot you know as I walk because I have a
website I have a website starting in
1987 I have a domain sorry dog starting
starting in year 2000 so you know I've
been writing web pages and for 20 plus
years so I know a lot of websites and
they they just died out you know they
people get old they retired or you know
they don't need you know so you see that
a lot and you you will see that you know
in 10 years from today like 10 like
today maybe react react Jaya is this so
popular angular 2
is so popular but you know in five years
in ten years
it's like possibly nobody ever heard of
them
you know the newer generation then
you're gonna tell your story how you
know how we react was anyway so there is
this library for two tips over lip it's
okay let me make a copy of these
actually so that so later on I can add
to my not actual page to see what topics
we've discussed so anyway so yeah to tip
is very useful and and that's how you do
it
then let me show you another one falling
snow effect now this is also from 1999
you see this since since 1999 you know
falling falling snow falling hearts of
falling rain and you know I have the
implement you know modern implementation
you do it this way but by the way so the
two tips and this phone is no effect
they are quite interesting because the
way you do them the technology is almost
like a happenstance is you know it just
it so happens that you can do them you
know the way you do them you know for
example let's say the let's say that
let's look at the to tip okay the two
tip so you must Hoover something and
something pops up but how do you do that
basically the way you do that is when
you know you create an event Mouse
Hoover so we must Hoover's a function is
called okay a function is code now all
this is is nothing special so when your
function is called you want to do the
this pop up balloon but how do you do
that the way you do that the technology
behind it is such that you create a new
HTML HTML element which border you know
like the way you want your to tip to
look HTML you know like you create a new
HTML tag let's say dive tag with image
or text inside it and you create a
border okay then you use JavaScript to
create CA CSS you know a cascading style
sheet for this element such that such
that it is actually in a different layer
that you know in a different layer so so
CSS allows you to that to do that let me
show you how that is done so CSS you
have these you have this position
statics relative fixed absolute kind of
properties for CSS and they have they
are fairly complicated they are fairly
complex to understand it somehow CSS is
this bogosity you know CSS is pretty bad
actually anyway so CSS you have these
position properties and with you know
static relative fixed absolute possible
values and some of them actually create
you know they they make the element to
into a new layer so in HTML you can kind
of have like a different layer layer as
in same thing like in english sharp
image editor you have different layers
and the layers in front will hide you
know behind you know height whatever is
behind it so that's it that is CSS
layers so what do you do with the
tooltip is that you use JavaScript to
create a new type elements then you make
its CSS so that it the
and that actually specify it is a new
layer so this element is a new layer so
that's that's that's what you do that's
how you get a tool tip so this is kind
of you know I don't think it is I don't
think it's kind of intentional original
design purpose you know it somehow just
works you know so it's you know yeah so
but in contrast to for example when you
look at GUI
you know gee GUI with widget libraries
for desktop for Linux for Mac OS for
Windows you know typically you have a
GUI library or widget library sometimes
it's called widget library for example
on Linux you have you know QT library oh
you have the genome library okay let's
not let's not look them up but anyway
those are GUI libraries and then in this
library you have bunch of functions that
you know draw buttons draw menus drawer
windows draw you know including two tips
you know they you know but those you
know this libraries function so they
they are actually designed for it which
is not so for I don't think it is a case
for CSS so synthesis you know somehow
CSS and because the popularity of
JavaScript they they kind of changed
their nature a little bit because and
you know so they meet so this topics
becomes part of history I mean the the
the subject is you know we have you know
hTML is originally designed just to show
academic publications typically like you
have headers you have sections in you
have paragraphs you have lists then over
the past you know 20 or 30 years it
becomes mostly I would say primarily as
it is as they are used primarily for the
purpose of writing web web applications
such as Amazon Gmail basically almost
every website you visit they are not so
much for communicating information
anymore of course they are web sites you
know there are news websites that you
know but anyway and CSS is originally
designed to control the style of your
layout not not layout exactly but the
style by anyway so it becomes it it has
somewhat changed to be adapted for web
application use so so anyway so I was
talking about my dumb scripting tutorial
of course if you like it you know by it
I have a you know you can buy it my
whole JavaScript in-depth tutorial and
the whole thing basically HTML CSS
JavaScript and Dom but anyway so today
yesterday I created several new pages
this dumb HTML GUI pages for example you
have buttons I show you how to create a
button and I show you how do you
manipulate a buttons behavior with
JavaScript like know when is it clicked
how do you get you know you know when
when is it clicked so you have this
bunch of GUI tutorials new page I
created them they they are updated from
my old HTML form for example this HTML
form an example I wrote this in 2005 and
so today it's a complete complete
different nature so anyway I want what I
want to say is that I created these new
pages about modern processing of GUI you
know how do you create GUI in your web
pages so that that is that that is one
topic now let's go to my web blog there
are several other topics and let's talk
about them okay so this so there is you
know browser get elements by class name
now returns a true array now this this
topic is a little bit advanced but if
you know if you are web dev you don't
know what I'm talking about so typically
when you use document get element by
they return not list or HTML collection
and they are not true arrays in
JavaScript JavaScript is this has this
kind of what or complication with array
I'm going to explain that in a bit
but anyway the you know when you use get
element by name the return value is not
a true array but rather it's called
array like object so what does that mean
in practice is that you cannot use you
cannot directly call any array methods
because you know those objects are not
erase you don't have the methods for for
JavaScript arrays so so to use them it's
a little bit complicated
but the thing I noticed today yesterday
was is that today on a safari web
browser and also on Google Chrome
browser they it looks like they are
they'd return true erase now that's
quite interesting actually let's let's
test it out to see if that's actually
true
now let me show you let's see do I want
to talk about JavaScript array or let's
see how many people are watching one
people okay so if you are watching you
know say hi and and and the means know
let's see what I want to talk about now
get element by name let's do a demo
let's do a demo then about this topic
about get element by class name so I'm
going to explain what it what what it
all means
okay so let's do that so I'm going to
create a new sauce start command log
okay let me start my command log in
Emacs so you can see all the commands I
call in Emacs hey good morning DeYoung
you just got in here great so we are
talking about some technical details of
JavaScript and web scripting by the way
what what you are a programmer right you
are in Airway and do you do web
applications okay let's let's go ahead
to the demo so let's open a new buffer
Emax buffer save this file as X X dot j
s actually x xj s okay and create a new
buffer again save this as X X dot HTML
and
okay okay something wrong with my mod so
we created a new HTML page and let's do
a dive get element by name so let's go
to
this page this page shows you all the
possible ways to get an element an HTML
element or XML not so you have Caleb
element by ID you have get element by
tag name so let's use get element by tag
name okay so now second let's go to xx
dot J s we want to link that okay and
let's create some tags key something one
something choose something three okay
so we created three paragraphs graphs
and then open the JavaScript file paste
it here constant x equals two tag name
tag name will be
P okay console log X
okay save it now open this file in in
browser and open the console log you can
see that it returns a HTML collection it
has three elements each element is the
HTML paragraph now what I want to do
what we want to do is we want to check
if that result is a true array so how do
you do that you have this function array
true I forgot what's the name so let's
go to JavaScript in-depth and let's go
to array array how-to okay so there it
is
array is array
let's do that okay and now we refresh
the page
oh then it returns force that's odd so
Deon says I do a bit of web stuff but I
mostly just use JavaScript as a way to
pipe data to the backend and to display
the result on the page I see okay so so
from here we know it is not a true array
because it reads returns force but
however let's try to use a array method
on them so if it's not true array then
supposedly we cannot use array method
now for each is is a array method let's
just use it let's see if it works
error function X X let's say
have a function it's just a console log
X dot
that's I want to get
in a text not value so I want to get
text content so there this supposed to
print something one something choose
something three the content of the
paragraph and now let's refresh the
browser okay so it says type aerial for
each is not a function so indeed that is
expected because X is not a ray
therefore it does not have the for each
method but in that case what we can do
is like this array prototype for each
dot core let's try that
this is the way to call a array function
on a array like object okay
let's refresh the browser it works it
works that's strange because yesterday
yesterday apparently this works let's
try that
this is not supposed to work if X is not
an array a true array but yesterday I
was working on something that worked
so that's your walks that's that's
that's very strange
so actually this is a strange thing
because these these these three dots
they are an operation code they are a
new JavaScript operate operator called
spread operator so so the operand to the
right of it should be a iterable
sub-object iterable object and true
array are iterable object but array like
objects are not eatable objects so why
should this work I do not know so the
next step we can do is we can write them
we can try to see if this X is a
iterable object now how can you tell if
something is iterable we can tell by
checking if it has symbol iterator
method okay so how can we tell if that
has a symbol iterator method we can do
it by
well one way one way we can do it is to
show to list all properties of the
object so let's go here javascript
properties list properties so we want to
list properties so we can use reflect on
keys so that's what we're gonna do
reflect on keys okay
we're gonna show all the properties of X
and we gonna print it and we're gonna
see if it has a symbol iterator property
so let's refresh so it does not have a
symbol iterator property you see all its
properties are just the integer 0 1 2
and length I think let's see
refresh yeah so it did so this is kind
of very strange to me so in summary when
you use get element by tag name or
something similar that returns a HTML
collection the type is technically
called HTML collection so when it
returns that but however we know that
HTML collection is not a true JavaScript
array no is it a JavaScript iterable
iterable object now because it's not a
true array therefore you cannot have for
each method you can you know you cannot
use for each method directly check you
know that we have verified however it is
not a iterable object but it works if if
we use the spread operator on it so so
this is kind of strange so seems somehow
the browser is able to use spread
operator on it even though it's not a
iterable object let's let's try one more
thing let's just print let's try to
print the symbol property
symbol iterator okay
it's refresh oh so it does have so it is
an iterator than my god
is this is amazing what so so at this
point there are several questions coming
up because right now we are seeing that
it does have the symbol dot iterator
property which is a symbol new thing in
JavaScript so it does have that property
so that means it is a iterable object
this HTML collection is a iterable
object but however why is that when we
use reflect on keys which which
basically print all possible keys it
does not show that property so let's go
back to reflect on keys let's double
check
so reflect on keys returns a array of
the objects keys including simple keys
in an immobile keys so why is it not
returning you know the symbol of
iterator key before so okay so I did at
this point let's try another thing let's
try to see check property existence
object has own property so X has own
property let's do that
okay so let's refresh the browser type
area
[Applause]
uncalled type arrow cannot convert a
symbol value to a string has own
property
oh wait a minute this should be like
that let's try again
wait I'm not seeing okay now I see what
it means so the object X do not have the
symbol dot iterator property however
however it must be inherited that's
right so I made a mistake it must be
inherited from whatever is HTML
collections parent yeah that that would
make sense
I see so now in summary HTML collection
is a iterable object let's do another
verification by checking the parent
using reflect has okay so reflect has
okay X and key is symbol iterator
it's refresh again okay so that is true
indeed so what
so in summary again htmlcollection is a
object that is a iterable object because
its parent alone the parent chain the
prototype chain they you know there is a
object that has the property symbol dot
iterator
so it is a iterate iterable object
however it is not a true array so that
is why you cannot use the true array you
know you cannot go every methods
directly however you can use the the
spread operator Hong it okay that makes
sense that I actually learned something
today for that okay I think that is
about JavaScript and that you know
that's about this topic so let me let me
type it out HTML so we found that HTML
collection is not a true array true
JavaScript array but is a iterable
object because the property
symbol iterator is in its total parent
chain Oh prototype chain okay so that is
why so we learned about that today
great I learned about that
so Dion say is the JavaScript have any
building it robust other yes
other than array yes by default the
three objects that that that are
iterable our array set in Matt I think
that's it so let's let's check my
tutorials each robot so let's go to each
Robo and scroll down standard each
horrible objects so you got string array
set and Matt yeah including string so
that that is about that I think that
that is about that then let's go to my
web tutorial let's see what what else
you know we talked about so yeah that
that is interesting because each Robo is
introduced in JavaScript 2015 you know
so let me let me describe the whole
problem with this you know so JavaScript
and Dom JavaScript the language is
itself extremely convoluted you know
it's a very extremely lousy language but
in 2015
beginning in 2015 they added a ton of
new features however it remains backward
compatible so meaning that you know you
could use JavaScript you know as as
powerful as you know Python or Ruby but
however it still has lots of you know
so-called watts or you know the kind of
defects or complexities you know so
that's one thing you know JavaScript
fifteen is pretty new
okay that's JavaScript very complex now
Dom when you actually code web webs
website applications you have to use the
Dom technology which is not really part
of the JavaScript language such as you
know such as get element by ID
you know document query selector you
know things like that you know control
manipulate the page so that's Dom that's
so called Dom you know which stands for
document object model but actually it's
not it's more than a you also have
browser object model so you know but we
basically just call it dumb okay
you use them to script web pages to
create web applications now when you use
Dom now dumb okay javascript is the
language is extremely complicated Dom is
also extremely complicated you know so
it's like hell especially in the 2000s
when browsers do not agree with each
other that that's that's far worse but
today that that problem went away mostly
you know so so you don't you know you no
longer have to worry much about browser
different browser behaviors you know but
still the DOM technology itself is
rather extremely convoluted you know and
together with you know you have to use
JavaScript Dom but also HTML and CSS CSS
is also fairly complicated when you get
to the details
so in summary they are all you know they
are like just you know there is
this technology but what can you do what
can you do you know you just move on
then okay so so they are complicated
then let me discuss why you know what's
the problem with this HTML collection
thing
so one of the problem because of these
complexities one example of this
complexity is that when you want to you
know when you want when you have a radio
button for example on this page you have
you have several things on a page you
want to get them all then you want to
you know you want to get them all so you
get a list kind of result you know listo
away kind of result then you want to
apply a function typically to all the
elements you know so normally you would
expect you know when you get you know
using Dom get element by name or
whatever you know to get a bunch of
elements you get a list then you call
array method to apply a function to them
all but that's that doesn't work you
know Ted so this is an example of the
complexity it doesn't work it doesn't
work because when you get a you know use
get element by name or something like
that it returns you know this so called
not least or htmlcollection basically
it's about it's just a list but they are
not true arrays so you cannot you know
call JavaScript method array methods all
right you have to either use a for loop
yeah you can use a for loop so you know
so that that is an example of the
complexity and I'm going to you know
possibly I'm going to explain why what's
the deal with true array or array like
things in JavaScript that's that is
another example that's an example of
JavaScript complexity this HTML
collection or not least do not return a
array that's an example of the Dom
complexity so you got this garbage
physically over a bunch of garbage and
also by the way when you use get element
by name you know there are several
functions some functions that allow used
to get a bunch of elements so you can
for example get all elements of the same
class name
or same tag names such as paragraph or
dive same class name or with a
particular name attribute basically you
get a list of results but then some of
them returns a not list you know the so
called not least some of them returns
the htmlcollection
type you know so you have these two
different things that that is another
complexity of the whole dumb thing you
know so you know so what's what's the
difference basically not least is
supposed to be just not including
whitespace okay that's another
complexity because in HTML you know when
you have these elements and when you
have whitespace between elements such as
line returned or space those white
spaces are also considered as a not you
know those are part of the branch of
your tree your HTML hierarchy so
including comments including like HTML
comments there's also or not so when you
when you get some element by some by
some you know children you know it order
children by element you get this a lot
of them are white space knots so what's
the use you know is so it's really
stupid really the reason they have white
space they count white space as part of
the knot is because you know suppose you
want to process HTML document but you
also want to preserve you know the
source code they are you know like where
people put new lines for example you are
writing a software to reformat HTML
source code so you can tell exactly
where is new line where is you know
whitespace you can manipulate them that
is I think that is the original reason
why white spaces are considered as a not
you know in in in Tom
but when you actually do web application
program I mean like nobody used to that
then you know what he uses that you know
that's it's rather stupid you know so
over the years they have created new
methods that kind of fix that yeah so so
the new mate for example the new method
that tried to fix that for example let's
go back to Dom scripting so here I
explained what are the white space knots
you can see you know here so they
introduced a bunch of new methods that
does not return kind of ignore the white
space knots okay so that's about white
space knots now white space knots is one
another example of the Dom complexity so
let's go back to our previous topic so
when you when you are using you know get
elements by tag or by name or by class
these kind of so-called selectors you
know they sometimes returns they not
least sometimes some of them returns a
htmlcollection you know the difference
originally was because not this contains
any not where our HTML collection is
supposed to ignore you know why space
not and they they they should also only
contain HTML elements but not a XML
elements so when you you know use SVG or
the XML technology the HTML collection
will not work so you see this this you
know all these complexities anyway
anyway so you have not least you have
HTML collection you have this kind of
complexity and today they also fix that
you know if you go to read html5 expect
from the what working group you know w
h8 e w
gee from their SPECT you can see they
talk about this thing they talk about
they are they are saying that
htmlcollection
is kind of obsolete but we cannot you
know remove it you know and they also
say it not least is also kind of
outdated
so they suggest you use there's a new
thing called
elements you know so when you call this
get element by name this supposed to
return this new new type new interface
code elements but however as far as I
know that is not popular yet you know
I'm not even sure if a browser
implements that so so that that that is
kind of the situation you know that's
some of the examples of the so many
complexities in JavaScript and Dom
scripting so let's see maybe I should do
a summary or maybe not so we talked
about yeah so let's get back to
[Music]
htmlcollection yeah okay maybe let's
let's talk about JavaScript array so
what is a deal with true array versus
you know array like object now that this
is another big complexity or what of
javascript you know in javascript you
have in a typical programming language
let's say python ruby or you know goal
and you know you have a array datatype
now radio of happy is easy to understand
it's basically just list of elements and
each elements can be referred to by a
integer index by an integer typically
from 0 so you have 0 1 array element 0
index first you know index 1 you know to
point to each element now that is also
true in JavaScript you have a you have
this object that's called array okay and
basically it's a list of elements and
you can and they are indexed by integers
however here is the thing you know this
is actually a huge bag of complexity
it's not something it's not just even
just a small complexity eating involves
almost the whole language it involves
other complexities in order to explain
that but I'm going to explain that so
what's the deal with our range and true
array versus array like so anyway in
JavaScript first of all the JavaScript
data types variables do not have types
but values has types so you have you
know you have these basic value types
undefined
no pulling string number symbol and
object that is all now notice there is
no types called array okay
so this is this is first of all this is
a major complexity in JavaScript
this actually no such type as array then
what is alrea already happens to be of
of the object type so what is the object
type object type
so object type so you see this is very
stupid because there is no array I mean
a language you define types but then you
don't have a Rea type you have object
now JavaScript array belongs to is
actually technically the of the type
object of all the things that are of the
object type then you have kind of like
subtypes so some object will be array
some object will be function some object
will be set you know like a math set
some object will be map type like a hash
table so you have this you know but
technically they are only just the same
type they are all just object so that is
actually this so this is actually the
the one of the big design problem of
JavaScript so when you have a something
of value that is an object type it may
actually be a function or it can be your
array or it can be other objects or it
can be iterable you know gets very
complex so what is array then array
array is a kind of a list of items so
but in JavaScript they are they are you
know they are of the type object but
however however they
how do you explain this okay so let me
let me explain what is the object again
you know so this is this is the
complexity JavaScript they the types the
object type is not really well-defined I
mean but it is well-defined in the sense
that any value it's not we're defining
are lots of ways any value if you run if
you call type of the operator type of
the value then you if it returns a
string object that means it's an object
but but there are a lot of exceptions
but anyway so I'm kind of getting
complicated myself but let me just you
know get to the bottom line so in
JavaScript when you have a ray that's
technically it's a object type there is
really no the only true way to find out
if it's okay so so it's an object type
but when you have an object object
typically typically in JavaScript is a
is a collection of key value pairs now
you can create any object such that all
the keys are integers like consecutive
integers like 0 1 2 3 so if you create
an object and such that its keys is 0 1
2 3 then it's kind of like a way you
know like JavaScript array but however
they are different
because the the JavaScript array it it's
you know it's not it's not a true array
dinner type in other languages in that
sense it's easily broken it can you know
if you delete element using the delete
operator let's say you have a ray of
five elements
you know index zero one two three four
and let's say you delete a element you
know by using a delete operator you
delete the element number three what you
get is a missing on element and that
stops being that of a fission array it
becomes what so called it becomes what
so called a sparse array okay so let's
look at my tutorial here it become a
sparse array okay the problem basically
the issue there are many issues but the
main issue is a JavaScript object an
array there is no clear distinction
between them between what is a object
and what is a array because first of all
there's no such actually there's no type
you know there is no value of the type
named array everything is just an object
so you get this you know so many
complexities but anyway there is a way
to find out if something is a true array
true array basically effectively what it
means is that it is a value that is
inherited you know whose parent is the
array dot prototype object so that is
kind of the definition of a true array
not not actually technically not
actually true but so there are so many
complicated complications but basically
in JavaScript array you know you can
create an object that is like array as
long as you give it a integer sequence
of
key values of string type and we should
usually call that array like object so
anyway I think I've kind of I think I
failed explaining this in a concise way
because javascript is so convoluted I
think you know convoluted in so many
ways I'm trying to explain them in a
latch logical fashion such that you know
if there are two complexities I explain
each one of them you know each one of
the complexities and tell you their
relations then you can see the whole
picture why it's so complicated because
it's complicated in so many ways you
know it is you know first of all the
language you know that the value of an
object type you know it's not you know
you don't have actually have array but
then you have this yeah it's very
complicated to explain actually so Dion
say is why did they do it like this I
mean basically JavaScript the language
was created was invented created and
implemented in ten days by this you know
by this Brenda guy from an escape you
know he's on Twitter so it's all done in
a rush in ten days literally you know
ten days design and implementation the
whole thing in ten days so in the
beginning it was designed to be for
non-programmers
you know for for non professional
programmers it is it was designed for
mostly you know the web designers the
HTML writers you know who creates HTML
pages so that they can have some kind of
interaction
nothing like today's you know web app
you know that is like far in the future
even he imagined it you know it's kind
of like science science fiction back
then so it was just designed to be a you
know non-professional scripting language
for non-programmers who write HTML so
anyway and it's rushed in ten days it's
based on scheme disk and it's based on
self language so that you know from
scheme this language you get this
function of programming thing where a
function can return a function or take a
function as its argument and from the
self language you get this prototype
based object system which is I don't
think it's good actually so anyway and
all this is are turning ten days and and
also the syntax must follow Java syntax
so there's another complexity because
back then you know the Netscape just
made a deal with Sun Microsystems where
some Microsystems spend millions of
dollars to advertise Java so they want
to write the popularity train so they
renamed their language to be Java Script
you know following Java even though the
two languages has nothing in common like
they like they are totally different
beasts from different universe but
because for commercial reasons for
marketing reasons Java seen Travis
scripts syntax tries to be like Java
that that so all these things together
that that that is why it becomes this
extremely complicated language
JavaScript and a lot of it you know a
lot of these problems if you trace you
know some of them is actually just a bug
you know it's just the bug in the code
for example for example in JavaScript
the data types one of the data type is
know okay let's go
to value types okay one of the data tab
is noir and if you call the typeof
operator on a value on the noir literal
value know what you get or say object
your eternal string that says object
okay this one why because but no you
know you see you see the problem here no
is a is a type of value in JavaScript by
the Specht okay there is a type called a
new and the only value of that of this
type is the literal in URL okay that is
the only value of this type there is
this type code no now there is another
type called
object okay then there there is this
operator called typeof operator when you
use this this operator on a value you
will get a string that indicate what
type that value is but when you use this
type of on a under normal thing on the
normal value when you say type of Nohr
it will actually returns object example
here you can see you see type of nor
equals object true so this is this is
like like a contradiction you know that
is like a major mistake
it's a why side so it turns out the
reason for these you know type of no
equal structure is because you know it's
just a bug in the code this guy he's a
master of javascript so he took it up
you can find the original source code
and he explained you know is basically
which is a coding mistake but we are
stuck with it you know because Java
JavaScript they decided they want to be
backward compatible so they you know
they are now going to fix this so we are
kind of stuck
with it so every person who learns
JavaScript you have to learn okay you
know type of no returns the string
object and every time you check
something is the object you have to deal
with this special case you know you have
to check whether it equals to new or you
know so yeah so you have these huge bag
of problems with JavaScript so okay that
so today we kind of covered actually we
went into a lot details about javascript
so back to the previous topic about you
know the Dom returning HTML collection
that kind of anyway so that we already
explained that so I kind of so I kind of
finished
you know we reached a point of a pause
so we kind of we cover this subject the
question is the question now is what
would be the next subject are we going
to stop this today's talk show or we
going to talk about something else so if
you guys have opinions we got five
people now so if you have opinions
questions let me know
we are at one hour and 14 minutes I
think that's that's good time for me to
stop actually and take a break so we
covered a lot so today actually the
whole day is about JavaScript and its
complexities so let me get a drink then
sheis okay now so this will be
considered the second half of the actual
episode of the day and this second half
we are just going to do some drinking
and random chat so Deon says I'm not
gonna crash
thanks for the streams I learned
something useful thank you thank you
so Deon what are you up to so are you
are you working your company hey George
good morning George what were you up to
guys so today's my juice is this
humongous pot oh okay
apple juice humongous this is from
Costco Costco kind of a warehouse kind
of a shop in USA in the rich and
prosperous USA but not so much today
comparatively speaking
you know you compare to China oh my god
but USA is still pretty good you know in
you know in USA like we are all
concerned especially us nerds
you know programmers we are concerned
about all the privacy
oh the government is you know watching
us you know all this in that and you
know but when you if you use a
smartphone like iPhone Google Apple
Facebook they track you everywhere far
more than you know even more so than the
covert FBI
you know secret stuff they know
everything about you every photo you
take you know so it's kind of first of
all I want to say it's kind of funny so
in USA in particular among us nerds we
are like complaining about privacy all
day I think it's only actually just as
nuts okay we are complaining about
privacy all day but meanwhile you know
if you look at you know your smartphone
that's used by you know most people
you know he's tracking you to death
so the nerds are not making sense at all
you know you are complaining about these
things but however most nuts yeah oh the
programmers I know they use the phone no
problem they use Google Maps they have
to almost like they have to you know so
it's kind of like this CD I am you know
beginning to think these nuts concerned
they are actually you know I'm beginning
to think they are driven by some sort of
the cooperate created propaganda now I'm
not too sure about this but I'm you know
I'm beginning to think that way because
they want you to think about these
things but however you have no effect at
all anyway that's one thing I want to
talk that's one thing okay but the other
thing I want to mention is that people
in China they it's like they don't have
these concerns about privacy at all you
know like in USA especially on the news
you know we want to say Oh China look at
look at China they are you know the
government Big Brother they are watching
monitoring everyone's behavior you know
you have credit card system you know
like what you can do depends on what you
have talked about on social networks
like the government is monitoring you
everything like we kind of we want to
make fun of you know we want to laugh at
China but however in China most people
they don't have your American type of
concerns about this this privacy you
know like I would say is more kind of
like traditional Chinese thinking they
don't care like they don't they don't
have this individual privacy concern you
know
you know the like it's not there you
know so why are we you know laughs had
you know Chinese thinking that they are
being monitored they know that but you
know I think a lot most people vast
majority of people in China that's just
not their concern that's so anyway okay
so it's the morning Norman Norman says I
encountered an Emacs annoyance do you
know the variable text coding style yes
I think yes I remember that
now documentation text gets weird
unicode punctuation substituted for
apostrophe Cannavale code properly I
have a big story to on that you know I
have a yeah I can go on for an hour did
this is because there's a in
the Emacs dev community
his name is David McKenzie something
like that okay we can I can look up and
show you my web blogs and I can point
you to the articles but we'll do that
but you know he is the one who created
this problem this is actually a big
story okay this is this happened about
three years ago okay let me just talk
about it
now if meanwhile enemies search so you
can find my website about this issue
such forks rd e max curly quote okay
not those actually I'm I know maybe I
don't have it published because you know
when I write blogs often quite often I
write sometimes I write I spend hours to
write a blog then decided you know I'm
not going to post it because it's rather
controversial you know especially in the
past few years like is a period from
night from 2011 from 2010 to 2011 to
2006 let's say I was in a bad state you
know I don't I try not to post anything
controversial and that's actually that's
bad that's bad for me as well because
you know you actually you really want to
be yourself if you want to you know you
want to be yourself that's the best way
for you to prosper you don't want to
hide you know try to hide you know for
example what I saw what I'm saying is
that you know I'm usually I have a lot
of opinions in a mutually controversial
you know and you know usually I don't
give a you know what these people
says I want to I want to pursue whatever
is true
possibly bias but you know I think it's
true to my best you know the best of my
ability to be not biased so I want to
say what is true and often that's just
controversial including you know you
know technique or topic in emacs least
being Python or non-technical topics
like something is taboo in USA but not
taboo to Chinese you know I grew up in
China you know that's something you can
talk about in China you know in Taiwan
but in USA that's a taboo topic you know
you can talk about that because you
almost everyone we hope you again is you
but I don't like that because I don't
think that's good you know if you look
at the long-term perspective you know
countries
even countries countries and empires
come and go you know and morality
you know ethics you know certain value
come and go you know it's sometimes this
is bad and under time this is great for
example today we have the gay issue and
trans issue that's that's a one example
so you know so anyway back to the topic
so okay I kind of digress digressed but
anyway so there is this Emacs issue
let's see
curvy quotes let's see if I can find out
okay one way is one way to find out is
to actually who's opened by mistake
create that so one way to find out is to
find out the guys name I'm going to show
you the article so no man are you still
here so yeah okay I'm going to I'm going
to talk about this topic about Kovac
curly quotes in Emacs what happens to it
so but first of all in order to find the
article I need to find a guy's name that
will help me find the article so this
guy who his name is Alan okay Alan
McKenzie so Alan McKenzie okay this guy
he he in my opinion he is the one to
blame for the whole mess hopeful for the
for the regression of Emacs
you know normally your software progress
advances he created this problem he made
him ax go back because he is a guy okay
he is a guy he does not like Unicode
okay his opinion he is quite his
oddly spoke a I don't know how old he is
but probably fifty something or sixty
something he is a German he's a German a
German guy he's in German and he is
right now the maintainer of C code C mod
+ C + + mod tsipras first mod is based
on C mod C mod is one of the the
earliest major mod in Emacs because
obviously because email you know back
then is C language you knows it's a
primary the the earliest major martini
in Emacs and it is also one of the most
complicated mod + C + first mod is based
on it and you know it's very very
complex but anyway he Alan McKenzie is a
maintainer of the C Mon okay and he's a
German guy he's a oldest guy and he is
one of the old generation of a Mac user
so his idea of using Emacs is like in
the 1980s or 1990s he refuses to change
okay you know maybe it's critical to say
put to put it that way but anyway the
way he uses Emacs is basically like like
1990s or 1980s okay there are few other
people like that Richard Stallman is
actually one of them he just he doesn't
know he doesn't actually know him acts
anymore he he's like using Emacs like in
the 1980s way anyway so Alan McKenzie
he's an old programmer okay
and his idea you know so he the way he
used in max is like 1980s or 1990s and
he refused he kind of he's also he
refused to like every time every one
year or two it this happens often every
year year two in Emacs dev mailing list
you have you know mention
ideas about changing a Jew I graphical
user interface and you know like kind of
modernization but but every time this
happens
Alan McKenzie is one of the guy who
shouted it down who shout it down
they are a minority of these people in
emag dis death the older generation they
don't want any change kind of modern
user request request a change to Emacs
they want to use Emacs the 1980s way
okay now now about the Unicode Anna
McKenzie is a guy who his idea of text
is ASCII text he do not want Unicode he
do like he does not that we have like we
had we had a major flame war fight about
this issue back back in 2008 let's say
Oh before Oh before okay like you can if
you search my name sorry and Adam
McKenzie on new scoops you will find it
you know Asian ten years ago 15 years
ago we had big flame wars but anyway
he's he doesn't like Unicode he think
that is like firing that that's like Oh
new kids you know kids stuff you know
these ten years ago he think it's kid
stuff you know new young people stupid
people they like Unicode like curry
quote so arrow you know his idea is pure
asking then us Unicode becomes more and
more he you know popular becomes the
mainstream you know today Unicode nobody
dare to say Unicode is no good you know
like all the web technologies or unicode
utf-8 so único becomes widely popular
then there's also an emoji of course
which is another topic so Unicode become
widely popular then what does this Adam
McKenzie say you know so as far as I
know there's nothing he can do you know
he kind of I think his stance is kind of
okay you know yeah in some case
you can use that you know II can became
big you know became that of that opinion
because obviously you cannot refuse the
advantages of Unicode you know where you
need Chinese you know Chinese Japanese
or Korean or Islamic Arabia text you
know you can use all of them in one
encoding so Alan Mackenzie obviously he
you know he he doesn't hold the opinion
that and everything should be asking
anymore but however this this this idiot
okay he hang him
this idiot he but he still insist that
único should not appear anywhere in
source code for such as eMac B's he
insists that you know you cannot use you
issue shall not have Unicode in an eMac
base source code everything should be
pure ASCII now let me talk about the
actual instant about three years ago
let me find ya let me find out my
article maybe you can so you can may
have more details so let's search for
his name in my Emacs blog let's say
quote
okay sorry max blog archive 2018 October
so here I discussed understand ASCII
control characters okay here I wrote a
little rant on that but actually that's
not the full article let me see
so here is another article Emacs
redisplay internals in JavaScript mod
wall okay though these are history and
they are big giant flame wars and here
let's see quote okay here I also
mentioned about the quote issue only a
little bit about a curly quote basically
what happens is that in 2008 is that no
it's it's it's not 2008 it's in let's
see if I can find out
okay I want to find an article because I
have written quite a lot about it but I
am Not sure I actually published it but
even if I did not publish it I should
have it in my in my blog here local
somewhere
oh okay so hold on a second it's I think
we will find it just give me a minute
okay I didn't I did not publish it
every time I need to find something it's
hard to find
I'm pretty sure it's some is there
somewhere let's try one more thing let's
go to
[Music]
let's websearch Allen sorry
now I really want to tell this story but
when I'm having problems finding my
article because this is a huge story
with hundreds flame wars going on in the
Emacs dev mailing list
hundreds frame was you know lasting for
over a month you know each each person's
got opinions but this Alan McKenzie so
that basically the story is that so
around 2016 ok I think it's around 2016
some there is this guy a long time old
Emacs Ted developer I forgot his name in
my article but I cannot find it right
now but so he made a commit to Emacs
such that such that in you know in email
is documentation for example let's go to
software keys ok so you can see
you know for example this this is a I'm
at least code and in you know eMac this
code if you want to refer to another
command or function you can use this
quote by using a tick like backtick
followed by a straight quote a single
straight quote that then when you then
when you do this wave function on the
function name for example describe
function you will see you see this
command is highlighted you know so you
can jump to it by just pressing enter so
that is how you do it mock up you know
you mock up this function name by this
by this back tick and a straight quote
now I have a article here if you go to
practical eMac this practical eMac list
and you go to emag list miscellaneous
stock string markup you can see I
described you know different ways to
mark up the dog stream in emag this
function you know in-line dog stream so
there's this situation now the problem
there is a kind of minor problem because
you are not using matching quotes
matching quote is much better than this
this kind of hack because back then you
know in 1980s you don't have curly quote
which is matching you know so but today
in lots of documentation they use
Unicode and Coleco it becomes more and
more popular
but anyway so there's this guy who fixed
the problem so they fixed it so that all
the inline dog uses curry quote matching
quote you know from Unicode but the
Allen McKenzie guy objected you know
basically he he is the the the single
the the guy who object to that he argues
that we should not do that you know we
should not have Unicode anywhere in
source code so what does he
pose you know the question remains
people like to see you know curly quotes
in the documentation when you do a
describe function because that way you
know it's more pleasing to the eye
because the quotes are matched you know
so that's the issue people want to fix
so he's a dn't suggestion is that is
that you have you create another layer
so that when you code this scribe
function the describe function will
process the string and and change this
mock up into the curry quote one you
know and that variable name you just
mentioned nomen that that variable name
takes coding style that is the result of
these mechanism you know so you look up
text coding style to see you know kind
of as a preference what you should
really want to see then you know the
describe function will process you know
you will show using those for example
let's look at the you know in line top
described variable text coding style so
it's a stock imitations is a style to
use for single quotes in help and
messages yeah so so it becomes more
complex because every time you code
describe function or related functions
it has to go through this process and it
converts certain ASCII characters into
the unicode character in his opinion in
Allen's opinion this is a you know you
think this is simpler because you know
because you don't have Unicode in in a
source code but so eventually he after
one hundred few thousand more than one
thousand I think thousands something
flamewars articles these the result is
that he kind of forced the guy to revert
the commit so that you know things are
according through the way he he prefer
and this this story relates through
another thing about Richard Stallman
in the end everything was going
smoothly you know there is no gonna no
revert but in the end it's Richard
Stallman the you know he has
not been coded for like 20 years he's
you know he don't know nothing he hasn't
code you know a thing for at least 10
years I would say at least then he made
a comment yeah yeah and he was not the
you know the the technical leader at the
time the leader is Stefan this Stephanie
guy Stephanie guy a functional language
researcher but anyway in the end vicious
Omer made a comment oh we should meet
you know we should not have Unicode in
Cisco that you know made the thing that
that kind of you know bread break broke
the camel's back that that that is
actually the final result but that but
he has no power technically speaking
richard stallman it was not the leader
you know the so-called maintainer of
eMac at the time he was Stefan guy and
Stefan did not object
you know the using code equals in source
code
so his Richard Stallman it's it's no
it's a it's a problem you know we chest
oh man what reason did he give he didn't
really give any reason you see the
situation is that you have 1,000 over a
thousand flame wars they are about like
four or five people who is on the album
Mackenzie's side which I don't agree
with their opinions they are just like
they are these typical elite UNIX
philosophy they you know they
talk the reason to me are not good
reasons on our quality reasons or
technically wrong incorrect no factually
incorrect you know here and there but
anyway they are about four or five
people who are on the ulema Kenzie's
side who does not want any Unicode in
source code and they give a bunch of
reasons you know
I can like you know refute it all of
them just either factually incorrect or
just wrong
well anyway so you have this flame war
and the situation and and the leader the
Stefan guy who was the maintainer he's
supposed to be the technical decision
the decider for these issues he did not
object okay so everything is fine then
if he if he did not object then you know
things will just go the way they are but
but then the Richard Stallman just says
oh you should you know he just made a
comment like he's not supposed to be a
technical leader his opinion matters
only when when there's something related
to politics like you know the license
you know or or or something has you know
political results such as such as
whether to use some open-source
libraries things like that
so really he has no technically speaking
by the new free software policy about
you know their leadership and
maintenance you know he has no say about
the you know he cannot make a decision
but any but however because he's such a
guy you know Richard Stallman he just
sit there he put his opinion out every
day and people just like implicit fee
they say you know what what whatever he
says has a big influence so I mean in
the end he just said you know he just
made some some common like one sentence
about please reverted because you know
he he didn't actually even tries to give
a reason he just said please whispered
it because source code should not
contain Unicode that is it you can find
actually you can find the whole issue
that's okay I cannot find my article but
we can find a Google that the Emacs dev
list thread on this issue so let's
search for Emacs dev list
Kerli quote maybe we'll find that okay I
got I found my I found my article here
okay you can you can read the whole
article then and you can also click to
go to the eMac list day of articles yeah
so this article I kind of I remember
this article is not fully written but
kind of you know it's it's is it's a
draft but anyway so you can go to the
Emacs death list to see the entire frame
war thousands of messages on this so
here is the message from Adam McKenzie
this is a first message that he he you
know he so his title you know his
upcoming loss of usability of Emacs
source files and Emacs
you know he plastered this dramatic
title because he really does not like
any Unicode you know so he want to push
his you know his opinion this article
began yet this this article began the
whole flame war you know thousands over
a thousand messages on it so this is
2015 2015 June yeah so that so you know
that's the whole issue and our strohman
message you can see strowman at the end
says this okay the guy who made the
change is Paul Edgard Paul Eggert he I
don't know him but I did my research
when I was writing this he turns out he
is also a very old programmer he is the
author of yak you know the yak pasa
I think the UNIX yak pasa pasa generator
so he made a change in anima can see
McKenzie you know turn it on turn it
down Richard Stallman
yeah this message there is a message
from Richard storm and that I don't know
I don't know if I included here but
anyway if you are interested you know
god we'd read this article no I don't
think it has anything to do with
compiling Emacs basically these people
their reason they just they just don't
like Unicode in source code because for
example Allen's campaign is that you
know then you cannot type it you know
many of these people's opinions are just
wrong because today you can actually see
tons of places that has Unicode Unicode
not ASCII characters in programming
source code including a down in the few
okay
in JavaScript many big libraries project
does that in : does that okay go line
source code you can see I'm not sure
about source code but in : foot okay at
least in : documentation in gold an
official documentation in scheme this
documentation actually I can say you
know in lots of these languages source
code in major projects not just like
tiny project but major projects of these
languages USC único you know non ASCII
characters
okay that's it for today so you have ten
seconds to give me your last thoughts
your final your parting words for today
you know I was watching Game of Thrones
and you know they be they behead people
you know they be anything go so but when
they do they ask what's your final word
you know you have to ask them that yeah
yeah that's Richard storm and I think
that's what Richard Stallman says good
evening so good have a good evening
see you guys