Welcome to another episode of Saw Talk
Show. We are going to code Wuam language
advent of code 2025 day five part two.
In this month I've done advent of code
almost every day. So check them out.
Okay, so let's begin. So the pink window
shows all my command calls and
keystrokes. So let me adjust it so that
it doesn't get hidden.
So show this is my website kasali.info
http nos. So we're going to do a code
and here is a rand of code and if you
are here say hi.
Uh, leave a comment. Love to see your
comment. If you are watching this
offline, play at two speed, twice as
fast.
Okay.
Now, uh, kali.info. I have complete
tutorial on wam language for
programmers. You can see uh complete
tutorial basics common syntax string
data structure list uh how do you create
a number boolean list and how do you
create a function and variable
conditional loop
and you can download wra engine for free
following this link okay so
uh so let's begin code okay so let's So
let's start with our language
my keyboard. Let me introduce you my
keyboard. This is ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 UHK80.
I have a video review on my website and
uh so here's Wua language new notebook
three shift enter to evaluate it and uh
magnify.
Okay. So this is Wuam notebook.
If you don't know what is Wufam
language, watch my video uh episode
episode 731.
That's one hour introduction
uh about 3 days ago. Okay. So let's see.
So Wam language advent of code they they
um okay I forgot to put it back.
Advent of code episode 734
and uh
we can start coding. Okay, hold on a
second. So, I'm using Emacs, the most
advanced text editor, and I'm using
Softly Keys, which is the most efficient
keybinding system for Emacs. Uh, so
here's a source code, 4,000 lines of
code. It's on GitHub and you can go to
the homepage
SFY keys. There are tens of video
tutorials I've done in the past.
Basically, it's model keybinding system
like Vim, but the
key key mapping are based on statistics
of command frequency. So, it's most
ergonomic.
The most used commands are assigned to
the most easy fingers. So, can you see
it? Yeah. So, that's keys. Okay. And all
links are here. Okay. So, that's Emacs.
And I'm also using a vorac keyboard
layout. And the pink window shows all my
command calls or keystrokes. Command
name on the right, keystroke on the
left. Vorac keyboard layout. Showing
browser. Back. Close. Close. Close. show
in browser. Okay, today's talk show. Now
let's do day five part two. Now day five
part one if you have seen uh yesterday
or two days ago that's that problem is
given a range of numbers 3 to 5 10 to 14
and so on and give a list of numbers you
want to find
how many of these given list of numbers
are in the range. So you want the total.
Okay, that was uh part one problem. So
today we are part two. So let's see.
Okay, can you see the whole thing? Uh,
okay. So part two,
the elves starts bringing their spoiled
inventory to the trash shoot at the back
of the kitchen so that they can stop
bugging you when they get new inventory.
The elves would like to know all of the
IDs that the fresh ingredient ID range
consider to be fresh. Okay.
So instead of counting them, you want
the list of them. An ingredient ID is
still considered fresh if it is in any
range. Okay.
Now the second section of the database,
the available ingredient IDs is
irrelevant. Here are the fresh
ingredient ID ranges from the above
example. Okay. So for each number called
ingredient ID. So do you guys understand
the problem? So you see for each number
given that each number is called
ingredient ID. So if they are in this
given range any of them that means this
ID is fresh.
So now
the second section of database here
fresh ingredient ID. So you want to get
a list of ranges that contains the fresh
ingredient ID
3 4 5 10.
Excuse me. I still have code.
So if you are here comment okay the
ingredient ids that are these ranges
considered to be fresh are 3 4 5 10 11
12 13
uh okay so basically combine them 19 and
12 13 14 19 and 20 and 20. Okay, because
20. So in this example,
the fresh ingredient ID ranges consider
a total of 14 ingredients ID to be
fresh.
Process the database file again. How
many ingredient IDs are considered to be
fresh according to the fresh ingredient
IDs range?
Okay. Now you don't care about this
given list of ids. You only care about
the range. Basically, you want to know.
So each line specify a range
and you want to combine all the ranges.
How many number how many total number
are in these ranges? Is that right?
process the data process the database
file again. How many ingredient IDs are
considered to be fresh according to the
fresh ingredient ID ranges? Okay, pretty
simple.
So the naive way to solve the this
problem is you just create a range of
all these numbers. Then you do a union
like a set union. So you got a unique
list of them. Then you just check then
you just count the length of that list
the union. Okay, that's the naive way.
Now why is that naive? because
because the date five problem input the
ranges are huge. So if you actually
generate a list of these numbers, they
are going to be uh millions trillions.
Let's see.
So for example, copy one of them new
buffer. Uh let's put them into true line
and magnify.
Okay. and uh this number let's let's put
a uh let's put you know so in Python for
example let's
cut close so let's let's do some testing
okay so in fact
uh let's say we can do this in Python or
JavaScript
or wam language basically you want to
know for example let's try wam language
they you want comma separated
You see in Wuam language it separates
for you.
So that's K mega
uh Petra.
So what what's above So let's
check
kibi mi gibbi keto mega chigga. Okay, it
didn't go beyond
matrix prefix. Now we are doing
excursion. We want to know what's above
I believe that's peta.
Oh, terra. That's right. So you got ter
mega kilo mega then terra.
Okay. So what is this number?
Kilo mega
terra
terra or tetra terra. Okay, terra and
terra. So 221 terra.
So that's 10 followed by 12 numbers, 12
zeros. That's like So it's like 12
digits. 12
+ 13 14 15 digit numbers.
So can you have sufficient memory to
actually um
create this large number?
Let's see again. So
so let's kind of cheat you know look at
you know actually this is not cheat. We
just want to know how big are the
numbers the input numbers which is part
of the problem you see. So the length
you can compare the length they don't go
over that. So that is about as as large
you get. Okay. So is that right? Yeah.
Okay. So if we just generate a range
let's say
um
let's say that okay let's see if it will
go
uh beyond memory so this number to this
number range okay let's see now let's um
let's look at my memory so wam language
right now 195 megabyte
Okay, let's check the me memory graph.
Now let's do this. Shift enter. General
the current computation was aborted
because there was info in insufficient
memory available to complete the
computation. So yeah, so you cannot do
that. That means you cannot do that in
Python in JavaScript.
The number the the array length is too
big. Okay. So language simply abort it
before it even computes it. Okay. So you
don't want so but to find the length
it's easy. You just take the second
number minus the first number.
Oh okay. So
but then you need to reduce. Okay.
That's uh that's a interesting problem.
You re you need to remove the
duplicates. Okay.
So, how do you solve this?
You see this is you know normally you
just generate the range and you do a
union very simple but now you cannot
generate the range.
Um
interesting
so what are the comments? Hikaran, do
you notice a lot of typing difference
between real staggered keyboard like
ultimate hacking keyboard and glove 80?
Okay, that's a very interesting
question.
It turns out it doesn't matter much.
Okay, let's let me digress on keyboard.
So, if you search for keyboard blog, you
you get to my keyboard blog, which is
this page. And there are over 1,000
articles. So you can see 1,400
articles on keyboard, mouse, input
devices, keyboard layout, trackboard and
so on. So you see I got my trackboard
here and mouse here. So uh all so when
you shop for keyboard there are many
considerations. Do you want it split? Do
you or do you want it can it be can it
tent like you know instead of flat it
goes like that right now this is tented
you know so and what uh what about the
key switches do you want it mechanical
key switches what's the difference does
it help does mechanical key switches
help your handheld and if so which one
there are so many of them mechanical key
switches so you can find um articles all
here. Okay, for example, history or go
history key switch guide. This section
is all about key switches and also key
cap design. You know, there's so many
issues and also uh keyboard layout,
keypad key design. So um keyboard layout
for example
voraci
vorac coac and so on. So there are many
issues to consider when you buy a
keyboard and about the relation to
handheld and so on and of course price
portability
is it wireless or USB what kind of
wireless wireless USB dongle or
Bluetooth? There's there are pros and
cons and also the weight of the keyboard
the construction the quality of course
and also the software can it remap keys
is it does it have memory inside the
keyboard or do you always have to use
software so lots of consideration now
one of them is uh let's go to key key
design okay one of them is about the
staggered
you know why are keyboards keys not
aligned vertical vertically like a grid
like a matrix you know that's simple
right because your fingers move up down
your fingers human hand is not you know
up and down right that's natural you
don't go like sideways you know like the
right hand goes sideway that way the
left hand you know so like if you
consider symmetry you want if you want
to go inward then it's like but then
it's like that. Anyway, okay, my uh
video window is too small. So, anyway,
why are they staggered? This way is
called staggered because back then 200
years ago when mechanical typewriter
were invented,
they are mechanical. So, let's go to
typewriters. So,
so I'm digressing a little bit because
you know to answer this question I'm
giving you a full detailed account
palash backup. Okay. So this is kind of
history of mechanical typewriters. You
can see elaborate ones 200 years ago.
Okay. So when typewriters were created
mechanical typewriters they they are
mechanical it's not electronics. So it
every time you press the key they hit a
hammer and so on. So they need this
mechanism you see all this elaborate
mechanism
behind them. So which means the keys
cannot align cannot be aligned
vertically. So they are like so-called
staggered or slanted.
So that you see the underneath the keys
you got those level levels. So they must
be aligned. You see? So they have room
to go to you know the the the mechanism
the hammer bars have room. That is why
the keyboard we use have this weird
slanted shape. They are not like
uh like uh regularly orthogonal like you
you think you know 45 degrees they are
not like that. They are like shaped
slanted in a weird way. That's because
this is why. Okay.
So when electronic keyboards are
invented like today for example let's go
when electronic keyboard you don't you
don't have those mechanical mechanisms
underneath it you know the earliest one
let's see uh
key switch guide go history keyboard
history you know so when digital
computers are created uh okay so where
is it And so let's open that one.
You know, for example, Invac PK200
keyboard 1966.
There's no mechanism underneath it. It's
just, you know, electronic computers.
But people, we human animals has a habit
because we are already used to
this,
you know, we are already used. Wait, by
the way, this this one is interesting.
They are vertical. Uh, yeah, this is
this one is kind of special. So, let's
go back. We are already used to this
slanted way. So, people when people see,
you know, so let me show you a vertical
uh align keyboard. Okay. So, let's go to
ergonomic keyboard review. So, you can
see glove 80. One of my favorite. You
see they are not staggered they are just
straight because your fingers move up
down that's more natural and lots of
more. So for example this is one of the
first you know so these are they what
they call this or linear okay so this
Kinesis keyboard Kinesis 360 I have
video reviews for all of them. Okay. For
this this this
uh and so and there's also so this one
also interesting ortholinear but they
are symmetric you know they are like
slanted but they are symmetric because
your hands are symmetric it's your your
hand doesn't grow that way you know your
hand are symmetric. So,
so when when um electronic keyboard got
invented
but people don't want it because habit
you know they they don't want this
straight you know orolinear because they
are used to the weird slant. Okay.
So that is a phenomenon
of many conventions of everyday things.
You know when technology improved
to have a better way but human animals
we refuse it. We don't want it because
we are already used to this weird
Okay. So that is why to this day all the
normal keyboards you know including for
example
uh Apple computers
you know all the keyboards you have this
weird slant which is idiotic extreme
but what can you do you know people are
used to it uh can we go let's show again
so open
uh Open open.
So you can see Apple iBook year 2003
and this is MacBook 2019. They are all
slanted and that's that one is special
anyway.
So um so question but today since about
10 years ago a lot of people you know we
change slowly every decade when the old
generation dies the new generation they
don't know what the are these
mechanical typewriters like never seen
it so they don't have this habit issue
so for for the new generation including
your children you know whatever you get
used to you think it's best normal but
then your children don't know what your
experience is. Your children think you
are idiot in many things including
programming languages. So the new
generation
they don't have attachment or habit with
this. So beginning about 10 years ago
there are many keyboards that are let's
go uh
you know they are not they they are
ortholinear
for example this one from China or
linear grid okay much better so when you
buy a keyboard today there's a question
should you go with the orolinear like
the modern supposedly better or should
you with a convent con conventional like
UHK 80 which is what I'm using.
So ideally in my opinion you should go
ortholinear. Orlinear is just better in
theory and in practice or okay or linear
straight. No weird slant like complete
idiot idiotic This this habit
you know habit indu induced
But however it is not a very important
issue. Okay. Now let me show you some
other examples. Ortholinear you know
symmetric. Okay that's good. Uh that's
good. But this one you see they they do
the kind of semi-traditional so people
came from traditional keyboard can get
used to this you know. So anyway, so the
qu question is when you buy a new
keyboard, you are aware of these issues.
You know, you got young, you know, so
but which one should you choose? So it
turns out this ortholinear or slanted
does not matter that much all things
considered. Okay, on a keyboard, you
know, do you want it split? Do you want
it um do you want it like the surface
curved? Do you want it you know
mechanical keys? Of course. Do you know
so many many choices and about keyboard
layout? So of all these choices as far
as handheld goes
whether it is slanted like the
traditional um slant or whether it's
ortholinear does not matter that much.
Okay. So for me
now I can use both of them trivially. I
like I don't even notice like if you
switch from one to the other you might
make some mistakes the first day then
you just get used to it. Okay. So for me
like I can switch from from the
staggered or the ortholinear
um you know any day you know any hour no
problem. Okay does that answer your
question? If I if I did answer your
question, say yes or something. Okay, so
that is a digression into keyboard. Now
let's go back to
let's go back to coding the problem.
Okay, so let me think. So we run into a
problem. How do you solve this? Okay,
makes sense. Fantastic. Thank you,
Palash.
Okay, let's solve this problem. So the
problem is you are given a bunch of
ranges. You want to find their union and
uh how many total are there. How do you
solve this? Let's see. Let's see.
So what you can do is you um
okay so you got range first of all you
sort them by the by the minimum by the
first number in the range okay then you
break them into segments
like for example 10 to 14
10 to 14 and 16 to 20 they overlap.
How do you know they overlap? Because
the first range last number the maximum
is wait they don't overlap. Hold on a
second. 10 to 14 16 to 20. Okay. Now
16 to 20 and 12 to 18 they overlap.
Okay. So let me show you how how that
works.
And uh let's also write it out. Okay. So
we forgot. So
uh so let's not let's not do this. Okay.
So
the naive way to solve is problem. So
the problem
the
description
carbon description
given a list of ranges. For example,
find how many total this
this
distinct
numbers are in them. Okay, that is the
problem description. Uh wait.
Okay. Problem description. Now,
now the naive way to solve this problem
is just
to generate a list of numbers for each
range.
Then you
do a set union of all the lists.
Then you just count
get the
length.
Okay. So does that make sense? Okay. Let
me uh let me put this
showing browser. So we got the problem
description and we got naive solution
but
the naive sol
okay
but the naive solution won't work
because the range the number range
too many numbers to fit into memory.
Okay, that is the problem. So
therefore,
here
better solution.
Here is a better solution. algorithm
description how we going to attack this
problem.
So given a list
of ranges
first we sort them. Okay.
Example
sort them
by their mean.
Okay. So press a key to sort them. Okay.
Actually uh press a key. Now you want to
sort uh
so in EMAC you can do this give a value
one then meta x sort numerical fields
okay so you sort it so you got it became
that
you see 128 become the notimate line
then 1620
you see different from here here is 16
20 then 12 18 right you saw them by
their first number then
you find their intersection
you
how do you say this you well uh how do
you say this let's focus on focus on
these two lines 12 to 18 16 to 20 they
overlap
you Find
ranges,
neighbor ranges that overlap.
And you do that by
to determine
overlap.
Lab or lab overlap.
Check the max of
uh
two ranges
overlap.
If the
max of burst
which is 18 is greater
or equals to the mean of the
next range. greater or equal yes
to the mean of the
second range.
Okay,
showing browser fantastic analysis of
the problem.
Anyone else watching say hi. Okay,
so
that's easy.
Now
when you deter when you find two ranges
that overlap
for example
that and that
you create a new range let's see uh
when you find the range overlap
You
you reduce the first
the max of the first range
by
the mean
of the second range
minus one.
For example,
becomes
um
because
minus 1. Does that make sense? So 1218
becomes 1215.
Then you got 16 to 20, right?
Yeah.
So then you can continue comparing that
and the next range. Okay. Does that make
sense? Yes.
Okay.
Let's make sure this algorithm works.
Okay, I think so.
Just this algorithm works. So you got a
list of numbers.
Sort them by the first.
Now what if let's see what if um what if
you have that that identical
okay so
if we follow our algorithm this will
become
12 to 11
and that doesn't work.
Yeah, that's you see this is a edge
case.
If they are repeated
then you got then by our algorithm you
get that
and
If the two ranges are identical,
simply remove them.
Okay, that works out.
So another a new rule before we do this
then first of all if two ranges are
identical just remove one of them.
Okay. Then what then? What else? Let's
see
what what about the special case of uh
what about special case of that?
Uh if
if you get that then the new
range for the first one is just
17. So that works out.
Yeah.
Okay.
So
better solution given these ranges.
First if uh first we saw them they mean
then if it so happens
that
two neighboring
ranges are identical.
Remove one of them.
Remove or search
ranges. Okay, first step. Then you find
neighboring ranges that overlap. Okay.
Okay. I think that's
that's great description analysis of the
problem. We got a solution already. Now
we got the algorithm to implement it is
trivial.
Okay. Anyone watching say hi. Okay. To
implement this is trivial. So
uh so let's let's you know let's go slow
and have fun uh I want to make this
instead of a hardcoded text let's make
it into actually um
uh paragraph instead of instead of
hardcoded.
Okay, let me just show you. Okay, so
problem description
given a list of ranges
uh
code.
I know. Okay.
Oh god. Sorry about that.
showing browser. So now that's a better
description problem description and
analysis.
Okay, let's start to implement this
problem.
Wolf language code
solution
w language code
input
input is just the first
set of numbers. Okay.
Okay. You need to turn that into a list
of ranges. Okay. So, we we go to
yesterday's
input and uh copy the code from there.
Okay.
Copy.
SL paste. Okay,
this this is official input. But now we
only care about the first segment.
So let me show you how that is the next
range list. Okay, we don't care about
the um
Okay.
Oh god. Got something wrong here.
That's it.
Uh, wait.
Okay. Now run the whole thing.
That's the result. Fantastic and
beautiful. Okay.
Wait, you forgot two expression. Uh
those are actually strings you need to
two expression. Okay.
Copy all. Go back here. Paste it. Shift
enter. Fantastic. Okay, that's the
answer. You got a list of ranges. Then
then what you do is you do something to
this list range list. Okay. So according
our plan the algorithm description we
going to go back to today we going to uh
mean max okay
so so first of all sort okay let's do
this um
let's let's do this uh in a trial and
error way so you can see the output then
we build our function Okay. So, here's a
list of ranges. Then we can actually So,
let's
Okay, that's our list range. Okay. Then
then what you do is you're going to do
something to that.
You want to sort them. Sort. Okay.
Now sort
takes two arguments. Uh you can actually
sort by
the difference is that sort takes a
function
predicate. Okay. Uh which is which is a
function takes two elements then returns
one or negative one. determine which one
is from or you can sort by
sort by will
sort by uh element they say first okay
that we'll do it okay so let me show you
shift enter I believe so you can see the
difference 1620 1218 now 1218 620 20.
Okay, that is the sort by the power of
sort by.
You can look up the documentation
language sort by the second argument is
a function that extract the element to
sort. Okay. Then you just delete
duplicate
unique. Wait. Um,
delete duplicate.
Let's check the documentation. Delete
duplicate data. Deletes all duplicates
of data. Okay, we can do that.
sort by then
delete duplicate now. Now in this
example,
okay, so hold on a second.
Uh do we have a uh sort by say let's
copy the uh
copy so for those it's easier to
understand. Okay. Now delete duplicate.
What happens is that now let's say
sorted ranges equals to okay
right
now delete duplicate will
now in our case we don't have duplicate
but but let's say if uh there is a
duplicate Let's say that.
Okay. So if you do that it will remove
the 128 that's repeated. You see
so this is the example. Okay. So we want
to do that
through the exorted ranges. Okay.
Just in case. Actually last time we
checked there's no duplicate. Okay. So
delete duplicate. Okay. Once you delete
the duplicate, then you want to check um
minmax.
So you want to map through all of them
and generate a new one. You want to
check the neighbors. Okay.
Okay. Now, let me show you what to do.
You want to um
partition. Let me show you what this do.
Okay. A
A
B
C
partition
uh two with a repetition of one. It will
return a a a
pair of list then I mean it will return
a b and bc it will return like
let's see d
E. Okay, I'll run it. You you'll see
what it mean.
You see AB B C D E. So it kind of
it partition a list with one element
repetition. Okay.
See example. Then we just map.
Sorry, hold on a second.
Then you just map.
For example, this is a list. You map a
function
to this list.
In here each
each of the a
b c act is a range. Okay. So for example
this a a this a and b are two ranges. A
is a range b is a range. Okay. Then you
write a function to reduce that compared
like a b are neighboring ranges. B and c
are neighboring ranges.
Hold on a second.
Okay. Then you
then you write the function ff. So what
the f do?
function.
Then
X range with
Okay.
So,
Okay. So that's the two ranges. Then
what you do is um
if
If the last number of range one, the
maximum
is uh
that algorithm. Okay.
If the max of the first range is greater
equal is greater than
the first
of the second range.
Then you return a range of
Okay, that's the
Well,
Let's continue. Okay. Then we clean the
code.
Okay. The first of range one to the last
of range two that means they overlap
otherwise
otherwise return
simply them as is. Okay.
Is that does that make sense?
Okay. So, we kind of you know so this
code
so that's our function. Okay. this.
Can you guys understand?
If last of the first range, let's double
check. If last of the first range which
is maximum is greater than or equals to
the uh the first range two. Okay, the
first of the range true
that means they overlap then you return
this otherwise you return them as is
uh
actually you can just return them as is.
Okay,
let's let's clean up the uh rename the
variable so it's easier to understand,
shall we?
Let's rename this range pair. Okay.
Okay.
So, copy that.
Paste it and
copy it
and paste it. So, language formatted.
It's kind of easier to understand.
Okay. Let's use the form. Okay.
So, so now it's easy to do. So, we
already, you know, we already got the,
you know, so actually, so let me just do
it. Um, code it
going to code this one shot. Okay. So,
so the these are kind of examples. Okay.
That mean these are like uh example
code.
Example code telling you what it is
doing. Okay.
Solution.
Okay. Showing browser problem
description and problem analysis.
Okay.
Problem
description. Better solution. Naive
solution.
Okay. Problem description.
Naive solution. Okay. Naive solution.
Need to move up.
Then better solution I'll go description
and here are solution. Now here is
sample code
uh sample code exchange list
you know this is our sample solution
just show the how it works. Okay, now we
going to code our real solution.
Okay, now we just copy the code here.
We just deleted
We just delete it. Uh
yeah. So, let's go back to here.
Yeah, let's copy that. Copy
paste. Okay, so
Okay, that's our range list.
Okay,
run it.
Correct.
Okay, we're going to do this one shot.
So, range list. So, width. Okay, range
list is that
wait, what you doing? So, make it one
line
range list.
And so here is the sample.
Okay, that's the range list. And uh then
we just do the function. Um so go back
to today
sort ranges. Okay. And let's copy that.
Copy.
So here is what we will do.
Okay. So many code.
So we got the range list and we want to
sort them.
Okay. Highlight the range list. Okay.
Sort it. Then delete duplicate.
Okay, I don't care about that. Don't
care about that. When you got solid
range, that's right. Then you partition
partition
this part. Okay, partition that.
Okay, partition that. Then you just uh
then you just map a function
map the function to the list this one.
Okay. Now what is the function? You're
going to map this ff which is this
function
that function. Okay. And that's it.
Let's uh bring our code. It's a
solution. Okay, we can run it. Let's
just run it. Okay. Right. Oh, yeah. You
you need to count the total. So, wait.
Uh first normal nonatomic. Okay. We got
the we got the issue.
Nonatomic expression expected. Okay. We
forgot something. Okay. So, let's double
check.
So range list that's right and uh
so this is a function mapped to this.
Is that correct?
Yeah. So
pair, right? Then you just map.
So map to this. That's right.
Then the function here is our function.
Let's be careful. Now where is X? That's
the that's where is wrong. So X is
undefined. X should be the range pair.
Okay,
range pair. So where is the X occur? So
that's it.
Run the whole code.
That's right. So you got this list of
unique ranges. Okay. Then you just
flatten
Okay, let me show you. Flatten that
result. Then uh flatten by by one level.
Then you just take the length. Okay, so
let me show you. Okay, so
so function
at okay. What is this function? your
function. This function will flatten x
by first level
then
then just take the length.
Okay. So so now it will return the
solution right
six.
Oh, wait. You want to know the distinct
numbers. So, you want to know Okay. So,
actually, you don't want to flatten.
Okay. So, instead of flatten, you want
to um
wait, you want to flatten.
Okay. Then,
okay. Is this get complicated? you you
flatten.
So you got um
you got a list of ranges. Okay. Then you
map to
then you map. Okay. This uh
function let me just write it. Okay. The
function will be
minus. So for example 20 minus 16 is
four. That means there are four of them.
17 18
19 20. So the last x minus
first
at x then you need to plus one.
So you want to map that function to this
thing. Okay. So can you guys see?
Okay. So you
okay cut
paste
okay this is the whole solution
uh I don't know if you guys will find it
readable
run it
okay general stop you got a problem
something okay so well I can
See?
Yeah.
Yeah. So, where is the problem?
Run it.
Nonatomic expression expected at
position one in last tense. So you got
the last 10. The flatten is wrong. So
okay, you can't do this yet. You I mean
you need to see the output. Okay. So
don't map yet. Okay.
Let's see what's the result.
So you got that result.
Then let's try the flatten.
That's not what you want. Okay. So you
want
uh function
flatten
one.
Okay.
Uh no that's not what you what you want.
Okay. So wait,
okay,
that's why you got a problem. So instead
you want instead of flatten, you want um
just flatten. Okay.
Do you guys find what I'm doing funny?
Then add and then partition.
Actually, we can you can do this. Okay.
You just need to uh say something like
that.
Yep.
So flatten level one to -2. Uh
Jesus.
Let's see. Flatten. Flatten n. Okay.
Flatten. Flatten to level n.
So flatten to level -2. Okay.
No.
So let me just do this again. We don't
get too complicated. Okay. Flatten. So
instead, let's just put that there.
Okay. So flatten -2.
Uh -1.
No
should be a negative number.
Uh okay. So the negative number let's
say so if it's one
you get.
So some part you don't want to flatten
to one. Yeah. So you don't So you can't
use flatten on this.
Yeah. Okay. So you have to do partition
then.
Okay.
Now
I'm pretty sure
uh wait.
Okay. Let me just do this in functional
way. Okay. Then then you just say
partition
partition button that all the way then
partition by two. Okay.
And it that should do it. Okay. That
that does it. Okay. That kind of
um that does it.
So let's delete all this junk. Okay. So
that is what you want to do. So you need
to fix your flatten code.
Yeah. So that needs should be that
instead of that
flatten at that that then you need to
map that to that. Okay. So
So let me try something.
Let's see the presidents. Okay,
let's see. Do I need Okay, so this is
perfect.
You don't need Okay, you don't need
parenthesis.
Okay, so we just run this code. This is
the solution. Okay,
comment it out.
This is the solution. Okay.
This this thing.
So wait. So last minus first map to that
then you need to actually total them.
Then
you need to actually total them.
Put a bracket in total.
I mean put a paren and total at
run it
26.
Now what what is that junk?
Oh yeah because we got this. Okay. 26.
Is that the solution?
Uh, consider a total of 14 ingredients
ID to be fresh. 14,
not 26. So, I got it wrong.
Yeah, annoying.
Very annoying. So, this code is getting
too complicated. I don't think people
understand. So we need to actually break
them into
smaller parts.
But anyway, the result is wrong. That
means we have to debug anyway. Oh
What? Why is it 26? Let's see. Let's run
this.
9 * 9 is 18.
5 3 is 8. So 9 * 3 27 - 1 is 26. That is
incorrect.
Okay. So
okay, this is a problem. Nobody's here.
Okay.
Okay. So, let's just this run this one
by one, shall we?
Even that part is wrong. So, what
it.
Okay, that returns that. Okay, then
let's just do this one by one so we
don't get
confused. Okay. So this map part
language open new one. paste
magnify
shift enter.
So we get this new list.
Is that correct?
We separated 35. Wait, this is like
totally wrong. How did we get this?
Okay, so then you need to break them
apart.
range pairs. Okay, that's range pairs.
Okay.
That's what you get.
example.
Okay.
Then
you map a function
to this range pair. So,
so what is the result?
Wait, something went missing. Okay. 35
1014.
35 1014 does not change. 1014 1218.
That became 1018. 104 128
10 to 14 12 to 18 that just become 101
18 that's correct.
Now 128 to 1620
that just becomes 1220.
Oh, so once you do this, you need to
recurse. You see, then you you know then
then you got 1014 and 1018. They
overlap. So you need to recurse this
tricky
Okay. So you know you can't do this
once. So
So okay, we can modify our function. So
to do it one shot. No actually we
already destroyed our function. So
yeah. So we so we need to recurse this.
Okay.
So once this done then you do need to
partition and flatten.
Okay. Then forget about that. Okay. So
you need to partition and flatten and
you need to re recurse this
fixed point obviously
fixed point at this this this this.
Okay. So actually we can do that and uh
try it
uh code with one argument two or more
argument expected. That's right. You
need a initial
you need a function.
Oh right that's right.
So this part this whole thing needs to
this whole thing needs to become a
function.
Yeah, we can do it. You know turn this
part into a function.
Okay, easy.
This range pair list is the input. Okay,
so
Wait. So this range pair there that
becomes a function. You see this is a
function
and and what this function do is
is actually
up to here.
Wait this section the function is kind
of nesting. Okay.
Do you know do you guys know what I
mean? Maybe not.
So from language.
So
okay. So you copy that. So fix point
takes a function and takes the initial
value. Okay. So fixed point
takes a function
cut that's a function then takes the
initial value. So what is the initial
value? That initial value is range pair
list. Okay then copy that
paste. Does that make sense? Shift
enter. Ah
Okay, this is taking too long. This is
becoming this is not good.
No, nobody's watching.
Okay, I just going to need I just going
to code it quickly. Okay, I'm just going
to code it for myself and finish the
problem.
It's been uh 90 minutes already, I
think.
Oh
This is very interesting.
Okay, this part is interesting because
it shows
that you need to do you need to recurse
this
Because 10:14
then you got 1018
in cold.
Okay, let me just think about this.
You can use block map
instead of the partition. Okay. Instead
of the flattening partition which is
much more efficient. Okay. Black M map
block map
was introduced in what year?
2015 10 years ago. Yeah, we can use
that. So instead of flatten and
partition by two, we can use block map.
That will save a lot of code this
partition and uh
okay. But uh what but what is the um
If they overlap,
then what you do?
If they overlap then
Now if they overlap then
first range one last range two.
That's right.
If they do not overlap.
Okay. Need some change of structure.
Just black map.
Okay.
We block this function.
If they overlap, if they overlap, then
you if they overlap, then you actually
need to return.
If they overlap
10, 14, 16, 20.
Yeah. Then you just return one thing.
this one thing.
If they do not overlap,
then you actually return the first one
instead of a pair. So that way you keep
the structure.
Do you guys understand? I don't think
so.
Well, you can't just return the first
one because
you cannot just return the first one.
you need to return the pair.
Well, in that case, you don't want to
use black block
See?
You can flatten them like that.
Okay. So, you need to like sequence
sequence is from 1996.
Yes.
What?
That's right.
Okay, more testing.
Perfect.
Wait, wait a second. No, not perfect.
35 10 14 16 20 12 18 no change.
Oh, because you didn't uh you didn't
sort and all that. So, you need to do
that first.
So forget about partition then.
Actually, you don't want to be pay list.
Okay, just range list.
That's right. Work on that.
Okay. Then you do this copy.
No change.
10 14
12 18
Why is it no change?
God, this is pretty bad. 10 14
last range one greater than first range
two then you return first range one last
range two
block Map
block map is not working.
Block map is not working.
Oh, you need to say two. Is that right?
Yeah, stupid.
That's right. The block map needs two
here.
What?
Fantastic. Now wait, there's something
still not right. 1620. So 128,
right? 128 1620
becomes 1220. So they get eliminated.
10:14
1218 10:14
They also need to change but they
didn't.
3 5 10 14 return as is.
This is incorrect.
This
splice is created in
2020.
Not sure I want to use this
experimental.
You know, you should use splice instead
of sequence there.
Yeah, that's what I want. You see,
that's what I want. But
Splice is created in
2020,
five years ago, kind of new,
so I'm not sure I want to use that. And
also it says experimental.
It basically remove the brackets around
it. So,
so I mean the issue here is that you
want to keep the structure so that you
don't have to every time you finish this
you have to do flatten and partition
to make it pairs to make it like that
the range. So,
so it was there a
function that uh
subset map
When is subset map created?
Also pretty new I think 2019.
Okay, I'm just going to stick with the
classic way. So,
uh, this is no good because it's now
taking more than hour to solve this
stupid problem.
So, I really need to
I need to speed up. This is no good
trivial problem. Let me I mean
if you do the procedural way although
it's tedious by now you you would have
solved it.
Okay block map
block map you want to keep the structure
return the same structure. So
if it is overlap then you return
Uh there's a there's also efficiency
issues you can consider.
So basically you need this step to be
repeated because
Okay, come on. Let's just solve it.
Solve this. Okay, so
Second range should be
well. One easy solution is to keep the
structure. You can just like
to keep the structure just do that.
Then you need to remove that zero one.
So you can say no.
Then you need to say delete more. No
more.
keep the structure. So you see you got a
list of ranges.
So you want to merge the ranges
sometimes
and otherwise leave it alone. Okay? You
want to sometimes merge the ranges or
leave alone. The
irregularity happens when you have a
pair of ranges and you merge them become
one range.
So how do you solve this?
So let's think about
I really want to solve this.
Okay. So in a functional way wam
language style. Okay. So you go to
Okay. So if you don't want to use
this map
block map,
you could go back to recursion.
Uh then recursion is kind of procedural
but um
Uh I like I prefer block map. Okay.
Okay. Let's just do block map. Let's
just do this in the way in a way.
Although it's not efficient but um
like we are doing here. Okay.
more then partition it then that will
do. Okay, just
just get it to work and remove the zero
zero. Okay.
Uh
paste shift enter. Yeah. Then 1014 and
1220 they needs to be uh you need to
repeat this process. Okay. So what you
can do is fixed point.
So didn't we have that there? Yes. So we
got the fixed point
and yeah so you need to turn the whole
thing into a function.
function
function.
Okay, then the function expression is
this
and the function input is uh
range
list. Okay, the function
input is range list.
So
okay actually they need to be
there. Okay so that will work
this function.
So this function
and then you just say fix point
fix point
the first argument is a function which
is this one. Okay. Then the second
argument is the actual range list.
Right. Yeah. So that's the second
argument. The first argument is a
function
we can say ff. So make
what are we doing?
This is kind of advanced, pretty
advanced functional programming. So, let
me show you. Let's just run it.
Shift enter. So they reduced to 3 5 10
3 minus
5 - 3 + 1 is 3 14 - 10 + 1 is 5
5 + 3 is 8. So is that the solution?
Wait 14.
What?
Wait, wait. 35
104. Wait. 1220 disappeared.
1220 disappeared.
What?
So this is just wrong. Jesus.
Now I am
Now I am really not feeling good about
this because we spent so much time
and did not
finish it.
Okay. summon an integer lead code.
So
yeah, this is so bad. Let's see.
Shift enter. Now copy that. Now if I put
that there.
So our algorithm is in fact wrong
because
now 12 to 20 disappeared.
So 104 12 20 do they overlap? Yes.
So it should become 104 to 1220. So it
should be two it should be 1020.
So why did this
104 last first? So first range one, last
range two,
last range two should be 20. So how did
we get 104?
But
we got the code just wrong somewhere.
Okay.
So, let's replace the function just by
f.
Oh,
wait. Block map.
Oh, you forgot block map. It should be
that. That's right. Block map by two
then overlap one. Oh, idiotic.
Okay, I have been idiotic all this time.
Block map.
Yeah, you forgot to say you have to say
one because we want one overlap. Okay,
so and
of course
here. Okay. So now if you do fixed point
now that's good. Okay. Now if you now
okay so now let's suppose this is good.
Delete
delete delete delete. So this is our
code. Perfect. Now, now we just um
Yeah, we just map this to it.
So, let's try it here.
Okay. So, map these two.
Shift Ctrl L to copy the last output.
last minus first
then total at as output
28 which is incorrect.
Oh wait oh you need to then what?
Wait hold on a second. So you need to
108 1020. Why is that not reduced?
Oh god. Now he ran into another problem
108 1020. They should become just 1020.
That's right. Now, if you do this again
and uh
last output,
do it. That's right. Copy the last input
and this part
will be last output.
Do it.
It did not reduce
1020 1018. So
the last maximum is greater than the
first
the last
first I mean the the the
maximum of a range
is greater than the minimum of the
second range then you merge them is so
108 1020 should become
10 20
but it did not happen.
It did not happen because
why did not happen? Let's see.
3 5 10 14 10 14 10 18
10 10 18 10 20 Why did we not get 10 18
10 20
What?
3 5 10 14 10 14 10 18 10 10 18 10 20
Is that right? Yes.
But then
But then what the is going on here?
No, because
what?
Wait, that's a function.
That's a function.
Okay, so this function got fed into
here.
So this is a function. This is the
function body.
Okay. And this is the argument.
I'm not seeing why it is.
I'm not seeing why this is not
walking.
Oh.
Yeah, this is pretty bad.
So
function.
mention it at
You know there's nothing
computer they don't make mistakes so you
always just work out diligently.
There's nothing can screw you up. Okay.
You can always find out what is wrong.
So let's just screw this um
this complicated nesting of functions.
Let's not
you know this part should be equivalent
just to that. I cannot believe it's the
Wait,
you don't need even need function here.
Yeah,
now this is simpler
what I was doing before.
This is simpler. Okay, run it.
Uh, wait.
What was I doing?
Let's start over again. Okay,
let go.
Copy.
Okay. Paste again.
Now again there is
you just simply go by logic nothing go
wrong. Okay. So that is a function.
Now you see this block is a function.
Okay.
Remove that function.
Remove it. Okay. And this range list is
now just that. Okay. Now this is again a
function. So so you can remove this
function
remove and you partition block x is just
that. Okay. So in other words this is
equivalent to that.
So why do you do this complicated form?
I'm doing this complicated form so you
avoid nesting because this is deep
nesting.
You get you get a problem when you have.
So you see
35 1014 1014.
So 3 5 10 14 1014 1018 18
and uh 108 1020. So you are missing 108
1020. Wait.
Okay, you up. So why do are you
doing the partition
So this so your code about this flatten
What?
God, this code is not good.
Yeah, our code, our block code is
perfect,
but this flatten and partition is
screwing it up.
That's right. That's right. If you are
using FF, but if you are not using FF,
it should work. Okay.
So, what is what the is going on
here? So,
so if you just use a list
then you see 108 10 1820. So then
okay where are we?
Okay, let me get this to work.
This is no good. This taking too long.
So
taking like too long and complicated.
Okay, let's try again. Range list is
that that's right
now. What's wrong with our block map?
block map produces that.
Then you need to
Then
like this.
Very
bad
holding this session.
10 14 12 18 12 18 16 20 So what do you
produce?
That's right. So,
so can you just flatten
level one?
Wait.
Yeah, you just flatten one level.
No need to partition
That's right. One level. No need to
partition
Okay,
our input.
This is the code.
Shift enter.
You need to uh wait. We already fixed
for why didn't it reduce?
1014 1018.
What? Uh
this function
at last shift enter.
1014 1018
10:14 10:18
Why did that not combine them?
So this is a problem. So X range is
Wait. So fixed point
function
this is
Did we have like syntax problem?
Okay. No.
What?
That's the function. This is the input.
Now what is original input? The original
input is just that
Okay, now it went into infinite
recursion
probably
language
kernel for Windows. was 60 70 mgabyte in
170 mgabyte.
Wow. Minimal use of memory. Something is
wrong.
There is a lot
organized by name by CPU
language kernel.
What?
Why does it run zero kernels?
But this is not exiting. So control
period to
stop.
Alt period. Okay.
Old period to old.
Yeah. Very, you know, we not doing good
today. So
although the solution is very close but
it's just something is wrong.
I'm going to delete this video.
Is there anyone watching then
people
I'm very annoyed you know
so this simple problem took two hours
and not done and now I'm kind of tired
of this
thing
this functional programming and We now
we get into infinite loop. Something
wrong with our code,
fixed point,
fixed point, a function, an expression.
A function and expression. The
expression is that and the function is
this function.
And this function takes a range list.
That's the input.
Okay. Then
then what it do? It
um
it flatten is said it does this block
map. It should work.
But I don't understand why this is not
work. Okay, let's try nest list.
Okay, next list of this function and the
input will be
that initial input
initial input and how many time you want
to nest three times.
Shift enter.
So here's the result. So the first time
the initial input is that then the first
time you you do it. Um can you do this
matrix form
table form? Okay.
So the first time wait uh 10 13
3 5 10 14 3 5 10 14 16 20 12 18 That's
the first time.
Second time 3 5 10 14 I don't like this
form. 10 20
16 20 16 18
This is the problem. Each time you got
more,
you see? So each time the list
increases.
What?
So in the step
104 104
Why does the list increase?
Okay, I'm tired and I'm going to maybe
DD this video
because
nobody's watching and it's taking 3
hours now.
I think I got to go.
Good.
Once you added it, it becomes input.
Interesting.
Yeah, the list gets longer. That's
It's just not right.
Idiotic.
What are what are these table view?
No, I'm just like doing random
spreadsheet.
Now I'm just doing random. Okay. The you
know our code is incorrect. It's
it's adding. Wait, is it possible for it
to uh grow?
So you map to a pair
if the if they overlap you reduce the
pair into
one range.
Okay. But now if they do not overlap
it return the pair itself.
You see but the thing is
you are doing the map block map. So you
are like almost increase the
you are mapping two neighbors. So every
time you do this you are
Yeah. So you you you don't want to Yeah.
That's why they increase. No, I know
they increase.
So,
so what you can do is you delete
duplicate each time you do this loop.
You delete duplicate again. But that's
not good. That's inefficient.
So you
So you see that's why you got them
repeated. So,
so this
see block map
block map block map block app.
I need to take a break.
I'm not going to finish this. I need to
take a break.
Okay.
very
frustrated with this,
what to do. Um, either take a break and
continue
or just stop
or stop and delete this video
because this video
the first hour is useful because we
analyze the problem.
Then we talked about we went into about
keyboards.
Um
but then
we went over um but then
now where the where is even my talk
show page
but then we um reanalyze the problem
very well.
Um but then we got code one code issue
after another.
So, it doesn't look good.
So, what uh delete the video.
But this
this should work. But now I'm just
tired. Okay. And I'm just now tired.
What to do now? Shoot.
I need a break for sure.
Okay, break. Break.
I'm going to come back. Maybe we'll
delete this video after all. But for
now, let me just take a break.
Do I still live in Mountain View? Yes.
Why do you ask that? Who are you?
Answer Amazon. What?
Why do you ask that question?
Who are you?
Okay, this up.
I don't feel like doing it.
Now, this is red wine. By the way, you
cannot see
not many like 200 milliliters.
Now, Amazon answer the question.
Who are you? Have you been watching my
videos? How long ago? Like because
that's a personal question and I'm
sensitive to
those of kind of questions because I
talk about all sort of things.
Okay, answer that question like
why why are you asking that question?
Who are you?
Because I don't remember
Amazon, you watch my video before
because on the internet there's all sort
of lookers. You don't know who they are.
Don't know where you came from.
Okay. Anyway, so answer that question.
Okay.
So,
so we got this situation this um this
block map.
Shall I explain what block map is?
uh be you know I explain everything this
take take 10 hours
but block block map allows you to map a
function to a list
with repetition so you can overlap them
we want to do that because given a list
of ranges we want to check neighboring
ranges so this pair of range we want to
check then this pair of range then next
you know every
two neighbors of the range. So that's
why we use block map. Alternatively is
you use partition which cut a list with
one repetition into pairs.
But if you do partition that's another
call. So you map and partition. So block
map combine the two function call into
one function call. So block map. So if
block map is given this input 35 1014
it will produce it will map like
like this 35 1014 1014 1218 128 1620
um
and uh and
128 1620 Yeah. So that's original input
list. Okay. So right now I'm just very
uh
not feeling good because I took 3 hours
to work on this and it's not working. So
let me just distract and go to I need to
turn on my mouse trailer because I used
to have mouse trailer. I turned it off
because I thought you don't need it, but
actually it's better to have mouse
trailer,
mouse pointer trailer. So, let's turn it
back on.
So, personalization, you go need to go
to uh block Bluetooth and devices
and mouse
and uh you can turn on uh pointing
trailer. Okay. So, scrolling mouse
pointer speed
enhance precision.
Additional mouse settings
there. This window 11 idiotic tiny
screen. I got 30 inch screen, but they
force your screen into this 2 inch.
You know, this is like extremely
idiotic. This 2-in screen mouse
properties is from 1990s.
So, you go to pointers, you go to
pointer options,
then you go to uh display pointer
trails. Now, it's better. Okay. Now say
okay.
So now I got kind of pointer tra
trailer. So anyway, block map
close that now. Emerson, did you answer
the question? Very annoying.
Answer the question, my friend, because
I answered your question.
because if you don't answer then I'm
more likely I feel like deleting this
video
and it's not good anyway. So block map
allows you to map with overlap.
So if the last range equals to you know
look at this part. If if this if
statement if the last range
the maximum part of one range is greater
or equals to the minimum of next range
then you return the pair of ranges into
single range.
Okay? Otherwise you return the pair of
ranges.
So that is a problem. So this is where
the ranges start to increase.
That's right. So if let's think about it
A B C
right.
So you want to do extra check if the
range if the two range is equal.
Okay. So, um we made actually we made a
progress
uh fix point. Okay. So, let's
So now the code here is fairly
complicated.
So if
if
Okay. If range one is exactly equals to
range two, then just return
range one. Otherwise
then you do this. Okay, that will fix
it. Okay, so this function um you know
it's getting complicated. So copy that
actually that should work.
Okay, so
so just come down and you'll solve the
problem.
Problem again remains. Why do you have
10 14 10 18?
God,
what's
1018 1020 That should be That should
have been merged.
1014 1018
you know that should have been merged.
Yeah, it did some clean up but it you
know it got 1014 1018. Why is it not
merged?
And you apply fixed point.
So 104 101 18 is the 14 greater than 10?
It is
very annoying.
Okay. Emma Emerson is not answering the
question.
Very annoying
because
you asked me a question.
Do you still live in Mountain View? Kind
of personal question and I answered it,
right? Yes, I still do. So,
as a courtesy, I ask you, why do you ask
that question? you should answer
and you are not answering. So that is
very annoying
for my for me for my personality.
Okay. So
this function so far
is just is it's just not doing the thing
we want,
you know. I don't know.
I get
Let's not do the fancy trick.
You see this knot is not correct.
I just don't understand.
So this is one shot.
Run it. You get that.
Okay. No change.
Copy that. Why? Why is it no change?
Why doesn't it change? Because 10:14
if So we got this if statement here
1014 1018. So why is it doesn't change?
I don't understand. So if this statement
so
108 1020 10 104 1018 18 so it does work
on those pair of ranges 10 18 1020
so but
this function is not actually working I
mean it's not actually reducing
the pair Yeah.
Function at
it.
bucket.
10 14 10 18 10 10 18 10 20.
So Emerson one, who are you?
stupid stupid um
you know YouTube. It used to be you can
check out their YouTube account and
stuff
but um
okay. So it's
remove that. Okay, remove that.
So, let's Add some print statements.
All right.
1018 1020
1018 then 1018 1020 that's correct okay
so it the range pair argument is correct
Now,
now let's print um
35 1014
1014 1018
Right. Okay. So, let's print
the ranges.
So 3 5 10 14. So
range pair
Range pair 35 1014. Range pair 1014
1018.
Why is it uh
the ranges
if Okay. So,
so that actually hold on a second. So
that
if range one and range two is equal then
do that otherwise
otherwise range one and range two are
not equal.
Okay, the ranges
now
overlap
happened.
Okay, shift enter. Range pair 3 5 10 14.
The range is
3, five. Range one and range two. Let's
change the name. Range one, one and two.
Okay. Range pair 3, 5, 10, 14. Range one
and two, 3, 5, 10, 14. Correct. Range
pair. So nothing happens to there. Range
pair 1014 1018.
Range one and two. 104 1018. Correct.
Overlap happened. 1014 1018.
Okay. over overlapped happened.
So overlap happened. You should return
this
first range one, last range two.
Okay, so that means 10 and 18.
Oh, wait. So you got so this you need
the commas I mean you need a semicolon
do again range pair 3 5 10 14 range one
and range two 3 5 10 14 correct range
pair nothing happens to those because
they don't overlap now range pair 104
1018 okay range one and range two 104
1018 correct overlap happened 1014 and
1018 Yes.
Then the result is 10 to 18. Okay. 10.
You know, it didn't print. That's good.
Then overlap happened. That's right.
Then range pair 108 1020.
Range one and two. 108. 1020. Overlap
happened. Yes.
So, so it returns. So overlap happened
is uh 1018 1020
over overlapped happened.
Okay, you see overlap happen 1014 1018
result is 10 and 1018 I mean result is
10 and 18 that's right and here overlap
happen 108 and 20 1020 result is 1020
20.
Okay. So result is 1018 and result is
1020. So that is correct.
Okay. That is correct.
3 5 10 14 10 18 10 20. So this is the
correct.
Then we are applying this function
flatten.
Did this flatten not work
at
last output?
It's correct.
Then
this flatten is correct. That's what we
got.
So originally it was
wait what what is the
1014 1018?
Wait a minute.
You see 35 and 1014
nothing happened.
So they remain
then overlap 1014 1018.
Oh, what the
So when nothing happened, you should
just return.
You see, it didn't change nothing at
all. Even even though our merge does
work the reason is
10 35 1014
return themselves
then 1014 1018 returns 1018.
That's right.
Then 1018 1020
returns 1020. That is right.
So we did merge
but however
1018 1020 become 1020 1014 1018 becomes
1018.
However, when uh 35 104 didn't change.
So, we discovered a fatal
flaw in our algorithm. Actually, a fatal
flaw. That's why it didn't change.
Even though some of them merged but
because you are overlapping your map you
are doing the block map.
So, can you guys see what I mean?
So, you know, so what happens is that
you got this thing
[Music]
So the result even though you did merge
but the result remains the Damn.
Amazing.
Wait. So what? So the result remain the
same. That's because
how does this work out logically?
Be sure to save this. save. Okay.
Let's see. So,
it doesn't change.
How does Wait, how does this work? How
does how do you resolve this this fatal
problem logically?
When you do block map, you are
decreasing by one element. Okay? Because
you are mapping between the neighbors.
But some of the result so that these two
10 14
Okay. So, you don't want to do block.
That's right.
That's right. Don't do block map
because you basically you are repeating.
Yeah. Don't do block map. Just do pairs
reduce every time. Take two parts.
I know what's going on. So, fat fatal
flaw with the blog map.
Then, should we write it down?
Don't overlap him
then repeat.
Okay, that is the problem. So,
so let's uh merge let's clean up the
code. Okay, so uh is this the code the
same?
Let's see.
Okay, I know what to do. Don't Don't use
block map
block map. Don't don't do this overlap.
Okay, that is that's why you got it
wrong.
But what if there is
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 10. So
I know what to do.
That will drop the E, which is not good.
make block code to arguments uh three or
four. Okay. So iff
still no answer
not good.
So, so the problem is if your range list
is odd number of them you cannot use
block map.
So if you arrange this this odd number
of them
you cannot use block map nor can you use
partition.
So we got a new problem.
So we have to use recurs then like nest
or or nest list.
This is interesting.
interesting inputs.
Yes. So you got a list of elements, you
want to merge some of them.
Now you got a new insight. You got a
list of ranges. Basically, you just want
to merge some of them around the
neighbors. Okay.
Um,
block map is a solution, but you run
into this weird situation where
it return itself basically.
So these two returns that these two
returns that
then they become
you see these two
10 10 18 10 20 10 14 10 18 20 10 10 20
What was the original
1014?
108.
So 104 108.
Oh, so you become this.
You got this 1014, 1018, 1020.
Wow.
Interesting.
That's interesting problem.
It returns itself. That is a problem.
Okay. So you need some kind you need a
better solution is like recursive then
Yeah, better solution. So you start to
have some kind of head and tail.
So the check you check the first so a
function that take a list of ranges you
check the first two ranges if they are
they don't overlap
then you return
you need to return kind of a list of two
parts the head and tail.
In the beginning the head is empty list.
It just got the tail. Then each
iteration the function.
So take the function take a list of head
and tail two parts.
If the head is empty then empty
otherwise you I mean each iteration you
take the first two ranges from the tail.
See if they overlap. If they do
merge it,
then put the merged result into the head
into the t into the tail of the head pen
to the head.
That's it. If they do not overlap,
okay, wait, hold on. So, so the function
will take, you know, we can write it
out. So,
Yeah, this this problem is uh
interesting. So you cannot use block. I
mean you can but then you have to like
shift
um you have to check even oddness of
that.
Okay. New Argo,
a function FF
that takes a list of head, part and
tail.
Two things,
head list, tail list.
Okay.
At least
is a list
of ranges
that do not
do not overlap.
Initially it is empty.
Tail list is a list of ranges to be
processed. Okay.
So the function
of this form.
Okay.
The function returns.
A new
by
comparing
The last item in
head list with
the first item
in tail list.
If they
do not overlap,
move
the first item in tail list to
head list.
If they do overlap,
Merge it.
Put result in head list.
Okay, that's a new function.
So this way each time
you will remove one range in the tail
list.
And each time you will grow an item in
the head list until the tail list is
empty.
Okay. So once you do this, you repeat
it.
Okay. I'm tired. I don't want to
implement this. Now it's three hours.
Uh,
okay. I I I think I need to say goodbye.
Now it's 12:20.
So, we've been coding this for 3 hours
and uh got this annoying no answer.
That
ticks me about,
you know, the private privacy issues and
the,
you know, your followers issue like you
don't know who they are.
And uh so this video has now nobody
watching, so I'm going to close it
and I might delete it. Okay, bye guys.