Hello hello hello good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of son talk
show so we start coding emacisp today so
let's
begin emac list audio check video check
okay
so so we're going to code the command
let's see close close go to talk show
talk show today's talk show and go down
there's emac coding Okay. And what are
we going to do today? Uh, audio check,
video check again. So, if you are
watching this live, say hi. Hi, Blue. I
know you. Blue three. And if you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5 speed
and skip around because I ramble. If you
don't play at 1.5 speed and don't skip
around, then it's going to be long and
boring unless you like my to hear my
voice. Okay. So today's talk show we're
gonna start to do live coding. Uh there
are two topics. Okay. Emac list write a
go-to character of current
number under cruiser in the next buffer.
So for example sometimes when you
compile or some sometimes you call some
command it says uh error line
number 195
uh something something. So you need to
jump to line number 195. So usually the
arrow is split. You know you got arrow
here. Can you see? So let's let's stop
that check. Yeah. So you got arrow here
says line number something and your
buffer is here. So you want to go to the
line number in this buffer, you know. So
you can write a command, press a key,
it'll jump to the right position. Okay.
So sometime sometimes it's line number
sometimes sometimes it's character
position. Now that's unique in EMAC
because in EMAC every cruiser is at a
particular position the beginning of the
buffer that's position one. Okay. Now by
the way the cruiser is meant to be
between characters. So
the beginning of buffer that position
before any character that's zero. Then I
mean that's one okay remember what start
with one then this character is uh two
and so on. Okay remember it's cruer
means between characters and the first
one is zero position. Okay so in EMAC
sometimes it'll tell you you know uh
character position it's rare you know
position something something a number
you want to jump to it move cursor to
it. Okay let's write that command then
there's another one let's worry about
that later. Okay, let's do the first
one. The cruel position jump. Uh, so
start a emac this code. Okay, and pop it
out and
defund. Am I doing
good? It's all good. Hot and say hi and
stuff. Okay. So, uh let's
say
kazar jump
uh go to ch uh char
position next buffer. Okay. Something
like that. That's my that's my command
name. Go to child position next buffer.
Let's let that be that. Okay. And uh
then we going to uh
documentation move
um to next buffer. Um so the the current
cursor pos the the number you want to go
to move cursor to the next buffer at
position that is
under cursor. Okay something like that.
This this is not the wording is not so
good because it's hard to understand
ambiguity. So we need to uh refine that
later.
Uh well, another way to say it uh is
um the
number under
[Music]
current
position jump
to it in next buffer. Something like
that. Okay. Something something like
that. The number the number in the
current cursor position jump to it in
next buffer. Okay. uh create date
version let's document date okay let's
begin so the first job the first job is
to grab the number
okay first job grab the number okay so
if we got a number
um
uh uh what okay a number you want to
grab it so
um so let so let's do Let's do this. Let
again let begin end.
Um the number. Yeah, you want grab
number. How do you do that? Uh uh
current word I believe.
Um yeah, let's just let's do it
manually.
Okay.
Uh skip skip
char not shell command skip char
backward. Okay. Skip chart backward.
Skip the character backward. Skip it
around 029. Let's see if that works.
Limit. We don't care. Let's run it.
Okay. Let's say
um Okay, let's say a number. Okay, a
number. We want to move to the beginning
of the number. So, let's try that. So,
the pink window shows all my command
calls. So, let's try that. So run eval
expression eval this expression skip
char backward
09 fantastic it works. So for example
something let's try it again.
Okay. Eval expression meta x code that
command and what expression? This one.
Skip chart backward 09. Does it work?
Yes. Okay.
So, so that and then set x
begin position at point. Point means the
the integer. It returns the integer of
the curs of position. Okay. So, that's
good. Now next we want to do skip char
forward. Go back. Okay. Skip char
forward. Uh 092 and limit. We don't
care. Okay.
Um then uh uh we can test it. Okay. So
let's put the cursor here again. Let's
test it. If our expression this
expression do it. Fantastic. Beautiful.
So set X
end position. Okay. So now we got the
beginning position and end position. Now
you just want to grab it. Okay. So what
you do is uh buff a substring no
properties. Okay. Beginning end. Okay.
And uh uh
number. So that is a number.
Set that to
uh
what to that. Prettify the code.
Fantastic. Beautiful. Okay. Now we got
the beginning position. We got end
position and we got the number we want
to jump to. Then all you have to do is
what is the command? This command next
window or frame. Uh let's go to it.
Uh let's just say other
frame.
Uh jump to
uh Emacs terminology very confusing
window means buffer this this one. Okay
this one let me just try that. Okay so
that means if you have a split buffer
like you can split in many ways that
move to the next pen. Okay, that's what
this other window mean. Move to the next
pen. Next pen, next, next, next, next.
You see? Okay.
So, so you go to the other pen, then you
just go to char and
xnum. Okay. Now, does go does go to char
offer you uh let's look at look up the
documentation. Does it take another
buffer? No, it just g uh takes a
position. Okay, good. Now purify the
code. I think we are
done. Move cursor to the next P buffer
at position that
is that
is at the position that that is under
cursor. Okay, let let's use that that is
more clear. So which one is more clear?
A the phrasing for this documentation or
B is uh the number under current cursor
position jump to it in next buffer.
Okay. So which one is more has more
clarity? Tell
me choker man. Hi. So you know so this
is okay. So let's not worry about that.
Okay. So eval the buffer. Fantastic. Now
we can try it. So let's see. So what is
the current buffer position cer position
of this right now? So let's um so we can
let's say here okay so we call describe
chart it will tell you position two 20
21 28 okay copy
it okay
so new buffer well actually let's leave
it now actually well anyway so 218 and
now let's move the cruiser somewhere
else to the bottom okay so now we want
to call this command okay
So call
uh what what is the name? Go
to chart
position. Go to position next. Okay. Do
it.
Failed integer or marker 218. So, oh you
you forgot to change string to number
because the go to chart requires a
number but your Xnum is a string you see
buff a substring so string to
num okay that eval the buffer split and
go to that okay now if you call it it
will move it to somewhere to here okay
let's
see meta
Go to it. Fantastic and beautiful. Can
you guys see? Fantastic. We've done it.
So, let's move to um position. That's
done, you know. So, it's syntax correct.
So, that is today's fruit. Now, we need
to write another one. Uh go to um line.
Okay. So, but let's rename this go to go
to position. Um wait it needs to be
um let's say go to char next buffer.
Okay that that is more in sync with how
emacs name it because in EMAC you have
the go to char command. It doesn't say
go to position but it says go to char.
So so this will be go to char next
buffer.
Okay fantastic and beautiful.
Now put it
back. Cut. Paste. Paste. Syntax. Curve
the hole. And now pop out. Pop out this
one. Now this one is go to line number.
Next buffer. Okay. Move cursor to next
buffer that at at position
at at line number that is under cursor.
Okay. Let's just just use
that.
Okay. Okay. Fantastic. We just modify
this. Um so what to do? So you need to
grab the number like before we have it.
Then you grab the number. Yes. Then you
go to line. So instead of go to chart,
go to
line. Describe function. Go to line. Do
we have it? Yes. It's defined in this
simple uh emac this
simple. Go to line go to line counting
from line one at beginning of a buffer.
Okay. Uh if called interactively
whatever okay so what uh so line number
buffer or it takes a buffer in this case
in relative. Okay. So okay so we copy
it. Go to line that's what we want.
Close it. go to line
that that's
it that is it okay now eval the
buffer so now Emacs also know this
command now let's find the line okay so
let's find the line what what is this
line number does it say
um so search for
line okay you see Emacs usually doesn't
tell you line numbers uh Emacs is like
character oriented. It doesn't go by
line. In most other editors, they go by
line, a line number then column number.
But Emacs is like uh that is not the
native
behavior. The native behavior is by
characters position. Okay. So uh so what
so this uh go to line
so that will work. Yes. So what what um
what what else we need to think about
other window then go to line I think
that's it oh you need to determine what
line is this okay this is line five okay
so let's
say the buffer let's switch to empty
let's say line five okay
now
call go to line number next buffer do it
fantastic Fantastic. Let's try it
again. Do it. Fantastic. Now, let's move
it to the
top. Fantastic. It always move here. You
see? Fantastic. And
beautiful. Now, put it back. Color the
buffer. Show in browser. Fantastic. Task
complete. Okay. So, am I doing good?
Thank you guys. Pay me. Okay, go to
sulli.info and
pay. Technically, we are done now. We
can continue to do the next one or we
can leave that
tomorrow. Uh, so it's only 15 minutes, I
think. Let's leave it tomorrow. Okay,
shall we? Fantastic. Thank
you. This is jaw
hat setting skater 3 server majong way
peanut. What the
That's um that's a name uh
scam. Uh let me show you about that one.
Okay. Name scam. So you go to Kasali
info. Kasali info. And uh go to the
homepage. Go down.
and go all the way down. Here is how you
pay me. Patreon, Amazon, gift card,
PayPal. Okay, copy my email address and
paste it. Then you can send me money.
Okay, but now we need to go to scams and
uh spam and CEO, SEO, those
scams and uh we got a name scam. So they
are dated. So this is my documentation
of the web spam, scam and SEO. SEO is
actually part of the scam and spam
created by
Google. Okay. So you know so over the
years every year or two there is a
different fashion and trend different
techniques of spam spam or scam. Okay.
So in year 2000 year 11 actually it goes
back to year 1990s but I only started to
write about it. So the first one 2011
translation SEO
scam. Okay. What they will do is that
they will send you email you know
politely request to translate one of
your pages in different language you
know in to for example English right? I
write English. So they will say oh uh we
are in Russia or we are in uh India or
not India but Russia or you know some
other country you know uh we need can
can we please translate your uh article
into our language uh I'm asking for
permission you know
but but
[Music]
actually so their website is actually
just a spam spam website like lots of
random ads. Okay. So they want your
article which is suppose you know they
pick a article you wrote very popular
they want a copy of it in their website
translated in other langu language but
their website you look at it it's like
full of like ads and gambling ads casino
ads or whatever whatever you know or
male brides you know so that's a
translation SEO scam you know they nice
they have people nice and gently write
you email asking for your permission for
this translation. They they never
mention, oh by the way, we got 1,000 ads
on our website. You know that's so lots
of techniques. So this is 2011. Now let
me mention this particular one setting
skater three something uh something.
Okay. So that would
be 2012 2014 five five spam 2014 that
still happens today you know today we
got thbot likes spam like on
Twitter the minute the the second you
post within a second you got people
thoughts you know girls like you know
girls thought bots they like your post
the like within a second happens often.
So five f favorite span. Okay. So
anyway, so there's a lot a lot of it.
Okay. Different
techniques. But then uh yeah, so here we
were talking about the inst insta bbots
scam. So you can see some of them insta
thoughtbot like the the moment like
within a second you post you got all
these girls who likes your post.
you know. So here's some examples. Okay.
My documentation of
society. Uh now, so now this is uh we
are looking for uh there YouTube spam
comments of random person names. Okay.
So this happened in
2024 beginning September. Precisely
beginning September. Okay. So when you
um you know on YouTube they you you got
lots of these comments like every day
you got tens 10 10 or something you know
like I have documentation of it and what
they post is just random people names
like this one Lori Cape then Wolf Me and
this one Dorothy Rich this one Emily
Drive this one Thompson Richard Garcia
Paul Martin Donald you know this one uh
This one, same guy. So he posted
several, you know, like this continue.
This lasted for like
um for a month. Okay, you just got this
random accounts posting just
names, you know, this go on and on to
your YouTube video. Okay, so these
are I just want to mention my uh
documentation of the spams and scams.
No, but we got this guy setting scatter
three server majong ways pean simul
don't know what that is. Okay, that's it
for today. Bye,
guys. So, we wrote this. Fantastic. The
other one we'll do next day. Okay, we
wrote this uh which is pretty good.
uh I actually I should show a example
where okay let's show example actually
where the actual error happens okay so
let's go to unic code uh let's go to my
webdev web my webdev page so let's go to
hsl color so you got JavaScript that
generates the syntax for the hue
saturation lightness color syntax for
CSS. You see, you can generate random
colors and then you can just copy it.
Okay. So, this page has a JavaScript.
Search for JS. There it is. Open it. Uh,
warning, there's a TypeScript exist. I'm
opening TypeScript instead. Indeed, this
is TypeScript. Okay. So, you look at you
see this this TypeScript. This is
JavaScript. The JavaScript is
automatically generated. Let's delete
it. So now it's good. Now it's just
TypeScript. Open it. So now let's press
a key to compile
it. Command successful. Okay. So now go
back to the directory.
Refresh. Uh refresh. You can see the
JavaScript version is generated. Okay.
Now go to TypeScript again. Now let's
now this time let's make an error
somewhere. Okay.
ttt let's see now
compile cannot find name ttt error
okay so there it is okay so uh let's see
um that arrow is too simple but it work
but so let's move here so you know
suppose your cursor is somewhere you
know so you you got this error so you
jump to the error line then you call
line number next buffer go to line
number okay do it
fantastic works okay so now remove that
compile it now it's
good shell command successful okay bye