Hello guys. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of Kasan Talk Show. You
are watching Kan Talk Show. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed. If
you are watching live, say hi. Love to
see your comments. We are going to
demonstrate this Pascal's theorem. Can
you see that? Beautiful. Amazing. Okay,
let me adjust my let me turn on my head
shot.
There it is. Hello. Uh so Pascal's
theorem
mathematics that's part of projective
geometry.
projective geometry and uh then so so uh
yeah I'm going to explain that then we
going to uh use AI you know what you are
seeing here is artificial intelligence
quot generated code so you see it's 3D
graphics it's quite amazing
so let me uh so uh let's let's start
okay so let's see let me let Let me get
my window set up. Uh,
so Emacs. Uh, so the pink window shows
all my command course and keystrokes.
Command course on the right, keystroke
on the left. Okay. So let me adjust it
and we got a narrow. Okay. So,
so Pascal's theorem, let me explain what
it is. Okay. So first of all uh so by
the way there is a Wikipedia article you
can read it but I'm not going to
interactively guide guide you through
okay uh then so let me show you Pascal's
theorem here
okay it's loading the page this
application is called G algebra so so
what happens is that Pascal theorem okay
let's see if I can magnify this yes I
can uh yeah okay so Pascal steering. So,
Pascal uh so let me adjust let me tell
you guys what this is in a moment. Okay.
Uh
wait, how how can I adjust the uh
conics? Okay. So, it needs to be
let's say
here,
here, right? Let's say
here. Okay. Let's say we start with a
circle. Okay. So, hold on a second.
So, let's say we start a circle.
Okay. Close enough. So, Pascal theorem
is that you draw you have a circle then
you draw six points on the circle. So,
where's point? So let's say so that's
one of the point 0 point 0 point 0.1 and
uh let's say point 2 here.
Okay wait let me adjust it. So 0.1 here
2 then 3 can you see that? Yes. Three
then 0 4
let's point let's put 0 four here and 0
five here and 6. So draw a circle first.
Then draw six more points. Okay? Like 1
2 3 4 5 six on the circle. Then then
what you do is you connect the lines
uh between these points in any order. So
right now we have 0.1 connected to point
2. You draw a line through it. Point 2
connected to 3. Draw a line through it.
The point can be anywhere on a circle.
Okay. Then 3 to point 4 you draw a line
to it. Then point 4 to 0.5 you draw a
line between them. Then 0.5 to 6 you
draw a line between them there. And 6 to
0.1 you draw a line again. So you draw a
line connecting each uh points. Now
one one of the uh one one of the you
know the the points can be drawn can be
connected in any order. So so for
example let's uh let's uh move about
this point order. So for example
so four five six you know they can be
any order. Okay. So right now I have 1 2
1 2 3 4 5 6. Okay, you know they can be
any order.
So you once you draw these lines
connecting through the points in any
order then what the Pascal theorem says
is that uh
let me let me adjust this a little bit
so it's actually easier to see the
theorem. So one two let's move the
second point here.
Let's move it. Let's see. One, two,
three.
Okay, let's just leave it like that. So,
we have now one, two, three,
four, five, six, and back to one. Okay,
six points. Draw a line uh through them
in any order. Now, what the Pascal
theorem says that the opposite
the opposite lines if you connect the um
the opposite lines will meet in a point.
So you have six points and you draw
lines between them. So you have six
lines and by opposite lines means you
know if your point you know like how do
I explain? So 1 2 3 4 5 six right? So
one two the opposite of one two the
opposite side of one two would be let's
say one
2 3 4 5 6 let's say you have a hexagon
so hexagon so one two the opposite would
be 1 2 3 4 5 would be four five so one
two
the opposite side of of the line one two
is four five the opposite line of 2
three
uh is
five and one you know so so each line
has the opposite line so what it is
saying is that you connect the opposite
lines the opposite lines will meet at a
point so let's say let's see the point
one here so point two here so we got one
two so the opposite uh side of the line
one two would be
four, five. Okay. So where is that four
and five? Four and five. These two blue.
Okay. They are like color in blue. So it
says they will meet in a point. That is
true. Then again if you you if you take
the opposite side of the two other then
that's the two red lines they they meet
in a point B here you can see B. Then
the green lines are the two opposite
sides. They meet at a point what? So,
Pascal theorem says all these
uh intersections will lie in a line. Can
you see? So, this dashed black black
line is a line that all these
intersections lie on, they will always
be on a line. So, doesn't matter where
where you begin the six points on the
cornic. So, let me try it again. Okay,
let's make it
let's see if we can try to make it more
um easy to understand. So let's try
again one.1
then three let's move there then
4.5
6. So now it's easier to see. Now it's a
kind of standard hexagon. One, two,
three, four, five, six. Now you can
easily see the opposite side. You see
you draw six points on a circle. Then
you connect, you know, uh the points in
any order. Okay? Then you then pascal
then then the opposite sides will meet
at a point. For example, this red and
this red line, they will meet at a point
far away. And these two green will meet
a point at a point. And these two blue
uh will meet a point these two blue
lines. But the Pascal theorem says that
all these intersections will actually
lie on the line. So right now you cannot
see it because they become far away.
Uh but if you like move the name closer
you can see you can see that black line.
So so this is Pascal steering. Okay. Now
remember you can connect the points in
any order. So as you drag so you can see
as I drag them you know they can be in
any order.
Uh so that's amazing. Pascal
discovered this when he was 16 and uh uh
so this is in year uh 1600s something
like that. Okay let's check Wikip
Wikipedia. Uh Bla uh Blae Pascal that's
a guy. Okay. In projective geometry,
Pascal theorem, also known as hexog
mysticism, mysticum theorem, Latin for
mystical hexog,
states that if six arbitrary points are
chosen on a conic,
I'll get to that later. Conic is a conic
section. So it can be a circle, it can
be a parabola, it can be a hypo
hyperola. So not just circle but we are
doing it on a circle for now but but you
can see we can change this this um conic
section to any of hyperola you see now
it becomes a hyperola you see and uh
hyperola and it's still true you know
any of these six points their opposite
side meets in at uh lies on a line but
you see, but it's hard to um
make them visually clear. So you can see
let's move the point number five.
You see? So right now this is a
hyperola. You can see so.1 is here
0.1
uh 2
is here
3 is here 4 is here and 0.5 is here and
6 is here. So this is true on a circle
on a hyperola on a elisp on a parabola.
Okay. So it says you know in projective
geometry Pascal theorem states that if
six arbitrary points are chosen on a
conic
and joined by line segments in any order
to form a hexagon. Then the three pairs
of opposite sides of the hexagon
meet at three points which lie on a
straight line. Okay. So and that line is
called Pascal line of the hexagon. Okay.
So you this dashed line is a Pascal
line. You can see
uh you see they you know there's three
points on it. A B C.
So let's So this works in any uh you
know any conic section. So let's change
this conic section back to a elisp
because when it's elisp it's easier to
see. So you see we can change it back to
a elisp.
Amazing. Is that amazing?
Hi Diego.
So that's Pascal's theorem. Okay. So uh
let's see what else what else I want to
do. And uh I mean so that's Pascal
theorem. You can read uh read Wikipedia
in detail. They also have a proof and uh
you know they have a proof here. And it
turns out this Pascal's theorem is
actually a special case a special case
of the um you know I just learned it
learned this special case of the Kaye
Bakarach
Bakar theorem.
uh this is very advanced
uh algebraic geometry you know
projective geometry and algebraic
geometry so I do not quite understand so
very advanced okay um so anyway but
Pascal's theorem itself is part of
projective projective geometry um you
know but it is a special case of the
other of this uh kay bakar rock theory
Anyway,
so Pascal Pascal discovered this when he
was 16 years old. Uh Pascal is is a guy.
So this is in 16
uh 1600s. Pascal is a guy is a he's a
genius, you know, and he is very much
into uh God. He's a believer in God.
uh but anyway he's one of the great uh
you know mathematician in history and uh
and uh he is um what is uh French he's
French n nationality
and he you know he's also known for
Pascal's triangle you must have heard
you know he's known for quite a quite
several things you know among men is
Pascal's wager that's very interesting
let me talk about that and he's also
known as Pascal's triangle. Pascal
triangle you must have heard or seen is
like that you know you you write 111 you
add the number together and there are
many properties about it. Okay, that's
Pascal's uh triangle which turns out is
known uh in China uh
very early like 1300s or even earlier.
Okay. So anyway, Pascal's triangle. So
Pascal very interesting guy. Now
Pascal's wager is is that you know
whether you should should you believe in
God you know should you or should you
not. So Pascal's wager is that says that
you should because it benefits you more
because if it if God exist
and you believe in God that's good you
know God will protect you you know you
you will go to heaven.
Um
but if God exist and you do not believe
in God then you would be in trouble. you
know, you're gonna be put to hell. You
know, you're going to be trouble.
Now, if God does not exist, then it
doesn't matter you believe it or not.
So, therefore, overall, it is
beneficial. It's it's, you know,
beneficial to you. It's optimal if you
actually believe in God because if you
don't believe it, nothing happens. But
if you believe I mean, if God exist,
then what you whether you believe or not
really matters. But if God does not
exist, exist it, you know, doesn't
matter either way. So overall, you have
four possibilities.
God exist, you believe it. God exist,
you do not believe it. God do not exist,
you believe God, God exist. And God do
not exist. And you uh do not believe God
doesn't ex uh does exist. So anyway, so
so you know this is called Pascal's
wager. Okay.
Okay. So what else? So let's you know
that's the Pascal guy. Very interesting.
Now let's talk about so Pascal theorem.
Uh and this what you have seen here this
application I wrote like 20 30 years
ago. I mean I created this uh this
demonstration but this application I
didn't write it. That application is
called G algebra. Okay. Let me show you.
So if you are into mathematics highly
recommend it Gbra application. Okay. Uh
so here is another Gbra application.
Uh so I have like about 30 40 g algebra
applications. So you can find them on my
website. Just search for visual
dictionary of special plane curves on
si.info.
Okay. Visual dictionary of of special
plane curves and and go all the way to
the bottom. You'll see a link to all the
gebra
uh files. So any one of these is very
interesting. Uh so let me show you one
of them.
So this this shows the uh rolling
circles. Okay. So you can you can see
you roll a circle. So if if you roll a
circle around another circle of the same
size then you will trace out this this
blue curve you know this black points.
Okay. So that that curve is called
cardioid cardioid. And you'll see that
when you have a coffee cup under the
sun, you'll see this kind of shape, you
know. So that's a optical property. And
also you see if you roll a circle
twice as large as a fixed circle, you
also trace out a cardio. So you can see
there are three circles here. Okay. Uh
so there are three circles. One is in
the middle a fixed circle. The other one
is a circle of the same size rolling
around it. You know, let's say uh you
see now there's another circle you see
that is twice as large.
So this circle also rose on the fixed
circle but it rose like the uh the
inside of it rose on the fixed circle.
So it's u do you understand? Can you
see? So now focus on this large circle.
Okay, focus on this large circle and and
see how how it rolls. Let me show let me
do it. Uh yeah, you got to drag that. So
you see you see and it turns out these
two rolling circles can be uh
are related together by this hex uh by
this uh parallelogram.
So there's a mechanism that link these
two rolling circles of different size
together and both of them trace out this
card cardioid curve. You see?
So that's uh fascinating.
Now this this the math I'm showing here
these are discovered like um around
1500s to 1800s. That's the era uh of
this very simple plain geometry
mathematics. Okay, you don't even need
calculus but you need a lot of geometry
to uh learn them. So the the optical
property I was talking about this. So
there are also other mathematicians
showing you about it. This one is on
YouTube.
Am I doing good? Are you guys listening?
I believe so. Who who is watching? How
many people? Six. Okay. So this is a
mathematician math methodologer. Uh he
talks about mandro broad mandro broad.
So why does mander broad set
times table?
>> Uh let me you know he talks about why is
the mander broad set looks very similar
to the cardioid curve that
that we are talking about. You see it's
quite amazing because the cardioid curve
is simply rolling a circle on another
now but the mander broad set the mander
broad set is very complicated thing you
know I can mand you know manderro set is
like um it's a you know you
you recursively apply a function to
itself you know like you have a function
you plug in a
comes out a number. Then you put the
number back into the function comes out
the number. You repeat you repeat this
process
to see if to see if the result gets
larger or larger forever.
Now if it does get larger and larger
forever then we say that point is
outside of this manderboard set. The
manderboard set is actually a set. So
you can see the black colored you know
the black parts are inside the set the
you know the rest of it is outside of
the set. So the black are inside. Okay.
So you begin with any point in the
plane. So it it takes a you know complex
number or or just or just think of x and
y two two numbers making one complex
number. Okay. So the function takes one
complex number. In other words, it takes
one
point, okay, X and Y.
So you feed those two numbers into the
function and we are output another pair
of numbers and the pair of numbers has a
distance. So you then you you take that
output, put it back into the function,
repeat to see if that distance gets
further further away, larger and larger.
If so then that pony is outside of the
man manderboard set. Okay. If the point
doesn't get larger but you can show that
it for forever stays you know never gets
extremely large then that point that you
begin with is inside the manderboard
manderboard set. So that's all the black
areas. So but it's you see but but then
what happens to around the edges that's
a very that's a ve very deep interesting
part you see. So the mander broad set is
amazing because it is um
you know you have to iterate basically
almost to infinitive for each point to
find out whether they are inside or not.
But anyway, but overall it takes it has
this shape and this shape looks like
looks like a you know rolling circle on
another. So this guy is trying is
explaining why it it is like that. Okay,
this is a 2015 video I watched long ago.
So anyway, back to cardio. So I was
saying so this um so you go to G algebra
you know G Algebra is a great
application uh you should uh
try it you know it's uh it's it's online
it was open source but they made it not
open source anymore
so anyway the now about another thing
about uh Pascal's theorem you see it
works in uh on any conics Now, so G
algebra can can draw any coin by giving
uh by a given five points. Okay, a conic
section is defined by five points. So
you can see one there,
two here,
third point there.
Uh one, two, three, uh one, two,
three of four. Fourth point is here and
five. So given five points on the plane,
it defines
exactly one conic section. So if if I
change this point you can see the conic
section changes. You can see I can turn
it into a parabola. This that's a
parabola.
Then back to hyperola. You see hyperola
hyperola hyper hyperola hyperola
hyperola. Then this is two
uh intersecting lines. That's a
degenerate degenerate case of hyperola.
So you can see so now it become back to
a so it's quite amazing
five points defines a coniconic section
okay so this is besides this is another
theorem besides the uh besides the
Pascal's theorem now another thing about
this another thing about this is so
Pascal theorem you can prove it you can
prove it by uh by by proving it on a
circle. So prove it. It is true on a
circle. You know, you can read the proof
on Wikipedia. But once you prove it on a
circle, the rest is easy because
because of projection. Okay? Because of
u let's see, let's go back. Because
projection. Now, how does that work?
Well, projection is because um
okay, projection that's that's because
uh Pascal theorem. Okay, so let's open a
new page. Uh because conic sections
elisp, hyperola, parabola, they are all
just shadow of a ball. So like that. So
you can do this at home. Take out a lamp
and put a ball on a table. If the if the
lamp or lights a candle you know you can
use a candle. So if the candle is below
the ball then the shadow is a hyperola.
Okay. If the candle is above the ball
above the top of the ball then the
shadow is ellipse.
you know this
if the candle is right at the same level
as the top of the ball then the shadow
is a parabola. Okay. So
you know it's just basically projection.
So,
so,
so projection then another thing you
know about lines is that
two lines if two lines intersect doesn't
m so doesn't matter then
so given a plain figure if two lines
intersect then you
okay let's let's get fancy okay
so let's say this paper is a plane let's
say I draw two line two lines on it okay
I draw two lines now what does
projection mean so projection let's say
so here's my desk right so let's say uh
my there's a lamp here the sunlight is
here so the sun so that this paper is
between the sunlight and my desk right
so whatever I draw on the paper the
sunlight will cast a shadow on the desk,
right? So if you have a line on the
paper, it will still become a line on
the desk, right? So this this this
process is called projection. You know,
you project
by straight lines. You project from one
plane to another plane. Okay? So this
paper is a plane and my desk is a plane.
So whatever I draw on the paper via a
light source, a a candle, it will be
projected whatever figure on the paper
to my desk. So the new shape on my desk
is called the projection of this of this
set on this paper, you know. So so but
we know intuitively line will become a
line. What if you have a circle? a
circle will become a ellisp just like
this. Um you know a circle will become a
ellisp.
Now if you if if I have a circle but I I
I I turn the paper around so it's like
angled very uh almost like passing the
passing the light source then you will
get a very sharp uh like very sharp
elis. So I mean very flat
you know something like very flat like
like you know like that you know you so
this anyway so this is called
projection. So you project from one
plane to another plane. Okay.
So you know line become lines and uh if
two lines intersect they will also
intersect or if or they will become if
two lines are parallel they will also
intersect
but the intersection may be very very
far away. Okay that's kind of let's say
let's look at the green uh can you see
green? Yeah, you know, let's let's say
okay, let's let's look at the um
let's look at the blue lines. Okay, so
there's one blue line there and one blue
line there. Okay, so you can see they
intersect in one point. Now if I move
these two here, they still intersect,
you know, here and there. But I move
these two there. So they become almost
parallel. You see their intersection
gets far away. You see the point here A
that's the intersection. But if I make
these two blue lines parallel
they you you can kind of think that they
intersect in a in a infinitely far away
point.
If I move the blue line back you know
then the intersection come back from to
the other side. You see this point. So
how can I make it clear? So do you see
what I'm saying? So watch the
intersection. Okay, watch the two blue
lines and this intersection. So I move
this point to make these two blue lines
parallel. So the intersection gets far
further away. Then the two intersections
the intersection come back from the
other side. Okay? And I can keep going.
Keep going. Uh keep going. Can you see?
So anyway, that's a that's projection.
So
So if two lines intersect and when you
projected, they will still intersect
except maybe at infinitely far away.
Okay. So that's a property of uh
projection.
And so back to the conic section. So, so
once you prove the Pascal's theorem for
a circle, you can kind of, you know,
it's fairly intuitive to see that it
also works on on on
any kind of elp and will also work on uh
hyperola because why? Because
remember because the hyperola is just um
where is my page? Remember the hyperola
is just a projection of a circle. You
see?
So anyway, that's about Pascal's
theorem. Now let me show you uh amazing
AI. Okay, are you guys still here?
Pravin hey I'm thinking about building
website uh
building website org docs using org docs
uh you can
so it's amazing that you can ask AI to
generate you see this amazing 3D uh
visualization application you know all
you have to say is I uh so I asked so
George did this okay so you know George
uh it uh a friend he just asked you know
using only HTML and JavaScript create a
visualization that helps me understand
Pascal's theorem the page should have an
overthe-top Barbie girl aesthetics use
3D animations you know so
can we magnify this uh control
plus control plus control plus.
Okay. But the panel gets too big. Uh
then you know the the Germany AI
generate the code. So let me show you
the code. So the code is actually here.
So I I've been looking at the code and I
fixed um I made the background black.
Then you can see you know it's amazing,
you know, you can see all the stars. But
however there's a issue. You see they
generated the all this the hexagon but
it didn't generate the Pascal line. I
suppose you see these two yellow moving
dots that's a line you know there
supposed to be a line between them that
shows the Pascal line but but this is
you know just this is just tremendously
amazing. I don't know how to write this
because you know so let let's let's show
the code. Okay, Pascal. Uh yeah, so I
kind of cleaned up a little bit. So
let's see. Uh that's today's page. So
so you can see uh so that's uh where's
the page? It generates the entire HTML
and everything. Okay. So
there here. So here's the source code.
This is a HTML file I cleaned up
originally. Let's see this is original
file. So original file it's just one
single file. So this file in this single
file you got JavaScript here. This one
this part is loading the three.js
library which is a 3D library uh doing
uh uh WebGL.
Yeah, WebGL for 3D graphics. Okay. Using
the GPU. So 3D, you know, if you open
it, it's, you know, it's minified. It's
so you can you can read it. So it's it's
using the 3D uh 3.js library and it's
also using this uh control file. Okay.
This based on uh you know like for the
for the sliders and whatnot. I suppose
then it is using uh yeah so the control
file control obit control.js JS then
it's using Google Google font. That's
how you get this uh Barbie look. So
where is it?
You see this Barbie look like Can you
actually see it?
Uh
can you actually see it? Uh,
you know, I want to know where did that
go to? Uh,
I don't want that. So,
what
anyway? So
yeah. So, so it's using the Google font.
It's actually using two fonts. One for
the title Pascal, you know, like Barbie
styled title.
Then, okay, that's the font, Google
font. Then here is the stylesheet.
Uh, here is a stylesheet, not too long.
Then, then here is the the text box.
this description.
Then here is a JavaScript, you know, so
JavaScript. So let's go to my version.
So because I cleaned it up a little bit.
So here's HTML. So it's all cleaned up.
So you got the three uh 3.js uh
JavaScript file which is I downloaded.
So now it's local.
Uh then you got the control JavaScript
file that's this file
uh unlike track ball control it
maintains the up direction object. So
this is for uh rotating the page I
suppose. So where is our page? So let's
go to the Barbie page.
Yeah. So you can see you can rotate it.
Amazing. I mean, I'm truly quite
impressed. I don't understand the code.
Okay. So, so you got the control file. I
mean, the mouse control, I suppose. Then
you got the font. I disabled because you
don't need font. Uh, Barbie font. So,
without Barbie font, if I showing this
in browser, it looks still pretty good.
So, and here is a CSS file. Not too not
too long. CSS file is mostly just for
the for this information box. Okay. But
then the JavaScript code. Okay. So you
know here's a description then the
JavaScript code there. So so this code
is generated by AI. Okay. I haven't
actually start to read it yet. So this
code is generated by AI
and it's using the 3.j JS which I don't
uh have experience. So
you know so it's quite amazing. So I you
know
let's see let let's see if we can
understand uh like how much can we
understand. So only 250 lines. Okay. So
let's see scene let scene camera render
renderer controls. So those are
variables. Then points is uh constant.
So let points array lines is a object
intersection points. Okay. Let's
highlight some of them.
Okay.
So you can see points lines intersection
points. No. Okay. So wait.
Okay.
You see, one of the problem with the app
is that it's not showing the line that
connect the Pascal lines. Okay. So,
so let me let me let me do it again.
Okay. Um,
you see it's not showing this line
containing the three intersection
points.
But I think it's there. It's just not
visible for some reason like we need to
change color or something because
apparently you know there there it is
intersection points now. No here create
Pascal lines.
So is there somewhere that specify a
color that's wrong? Maybe this.
Okay. So So we need a color. Um okay.
Let's let's try to change the color
backup. Go to CSS, show my CSS page, and
the color syntax.
Uh, let's try green. Okay, so let's try
line
coet.
So, cut, paste.
Uh, wait, cut, paste, and uh, okay. So I
suppose that that
Okay, now we have a new code. Let's see.
Refresh.
Okay, it's not showing Pascal lines.
Okay, that's
where's the color used did somewhere.
Okay, so here are stars. the stars
behind him. Amazing. 3D stars.
Wow. It's truly amazing.
Update points. So, let's see the past.
Create sparkles. Wow.
Create sparkles. Okay.
Now I want to get the Pascal lines to
work. Okay. So where is the
so so where so this function create
Pascal lines where is it used? So it's
used here. Okay. Now let's highlight it.
Okay, that's uh kind of pink.
So
create Pascal lines. What does it do?
Okay, material.
Okay, so you got this material.
Color
color. Why is it not showing though?
Uh scale line width line width let's say
10. Let's just say refresh.
No, it's not showing.
But I'm I love it. I love this so much.
So scale line width 10
undo dash size.
Oh, so it's also using dash
uh could it be
gap size dash size? Could that be no
problem
geometry
anyway? So you know if I were to write
this you know I don't know this library
you know I don't know this three
three.js JS library. But even if I know
that library, how do I how how would I
for example in Wufam language I can do
3D uh programming, 3D geometry. How
would I
you know create this uh animation?
It would it would not be very trivial.
It would take me a day or two.
So anyway, I think that's it for today.
you know we we didn't get to fix the
Pascal you know to show the line
and another you see another thing
fantastic if if we are able to you know
drag the point just like the
two-dimensional version
like can we show the two-dimensional
version you know if we were able to
change the point order then that would
be amazing and then if we can change you
know the the actual hyperola, you know,
from from EVISP to hyper hyperola and
stuff
that would be amazing in 3D. Okay. In um
let's go back to browser.
Okay, I think that's it for today.
Anything else?
Bye, guys.
So, that's 40. That's 50 minutes. Uh
yeah. So amazing you know. So this is
just asking u um AI bot for a single
question. You know it generates a code.
Me been doing 3D programming for like 20
30 years. You know uh
I'm not sure I can generate I can create
this in woof language in one hour. Um
yeah and uh yeah so it's it's quite
amazing. So let's close that. Close
that. Let's let's wrap up. Okay. So
here's today's talk show and there's
another one someone else did visualizing
uh formula. I haven't had time to look
into, you know, just the Barbie one took
me, you know, a while to look into.
And we, you know, I'm not successful.
But let's try to ask um Gro. Let's see
what GU returns. Okay, that would be
interesting.
So, let's go to Gro.
Okay, let's do GU.
Ask exactly the same question using only
HTML. Let's magnify
using only HTML and JavaScript. Okay.
Um, enter.
Okay. To create a visual uh
representation of Pascal theorem with
Barbie girl aesthetics using HTML,
JavaScript, and 3D animations, we'll use
3.js for 3D rendering. Pascal theorem
states that for a conic section, a
circle or elisp, if six points from a
hexagon inscribed on a conic, the three
intersection points of the opposite
sides are collinear. The page will
feature a 3D visualization of a conic
section and with six dragable points.
Oh, that's extra. forming a hexagon
lines connecting opposite side. Okay,
let's see.
Let's see. Oh, Grog. So, it finished.
Let's do it. Okay, let's try the Grog.
Let's how to use
this. You know, I kind of I guess I know
how to use Let's just copy it.
Copy it. New page. Paste it. Save it.
XX. H uh HTML for now. Wait, that exist
uh x barbie.html
for now. Okay. And uh yeah, so let's now
before I show in browser, let's check if
there's any like risky code like phone
home. Usually I double check because I
don't want it to contact whatever. So
this is the 3.js JS and here's it's
using the same controls file. Okay. Then
then here is a JavaScript. Here is a
JavaScript. Okay. Blah blah blah. And
that's it. What what about CSS? Wait,
where where is his CSS?
Search for CSS. Oh, wait. Search for
style. Oh, here. That's a style. Okay.
Showing browser.
[Laughter]
Is it 3D? Yes. Oh my god. Now, can you
drag the point? Yes, you can. Wait,
what?
What? How do I
track? Oh, okay. But it's incorrect
though. It's only one. Wow. Okay. So
when you move your mouse the whole thing
So when you move your mouse it rotates
the thing. Okay. Now okay but this is
not you know
so now if you stop and now you you can
how do I drag that? So you can change
the point.
Okay.
I'm not still I'm still not clear what
exactly are the controls but
but anyway so there it is. Drag the pink
points to move them on the elisp. Watch
the intersection points form a straight
line. Okay.
Okay. It's done. But it's still not very
good. You can see. But now can we
can we change the conics to a hyperola?
No. Okay. Well, anyway,
bye guys. Now, if you like my stuff,
support me. Okay. So, you know, go
to.info.info.
Uh
kasari.info. Click on click on that.
Click on that. Click on that homepage.
Go to homepage button and go to the
bottom. Pay me PayPal, Patreon, Amazon
gift card. Okay? If you have a job, pay
me a 100. Thank you very much.
Bye, guys.