hello good morning welcome to another
episode of kar talk show today we are
going to code emac lisp we're going to
code several emac lisp commands for your
emac fans uh and here's my keyboard
glove 80
fantastic I have reviews on my website
and YouTube live uh video reviews gl8
ultimate hacking keyboard ultimate
fantastic newly track ball fantastic
actually I've been thinking maybe asking
the game ball guys to give me one so I
can help them sell and I would love it
and this is uh Logitech you know very
common Gamers for the gamers you know
they got sping wheel fantastic and this
been delayed and delayed this is the
most
fancy input device a keyboard this is
called swab board s v a l b o a r d swab
board data hand if you search it you'll
find it of course then there's a left
hand side and we'll be using it but not
yet so much delay so I'm going
to uh sorry about that so I you know I
promote them for each of my live stream
until one day I'm using
it and I'll let you guys how it goes uh
okay so let's begin today's main topic
which is uh Emax lisp coding one of my
one of my mainstream topic if you are
here say hi uh if you are not
here feel free to skip around because I
talk randomish nonstop okay today's
topic today's topic is goingon to we're
going to do write a few emx command one
of them is tarle theme toggle do theme
for example
if I do it manually that would be load
theme meta X load theme okay then you
pick a theme now my favorite
is uh deep blue for at night so deep
blue so there it is can you see it
yes CH thank you
crystals is Lyon Superior to wolam
language Lyon are you
kidding Lyon SC language it's the worst
programming language ever possible worse
even than Pearl
okay worse than bash worse than pear
Pearl worse than the worst [ __ ] that's
the Lindon scripting language that's
that's what you're talking about right
I'll talk you I'll talk about that uh
after let's do iMac this first because
Lindam scripting language that's the
scripting language for second life of
lindom Labs second life is the virtual
reality I lived in it for like four
years every day like eight hours a day
uh quite interesting I talked about that
many times and they got the Lindon
scripting language which is very
different in nature from other the
programming languages because it's
virtual you know you you you program in
a virtual world any
anyway but that's a worst
language Okay so today we're going to uh
so doc theme we're going to write toggle
Dark theme okay so to disable it you
call uh dis theme okay then then this
boid okay so now you got the white
background okay so okay let's set uh
background set background color which is
my usual color which color honey
Drew okay honey honey dew
uh which which one is
it honey de yeah okay this is my normal
this is normal my normal uh theme no
theme just background color so we're
going to write that then we're going to
write a from evur line I'm going to show
you that's for wolam language I'm going
to enhance that command then we're going
to write AA print list Anda print hash
that's emac list so when you have a list
usually it prints in one line so it's
hard to read but instead you want one
item per line so we going to write
that okay so hello Dan from Spain
fantastic Spain from
Europe uh bro hi I love your streams
especially the math content I think
that's the let's see math content thank
you okay yeah it's way to hear you guys
you know what you guys like to see my
live stream because I do a lots of
things
um Lindon is the most eloquent carefully
crafted language yeah okay so let's
let's begin to write okay so I'm using
sarly keys you probably know already CA
flly Keys okay uh that is CA FL Keys
okay source code 4,000 lines and you can
get it for free and it's the most
efficient key binding system for
emac more efficient than Vim more
efficient than Neo more efficient than
Evo mod on the left uh on the left here
it's usually pink windows so let's set
background set background color pink
okay okay so this window shows all my
command Calles and keystrokes as I type
them uh uh you know so undo so you can
see and the keys on the left side I'm
using a v keyboard layout okay let's
begin so close that uh CL s FL Keys okay
uh copy that close close write a toggle
theme yes that's what we're going to do
and uh delete that delete that delete
that section and uh delete that section
okay so also delete that showing browser
that's what we're going to do today so
um you see this is I'm usinga flag keys
and HTML the most efficient
possible so yeah so themes okay so let's
start a emac l code block so D for
defend and I'm usinga emac L mod you
have to pay to get it because for 20
years nobody pays and I became tech
support abused and you know so now you
pay and it's open source I sent you the
uh source code okay
defenda toggle theme okay tle theme
let's just say that okay let's not be
too elaborate let's just get to work so
let's say load theme uh not load okay
load theme okay and uh the theme name
will be what is it uh deep blue I think
load theme deep deep uh
what deeper blue okay
deeper blue okay now in the other case I
want to disable themes so that would
be disable theme what's the
documentation look of dis function this
uh so dis theme you have to give a theme
name disable available and face settings
by the theme okay uh list
okay okay let's just go simple so it
requires an argument so yeah so let's
just say that we can enhance the command
later to have you know to have a
different choices choices of themes to
tarle now this toggle theme command is
basically just designed to toggle into
the do theme so at a daytime you you
have daytime theme uh light theme then
uh but anyway I'm just going to do this
okay so how do you know um if the theme
is already enabled or not I mean what's
the current state okay let's find
out so describe function disable theme
so it says um you know dis variable so
see this variable for list of enabled
themes so after theme has been disabled
runs disable theme functions okay what
is
that uh abnormal hook okay that's a hook
we don't care go back go back is L so
let's look at custom enable themes value
is new list of custom enable custom
themes um you know emac themes is
annoying because you can enable a theme
not just one you can enable another
theme so they kind of supposedly combine
them you know why does emac people do
that because supposedly you know it's
more functionality it's more power
that's why oh customizable so you can
customize everything but you know a
theme you should just be one theme I
mean what's the point of com Ling themes
I suppose the idea is that each theme
can can be a theme of just minimal you
know like one theme for background
another theme for coloring text so you
can combine you know you can pick
different themes that like
modularization like theme became module
so you can create your best theme by
combining them that's I suppose that's
idea of allowing more than one theme to
be enabled but I think it's cly it's uh
you know it's kind of like over
engineering all the existing bundle
themes in emac they are full themes they
are not just you know small part of it
so so the result of this over
engineering is
complexity you know Custom Custom
enabled themes okay so the current value
is near um
basically I want to disable all them
okay is there a function that just
basically disable all uh
themes you know so this custom thing is
no good okay so I don't know so we have
to look
for so one two things we need we need to
find the current state of themes
um
okay let write it out so it's so we have
Clarity especially for later viewers CH
Ching thank you Chris afterward can you
show how you insert current date oh
that's easy so current date there it is
so suppose you want full ISO
date so you can pick the USA style
United State deep State style that's a
typical USA style so uh so Universal
command first press the key to insert so
that command is called insert date and
you can find it cancel um okay cancel
cancel okay there it is so you can find
that just by Google search okay wait uh
so Google search look up web jun j
Jun there it is insert dat time click
there is a code okay so you can it's for
free for you
guys okay so uh custom uh so first
problem find out what's the current in
enabled theme if any okay so if there's
no theme then you enable otherwise you
disable Okay
um okay
so so this is one possibility is using
that but I don't think but I think maybe
there's a simple way
so now you go to Kar emx blog clicks
onar emx
tutorial search for themes okay it's not
here you click on emac in it search
for theme there it is set color theme so
everything you need to know about color
themes in emac is
here okay so you got load themes that's
how you load a theme or you can use
customized themes to get this
GUI then clear color theme disable theme
yeah but then you need a theme
name
uh let's look
up I want a way easy way to disable all
themes the problem here with this
disable theme is that it requires a
theme
name okay uh set color theme in emx in
it that's how you do it uh theme Gallery
so it's a gallery of all the themes
bundled with emac you can look and
compare so those are dark themes and
there's um light
themes okay so yeah okay my
documentation doesn't say okay let's
just do it
um okay
so what talk show close close and this
showing browser emac block close
close okay let's just code in
um let's
see is this a function or a variable so
oh okay so it's NE that means there's no
thing
if okay if this is
Neil if it's true to something if it's
Neil then then do that okay then load
theme now if it's not Neo then you
disable it okay that's uh I think that's
it so this function we just Target okay
let's eval the
buer try it okay
so M
X tarle theme do it
fantastic beautiful call it
again beautiful okay let's that's it
that's it so let we don't even need this
clean up the
code beautiful
uh tarle a doc uh let's full
documentation
tarle the deep
blue theme okay full documentation now
put it back syntax collect showing
browser fantastic that's one thing
done next we're going to call this from
EV line or let's let's call the print
list first
okay so let's uh color colorize the
command name do it and do it turn it
into HTML showing browser that's what we
going have to L CH Ching uh can you show
the insert curent dat yeah that that's
already done hey hey hey hey Jason
Jones uh Raa hi
uh did I get my drink okay I need to get
my drink so we
that's today's drink is brought you by
uh cranberry and watermelon juice no
sugar
added
never drink or eat anything with manmade
sugar uh for those of you concerned
about diet okay
next uh next we're going to
do uh let's say let's organize Let's uh
put this one to the
top okay that is already done then exam
print list
okay uh and not print hash okay let's
write
it emac this code write those okay pop
it
out Define function that okay
and print list one item per line
okay okay let's do that uh do I have it
already WR
sometimes I have I forgot so let's go
to uh packages search for U there it is
emac open it list matching lines
defend so let's see if there's a so
there is a print hash is already there
uh print okay there's print hash is
already
there and in fact I have it on a website
so go there showing
browser print hash how fantastic you can
grab
it so let print hash okay let's copy the
code actually I don't need to copy the
code because it's so simple but close
close close Okay but anyway here's a
code for that so how do you print the
list you want
to so actually
um uh okay this this this needs
Improvement actually so you see this
print hash it map hash so it goes
through every item in a hash table and
for each key and value it call Print
okay that's how it works but this is not
the most
efficient because let's say if you have
a hash table of 1,000 items this will
call Print 1,000 times in fact you know
it print tce you know it call Print
twice so 2,000 times so every time you
call a the more times you call a
function the slower it is and also every
time you interact with the input and
output it's even M much slower
so there's a much more efficient way to
do this let's let me let me do that um
in here so for example first of all
let's
um let's do it one one of the way okay
so you need a
uh okay you need a list there let's uh
list that's the argument so you want
to print the
list okay uh and Lambda uh yeah Lambda X
so you just uh here
uh uh which one you want so there are
several versions of printing in like
this so let's just say print okay so you
want to print it format X okay that's it
basically so that's one way to do it the
inefficient way so we don't need the let
anymore okay clean it clean it clean it
okay there yeah okay dat okay that's one
way to do it let's eval the buer okay
eval the buer then now let's say let's
create a list okay so let's say a list
um number
sequence so number sequence in iMac list
is like range in Python and other
programming languages so let's say from
1 to 50 increment one
okay so that get you a list and for
example let's run it run it you can see
at the bottom now let's call this
command on
it there it is okay run it you see so
let's go to the message Prof you can see
it prints him out like
that uh it adds extra line so you you
don't
um so that's because of the print print
function adds extra line output in
printed representation with new line
around
it
uh actually you don't need this format
because print takes care of it so you
just like
that um
yeah eval it it still does print the new
line though you see so close that so um
so if you don't want you know I
so let's try it so if you you see
um okay so it doesn't so it still prints
uh extra new l
so so you can look up the print
documentation there are several print
document uh in emac this so I can show
you again go to emac
disp emac disp Basics go there and uh
there is a section on print so there it
is so this is all possible ways to print
in emac lisp so you got messages you got
insert which insert into the buffer uh
then you have print you have print one
print one print C it kind of confusing
so every time like I have to read the
documentation like the difference is
that some of them prints a new line some
of them does not some of them prints in
a this readable way so when you have a
string it will print the
quote and but some of them do not do
that it when you have a string it just
print the string without a quote so it's
more readable so that's the difference
between print and print one and print C
uh so every time I have to like read it
which one is
which uh this so print prints in this
syntax that means includes a quote add a
new line okay so optional act for uh for
Target buffer okay so print one
so PR C does not add a new
U oh yeah so in this case it doesn't
print the quote because those are
numbers those are not
least okay so actually I want print C
okay eval eval show okay now it does
that no new line
so so what you can do is then you print
see again then just a new line okay yeah
but then it becomes small inefficient
try it so you can
see there it is okay but that's but
basically that's you know that's a
command but now let's do it the more
efficient way so let's write a second
version okay this version will'll be not
using map we'll use map
concact okay this is more proper
function because it doesn't call Print
1,000 times if you have list of 1,000
items it call this function one time to
convert a list into a giant string so
let me show you
so so the sequence is going to be the
list and optional separator yes we want
that and that is going to be a new line
and what is a function you want to map
to uh of course
format because sometimes an list item
let's say is a conell or something other
than a simple number or a string then
you want to format it because otherwise
it prints some kind of
uh garbage or unpredict unpredictable
things so anyway format so so so you
want to write a function here lamb for
Lambda and for each item you format it
okay credify the code that's
it it just return this string okay once
you return this string you need to print
it so
print okay print this
thing okay fantastic now eval it go here
eval show the message
buffer
fantastic is that what we want yes
that's what we want okay let's uh test a
different
case for example something
this list
um uh you know random
number okay then then let's say another
list okay three four five let's see how
does that work
out run it show message
buffer oh so you see so it you know this
is what it prints now we don't want the
quote at the beginning and end
so we want so we want we don't want
print we want print C and then at the
end after you print it
you print C
again with a new line so there it is our
function
beautiful now evalate and uh eval this
showing wait close that let's eval go to
message
buffer there it is it prints that uh
then then it uh okay we some more things
to
fix anyway that's that's a command Okay
so
uh eval
eval yeah you see at the end it prints
on double quote that's not what we
want let's say print without argument
you cannot do that it requires an
argument okay so why is this let's just
eval
that you see uh
Eva show so it prints that
quote now why is that is
because
um print in in a more human readable
format no string
delimeters so but if you have a line
return it as string de Del limiters is
that
right PR one does not add new line at
the
end oh PR C okay print C no new line at
end yeah but we want a new
line print one
it should work but I don't know print
one let's just try print one
okay so EV about that try that it still
does that okay try this it still does
that okay I need
to am I not thinking about something I I
I don't know print C doesn't print a new
line and Print in a human readable
way yeah but we do want to oh wait
okay so you want to so actually you are
you see this
function and it's a bit hard to
explain you know you know when you this
function
yeah it's a bit complicated to explain
so this function basically there's a
difference when you call a function
within a this
program and when you call a function and
it
automatically output to the message sper
so in you see whenever you run a
function it automatically print you know
in when you when you call a function
like right now like we are calling
eval um you can see we are calling eval
there eval last
six so when you do that the function
will do whatever it does you know such a
Sprint but but when you eval last
symbolic expression it will also also
automatically print whatever the
function returns so in fact it kind of
print twice
the first time is whatever the function
actually do you know because our
function actually does print so when you
so they print to the message buffer
messages buffer so that's one time then
because you are calling the Eva
sex it will also print automatically the
output of this function now what is the
output of this function it is
is uh so what is the output of this
function uh
eval a empty string I mean uh I mean
uh it it it returns this string itself
therefore therefore you see that's why
you see that because it is emx that's
Auto print to message buffer that
created this quotes
okay so so what does that mean does it
is a problem no it's not a problem you
you you want to make sure what uh you
want
to you you want this function to return
a string okay let's let's put
documentation okay if code um the
function returns a
stream okay that's you know so so this
function will return a string so let's
let's uh make local variable X
so let's say x string let's say X Out
okay
then set X out to be this string okay
then
you then you print it okay uh yeah
okay that's side effect but what's the
return value well in the case the print
function returns this string itself
so so let's remove that clean up the
code that's how it looks evaluate it and
uh let's you know let's let me show you
another way to interative interactively
call it so we're going to call this
function
but we want to insert the
result of the function right here okay
so what you do is you call control view
control U Universal argument
then eval last sex you see so it returns
a string correct but if you look at the
message sper you see it doesn't print
that quote beautiful
does that make sense is my
explanation clear CH Ching thank you
Chris I thought Dark theme is bad yes in
general it's bad but sometimes it's
useful like when when when the all the
lights you if you wife is sleeping you
want all the lights are out you don't
want the shiny screen because that's
disturbing you know so you know so so
when the only case I I have um Dark
theme is when the lights are all out
that's a use case okay but usually you
know Dark theme is not really good
because you know many of the programmers
the online fat the CSS Guru idiots you
know they are very popular like they are
I work for you know they are the
Google's you know web design lead or
they are promoted by Hacker News this is
CSS Fox Web Design you know they are the
designer of something some some you know
signal 37 F they created
this uh fat and myth and
unscientific okay and also Apple you
know but anyway you know
so basically Dark theme you know when
you have doc theme let's let's R tle do
theme okay and also go
here Taro by the way this is um po shell
let me show you power the power of power
shello Dark theme so watch the watch the
my browser okay do it there it is do
theme dark theme dark theme the whole
thing Twitter XCOM andar Discord you see
so you can get this
command s t do theme if you just search
it in poell you
see but but see but you see emac does
not respect the operating systems doc
theme setting so for emac you have to
manually um do it you
know you know
anyway so what one so why why is stock
thing bad usually it's harder to read
okay and you can how can you prove it
you can prove it by watching YouTube
videos okay if you go watch YouTube
videos like right now and if they are
doing coding like the screen is full of
code you know then when you turn on Dark
theme it's you you will immediately
realize it's hard to read
okay so that's you know dark them is
actually just harder to read Because
naturally in human history we don't you
know we we
see things under the sunlight at night
we don't go go out otherwise you got
eaten by lions and wolves okay so at
night so your eyes is not is is your
eyes is more adapted under the bright
sunlight not the
glowy Dark theme [ __ ]
okay that's a correction to the you know
a poke to the myth of the programmers
those are Hacker News those are the Unix
hackers Unix python Elite heads they
tell you what to do and often time half
of the time they are just
wrong but they make money you know they
uh they are the influencers they are the
so-called thought leaders you know the
Silicon Valley full of
these scammers and grifters okay so
anyway uh so I mean so you can check you
know check see which one is easy easier
to read so bright theme
or dark theme
let's try again bright
theme dark theme okay let's go back to
Bright theme okay so
anyway tarle it
back okay so what's next we got one more
thing to do so let's Clan up the code so
there are two
versions this version is less
efficient because it print me a thousand
times this version is efficient and
better okay and besides you can just um
you know
anyway
so yeah so and the print hash same thing
we just fix it to use uh to use the map
concact okay put it back syntax CCT
showing browser fantastic now we got one
more thing to do so it's already 50
minutes
okay one more thing to do CH
[Music]
Ching can you explain the Ogo emac
logo the fat man on couch
yes okay yeah so Emax logo so you can um
go to just search for emac blog you will
arrive at s code my website next page go
to emac blog then go you know this
navigation bar at the top goes to the
top of the directory I mean the top of
the
project and then you go
down uh video tutorials all my best
videos on emac and emac this is here
okay this this section this page is is
new so check it out uh by now I've done
you know like what's today's
episode showing browser talk show
episode
576 so by now I've done 500 videos you
know
this uh okay so back to emac tutorial
homepage go down there's a fun section
emac fun section so here is a section of
fun things okay so so one of them is
logo so my website I used to run Ergo
.org uh complex story anyway
so you know but now I all merged back to
Kali
info
kali.org or cali. info okay that's my
two websites I run now but I used to for
10 years or so I had all my emac stuff
is on oac.org
so Ugo emx is a emx distribution I began
around
2008 okay 2008 and one of the guy who
joined the team is David Capello okay
David Capello he's a great programmer
but he's a c programmer okay he's he
loves
C he
you know he so that's uh different for
me his idea is that you need you you
just need to prac be practical se's the
most practical of them all you know he's
but he's a great programmer okay so he
helped a
lot in oo emx because Ugo emx is a
complete emx drro you download the zip
file especially for Windows yeah for
Windows you download the zip file
everything runs everything set up you
know so one of the feature is the oo
emac key binding which eventually became
Sly Keys okay so anyway so but David
Capello is also you know by the way he's
a great programmer he's most famous for
creating asite okay so he's into classic
arcade game stuff gaming you know he's a
game programmer
too and so his most famous project is
this ter
JavaScript asper right very popular so
this program is for creating pixel art
animations so if you are creating you
know classic games you need a lot of
pixel art let's see can we play
some you know kind of like that so
so this program is just for creating
this pixel art you know there's a lot
great funny examples you can
see uh you know so anyway so he helped
and he's also by the way he's also an
artist he draws so he
created this
mascot you know he just you know I
didn't ask him to design a guy a fact
guy or something he just he just created
entirely this thing on his
own you know so and I liked it so that
became the Ugo emac logo you know this
fat guy watching
[Music]
TV with the remote control this is kind
of
classic uh theme of the 90s I would say
you know you know so and then he also O
created you know some variant logos but
I didn't like this though but I like the
you know this fat guy okay that's that
okay one more thing one last code we
need to do okay let's just code it
fast from line okay
so okay if I go if I do
quickly then most people wouldn't know
what I'm doing
doing but if I do slowly with
explanation it will take like 20 minutes
so maybe let's do it another day shall
we so how how are you guys did you guys
like today's talk
show uh is how how are you guys from
Spain how many people watching five or
is it
one uh which
window Okay so clst
that eight people watching
fantastic I think that's it for today
this eval current line let's do it next
time this wolam language okay let me
talk random for a while for five
minutes okay so delete that go to too
now I have 1,000 toos piled up you know
so search for talk show so this page is
bunch of talk show possible
todos like usually items that I can easy
easily do without preparation you know
so you know a bunch of things um
anyway so we do that next time and
meanwhile go to S code uh yeah let me
talk random about
several things keyboard block very
interesting emac blog programming blog
web dev blog math blog oh my God Jesus
Unicode blog okay so let me show you my
Unicode blog there's
some interesting things gun emoji
history the history of gun emoji okay so
you know since
2016 the US a kind of very corrupt deep
State
they they started
to change the meaning of English you
know they are they are trying to erase
you know change the meaning of English
words by force you know if you don't
obey if you don't use the jargon or
terms they think you should you know you
got banned from YouTube from Twitter you
know the Jack do is Twitter you got
banned from lots of website you all if
you are too loud your bank account get
cancelled your PayPal your you know
whatever
patreon they force change the language
we use okay and one of the thing they
force change is unic Code
Emoji so you can see here's a history
you know unic code has this Emoji you
know one of them is
skun you know so they they want to
change that started by Apple Apple is
one of the most
severe
scum since ever since Steve Jobs died
okay Steve Jobs is the greatest
innovator he brought us the most innov
Innovations in computer hardware he's he
basically single-handed
created the online streaming business
he's basically also by himself he
created the entire phone industry the
mobile phone an evolution you know
that's Steve Jobs since since he died
Apple
becomes led by this guy team something
you know
he's you know uh so they Apple started
to begin this replacing the gun emoji by
a water
pistol that's the beginning that's
2016 the beginning of social justice
Warrior
scan by force lots of violence on the
street beating people burning buildings
nothing you can do you know
they like they they are like the
criminals you know lower class criminals
sponsored by this by this Apple billion
dollar business Apple Google Facebook
you know so they pushed so one of the
thing you know they firstc change of the
language we use and one of the thing
thing they did is change the gun emoji
replacing it by water
pistol why do they do that well they say
oh because gun you have a gun picture
that will cause more violence okay
that's one of the you know the
their Theory
okay
so it's a history of emoji Okay g so
what but elen musk who is fighting this
this kind of very cor corrupt government
so he bought Twitter and lots of things
happened
he he made happen the Twitter files
which is exposing all the crimes of the
US say government expose it with
evidence lots of it that's Twitter files
okay that's one of the biggest thing
happened a year or two ago
then about three days ago two days
ago uh he reverted so on Twitter now the
gun emoji shows like a gun
okay so that's a kind of a chapter of
the history history of emoji and a
substory to the polit politics in
USA uh okay so started to talk politics
uh
then I think maybe that's it that's it
for
today uh so you see Google is still
using water gun Google Apple you know
they haven't changed yet but I'm pretty
hopeful they will change okay because
this corrupt you know whenever there's a
corrupt things happening in
society it may it may Thrive for a while
usually you know several years but
eventually if it's corrupt if it is
untrue they always die out okay because
truth is the most powerful why is there
because is there a god no it's because
you know you have a crowd you have all
the people on Earth usually when you
have something fake and true that
benefit not everyone usually just a
small group of people maybe a large
group of people but all the rest of the
people the truth is more beneficial to
them so you have this power in Balance
you know the small group of people who
are corrupt or bad maybe Mafia or
gangsters or whatever or maybe a you
know corrupt government or a rug country
you know but they are not everyone most
other people don't want something that's
fake because it har is harmful to them
okay
so if if your small group is very
powerful but you can't last for long
unless you control everyone but that's
almost impossible So eventually you know
what what's true
we usually not always I mean kind you
know statistically they always will win
okay because most people they want truth
because truth benefit overall
everyone so I'm kind of hopeful that
Apple this apple Google Microsoft you
know uh Samsung Facebook they will also
revert gun emoj to gun emoji okay Emoji
is just Emoji if you want you know if
you want to talk about actual
violence that has very little to nothing
to do with with you know whether a Emoji
shows up as you know a water gun or
not okay then that went into a heavy
politics thing so I think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching um
yeah if you like my stuff pay me okay
you can just go
to C code my website
c.in scroll down all the way and you
will find my patreon and
PayPal and Amazon Amazon gift card me
okay I need to increase the price you
know pay me like you know $100 one shot
you know do that once a year that'll be
appreciated if you like my stuff okay
okay thank you guys for watching bye