good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of excite up show today is
September 16th Monday 2019
8 o clock p.m. San Francisco time oh I
need to hold on a second
so no eyes here
no one is here yet today is Monday
Monday 8 o clock so this time so I guess
this time is not a popular time for
everyone and I do have one person
watching so say hi and let me know what
topic you like to talk about just type
in the chat box and some talk show this
show is pretty easygoing you just pick a
topic and we can talk about that it can
be technical programming languages
tutorial and sundry interesting things
okay now let me now on the Left panel on
the left window you can see all the
Emacs commands I call okay let's create
some Hawk show today's state today state
saw a new page create a new HTML page
make it a list put it here D and then
open the file showing browser okay so
this is gonna be today's notes and since
there is no one here let us let me just
talk random then and here someone's here
and say something okay okay okay okay
now some talk show okay so random topic
okay hold on a second let me let me get
this here so I can kind of see myself
okay random topic now let's go to Saudi
website let's see what we have to say
now here is the section about keyboard
this fresh tribe is fantastic you go by
it just go to Saudi Saudi keyboard just
search for that you'll find it Mike
Blagh and these we talked about the
other day okay so that's about keyboards
oh one more thing
now I've said this before never ever buy
this webcam
this is Logitech c920 or C 922 they are
pretty much the same and they are highly
recommended online you see them
everywhere in reviews and they'll say oh
this is a good one buy this one don't
buy that one that's the one I'm using
right now you are seeing me it's the
it's got autofocus problems so if you
are reviewing keyboard anything close it
won't focus okay it won't focus you're
just like going out and end up being a
fuzzy and if you go to Amazon reviews
you can see the some of the bad reviews
saying that but you know but you know
typically all the review says you know
recommend buy this one it's it's kind of
a lie
I cannot imagine people honest like
honestly most people do not see the
autofocus problem so possibly there is
some you know paid reviews you know
these days you can never know because
lots of these are going on in a
background you know I pay you you say
good things about me so anyway don't buy
this logitech c920 okay now however I
know this one is pretty good this one is
some kind of nameless brand okay I
suppose this is from China you know they
just have a random brand name ons on oh
okay anyway so this one at least
according to Amazon it's got pretty good
reviews and it it has autofocus and does
not have the fuzziness problem so I
recommend buying inst buying this one
I'm going to get it so that I can
actually do reviews on keyboard morning
Barrio so yeah so I think you know I
recommend this one this one is only $60
you know I'm talking about those under
you know around $60 $70 same thing same
thing with this okay but of course if
you have you know if you are a
programmer you work for Google or
whatever you can buy you know you can
spend 300 400 dollars buy a good one
okay but for you know if you don't have
that much money I think I'm going to get
this one so that's about web cam so
Barry oh what way up from again pareo
and so what what is today's topic like
pick a topic otherwise I'm just going to
go random you know just type type of
topic please
so keyboard that's about keyboard and
about programming there are something
interesting to say Oh Houston okay right
Houston Houston every time every time I
hear I hear Houston the the hey you know
I'm thinking houston we got a problem
that's that's the thing so so you're a
programmer right your email is okay so
let's let's talk about you might be slim
yeah that's this this let's just do that
right away
okay eMac this but okay so which topic
though let's see what we have here so we
have a let's copy that okay it's too
small to see so we have so let's talk
about eMac this let's see what are the
topic eMac this let a English to Braille
command okay eMac this demo search tml
brackets to HTML okay
both of them are good hot topics which
one you prefer we can go to one of them
first any yeah it's better if you always
tell me you know because so so I write a
major mode for a domain-specific
language okay that's cool what is it
like you know feel feel free to post
your links and stuff you know okay so
actually let me get a drink so let's
talk about demo HTML bracket to HTML
let's do that first
then we talk about eMac B's you know II
yeah so okay let's let's let's do a demo
of the site HTML bracket to HTML okay
again remember the left the left window
shows all my Emacs commands every
command I call it's going to show up
there so if you don't know what I'm
doing like Oh what is that command that
does that for example let me do this
thing okay undo thing and do go here
ting and do okay that deletes the whole
block of code and that commands if you
look at the left window you can see that
command is sati did context block and if
you search that yours you'll find a code
on my website you almost always most of
them so okay so let's talk about the
sati lead bracket to HTML thing so let's
describe function paste a function name
enter so Emacs give you the
documentation for the function then
press tab and you can jump to the
function jump to the source code so here
is the function here is a function so
let's see okay okay it's a bit long it's
like 200 lines
okay so Kasab HTML bracket to HTML let
me demonstrate what does that do first
okay
so on a second let me open a new buffer
switch to HTML switch to the
buffer oh yeah so switch to the same
buffer then oh I need to magnify you
know because people have mentioned the
text may be too small so is that better
so anyway so let's go back let me demo
demonstrate what is - exactly so so
showing browser okay that's my some talk
show for today type of date yes correct
so for example I want to say I just read
a article titled modern society oh okay
and make it a paragraph showing browser
you see I use these angle brackets now
this angle bracket is called let's
describe cha the name of that bracket is
called left angle bracket now that is
actually a Chinese bracket okay so so
anyway so are you so in Chinese
punctuation that bracket typically is
used to enclose titles book title TV
title article title or chapter name
section name things like that you by
tradition by convention you use angle
bracket this is a traditional Chinese
punctuation usage okay now for example
in English the tradition is to it had it
italic utilize it for example in English
typically you will say select that
insert attack I okay show ok showing
browser you see I just read the article
titled modern society you know utilized
that's English tradition but in Chinese
tradition there are many okay I mean
another tradition is use kind of squeak
squeak ly underlined or anything that's
a title anyway
angle bracket is kind of the traditional
one of the commission so in fact let me
show you article I want to show you Alec
oh sorry
Chinese punk actually excited Unicode
okay sorry Unicode okay Unicode such
sorry yes that's my site go there and
then scroll down you have a bracket
section bracket now this page shows you
all possible brackets in Unicode
all of them okay if it's not on this
page it doesn't exist so you can see all
these you know this parentheses square
bracket they are typical then you have
curly quotes single calico double curly
called French quote or sometimes called
good it oh you know I don't know how to
pronounce it but anyway French quote or
angle quote then you have full size you
know you have many variations you some
of them are math brackets some but some
of them look fancy so anyway these are
all the brackets
okay let's copy that paste it here okay
and let me talk about the Chinese
bracket so this this this this
especially this line okay all these are
Chinese brackets corner bracket angle
bracket double angle bracket then
ticular bracket Toto is shell bracket
and you have total left total shell
bracket left black totally shot bracket
well actually the the here over here the
the font is incorrect this one should be
white like it should be outlined I think
so yeah I think the font is incorrect
here but anyway these are
Chinese racquets so if you read Chinese
you know you go to Chinese website you
see these bracket often and but actually
it's quite useful in English context
because you know brackets is a one of
the basic it's a syntactic eunuch it's
it's kind of it's one of the unique it
is a character that has the unique
property such that they comes in matched
pairs so whenever you have you know a
bracket pair they big they you know they
have the property and it's also obvious
that they enclose some text so this is a
these are very good for you know for
English for example so anyway so that's
about Unicode characters and let me talk
about let me just mention Chinese
punctuation for those of you interested
on that I used to have a link here I
guess I removed it okay so search for
Casali Chinese punctuation okay I have a
article that explains what is the
difference I mean what does Chinese I
mean you know Chinese characters right
Chinese takes out Chinese characters but
what is their punctuation how do they
differ from English so this article
explained that basically it's the same
as English okay except you have you know
you have the typical period comma colon
semicolon question mark exclamation mark
you know but you also have some of the
you know special brackets so anyway let
me post this here that's a part of what
we are talking about then actually let
me let me clean this up so these two are
the things we want to talk about so
that's about Chinese punctuation okay
now close that close that and let let's
talk about so let me finish talking
about these so I wrote this you know I
read an article titled modern society
now I use the convention to bracket this
in
and go bracket then look look at the
left window I mean look look I'm going
to call command and transform it look
face a key and it becomes sight you see
it becomes HTML site tag now showing
browser now it looks nice it's red and
utilized so this is my own convention
whenever I have a title I make it read
and utilized so that any title can stand
out because utilized text they don't
stand out that much I wanted us to stand
out so if this title can be applied to
book title website title you know some
website article title or movie title you
know what what movie you watched
spider-man you know you can say Spider
me so that's so the command I just
called its undo okay and do it let's do
it again you see so the command just
called it's called HTML brackets to HTML
and the way I you know so the way I do
this is just my own Commission so
whenever I have a title first of all I I
make them into a angle bracket this is
the title you know I put them in side
angle bracket then I call the command to
transform into site tag side is for
citation you know typically it means
title now also this is not just for this
use there are other uses for example I
want to have a code for example x equals
to 3 plus 5 3 + 5 okay
now suppose this is a code right so I
put them into corner bracket you see can
you see a hold on second is this too
small or what okay so I put them into a
corner bracket like that then I call the
command again and they become cold
you know the HTML tag code so make a
paragraph showing browser you see code
any code my own convention is that they
are colored red and they are also using
monospace font so that's just my
confirmation but anyway the point of
showing them is to is to tell you about
this command I'm using it is this
command that does the job exciting email
bracket to HTML so they convert any type
of bracket to th HTML tags okay so but
why am I talking about this command is
there something I want to do no I guess
not
yeah I just so I guess it's just a demo
demo of this Emacs command and this
Emacs command oh I don't have a HTML
page for it like I don't have it on my
website so maybe I should add that oh we
should we should jump to the next topic
which is which is write a emag list
command to convert English letters to
Braille so let me read a question from
burial so Mario says it's actually not a
language in a strict sense it's a
simulation program that has several
hundreds of even thousand keywords okay
anyway I'm trying to come up with good
key bindings to move to move to next
previous keyword or section of the code
fire okay
as an extrema I also use Evo mod and not
sure if I'm already I'm ready to give it
up the problem is ievo steals or good
key bindings okay
such as square brackets okay and so on
what would you recommend okay that
question the question about key binding
choices that is actually a difficult one
and there is no easy answer okay it
doesn't matter what you do you cannot
run into problems why because if you are
Emacs user using Emacs key bindings
basically all the key binding all the
good ones are taken
okay now
let me categorize them into two group of
users default Emacs keybinding users and
vim users okay you have him use okay
let's talk about that later but let me
focus on the normal Emacs combining
users so in that case what was a good
choices of key bindings let me talk
about that so you go to my Emacs blog
sorry Emacs blog go to Emacs keys
this section is an index of all articles
related to key binding then you go you
look you go to how to define keys
okay now this is a big you know 10 like
five pages article that describe all you
need to know about how to you know write
code to create custom shortcuts key
shortcuts now there is a subsection on
this page that tells you what keys you
should not use and what keys are good
choices now I'm going to skip what keys
to avoid basically you want to avoid any
ctrl+ question mark and avoid any
control edge also ok ctrl + edge don't
do that
avoid any escape key don't don't create
a key binding that involves escape key
do not do any key binding involves ctrl
+ left square bracket neither ok don't
do that and do not use any ctrl shift
later okay and do not use ctrl n do not
use any key binding that involves Enter
dude you know and do not use any
combining involves control I or the tab
key okay that those are the ones you
should not use why well that's a bit
more detail you can read the page okay
you know
just just just go to my website and read
it later okay so I'm gonna type that
page here okay so that those are the
keys you don't want to you don't don't
bind those keys unless you already you
are a master of he winding like you know
you know you don't care what I say you
already know everything so you know case
you know you are on your own of course
you know this stuff but for now you know
just trust me don't just don't don't
don't buy any those keys okay for for
the sanity of your life okay now what's
some good keys the good keys are
function keys okay f f5 to f12 Emacs has
default for F 1 2 F 4 and basically I
will say you can use function keys for
your own keys okay or controllers
function keys or shift first function
keys or aught first function function
keys
you know meta you know depend you know
so function key combination or those are
good now besides that they are not many
good choices ok now I'm talking about
normal Emacs users you don't really
easily it's a hard problem you know you
can ask anyone each person we have to
have different opinions trying to solve
it because basically all you know all
the easy key is already used up by
either minor mod or by major mod because
everyone wants to have easy keys now
Emacs assign a set of keys that is
designed for custom for user customer
customization that is in Emacs this
manual there's a chapter saying that you
know it tells all the mod writers that
you should not find these keys because
these keys are reserved for users to
customize Emacs
what are those keys those are f5 to f9
and control C followed by one single
letter ok that is it
so Emacs officially we
deserve these keys for the user so you
can be sure that it is true that no
major mod or minor mod will use those
keys so when you use those keys you'll
be okay
there will be no conflict but those are
not good keys because f 5 2 F 9 5 6 7 8
9 there are only 5 keys I mean typically
you want you have 10 more keys you want
to customize you know yummy for your own
commands if you use eMac long enough so
that's only 6 keys that's not enough and
the ctrl + C letter that's you know
that's too many keys I mean if if you
have some commands you use every you
know of a few times a minute that's too
many keys you are rather prefer let's
say ctrl T or control Y or something you
know that's much better for you
because many default control keys you
don't use so in summary
Emacs manual gives gives you these keys
that that says these are for user keys
but in practice that's not very good so
you you could you know you could use
function keys function keys is not also
not a very good solution because for
many people they don't have function
keys with you know they don't have a
keyboard with function keys Oh on the
Mac by default the function keys does
you know some volume up volume down
eject these things like that you know so
you don't have function keys so anyway
so what is the solution this is the in
short there is no good solution so you
just have to kind of find your way find
a way now I do have a solution now let
me let me talk about this solution but
before we do that let me talk about the
vim situation the vim uses okay for vim
users basically you have the same
problem because if you are vim user of
evil mod user right all the keys are
used up you know all the keys are used
up what so what can you do you either go
back to the what
emacs menu suggest you know control see
later that's you know and that's only 26
keys you know that's not many you know
so so you also have a problem now let me
recommend a suggestion okay
this so my solution is key sequences
okay let me tell you about that okay key
sequences now let me read the comments
first okay so Barry who else is here
today nobody he feels a code come on
guys five people post questions okay
questions stuff so barrio Barrios from
Houston says control arrow or old arrow
yeah that's good
so Barry says how about control arrow or
old arrow that's good but some art some
art okay also use that now remembered
you know like with what we mentioned you
know Emacs by Emacs manual it but
officially it reserves certain keys for
users customization now those does do
not include control arrows in old arrows
so some mod actually use that for
example if I recall correctly there is a
like if you go to practice practice
Emacs you go to manage windows topic you
go to effective window management save
split windows configuration you have any
way that I mean let's not then forget
about looking at but you know since you
so control arrow arrow arrow that's good
but some mod will use it also also those
are not super
up that those are not optimal keys
okay this non-optimal because you need
to move their hand one hand to control
one hand to arrow you know it's it's
then they move back so you know that's
not optimal but those are good ok you
can use those you know key binding is an
odd you know part science part art and
also different people very very squiggly
also depends on what keyboard you you
use I mean if you yeah let's talk about
that as well let me keep the let's don't
let's to keep talk about that because
that's also important critical topic
okay let me let me post it here so I
don't forget oh yeah and we need to
actually start to work on eMac beasts
okay so so it also depends on keyboards
like most people you know you are used
to these PC keyboards okay that's great
so to you controls your arrow is there
and but a lot of other people they are
using different keyboard and and that
changes things entirely because to you
in your brain you think oh we should
control T something everything you know
control T is the best you know but to
other people they like that they they
are using this kind of keyboard so their
mindset is in 100% is totally different
from yours but you never imagined but
because most of us you know we leaving
out in your life we are only know 10
people 50 people you know we don't see
the whole outside so you don't imagine
you never thought of what other people
are using what's the situation you know
so so keyboard actually come into a play
majorly so whenever you talk about key
binding remember you must you must
remember what are you saying
I mean and what are you saying and what
what is a keyboard you are talking about
so to you I don't know what keyboard you
are using you know anyway control arrow
so that you know that's good but just
but when it comes to some key bindings
keep
keyboard matters greatly you know makes
a huge difference in your key binding
your choices of key binding or which key
binding you like it has major impact it
changed in fact it changes your entire
key binding set even for example if you
are mostly working with laptops or
laptop style keyboards that's entirely
different from if you are using you know
these full-sized keyboards you know
entire different experience and and your
choices of keys will be different okay
and also even though this PC keyboard
you see all these PC keyboard you know
they are pretty much the same right you
know control or they are own you know
pretty much the standard position but
actually not when you actually use a
keyboard then suppose you buy another
keyboard your your your know your take
you a few days to get used to because
even though they are all kind of the
same but actually there's minor details
the key you know the gap size you know
little micro details they actually has a
big impact okay not negligible impact -
to which Keys you prefer to press okay
things like that so keep keyboard in
mind and also let me just mention you
know I study keyboard right I'm keyboard
phonetic so so you know go to my website
you know exotic keyboard and read the
articles find the keyboard you like if
you like it buy it from my website okay
so that that way I get some financial
support okay that's about keyboard now
so let's let me go let's go back to talk
about what key binding I recommend there
is one there is a good solution the
solution is key sequences now this page
this page is a tutorial how how do you
define key sequences in Emacs okay so
let's pause it here
okay key sequences these are today's
topic ok key sequence
so let's go back to the article key
sequences okay so what does that mean
that means
so you just for example f na f6 you
press you know you you you it's almost
like hunt hunt and peck
you know like email do you imagine your
hand is a pecker like a bird you know if
Knight f6 that's that's P sequence okay
f9 f7 that's another thing f9 FA F and I
if Knight okay
you know if one F of five let's go
that's key sequences once you know key
sequences has many several advantages
they are great they are you know this is
what I recommend this is I fully
recommend you should do this you use key
sequences for example I'm using some
flight keys right I mean you are the
evil mod user that's great sir Frankie's
is kind of like Evo mod kind of like vim
okay it's a modal so you have insert mod
command mod but also I have key
sequences for example I press let me
show you okay space control edge okay
now Emacs pop up all these this page
these are all my key sequences you can
see go to the bottom there are about 200
of them so if I press f8 space tab is
one thing space 3 is another thing space
6 is another thing space G is another
command space K is another command and
so on abcdefg you know all that all
together they are 200 of them all these
are key sequences meaning that you know
it's just sequence of keys and I limit
myself to no more than three keys three
keys key sequence more than three is too
much
okay so two key you know to sequence of
two keys or three okay the most
frequently used command you give it
sequence of two keys
the you know let's use you give it
sequence of three keys for example look
at here I have space key sweet space t1
space t2 space t 3 so long and space key
a state space keys C and so on you know
key sequences now when you have a key
sequence the first key
we call it the leader key you know the
beginning key the leader key this is
this is important because so so so when
so if you look at these key key
sequences what if you want to enter
space now because I'm using some model
marks stuff like he's so I have model
and command I mean in so mod and command
mod so when I mean insert mod space just
insert space when when I'm in command
mod space key is the leader key for key
sequences so that's why I have all these
key sequences highly recommended and the
for evil mod for evil mod ok Barry oh I
know there is a package now I don't know
exactly what's the name they also have
key sequences just like what I have here
okay they're ketosis is different for my
but are you familiar if you know it's a
it ok anyone so that is I recommend
Barry oh you know get get that key
sequence package and try to create your
custom keys custom keys there like for
example let's say if space key is a
leader key then then the second key
choose a key that that is for all your
custom keys so for example for example
space key anything that begins with
space key is all your personal key
bindings okay that is my solution key
sequences now one of the issue is how do
you choose a the beginning key like the
leader key
okay if you have function keys for
example you can make it f5 so whenever
you want a key sequence you know just
pick f5 f5 then a b f5
f7 f Knight f5 a see that's another
command okay things like that so you
have so one advantage of key there are
at least two advantages of using key
sequence one it's easier on a hand you
know when you do a control combination
that's actually that's a worst for your
hand health
don't ever if you possibly can
don't ever use control or odd metal
sequences don't do that I mean
combination don't don't do those codes
use Kissick so key sequence one
advantage is easier on your hands the
second advantage is that you actually
have a lot more key possibilities than
the key combination I have Ark on that
you know I have like tens of articles so
let me show you okay so let's go to key
binding let's go to my keyboard block
let me go to show you that article so
you go to key binding you go to the
first article how many keyboard
shortcuts are there so in this page I
calculate how many possible combinations
of key binding you have when you have
chords Keys involving ctrl alt shift
Windows key okay you compute how many
possible possibilities are there then
you also compute how many possible
possibilities you have if you use key
sequences you know I compute it turns
out key sequences you know in both case
if you involve in key sequences it just
as far more possibilities than being key
codes okay you can read this article for
detail so that's about that so let me
paste that article here okay so so far
so good Mario
I mean give me some feedback let me I
mean does that make sense so okay so so
yeah so so back to so let's conclude so
key sequence is good because it's good
for your hand health and also it
actually creates much more possibilities
meaning that you can have you know you
will not run out of keys like sometimes
you have lots of command so which you
know how do you know the key line is
that you already have used you know you
you have less of that problem so that's
about key sequences and that concludes
that topic about about what is a good
key binding choices in Emacs
okay so raha not have says good morning
hey man I've been using your single key
binding for a year now f10 terminal f6
close fantastic just want to say thanks
for great tip thank you thank you rob
Mohammed says hexa can you talk about
your favorite Emacs packages yeah I
that's I think I think let's do eMac
list because that's a topic we want to
we started you know Barry you asked me
before so let's you know let me do that
today actually about packages I don't
use much okay I I think in in my past
videos this month or last month I've
talked about that basically let's see if
I can find it okay so talk it's this
let's see if I can find it quickly such
for packages okay so anyway I don't
remember when like ten days ago 20 days
ago I did I talked that basically I
don't I don't use I only use like five
packages match it is one of them and and
and the smacks is another one that's
basically that's the two I'd we like the
most
okay you you you your favorites cause
stuff like keys thank you
saga Neha again Neha
she she what salvation on get someone
that side PD PD sound doesn't it make
home yoga dance yoga DeSean pungho
dancer
what'd your mom say a million without
knowing good sermon someone that's a
tally Billy Billy something don't I so
so you are in China right again one so
far scene says I have a specific
question about the package all the icons
tired okay I don't know that package but
I worry that it may be too specific and
wouldn't be helpful to anyone but me
yeah I don't know that package but if
you have a question just type it okay
like don't okay I mean it's better the
meta question I can ask this question I
mean just type it if I see if I know the
answer I can answer right away if I
don't know then you know no you know
type it and somebody maybe know so I
don't know I haven't tried I don't I
haven't heard of that package package or
the icons tired yeah I don't know what
which is that you know feel free to just
type the questions okay so let's do eMac
this let's do eMac this let's bits let's
do this one
okay thank thanks Fabio and good morning
Pablo Pablo is making a do-it-yourself
keyboard that's great so Pablo is making
that so Pablo do you have a link you
know post it feel free that easy it's
good you know post it if you have a link
to the photo of your current status of
your do-it-yourself keyboard okay let's
talk about email is okay so I wanted to
because that's a one of the topic we
want to do today so let's let's begin
talking about email list and emag this
yeah so the the the the task we want to
do is to create a command that converts
English to Braille commands
okay so first of all let's go to first
of all let's go to Unicode Braille let
me show you what is that about
sorry Unicode okay
únicos search go down go down there it
is well now Braille
as you know Braille is for the blind you
can like touch and feel and you know
read it and you know the dots pattern of
dots that represents English letters oh
cool
so sobre oh look at Braille is this is
very interesting for those of you
programmers or mathematically in kind
because a Braille pair is a
combinatorial patterns of six dots in
fact you know the standard Braille are
six starts so you have different
patterns
now the but they are also eight dots for
patterns so you can see the these are
pre or your parents now let's talk about
the standard bales now standard
Brielle's now one of the interesting
aspect is combinatorial issue like
mathematics for example one of the
interesting questions how do you order
you know the combination of dots how do
you order them for example let's look at
this section okay this section this
section orders them by that so you can
see the first scoop is or single dot
then the second you know well yeah
single dot you have six possibilities
because there are six starts you know
each each one single dot a different
position you have want you know six
possibilities then followed by two dots
patterns so two dots two dots two dots
two dots you know you have again you
have more than six possibilities you
have I don't know how many so six pick
two combinatoric there's a formula okay
there's a math formula
well we can look into but that's that's
going into math let's skip that anyway
this is interesting because you you want
to order these stats so one way is to
order them by how many number of dots so
beginning with just one dot then you
have two dots then you have three three
dot patterns like this and four five and
then six you know six dots that's that's
one way to order it another way to order
it is you okay let's try this one okay
this section sewed by name or name by
dot position
what it means is that you order them by
you begin with one dot and from now on
any subsequent cell per cell always have
that dot on for example this one begin
with with the upper left dot so the
second one also have upper left out in
fact all the rest have upper left dot on
you know on there and here you you run
out of possibilities and here so for
example and here this one this is the
first one that does not have over left
dot so that so this is another way to
order it that's not a complete
description anyway I wanted to mention
you know the ordering problem is an
interesting issue because you have
several orders and also let me mention
well each dot has a name they are named
like this niche studies associated with
a1 number so they are named one two
three four five six
and according to position so top left is
one then second row left is two third
row left is three then right column
first is four then then right column
second is five right column third row
six you know
you order them that way so so once you
have a name for each dot then given any
Braille pattern you have a sequence of a
numbers sequence of numbers that
represents this sprayer character so for
example let's see this one you can see
it's called the Unicode name is Sparrow
pattern dots one okay on the other hand
let's look at this character let's look
at this character the name is pale
patterned dots one two three four five
six meaning or dots are present let's
look at this one this one is named
peridots three of had and dots one two
meaning that you know the dot named one
is present and the dar named two is
present and this one for example is
named well pad and that's three five you
know the the three that are three and
dot five are present so so this way any
Braille pattern can have a name and the
name has a unique odor because you just
order them by you know by numerical one
two three four five six so so once you
have a name for each barrel pattern now
you can order them by simply using this
this name you know this sequence of
number names so that's another naming I
mean that's another way to order prayer
and when you order prayer like that this
is what you get you see you see this is
what you get this this section so so so
far you can see three different ways to
order Braille the one with the number of
count of dots is the most intuitive so
anyway that's a Braille okay that's some
interesting thing about Braille but I
wrote this JavaScript application look
look this application translates or
convert
it's English letters or words into rail
patterns in real-time so so this I
created this this app you know
JavaScript in JavaScript a pamphlet so
that's fantastic so right now what we
want to do we want to write a Emacs
command so we press a button it becomes
Braille press a button again it becomes
back to English letter so let's do that
okay that will take like 20 minutes or
also
so okay we got seven people watching so
let's let's do that let me just do this
quickly then so let's go to Emacs block
let's go to actually I have some similar
things so let's go to command examples
and let's go to HTML commands do things
at point insert things I have I have a
bunch of examples okay let's see if I
can find it right he made your mod
let's go to emag list miscellaneous
okay so I don't know actually I don't
know where is it the article because
there's too many articles
you know III wrote so many articles like
over the past ten years I tried to
organize them that's a lot walk you
organize organize organize he still
needs to be organized because so let me
try to find a command script examples
commands examples
okay forget let's just go web search
so you open a new buffer saw Emacs
convert Latin okay just type that then
you'll find it so there it is Emacs
Latin to gothic so let me let me show
you these commands okay because because
we are going to write a something very
similar so type that command there and
I'm gonna for example type something
here and let's see what happens okay now
I call the command meter X and I say saw
convert Latin to gothic okay enter there
it is no no let me magnify okay you see
so copy that paste it here so let's call
it again so okay so let's call it again
to convert it back okay so so let me try
another command saw convert Latin to run
okay now it becomes run characters run
is a another Asian character so copy
that wait and we can convert it back
okay you just press ctrl you first okay
now we are back okay so these are some
examples of Emacs commands that does
this kind of conversion okay they are
kind of too small so let's add a class
okay class big random number okay and
okay
and then go to the top of the buffer
shrink a little bit shrink and insert a
style okay that then that then switch to
our CSS mod
font size font size - um that's good
close we open showing browser there you
go
okay so there you have it
why is is not oh okay so this gotta
actually this is gonna go here showing
browser okay so so you have a command to
convert to gothic and let me type let me
show you the command okay so here is a
source code here is my HTML page and
copy the file path close that codes that
for the link here and go down gothic so
let's go to gothic copy the file path
put it here
Vai and you can see they are all
linked here and so what we want to do is
we want to do something very similar to
this because we want to convert to we
want to convert it to the Braille right
so what we do let's just copy this code
here okay
convert to gothic Latin okay Latin to
gothic
describe function go to the source code
here is the code copy close and create a
new buffer emag this paste it there
open into a new buffer now here's the
code and now we want to change the name
convert Latin to Braille okay let's say
- well okay and let's forget about the
documentation and we can fix that later
then all we need to change is this
section basically we need to you know
because here we have a list of pairs
that is a map between Latin characters
and the and the gothic alphabet we want
a map of letters to bear so okay so here
let me do this okay so this this let's
call sways - new line okay wait and
that's it's not like what we want so
actually select that copy dad
krory replace okay that's better so here
is the this is the the map we want to
change once we change the map basically
everything is already done because we
copy the code already so income any
comments guys comments oh is it
is this boring you know is this morning
or you know say it I know so first of
all so let's take this do it let's speed
up in let's go to so let's go through my
unicode website let's go to Braille
okay that's there is a Braille website
I'm going to the Braille website because
I can look at my JavaScript code to get
a map so search for go to the top search
for da GS there it is Unicode Braille so
here is the the map this is the
JavaScript that does the conversion so
all we want is to get the map to grab
the map so copy copy it close close we
don't need any more cross now we are
back in Emacs then we just need to paste
this and we need to convert this
JavaScript array syntax to Emacs syntax
okay so what we do is we cut we copy the
whole section we narrow to region and
now we remove the ending bracket so
let's see yeah we want to convert it to
Emacs right so actually remove all
remove all coma actually so query
replace delete coma do that for all and
credibly place that coma do it for so I
think that's that's the this syntax that
should be right
so why done so why done that's correct
so this is the
old gothic so we don't need it anymore
let's see so we have English letter -
gothic right we don't need it anymore so
okay
delete that okay so we have that and why
don't we compact it so that compact
compact okay so we can see the whole
buffer okay basically I think that's it
we can actually try it then maybe
possibly explain what's going on with a
code so give a buffer so now Emacs know
so command now let's just let's try it
okay copy this paste here select it
caw-caw Latin to Braille enter yay I
think it actually worked
magnify yeah it worked you know Emacs
Emacs for some reason is using this
found where the empty dark dot are shown
as white dots but you know that's the
way okay that's let's compare so for
example let's go to my application here
Unicode Braille yeah so so that's the
English right so wait hold on let's see
if this works
okay copy the English paste here shrink
okay and copy the Braille here copy back
to Emacs paste okay so you actually need
it to be bigger so delete that new
buffer actually new let's go over here
new buffer taste magnifying okay so that
is that now let's try the same thing
okay copy that paste it here
Kota command sock invert Latin to bail
okay
now let's see if this nine and this and
this line are the same okay let's do a
search such indeed they are the same so
actually it works
so actually we just we have just created
we have just written this command now no
okay no questions guys pareo what do you
think is that I mean this makes sense
Oh Barry O Muhammad and un fastened say
something so does that make sense so far
so actually so now we are kind of done
and wait him s mi mi let's see let me
check yeah i'm i'm okay i mom
so now we are actually kind of done so i
mean it depends on what you guys want we
would I can you know at no Morea would
just explain the code a little bit how
it works or if you rather see something
else like you know let me know
so that's cranberry juice then some tea
common guys coming no comment okay I'm
going to okay I guess I explained some
codes for five minutes and I'll be it
for today so this so this emag base code
first of all we have we have three
arguments beginning and in reverse
direction okay
beginning end is the beginning position
beginning end positions crucial
positions like you know Emacs determine
kusa position spy by what's called the
point basically it's just a number so in
the beginning of a buffer the crucial
position is what and you can find out by
calling describe chart for example let's
go ahead describe chart and you can see
position 1 of 1 5 5 9
so 1 5 5 9 that means the end of a
buffer the last position is 1 5 5 9 for
example let's call describe cha ok
describe cha you see one five five nine
of one five five nine so that's a cool
supposition
okay and so this function takes three
arguments beginning ends are closed
positions and this reverse direction is
either true or false true means reverse
the direction meaning that you are
converting Braille to English letters
now if force that means to not reverse
direction so you are converting English
letters to bear now he Emacs true is
represented by the symbol T okay and
force by convention is Neil
that's a Emacs convention true is T
force is near in fact anything not true
is
anything not neo is true okay that's a
Emacs this convention let's go to my
email this tutorial you can check double
check base double check
Emacs basics printing arithmetics
convert float int true force okay it is
the symbol neo is false
anything else is true also neo is
equivalent to the empty list so empty
list is also false by convention the
symbol T is used for true right so so
anything not neo is true and by
convention symbol T is used for true so
anyway this function takes three
arguments now when you call it
interactively for example let's call it
for example it's something okay some and
let's call it come by Latin to Braille
okay it converted but I didn't give any
argument how does it find out where is
the beginning position where is the end
position and whether to convert you know
or reverse direction I didn't say but
how does Emacs know Emacs knows because
you are in eMac this you can use this
interactive cross so here we have
interactive is you interactive if user
region is true if use of region is true
then then we turn this list otherwise
return is this list user region P means
if there is a selection then it's true
okay so if there's a selection then I
return this list which which means you
know region beginning with an end and
can cause a current refix arc so if I
have a selection this list will be
returned and this list will be fed into
the parameters of this function why
because that is
the job that is the purpose of
interactive so when you have interactive
and when the interactive returns the
list that list will become the
parameters of this function so that is
why even I didn't tell you max you know
where where I wanted to begin oh and
Emacs knows because interactive cross is
a way for Emacs to automatically feed
whatever you want to give to the
functions argument when a function is
called interactively that is the purpose
of the interactive thing so if user if
you switch and P is false meaning that
basically means I don't have a bitchen
like I don't have a selection then what
I do so I say I you know I say here I
return this list it says line beginning
position lying in position and current
prefix arc so line beginning your so you
just basically current lie so it
consider current is the region that's
what Y is y it does now the the current
prefix up is that's basically that's
control you okay that's that's basically
like when you press can like first for
some commands you can change its
behavior by pressing control you before
you call the command so when you do that
when you press control you first that
the value will be saved in the variable
current prefix ugh okay so that that is
why you have these I mean that's what
current prefix arc is for and current
prefix arc the value is feed to the
parameter reverse direction true or
false so that's how Emacs knows I want
to you know which direction I want to
convert
okay no no comments guys okay so that I
think then
so that that is how you so we so far we
just explained how this function gets
its parameters and what what does the
parameter means and then then basically
what you do is you just go through you
just go through find and replace
like you know you in a buffer you
basically the heart of the program is
this is this line okay so while search
for word some character okay
now if it's found then just replace it
we face it with the weep
you know the second element the the you
know so what did so what does this do is
that you see this part we have a map and
we map this function to this map and
what is that what is that map that map
is this character map from letter to
Braille or from rail to letter now
depending on the reverse direction you
see you see this this code here this if
statement oops this if statement so if
reverse direction is true then you do
this okay otherwise you just return the
latin to gothic map okay that name is
bad so let's change the name latin to
gothic let's change it to latin to real
okay when we face replace replace okay
so so this if block that sets what user
map is
okay in fact let's change the code
that's not let's change the structure of
the code okay so let me so set user map
use a map will equal to this okay
okay so so so this code is the old code
we are improving it this one is better
so because this this one is better
because in our set in the beginning we
know what is doing is trying to set a
value to use map use map is a map we
want to use depending on the direction
so so we are setting the value what's
the value well depends on if the reverse
direction is true or not if it's true
then we have this function this function
basically reverse this list of pairs
reverse each pair in the list and
returns a new list so that is what is
part two but if reverse direction is is
false then we just return you know Latin
to Braille map you know so it's very
good so we have Cairo fact we have
simplified this this you know here this
is this blood block of code we have
actually made it better so okay so let's
copy that again let's try let's see if
this works
selected some thing select ok so Coit
Braille it works okay okay so that's
about that then then we just do we
narrow to region then we we set case for
such Neil we don't want to deal with
capital letters actually we want to deal
with capital letters I mean in Braille
there is no take there is no Braille
characters over only correspond to
lowercase okay yeah lower case there's
actually no Braille cell for capital
letters
but however when you want to represent
capital letters in Braille
you have a special Braille pattern you
place in front of a character or a ward
okay something like that
so in Braille in general you don't have
capital letters so so in for for our
purposes we just want to do such case
for such meaning that doesn't matter is
capital case or lowercase to the
conversion okay so that's what we want
to do and and then we map we map a
function this lambda function to the map
you know to this map we go through each
pair of you know letter and replacement
better and replacement we go to each one
of them for each one of them so for each
one of them we we search through the
buffer you know God first of all go to
the beginning of the buffer then while
such you know you found that character
of the first element if you found it
then you do that we place we face it by
the second element in the pair you know
so that's how this code works okay so I
guess that's it for today then so any
questions about that that's it that that
it that is it this function is complete
this function is complete and everything
seems nice yes let's maybe clean it a
little bit yeah create a rabbit so let's
remove the redundant space and so and so
on then delete it paste it back here
color it showing browser scroll down we
have it today and I'm going to make this
into a HT HT ml page on my
Emax website so it's good anyone so hold
on a second I'm thinking there is
something wrong with the chatbox Oh is
there
still here guys okay so you guys been
quiet okay so that's it for today yeah
that's it for today so thank you guys
for watching hope to see you in next
episode now if you like my stuff
I have Emax tutorial I have this
fantastic Emacs tutorial you can buy the
whole thing for $30 very cheap I mean
the main thing is that you get this
complete eMac this tutorial from the
ground up they are not much out there
actually they are not even much eMac B's
books so you know if you like my stuff
buy it
there is a PI link somewhere here yeah
at the bottom and there is this video I
did this video a few months ago about
teaching you eMac Lisp so you might
check it out and buy my tutorials so
thank you guys for watching bye