good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sun talk
show today we're gonna talk about mufam
language mathematica
lots of interesting things and uh so
it's mostly gonna be woofing language uh
post your questions
in in the chat box
and uh so we i'm going to show i'm going
to do some demo of wufang language
mathematica and i'm going to give you
a basic tutorial for programmers how to
program mathematica
mathematica is huge you know you know
now it's got 6
000 functions building you don't need to
load any libraries
6 000 artificial intelligence uh
functions building
uh and you know uh so i'm going to
so i'm going to first of all i'm going
to tell you how to get wufang language
for free
and uh um and there are three videos i
did
before on wolfram language on the on the
nature of the wufang language
and you know mostly my audience you guys
are programmers that's
that's what i'm uh that's my topic it's
going to about i'm
talking about um language for
programmers
so you know you can ask me questions in
comparison to python
lisp you know things like that uh and
so i'm going to so i did three videos
before check them out in the past month
you know
it's on my youtube just search for my
name and mathematica
or ufam language so i'm going to show
then i'm going to show you
um a very interesting thing about
uh about this
contour plot plot okay this is a
this is a problem in a computational
geometry
and uh it's very interesting because you
can try to implement this
in in your favorite language in python
you know
with ai or whatever in golan in scheme
list
you know you can try you know and you
you of course you need a graphics
uh library or something to do this but
this is a very
hard problem okay and it's very easy to
understand i'm going to
explain and show you so uh then i'm
going to
so basic tutorial on wolfen language and
i'm
also going to show you uh you know
wolfram language is
tremendous huge um
uh wolfram language doc okay
it's 6 000 functions i'm going to show
you
how to learn it you know you know like
how is the tutorial i mean their
documentation structured
you know you know one of one of the
interesting questions as a
technical writer documentation writer
you know if you are a programmer
you read about documentation in python
language in golan
in this you know each one has their
different documentation
writing style and style
and uh uh
yeah they have you know pearl python
ruby they all have different styles and
they're you know java for example
uh with the javadoc so so one of the
interesting problem
is about organization and how do you
specify a function you know
for example if you have a function you
know it takes several arguments
and some of the arguments are optional
how do you
you know write it how do you present
that you know
in different programming languages they
all have different styles and so
and one of the interesting problem for
wolfen language is that you have
6 000 functions built in
so you know how do you categorize it for
example in java
you know you know you know you know in
if you are a
programmer for java or python
or golan you know each one have
different style how do you find your
function you want
so for example in java they categorize
everything into a
object tree kind of so you have the left
panel of interfaces and objects and for
python it's a mess
for php you just search for the function
name or your or
what you try to do array you know take
elements of array for php
uh usually you'll find it right away and
for emac list
for example the documentation
organization is hell
basically they want you to read from the
beginning page to the end
yeah very hard to find exactly what you
need so different styles you know
so one of the problem in writing a
documentation for programming language
is how do you organize or
you know organize your functions you
know some you know this fairly complex
because sometimes
they you know you have building
variables sometimes you have
um you know functions
sometimes the function belongs to in
another library so you have you know
default libraries come with a language
such as python so-called
battery included so if python is battery
included
then wufang language is the whole earth
you know so six thousand functions how
do you
you know you know write a documentation
for them so that
things are easy to find i'm gonna show
you how uh to go about because nobody
yeah even including stefan wolfham the
guy who created language you know
made half of the you know a lot a lot of
the functions he
may not remember and don't use you know
because you know it has become very few
huge
and uh so how do you how do you go about
uh
learning the wufan language and i'm also
going to tell you which
there you know there are quite a few
books on wolfen language there are
tutorials i'm
going to tell you which one i recommend
and
so then i'm going to give you a basic
introduction to from language
i'm going to go fast today okay to focus
on this
and i'm going to show you type settings
in mathematica
some synthetical features how how often
language
is um shares the nature of lisp
or the lisp characteristics okay and
that's about it and
i'm yeah and also you can
find a notebook you know what is the
notebook uh how it is
you know in fact you can think of
notebook is
uh a magnet uh it's like a org mod you
know my my audience like oaks oak mod
language is one magnitude beyond that
it's just like oak mod you know but it's
one magnitude beyond you can evaluate
uh evaluate code you can create headers
and footers you have
images and so on and including
animations and
synthesizer yeah yes you have functions
that creates
sounds you know you give a a wave
function for a sound you hear
play it so six six thousand functions
you know one way to
uh characterize language languages
saying you know it's a ai
it uh it's a ai programming language
okay it's an ai
building ai programming language you can
think of uh it as that
in fact it has a natural voice natural
language recognition so instead of
typing
you know instead of typing code
i never actually use this function but
let's try it okay plot
sign okay let's magnify
natural language recognition okay so
that's what
you know suppose this will work let's
try it
okay actually uh yes so how how do you
actually okay you just click on that
indeed fantastic
what wait where's the output
uh this is this is
okay wait so actually from what i know
uh sign so cut that you don't need you
don't want to evaluate okay
paste let's try that
ah what's going on
okay maybe i need to restart mathematica
let's try again okay
uh evaluation quit kernel
quit local kernel yes so that you know
maybe i did something that
screwed up things mathematica
so uh let's do 1 plus
3 plus 2 okay
okay uh the kernel began
let's magnify a bit okay so
now i want to use natural language
recognition okay plot
plot sine plot cosine okay cosine let's
see
what happens
okay so i never used this before
so it's telling you you know it's
interpret interpreting
the meaning of plus sign and it gives
this result
and this result is supposed supposed to
be the
syntax for uh wufang language to plot
cosine so let me just
copy that so you just click on that it
becomes that
evaluate wait
what happened to my mathematica
this is
okay that's embarrassing so let's try it
manually
plot psi
x then x from negative seven
to seven enter okay
i think that's a bug jesus
[Laughter]
natural language processing that that
doesn't work
for some reason i have to figure it out
okay i have to show all results
input interpretation okay and
and okay it actually plots it
but then
wait can i actually adjust this
uh i should be able to but something is
wrong i'm not sure i never used this
before but anyway
so let's go back so if you have
questions posted okay i'd love to see
you
hi uh victor okay
so how do you get it for free first of
all so you go to my website
very easy okay so let me show you you go
to just go to my website
sardi dot info
and you go to programming you go to
programming tutorials
you go to wolfram language then you know
here's one of the video i did on wufang
language you know two of them
actually is three by now you know i'm
beginning to update this
uh page so then here is how do you get
wufang language for free so you can buy
either buy a raspberry pi it's included
the full version okay
uh but you can only run it on raspberry
pi
or you can uh download you know for free
the wolfram engine the wolfram script
it's free actually uh in fact i
recommend you just buy it okay so copy
that
back to emacs let me write down
uh how to get wu from language for free
yeah okay
so i did three videos before let's go
over the topic and let me show you okay
so now let's talk about
this very interesting uh uh
computational geometry problem i just
discovered today
you know i'm i programmed movement
language for like 10 years
mostly in the 1990s like i i read the 1
000 page documentation in fact that is
still good okay
you uh they don't sell it anymore but
you go to so i
uh the last printed book for wufang
language
is called the mathematica book
okay you go to amazon you type the
mathematica book
okay this one okay so the mathematical
book the fifth version i believe that's
the last one this
is uh and this is version four so
the mathematical book okay so when you
click on that
this is um so 18 used from 22.
this is like a thousand 200 pages this
thick okay it's
very heavy so in the 1990s
i read this book three times from cover
to cover from the first word preface
whatever
to the last word three times in
different years so i'm a master you can
well
yeah i'm a master of mathematica but i
haven't been coding mathematica for 15
years
the nature of the language doesn't
change okay mathematica
so uh do they have a picture you know so
you know you if you search online you'll
find a picture of this book
this thick uh so this book
actually i still recommend
it's cheap you know you can you you know
i still recommend it because
it uh if you read this book it
you'll learn the fundamentals the core
of mathematica you know since
since let's say year 2000 i mean before
year 2000
after year 2000 they just added tons of
new
um functions you know each function is
like a little
artificial intelligence program you'll
see okay let me show you let me start to
talk about that
why is mathematica i i call it
artificial intelligence language you
know building
so let me show you this very interesting
problem
uh wufang language notes okay these are
the kind of the
my to do things you know i'm writing
them down so there is this list contour
plot 3d okay
so uh let's go to wufang language so
this contour plot 3d uh let me show you
list con to plot 3d
okay let's go to the documentation but
so you are looking at the documentation
of the wufang language and by the way
this is exactly the same thing
if you go to the woofan language
documentation
web page it's exactly the same thing you
know you
i just have a local version
so i'm gonna tell you i'm going to tell
you how do you uh
you know which part to read because
there are too many you can read it for
a few years but first of all let me show
you uh this very interesting
uh thing so there's a building function
that's a list contour plot 3d
so what that does what does it do
so you give it a array uh
you know three dimensional array
basically your nested
uh you know just like a matrix okay 3d
make
three-dimensional matrix then it plots
it
you know it plots it as a contour
so so what that means is that you know
uh
let me show you okay so maybe i can show
you um
okay it'll take some time to
show these but but anyway let's evaluate
these okay
let me explain what these uh do
so basically basically you have a
let me first explain okay so basically
uh okay evaluate
so basically and then you can rotate it
so you you know
this is like an implicit plot by the way
but it's a three-dimensional implicit
plot
you know two plot is implicit functions
is uh
is hard okay it's a computational
geometry problem
good morning reaper good morning dizzy
i learned math in english uh when i was
like studying in my when i was 20 years
old
have you read an article about math
learning roadmap what to learn
uh first and next uh yeah but
um but can you run a wrapper for wolfram
in global emacs yes you can
there are several packages to do that
you know
it there was a package even in the 19
in year 2000 okay but over the years
uh there's a lot of change a lot of
change you know
in the 1990s wufang language actually
supports
emacs key binding you know this option
but they dropped that around 2005
because the
you know the the emacs people they be
they dwindled and drinker and dwindle
and
and in the 1990s it's fairly popular
for uh for for lots of applica you know
editors to support emacs key binding but
not
not today they they begin to remove it
around
uh 2005 also because either emacs
you know group they just shrinked
and by the way stefan wuform is also an
emacs user
he was i'm not sure today but he was in
the 1990s
so uh so they are still i i think they
are still
uh emac emacs packages that connects
to the wolfram language so you can code
inside emacs list but i i'm not sure how
robust
uh are they i don't think none of them
are very good
so uh anyway so
you know the reason you can do that is
because like i talked about last time
wufam language you know
it comes in two parts the kernel or
server you know it's
commonly known as server and the front
end front end is what you see
the notebook so front end whenever you
evaluate something it talks through so
it sends the information to the server
server replies then uh via wufam
language protocol that was used to known
as math link
but i think they changed the name it was
known as math link
okay that's a protocol for uh
for uh language communicating to the
front end and
and the server the kernel it's called
kernel
so so you can write you know you can any
any ide you know in emacs in veeam even
i
i suppose if veeam script can do that i
mean
in basically uh in vs code
you can write you can you can write the
interface to
from language you know using the math
link protocol whatever it's called today
so anyway so so let me show yeah let me
explain this thing okay so
this thing is a yeah let me just explain
okay so this
this function what's interesting about
this function this
function involves a okay or rather
it involves a lot computational geometry
okay let me put this way you you could
implement this function it will take you
a year okay
it will take you a year just to
implement this
one function to to plot this thing
uh how is it so it's a lot of different
uh computational geometry knowledge
involved you you need to do it
efficiently
so efficiently so so so what does this
do is that you have a
um so you given
you are given a three-dimensional matrix
okay let me show you the matrix
okay let's just show it okay so this
actually generates a matrix
uh let me show you okay so here's the
expression x squared y
squared minus z squared and
plus a random number so they you know
why do they put that because
i guess they put that you know they add
a little random numbers
to jiggle them a little bit so it
actually shows the power of this
function the
the function actually we will find the
nearby points and connect them into a
surface
but anyway so so this expression is just
basically x
plus x squared y squared squared minus
z squared and that if you set that
equals to zero what you get is this cone
okay
you know very sharp clear double coil
actually we can plot that
uh yeah plus 3d i think
um
you know it's been a while i uh
use mathematica so i have two yeah like
i suppose
these um
no not plot 3d because this this is kind
of a
implicit yeah so you see anyway so
here's the expression okay
you know that if you said that equals to
a constant
so you get a equation of three variables
x
y z and to find the solution the
solution
solution set if you plot it it's going
to be a you know double cone
so they added a little bit random number
but anyway so this
expression if you want to generate a
matrix you
you can use this table function so here
x
goes from negative 2 to 2 instead of
in steps of 0.2 and similarly for y
and z okay so let's evaluate it so you
got
huge number of uh a huge
number of output that's why you see
these
kind of uh condensed you know output so
let me let me do a
little let's say
in step of 0.5 so we're going we don't
get that
huge uh output
so that you can actually see the
structure so here
is the matrix three-dimensional matrix
basically you have basically it's
just a nested list okay so for example
this is the uh one
one row of the list you know 3d list so
it's nested twice so you got a bunch of
uh points uh not you know
a bunch of values not points so you know
3d matrix you you got a bunch of
values so you uh you want interpreted
you know each
each value has an index for example
first element is one
second element is two now so for example
this one
the index for this number is one one one
because
that's of in the first um because that's
the first
row and inside this row
it's the first
you know another dimensional row and
inside this row
it's the first item so the index for
this number is one one one
uh the index for this number is one one
two and so on and for this one is
one one one two one okay so each element
in the 3d
array has a index so an
index is three numbers so the three
numbers you can consider them as
coordinate in 3d space
x y z so essentially what you get is a
you know you get
you got a space 3d space that
each grid point is a value okay so all
these values
correspond to you know figure out the
space in a cube now in order to so
that's a 3d matrix okay 3d array
whatever you call it in different
languages
now in order to so so what this function
does you know this contour plot is that
so you you it takes a 3d matrix you know
like what do
we had a 3d matrix a bunch of numbers
that feels a space you want to find out
first the first job is to find
all the numbers that have the same value
okay
you want to find all the numbers that's
the same value or approximately the same
now
this thing alone you know you can write
this in python
you know not too difficult you know in
an hour but
to do this efficiently that's
not that's not a trivial problem because
essentially you have to compare each
number to every other number
and repeat so it's exponential if you do
it in a
uh you know brute force way so first
problem
if you is that you have to find
you know given a thousand potentially
thou tens of thousands of numbers you
have to find
all uh you know in other words
equivalent
equivalent class you have to categorize
the numbers so that you know you
you have to find all the numbers that
are the same now the
that's the first step you know not
easy to implement efficiently the second
step is that you want to
if two numbers okay so if two numbers in
this matrix
have the same value uh for example that
can we find it no it will be hard to you
know
for example this number is 5 you know
maybe there's another number that's also
5.29 something if the
if two numbers are the same you want to
see
if they are adjacent you know you know
you want to see if they are adjacent to
each other if they are
then they kind of form a connection if
you know you want to see if they are
connected if they are not adjacent they
are they are not now how do you tell if
they are
adjacent you know basically you tell by
the matrix
index because remember these numbers
correspond to
you know like grid points in the
in in in this cube so you want to find
which numbers are adjacent the same
numbers are adjacent and that's
again that's a a very computational
intensive
problem that's also that you know in
computational geometry you study this
so that's the second thing then after
that suppose
then after that you got a bunch of
numbers that you know
should represent this cone you know 3d
coordinates
each you know each number is not
actually a coordinate each number is
just a number
but but their index forms the
coordinates so so after
so after that you got a bunch of uh
basically dots
points you want to draw a surface and
how do you do that that's another
computational geometry problem you got a
bunch of numbers they form
a surface you want to mesh you you want
to create a mesh out of it
so let's see uh for example let let's do
a
one with mesh okay so you can actually
see the mesh
you know okay they they do the mesh in
another
in a different way but typically it's
triangulation okay so you
for every three points you want to
connect them and that's not easy
so so that is the that is this is what
this function does
you know so uh
so that's what i'm talking about that's
uh that's experience that
uh okay so uh how long have i been
talking 51 minutes
i gotta go in 20 minutes
i didn't even begin to talk about lots
of the
things i want to talk about
okay so so okay let me continue with
this then
now so you got this list contour
plot okay now there is another one
that's actually more
complex you know one step more
difficult let's go to home
let's go to
visualization and graphics okay data
visualization
then you know you have tens of functions
that does plot
uh so i want to show you
so i just showed you this list contour
3d then let me show you another one this
contour
okay now the next function this one okay
this
contour plot list slice
contour plot 3d so basically you now you
have a contour
uh you have a contour you know basically
a
a plot of a implicit
equation with three variables
now this is more advanced you know this
now now you want to
slice it with a plane then you want to
draw the contours on the plane
so so what does that mean well it means
you have one
suppose you have one surface in 3d space
then you have another plane that
intersects the surface
so basically what you want to do is you
want to find the points of intersections
and draw that intersection as a curve
on the plane so that's what this
function is about
this list slice
contour plot 3d okay and but
not just that the you know the
intersection the plane
can be can actually be any surface
so basically you have a surface then you
have another surface
they intersect
then you can you you can use this
function to plot it
and the other intersections will become
curves on this uh you know on this
surface
so that um so that's my you know that
that's very interesting that
so this is you know one of the 6 000
functions in mathematica that's what i
why i say that mathematica is kind of
kind of um gather you know how the set
the way stefan wufran put it would be
the knowledge base
you know knowledge base means
computation something like that
basically it embodies you know
the the ufam language embodies all
knowledge essentially oh okay well or in
a practical sense
embodies all computational knowledge
that is whatever
all the algorithms we know if it's
useful
it's already in language for example um
you know you might heard of you know
coding problems
interview coding problems like like
for example the linear distance
uh that computes the distances
between strings something like that okay
so you have several
articles on that
i spelled it wrong
hey wait there's a wikipedia article on
that okay
there is there it is
uh okay revenge
ten distance revenge then distance is a
way to calculate
how different two words uh
are from one another okay like sometimes
this is posted
posted as a interview uh problem you
know you have to be smart
to implement that but you know so so
this is one of the algorithm
about strings and using i believe it is
in wufang language okay
so let's try it
uh no lev and
okay i don't see it uh
okay
let me let me do this okay uh oops
what did i do is type
multiply wait wait is multiply sign
okay that's wrong
okay i i don't see that levy sevilla
tensor
whatever that is uh
levy civita tensor gives the
the dimensional levy sivatar totally uh
anti-symmetric cancer tensor is
basically
like a multi-dimensional matrix
levee distribution represents a levy
levy distribution i don't know what that
is
so but anyway this shows some of the
examples
of you know let's look up wikipedia what
what the hell is levy distribution now
let's
first of all see the documentation okay
levy distribution you know some yeah
some some distribution in statistics
okay so in now i'm pretty sure there
is a uh wikipedia article
on that but
it may use a different name sometimes
the you know
the choice of naming is different oh
there it is file every distribution png
now where is this used
okay interesting there is no um
there's actually no english version
of this distribution there is uh french
polish something something uk
uh wait what is the russian there's no
english article on this
anyway so so that's why i say wufam
language is you know embodiment you know
it's kind of a
ai language construction okay let's go
on to the next topic
okay let's see what the next thing i
want to talk about i need to go
in like in like 20 minutes
okay how do how to learn wufang language
show stefan wufam's tutorial yeah okay
so
okay so back to language you know how um
you know 6 000 functions where do you
begin
okay first of all you
can use wufang language as a fantastic
graphics calculator okay just you know
they categorize their functions into
fields
for example if you are interested in
sound and video sound generation
uh let's say sound okay you know play
display sound sound notes okay let's
let's go sound okay you can
okay so sound note c that plays the note
c
c and g okay i don't know if you can
hear it can you
hear it let's see
let me play it again uh
yeah you can hear it and then you can
also give a function
uh you know a wave function so here is a
sine wave which is a pure function
you know they actually they they play
two different uh
waves so let's play it let's evaluate
[Music]
so this is kind of so you can imagine
this as a
fundamentals of a synthesizer so you can
actually start to write a program
to build your own frequency modulation
synthesizer or addictive synthesizer
you know you can do that in fact there's
a blog
someone uh actually did it you know so
you're
you know if you have a woofing language
you can create you know you can write
your own synthesizers because
you know these functions are building so
that's why i say you know
have you ever seen a language that does
that no
you know not haskell not not the fancy
haskell not erlang you know that
of course they have different purposes
rust you know judea but wufam language
is kind of the
giant engine that includes everything
you know you just see
sit here like in my power station and
you just
you can compute almost every anything
that's
practically uh in a language
so so sound function so what else i want
to say
okay so so so i was saying you know so
first of all you can just play with
language you know
you know you look at the you know
different categories
visualization uh you know like
i just did you know i i i'm trying to
get a
you know because i haven't been coding
language for like 15 years seriously
so i i wanted to get an overview what
what is new
you know so i started to look you know
in detail
in the you know the whole documentation
and visualization is one of my primary
interests
so i started to look so so one way
easily you know you can just explore you
know just different
um things sound videos so if you are in
uh interested in for example uh
here is image manipulation you can
actually build a photoshop
with code uh
you know this this is new i haven't used
any of these but
any image manipulation higher
mathematical computation
now this is a kind of the traditional
computer algebra system you can solve
linear algebra tensor algebra
polynomial algebra you know whatever
degree 10th degree polynomial
real complex analysis you know uh
integral
and so on discrete calculus
iterated maps and fractals neural
networks there it is you know ai
probability theory and so on so that's a
category of
math which is the classic
uh purpose of mathematica wufam language
so uh string and text you know here is a
category
you programmers or system admin are
interested you know
all about manipulating strings and
actually
you know i discovered the wolfram
language is regular expression is
is i i don't want to say it now because
i haven't actually looked into
in detail but i i got an impression it's
far more
powerful than regular expression yeah
pearl whatever
because because anyway i'm not going to
get into because i haven't
you know i'm not too sure i only looked
at
it you know i got you know uh for a
minute
so uh graphs and networks if you are
into graph theory
here is you know graph theory stuff
let's see graph plot
so given any graph you can plot it and
you will automatically figure out how to
arrange the points
so that it came out something
easy to read so you have uh
you have tree plot
uh you know you know i know there are
packages doing that
and and you know doing this it's not
easy again it
it's not trivial okay it's a another um
yeah layout of graphs it's computational
geometry problem
you know you are given a graph okay you
can actually
manufacture you know so this is a graph
so how do you represent a graph
basically you give you give a list of
labels then you give a list of edges
each
basically array okay each element of the
array
is two labels that represent an edge
edge of a graph so you just a bunch of
data you know
you know a bunch of edges so that rivers
you know the
that represents which points are which
label or whatever
symbol you are connected to which like
each label can be a b
c d e f g you know each one of these not
is
you know a b c d f g you have you can
have thousands of them
then you have a list of data that says
which are connected to which so it's
just a bunch of data but you want to
show it you know
so how does mathematica know you know in
in the case of this
this particular graph it's symmetric you
know it has a
bilateral symmetry you know it's
it's it's uh it's a it's a non-trivial
problem
given the arbitrary graph to format it
for visual representation
in the best way you know so for this
graph
there are so many different
visualizations you can plot it like a
tree
or you you or you know in this case a
circular
so mathematica we actually automatically
figure it out
that's a you know that's another that's
what i mean by mathematica it's kind of
has
you know all the ai buildings so if you
um for example if you are a computer
scientist
a phd suppose you are a phd in computer
science
you know in computer science you there
are so many subfields
you know computational geometry graph
theory you know
so you have x x you have lots of
algorithms you know finding the path of
a graph and so on
and also representation of a graph
and you know you can go to wikipedia
then you'll see hundred articles about
graph theory and algorithms
so the point about mathematica is that
you know if there's algorithm known
it's building okay so so how does
mathematica know
to plot this this way because you know
it has algorithms it
and it automatically choose
using ai kind of ai to choose the you
know represent representation for you
so that that's what i mean so so first
of all to in order to learn mathematica
you know the 6 000 functions you can
just
explore all these okay then let me tell
you
two um let me tell you
two two things to learn systematically
now as a programmer okay one of the way
okay when you look at this page the the
thing
you really want to understand
as a programmer is this the first part
core language and structure okay
uh again there's so many so let's begin
with language overview so this is as a
programmer this is this part
is what you want to uh go
through if you want to if you
if your goal is to master mathematics
i mean that's the wolfram language i
mean first of all you play with it you
know
you look at all the fancy functions
which is
vast majority of math you know wolfen
language users do you know they are
scientists you know they are not really
usually they are not programmers
you know they just want to you know they
have lots of data they just want to
visualize it
or do computations so you you try a
function
and there are a lot of examples you know
you just you just try it
and usually you know so that's first
thing you look around
then but if you really want to master
mathematica you plan to
really know it well as a programmer
this part is what you want to know you
want to dive in depth you want to
understand
each and uh yeah basically each and
every
of these functions in this uh core
language
stroke and structure okay basically
the first one okay um that's what you
want to go through
so that's one thing for programmers if
you want to really master mathematica
now if you
now again now now if you are a
programmer but you don't
really you know you are beginner
programmer okay
what do you do to uh
to get the introduction okay so what you
do is you follow this
um this tutorial written by wufam
himself
okay let me show you where
uh fast introduction to fan language no
that's not what i want
that's not um
let's see um this
rule and patterns okay let's try that
i'm i'm trying to find you
the
the book okay the easiest way is just
search for stefan
wolfram tutorial
okay
oh yeah that's the one uh wait
no that's not the one okay here here
okay
an elementary introduction to oofam
language
okay this this um the page you are
looking at the fast introduction for
programmers
i'm not sure it's a uh
i'm not sure it's um
very good no is it very bad i don't know
i
you know i but actually what i recommend
is this one
an elementary introduction to wufam
language and
in fact he sent me a copy like five
years ago
when he when he wrote this
so and i recommend this book okay you
just go through
chapter one two three if you are a
programmer you can go through very fast
you know uh
five minutes for each chapter or three
minutes
you know go through this one okay stefan
wu from an elementary introduction to
the wufang language
so in summer in summary to learn
mathematica
there are a few ways one is
that you just explore like play with it
as a
fantastic giant graphing calculator you
just play with it
you know just click on what area you are
interested in just try it
that's one way so first first of all you
do that you get you get a feel of what's
a notebook and so on
then the second way is to study this
this book wufam language an elementary
introduction by wufa
then another way then after that you
want if you really want to master
mathematica
uh study this part okay call language
structure
now this this is the part that basically
haven't changed uh for
30 years they added a few
you know they added like 10 or 20 new
uh new conditional constructs you know
but basically it's the same
mathematica i know i know of anyway i
don't have time to explain today i have
to go
actually so any questions any
questions and comments
okay five more minutes i'm going to
close so i i you know i because i have
to go
so because otherwise i'm going to
actually teach you
the fundamentals of mathematica as for
programmers okay
you know because because i've been
coding it for 10 years i also
work at wolfram for a while in 1995 so i
um the language is essentially
you know the nature you know the
construct how do you program you know
it's essentially the same
they just added two they just added
three
three thousand more ai functions like
one function
you know you know some of these
functions like for example we showed the
this contour plot
how many lines of that is in haskell
ten thousand okay yeah that's true
how many lines to write this in haskell
ten thousand yeah not enough 20
000 okay just for this function you have
to write 20 000
lines of haskell now if
that's not even including graphics
functions i mean haskell doesn't you
know most languages
doesn't have built-in graphical api they
cannot show a graph like that you know
if you count the graphic graphics stuff
that's like 10 million
you know 1 million lines of code right
away
but we let's let's not count that let's
just say
to be able to find the points that's the
same you know a bunch of points that
forms a mesh
you know to do that it has got uh yeah
20 000 or
maybe ten thousand lines of code in asco
and you see it's one thousand one
hundred thousand lines of code
so that's why and mathematica has has
fixed
you know that's why each function in
mathematica is kind of
very condensed you know that lets you do
prototype or some idea about sound of
about visualization about
you know getting info information from
statistics
or artificial intelligence research you
know prototype
you know machine learning um that's why
it's
incredible okay incredible let me let's
look at some of the
uh questions post questions okay i'm
gonna
shut down have you ever used
mathematica industry for just uh or just
for fun
well i of course i
you know wufang language they they are
in a different industry
then programming okay i gotta go you
know in most programming languages
python let's i gotta go
my alarm clock went off let me talk
four or five minutes okay so you most
likely like golan
cc plus first what's their industry well
uh you know see for example writing
operating systems
embedded devices uh you know linux
kernel
or driver smart driver you know you need
c
you know or c like languages rust for
example
uh what about c plus plus well some of
them you can do with c
plus plus but usually not then c plus
plus is
often used for you know gaming gaming
you know you write 3d game
engines right and gold line is kind of
similar okay
uh and rust you know just you know
kind of also fits that wheel now
for python ruby bash what they you know
what's their industry usually web
programming is
usually higher level web programming
prototyping
uh you know or artificial or interface
to artificial intelligence for example
google has
quite a few neural networks or machine
learning
libraries they are usually written in c
or java you know
but the the interface to them is usually
python
so python will ruby or bash you know
you know python ruby are they are good
they're higher level they are you know
they you can write a web application
you can write interface with them that's
basically their industry
you know you don't you don't write the
operating system with python okay
almost never uh
then so in a similar way mathematica has
it you know so what ways mathematical
use you know you you it's not right you
know you don't use mathematica to write
operating system it's not low level
you don't use it to write a game engine
you don't use to write
right so what do you use it for
it's usually not used by programmers
it's used by
well today a lot of programmers let me
explain okay but mostly it's used by
mathematicians
physicists engineers engineers in
diverse fields in
geology biology biochemistry
in chemistry in physics you do research
you have lots of data from nasa you know
space
stars you know telescopes data you want
to
analyze the data that's what you know
mathematica is for or if you are an
engineer you are building a car
you are designing a new engine you want
to prototype or you want to
uh have a heat you know
if suppose you are building a you know
the engine for a
jet you know jet fighter you know huge
um
uh how do you call those engines uh
turbines you know you want to
model or you want to model whether you
know science
science and engineering that's that's
the scientists and
engineers that's the people that's where
wolverine language
is used in typically not programmers but
beginning around year to year uh 2010
lots of programmers as well because why
because
machine learning artificial intelligence
neural networks
you know google is you know very big
with it you need you know programmers
started to
for example today there are quite a few
jobs of data science you know
where you don't just you know you are
not you know you have to be a
mathematician statistician
but you also have to code coding is
actually part of your main job you have
to code
a lot so
so that's where mathematica is used
these days by programmers as well high
level programmers not
not the typical see just
those type of people guys who talk about
memory and
indian float all the time
okay that's it for today i gotta go so
thank you guys for watching
by my tutorial so donate patreon me if
you
uh like my stuff and again you can
um you know i got wufang language for
free
you can get well because they send it to
me okay so
and uh but you can also get it for free
uh you know
[Music]
uh very cheap or free so i have a link i
talked about it in the
beginning of my video where's my link i
don't have the link but anyway
so thank you guys for watching bye guys
uh okay i'm shutting down in one minute
any more questions
so yeah in 1990s i do visualization kind
of
if you want to say you know the question
is do have i ever used
for industry yeah i wrote lots of
programs for example i showed in my last
video or these programs
basically you can say they are in
educational industry
let me show you my let me show you my
first
most popular project
visual dictionary of
playing curves so this is a math
education industry you can say that so i
wrote all this this is 1997.
i wrote all these in wolfen language
they tell you
lots of the properties
of curves you know they especially
visually so you can easily understand
for example this
curve there are quite a few spirals you
know this
this one is archimedean spiral this one
is equal angular spiral
this one is called liters liters is
interesting because you can see
uh let me magnify okay so you can see
it's used in you know it's a model of
the
pope's arch bishop
corsia it's this thing is called corsia
so it has
history and it's also you know the
violent squirrel
are modeled after this curve so if you
are building a violent you know if you
are a carpenter building a
how do you how do you create this thing
well mathematics okay this is this curve
is called liters
uh and you know this formula so so i
wrote this mathematical programs
to kind of for math education you know
when you are studying calculus so you
can easily see oh
oh you know once you see this oh you
really you understand it right away
lots of properties so there are
different spirals
how they differ for example this one you
all this one you you also see very
uh very popular you see it all the time
like all the
especially all the memes let me show you
some you know for example
seashells or this cauliflower you know
this uh
fractal cauliflower this actually you
can buy
uh you know and the growth of seashells
okay
you know so uh and this page
the mathematics of seashell this this is
again plotted with mathematica
uh back in 1995 okay so i wrote this
uh so so what so what's special about
this spiral why is it
like what do you mean equal angular this
this this one is called equi-angular
spiral also
known as logarithmic spiral
uh a bit history and description uh why
is it equal angular because
if you draw a line from the center
you know the chord the center or pole of
the spiral
you you draw a line okay
then the line will always always
across the curve in a d
in a degree in an angle that's constant
doesn't matter where the line is it'll
be constant everywhere
so this curve is actually there's a
family of them all these any
any one of these uh or equal angular
spiral so they just have different
constant you know the angle is different
for each one of them
so you draw a line you know for any one
of them they'll be
the same angle every for any line so
that's why it's called equiangular
and and there's lots of properties and
famous
stories you know one of the
mathematician uh who's this name history
who who died you know when he said you
know when he died he says
you know when i die on my grave i want
the tombstone
that says i shall rise the same though
changed
okay that is you know in
in latin i don't know how do you know
jacob bernoulli one of the famous
mathematician
uh in 1600s
uh so i don't think you can actually see
the tom stone
okay you actually you know on wikipedia
you'll see it
uh yeah there's a tome stone but yeah
yeah so here is a
uh john jonathan jacob
jacob bernoulli's tom stone you know you
can see an equi angular
you know back then you know so all these
properties how do you how do you know
well
you know in 1500 mathematicians study
and you know
studied it it doesn't come free you know
today it's very easy to explain and so
on but before you don't know
so anyway so that's one of my projects
so technically it would be
in educational math education industry
and archimedes spiral is also very
interesting
it's a spiral such that the growth you
know the length of this
uh how do you say the it's um
yeah the the turning rate of the spiral
is the same as the
arc length uh the constant ratio
something like that
you know i did this 25 years ago
uh so this is called archimedes why is
it archimedean because archimedes
you know the greek mathematician like uh
2000 years ago he knew this
he knew this and he created he actually
created
a device to um
to get the water is of something you
know you can
so this you know this today there's a
wikipedia article on
on any of these curves so they give they
have a lot of photos
and and history much more than what i
have
today uh so i did this in 1995 so that's
it for today um
okay uh
okay i gotta go thank you guys bye
uh where's the chat in stream