Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of talk show. We are going to code uh
Goland. We're going to code several
languages today. Go language and eaglist
and wam language. So what we're going to
do is we're going to create a hash
table. We're going to go through a
directory a directory of about 30,000
files. So for each file you know uh
create a hash table. The key is going to
be the full file path.
Uh full p file path like that. And the
value uh we're gonna ignore the value.
The value is just going to be one. Okay.
So we're going to do this in goline. But
also another important thing is that um
let me let me show you. Okay. Another
important thing is that we want to have
a list of directories to skip. So for
example, typically you have the git
directory and in that directory you have
like thousands of files. Um so you want
to you know given a list of a
directories you want to skip them. So
anyway you create a hash table then what
you do is that you go through each key
in the hash table you check if the keys
exist. Of course it it will it does but
we are we we'll do that to test the
speed. Okay. So we we write that in
Golam. Um then we write that in uh EMAC
list. Then we write that in Wufa
language. I hope we can finish this in
like 40 minutes or or more. Um
if you are watching offline, watch at
1.5 speed because I ramble. If you are
watching here, say hi. Hi. I don't know.
Fantastic. Okay.
Play at 1.5 speed and speak skip around
when you are watching offline. I'm just
going to go easy.
Happy July 4th. Today is July 4th. So
this is my tea
and uh red light. Why red light? You
know, I recommend, highly recommend you
go by red light because red light um
they uh they sooththe is your eye,
soothe is your brain. So after the sun
is set, turn on red light. It's very
good for you. Okay, so let's go back. Um
okay, so let's begin coding. Okay, let's
see. I you know I hope we can do this
like finish in 30 minutes or so. Okay.
So keyboard block we don't care. So okay
so um so this is uh keyboard block
close. Okay. So here is a code. So what
we are doing is that I have this code
already.
This is validate uh this this code in go
language is validate a website. So my
website is about uh 10,000 HTML files.
If you count image files, it's going to
be um it's gonna be like um 30,000 files
or more. Okay. So, so you go through bas
basically what you want to do is you
want you you want to find um you want to
find bad links for example a link like
that. Uh so let's de let let me
demonstrate that. Okay. So um so copy
the file path and go to my script. Uh
okay, close that. Okay, so here is the
script and go down and here you say
where do you want the uh the directory
to start checking. Okay, so let's put
that and remove that. So input directory
is going to be you know just let's just
check uh files in Goland. So run it. So
now done. So done in 0.3 seconds you
know it's checking this directory check
all HTML and XML files done in 0.3
seconds if there's any bad link you will
print it but so let's so there's no bad
link but let's try to create one okay so
um so what is this today's talk show uh
let's say uh something okay something
something a file
uh some file no exist. Okay, try to open
it. It doesn't exist. Okay, showing
browser. So there it is. So copy the
file path. Now go to the goland
uh close that. Go to the goline
directory. So paste the talk show
directory. Run it.
Uh okay. So now it says uh you know
finish in one second. Back links are
printed above. So this is a back link.
Now let's color it. Uh color it. So now
you can see. Oh god.
So you can see you can jump to it. Open
it. So it shows right there. So that
links does not it doesn't exist. So that
that is the um this goland script. So
can you know if you can go to my website
and you can find it. I just update it.
But this script is pretty slow. If I do
this on my website, uh it takes 40
seconds,
you know, the first run will take a
minute because the first run whenever
you do write whenever you write a script
that is disk heavy that access reads
file then it'll take a long time because
uh disk is very slow even if you have a
flash drive or have a flash drive. Uh
but the second time you run it then
everything is in memory so you can kind
of see it. So the second time will be
fast. So even in in uh if everything is
in memory uh this script will still take
like 40 sec 30 seconds. I saved 10
seconds. So I was trying to uh speed it
up. So anyway, let's go to what we have
to do today. Okay. So let's uh let's
let's just uh
that is the reason you know trying to
why are we creating a hashmap? because
I'm trying to speed up because one of
the issue in Goland is that uh in Goland
uh let me show you. So there is no
function that checks if file exist. You
have to write your own and basically the
way basically there's no function that
checks if a file exist. This function
exists in emacis in python and in wan
language in others but not in golan. So,
but if you want to check if a a file
path, you know, the file exists, you
have to write a function yourself like
this. And and basically, you just you
just try to, you know,
try to uh get the information from that
file and if that file doesn't exist, you
get error. Then if there's an error, you
return, you know, you return it says,
you know, so basically there's no way to
check file exist. I don't know why. uh
that's a technical details for uh imp
you know uh programming file system
implementation
I don't know why so anyway so I was
wondering if this this thing you know
check file exists is slowing things down
because every HTML page you have 10 or
20 30 links to other file for each link
you have to find the full path and check
that file exist so you are coding this
like you know uh 30 100,000 times. So I
was wondering if it's faster if you just
create a hash table of of all files in
your directory then just check the hash
key exist. So you know that's my guess.
I don't know for sure. So this is one of
the possibility this file is slow. So
anyway let's but but let's start to
write uh what we have to do. Okay. So
let's start a goland. Uh and uh and
basically yeah so let's start a goland
go. Uh so what are we doing is we are
doing this copy. Uh any questions
comments say it. Okay. Hello GCS. Okay.
So so this is
um
okay. So uh so create a hash table.
Okay. So let's begin to code it. So we
want to create a hash table. Uh I
haven't coding I haven't been coding uh
Goland for like um several years. So I
don't remember. So Goland,
but I have a tutorial. So let's see uh
search for it. You'll find it.info.
Goland tutorial. So how uh so we want to
check go to data structure. So we copy
it. Go to data structure map. in Golan.
It's called map. Close that. Uh go to
talk show. Uh yeah. So link it. Okay. So
we're gonna do Goland and we're going to
do Wuam language later on. Okay. So
Wufam language tutorial. Search for it.
You'll find it on.info and uh and wam
language for programmers. There's also a
hasht.
So close that. Uh so wam language and
we're going to do emac. Okay. So
actually why don't we uh go to the hash
table directly. So Golan map. So in
Golan hash table is called map
now in uh
wait
ah god we got to do this faster. Okay.
So, so now in wolfen language it's
called association list. Data structure
associ association list. Okay. And in
eac list
it's called um it's called hasht. Okay.
So uh vector sequences hasht. Okay. So
we going to uh write in all these
languages. Can I finish it? I hope so.
Uh let's let's do quickly uh master
coding fast. We need to master coding
this. Okay. So uh yeah. So anyway, so uh
okay go uh yeah. So that's why. Okay. So
now Golan here and go language hasht go
language. Uh
God, why why are we
uh
okay? I need to reorder the links. Okay,
that's why I'm a bit fussy. Okay, so
Golan map this hasht wam language
association. Um okay, so now wait. So go
to So how do you do map in Golan? All
you have to do is um just that.
Okay. So, uh create a mash uh create a
hasht
uh hasht map of key string and integer.
Okay, that's fine. And now we want to
traverse a directory. So, how do you
traverse a directory? I don't remember.
So, let's see. Uh walk directory. Okay,
in in Golang walking d uh directory is
fairly complicated. Okay, so you can
check out my tutorial. But basically
what you need to do is you need to it's
it's fairly complicated. Okay. So let me
just copy the code here.
Uh well god
okay so so goland worker directory. So
let's see. So you need uh oh god you
need okay. So
package main then you need to import um
you need to import all that. Okay. So we
are dealing with static languages which
is always a bit tedious. Okay. So this
is input direct directory um input
directory go through a directory and
print a file name extension. Okay. So we
don't need this men.
Okay. So delete that delete that. So
that is the global variable extra. Okay.
So this is how you work a directory. So
this is a hash table. Let's comment it
out yet.
Uh do function. So let's rename it uh do
file.
Uh let's change it to file. Okay. So so
work directory to worker directory. So
here is our main. Okay. So uh got this.
Okay. We need to finish this fast. So
you can you can see here is a main and
uh and this is a function to uh so in
order to walk a directory what you need
is uh is basically this block and uh
this this this is the line. Okay, file
path work you file path is a
is is a uh package you load. Okay. So,
um
what
is going on? Cancel that.
Yeah. File path is a package you load.
So, you say file path work and you give
a directory path and you give a
function. Now, you have to write this
function. Now the complicated part is
that this function
uh what
this function uh okay do file this
function is uh takes three arguments and
they meet they needs to be this type
string info uh of the type file system
entry and x and error okay so uh goline
is a compile language that's why so you
need to declare io slash FS file system
to get this the entry type. So anyway,
so if error is neo so um
so let's write this quickly. So okay
so walk the and you need this function.
This function takes um three argument
the file path the
the info the entry info and errors. So
this work will pass the argument to this
do file function. Okay. Uh so check
error. So if there's a error then just
print and exit. Okay. Otherwise uh
otherwise say we are traversing this
path then find out then find out if it's
a directory or file. So if it's a
directory just print is the okay
otherwise print the file name extension.
Okay that's how you do it. So can we run
it? Yes, I think so. So right now this
just traverse a directory. Okay. So now
where's the directory? Uh right now
that's JavaScript. Let's just run it.
Okay. Fantastic.
Okay. So for each file you got the path
then this is the directory name file
name extension the path directory name
file. So this is working perfect. Okay.
So now but we don't need uh to print all
that. We need the hash table. So now
declare a hasht uh file um
table. Okay, let's name it e x file
table.
Uh okay. Okay. So that's a hash table.
Then then how do you add hasht? So okay.
So let's go to talk show.
Uh today's talk show Golan
uh that's yeah okay so hasht is right
there so
so how do you add a hash table you just
create map with make uh so
syntax for wait concentrate syntax for
map type uh create map literal
expression okay so you can create you
know you can do it with literal
expression Then uh create map with make
um
then okay so this is how you add an
entry. Okay close that
uh go to our code
go to our code.
So this is how you add. So okay cut
that. So for this function if it's a
directory do we do we want to add the
directory? No. Okay. So if if it's a
directory ignore otherwise
we want to add it. Okay. So um x file
table
um
then uh then use uh then directory file
path. Okay. Uh no directory
name.
Okay. So, which one is it?
Okay. I
don't know what is it. Okay. So
I think S show in desktop doesn't work
when there are
when there are spaces in a file path.
Oh, okay. So you need to um
uh you know if you file a bug report
that's about Emacs then then we'll fix
it or or contact me in Discord.
But let's but let's focus on this right
now. So
so file path X path the file name. So
okay. So
X path.
Okay. So
no. Okay. So X path is the entry. Okay.
So now add the entry to uh
so we don't want this print. Cut it.
Find out it's a directory or file. So if
it's a directory ignore. Now how do you
ignore I forgot how when you ignore how
do you um like what value do we have to
put there empty just you can leave it
empty that's right this is not emac this
or functional programming so anyway so
so if it's a file then you add
the file path and just value one okay so
comment that out you don't want that.
Okay. So,
okay. And the directory, we don't care.
File name,
uh, remove it. That's how you get the
name and the extension. Okay, we don't
care.
Okay, that's right. Uh, undefined X file
table. What?
Oh, we commented out. That's right. So,
this the the name is not so good. Let's
see. Uh X table. Okay. Let's just say X
table.
Uh
okay. Run it.
Okay. You got arrow uh
means something
X table path. So why is the it's a map
stream int.
It's a
what
Go um line 32 I guess. So this is
creating a problem. Why why is that?
So wait is it because of that?
Uh no
uh panic assignment to entry in neo map.
Assignment to entry in neo map. So how
do you do a hasht?
What?
Oh.
Oh, that's right. Wait, how did I uh Oh,
yeah. We forgot the We got it wrong.
Okay, so this should be
That's right. Run it.
Okay, so this is Easter.
Remove it.
Run it. Fantastic. Now we created hasht.
Now how do you print hasht? Let's print
hash table. Okay. Um,
uh, what is this? Uh, okay. So, so leave
that. Okay. So, now print hasht. So, now
we need to, uh, loop through hasht.
Okay. So, copy that.
You know, static languages got this main
thing and got this package. you know
those are annoying
because you have like so-called boiler
templates.
So okay how do you print hash table?
Okay so for key value in hash table x
table then uh then that's how you print
it. Okay. So,
so yeah. So, we got key and value. Okay.
So, that's how you print hasht.
Fantastic. Okay. Fantastic. So, this is
all these are all my JavaScript files.
Uh that's right. So, we
basically we done. So, oh there's one
more thing. So we need to uh specify
what uh file path names to
skip. Okay. So I already have the code
somewhere here. So let's copy it. So
let's use this
to skip. Okay. So you need that.
So if the file name matches one of
these, skip it. Okay. Uh yeah.
Okay. So how do you do it? Um you have
to write a function. So let me just um
find it. Okay.
Kind of. Yeah. So you have to write it
is string in array. So let's just copy
that.
Okay. So here is a function
string in array given a string and given
array. So if
return true if x equals to any of y
uh
okay so then so it's just the directory
name.
So you need to
yeah you need to so you need to get the
directory. Okay. So let's go to my file
string in array um
okay local
string array where is it used so you
need to get the uh directory name that's
that's the space thing uh yeah okay so
that's how you call it
I haven't called it Um I haven't coded
um
Goland for like 3 years or something.
Okay. So close it. So So now let's go to
the traverse. So if is a directory.
Yeah. So if it's a directory
then if
the directory name
is one of these the two skip
then
simply return this. Okay. So so where is
this? Okay. So you need to be careful.
So file path. So
um
so where is this? What is this file
path? So this file path is from
oh that's the package name. No. Okay. So
good. Um so close that. So this file
path is just a package name package
name.base.
So if it's a directory and it's one of
these the to skip and just skip it.
Okay.
Okay. So
before we do that okay and uh
let's run it.
Okay. Now check if there is a a
directory. Yes. Because this I
is all images. You see this I is all
image. This is image directory for my
JavaScript. So when you so and it's
actually got you know so there's a lot
of
um there's a lot of you know it it went
through all the image directories for
example uh
you know so so but now we if it's a if
it's Um,
yeah. So, we can kind of check that.
Okay. Okay. Let's let's test test this.
Okay. Go to talk show. Copy the file
path. Close it. And now, uh, let's test
this talk show file path.
Okay. Now, okay. Remove that. So, run
it. Okay. So we see
um
uh 2,00 lines of you know 2,000 lines
and uh this backslash let's change it to
forward slash that like be um you know
on the windows um
let's change it to forward slash okay so
how do you change the slash there is
this uh function. Okay. So, let's go.
Uh did we just close it? Yes. Okay.
Damn.
So, we want to
So,
right now, fireworks is going. Happy
July 4th.
Uh right now it's 9:00, 9:30 in
California. So fireworks is going. So
file path uh two slash okay then clean
uh clean.
Now clean just means you know remove
remove extra dot dot slash you know
remove redundant you know clean the file
path. But however the file path is what
whatever the native
uh file path syntax for example on
Windows it's backslash.
So you want to change it to slash
because that unifies it. You know the
backslash and slash is very annoying
because when you run this on Windows on
the Mac you know it doesn't work on
Linux doesn't work. You have to you know
like your input you know you know
doesn't work. So you want to make it so
that it's always just slash. Okay.
So that's why so we we want to do this
to the file path. Okay.
And also since you know this just uh
let's make some uh clean up so that you
know so that in case if I give backslash
it will um
you know clean it up. Okay. So let's say
x do equals to um
uh
I don't want to name so this this way
just uh make sure it's always slash
uh
so this change extra to input the okay
uh change it to X input.
Okay, so now run it.
Okay, so we got talk show slash correct.
Now we want to skip the I directory. So
let's try it to see if this skip
mechanism works. I Okay, run it.
Okay, you don't see the slash I anymore.
Fantastic. So it's working. Fantastic.
Great. So we finished the goland part.
Now put it back. Syntax collect showing
browser. We finished the goland. Uh we
haven't tested. We need to go through
the script and to see if it exist
actually. So um
so but we can change that. Okay. Then we
need to measure the speed. Okay.
So you can see uh what we need to do is
described here
uh and also here. So the last part is to
go through the hash table. So go to the
bottom uh hash table for each key. Uh we
don't care about the value. We want to
check if it it exist. It's kind of
redundant but we are doing it for the uh
for the sake of testing speed. So,
Goland map, how do you check an item
exist? Okay. Uh, set value delete key.
Uh, where is it? Syntax for map type
create map little expression create map
with make get value.
When a key does not exist, the f first
value is the maps type zero value. Okay.
So that's just the syntax.
Okay. So that's so basically we just um
so key
X table
that key
if
that
equals to one
then good. Okay then then good just
print key don't print the value okay
else do nothing okay so so pify the code
fantastic okay
if the key value equals to one do that
it's okay so you know it's always exist
Good. Okay, that's fantastic. Now, how
do you check? How do you test the speed?
Uh, you know, we can God, it's already
40 minutes. Um,
uh, okay, let's, you know, let's, um,
keep going. So, uh, to check the speed,
we just do that. Okay. So,
so split the window. Go back to our
code. Uh so there start time and uh
uh I already have the code here. So
let's just use it here. Okay.
So start time is there and then at the
bottom you say end time equals time dot
now end time difference is end time sub
dot subtubract start time in seconds
then time span okay so run it run
okay so you undefined time oh you need
to load time so one of the
uh issues
okay fantastic time spent and 0.3
seconds. Fantastic. Okay, so put it
back. Syntax color. That's it for Golad.
Now, let's do emac this.
Oh,
increase the volume on my mic.
uh you know I think because of the
there's a upgrade of the um upgrade of
the OBS software I'm using and it seems
the volume decreased a little bit but
it's already at maximum and also my
microphone I already turned it to to
maximum and also actually it's very
close to my mouse so I think you know
maybe you need you can you try to
Check. Check.
You know,
I think I'm already at maximum, but I
can make it louder. But that's going to,
you know, that's like doing advanced
stuff.
I like the light in the background.
Okay. So anyway, so we we finished
Goland. Now let's um
let's do let's let's do the whole info.
Let's see how long it takes. Uh it
shouldn't print. I don't want it to
print. 3.5 seconds. Wow. So it's
actually very fast. Um
so where is it printing all that?
Oh, because of the hash table. Yeah, I
don't want it.
Uh, so if we don't do that, can we can
we do that? Yep. Oh, it's even faster if
you don't print it. Okay. So, anyway,
that's the uh that's the goland. Let's
do emac list. Okay.
Uh god emac this is you know I've been
doing emacs a lot so let's why not we
why don't we try wra language
uh that would be interesting okay uh
because emacs I I've done like tens of
videos about creating a hash table so
let's do wra language okay so um
so what we want to do is this okay
uh what
Oh uh wam language. Okay. So actually
create a hash table each key is that
then uh okay so hash table. So um so uh
what is the directory this? Let's let's
try that. Okay. So directory and also
another important thing is this uh to
skip
and okay. So so how do you Okay. So I
don't remember.
So let's see language tutorial. How do
you um so first of all you want to walk
directory. Okay. So walking a directory
is going to be
um data structure directory. So that
would be uh god I need to walk
um read file load file uh shell task
shell task. Okay, file path functions
work directory there.
Uh, so it's very simple. Okay, just file
names return a list of all files and
directories in the current directory.
Okay, that's so extremely um
simple. Okay, file names.
Uh, yeah. Uh, okay. So um input
the
okay so this this is input directory
then you just say file names
file list equals file list equals to
file names input directory and but we
want to filter some of them out. Okay.
So let's see string pattern. We want
every file except um
any of the patterns. So oh that would be
interesting. So
so there are several way to do it. One
way is simply just do this. Okay. So we
so simply do this and it should create a
list of files. So let's see. Uh yeah. So
let's just run it.
Starting wam language. It'll take a a
while for the first time.
Okay. So it says done. So uh does it why
doesn't it print? Okay. Yeah. Because
you put a semicolon. So now run again.
Uh
it's just one file. So input directory
file names input directory. So why is it
just one single file? Uh
file name string pattern. These files of
current whose name?
Uh
okay. Yeah. Oh yeah. So uh so you need
the string pattern and uh
Okay. So, so all you need to do is
actually say or here. Okay. Wait. Uh,
lower case there. Okay. There.
Okay. So, now you got like all the
names. Copy the buffer. New buffer.
Paste it. Now make it one line each. So
you can see it includes all files. Now
you you got this one key. the um
backslash and slash. Okay. So,
for example, that's a thumbnail to my
wait, for example, that's a thumbnail to
my YouTube. Um so, but that's how you do
it. So, it's done. Uh you know, 1,000
files, uh 1500 files. So, so you get the
close that. Now you now you can change
this all to a pattern to to the files
you want to skip pattern. Okay. So uh
you know
so you want to some kind of like um
you know skip those. So you need to um
let's see the documentation again. file
name string pattern. So you want a
string pattern
that
okay you want a negation of a string
pattern we can do that okay so let's do
that um so for example if you want to do
by extension that's all you have to do
but we want string pattern so let's do
that
string pattern can be regular expression
too I think the pattern can be wild card
pattern or regular expression. Okay. Um
Okay, let's try regular expression.
So copy
uh
okay so let's go to talk show uh today's
talk show and uh go to the top
uh
frame language traversal directory.
Okay. So,
okay. So, so what we going to do? What
we doing is that uh this is this is
check local links close. So, wam
language we are getting a list of file
names. Yeah, we want to do a string
pattern and uh uh list files
association. So how do you do string
pattern regular expression?
Uh so you can use string expression. So
let's use string expression to be u to
be um you know to be different. So, wuam
language supports regular expression
like the normal regular expression but
it also supports its own basically its
own syntax for regular expression. So
let's do this because not because this
is um would be interesting. It would be
novel.
So you want a string expression. Okay.
And uh okay. So this that's what you
want. Okay. So here you want string
expression. Okay. And what expression
you want? Uh you want some kind of not
uh wait.
Okay. So you got the pattern syntax
here.
Uh, and so what we want is we want a
expression that says not any one of
these.
Okay, not any one of these.
So
uh that would be interesting. So what so
uh
so let's just try a simple one. Let's
just say we we don't want the I
directory. So
okay, let's try that string expression
except
maybe a walk. Let's
uh
first of all let's try that.
Okay. So
then Okay. So
what the
What?
Okay. So you got the I directory
and uh wait what you are the I
directory.
Oh so it didn't it didn't dive into the
I directory. So
okay so it did not dive into so you want
to include subdirectories. So move from
list files.
Okay. So you want to dive into
subdirectories. So that's what you want.
Oh yeah, you need to specify a level.
Okay. So that's very interesting.
So instead of that here is the depth. So
you can say two or three or you can say
infinity.
Okay. Yeah.
Now run it.
Okay. Now make it each line uh you know
one item per line. So you can now you
can see all these
uh files in the I directory. So there's
a lot of you know JPEG files for example
SAS coid.
Okay. So, but now we want to skip the uh
I okay so which is
instead of all we use that instead okay
let's try run it
empty okay so this expression is not
correct um
uh except that.
So,
oh god, this is gonna take a long time.
This is not
uh because it's using backslash. Oh god.
So try this uh try that. Okay.
Empty. So
uh this
Why is that empty?
So, back slash
backslash.
Oh, so it only check the file name. It
doesn't check the um
is that right?
So this the first argument here
can be a pattern but that pattern only
match the file name.
These files of current whose name match
your string pattern. The pattern can be
a wild card or regular expression.
Right? So,
so the pattern is not checking against
the full file path. In other words, it
doesn't check the directory part. That's
why that's why this, you know, doesn't
work because it's not seeing
the directory.
So,
okay, that's, you know, that's fine. Uh
let's just do filter. Okay, now you got
a list of files. Now you just uh you
just want to filter. Okay, so how do you
filter? You can use cases
uh and others. So let's have a look. W
language. Uh okay, at this rate we're
not going to finish, but let's try. So
you want you got a list of things you
want to filter them out. So um
so that would go to that would be list
and list. Okay. So list you got list
position list level list operations.
Then you got filter. Okay. So you can
filter by a function
or you can filter by a pattern.
Uh filter list by pattern. Let's see.
uh this is symbolic pattern. Okay. So
yeah in the in our case our list every
item is a string. So
uh can this actually use a string
pattern? I'm not sure
literal expression uh filter element by
pattern. So let's look up the
documentation for cases.
So is this interesting?
So ACP's question why did you uh add a
path to a map? Because map is what we
want because we I uh because we need to
check if uh because many reasons. So
first of all in Golan there's no
function to check if a file exist there
basically none. you have to write your
own. But even if you write your own, you
rely on the error message. You check the
error. If the error is true, then you
know the file doesn't exist. So that's
kind of I don't know why is that.
Uh so
you can create a hashmap for list of
files and just check the key exist. That
way is you know a workar around to check
if a file exist without you know
checking the error trying to access the
file and get an error and check the
error. So that way it might be faster
too. So that's one of the reason you
create a hash table of files in all in
all directories instead of just a list.
Okay.
The other reason we want a hash table is
because we are writing a program auto
ultimately I'm writing a program to
check all file links in 10,000 HTML
files. Each HTML file has 10 or 30
links. Each link is a file path you know
pointing to another file. So you are
essentially checking file existence
10,000 you know 100,000 times.
So
when you have a hash table you know it's
very fast to check if the if if the file
path is already there. So you don't have
to check file existence. Okay that's so
that is the reason we are building hash
table. So anyway back to wufam language.
So uh so we are we want to know if you
know we got the list of strings we want
to know we want to filter the list. So
there are many ways you know. So one way
is you know one way is just filter by a
function. This is familiar to most
people in Python, in JavaScript, in
every language you create, you know you
can filter by a function. Okay. Uh
that's boring.
So I'm trying to see if we can use this
pattern matching uh in w language, you
know, just to demonstrate something
different. That's why I'm looking into
uh you know this. But the question now
is can this pattern be a textual
pattern? I don't think so. Okay.
Uh
yeah that's that pattern is symbolic
pattern which means basically your
syntax basically your expression. So so
let's not use that. Okay. So let's just
say select. Okay. Select um
okay select then file list okay so wait
so let's rename it because
when you have something in English it's
easier to complete and so on okay now
you need a function uh you need a
function and uh and this function will
be um we'll try to match the string okay
uh So you need a function. The function
the function takes okay so where is it
the function takes argument then the
expression is if that match okay string
match something string match or match
string okay so we need to go back to wam
language to to check for string function
we want to check match string string
match okay string start string ends
string match two. Okay. So that's you
know that's an example of using regular
expression. Okay. So
string match
function X. Okay. So that's X. So here's
a regular expression. regular expression
if it's I let's say
uh then you want to negate it okay so
uh stream match and uh not
okay basically so new list something
okay let's let me just try it okay
so now you just need to print new. Let's
try it.
Uh, okay. Regular expression something
missing. God, what?
Oh, so wait.
So wait, string match Q
string and pattern. Okay, regular
expression pattern. Okay. So, why is
that missing?
This backslash is always very annoying.
Okay. Run it.
Okay. I don't want it. I don't want
that. So, let's say
so if it says at the end of code then
remove it. Okay. So, just for testing
purposes now. Okay.
it.
So, it's still got a vin of a code.
Uh,
did we filter? Wait,
are we printing the right things? So,
this is what we want to print. So
function
select
let's not not stream match
function stream match that regular
expression available code
uh what is this string pattern regular
expression
Yeah,
empty. Okay. So,
is that because
Yeah. Okay. So, that is why. So, now you
can see now it's all just advent of
code. Okay. So, but what we want is we
want
I okay and we want to negate it.
So
if it contains I remove it.
Okay. No, but this regular expression
is it because you need four of it
annoying the back, you know?
What?
Oh, wait. Wait. This knot needs to be
here. That's right.
Okay. So now,
now it's still right there.
So
uh so you actually need uh this is quite
annoying.
This is not the right way to do it. But
uh
but we uh Okay, that's pretty bad.
Okay, maybe that's enough of wam
language. Um
you know because I haven't,
you know, wam language. I haven't
been using wuam. I have not used wam
language to do this uh kind of text
processing much.
So,
so, so now it's not smooth and we are
just like all screwed up. We are trying
to so let's get a file list and we are
trying to it should be very simple.
Okay. So and uh we were trying to use
string expression then we switch to
regular expression and uh you know this
should be string contains okay not
string match because I'm not paying
attention I'm not concentrating
uh okay not strand string
contain
there it is not str match okay so if
string contains
uh in this case string contains x
uh and we don't even need regular
expression anymore. So you know if we
just say string contains then maybe that
can can we do that
successful? You see it doesn't have
you know if I go to the talk show
directory uh not here delete the um if I
go to the talksh show directory
talk show you see there's a image
directory
uh you know and there's got you know 500
files there.
Uh and now
they are not shown
because
because of this. So we successfully
filter them out.
Uh but right now it's just one of these.
We want to filter them out for all these
of all of that. So in order to do that,
you can just map. Okay. So
uh do I need to Okay, I'm just um
okay to skip equals to then this make it
into a list. Okay, you want a list of
directory to skip. Okay. And uh yeah.
Yeah. So each one is a directory. Okay.
uh then we going to so so then the new
list will equals to you want to map this
to this. Okay. So basically
um
basically new list
equals to map. Okay. You want to map
function to
you want to map a function to uh
to file list. Okay. Then the here is a
function
and what this function do is that this
function will uh
will um basically will
recurse. Okay. So wait. So for each one
of these you want to go through reduce
fold. Okay. So actually you need to use
fold functional programming
uh fold
fold
the to skip. Okay. Now you need apply a
function to it and uh and then you need
the first item
in netit value.
Okay, let's look up the documentation.
Fold fx list. Okay. So, so, so initial
value that's just, uh, so anyway, what
you're going to do, so for each one, you
want to select
uh, this is getting complicated.
Select from file list
by this function.
Uh actually you don't you know you can
just pass it multiple criterians in
select
what what
god
I need to code wuam language more
because right now it's not it's not
going so Well,
uh
can so you know like one
we you know one idea after another. So
so I guess uh should I stop? There's
seven people watching. Is it interesting
or should I switch to uh EMACP?
But eag this, you know, I've been doing
it so much.
So actually the trick is to you really
just need to think about it. You cannot
just like
trial and error and doing pot shots. So
let me you know let me relax and then
take it slowly.
Am I doing fine? Yes. Star Wars
Okay. So, let's get back to what we need
to do. So, we got a directory. We got a
input directory. We got a input
directory.
We want to um we want to go through
every file in a directory but skip this
directories if the name match. Okay. And
one way so this should be over here. So
above that is all parameters kind of
good coding practice. So input directory
and directory to skip that's a
specification then you start your code
here. So this file names gets all files
in a directory
to the depth of infinity.
Okay. Then um
now it it can also take from nth level
to mth level and it can also take
multiple directories.
So
yeah. So it can
Okay. And you also you can also even
specifically specify
nth level of a directory. So if a
directory is nested you know three
levels deep only that
files in those directories. So you can
do that. Uh
okay. So so this gives you a list of
file names. What pattern all of it
doesn't? Uh so do I care actually?
So the pattern only matches file name
not directory name. So this is useless
for me. Better double check.
Yeah. So
another so you know the thing is we are
trying to figure out how to do this you
know wam language is normally used for
you know mathematics mathematics physics
engineering
uh but this traversing directory is
usually cis admin text processing so
you know so I rarely I haven't used this
much
um
and you can also you know give it
several directories. So but we but we
want to skip some of these. Okay. So one
of the you know
so
so one of the thing we can think about
is there some fix some function building
function that just do it one shot like
we don't have to do map or filter or
select
uh you know that's a you know so
so we want to skip these directories so
If if one of the parent directories want
contains you know is one of these we
want to skip it. Okay suppose there's no
search direct function. Okay then
then what we do is we can do a filter
you know we get everything first. Uh but
that's not efficient because for example
if you have git directory usually
there's like hundreds of files in it and
lots of sub subd directories. So you
don't want
you don't want get all names first then
filter out the git you know whatever
contains the git path.
That's a that's an issue. Okay that that
is a issue.
So now there's a question. So if we are
doing this for real you know real life
problem using wolfam language how do you
solve this? You know we can we can get
all files first then filter it but
that's not efficient when you have like
um kit.
So another way is you can
Yeah. So what so you know it must you
know this this must be a way
uh so we have to just carefully read the
documentation. Okay. There's no way
around it.
So file names form list all files in the
current working directory whose name
match the string pattern form. But the
problem is it only match the file name
part not the directory. If it matches
directory then we are solved. Okay. So
let's read in detail. Um
file names can be given as literal
strings or string expression or regular
expression. Okay. In abbreviated string
patterns star stand for any sequence of
zero. So that's wild card pattern. Okay.
Uh
you know so yeah so let's see next
so verbatim specify the string should be
matched with wild cards. Okay so that is
like verbatim you know wild card.
uh then you can say infinity
for so-called recursive you know idiotic
jargon in Unix recursive
in fact it doesn't mean recursive at all
because recursive means implementation
it does not mean
you know it it just list you know it
does not
specify subdirectory and all its
subdirectories is for example let me let
me say it this way it's simpler so for
example if you have a tree you know you
don't say if you want all the leaves of
a tree you don't say recursively get the
leaves recursively that's what that's
not what you say you simply say all the
leaves or all the branches of a tree you
don't say all you know all branches
recursively
because recursive
is mostly a verb that that's related to
implementation. So if you want to get
all the leaves of a tree, you can
implement your program in a recursive
way by writing a recursive function that
calls itself
or you can use nested loop. So when you
say get all things in a directory and
subdirectory and all their subdirectory
it is you know the word recursive is
irrelevant but the Unix and C idiots
they don't know. So for example in wuam
language they don't say you know when
you have infinity you know the third
argument specify how deep you want to
go. So you can say infinity which is
represented by a symbol you know it just
means all levels all levels and then you
know ex it explains that it looks for
files in all subdirectories of the it
doesn't say recursively
like the Unix idiots
Unix and Linux and basically that you
know bad concept bad thinking spread to
All programming languages, industrial
coders, you know, they they always just
say recursively. Anyway, that's a
digression. Okay. So, so we are reading
this. So, file name. So, list of files
returned by file names is sorted. Okay.
That's kind of make it slow. Um, then
file name form. Then you can add a
braces to to the third argument so that
it only includes that
level of depth.
Okay. The forms can can include relative
or abs. Oh wait here
the forms can include relative or
absolute directory specifications there.
Okay. So that is the key.
So we can specify our patterns here.
Okay.
Yeah. Um yes or no. Yes.
The question is how but that's a detail
we'll see.
Okay. Setting the option ignore case
true. Okay. That's ignore case. Okay. Uh
then Okay. Then
fantastic.
Okay. So, so the form can be
can include absolute directory
specification. Now we need a example.
Okay. Jesus, they don't have example.
You see in this case there's only one
example because
because this is not typically you know
mathematics or physics so not many
people is using this
uh
okay so but now but you see this this
sentence is most important the form can
include relative for absolute directory
specification. Okay. But how
match the form.
So this needs to be a pattern.
But
how do you specify? You need a negation
pattern. Okay. So this so if we um let's
try this again.
Let's let's forget about that. Okay.
So,
so this part can be
uh let's say
what? Oh, we need to do that.
Okay. So, now it's just all a vin of
code because it it only match that. You
see,
you see because we searched for advent.
Okay. But we want a negation of this.
Okay. So let's try first of all let's
try to see how to how to how to get uh
negation work. Okay. So, so file name is
a pattern. So, instead of using wild
card, we we now use string expression.
Okay. Uh and in this case string
expression, let's just say event. Okay.
Now, let's do that. Let's see.
Run it. None. Okay. now. Um,
okay. Maybe let's not try uh that yet.
So, let's just try that. Okay.
And it
empty.
Uh,
wait. So, this form
can they be string expression? Yes, they
can. says right here file names can be
given as literal strings
string expression string patterns
regular expression object.
Okay.
So,
oh yeah, but you need to the problem is
you need to match all part of it,
not just advent because the event won't
match. You need to match all part of it.
So, so let's go back. So, let's get this
to work. Okay, I'm just pressing on.
So you get back to about string
expression. Okay. So a string expression
uh any single character character class.
Okay. So let So
Uh so character class little character
any single character.
Okay. So character class
character class exclusion.
Okay
match boundary.
Okay we don't care.
And repeat.
Okay. So repeat you just say dot dot one
or more times. Okay. So let's say
let me let me show you how this works.
Okay,
so string expression.
Okay, so
letter character dot dot
So that means one or more letters.
Okay. Then something advanc.
But actually we want to include the
slash or backslash.
Okay.
Uh but let's say that
okay. So now we if we run it that won't
work because we don't have any slash
character. Okay. What about any
character? So underscore is any
character. So let's just say underscore
underscore any character one or more
times then event then any character one
or more times. Do it.
Oh yeah, we missing a comma.
I mean uh yeah, comma do it.
Uh invalid syntax.
Uh
wait any character.
So underscore means any single
character.
Okay. So why is that? Uh
pattern one or more times. zero or more
times
alternatives.
Jesus
starting to get annoying
this when
I don't think so. Okay.
Oh. Oh, right. You need par Jesus. Okay.
So, now
fantastic. You see,
so what we done is that we
we are using file names one single
function call. Okay. Now you know let's
you know let's brag about this. You see
we want all files in this directory but
skip this and now we only one single
function call gives you give us the
result. Okay let's remove that. Okay one
single function call and this function
is just file names and takes three
arguments. Okay, a pattern
of the file path full path then the
input directory then depth. Okay, now
the pattern is the tricky new thing
here. The pattern we can use a regular
expression. We can you know I can try a
regular expression or we can use string
expression which is a new kind of syntax
similar you know almost similar very
very similar same purpose as regular
regular expression. Okay. And here we
say
you know it the the string expression
can take any number of arguments.
They basically just join them. Okay,
remember this represent a string pattern
like a regular expression. Okay, so the
first thing you say is that any
character one or more times then
followed by event then followed by any
character one or more times. Okay. So
one single function call
you get a list of
of of
all file path full name and skip and o
only match this pattern. Okay. So what
we want to do now is we want to like
negate it. We want to check if it does
not match any of these
Okay. And uh
and
so negation um negation is you know
here.
So literal character sequence any single
character you just have to read it
carefully and think you cannot rush. So
is anyone still here?
So okay any single character character
classes
uh
okay
character classes then
character class exclusion. So you got
except.
Okay. So except allows you to
um
we want to try to have a except
so
accept this.
So except a pattern.
Okay. So actually we can do this. Let's
see. Except a pattern. Okay.
Um so copy that. Make a copy. Then
except it instead of event we say except
advent.
Okay. Now comment that out.
Uh, wait.
Run it.
No.
Uh,
except or.
Okay. So, you know, except
Why? Why is it Why is it that except
doesn't work? I don't understand,
isn't it?
No.
Uh,
okay. I think maybe I should stop
zero or more times. Okay, let's try
instead of one or more times, let's say,
wait. So,
I don't think this works.
This is embarrassing.
Alternatives
named capture. Okay.
Conditional check on pattern. That's it.
So what we want is anything one or more
uh
Okay, probably everyone is gone.
God
uh this
god.
So pattern god
need to get this to work.
So we are trying to match your pattern
and this is the text pattern one one or
more
but except how do you express
how do you express except a sequence of
characters.
Okay, you just have to think carefully.
Uh
so you got
uh string expression pattern syntax.
Okay. So here is a sample code literal
character sequence.
Okay. Except Oh, except
except a pattern that is not pattern. A
pattern that is not pattern.
So,
so this pattern
why can this work except advant
um
the argument to accept can be a string,
right?
You know, here's a example showing the
argument is a single character string.
Okay.
But it could be more than one character,
too. Right now, do we have a link to
documentation? No. I need to add
it.
Uh, no. I don't have link to
documentation. So
what?
Oh, that is because Oh. Oh, this is
incomplete. My tutorial here is
incomplete. That is why. So, let's go to
string expression
and let's go to wam language. Okay.
Yeah. So, woofer language got the full
thing except that you guys cannot see.
Okay. So,
so let's go to example and ignore case.
Let's go to FM language documentation
for the string expression. Okay.
So this is spectacular and
very complicated.
Um
so you can see so what we need to do is
that we want
we have a list of strings we don't want
to match any of it.
Okay. So you got pattern any order fixed
order pattern condition
number in string uh
and you can you can also include regular
expression you can embed regular
expression in it.
Oh yeah you got characters and character
range
uh hexa decimal character.
So but except
so any character except once. Okay. So
except is
okay. So
shortest and longest.
Um
okay. So but
date pattern number string wh okay I
haven't found
so here is a patterns
here at least match one of these
patterns okay
uh but how do you negate it.
You see right now this pattern
how do you say you know you can
so you can construct a syntax using all
these elements to represent a text
pattern. Okay. But once you have a
pattern, how do you say
you know anything that does not match
this pattern? In other words, negation.
So that is tricky even in regular
expression because in regular expression
you cannot negate it. You can only you
know the you cannot negate the pattern
except except in a you know uh a class
of characters
but you cannot negate you know you
cannot say whatever does not match this
pattern. You can sometimes do that
via the function that uses a regular
expression. So the function can say you
know grab
print only if it does not match you know
this pattern. So the function
that
use the regular expression as argument
the function may be able to say you know
return only if it doesn't match.
Okay. But the but the regular expression
itself
does it have a way to say you know
negate the whole pattern? No, I don't
think so.
Okay.
So, but what about wam language string
expression? So, wuam language string
expression is like an alternative to
regular expression. So regular
expression does not have a way to negate
a pattern
because I I think because by the very
semantic of regular expression is is
supposed to match. It's not supposed to
express express something does not
match.
uh
but it should be possible to negate you
know the you know but it just I think
historically it just never happened. So
anyway in in string expression of wra
language
does it
allow you to negate a whole pattern?
Okay. So that is the question. So that
for that question we have to read the
documentation carefully.
Uh any order fixed order
pattern and condition
pattern for which condition evaluate to
true. Um
you know that is like
extra test. um
character object an object representing
a character class.
Okay, so string expression arbitrary
string expression. So you can embed
string expression inside string
expression. By the way, woofam language
the implementation of string expression
is that it converted to regular
expression.
So it's kind of funny. Uh so anyway
character characters
so that's any you know you can specify a
character class by this and character
range by this and hexad decimal
characters digital characters little
characters
whaleace characters what so what about
the except that looks really promising
that should be
that
really this should be is a pattern
object which represent any expression
except one that matches.
So this is what we want really.
Okay. But um but how do you you see but
you see
oh okay so let's use it outside. Okay.
So let's you know Let's let's try this.
Okay.
Um,
wait. Except takes.
Okay. So, this is a bit complicated, but
let me show you. Okay. So, we have
nested string expressions, I think.
Okay. string expression then inside it
it's a except
then inside except is string expression
and here is just advent okay so that is
what we're going to try
very advanced okay so we got like now we
have nested string expression okay
please make it book
warning comma. Okay. Oh yeah, we got
extra comma. We don't want.
Okay, now do it again.
None, which is incorrect.
Okay, this idea failed.
Wait.
Uh, but now you don't need this.
Maybe we are making it far more
complicated than necessary.
No.
Uh you see the thing is that you really
do needs to match the hole.
Okay. So no
god
what?
Okay. So
wait you know let me try another idea.
So this except not working
what about alternative. Okay so we can
use alternative can we? Yes. Okay. So
that
um
no we really want negation.
We really want negation but now but we
don't know how it works.
What Emacs theme do you use? Just search
for Kali Emacs theme. you'll find it.
Okay, I think maybe that's it. We This
is uh this is not working out.
So,
so the real question is except
but
it seems to you know but
did we look at all the examples
except works in string expression. Okay,
this is what what we want is a pattern
object with which represents any
expression except one that matches C.
Okay, that's what we want. But
though but but there is no good example.
You see,
you know, this there's no good example.
We we want um
you know, right? You know, over here
it's using it as a
you know, that's basically a character
class. That's not what we want. We want
the character sequence.
And here it's using it as a symbolic
pattern for integers, not string match.
And here it's using okay, here is a
string, but it's except digit
characters. So digit character is a
sequence of characters. Okay.
Uh
right. What we want what we want is a
you know negation of a sequence of
characters
not not this.
So here's another example. This is
symbolic you know integer. Now use a
text pattern matching that doesn't work.
I mean, except um
Oh, wait.
My mouse is out of battery. My track
ball.
Okay. Applications.
Um applications. No. Okay. So,
so you see uh it's not,
you know, it's not right. So I think
actually we stopped today. We stopped
now.
Okay. Needs needs more work. Okay. Okay.
Bye guys.