good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of accent talk show today he's
2019 October 20th Sunday 10 o clock a.m.
San Francisco time good morning Bart
good morning League of noobs today I do
not have a topic so I'm just going to
talk random and bar says can you can you
apply a functional programming style in
goal at yes indeed but not as Extreme as
Haskell however you can't because the
fundamental requirement of functional
programming is the fundamental
requirement for a functional programming
language is that a function can take
another function as input and can return
a function as output that is one of the
primary requirement but also the other
things is for lack of a standard term is
that basically the language when you
program the language it does not require
you to use lots of side effects so why
do I pray I don't pray yeah you know
he's just my random gesture you know
like the Joker says have you ever danced
with under the pale moonlight I just
like the sound of it that is what I do
often without there is no meaning
sometimes okay so I don't have a topic
so let's just do random
and random stuff random random service
so first of all start sod command log
thank you for joining me part
again and okay so let's random yeah so
I'm just going to okay ticket so let's
start
it's magnify this talk show date create
a new HTML page make it a link cut the
line go over here taste it remove that
cut that go to the URL pot enter to open
the page magnify
paste the link here make it a list
showing browser and take can we what we
have here is taken action figures Naruto
gesture
now he's Naruto some Japanese comics
anime or was it American comics similar
to Japanese so I don't know what is
Naruto he's a guy with a kind of a Spyro
on his head wearing a band something
like that Naruto so you see this is
Japanese PVC figures we we need to need
to go wait it cannot go anyway you see
the intricacy the intricacy the sexiness
oh there there you go
the intricacy the sexiness and the
technology of sculptures modern
technology of sculptures Japanese makes
it taken figurine looks like your wife
it looks it looks them like my wife yes
indeed blonde she's not a blonde she's a
brunette okay so that's about that okay
you guys you
by you by to help the economy to help
the world economy to help the weak okay
so there is the link by sexy figure
figure okay you see there is a
linguistic issue here because I wrote
articles about these PVC figures for
example if we go to Mike's arts page
okay there pretty girl doing your gun
asean squad you know the other day I
noticed I discovered wait and we we
start to we begin to digress
so PVC figures that's the first topic
and also okay so the other day I was
watching you know this is the this thing
called Asian squad if I wasn't broken 20
I would you know there is this ACN squad
okay so you guys know what ACN Scott is
like I don't know if I can show you you
I need to point my camera at oh my god
I'm going to point that camera at my
room I'm not sure that's a good thing
what I have to let's see okay so I think
you can see it
but hold on a second okay they make I
don't know what what garbage I have
doesn't matter okay so Asian squat it
looks like this
it's Asian squat you see like that ACN
squat okay so that's Asian squat and you
eat
chopstick you eat
that is the ASEAN squat okay
so ASEAN Squad
I discovered Europeans they cannot do
that and you know you go to youtube you
search for Asian squad you will see
several videos and I thought why when I
watched the first video I thought you
know I thought it's a joke it's a meme
or something like that but actually it
is true by the way she's not doing ASEAN
squat she's doing something you know
yeah they are you know women are into
yoga stuff Yoga is useless thing
so Asian squat day I discovered
Europeans they cannot do that and I was
I was totally surprised I discovered
this last week I was completely
surprised because I thought that's just
a natural human position take a crap I
would be very surprised if this creep
would not become a big fat meme you know
you're not yeah but but the thing is
that squat in Asia in China was in
Taiwanese I grew up and I know in South
Asia for - for sure you do that
all the time like everyone does it
you know maybe not women because you
know females you don't squat because
there's sexual implications but when you
are younger you know when when children
you squat all the time so I was rather I
was actually surprised that European
people cannot do that so that is about
the taken figure okay and yesterday we
talked about math books so there's more
math books you can buy this are some of
my math books lots of them I've thrown
them out
you go there and you buy so bar says I
would be very surprised of this clip
okay someone someone should make a music
video remix of this [ __ ] Asian squad
with whoop whoop whoop
you know actually someone made a techno
music out of my talk when you know like
a [ __ ] the short clip have you seen it
he he posted on this chord but that one
is not particularly good so we are
saying a few days ago so we are saying
you know when you have a better video
I'll link it but you know it's really
good
it says technology will help us
technology will help us yes okay so
League of noobs good books on
probability no I don't have a good
suggestion on probability but however I
have a you know I'm talking about the
books I own you know almost all these
books I bought in 1990s pretty pretty
much around 2000 year 2000 1999 when I
have money I was working so I finally
bought the math books I want because
before you know before 1998 I was kind
of poor very poor too so when you are
student you know you go to bookstores
you see this math books math books tends
to be very expensive and you know back
in 1990s it's 50 dollars today it's even
more you know today's textbooks hundred
dollars something so very expensive and
you you know you you drive all over them
you drew all over them I used to go to
Stanford bookstore almost every
month Stanford University it's right
down here
so in the 1990s I used to go there every
month and I just go there I go to the
math section you know you have a higher
of math books latest math and I just go
there stay there for three hours every
every month or so and you read them you
you know you sit there and read them to
see the preface what what are the things
you know what what is you know for
example the projective geometry what is
polytopes what is topology things like
that you just read stuff so yeah so back
then so when you are student you don't
have money but finally we when you
graduate you walk and you can buy all
the books you want it so I bought some
of this is you know many of them have
throw away throw away since this RC
awesome basically that's my bookshop in
the back that's all the books I have
basically and okay T'Pol I mean
probability I don't have a
recommendation for probability so I
don't have a book on probability but
however if you go to here there is this
book I think it's a reasonable
introduction to probability okay so
let's put it here taking action figures
you look more professional with our
glasses oh oh that's fantastic
I used to wear contact lenses so when I
was younger I was the Superman I was the
beautiful Superman so I don't wear
contact lenses up until 45 or so okay so
that's that what is the next thing yes
next thing let's see what clothes that I
have 12 people watching welcome so you
know PVC figures this amazing so this
that figure you just saw is this drawing
this is 3d rendering of the taking game
anyway so this mouse this mass is
interesting because there's a new
technology here let me show you this
mouse okay
copy it close go to Emacs paste it here
make it make a link okay make a link
open link in brave so we have JavaScript
okay then and now here you can see the
video turn on the JavaScript and reload
thank you I am going to read it tonight
great probability Prabha you need
probability before you study serious
statistics
okay so study probability then you can
move on stat to statistics by the way I
don't like statistics I like probability
is much more interesting but but
generally statistics is the applied
mathematics so for example in AI
industry today at Google Facebook you
know we are doing or doing a
Oh noona noona you know neuro-networks
that's critical that's the future neural
networks will is crap but it's fashion
it's a it's a fashion today in
technology neural networks now when you
study neural networks when you implement
neural networks you need strong
understanding of statistics because to
train the neural neural network brain
because otherwise it doesn't work here
so you need so you have to study
probability then study statistics then
you can go into data mining data mining
neural networks
oh that's the future well that's not
that that's not the future okay the
alternative to AI the alternative to
neuro networks approach of AI is
Symbolics
and the proof proof systems prove theory
that is what I'm I am interested neural
networks not much neural networks is
crap okay you an extra let's let's Mike
Sally neural networks ok such that in
Google artificial neural networks is
nasty this is my article ok copy at
pasted link of i showing browser other
vision neuro networks is nasty why is it
nasty
you know today about two years ago
Google alpha go then they then one year
later they have a new version called
alpha zero that beats the word spaced
best go champion the go game ASEAN game
champion in China okay there's a event
before that it's in Japan but anyway so
so Google beat the world champion of go
and that's you know good alpha zero and
that is using neural network
methodology approach and and it has
become so advanced the alpha zero it's
so advanced so that let's let's let me
show you some of the articles I've
written I've studied this in detail this
situation you see this is Korea yeah
Koreans got hot girls this is the event
back in 2016 when alphago which is a
version before alpha zero a [ __ ] went
to Japan to challenge this go expert
Lisa dough
Lisa though he's that like the top five
go player ranked at the time so at a
time we are thinking that Google will
never beat human because computer go is
very pretty lousy so people are taking
it as a you know it's kind of
entertainment he's kind of it go yeah I
mean it's kind of fun you interpret him
and I mean even Lisa said oh you know at
that at the time you know even him we
are thinking although experts are
thinking okay this is this would be fun
to watch but for Google to beat him now
this never and it's not you know you
we're gonna wait for five years or ten
years
but surprise Google go actually beat
beat the guy so that's that is really
something shocking you know if we are
going to talk about computer technology
the history of computer technology this
is a big event especially AI history of
AI this is a huge event because AI for a
long time we thought that go is the game
that determines whether we have AI or
not anyway in 2016 Google a Falco beat
the words you know the top player Lisa
doe
next year in 2017 or was a 2018 January
anyways
so Google created a new version alpha
zero now alpha zero again in space our
neural neural net technology okay did I
think this haven't yet so let's link it
so that I want to link it because people
being asking you know I'm doing one hour
or 90 minutes video every day and the
coordination of the I mean the people
like I talked so many things people want
to have a time stand like what the
topics I it's you know if the if the
video is one hour long it will take
about three to four hours to actually
create timestamps you know extra three
or four hours it's so it's tremendous
read time consuming I used to do it but
now I simply just put the topics like
like right now I'm trying that's why you
see me keep posting Emacs because I
tried to why I talk I try to put the new
topics in order preferably so so later
today I don't have to watch the whole
thing and back and forth and so on and
get the links so anyway so yeah someone
you know somebody if you go to my
youtube channel someone just post a
message asking me it's so don't stop
asking me to you know to get the
timestamps okay not do that unless they
are loads of money coming my way so so
guys if you like my stuff PayPal you
know how my website you can find PayPal
and patreon information but you guys
heard of it many of many times but
anyways I mean I'm talking about in many
other people so anyway so back let's go
back to go so so so next year fr0 came
around alpha zero now alpha zero
is trained completely by itself that is
it does not ever use any human go
history input you know human go games so
it just begin with the rule of goes new
lures of go then alpha zero just play
with itself you know billion billion
times a day just play with it play but
with itself and that is amazing and now
and after I think after half a year or
month you have to have a year they kugel
has published this information in
academic paper journals so after half a
month it becomes incredible it becomes
it beats the alphas go version the
previous version that beats Lisa doe so
it beats beats alphago then Google offer
zero challenged the at the time 2018 the
Chinese the current champion the Chinese
guy grouchy his name is Katya okay I
also have article here somewhere
so but in anyway this is fact in 2016 I
have recorded every game you know I have
studied every game I'm not much of a go
player but but this thing interest me
much I do play go but not very good so
game records so COBOL has a impact on
humanity
there it is here is the second article
so this is this happened in 2017 January
so alpha zero came out and it beats you
know the the the champion at the time in
China and I also studied basically every
game and I watched it live so it's
incredible it's amazing and
but the point is I mean the the the
thing here is that alpha zero just learn
the rule of rule of God by itself and it
can be the world's top human champion
and also by far you know like like by
far but but by this time people know
like today you know you talk to go
experts you can you know in Western
society you don't have much go you have
lot a lot of chests a lot of chests but
you don't have much go information like
for every go article you can find a
thousand go articles in China in Asia
Taiwan Japan Korea so I forego it's just
alpha 0 alpha 0 the new new version is
just amazing truly amazing
but however here's the thing alpha zero
is based on neural networks so so now
that you can beat world champion but
however you cannot teach humans how to
play go in in the sense that you do not
when you use neuro next neural new road
networks it does not know how things are
done it is like talking to a some human
calculator okay so he can calculate
amazing things you know idiot savants
things like that he can do he make
amazing things but it's but it's like a
magic he cannot tell you how it is done
you do not learn what is a theory
what is the techniques that is the
situation with neural networks so that
is what this article is about artificial
neural networks is nasty because you
don't learn anything you you just got a
black box that just can do great things
in this particular area he just gives
you the answer
it doesn't know there's no way to find
out how is it done because neural
networks it's not a deterministic
algorithm okay well it's kind of
determine yeah you know it depends what
I'm trying to say is I there's no
information you can get out of it on how
on the problem itself it can just give
you answers that's why that's why you
think of it as training it's like it's
like humans brain almost okay I think I
good morning good morning good morning
guys
Freddie Freeman says lucky I saw your
streaming now yesterday I was it was
funny I was watching some of your videos
then I saw your streaming but he was
just over when I joined okay only I can
see honey Atkins I can't see your
desktop nah me too what oh [ __ ]
okay I've been talking for 10 minutes
and wasted all my articles I'm trying to
show you okay here are the articles so
here's artificial neural network is
nasty here is okay so here is alpha girl
versus Lisa doll so the here is 2016
okay pictures lovely Korean ladies there
it is this is the event in Japan but
over the Asia they are you know you see
this picture this this is in Korea South
Korea and they have a TV on the street
showing a go game this is how crazy go
game is in Asia so you know so so you
have a lot videos these are on YouTube
by the way I have watched them and this
one is alpha zero beats beats world
champions 60 to zero yeah and also a lot
of videos okay so I should feel bad
about that I missed all the things
anyway
a nice focused live stream come on in
Matt is it just me okay so nobody can
see the screen everyone chill is it
black so we cannot talk or was it black
it wasn't black before I eat it was my
face really complicated function can we
talk about the alternative to to
neuro-networks or rather what you see
was a better alternative yeah so the
alternative to two neural network is
called symbolic AI
that's such a general name for it okay
symbolic AI there it is Wikipedia
article symbolic artificial intelligence
now this article is not very much
detailed because you know it's just got
like you know one page idiotic why is it
like that because symbolic AI has been
fallen out of favor
nobody is recent researching it much
anymore the neural networks works you
know working a sense it's taking over
but but but it has far much ways to go
because today if you go to Google
Translate machines cannot translate
languages even they do a very bad job
and those you know Google Translate for
example or almost any others they are
using neural network to do the
translation so you can see we are far
from being perfection you know the when
you got when you do translation it
doesn't work for example Chinese to
English it doesn't translate well so the
alternative is symbolic artificial
intelligence what what does it mean
based basically it's
it's it's like true theories like proof
systems you understand the situation you
for example let's take the job of
translation okay like like let's say
Chinese to English Chinese to English
hold on second my roommate my roommate
they asking me to eat or something so
Chinese to English site so you if you're
gonna translate Chinese into English so
right now the Google Translate they are
using neural networks to do the job so
what does I mean basically you read
turns of translations like billions for
for example you have you have a book
let's say not a book let's just say a
paragraph okay a paragraph in English
and you have the same paragraph
translated in Chinese so that's the
input and now you have like good jjigae
billion of it you know Petra by 2 or
something you know of this information
you feed it to the neural networks this
is the training stage so so what it says
you know so the neural network just you
know it sees these and it's you know it
sees this as a correct result
so the neural network reads that then
you keep reading that so eventually it
gets some sort of statistical data about
what is the correct translation you know
it doesn't it doesn't understand nothing
it doesn't understand alphabet it
doesn't understand oh wow there's a
spider I don't know how did this writer
get into my head so neural network they
don't understand nothing they just read
the inputs massive number of them and
essentially the way it works is that it
accumulates statistical data about when
it sees this issue
returned that it's that's the way it
works in essence so that is why so after
obedience billions billions of the it is
input then you just give it a English
sentence and and you just come out
Chinese you know it's by statistical
kind of inference it means but it
doesn't understand nothing that's the
thing you see it doesn't understand
nothing it doesn't understand nothing
same thing with the afar 0go technology
you know when when you teach go when you
learn go or when you learn chess when
you learn chess from a master for
example they typically tell you there
are certain you know strategy how do you
check things how do you you want to
control the center things like that
theory but if you with neural network
you know today you have chess engines
that's far better than human you it
doesn't have this kind of information it
doesn't know it just know what is the
move to make okay so
so we were talking about yet neuro
networks
so that's how neural network does
translation now what is the alternative
the symbolic artificial intelligence for
lack of better jargon well basically the
yeah oh the better term is good
old-fashioned artificial intelligence so
this in this approach you so you you
study the English grammar you know you
kind of formalize the English language
or Chinese language you kind of you know
you derive you create theories or rules
about how words are put together you
know the semantics the syntax you know
you study them you create a route rules
then you write programs this is the
symbolic artificial intelligence
approach okay so if this way it seems
this way is not you know it seems the
neural network is performing better so
that's that is why this is falling apart
no one is doing this kind of thing but
however with this approach if it's
successful then your program you know
you code it then you understand that the
the the you understand why it gives us
some answers
you know why sometimes it made a mistake
in translation you can find out exactly
you know what theory or what rule is
wrong things like that so that is the
that is that good morning this
probability book is good
oh good morning Kathy can we create
consciousness with neuro network that's
a that's a very interesting question we
can go into so let me check out comments
quickly okay so let's see did I miss
anything I'm pissed off about that my
videos being hidden like you know not
showing my articles for like five or ten
minutes
the idiocy of XRD anyway so let's go
back here good books so actually so what
so actually Bart asked a question in the
beginning can you do yeah can you apply
a function of I mean styling : yeah yeah
I guess I answered that kind of so we
cannot so we can't talk to machine to
understand how they do things no no not
if they are using neural networks to do
the job
can we talk about alternative okay so
just reference the hakka okay so let's
see Bart says I remember now that your
RSS is spoken which the links within
your RSS are local not public no that is
not because my RSS is spoken that is
because the RSS client you are using his
broken okay oh my god this is another
one of my big gripe because when I do
things usually I read the spec you know
okay so this lets go such sorry RSS
right let me tell you the story about
that that's a big story it's it lodged
in my mind as a hatred towards the then
you know the generic programming
community especially the UNIX types you
know they tell you what to do every day
meanwhile they are completely wrong so
anyway let me tell you the story about
that so here is my Adam web feet
tutorial I wrote this in 2006 because
that is the year I started to create RSS
for myself Adam is one of the web feet
format before Adam it is the RSS which
stand for something something since in
syndication or Really Simple Syndication
you know ass it's created by this
[ __ ] Dave Winer David whiner okay
he's a s David whiner he created he
invented RSS basically David wine okay
that's his name he ate Dave Dave Dave
Winer okay ass and he is also a very
haughty arrogant guy he is very you know
in my opinion he is not very good person
not-not-not he hasn't done anything bad
okay but it's just I don't like the guy
so anyway Adam so so later on you have
this Adam format which is much better in
and standardized rectified standardized
much better than RSS RSS has multiple
formats you know it's a mess OSs one is
two then there's different noises -
things like that dave winer and he you
know he refused to release RSS into pot
you know into the public domain into the
you know things like that so anyway
there came the Adam web feed Adam a new
format format Adam is in part created by
this guy who killed himself about seven
years ago what is his name
he is also responsible he also created
he is one where the founder of Reddit
what's his name guys help me out a bit
type the name you know he's a very young
guy you know the reason he died because
he is being sued by US government by FBI
because he went to MIT Aaron Schwartz
Thank You Benjamin
bit but German Aaron Schwartz yes indeed
that that is a guy so Aaron Schwartz he
he partly created you know he's one of
the guy who helped to
create Adam so let's go back to the
story why what's the problem with you
know why the your ISS kind is broken
this is a big thing here okay here web
feed reader bug on relative link so this
is written okay this is written in 2006
you see now let me show you a RSS file
so you go to my programming blog so you
go this is my programming blog and there
is the ISS feed and we can go into it I
can just press a button okay here is my
ISS feed file corresponding to this link
you see so exam problem in blog
programming computing technique in broth
you know that that is this file so OSS
is pretty simple you see you have this
header is special but then every part is
just this like this entry so that is
entry then you have another entry let's
drink okay
then you have another entry then you
have another entry you know things like
that so and each entry is just me
magnify now each entry is just you know
title ID update the in content then link
that's it pretty simple okay this is
Adam format for RSS now RSS format
itself is very similar it's pretty
pretty much the same now about relative
links you see I have relative links here
you see this link how to make video
games you see the link here is related
related to this directory it should is
it it is allowed in Adam it's valid
because you can you can see word
does it say you can see let me show you
okay you see this line feed xmlns that's
that is stand for namespace you know XML
become so complicated
they started to have namespace and every
time when a simple great technology
becomes the industry standard that
standardized by this big you know
organization standardization
organization they become crap they
become fright you know by Google by
Apple you know it becomes garbage XML
that's the story of XML FA now it was
truly one of the great great markup
language with the most simple syntax but
it becomes so complex with namespace and
and and you know anyway so you have this
line feed XML in NS namespace okay then
you have a URL you see w3.org that's the
oak that standardized web tech such as h
net HTML and stuff so you know let's
look at what they say they're actually
you know this URL is supposed to be the
specification of adam okay the link is
even dead it's a [ __ ] [ __ ] the industry
then you see this part XML : base okay
there it is you know you you have this
ie ft ie ft is another [ __ ] that created
the UNIX the UNIX philosophers love for
the RFC request for comments
ok back to this line so you see this
space you see so whenever you see a
relative link it should be based on this
this link this is by spec ok I'm now
going to show you the spec because the
SPECT is linked I believe I linked in my
article that teaches Adam I somewhere
here yeah there it is
reference you know ie TF dot org RFC for
to a seven [ __ ] IFC [ __ ] UNIX [ __ ] UNIX
people excuse me excuse my French this
you know you guys probably don't know
because now it's old IFC was the thing
that's chanted by UNIX loving people all
the time now why is it bad I'm not
nervous not going to that because I'm
gonna talk to hours for that because you
know you you such sorry IFC you start to
find many of my Holocaust but we got
articles we got things piled up right
now
so anyway Adam is supposed to support
relative links in fact it's you know
relative links is supported by HTML is
supposed to be everywhere okay so it's
supposed to walk but however however
even back in let's see okay so let me
show you actually I need to copy this
link and paste it here okay and show in
browser and click on that so II so back
in 2006
you know back in 2006 ISS is popular
every website every basically every
commercial web site you know its website
run by companies organizations has a RSS
feed today it's kind of died you know
it's killed by Twitter by Facebook
because they don't want blogs they want
their you know they want their you know
interactive you know the social network
[ __ ] so they cured blog they kill the in
the figure they killed individualism
with the help of open source and free
software foundation [ __ ]
that's the siege that's that's why we
have Twitter and Facebook why because
you know trick Facebook is based on PHP
PHP is written open source not just
because that many other reasons
way back to the back to the relative
link of ISS so even back in 2006 Google
Yahoo Yahoo is around back then Yahoo
Google these giant corporations they all
have RSS and and also they all have most
of them a lot of them has their own RSS
client and also back then all the
browsers Safari
Google Google Chrome was not there yet
in 2006 Safari you know many balls 5x5
Aqsa was was the most popular at the
time
they have RSS feed readers spilled into
the browser you know a few years ago
they removed it so a lot browser don't
have it anymore
like you yeah I'm not sure Firefox even
support that I don't think so
hey they removed it back in 2006 every
browser is like oh a new new new version
announcement today you can read ISS in
the browser
you know big headlines the Safari and
all every every every browser you know
and then they do what is is SOI RSS
aggregator you know aggregate that's
that's another jargon very popular back
thing RSS aggregators or that features
you so you can you know stuff and you
know they about ten years ago they they
they quietly all removed it these
[ __ ] corporations Firefox Siskin
open-source [ __ ] it's you know
open-source white-white you know yeah
that's that is proper you know when I
say these [ __ ]
sometimes they is a bit exaggeration
because sometimes you need proper you
know reasons for anything anyway but
it's not wrong okay Firefox is one of
the primary spearhead of open-source
and then they you know I talked about
this a few times they donate to the
social justice against a criminal group
antifa about two years ago and they they
try to have secret you know commercial
plug in stuff you know he's all over the
news so anyway and also Firefox they you
know so the the free software open
source idiots you know they want to use
Firefox in in new project Inc gnome
yes Inc no okay so the Linux chrome they
want to use Firefox but Firefox says
they have lawyers they says no thou
shalt not use our logo otherwise we're
gonna sue your ass this is about ten
years ago
Firefox toad toad the groom and free
software guys you know you cannot use
our logo yes we are open-source yes you
can use out you know browsing your in
your in your gnome Linux or whatever but
you cannot use our logo Firefox
otherwise we're gonna sue you there's a
big fight controversy you know I'm not
in on the web you can if you pay
attention you know but but but you know
I'm not going to show the Holocaust
because open-source stories there are
too many yeah and and you don't know
because you don't know because you you
you only see things you want to believe
so all the negatives people don't know
vote it down nobody see it it's
forgotten
so anyway Firefox did that but after ten
years later you know like about five
years ago about yeah about five years
ago mm I don't know 2014 or something
the in Firefox says by the way that that
is why by the way this is why in Linux
you don't it's not called Firefox it sky
it's called iceweasel or something I
scat as we saw
him and the open source you know idiots
first the ideology they mix each other
they don't mix or together they don't
know what they're doing you know they
just find usually you end up with the
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] up miss so you have
ice cap there every iceweasel you know
things like that why do they have that
one one of the fundamental reason they
may be peace because Firefox threatens
to sue them if they use the name Firefox
or if they use the Firefox logo you know
this this is from Firefox the open
source the sharing the you know the kind
to humanity people open source [ __ ]
but okay so this is a nice incident
backing I don't know 2007-2008 oh I
don't know
but after after ten years late ten years
later when Google Chrome becomes the
number one browser Firefox today is like
it's like a small player nobody is using
is about to die okay Firefox today is
about to die so when that happens
Firefox says welcome back welcome back
with free software foundation welcome
back Linux chrome you asked welcome you
are very welcome please to our use our
logo please
[ __ ] the open-source [ __ ] its if you
don't believe me look up okay look up
you know five five Firefox logo as you
you know if you want to I'm pretty sure
you can find it within ten minutes
huge tons of articles you want to find
two things one how Firefox threatens
lawsuit to the Google oh no you know
goooo chrome for using their logo that's
one thing you want to find go find it
the second thing is is the second thing
is after ten years when Firefox becomes
lost you know firebox is struggling then
they started to say please we use it use
our logo okay it's allowed now go go to
research if you truly believe open
source kind of thing
now now Benjamin says so do you prefer
up close you know that's a complicated
question you know you had any ways I can
tell you what I don't want I don't want
fake news
I don't want ideological fake news and
that is most of the open source
mentality thoughts and what you read
about open source on you know those are
all fake news that's what that's what I
want from their home you can you can get
on to better things
not necessary proprietary ok so anyway
so back to the oh yeah so I so I was
saying you know the relative links they
in backing even 2006 all the browser's
their clients the relative links are
broken they don't didn't walk they don't
support the you know the atom protocol
properly they don't walk why does it not
work you know I mean major okay we are
talking about Google yeah I have details
here okay for example 2012 ok 2012
Google's feed reader fixed the relative
links link bug took them six years
[ __ ] six years to fix it 2014
Christophe Whalen's feed reader our feed
okay if you use Emacs you probably know
his package it's very well done Alfie
he's kind of friend
we're I mean we are acquaintances and I
would consider him a friend he's very
great he's one of the greatest email is
coda
better than me he know the Magnus better
than me but also he's the one of the
rare few who actually blog about eMac
this you know on a web you can see tons
of bloggers of eMac B's you know most of
the amassed majority of them are
beginners you know they you try to learn
you Mack this then you start to write
block okay and most of them they are
just like one page you know they didn't
it's not very good but Christopher
Whelan's now he he doesn't have a full
emag based tutorial he's just blog you
know he's just blogging about emag least
or the issues or Emacs or he's also a
classic game he programmed games you
know he's a he's a C expert you know
kind of the low-level different for me
he's time type the type u of the typical
I would say he's very much the UNIX
philosophy type of people okay so we did
we disagree there being a lot of
viewpoints he's very much the low-level
UNIX philosophy see kind of thing
compilers how memory works you know he's
that type but he's very good he's you
know he so he wrote the RSS feed L feed
package for Emacs in Emacs Lisp and
that's very good I recommend it so so he
finally he also fixed the problem he had
this book to for like two or three years
you know so he finally you know fix it
and he told me about it
you know and 2018 a master than part for
Emacs feat have I have this problem too
okay so but let's go back 2006 what did
I say Google there it is you don't you
know Nancy so I just discovered books in
RSS aggregator in google.com my
yahoo.com my msn.com these are major
billion-dollar corporations they have
they cannot they cannot write a program
that the simple program to read ISS feed
there's a story okay that's a story so
so but what what kind are you using you
know you know so why do they not have I
mean why do they all have this problem I
mean it seems incredible I mean why do
all these big corporations
client do not support the very extremely
simple idea of relative links because
relative links is pretty common you know
in HTML well the reason is well I can
tell you the reason the most of the time
when when people do is they have the
fool URL they don't use creative links
okay and also partly because Adam is s
you know Isis is a mess
there's no speck you know it's by the
Dave Winer
[ __ ] you know the Dave Winer [ __ ]
so he you know he just do what he wants
you know that's basically when you
become famous he's one of the you know
popular famous guy you will see he's one
of those guy you know celebrity program
a celebrity you have a lot tons of
people follow us every time he says some
[ __ ] then you have follow us you know we
treating him oh you know God opened his
mouth you know we should do this or that
he's one of that Skype and when and he
doesn't you know I assess didn't have
aspect you know it's a mess and you have
several versions Isis one is two or we
need you know what does is for a
one-time it's really simple syndicate
another time it's something something
more you know more sounds nice more
formal its [ __ ] in open-source
[ __ ]
I got to make dinner so have a good time
big of noobs okay do you know dinnertime
Internet's own body I say a good
documentation about him yeah yeah about
Aaron Schwartz you know all these
information they are Aaron Schwartz why
did he himself you know why did FBI
catch him on the surface the reason is
because he is trying to download you
know all the the mega tons of whatever
the academic papers published you know
copyrighted copyrighted by these
publishers he's you know downloading
them massively but I've read that you
know the other reason the possibly the
actual the real reason he's in limelight
is because WikiLeaks he is connected
with WikiLeaks he is you know he has at
least the the the minimum thing we can
say that is true is that he is he has
communicated with what's what's his name
the WikiLeaks guy who is who lives in
the educate or in a room without seeing
the Sun for six years the WikiLeaks and
what's his name
Assange yes thank you was hot Julian
Assange okay since we mentioned him
let's search for yeah actually I have
quite a lot articles about him but but
let's show interesting ones let's not
show more controversial ones okay let's
show this one
he's he preached a sermon in 2013 went
to London to Julian Assange is aboard
and you know they met they took a photo
together with a photo of Edward Snowden
and Julian Assange is a Emacs user in
fact back in 2009 t back in 1998 he
wrote Emacs package and I have
documentation here I have proof you know
I've looked into you know some people
say oh maybe that's a different Julian
Assange you know that's that is the 100%
like no doubt about it I mean it's clear
it's plain and clear you can see and
that was his nog III Q oak Judy massage
Assange packing you see this is 1998 he
wrote the Emacs package okay that's
that's about Julian Assange but I think
I was talking we digressed to the RSS
what were we talking about before
well I in the middle of something that's
incomplete
shut up
shut shut up meow cat seemed to suffer I
didn't know about suffer at the time
okay so DP says nice tea to your
audience you could use absolute URL
singers that's a that's a pen you know
that's well yeah I could but you know it
it takes a lot more work I mean it's
it's you see okay the the main reason
here's here's why I do not use fully
qualified URL in my RSS feed
the main reason is let's go through my
so let's go through my programming blog
let's go to keyboard blog is something
interesting no not really okay so so
here's my keyboard rock so here's RSS
feed the main reason I do not use full
URL is because you see my website my
HTML entire website is designed so that
it's a it's a documentation technology
okay not necessarily for the web it's
simply just a documentation technology
like PDF okay meaning that I can I can
zip it up I can just send it to you then
you can read it on your hard disk you
know it works on the web too but but
it's also a documentation technology by
itself that is why when I have ISS feed
you know I click it I can click it and
go to my page actually not not that
because I started to use fooling you
know I don't know I don't want that
because you see now I create
I went to my ex Audion for I went to the
website I went to Lee I need an Internet
I don't want that this is supposed to be
local if you are local you click things
you know that's local available it's you
be local not go to some website not
phone home okay
hey this guy we got this guy's computer
but if you are visiting RSS on a website
then then you have the web thing it goes
to the website right so it works both
ways but however however if you start to
use fully qualified links then you look
you lost the the property where local
files remain local like some links will
just go to some some web site like go to
Microsoft web site so I don't want that
you see that's no good that's not
supposed to be good so that is why I try
not to use fooling you know because when
you have relatively accessible you know
it's supposed to be workbooks with ways
convert your relative links on the fly
when creating your feeds it's not that
hard now I know what you guys saying you
know TV so every time I talk about
something it is it's a it's common then
people tell me the names need knocks
people or people you know they tell me
oh you should do this or that it takes
time it takes time I have 6,000 pages I
have you know I have already I spent my
life doing all this script to create the
systems of course then they oh you could
do that too you can do that I cannot I
cannot do that I don't have money that's
the situation I think that's it for
today so today we talked about what to
join what to join you in it's okay in
anyway so what how long have I been
talking
one hour and ten minutes okay I think
that's it
we got 20 people watching that's
fantastic
would you like to answer a technical
question shoot just shoot me I'll cat
just shoot as an iced tea to your
audience you know RSS is kind of dead I
don't think you know not many people use
it you know I have my blogs I have like
seven rocks and the most popular is
probably my Emacs blog and the active
the number of active users you know
active readers for my Emacs blog will be
maybe 300 you know let's say people who
check it weekly maybe 300 not many
anyway I am not even sure it's 300 today
maybe just 50 or 100 yeah I would say I
would say you know look at my look at my
YouTube then you know you know YouTube I
have 20 people watching and each video
have you know 100 people watching most
of my videos 100 so you could say you
can you can Church by that so the number
of my active followers is you know 100
or 200 300 that's it so so why do I is
you know I I paint about to do all these
things nobody really cares there's no
money and you know that's the situation
so meow can says and technical question
70 meanings connect to remote service Oh
meow cat says how does PDF document
connects to a remote server I don't
really know maokai says some PDF when
you open it attempts to connect to the
remote server yes that's very annoying
it's a [ __ ] annoying that's one of
the reason I hate PDF I don't like PDF
at all I do not use PDF I don't want to
use PDF so PDF I think the happen I
think it happens
I don't know this hundred percent but I
have looked a little bit into I think
that happens is when they have
JavaScript now you know PDF now today
they support JavaScript so I think ok
that's that's when it connects to
servers
no I think meow cats question is he
doesn't want to hold oh is he he wanted
to do that okay I don't know
and by the way PDF is also open source
okay the PDF spec is actually kind of it
says is you know it's supposed to be
open format so you are actually it's
allowed for you to read the tech you
know you can read the spec you you
you'll find out and you can implement it
if you want yeah so you know cat so you
can you know you can go read the spec
it's open it's on a web so we've been
talking for one hour and 13 minutes so
and I think that's it for today and for
next week I'm thinking of let's I want
to change your time and actually I just
want to go random let's I'm thinking of
going random time for for next week and
I want to change your time because you
know in Australia and in China they
don't have they cannot like at this time
it would be 3 o clock or 4 o'clock in
the morning for them so I've been doing
tailed you know I've been doing 10 o
clock for the past 2 or 3 months 2
months at least I think so they are
missing out I guess
so I wanted to change your time so they
can also join me live so we can have
different you know some people they
haven't been on for a while and so the
next question is how to pick a time
that's that's that's indecision
indecision because I could I could
follow any time around the clock you
know I can choose any time I want but
however I do I have constraints here
because I mean apartment here so the
best time that the time I'm thinking is
5 o'clock a.m. San Francisco time 5
o'clock a
San Francisco time so that would be four
hours four hours earlier one two three
four five five hours earlier than my
usual ten o'clock five hour earlier so
if I do that then people in Europe and
in China in Australia they can all join
me but however if I do that five o'clock
a.m. my time that means I cannot talk I
have to I have to talk like this I have
to talk actually is quieter than this
because because five vocal game and
everyone sleeping my roommates are
sleeping and my neighbours upstairs you
know there's a thing war you can hear
them I'm pretty sure they can hear me I
cannot talk loud so I have to be super
super quiet so that may be a issue so
but I would be interesting as well
because when I started you know if you
do really quiet then it becomes ASMR
this becomes a fashionable thing among
the Millennial Generation thing ASMR you
know SSM is supposed to be the thing you
speak quietly like it's supposed to
trigger your nervous your brain into a
present it's become a present trigger
triggering of your brain supposedly okay
these idiots millennial idiots and
gammas with their things ASMR it becomes
hugely popular okay it's search for ASMR
channels and mostly you know mostly
girls are doing these they you know they
have you see this girl gentle whisper
SAS ml 1.7 million followers ASMR daring
darling 2.4 million followers
it's a SM
[ __ ] [ __ ] you I am the opposite of SMR
okay you listen you watch Santa show
it's pain its pain to you triggers the
pain receptor in your nervous system is
a maja I have subscribed actually to one
Chinese girl that's ASMR you're so
[ __ ] idiotic these people and they
make money you see this is as technology
progresses you have more diversity of
jobs so these are jobs these are their
jobs if their job is to go online and do
no it's not poem okay oh you guys don't
know that guys oh my god you guys need
to check out you guys need to check out
the essay master actually let me show
you one of the one I subscribed to
YouTube because the others I haven't I
haven't seen them I haven't watched him
but I I heard them I know it's a thing
but I didn't realize I know it's there
but I've never actually searched for it
but I know there is this Chinese girl
who is doing that let's go to my
subscriptions and look at this this
youtubers the [ __ ] oh oh creek bed Oh
[ __ ] brainless brainless people
Brenda's people doing Creek rates every
title every picture of them
this [ __ ] this especially the Tim
poor today
Oh bad something-something band
PewDiePie banned in China oh and you
need to talk about it it's a important
it's critical China China China China is
a dramatic thing you know China is one
of the dramatic thing you have to talk
about China you you put China in your
youtube title and say pad censored been
you know the censor is not good enough
you have to say pad China banned
something or China
something something China then your
video will sell you will become rich my
friends put China in your video title
you become rich
so this ASMR guy which one is this this
Lauren Chen the roaming millennial [ __ ]
idiots okay not [ __ ] but idiot complete
idiot and this h3h3 idiot okay they are
fine people by the way they are good
people okay but the edges idiots
oh my god Lauren Chen and and another
thing is that you look at girls channels
okay pretty girls you look at girls
channels yeah shut up
okay so let's no let's go to
let's go to you go to her Channel Joker
movie review yeah let me talk about
Joker
I watched it so you look at this pretty
girls Channel you know they are they are
one ton of them on YouTube one make a
ton of them you see Lauren Chen for
example they you she make sure every her
video features her beautiful face
alongside of it by the way this is
critical okay on the surface you might
think oh you know she's talking about
someone of course and then she put her
face but actually the reason the girls
put their face on each one you know
plastered used you see them all over you
know different channels you see them
every every girl the reason is that that
sells okay that sells when you have a
you know the girl of either yourself or
some other girl it needs not yourself
okay a pretty girl you'll find
statistics statistically your click rate
went up you know girls they sells they
sell not just girls sales they sell them
self to girls
okay so shut up shut the [ __ ] up you
know nothing let's look at this ASMR I
subscribed to her I've watched I watched
a few way not this guy is a great guy
okay this guy boogie this is guy a very
interesting story but I wanted to show
the the the ASMR thing okay hold on a
second I made a mistake in creaking who
is that oh these they are here this
Chinese girl she's got 1 million
subscribers
so in this one she's doing deep cleaning
doctor deep clean a doctor deep skin
cleaning treatment ASMR some of them
last for hours yeah that's what they
this is a profession you know these are
the Oh her videos
Jesus close down
so deep he says if it sells to have good
thumbnails then she's not an idiot but
in fact smart after all well yeah you
could say that but that's a matter of
interpretation of the words because when
I say idiots you know there are so many
interpretations I mean okay yeah well II
do again this is when you need to adapt
adapt adopt the Western philosophy or
mentality of using a precision like
Jordan Peterson okay so you don't i
don't yeah i should not pour them idiots
but rather i would the proper world
would be lame these people are what how
should i say they are just without
insights okay they are just without
inside the app they are better words
okay these people are just the best
words are just idiots okay that's caused
us say for the money he's a professional
victim who the word is slimy slimy
well that Sammy nothing you know many of
these people they are just no more
people okay they are not they are not
idiots they are just they are they are
like you are yeah intellectually they
are probably they are above average okay
they this this ASMR thing okay it's a
it's a job and they make a living and
it's one of the world's most easy job
okay and they are able to make a living
out of it that's that's not easy okay
it's it's easier said than done and they
you know they do these things and you
have to and there are competitions you
know you can just oh I'm going to start
a chant channel with a s
SMI and you're gonna expect that you're
gonna have a million followers next year
you know that's not true and you know
and you have to do actually you do have
to put in some work you have to pie
things you have to make yourself pretty
you know if you are a natural
pretty girl then you have to do makeups
you know you have to spend time to do
them but still I mean overall it's still
one of the easiest job in the world you
know and you have to buy things you have
to know what people like you have to buy
you know unlike my room you have to have
pretty background you know everything
you pretty so these people you know the
but you know from a so what I'm saying
is a for my point of view from a
philosophy point of view from history
point of view from human animal history
point of view these people are just
insignificant did the idiot okay
temple ghee yeah Pookie okay yeah boogy
boogy oh I guess he was to that too but
he also he is you know super fat that
also that is his selling point as well
so I think that's it for today thank you
guys for watching I think I'm gonna shut
down in one minutes or two and let's see
what any questions I missed seem to seem
to where you form I forgot are you in
Perth Australia - oh are you where are
you Oh joke an interview okay Joker so I
went to watch Joker about three days ago
three or four days ago and Joker I have
never been to a movie theatre for for
over 10 years or 15 years but I went to
Joker in the movie theatre a few days
ago
and it's rather a disappointment so
first of all the Joker movie is not a
superhero movie so you go there you will
not see you know fighting or extinct
explore explore Nate it's explosions you
will not see big explosions or fighting
or anything like that
nothing nothing like that nothing zero
okay instead it is a psychological drama
it's like it's a drama okay it's a drama
movie so for example you watch maybe
mystery you know in a cat movie category
of mystery or suspense or psychological
thriller
there's not even much killing or
anything like that there's nothing it's
not even like a murder you know Friday
to 13 nothing I got so but so the film
belongs to the drama
movie no I actually like psychological
drama very much much better than then
superhero movies you know those
spaceships or you know there anything
like that I don't I actually do like
psychological thrillers very much such
as Sex Lies and videotape that's a very
famous psychological drama 20 years ago
or 30 years ago but however Joker so it
is a psychological drama but however
it's kind of disappointing
disappointment it's not I would say it's
not that great it's not that good I
would not watch it again
I would not watch it the second time
okay it's kind of boring me so it's not
very good so why is it not good because
when you have a psychological drama you
know the thing is about psychology the
thing is about you know different aspect
of psychology human animals behavior but
the Joker the movie is it's very simple
it's rather very simple it's it's almost
stereotypical essentially so you have a
guy who have a bad life bad life who is
suffers from psychological problems
personality disorders who is a often
who's got a bad abusive mom you know
typical typical elements of psychology
of serial killers things like that you
know he so he's got his unfortunate guy
so but he's a good guy he tried to do
good things but but society is unkind to
him so he become he became this you know
be he became Joker and that that that is
it that that is the whole thing about
the movie there's nothing interesting
that that is it so I didn't really like
enjoyed the movie
okay so that's it for today thank you
guys for watching so what were you doing
now you are a medical doctor now okay
that that's surprising so yeah I yeah so
I guess you went through so you are now
a doctor okay okay so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching well
by the way doctor that's congratulations
though I mean that's so do you make a
lot money
same-same Isom okay that's it I'm gonna
shut down okay bye guys thanks for
coming