good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of startup show today we are
going to do event of code
day five is it day five
yes day five so advantage of code in
Wolfram language and the day five okay
and today I hope to do two or three of
them let's you know I hope to finish two
or three problems in one hour
well I explain
things okay start movem language
so if you are new here let me mention
that let's magnify
okay start the Wolfram engine three
okay so if you are new here just go to
sardi.info okay excited.info this is my
website and I have
lots of programming language tutorials
uh wolfam language emacs emac disp you
know
full form language emacs emac these
those are good ones and unicode uh for
programmers everything you need to know
about Unicode uh HTML as well
introduction and visual CSS okay
so you can learn you know I've been
coding for 30 years and JavaScript in
depth this is the best
JavaScript tutorial on Earth
you know according to me but I would say
they are top three this is among top
three JavaScript tutorials complete you
know I I spent three years writing this
reading you know all the JavaScript spec
spect
okay and uh all my tutorials are written
in a way that's easy to understand
every paragraph has the example
Standalone example you can run it you
know
and and in this and No Nonsense no
talking about
how you should use open source or how
you should use patterns or how you
should use object you know everything is
concrete you know exactly what you type
what it happens what it does all my
tutorials are of that nature in a sense
you can say it's a mathematical way
uh styled tutorial but when you say the
word mathematics people get scared they
think oh it's gonna be monad and they
don't no it's not like that okay and no
ninja no Zen no State storytelling oh
I've been programming C for 10 years
then I went into uh
small talk then therefore python is this
way no such thing okay just concrete
everything you know all my tutorials are
of that nature so JavaScript
and of course then you can use SVG which
allows you to have Graphics interactive
graphics online in Us in particular
charts
and Powershell which becomes its best
shell okay it's a best modern shop
Powershell
much better than Bash biomagnitude
uh then Golan my favorite low-level
industry language this should be C and C
plus first should be wiped out and I
would also say Java they should be just
wiped out okay Golan I stick with Golan
uh rust
uh is not my thing you know it's one of
the fad today but a lot I got a lot
people ask me asking me what do I think
of just I don't know rust okay but I
don't think it's
that could be yeah for lots of reasons
Golan okay Simplicity concrete
Simplicity simple and fast
very simple golang is in fact simpler
than than python simpler than python
than Powershell than JavaScript
JavaScript is Extreme most complex okay
Cola is simpler than
partial python JavaScript
you know yeah it's simpler so Golan and
it's widely used you know you get a job
if you master you you want to master
start a project with the Golan
okay so and Ruby is more elegant than
Pearl and python python Ruby Pro is the
same class pattern you know like
alsoever tutorial on Python and Paul Ray
this is the old classic node thing you
know it generates
um
rendered you know Ray tracing rendering
so there's a tutorial on poor Ray and
others SVN SVN is basically absolute
replaced by git and I also have a
tutorial on git
uh there it is okay and there's Linux of
course very practical you know
okay
so today
let's do uh then and lots of other
things comments commentaries on
programming language on programming
language industry on hackers on the
hacker culture on the programming uh you
know industry culture uh and uh jargons
and that documentation lots of
essays on documentation there's you know
it's a field of technical writing and
plus my commentary and technology in the
past 30 years the progress of Technology
you know today we have YouTube's live
streaming or cell phone iPhone so you
know that's we have that's that's what
made this um talk show possible
and I'm also on
Odyssey subscribe me there okay Odyssey
is a good thing
uh and then
then I begin with mathematics this is my
old stuff the that made my website the
most popular lots of mathematics okay
okay so let's go back to let's start to
do the Advent of code and this time I'm
it's probably going to be boring for you
guys because I'm just gonna focus on
coding it
um okay let's start start the Wolfram
language is there anything I want uh
anything else I want to cover uh
no I think that's it okay check audio
check video check okay
okay so um
and there is my Saudi Discord showing we
we talk about real life stuff so if you
join uh preferably you show your real
name and real photo of yourself and talk
about real life stuff not memes or not
just like
uh stay in remote and you know
real life
okay so wolfam language
so today I'm going to try so many uh as
many problems uh as much as possible
okay so yesterday we so if you go to my
website Saudi Dot info
then
you go down this Excel talk show that's
the index of my all of my talk shows for
the past three years since I begin so
the earliest is something like
uh 2019 January there might be a few
actually before but anyway 2019 is when
I started to do every week at least then
about two years ago I started to do
exclusively live stream
you know I don't do videos like I just
do live stream because I prefer that way
live stream is is more genuine you know
I talk you you know you I talk you
listen I see your chat uh it's more
genuine instead of you know
15 minutes 10 minutes focused on our
topic or tutorial that is very good as
well but you know so people can learn
things but that but I prefer
live stream you know one one hour alone
so you uh
so there's a real
human interaction going on so okay so
so then so yesterday we did Advent of
code day one day two day three day four
all the solutions for example yesterday
is one single line in Wu fam language
okay okay so today
so okay let's begin
let's begin
this this is my drinks apple juice and
tea okay
comments and questions posted okay
okay so at the end of code you have to
do you have to go to this calendar thing
return to your event of code calendar
so number five okay
number five I haven't read the problem
so live coding real time trying to solve
the solution
day five okay
the Expedition can the Expedition can
depart as soon as the final supplies
have been uploaded
from the ships supplies are stored in
stacks of marked crates
but because the needed supplies are
buried under many other crates the
crates needs to be rearranged okay the
ships has a giant cargo crane
giant cargo Queen you know
capable of moving crates between stacks
okay supplies are stored in stacks
stacks of crates okay so you have a
crane moving the crates between Stacks
so it's almost like a tower of Hanoi
programming exercise which which is very
interesting if you don't know look up
Tower of Hanoi programming exercise okay
so Stacks creates
moving crates between Stacks to ensure
number the crates gets crushed or fall
over
the queen operator will rearrange them
in a series of carefully planned steps
after the crates are rearranged the
desired crates will be at the top of
each stack okay so you have something at
the bottom you need to move them to the
top
but
when you move you you can probably only
move the top one so it's like a
stack problem exactly there's a data
structure called stack
so the elves don't want to interrupt the
crane operator during this dedicate
during this delegate
delicate procedure
but they forgot to ask her
which crate will end up where
and they want to be ready to unload them
as soon as possible so they can embark
okay
so they do however have a drawing of the
starting stacks of the crates and the
real Arrangement procedure okay so here
is your input
okay so we have like three stacks I
suppose one two three three columns
move one from two to one
okay move move one from two two one two
two one move three from one two three
one two three
move two from two to one
okay move one from one to two
okay so the result will be the column
two will be n m I suppose so in this
example there are three stacks of crates
stack one contains two crates
crazy is at the button on the bottom and
create N is a top okay
snack 2 contains three crates
they creates m c d
check okay finally stack 3 contains a
single create P check okay
then the rearrangement procedure is
given which is this okay in each step of
the procedure a quantity of grades is
moved from one stack to a different
stack in the first step of the above
real Arrangement procedure when credit
is moved from stack two to one two two
one
yeah the move number one okay
uh
in the first step of the okay the
resulting in this configuration exactly
so
here are the procedure which is an
algorithm
okay and that those English words can be
considered the programming language
okay
so in the Second Step the three crates
are moved from stack one two three let's
see Second Step move three from one to
three okay
like that okay
so I moved one at a time so the first
grade to be moved d
ends up below the second and third grade
what okay right so
so step three move one two three
one two three okay
uh yeah so D is on one so
yeah
okay
creates a moved one at a time so the
first grade to be moved T ends up below
the second in third grade okay
okay there's a
anyway so then both crates are moved
from stack two to stack one
okay again because crates are moved one
at a time crazy ends up below grades
uh M okay finally one query is moved
from stack one to stack two
okay that's uh yeah okay so
this problem is exactly like power of
Hanoi at least so far so let me show you
if you don't know
uh which is a
Fable from the Bible okay Tower of Hanoi
let's look
I mean I suppose I mean as far as I know
there's a story in the Bible That's the
Tower of Hanoi
so allegory to some stories in Bible
why because this is advent of code which
is a Christian thing
okay so you know this is a person
basically your goal is to Tower of Hanoi
is to move this stack of disks from one
pile to the other with one rule
at all times there must be no bigger
disk
on top of a smaller one
and you can only move one disk at a time
so uh so this problem the essence
involves kind of like uh involves binary
number
kind of the principle
okay so this so this problem is
basically
similar let's see what is exactly the
problem
so it helps just need to know which
crate will end up on top of each stack
which query will end up on top of each
stack okay so you want the you want to
know the end result of the top
the topmost one
of the three columns okay in this
example the top crates are C in stack
stack one m in stack two and the Z in
snack three okay so you you should
combine these together and give that
give the elves the message
CMZ okay
so after the rearrangement procedure
completes what create ends up on top of
each stack okay this problem is very
easy
so you given a stack of original
configuration
and you are also given a
uh
a source code algorithm of the procedure
okay and
the problem asks the problem is
you know if after following the
procedure
what's the result essentially
so in other words what is the result
after you run the code
very interesting so
uh so it's not you know it's a bit
different from Tower of Hanoi but
the the the the kind of the game is the
same the rule is the same okay let's
close Tower manui
so basically
you can think it's almost you know let
me go elaborate it's almost like given a
input and given a program you want to
run a program and see what is the result
that's one that's a that's kind of the
computer science way of putting it but
in practice you just want to
okay let's think about how do we do this
okay
so Three Stacks so you begin with input
so obviously this is the input you need
to pause it
okay X input
let's say it's a string like before
God very annoying
you know one of the issue with the
advantage of a code is that
it's a coding problem it's a coding
challenge however
it does not require you to submit the
code nor does it specify exactly
in you know in terms of technicality
what exactly is the input it just tells
you that this is an input you can use a
spreadsheet you know you can use you can
you can you can find the answer in any
way you want
you know so
I mean the point is it doesn't say this
must be a file it comes from a file or a
string or at least a distance it doesn't
say so but so far we assumed it's a
string
but in this example
if you assume it's a string it's going
to be very complex because you have two
parts these you know you have to pass
this into a Stacks so
so it's not good so so the easy easier
way is actually to
to already begin with a algorithm wait
okay so you know for example we can we
can start with the algorithm let's say
stack one
stack one is
n z okay for example stack two you know
we can start that way
d c m
okay and so on but that may not work
because you need to know what is the
input so let's see get get your personal
input let's see what is the input
okay
oh
so this this so if the
input is like that you actually need to
pass it
because you cannot manually you know
write this out so let's copy the input
save
uh wait I don't want to save here so
hold on a second let's go to talk show
today's talk show go to diet and here's
the event of code
open a new one
copy that close save this as advantage
of code input
and this is day five
what
and
day five okay so here is day five's
input
how do we turn this into actual data
structure
this is
oh
not sure I can finish more than one
problem today
you know you can cheat just by manually
create a list of one to you know
and with the emac with help from emacs
you can somewhat do that much easier you
can easily do that turn this into a
whatever programming language is data
structure
basically a list of lists a list of nine
items each one is a list
but
which would work I mean I mean because
the wind of code doesn't specify you
need to be
you need to pass this string but
but since we are doing coding challenge
we should think of some
better Ways How do you
okay God how do you how do you pass
these
okay this is this is not easy
the Advent of code day five
so hello guys good morning annoyed
secondary account
use a two-dimensional array second part
of day five is easy okay so Splendid
Splendid is a expert of PHP professional
expert
by the way PHP is a language Lab
at by a lot hacker types but actually I
think PHP is good
I call it PHP
I'm you know I could I I pretty much
mastered it
15 years ago but I haven't coded since
but did PHP improved a lot anyway so
so how do you pass these do you do you
how did you do it Mr Splendid let me
think about this
two-dimensional array but the problem is
how do you you have to pass it or of
course you can cheat you know if you
cheat then you can say for example let's
add this this you know let's add this
let me let me do this again so if we are
going to cheat it's easy uh wait let's
just say zero okay zero let's you know
that's cheating you know we just add
this
you know we just fill in the uh the ones
that doesn't have then you have a
structure you know rectangular ASCII
text then you can easily manipulate you
can
you know you have to
um
do that
okay
for example
this is this is
kind of considered cheating okay
I mean not really cheating because it
doesn't say you have to do certain way
but you can do it this way but the
problem is you know then this is not
good because the problem is
the point about programming is that
suppose the input is a million columns
and the stack can be ten thousand
crates what you're gonna do you can you
are not going to manually you know do it
so that's not a good solution
if the input is this string then it's
super easy you know it's super easy you
just split the strain into a list then
do a transpose then you drop the first
uh first row and then then then remove
the bracket find replace remove the
bracket then put a string that that's it
you know you got the data structure and
then delete those zeros you know then
you got it
but that's not so um
so how do you
is it possible yes it is possible but
how do you do it
so again speed string is a re is the um
yeah you split the string
and uh
Okay so
yeah
hold on a second okay
let's let's copy that okay
here
what is this
day four
okay
yeah
yeah today's this one so
yeah let's put it here
and the
let's remove that save it copy the file
path close it close it
open it
so here is the input okay showing
browser
so our problem now is to figure out how
do you pass this thing
okay suppose
uh
uh chunk full filter and letters
transpose oh
oh
good solution excellent
so so what you do is that you you know
for each stream first of all you split
into by by new line character so you got
lines a list of lines each one is a
string then
you just consider each
four characters that's that's it thank
you fantastic
okay let's start coding let's start
coding and then okay so the input um
yeah so the input let's not worry about
that okay okay first let's work on this
part
okay so we know how to do that for the
input
so we got a list at least each list is a
stack
now the second part
uh movement so that is about the
algorithm uh so you want to turn this
so what you can do one way to do it is
to turn this procedure in English into
translate this procedure into your
language
so this move one from two to one will
just become
for example in python or something yeah
you just become
pop
you know pop list let's say pump stack
from two to one so pop stack
two second stack okay or you can in
Python in Python you just write
something like that
um Stacks so the second stack you pop it
then push okay so in Python you would do
something like that
pop and push that so you just stream
manipulation find and replace you know
use regular expression or whatever turn
each one of these into
into the source code of your language
you are writing a mini compiler
or transpiler so you turn that English
into this code then you just in in
Python you just do Eva or JavaScript
or list of language you can all do that
but that's one way another way is that
you know this uh all you have to do is
to extract the numbers you know don't
mind the word move from you know just
get the numbers one two one so
okay
let's let's start to write the code then
um so that's what is
okay so that's python
okay let's begin to write it so input so
first of all X1 just like before we
defined a bunch of in the inter
intermediate variables okay so stream
split okay
sprayed by input and split by
End of Line character okay then
X2
you split again
This Time by oh wait this time by
four characters four characters each
so you don't so you don't call split
instead you call stream partition okay
that's in Wolfram language
Okay so
so right now
X1 is a list of strings
each element is a line okay that's x one
now we want to so how do you process
each line
and you need to do that for every line
so therefore we need the map just like
yesterday
just like a lot of event um
so you want to map a function to the X1
one line at a time and then you need to
give a function
and this function you know Ampersand
that's a shortcut to stand for function
and the pound sign is a shortcut to
stand for the argument okay so so this
thing is a function a Lambda function or
Anonymous function so this function
takes one argument
and it will Partition meaning that it
will split the string
by every
four characters okay so let's count yeah
that's right one two three four
and let's let's let's make sure there is
no off by one Arrow so one two three
four one two three
it's missing a character
okay but no problem the string partition
when there is not enough string you're
just um
ignore I mean it will just take whatever
there is okay so I think that's it so
first of all let's do this and see what
is the result
close that true frame language
paste it
run it
okay uh this is incorrect
you know ignore those move from two
first so first of all it's
X2
X2 becomes this empty so incorrect so
what is the documentation for string
partition
and then overlapping substrings of
length n okay yeah that's correct but
why is our
function not correct
X1
what is X1
I wanted to show the
length 33 no this is not right
the length should be just one two three
four five ten or something
so when where did we go on string split
input
back
why is it not doing
you know in fact I can run this thing in
EX
wait
I'm using subwoof and mod you see here's
a result I can run a thing
emacs but
it's incorrect
why is it incorrect
um
so first of all we string splits
this input okay
string split by chunks of four
okay
okay then
for each one with party why is it not
right
what's let's let's just say what is X1
this is just wrong
like a strange split now let's give it a
by default it assumes a line but now
let's be explicit
now it works
you know by by default it is a
that that is a default an empty line
here but I don't understand why he
wasn't working before that's the correct
answer
yeah that's the correct answer each
element is a line right but but why is
it
why is it if you don't give that it
and see split string
pattern
let's see
what is the defaults
okay so now you can see
Oh by default is split by white space so
any white space we come there that's why
so now it's better now
run it actually running emacs
fantastic
okay now now there are two parts of the
input one is the
you know the actual input the other one
is a different input about procedure so
let's split them okay so
so first of all split by two
empty lines okay then
in one
imp one M2 okay
imp one will be X1 the first part okay
and M2 will be the second part then
then the first part X imp one okay let's
just do it
did we did we stream partition it
okay so let's do it dance
what is the output of X2
stream partition
what is X imp one
okay that's correct
oh wait you forgot to do something okay
so
once you split into two sections of
strings then you need to
okay you need to split string again
okay
like that okay then
okay that's right let's try it
fantastic
yeah it's a list of
uh
see
no
oh yeah you forgot this is not double n
this is single end let's do it again
fantastic this is the result we are
looking for
no it's not correct NC yeah it just
dropped you see
oh you know you see this at the end of
code
they actually tried to be
helpful because they add spaces at the
end
it tries to make the fog forever easier
for you they add the spaces after that
but still our code is not right
you know so because the the first one
should be
three elements
uh
you know for so for example X2
and thanks to
yeah
X2
the first element the first element okay
that's a
empty string
you know then let's say the length
percentage signs stand for that last
output and slash slash is the pipe
notation so we can just say
here
I think is zero what the
okay let's try this
uh wait it's a string
okay that's a function
at
see what we got this this is taking
on our long walk
string partition
what what why why is it uh
how many characters are there
one two three four
one two three four one two three four oh
it automatically
the partition function does it
automatically drops the
empty lines
so is your option
no option Okay so
sorry this is taking a while
why is it uh
stream partition
uh yeah so what why is it not
let's say two
let's say three
whatever you know I wish we found
language would show the
input form Okay so
last output slash slash input form
that should show the
quote
okay let's do this again
now let's say three
one two three
one two three four
now what happened to the last
one two three okay so if there's not
enough
then the stream partition just drops it
no okay that's not
let's say
okay
one two three four five six seven eight
yeah when there's not enough you'll just
drop it
not good
but even even so why is it there should
be enough one two three four one two
three four
two three okay that's not enough now
what about the original problem
one two three four one two three four
one two three
the original
the original problem does have
okay
it does have so that means our code is
wrong here it's copied original
let's
one two three four one two three four
one two three
okay one two three four one two three
four one two three
four
uh show space show empty space
one two three four one two three four
ah yeah okay the last one is a return
that's why
so what you have to do you know easy
solution is to pad it
pad is uh expensive operation we
okay so okay Pat it
and stream partition okay stream
partition now you want to before you
partition you want to say
pad string okay
okay a string pad left string pad right
okay there it is
make string to be of length in
okay padding it on the right with spaces
okay so okay
had right okay
we want padded to the right and
and how many
oh the column also Divas what the
the number of column also differs in
this example case there's three but in
the real input you know it's 10 or
something
so you have to actually find out how
many
uh to to make the whole thing
completely programmed programmatically
done without any manual intervention you
need to find out how many columns are
there okay let's do
tedious problem
so okay so so
let's let's just say x Stacks okay
process okay
so it's easier to read for people
okay so we have the input and the input
to become a list then we have stacks and
procedure then X2 is the
stack list
okay
list of stacks okay
okay so and here we want to pad yeah but
before we pad you need to know how many
how many
you know you need to know how many
columns uh
so
come let's say that okay so how do you
get column count you
you
hey this is not Stacks this is ah
this is not even Stacks yet this is just
Rose
lines okay so this Stacks is lines
so you have a bunch of lines
so you get the last line
okay
let's add
the last line which is this line
then you and then you split string fact
tedious
you then use you split it by empty space
okay then you get then you want to get
the last one okay actually so you can
just say last again
yeah then use you want to say two
expression okay
[Music]
okay that's columns count
column count okay then you get column
count that's
that's you make sure you have
column count times four
okay so we have lots of variables now
you know right now now look at you know
there are Extra Spaces there right now
let's remove them
so we actually change the input but our
code is more robust because we are
actually Pat them to make them uh enough
Okay so
so now stop showing my space now we have
column count now string pad right column
count times four
then
to make sure each line is of that long
then you
stream then then then then
you partition it yeah then okay then we
can
okay let's go back to fame language
paste the code run it
beautiful
this is the desired result because they
are
because they are uh
one two three four four what is this
yeah four
um
three three stacks but four lines
right
so now once you get this all you have to
do is you want to turn them
into a
turn them into a array you know array of
array so easy these sub stacks
you want to drop the last one okay you
want to drop the last one
okay there is uh let's see
okay so you can just say here
list of stacks
show up okay
drop at the argument
actually you need um
okay so hold on a second
drop the argument
last one negative one
so this becomes a function
apply apply it okay so you know so this
part
we can write it this way
so this this is so the add sign is a
prefix notation so here that's a Lambda
that's a pure function that's Lambda or
Anonymous function
apply this function applied at you know
the rest or you can you can put them
inside the bracket you can put this part
into into you know the Palm side either
way I mean that's a
advantage of the flexibility of syntax
you know digression okay so now you
dropped it now you can put another
function in front we want to transpose
okay
that should be it let's let me show you
so
so remember before we have something
looks like that
but now here actually looks like stacks
you see
NZ DCM
and empty and the P okay so yeah n z
DCM and P okay now the next thing we
have to do is we want to drop those that
are empty
empty string annoying he tries four
characters
yeah okay then so we
again
delete cases so we can add another
function let me show you here okay so we
just
call a function in front Okay in front
and this function will be
TD cases
Okay so
the so this is argument and the second
argument will be
a stream one two three four four empty
charts okay so now
we don't need this so copy all so by the
way
uh zelfa if you are watching we were
talking about
doing this in scheme disp
you know in scheme this you can so you
know Alfred also didn't want in Cypher
in fantastic you know which is very
practical skim this
so but what I mean is that you you could
in scheme this you can do something
similar like what I'm doing all you have
to do is just simply pipe lambdas pipe
pipe pipe you know chaining functions
which is one of the most common idiom in
functional programming okay so now
delete cases let's run it
okay oh we already did let's run it
what
it didn't delete what the let's try
here
uh
so here's the argument
and uh
come in stream one two three four
isn't it
it worked there why is it my um
oh you you need to map this to
right you need to map this to each one
each one of the items so instead of at
you want to say map okay copy all back
here paste run it
fantastic
here is our
solution now
let's see what are they
actually we have a lot to do
What what is the
what's what's the length of the D let's
see one
so wait look
so list of stacks
okay at least the stack
last
it's one thing
okay
length one
okay but what is the type
what it's not a string what what the
so we are trying to find out the last
round oh it's a beast yeah so
the last item is a list then the first
item
then first item
there is a string okay then you want to
know the length
the last item in the first item
oh yeah yeah you don't want the true
that returns true
what
the last item
then the first item
yeah let's do this okay
let's see what exactly okay there is a
space
yeah I mean we have to chop this space
and also we need to remove the
the square bracket that
and and then we need to this is not
efficient we need to do something to
make them efficient and too much lots of
work to do
so first of all let's let's let's make
it clean okay so let's remove the
DD trading DD trading um string Okay so
so which command is the delete Trading
space trim trim stream stream okay that
must be stream trim
there it is stream trim okay
and so somewhere you want to apply
string trim okay
so
so let's let's do it to
no we cannot do it there because
some lines
so lines becomes
so that's the number of columns uh
somewhere here
Okay so
stream partition
so after you partition it
let's do it here so you can easier to
see so pad right then partition it okay
then you
partition it then you map it to lines
okay
once you partition
okay we can we can kind of add it here
so let's see
and it's getting more complicated here
so
change stream
trim
map
okay I think that's it
do it
then the delete cases is just
um
the delete case is just empty string
okay let's copy it
yep it's perfect perfect one shot coding
oh yeah we and then we need to replace
the
yeah okay yeah we need to replace the
string replace why is it not
Wolfram language crashed
because the helper window I think
there's a bug whenever you
open the help window and try to enlarge
it crashed
okay yeah anyway
good thing
that I was working in emacs so we have
all the code here
so now
stream
[Music]
yeah screen replace okay
strings replace
okay showing documentation okay showing
documentation
on JavaScript string replace okay string
replace something and we want to replace
what we want to replace we want to
replace oh yeah
several multiple replacement
okay
left bracket
by empty string
[Music]
okay that's one thing then right bracket
by empty string okay
yeah so this is a function make it
into a function and this is X is the
argument so we want to play this
function
uh
here so the code is becoming
extremely Advanced functional
programming okay the code here
foreign
so
you won't do that
yeah to each and every item
I think that's it okay
yeah copy it back to Fan language
paste it so here is the code let's see
a stream replace okay so first of all
so the code let me go over Okay so
what you're doing is you
first of all you do a map
so you map
this function
to list of lines okay
so
this function will apply to each line
of string okay so it begin but so what
does this function do it begin by
add
Ed pad it to the Right add in space
okay make sure they are num you know
like number of count plus times for
spaces I mean
a string length then you partition it by
four
okay
so you got a list of strings
okay then you trim each item
you got a list of streams so you do
stream trim and
slash add that means map that's the
shortcut for the
for them for the map
for the for the map here okay so then
you apply stream trim to each one of the
stack thing then you do
then you do uh then you map again this
time you do uh
string replace okay
you you replace the square brackets so
actually that step can be shortened so
we don't have to map it twice so we just
put stream trim here
okay
okay so the result once you got the
result you drop
the last row because the last row is
just the numbers
once you drop it you do a transpose
you do a transpose so it will become
columns column becomes row so you
actually got a list of stacks you know a
vertical you need some Stacks so after
you transpose then you apply the delete
cases empty string to remove those empty
Stacks okay that's what it is
copy your
paste
rednet
beautiful now it's beautiful each one of
the stack item crate is just a single
character
Okay so
NZ
is the First Column okay the first
vertical the first
how they how they call it there the
first stack yeah
okay so uh I use all fan language
okay we already did almost 80 minutes
back
okay so yeah we got okay we got a list
of stacks now what's next
yeah then then you have to
okay you have to okay let's uh let's
do this quickly
and so how do you turn this into code
okay so that's that's what you have to
do
Okay so
so here's a procedure string
uh then procedure string
[Music]
you know you want to turn these so what
do you want to turn it into what you
want to turn it into is let's turn it
into the Wolfram language code so okay
so what you want to do
uh
move one from two to one pushing pop
Okay so
let's see you know wolfam language
doesn't use
this push pop kind of jargon it uses
append
and prepend and delete uh let me show
you okay
so go through the woofam language
tutorials I have written then you go to
list position in your list get elements
add elements delete elements change
elements let's see add elements so you
can use insert
so but what we really want is push and
pop because that's for Stacks we want to
we have a variable that stands for the
stacks we want to
yeah okay so you can use a pen tool you
can use
you know this this methods are not
efficient in Wolfram language because
wufam language each list whenever you
add item or remove item it has to
regenerate the whole list so it's not
suitable
if you really want to Stack you have to
there are other methods
so if you have you know a real life
programming problem where your stack is
thousands of items I mean you you need
to constantly push and pop then you
should not use a list okay you should
use other ways you know you should not
use any of the prepanned or paint
because that's very inefficient
that's one of the
flaw that's one of the you know major
frequently asked questions when you do
if you do that it's gonna be very slow
but of course for this toy problem even
thousands of items there's no problem I
mean but in real life you have millions
of
uh you know push and pop and it's not
good
so anyway so what are we uh so we we
want to turn this okay so push pop is
one solution which is a PIN pre-pin to
append prepend return a new expression
with new item added okay
yeah and also wolfam language when you
push and pop it doesn't really just
return that item
you know because that's procedural
programming that do that kind of thing I
mean the very concept of push and pop is
procedural language thing in functional
language you don't do that
uh so how do you how do you efficiently
Implement a stack
uh actually I never thought of it in
functional language
well I mean you can do nested list
that's what yeah the the real data
structure at least that's what it's for
so instead of so what you have to do in
ufan language is you started to Nest
list where each list these two items
yeah then then you know then it becomes
just like lisps cons uh
but
anyway so let me look into the problem
so
DD alignment so you can drop
okay this this stack is not a good
you know the push pop is not a good
idiom here
yeah this pushing pop
push and pop is not a good idiom in
Wolfram language
so you
so what should we do then
so change element replace part
okay so actually I have to think about
what what's the best way to do a stack
in a functional language
other than using
cons nested list
um
uh cons is not good you know it's it is
not good in
okay so I don't want to use cons I don't
want to use act you know to implement
nested yeast
uh
so the other alternative in general is
just use a vector you know so called
Vector array you know in
in C language jargon you use array which
means a fixed length
thing
so in this example depends on how big is
a stack it doesn't never it doesn't
actually say
so you might
you know have a fixed stack of 1000
items that's not a good solution you
know because
this is you know yeah well
okay
I think what we're gonna do is just just
use pushing
pop okay just inefficient
okay so first of all pop which what do
you want to do with pop pop is drop
you know it doesn't move from language
doesn't really have that
you know there's no one single function
that Returns the item and you know
so when you do
push your pop in other languages
when you do
pop for example in Pearl in Python in
JavaScript
when you do pop but in Wolfram language
that would become two things that would
become
uh
that will become delete or drop
Plus
get get the first item
okay well
GD by position okay so which one should
I use drop or delete
no because these are functional so they
don't actually
uh modify the variable so you actually
want to use
append to
pre-pint to
foreign
getting too slow here
okay that that gets the first item
and uh
and drop
da these pushing pop is really your
pain in move from language
okay can you use some other data
structure for for the stack
I mean in wolfan language what is the
best way actually this is a good
question I never thought of what is the
best way what is a of an efficient way
to
Implement a stack
in a functional language but without
using nested list without actually
building or nesting at least yourself
well the obvious and obvious answer is
Vector
you you know you have a fixed length
Vector of a big face length but you have
to know what what is the length though
yeah yeah but the problem is you don't
know the length
so then you have to you know presume a
length then if it's beyond you extend it
uh then that's cumbersome that's like
implementing a whole smart array like in
Python Ruby
oh yeah so you can use faster rate oh
wait so in open language you can
actually use because it's a term
rewriting system
yeah you can you can I can do that
yeah
so this is very very boring for you guys
I suppose
uh uh let's see
oh I do have four people watching
still
so what do you guys say
should I go all the way you know dive
into the depth of Wolfram language
or should I you know I'm just mumbling
actually I should really just solve this
problem
uh
okay
okay so now right now I have two choices
simply get it to work you know use
whatever you know it doesn't matter it's
inefficient or actually
use the efficient way the proper Wolfram
language you know idiom to
to represent the stack
so but if I do that
I still need to think about how though
because it's not very obvious
this uh
stack let's see can you use pass array
not really
because you really need a stack it you
know grow and Shrink arbitrarily
uh
you really need a stack and
but you can represent a stack for
example let's say SS let's say St let's
say SS
you can you can you can you can emulate
the stack by
just
um
just do something like that first item
okay
you know this way
you know you are adding let's say ABC
okay
this way this is how you add
let's say stack of three a b c c on top
you can emulate the stack this way this
way
you know you are actually defining wait
not not not two brackets
this way
you know you are technically what you
are doing is that you are seeing a
function whatever as xst argument when
when argument is one you equals to A so
it's using a term rewriting system
whenever you see this replace it with a
whenever you see this suppose your
function with argument two you replace
it with B uh so you are essentially
defining many functions of with a single
constant given argument
but this way you actually you are
emulating a list or a stack
without actually actually having a data
structure of a list so this way you can
you they don't need to be consecutive
you can just have that with the missing
you know a stock stack so but what you
need to just you need to keep track your
you know your indexes that's you have to
manually so to append
so you to append the item let's say
append a new
or you have to say is
four let's say x uh
you know that's you have to keep track
of this index that's how you do a pin
uh and to do
push okay let's say push and to do drop
you just say
to do a job you just say
so easy though
okay you can you can do it you can okay
to do a drop you all you have to say is
that
yeah so this is how you do drug so let's
write it down okay
and this is
okay we are actually I'm not doing good
here I'm just digressing into something
else
who famland has
sharp first
uh
okay so Wolfram language has dropped in
first
that together they are like pop in most
languages
and you have prepared and prepared to
that that are like push uh in most
languages however
like Python and Ruby okay so Wolfram
this is like a smart bet smart Vector
it's not actually it's a smart array
okay
just like Python and Ruby and it is
inefficient if you constantly need to
push and pop and push you know change
the length
thousands of times okay
that is
so but
so
we can
sew a efficient way
to implement stack is by a fixed length
array
of huge
uh
size
with empty
slots are zero or such okay but the
problem with that is that you have to
know you have to have an estimate of
what is your length
okay
for this problem we can actually you
know I'm kind of just digressing but
this problem let's see what's the input
yeah that's small you know you can just
say each one is 50 yeah they don't solve
it but
but I'm digressing
okay so but
another way
more advanced
to
to implement a stack is by
using the term rewriting nature
of who fam language okay and it would be
something like this
example stack okay so let's
failed in this problem
okay something like that
showing browser
so this is about Stacks in Wolfram
language yeah okay but yeah we I'm just
wasting time so let's just do the normal
way let's just use the inner efficient
way
so now we got a stack so we want to
translate into the Wolfram code okay so
let's start to translate this English
into fan language code so move one move
one from two to
move one from two to one
okay move move move so so the the first
number is how many times to do it okay
the second number is the number list
okay so these two stacks so okay so move
one from two to one
how does what is the code that means
so from two
so this is the second list of stacks the
second stack to the first stack so how
do you do that so you want to pop
pop these okay so pop pop is drop okay
so Wolfram language uh
transfers into n Okay so
yeah this is very tedious because who
fan language is a function of
programming language it doesn't change
variables so this drop they just return
the new result
so when you want to do this you act you
have to
drop it get that first I item
then save the draft result into your
list of stacks then push that item into
the second you know stack then you then
you have to save that save your list of
stacks again back
so it's almost two hours back
I failed here I basically this so far
how do I it's here some other way
so move that from two to one is here
some other way then
okay I think I know a better way
so you see oh I found a better way I
found a much better way suitable for
Wolfram language
is that true yes
so instead of using Stacks Stacks is
actually very natural in the standard
structure but instead of using Stacks
you see notice the number of crates
never change
the number of crates never change okay
so you can consider the whole list of
crates as one single list
you never shrink or increase the crates
you know this size you never change the
this size so but
so you need to but you need to you need
to have a separator you know between the
columns so you just add an empty thing
let's say zero
to indicate where each crate separates
but if you do that
so remember the list of crates never
changes
so that actually in fact the the at
least the number of crates can be in
fact can be your stack size the maximum
stack size that's right
so that can be your maximum stack size
yeah so in fact so we can go back to
using the rate idea
so
okay and yeah I want to solve this okay
so what uh what do you do now
foreign
okay here's what we do here's what to do
okay so uh let's just first let's let's
equals to
drop Okay so
yeah this is extremely inefficient this
this is extremely inefficient what we
are doing here
move two to one so
so it's just first
and then this this drop in the take is
not good
foreign
so drop first
prepend
okay so actually
so this is what it is this English
translates to that
uh very very inefficient in open
language
let's see what is preparing argument
expression and element okay so
expression first
okay so that's what move one
two to one means
and you need to actually you need to
Loop this because if this when U comes
to move three
then you need to do this three times
so very bad very very this is extremely
inefficient
so I don't want to do this okay and
extremely inefficient the code is also
extremely ugly this is not
you know again push and pop they are not
functional programming Concepts you
don't do that in commissioner
programming but actually I never thought
of
what is the equivalent though well I
mean well okay the the the the the the
way is you just create Nest at least
just like these pecans cons
okay and I don't want that let's let's
think about the other way now let's
think about
the idea that the create the number of
crates never change
well if you do that then
it's about shuffling
of the zeros and you know let me show
you an example
so if you have a b c d
let's say
uh let's say
okay
[Music]
and
Z
d
C
[Music]
m
so that's one way to represent this
stack
so in this way all you have to do is
just Shuffle Shuffle those
Shuffle those okay
so one two three two two one one two
three so
oh God I I I need to go to the bathroom
any ones you're watching
okay
let's take a break then you know now
it's almost two hours let's let me take
a break and uh
we ran back
yeah I want to finish this problem in
the most efficient way possible
and uh yeah and the more more general
you know I want to do that that's the
point of doing these exercises not just
to get the answer okay so I'll be back
in five minutes
foreign
and back
okay
two hours already
so they are simple way to go now the
problem is in implementing a stack you
know so there are multiple ways okay
this this is turns out to be a more kind
of General problem
so let me just go full out then
the problem
requires
implementing the
data structure
of stacks
okay
it requires a
Instax
not just one but n of them
and
[Music]
snacks
is not a good data structure
in functional programming languages
[Music]
such as
your family
because it requires
change of
data
variable
[Music]
okay
okay and uh
it's not a good data structured in
functional programming languages
okay because it's not a good data
structure
um but most I suppose most programming
languages they have a way already
functional programming language they
already have a idiomatic way to
represent the stack
[Music]
okay so wait so anyway so
one most common way
to
Implement stack
in an efficient way
in functional programming languages
is by
so called list haka
next list of two
things
okay
that is the standard
the standard way to implement stack in
an efficient way in functional
programming languages
is by
by
nested list linked it's called linked
list
okay
that's this cons in fact in Haskell
that's the way you do it too as far as I
know I don't know Haskell but I know a
little bit you know you don't have
arbitrary
you don't have at least in Haskell you
in you have to implement it
by
by Nest by linked list okay
uh
so
can we do that yes of course we can do
that in Wolfram language but I've never
done
um
refresh okay
okay
what
uh something else okay
in functional function is by linked list
okay so
so we can do that or
alternatively
we can Implement stack by
a fixed array
with a fixed size
length okay
and in this case we need not just one
stack we need multiple stacks
okay so it gets it gets tedious
uh and by the way this can also be done
I was going for a walk so this actually
can be done in this way okay
you know represent that
[Music]
um
that's right
two two one so
two two one so one is two and
move one from two to one
right
from two to one
from two to one so
if we paint to one
by
by taking the first item of the number
two
okay
then
then the second stack
two two one is just to drop
the second step
foreign
yeah you can so
yeah so these two lines represent that
thing
or you can also do it this way uh double
check
one two three
two two one yeah one two three yeah you
can do it this way I'll do it this way
this way is more efficient than that one
because that one requires you see the
first
from two to one
you know actually so this is incorrect
what
so the first stack is uh
two two one so the third one doesn't
change okay
so here's a third one that doesn't
change the second one is dropped one the
first one is
you get the first of the second one
then you prepend it to the first one so
you can do it
that way or that way the second one is
more efficient
but both of these are very inefficient
because you are changing the structure
multiple times
not functional programming friendly Okay
so
so we are doing a stack so
um so we talked about stack how do you
how do you implement that
in functional language so
one way the standard way too is a nested
list
so how do we how do we how do you do
that well in Wolfram language you can
say
um
yeah let's take 10 minutes take five
minutes to code it to create a data
structure of a nested list
um
yeah
we can do that though we should do that
but but there are also different ways to
solve this problem
so you can use nested okay let's go back
to writing it out
so
so let's see so
we need multiple Stacks okay
ways to implement a stack in a
functional programming
languages okay
you can use a linked list or
you can use the fixed array with a fixed
length
if you want to do that
the problem here
use 0 to
indicate empty item empty slot okay
the problem here
is when you want to push and
push all pop
you need to
end
where the real item begin
so for example
you can
keep a index
to indicate the wheel the where the real
item begin
because when you pop that means replace
the first item by zero
when you push
means you want to replace the last item
by a new value
okay
pop means pop means
replace the first
and then zero value
by new value
and
by zero
and return that value okay so that's
what pop means
push means replace the
last okay let me paste the
replace the last
Zero by
a new value
Okay so so let's show in browser
let's you know we are starting to write
the blog
okay the problem requires implementing
the stack data structure it requires
multiple number of stacks okay
and stacks is not a good data structure
in functional programming languages such
as full family and because it requires
change of data variable
okay so ways to implement a stack in a
functional programming language there
are several ways the standard way is to
implement to implement stack is a
efficient way is uh
linked list okay
and alternatively we can Implement stack
by fixed array with a fixed length with
zero to indicate empty slot the problem
here is when you want to push your pop
you need to find where the real item
begin so for example you can keep an
index
for example pop means replace the first
and zero value by zero
and return that value okay but you must
find it so each time you know maybe you
have a thousand zeros it takes time to
do that
so alternatively
you can
create a constant you know a variable
that indicates what's the current stack
like a pointer okay the the current and
the zero value
foreign
keep writing it
instead of searching
for the
first none zero you can
search it once
save it as index
okay
okay so that's how you implement stack
by linked list is one way
by fixed array
with zero or other to indicate empty
start okay that's two way
now the Third Way
now that's two way too General to
represent the stack
now
let's just think about write it up in
terms relating system
is to
is
use a
particular
symbolic sequence
for example
let me just write it this out
foreign
painting
input
okay we have now three ways of implement
implementing a stack
Okay so three ways by a linked list
by array with zero order to indicate
empty stocks
slot by a fixed array
okay or in terms of the writing system
use symbol sequence to stand for stack
and its items okay now we can do this is
example of
of using fixed array and the issue we
have to do then here's the example of
using term rewriting uh
let's see let's just write this out
okay maybe that
okay can we do this
so this is one way to do it okay so
let's
uh
yeah just problem
and I'm gonna finish this problem or not
if you want to do this you need you need
to keep manage your variable index
so
yeah it's a problem
so how do you implement push
okay this is this is
this needs to work out you know it needs
a lot of code to actually work this out
um
okay
so that's no good no that's no good
so fast
two hours
and uh why don't we I mean
we could also just try to implement the
nested at least
to start to write code a linked a link
to this
or let's just forget all about that and
just use the drop and
you know
just use these
yeah but this is extremely inefficient
and in elegant and especially when you
want to do these end times so how do you
do these end times so let's do that
do
okay this is how you do it n times
uh
yeah to do it you know one time
yeah so we can you can do this this is
extremely inefficient oh my God in the
pain
so you see move one
from two to one so that one is indicated
here this 2 means just to this number of
times okay so do one and form two to one
so two is indicated here
and one is indicated here
uh in fact if it involves three the code
here will also change
so this is not this is very bad code
because you know you cannot you can tell
because you cannot see there's no
structure doesn't correspond to the
numbers you want a way to exactly
correspond to the numbers
you know in in in in in imperative
programming language it's just so easy
for example you can do a push pop yeah
stack one
yeah that's how you do
so for example in Python
this is
this is in Python okay
uh and uh that's just that line and uh
right
pops the stack at least two two one and
repeat so you do a loop how do you do a
constant Loop
in Python
foreign
Loop exit Loop
well there's no
okay this we can use four in range
so let's
let's write this in Python
there it is
before we ranging so this is
a
m
n p okay so do this m times 4X in range
M times okay you don't care what x is so
you do push
and let's say you have a stack
is just a list right and this is
represented by what
at least oh yeah so square bracket stack
okay so so you all you have to do it
actually so you have a list of these
okay
let's say you have three stacks okay
so all you have to do is push
that and push
push stack from in
pop so pop in
stack based in
and let's get this right okay
that's right so stack list
and see if I want can we yeah this okay
so stack list
God
so stack based
pop the nth stack
can you actually pop no well in Python
you
you pop by it's
um object oriented
so these methods yeah so you object
oriented
so you say this instead
pop okay
and the push is
so you
push
that's it that's that's what you do in
Python okay
yeah you stack this in and stack this p
it's a python code
okay
now that you it's the problem is just
that in Wolfram language it's not
suitable
so bad demonstration so bad
so back so bad because we have we are
trying to
put in a code I need to get back to
doing those when College work slows down
stop on day night first doing it in C oh
my God C
a real men's programming language
okay we we kind of um what am I going to
do now uh
I want to solve the problem okay let's
solve the problem let's not go into you
know
General
philosophy and stuff and it's solve the
problem now let's just try to make this
so you know today that's our solution
but now the problem is just the stacks
let's try to make these somehow more
um efficient it's just let it be so
so what you really need to do is to
represent this thing okay
you see to represent that this is what
you do and More in general so
move
uh let's see how is this python variable
move in
okay let's fix that python this is a
variable naming change okay
mobile P from n to
M2 n okay so this is gonna be P times
and
this we don't use that's a convention
for variables you don't use
and here I believe that works in Python
um let's just say x okay so full uh P
times so uh
pop M to n okay
for M to n do it P times okay that's
right that's python okay
move p
number of times okay
so that's python good okay save it go
back to the Wolfram language code so
move key from
p
number times from
stack M to Stack n the way you do that
is you
a list of stacks uh
m2n so wait
yeah so we need to clean these up really
so
yeah so when you have a general variable
this doesn't work neither
move p number of times so okay so
that is p
easy okay 2p times
from stack M to n okay
stack M2 n okay so all you have to do is
okay yeah now I get it
stack M2 in so stack M and stack in
both changes
okay
so m and n
both of them changed
so the new m
so we want to do n first
so n will be
appended from M okay so yeah
so
pre-pinned
pre-pinned the end
by
m
stack M the first item prepended to the
stack in
okay then the change for m is easy
it's just
okay it's like that
so you have two
um
two procedures
so actually we don't need so simplify it
so much simplified
so do these P times
for each time you want to
to stack in
okay so you prepend
this sub stack so from M to n so from n
m
to one single in
then you then you drop the first item of
the
m
okay that's inefficient but let's make
it efficient okay
with
with is a local variable of constants
okay
so
so first item okay
so you can do that so we move these two
inside
so first item is
first item equals to
okay
it goes through the to the first
then okay
now
yeah this is still
packing efficient
history of ranking inefficient
yeah this is
you know in Wolfram language or any
function of following language you don't
you don't you know the push pop is very
problematic unless you have a nested you
know link linked to this
can you explain why it was inefficient
basically because
in well okay so
so
let me explain Okay so
a stack is a data structure where you
have a kind of array kind of thing you
know a list of items but you constantly
add an item to the front or drop an item
so you so you have two operations delete
an item in the front sometimes in the
back it doesn't matter but you let's
just say in the front Okay so you drop
you can delete one item at a time you
can delete or delete it more you know or
you can add item to the front so every
type so that's the two operation for
stack you know
usually called push or pop push means
add pop means drop
okay and when you do pop you also return
that value return whatever is the first
first item of the
stack okay push and pop you can think of
uh it as a stack of bush books or stack
of dishes you always take the first one
you know you put a new new dish on top
you know you stack them up or when you
take them out you know you from the top
you know stack okay very common data
structure
but when you to implement that usually
so you need some kind of array Or List
depending on what language they mean
different things but in terms of C array
means a fixed list a fixed fixed length
you know
so when you have an array fixed length
number of items
you cannot change the size of the array
okay that's the case for c for Java
so if you need to
push and add an item to the array or if
you need to remove item you essentially
just create a new array so suppose you
have a stack of 1000 items now you're
gonna push one item
okay yes then in C or in Java what
happens that you have to create a new
array you know what they say we allocate
memory so that's a very expensive
process if you have an array of let's
say 1 million items it takes
10 minutes to do it okay
something like that
okay so you cannot change the array so
whenever you want to change the size of
array you have to recreate like create a
new array and replace the value of the
variable something like that okay that
is why that's the data structure of
array
in in the low level C Sense you know the
actual bits you know the electronic you
know that's that's the way it is
so
so what do you so what do you if you
want the list that you can constantly
append or pre-pin you know things
constantly change size
so to do that efficiently you have
several ways okay in the least tradition
what you have is a linked list
so in this you don't actually have a
so a linked list so let me explain what
is a linked list linked list is just a
nested array of
nested
array of two items so you start with the
array of only two items never changes
in fact in this in common disk
in scheming this in emac this that's a
primary data structure
so you have a it's called cons
okay so you have a kind of a thing
that's made of two things it's like just
a fixed length array of two items okay
so if you want to add items you
you Nest the second part you replace the
second part by another array of two
items cons okay
so now you can consider you have a list
of two items
it's hard to explain it takes more time
so that's a basic that's the idea so you
are so creating a list
let's say 10 items what you are actually
doing is that you have an array of two
items the second part
the first part is represents the first
item in your list but the second part is
the array again of two items the first
part of the other that thing represent
the second element of your list and the
third and the second part of that array
is again a nested array array of two
items and so on and so forth so you tell
nesting you tell nesting this a bunch of
array of two items in this it's called
cons c-o-n-s okay
so and at the very
last one the innermost one array of two
items the last
part of the array is Neo that represents
okay there's no more that's it stop you
know that's the end of this nesting
giant huge nesting nested thing of array
of two things you know so that's cons
in this that's called canceling this and
that that this this kind of nesting this
way of nesting data structure is called
linked list
okay it's called linked list
and in Haskell so this is one way this
is one way to
to have a efficient data structure at
least like data structure where you can
always add things and remove things
constantly push and pop efficiency
because every time you remove the item
all you have to do is you just
just just delete the first array so you
you don't change anything you just
remove the first array you just you just
get this the you know remember array
just two items you just get the second
part you ignore the first part you know
so that's how you drop
and add is very very easy too you just
add another array so
constant time so it's constant time so
but the problem with linked list is that
you can only add to the front or drop
from the front if you want to get the
nth item
then that's problem that you have to
start to set you know count the index
and see the nth nesting
the first element of the nth nesting is
your nth element in your list okay that
is the linked list
uh in fact this this linked list thing
array Vector what's the difference
that's a big topic okay and it took me
10 years to actually
really understand it okay so let me just
point you to Wikipedia linked list
uh linked this data structure Wikipedia
okay
so there's you know so you can see you
see that each one of those squares
reverse is like an array of two items
the second part
is again array of two items
and so on and so on and so on so at
least
to represent the list or you know a
sequence of elements you actually just
Nest this
cons
very extremely idiotic okay this
and and so this allows you to
very efficiently add one element in the
front you know always just push or drop
one element in the front very efficient
but if you want to insert to the end
position that's not that's very
inefficient or if you want to get the
nth element very inefficient because
every time you have to Traverse this
nesting until you reach that so that's
one way that's one way to implement
uh sequence kind of thing
and the advantage with linked list is
that you can
quickly do push and drop
efficiently but if you want to random
access varying efficient okay so another
way is just with a standard array of
size n fixed length you can never change
the size if you want to change size you
the the language has to recreate the
whole array you know so that the
advantage is that it's very fast to get
nth element okay that's a very fast to
get the nth element however
it's very expensive when you want to
delete some element doesn't matter in
front in back or as something insert
something because it has to recreate the
whole array
very expensive when you when the array
is large like one 10 000 items okay
so let's so so you can you know look at
this article that's that's about that
array okay
so we are talking about different
implementations for kind of a sequence
or collection kind of thing so a raised
one
linked list another one
another solution which is what python
Ruby JavaScript they at least they they
are so called away you know each
language have different names but
but JavaScript
python
Ruby
their list or their array is a smarter
play so what they do is that they
basically have an array of fixed length
but they keep a variable that indicates
what's the current Max
number of items in the list okay so if
you are going to add an element then it
checks if that's beyond the current
array size if it is then it recreate the
entire array very costly but however it
does that it just double the size so if
your current array is size 8
and if you want to add one more element
then it's very costly it says oh you are
you know it's beyond so I'm going to
create a new array of
16 elements so a lot more room doing I'm
gonna do this one time so yeah it's slow
but I'm gonna do it one time but however
I give you
you know seven more extra space so you
can work with it
so what those empty spaces they just put
zero they put some special value
but they keep track you know they keep
track you know what's the current Max
number the actual number but they
actually have something hidden you don't
see it so they represent that these
things what there's no proper name to it
I just call it smart array
so it's a ray but with the wrapper you
know so you don't see the hidden element
so the advantage is is of these smart
array is that it's very fast to get any
nth element and you it's also
fast to either append or prepared
depending on how it's implemented very
fast
but if you want to insert something in
the middle
again that depends on implementations so
but basically they avoid recreating the
whole array
so but if you keep adding elements let's
see let's say to the front or the button
or the end
you know
anytime
it's beyond the size it has you just
recreate the array with a lot more empty
uh values so it so it reduces the number
of times you have to
kind of recreate the array okay that's
one solution this solution is used by
I think every almost every language
python JavaScript
uh
Ed Ruby at least okay smart array you
know they just call it they they may
call at least already at you know
depends on the language okay smart array
uh in wolfam language case I think it's
also a smart array okay
um
yeah
so why am I first about this because
well it's just not um
I shouldn't worry too much about it I
should just I should have just coded
this you know in a beginning and save
three hours of talking
stretchy buffer oh okay that's uh that's
a new term so
okay so this all right this data
structure you know actually that this
this is you know let me explain this is
this person me for over 10 years for for
about 15 years or 20 of my programming
life I don't understand it like what
because this this is this is not
mathematics okay let me let me explain
this one this is one of my it took me 20
years in heated argument with the
coders in C plus plus coders
about this because
this C C plus plus Java this type of
coders they know this well they are very
excited about this but they don't
understand the mathematical concept let
me explain
so mathematically they are just a
sequence of things why so why is it that
you know for what reason what is the
reason that when you have a array you
know the CRA fixed size what is the
reason where you when you have an array
it is constant time to constant Random
Access time
that doesn't make sense
I mean suppose you got given an abacus
Abacus is a computer
you know
or a turing machine
why is it constant access time when you
have a raised data structure let's say
you want to get the 1 millionth item
don't you have to move the needle you
know until it reaches one millionth
right
but that's not the case what so why is
it constant nobody can explain this this
C C plus plus idiots they don't know
they cannot explain
but they can they can they can just tell
you it's constant okay that's just how
computer works
the reason
it works that way
is because the way the electronics the
CPU the memory the memory the way the
memory is actually
because it's actually just parallel
computation by Nature the the way the
memory is implemented happens to be
parallel for array okay so there is a
article
let me show you
so search for Saudi array constant time
so this this puzzled me for like 15
years and eventually one day I found the
answer
you know so this article why is array of
says constant time this compiler writers
they cannot explain you know you read
you know in fact or just about all
textbooks even Wikipedia you know even
Wikipedia you know you go to you read a
radial structure I have a screenshot of
it okay so it says they effectively the
re so why is the reason why is it
constant
Wikipedia says they effectively exploit
the addressing logic of computers that's
it
why is array access constant
so you go to Wikipedia you know and it
has
you know 10 pages about it but why is it
constant
the only answer it says it's just this
sentence they effectively exploit the
addressing logic of computers what what
the the that does that mean
an abacus is a computer how is it
how does you know you can have Abacus
you know it's consider each column as a
array the first row how is it constant
you know even with your fingers you have
to move you know one millionth column is
you have to move all the way there how
is it constant
so Wikipedia says they effectively
exploit the addressing logic of
computers which is
not a good answer you know what what
computers
DNA computer is a computer content
computer is also a computer what do you
mean logic of computers they mean Logics
they are exploit the addressing logic of
electronic computers of the way we
happen to implement the memory that's
what they actually mean and even that is
without explanation
so one day I found this you know in 2016
I found this blog here okay why is
indexing faster than binary search by
this Chinese guy he's kind of famous
famous Chinese programmer very famous
very popular among the China programmer
community in Wang that's his name he has
a Blog in in English okay
he explained it I I read this oh my God
this this literally solved a question I
have for about 20 years or 15 years
why why is array access constant
because the the way the electronics
the memory implementation of the memory
so happens it's parallel okay it's just
parallel computation this you don't have
to count until the median you know you
just parallel the way electronic works
okay you can see the diagram so that's
why that is why
array access is constant time
and this is not mathematics okay there's
not there's zero mathematics in this
there's no it's not a mathematical
property it's just the electronics
engineering happenstance okay on Abacus
is it true but you have array it's
constant time no
on a chewing machine is it true when you
implement arrays constant time no
okay so this is just it just so happens
on the electron the digital machine you
know you have this
but however all the textbooks doesn't
matter algorithms textbook I don't know
about Ruth
book but you look at all the textbooks
data structure they don't they don't
have one you know they don't have one
lie that explains why
they just tell you that array access is
constant time abandoned Random Access
Okay so
so this is the rent that's this this is
why you know I'm kind of stuck on this
because I don't want you know because I
have my
I'm trying to get over you know I'm
trying to find a better way to implement
the stack
but anyway today it's been three hours
and I rented a bunch but I haven't
solved the problem
very bad
uh so thanks for expanding uh sometimes
called Vector yeah so in emac this you
also have Vector but it's not
in emac this and in common disk you have
a thing called vector and that is just C
array so it's very confusing you know so
I have another article
about
what does least array Vector you know
things mean in different languages
anyway
basically because the address circuit in
the CPU runs in constant time okay yes
you have the address the memory uh first
a position of the vector in first sum
value
okay uh
so that in one experience that adding
two numbers of three bits would be the
same time as adding to a number of 60
bits yeah
yeah I don't know I don't know the low
level of CPU much I started to learn
about that but anyway so
I want to I want to end the video but I
failed in getting this solving the
problem of today
so does this work actually let's forget
about that
I mean does this work let me maybe I can
finish in five minutes let's hope okay
let's just put that there
so
does this work first item equals true so
from stack M to stack in so
stack him
massage
so you drop it
and then you
resubstack then you prepend right yeah I
think this works but okay so even this
works then we need to
we need to convert
we need to write code to convert this
string
to um
to this okay so we need to convert that
to that okay
um
yeah too bad
that's gonna take another at least 10
minutes
um that's it for today
okay yeah new chance to learn so
it's too long today three hours already
so let's that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
uh yeah interesting stuff
okay bye guys
so so what we have is a bunch of
you know extraneous discussion I'll have
to you know many but we have some very
interesting questions today
about how do you implement a stack
in a functional programming language
you know in Haskell in this fight I know
for sure they just use linked these
uh
okay bye bye guys
you're still here thank you