Good morning. Good morning.
Uh welcome to another episode of Sound
Talk Show.
We are going to code JavaScript today.
Uh let's see see So, keyboard, this is
ultimate hacking keyboard 80, UHK80.
Fantastic. Check it out on my YouTube
uh review, okay?
Uh audio check, video check. So, we are
going to code
JavaScript today.
Okay? Those of you came here because of
the pretty girls that's generated by AI,
okay? So, you can see
Guoq today is generating like huge
amount of girls. Um
you know, like you huge amount. Like you
ask it a question, it generates like
uh 20
pictures.
So, I'm asking it to generate Chinese
woman from Beijing with Chun-Li hairdo
wearing a cheongsam that says JS at top,
JavaScript.
So, actually that's not my prompt. My
prompt was um you know, draw a Chinese
girl
from Beijing with Chun-Li hairdo wearing
a cheongsam that says So, I said draw a
Chinese girl, but it changes to Chinese
woman.
So, anyway, you can see
it just generates tons of pictures. And
for each one, you can click on the uh
play and we'll make a video.
And and by the way, previously I was
asking it to
you know, to draw a hot Chinese girl
wearing a
red halter tops that says
JS, okay? Then it generates a bunch of
these.
>> [laughter]
>> Kind of soft porn. I don't want to
scroll up, okay?
You know, I cannot use that for my
YouTube thumbnail.
But so, my point is that Guoq, you know,
the guoq.com AI, they generate images
that
um
that you know, that that
you know, when you when you generate
images of girls, they tends to be
hot, you know?
Anyway, so
so that like like if if you don't want,
you know, too sensitive a picture, you
have to actually try to tone it down.
Otherwise, it generate pictures you
cannot use. So, anyway, so that's the um
that's Guoq. So, any you know, any of
these picture Let's try one of them,
okay? Let's see, you know, let me
demonstrate the Guoq
um artificial intelligence AI
uh the state of the art. Actually, by
next month it's going to be something
else. It's changing so extremely fast,
okay?
Uh so, let's see, you know
So, why do I ask Beijing
girl?
You know, why why do I pick Beijing? For
no particular reason. It's only because
like when you ask a general question,
then it generates a bunch of
like the you know, the pop thought
girls, you know, that kind of look.
I don't want that look. So, that's why I
choose you know, so that's why I'm
specific about like
draw a Beijing girl.
So, anyway, you can see some of these
funky things. You see, I ask it to
imprint JavaScript JS on the cheongsam.
Uh but
but so so it did it here, but because
this is so unusual, it didn't do it on
on the the other ones. But some of them
that you see, they didn't do it, but
they they just printed at the top of the
picture, you see. And this one you see
very uh creative, you know, they kind of
tried to put JS on on that image on the
uh on the cheongsam.
And also here, you can see her color.
Okay, wait.
Uh
Let me go down. Okay, so anyway
um
Well, so so let's do you know, let's
just you know, hit There is another JS
there.
Uh let's do this one. This one, she is
hot, okay? Let's see what kind of
animation do we get?
If you are watching here, say hi in a
chat.
If you are watching offline, play 1.5
speed. Wow, look at that.
Amazing.
Let's hide it, okay?
Oh, and save. Okay, so it's like it's
auto saved.
What amazing thing.
Wow.
It's just amazing. It anatomically
correct. Like I was looking at
you know, the the the uh anyway, so
there it is, okay?
Uh okay, so so that's about the China
girl.
So, we are going to do code JavaScript,
okay? So, today so here's uh Sound Talk
Show today.
Uh
and I haven't fixed my website yet, so I
cannot update my website. It hasn't been
updated for
uh almost 2 month now.
Anyway.
So, for those of you know me, so I got a
website xahlee.info.
Okay, so
Hello. Hello, JJ.
So, xahlee.info, let's go to
uh
x a h l e e
Unicode.
Okay? Just search for that, you'll find
it, okay? Then you can go to my website.
Okay, then you can you know, one of the
greatest Unicode website. You can type,
let's say w a t e r, then you get all
Unicode whose name contains the word
water or fire or whatever.
Okay, so so the Unicode page, let's just
get down to what we want to do today.
So, this is going to be boring. It's
JavaScript coding, okay?
Uh where are you from, JJ? I don't
remember uh you.
So, JavaScript coding, let's just get on
to JavaScript coding, okay?
So, I want to do So, this is a good
page. This this page is about characters
that are used for user interface, okay?
So, you got this bar at the top. You can
you can make you can make it show
symbols or emoji. You see, because some
Unicode characters
they
can be shown as both emoji or text. For
example, the watch used to be text. Then
they they they made it to be also emoji.
For some characters. So, this is
actually a very complicated issue. Let
me just show you, okay? So, shown as
emoji
uh
show a symbol, so you can see all these
become using symbol font. You see this
watch and hourglass, you see they became
symbols. Um
But you can click um go back to
what?
Symbols or emoji, you can click emoji
then they become emoji.
So, you can see that. You can also show
names, so you can see each character
shows all their names, so you can
search, for example power.
Um
Okay, hide names and uh using Google
font or using Microsoft font, you see
they look different, okay? So, for
example, you go to faces
uh
use symbol font, it become like that.
Some of them they don't become symbols
because they are always emoji,
complicated, okay?
Anyway, so you can use uh show as emoji,
then you can choose show it using
Google's font or using Microsoft font
or using Apple's font, which is not
available on my computer.
Okay, so you got this bar.
But sometimes like you are down here,
but I Now, I want to see what does this
looks like in symbols font or do they
even have a symbols representation? So,
you need to go up
then click, then go down.
Uh where are they? You see, it's so it's
it's an issue.
You know, you you want to see them as
emoji, so you need to go up, then click
emoji, then you go down, where are they?
You know, so I want to change this bar
so that
so that there's a button that says
toggle. It it it will like
you you click it, it will pop up like
and show on the top or you know, stick
to the window side.
Then click again, it will pop
back to the page. So, that's what we
want to do, okay? That's what we're
going to do.
From Appleton, Wisconsin. Oh, okay. So,
I I think I
uh was it you before talking on Discord
somewhere someone from Wisconsin?
Yeah, make make a copy.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, so
um
JavaScript. So, have you coded
JavaScript before? Are you a web dev?
So, let's code that. Okay, so
So, Unicode, so that code is
that code is right here, okay?
So, you got Let Let me show you Let me
show this
um separate. So, that
become
So, it looks like that, okay? So, you
got
you got this one component div. Then you
the second component they they are pick
font.
Uh then you got
you got uh JavaScript, okay? Now, let's
open the Java So, let's delete that.
Okay, same you know, this is just one
single line. Let's open that. So, this
file is actually TypeScript. So, you can
see TypeScript. It compiles to
JavaScript. I'm coding in TypeScript,
okay?
So, uh version So, what So, what
So, what this button do, you see, is
that it Let me explain what it does,
okay? So, there is no by default it
doesn't you know, this doesn't exist.
The JavaScript will insert that. So, the
JavaScript will first of all find um
Okay, so
So, you you see there is uh well
let me show that. So, you see that's the
div ID. That's where JavaScript will
insert.
You see
wait.
Font pick panel, that is this panel.
So, over here it's it's text.
Okay, then you just insert it.
Okay, so you can see
inner HTML, you just
document.getElementById
pick font, then inner HTML equals to
that. So, basically it just
um
it just insert it into this div element.
Hold on a sec.
That is my alarm clock.
Today's drink is tea.
So far, so good.
Okay, so
So, it just insert, okay? So, let let me
look at the code, okay?
Um
So, the code code is very short.
And just
insert that.
Then show name 140 is the show name.
Does that appear anywhere else?
Oh, okay. So, that is the
Yeah, so that
Okay, I'm getting
No, I'm getting kind of discouraged.
Because
I'm running into this issue.
Uh the issue is it's somewhat
complicated, you know, I I need to
make this talk show such that
you guys understand what I'm doing. So,
the issue is
I can do this when I want.
But if I just do it, you guys don't know
what I'm doing. So, it's very boring.
It's It's boring anyway.
Anyway, the alternative ideal situation
is that
while I code, I also explain step step
by step, so you guys understand what's
going on.
Uh that is ideal situation, okay?
So, we need to do
Let me try to do that, okay? But doing
that is not so trivial because
Okay, let me try to do that. So,
we want to um
Yeah, so do we actually have it written
down?
You see, we want to um write code to
toggle
a widget. Okay, so Let me Let's make it
better.
Write JavaScript code to toggle a user
interface
widget.
Either
uh you know, into
a fixed position relative to viewport.
Okay, that's what we want to do, okay?
Remove the to-do.
Show.
Okay, that is what we want to do. Remove
Remove the date.
Okay.
And uh
So,
So, that is the page and uh the job
right now. So, you
So, you need to
um
So, should I explain what does the
JavaScript do?
Uh So, anyway, on this page you got this
div.
Uh then you got JavaScript. The
JavaScript will just insert um
insert this
the whole
user interface widget, okay? In this
line.
Once you insert the user interface in uh
widget, then the rest of it is about
uh input box, the radio box, um
Um
Okay, so you cannot see well.
It's because
So, anyway, so you So, you got this
bunch of radio box, then you got this uh
you got this checkbox, which is the uh
show name, okay? So, you can see that is
this this box, show name.
Okay, so you can check symbols, emoji
symbols, okay? So, that's this
text. This is a JavaScript. This That's
a string, okay? That's called template
string.
You see, because of this uh because of
that backtick character, that's called
grave accent.
Okay, there.
Uh So, that's a template string
JavaScript. So, you just insert that
into the you know, H uh inner HTML, then
the show name
uh is one of these uh you know, that's
the show name um
box.
Okay, so if So, you get the ID, get the
element. That's how you get element.
Then
then um
So, this is a toggle function, yeah?
Toggle function there.
So, when when this function is called,
if the show name is null, just return
it. Okay, otherwise um
No, yeah, show in case in case that
widget is not there.
Just um
kind of safety coding. It should always
be there. So, you know, So, that's this
So, if show show name 140 is checked,
then
um
then call the function show info. So,
show info will actually functions here.
It will
um
Okay, it will do
Why is there a space? It will basically
array from query select all Unicode. So,
select all
elements that has the class Unicode
Excel or emoji Excel.
Select all of them and
uh
array from
array from 10 daily. So, what?
Then Oh, yeah, then apply this add info.
Um
function, okay? Then you add info. So,
actually So,
So, for each of the
element that is a Unicode or or emoji,
you call the function
you call the function add info.
Okay?
Which is there. So, it's it's a bit
complicated.
Add info.
So, so for each character So, do you
guys see what I'm saying? Hello.
Hello Dam Sik. Hello Diego.
So, do you guys see what I'm doing? It's
a bit complicated.
You know, do you guys watch other
people's JavaScript live stream? Like I
wonder how they do it. I mean
you know
like
um
because I think it's
complicated and I'm afraid
I'm not doing a good job explaining it
because
it's almost impossible.
Unless you already know JavaScript, then
then you know, you look at my code, you
kind of understand right away.
But otherwise, if you are new to
web dev, like you wouldn't have any idea
what I'm doing.
That's That's what I think.
I mean, you have vague idea, but it's
it's fairly complicated. Okay, so
JavaScript. Anyway, so let's you know,
we have to do this. So, let's go move
on. So, add info.
Add info, you
you
you need to
Okay, so it's a bit complicated. You
see, you go to the you see
So, for example, you go to this page,
you see this Unicode, right? So, how are
they implemented? They are done like
this. So, you can see there's a Unicode.
Uh it has a span tag wrapped around it.
This is a power symbol. This is Unicode
name. And here's the title. Title is the
the value of the title is the Unicode
code point in hexadecimals in standard
notation and its name.
Um so, for each Unicode character, it's
implement you got a span. Okay?
So, and and each one has a class Unicode
excel or
either that or emoji excel. So, this
this section is a mouse pointer. So, you
can see
there.
See?
Now, is mouse pointer actually emoji?
Uh no.
So, that's a mistake. So, you know, it
should be just Unicode.
Anyway, so
So, for each Unicode character, you got
this span.
Then
then what? Then
um
then you see this this code, it gets a
title.
Why? Because that's the title, you know,
the value of the title contains Unicode
name and the Unicode uh
code point.
So, that's why it gets a title because
it you need to So, then you extract the
name.
So, you can see you extract the Unicode
name somewhere.
Uh
so, get the title value of the title.
So,
then
um
Right, then you create a new na- new
node. Then all you do is just insert the
node. So, so you can see So, insert
after
insert after the X X is the um
um
Get attribute title. So, what is the uh
X X X is whatever
the current element. Okay, so that's So,
what happens is is that you click on
show name.
This is what happens. Click click click.
Click. You see it inserts this
the value from the title
attribute.
That's what it does. Okay? So, that's
this function add info.
Uh
Okay, so we kind of explain how this
show name works.
Right? Does that make sense, guys?
I scanned JavaScript the good parts.
Okay, that's very good. That's a good
book. That's a great book, but that's
very old. That That book is like
I think 15 years old was it 20 years
old?
And JavaScript has changed tremendously.
So, even if you have read that book in
detail 20 20 years ago, it doesn't work
today.
Yeah, JavaScript has changed
tremendously and uh
and web dev, you know, it is very
complicated. Hello ACP, makes sense.
Okay.
So, so we got this widget. Okay, so we
explain how the show name works. Okay?
Then you got this uh the other things uh
font um emoji.
So, those those part Yeah, so let me
explain. So, those uh those together are
these radio
buttons. They are called radio buttons
because if you click one of them, the
other one
pops up. You know, it's
which means only one of them can be
selected. You see? Emoji show us emoji
or show us symbol or us emoji or use
Google font. You see?
So, um
So, that's this this Okay, so
So, when you click on them, let's say
you click on symbol. So, what happens is
that So, you see
you see that when you click on symbol,
that's that.
Um so, then you have a event viewer.
Okay, so let me show you.
So, you see here
is a section where I add all the events.
Okay, so array from
uh font
font button 15. What is that? Yeah, so
you see these are radio boxes and they
have a name
font button 15. 15 is just a random
number to make the name unique.
Okay? So, you got
you know, so all these radio boxes, they
have the font button 15 as their name.
So, you select all of them.
Uh wait, so you see uh
This is This is how you get the element.
Query select all
font font button 15. Okay, so you select
all of them.
I mean, that's the element, the radio
box. Okay?
Then you
then you um for each Wait.
For each of them
you run this function. And what this
function do? It add event listener
input.
So, whenever
each one of these uh
radio buttons are changed, that's the
in- event. I mean, input. So, whenever
they get a input
you call the function if change fonts.
Okay?
Now, ignore that force that last
argument. That's for something I forgot,
but
unimportant. That's there because of
history of the web. Very complicated.
Add event is listener.
Add event listener is a function
in the browser. Okay, that's not part of
JavaScript, but it's a function in the
browser.
Uh so, anyway, so
So, for each of these radio button
elements
whenever there's a event of input, means
like user click on it you then you call
the function change font. Okay? Now,
let's look at that function.
So, here is the function and what the
function do? So, the function do this
thing.
Not long, okay? But um
You see, it So, what the function does
is it just um
it just First of all, um
it
get all elements
of font button 15.
Get those that has the status of
checked. Okay? So, that means the
current checked
element. Okay?
So, once you get that, so that will be
assigned to X val. Wait. This this
thing. Okay? So, and what is the value?
That the value would be just like the
value here. So, the value is either
symbol or emoji or Google or MS or
Apple. Okay?
So, let's go back.
Yeah, so that's that's
that's this X val. It's a string.
Uh you see checked and dot. So, this is
JavaScript. This is functional
programming style JavaScript. So, very
uh kind of very dense and advanced.
So, that's the you know, that's X val is
either
is a string that says symbol or Google
or
Microsoft or Apple.
So, then
you select all elements that's a class
name Unicode or emoji, which means
you know, any of the Unicode characters.
Then for each one of them, you call this
function. And what does function do?
Is that if the value is equals to
symbol, that means you want to show um
all the Unicode symbols.
Then you change, you know, the the style
attribute.
And the font family value change it to
um
to this this line, okay? So, it's either
Segoe UI Symbol, that's uh
that's uh
font for Microsoft for symbols, for
Unicode symbols. So, you can change it
to Apple symbols. So, if that the first
one doesn't exist, then you use Apple
symbols. If that doesn't exist, then you
use Noto Sans Emo symbols, too.
So, anyway, the
why, you know, so these are font names.
These are fonts
for Unicode symbols. So, they are kind
of technical. You have to know exactly
which one they are.
You have to do research. So, I, you
know, I've done so, so I know on
Microsoft Windows,
their default symbol font for Unicode
is Segoe UI Symbol.
Okay? Then, for Apple's, it's Apple
symbols. For
And Google Google has a symbol font,
you know, you can download from Google
or any laptop that's from Google, like
Google Chrome laptop,
meaning Google Chrome OS.
So, Noto Sans Symbols 2 is one of the
another popular um
emoji for Unicode symbols. Now, what
what are Unicode symbols? Unicode
symbols are
uh uh this kind of this character, you
know, this, you know, technical symbols.
Some of them are also emoji. That's why
you, you know, that's why it's a bit
complicated, but um
you know, I I have a blog on that, um
but let's not go there, okay? So,
anyway,
so, the point is that you have to know
So, Unicode symbol, you know, Unicode
Unicode uh symbols, for example, these
punctuations, so, of course, they are
a lot of them are considered as symbols,
okay? They are not emoji. So, if even if
you say emoji font, you see some of them
are not emoji. They never become emoji,
you know,
while some of them became emoji.
Okay, the reason for that, okay, let me
actually explain that. The reason is
because it's very complicated. It's a
basically a Unicode fuck-up, okay? So,
you go [snorts] to the Unicode search my
website, xahlee.info,
Unicode.
Okay, you go to xahlee.info, then you go
down, then you go to you look at the
Unicode,
uh then you go down uh to the bottom
on the left panel, the navigation bar,
you can see
uh
miscellaneous index, okay?
Then here, you can see there's article
um [snorts]
So, it's all these are uh interesting
uh
issues about Unicode. So, one of the
articles is named Unicode Emoji versus
Text.
Okay? So, sometimes around 2000 uh
18,
Unicode made a huge change so that
symbols
now become emoji for some symbols, okay?
So, so it became very confusing. For
example, if you, you know, use Unicode
symbols for
the, for example, the keyboard speaker
volume up or volume down,
or next song, previous song, stop, or
mute, you know,
>> [snorts]
>> you are writing an article, so you are,
you know, tell maybe a tutorial telling
people how to
uh
a particular keyboard, you know,
technical documentation, let's say.
Then all of a sudden, they become these
emoji, they become pictures. So, it's
that's very annoying. You don't want
that, especially in mathematics. For
example, if you are writing mathematics,
then some of the symbol become like
colorful pictures.
So, this happened
very bad.
And now it is considered a mistake,
okay? Unicode Consortium, the
corporation, I mean, the organization
that
created Unicode
in 1989 or so, they now consider this a
mistake.
So, what exactly happened is that they
uh what they did is that they um
you know, so they they made some
characters
to represent
both emoji and
text
by using the same character.
So, that that is why, for example, you
know, this um
ne- uh let's say play and pause
button.
I mean, that character, okay? Like
before, you know, it was a symbol, but
sometimes people wanted to be like a
picture emoji, right?
So, one way to do it is you just create
a new symbol for the emoji
version of that. But they decided to use
the same symbol.
And they decided so they they create
they created a uh
a so-called invisible variation
selector.
So that if you want emoji, then you add
a invisible character
after the character you want, then it
should be shown in emoji.
If you want it to be a represented as a
text version, you have to add this
invisible variation selector character,
you know, right after it, then it should
should be shown as text, okay? So, for
example, we can see some of the
variations um
uh for example, this uh right and left
arrow.
Left right arrow, Unicode.
Um 2194 in hexadecimal, you can see.
You can it, you know, that character can
be shown as emoji or as text.
And some other
uh characters such as trademark symbol
and others in football, okay?
So, anyway, so so so they created this
variation selector as a way to decide,
you know, whether you want it to be
shown as emoji or text. But that's
that's not all, but because it is very
complex. So,
the- so then but, you know, so for every
Unicode character, they they have like
they they
they specify whether this character can
be shown
as both text or emoji. In other words,
it has both versions. Or for some
characters, they have both versions,
okay? Can be emoji or text. And they
specify it should default to emoji
if you do not use any of the, you know,
variation selector.
Okay, you guys know what I'm saying.
So, for some characters, they can be
shown as emoji and text. And they
default to emoji.
For other set of characters,
they can be shown as emoji or text, but
they default to text
by Unicode specification, okay?
Then for some other characters, they are
always shown as emoji. There's no text
version, okay? These are examples.
Then
Okay, then that's it. Then for the rest
of the characters, there's only text
version, okay? So, they created this
variation extremely complex. There's no
way for you to know, like given a
Unicode character, whether
you know, that character can be shown as
emoji,
I mean, whether it has emoji version or
not.
And there's no way to tell if that
default supposed to default to emoji or
text,
like whether you need to add, you know,
add the variation, the invisible
character. Extremely complicated, you
know, you have to add a invisible
character right after that character.
So, this this is a major problem. And in
fact, you know, most of the website, for
example, Twitter, they don't actually
respect this
in- variation selector. Even if you
use it correctly, you know, after all
this ordeal, you use it correctly, they
doesn't
you know, if you specify, you know, they
doesn't do it. Like most of the time,
they just show it as emoji.
Okay?
So, this created This is a huge problem.
So, and now it is understood as a
mistake. Unicode Consortium, you know,
it's recognized as a mistake.
They should have just have separate um
characters, you know, like a separate
character if you want a emoji
version.
Um so, okay, so that's about that, okay?
So, emoji versus text, okay?
Uh so, now but let's go back.
Let me answer that question. So yeah, so
in um
So ACP says about the HTML input
element. Uh, that that is because this
is this is um
This is from This is because TypeScript,
okay?
That's why you have that. That is a
TypeScript thing. So in TypeScript, if
you don't put this
then when you compile it, you'll tell
you say error. For example, let's
compile the code, okay? Compile it.
Uh,
you see command shell command
successful. Can you see?
Uh, so you can see
uh, running TSC, that's a TypeScript
compiler.
Uh, target [clears throat] 2021
successful. And I run it in Emacs
because I'm using
Where is the command? You see exit
JavaScript TypeScript compiled file.
That is a
describe function
press the key describe key, so that is
the
that is my Emacs code. So you can look
at the source code. So that is So I call
this
Emacs this command
to
then it in turn it calls the type
TypeScript compiler
to compile
the TypeScript to JavaScript, okay?
Let's do it again. So let's go to the
So you can see
Here's a JavaScript. Open it. Delete it.
Refresh, okay? JavaScript is done. Now
open the TypeScript. Open it.
Press
tab C.
Compile successful.
Go down. Refresh. Now you can see that's
the
JavaScript compiled JavaScript code. Now
you see in the compiled JavaScript code,
you don't see that uh, HTML input
element.
Uh, that's only in TypeScript because if
you remove this, for example, let's
remove it.
Delete it, okay? Now save. Compile it.
It'll say error.
Error TS2339
property value does not exist on the
type element.
So TypeScript is very type sensitive,
you know, it has to check, you know, so
that that is why you have to add that.
Kind of a hack. I mean It it's a
problem, you know, it's very annoying.
Like every time like
why do I get that error? You don't know
how to solve it. You have to search the
web. Then people say, oh, you by the
way, you need to force
you know, you need to force this into
HTML input element type. And what What
are these types, you know, these are the
DOM, so-called document object model
things.
They are very complex because they are
like
20 years, 30 years baggage. So like you
don't even like very few people actually
know like which which element is like a
subset of, you know, like a hierarchy
object hierarchy of some other like you
don't even know. And and and lots of
history and baggage, so it's not very
clean. It's like very complicated.
So in TypeScript, you know, so that then
you find out, oh, you just, you know,
you just add this, okay? And also
um, now that we are talking about this,
you know, also there's a two different
syntax.
One is you
you know, you do the angle bracket less
than sign and greater than sign, okay?
In front of whatever type you want to
um
cast.
You know, that's a C and C++ idiots'
jargon.
Uh, cast, you know, they call it type
type casting, you [ __ ] idiots.
So these are the bit fiddlers'
convention, okay? This this kind of idea
came from the bit fiddlers from the C
[ __ ]
Okay?
As anyway, so but in TypeScript you you
have two syntaxes. One is like you put
the type like and enclose them in the
less than greater than symbol in front
of it. Or another way is you say as then
then the type, okay?
So
So let me digress. So on this particular
issue, I don't think it's first, you
know, from a language design
in
in you know
I believe in language design, you do not
want to have multiple ways to do the
same thing.
So in my opinion, one one of these
syntaxes should be eliminated. You know,
you shouldn't have like, oh, by the way,
you can also write it in this way. So
one of these ways, you know, write it
write the type after, you know, followed
by as keyword, okay? So my opinion is
that you should not
have more than one way to do things in
general, okay? That's one thing.
Now the other then another separate
issue is that when I learned about this,
I always preferred uh, this way.
You know, we could because I think, you
know, adding a as keyword you know, you
you got as, you know, as keyword. I
don't I
don't think it's good.
But actually now I prefer this because
this as keyword
is part of English. You can search for
it, you know, you can search for
example, you can like
uh, what?
You know, you you can you can start to
search grep, you know, English words.
So one one of the syntaxes is using
English words, then
you know, then the type. So the other
way is you use, you know, this basically
uh
punctuation. This kind of you know,
syntax.
So I think
these days I think, you know, using the
same English word is better, okay?
Um
because syntax, if you use syntax, it's
hard to search. For example, all these
are syntaxes, you know, arrow.
You know, the the the arrow function
equal greater than or the block
or or semicolon or, you know, all these
are special syntaxes or the triple
equal.
So you can In fact, you can change all
your function names. I mean I did I mean
in in a in a way, in a sense, when you
design a programming language, you can
make all your programming
uh, language functions like for each of
array from or add event listener or if,
you can change them all just to syntax.
So you never have English words in your
language. Like also return, you know,
you can you can create your language
such that, for example, two semicolons
means return.
So you can change all
you can create a programming language
such such that it doesn't use any
sequence of English letters at all
because this every function is done as
an operator. You can do that.
So that that language that would be
hell, okay? Actually that actually not
you know, that language would be APL.
APL
is like that. Um, okay. So, you know, I
have actually have an article. Uh, let
me show you the article. Um
Should I show the article? Yeah, we are
digressing, okay?
Okay, so let me let me just show you
APL. So I have APL is a programming
language, so um yeah.
APL, this is APL programming language
characters. It's known by this famous
for the weird symbol it uses.
So here is sample APL code, okay?
Sample APL
code. So it's like
impossible to kind of incomprehensible,
but very terse, okay?
So that's that's kind of APL source
code. I don't By the way, I don't know
APL, so
you know, I just know so much as, you
know, like um
I just know what it is.
Uh, what I want to show you is why don't
Uh, I wanted to Okay, this this should
be uh
Uh
Anyway, so this is the APL keyboard,
okay? So let me show you APL stuff.
So APL,
um
So this is original computer with the
APL keyboard, kind of.
That's called IBM
printing terminal.
It is the first
hardware with the APL programming
language
labels on the keys.
So, this is the first kind of the
I mean, back then they don't you know,
so this is 1965.
Back then it's not like today you have a
computer, you know, you you use this
printing terminal
to program the APL language. Then
then I'm not sure what what how it's
done exactly. Then is is is it punch
cards or what?
So, I don't know.
So, that there's this article. So, and
then you got all the APL symbols in
Unicode. But, you can see this is a
complete list of them.
These are from the APL programming
language. APL stand for A Programming
Language.
That's just
how it stand for.
Okay.
And then uh yeah, and then I I have an
article, you know,
uh
telling you how you can create your own
keyboard shortcuts
to type all these APL symbols or
any other math symbols.
Okay.
So, that's uh some of the articles I
want to show you.
So, back to So, we digressed
along uh you can force the type. Yeah,
so we digressed into that topic. Now,
let's go back to um
here. So,
you see, another way to write this is uh
so, this is change font. Another way to
write this, let's do that.
is So, if you don't want that there,
then you um
then it's like
hard.
Then you got this creature. Okay, let's
see which one is simpler.
>> [laughter]
>> You see, so one way is like that.
Um
then but if you prefer the as something
as, you know, type, then you do it this
way. Now, let's uh sync syntax
format uh the page. Let's see how it
shows.
Okay, yeah.
So, which one
you know, the reason you have to do it
Well, okay, you don't need this for an
actually because
Yeah, so
Yeah, that can do it.
Mhm.
Okay, so that's about that. So, um but
um
Well, if we do we should we make the
change here?
Okay, I'm just going to code, okay?
So, uh
the right now the question is should I
make the change?
You see
this um
Yeah.
So, comment that out. Compile the page.
Go to that go to a HTML.
And uh that's
go go to my JavaScript.
Go to the Unicode page.
And now, let's see if it works.
The the part we
we just changed is the uh
uh font font buttons. Okay, so let's try
symbols. Emoji still works.
Google, Microsoft, Google still works.
Good. Okay, it's
So, make the change, okay?
So, we covered so far we basically just
covered how this
UI widget bar
bar works, okay? That's what we did.
We covered, you know, how this works.
So, now
is actually to actually do it. We we
want to add a
um
>> [clears throat]
>> Let me let me just start to write it,
okay?
We we want to add some kind of um So,
what is this God?
Copy go back to the page.
So, I'm talk show.
Uh we want to add Let's see. Let's go
here.
Update the date.
Let's say
you know, that's that's the this bar.
You see, in HTML it makes it easier to
see. So, now
So, that's this bar.
You want to add another
You want to add a button. So, when
people click on that, this bar will be
fixed to a corner, something like that.
When it's clicked again, you'll jump
back. Okay.
So, you want a button. So, should that
be a button or should that be a
uh checkbox? Let's see.
Yeah, okay. So, let's duplicate that.
Duplicate that. Duplicate that. So,
wait.
So, you want to say
toggle float, something like that. Just
a random name, okay? Toggle float.
And then uh checkbox, yes. Uh then the
name, let's just say toggle float.
Okay, give it a number, random number,
okay?
ID toggle float. Then name also that.
Then uh value
let's say the value is also that, okay?
Then um
Let's say uh float.
Let's For now, let's just say float. So,
when you show this,
you see, this this this is the thing we
want. So, when you click on that, it
will
um
float. What do you like about JavaScript
cuz I I played around with
it a bit, but it didn't catch me.
I don't like JavaScript. JavaScript is
one of the worst language, okay?
Now, um
if I keep talking about it, it's going
to be 1-hour rant.
So,
you might check my older YouTube. Search
for JavaScript. I
done several.
Uh
about why it's worst language. Yes, they
are actually several good ones. So,
let me show that, okay? Let me show that
quickly.
So, you go to my talk show cuz I talk
show. Then there is talk show best best
of index, okay?
Then there's a keyboard videos. There's
Emacs and Emacs this videos collection.
So, Wolfram language collection with I
need to change this
to not use a briefs, okay? So, open
that.
So, instead So, now let's just say
Wolfram language, okay?
So, there's a Wolfram language video
collection.
There there's a something about life,
society, humanity topics.
Not specific to anything.
Then there is
uh parents ask for girlfriend, the
[ __ ] sign. What is a [ __ ] sign? I
don't even remember. Oh, that's a
Unicode, I believe.
Then there's a section section of topic
related to hacker culture, Unix, and
Linux.
Okay, uh that's my rant against Unix
and C.
Okay.
Then there's a section on programming
language design, okay? So, I think
JavaScript uh would be somewhere here.
Now, some of these are old, okay? So,
let's see.
Then there's a section of my videos
about math and geometry. Then there's a
section about personal stuff, best code.
Then a section about best coding videos.
So, this is right a search engine for my
website JavaScript coding.
Uh
and uh okay.
Uh so, where is my video about
JavaScript? Let's see. Uh
Why so, there is one called
Why Mozilla MDN JavaScript tutorial
sucks, okay?
Then, there is one demo of the extreme
idiocy of Python, JavaScript, Ruby,
Lisp, Pascal.
Um
about code formatting, okay?
So, I don't think I listed my JavaScript
talk
on this page, okay?
So, you know, one of one of the issues
with doing videos by now I've doing I've
been doing videos for 5 years.
So, today's episode is 800 700
something.
Uh wait, only 700?
Today, 784. So, almost 800 videos. Is
that
especially when you do it live, you
know, like each 1-hour video you talked
about several things.
But, you don't like you know, it's just
in the past. So, it became
It's actually kind of natural, but it's
harder to They are not indexed.
So, I don't know. I know for sure that
I've talked about why JavaScript sucks
in depth, okay? Very good video. I think
actually recently about maybe 3 months
ago.
So, you just search for uh
Okay, so this one's episode 750 on
standard JavaScript style JavaScript
info site review.
Uh
So, search for JavaScript.
Okay?
So, another episode 748 Emacs recommend
to eval selection F sharp JavaScript.
Uh sev- episode 746 JavaScript in depth.
So, this is this year January uh
JavaScript in depth compare array and
object equality.
Yeah, okay. So, I think this, you know,
January.
So, episode 746 745
uh 744.
They are pretty good. They They are like
uh I think
kind of technical detail, okay? But,
but overall on the JavaScript language
somewhere there. I don't remember when,
but
I discussed in depth why JavaScript
really sucks.
Well, the short answer is because it was
created in 10 days under pressure, you
know, they like
design and write the compiler in
literally just 10 days.
It was you know, it came from Scheme,
this very functional programming
language and Self, the programming
language.
Uh that's the fact that's what, you
know, Brendan Eich
is a fan of Scheme Lisp.
He got hired supposedly to code Scheme,
you know,
at Mozilla, which is the granddaddy of
Fi- Firefox today.
It's a granddaddy of the web, you know,
the the Mozilla browser, Nes- Netscape.
So, anyway. So, but
it turned out he has to create the
JavaScript language in 10 days.
And they he was told you have to make
the syntax you you have to make it look
like Java.
You know, the Sun Microsystem, today
Oracle, the Java crap, the Java
programming language, you know.
So, it's long history. Any- anyway, so
you he was told you have to make it look
like Java.
So, that's why JavaScript is very [ __ ]
in the ass from the beginning.
It's a functional programming language,
you know, JavaScript is very functional.
But, you have to make it, you know, look
like, you know, Java and change, you
know, they changed the name, so it was
called LiveScript. Before that, it was
called uh Oak, Oak, you know, something.
Anyway, but eventually they have to for
marketing reasons, for corporate
reasons, they changed the name to
JavaScript.
Why? Because so, it sounds like Java,
you know, it sounds like it's part of
the Java because the Sun Microsystems
back then spent literally millions and
millions dollars
marketing like every even
non-programmers, they heard about Java.
In magazines, you know, back then you
don't have internet like today, but you
have like magazines or sort of magazines
or newspapers, you know, you can so, you
open you you see advertisement, okay?
So, [snorts] they Sun Microsystem, they
spent, you know, millions millions
dollars advertising Java. I think it's
the most
it's a marketing spend on a programming
language, the biggest in history.
By Sun Microsystems, which died around
2007,
uh bought by Oracle. You know, Sun
Microsystem bankrupt.
So, anyway. So, so so Java, you know, so
they created, you know, a language the
language Java. So, but
so, it was hugely popular because, you
know, partly because marketing because
Java is supposed to like replace C++.
Like, you know, with the jargon write
one write once run everywhere.
With a virtual machine.
Which is not a new idea, right?
Anyway, so Java is hugely marketed. And
Netscape
and Sun Microsystems, they they thought,
you know, we're going to work together.
Let's Let's put Java in every browser.
That's what they did. Okay? They put
Java in every browser.
I mean well, I mean Netscape browser
like bundled support Java.
And the vision is that in browser you're
going to
code Java. So, it's not it's not just
HTML static. So, you can you have Java.
Uh Java plugin and stuff complicated,
okay?
And you have VRML supposed to be like 3D
things, you know.
Which also dead, which also died. VRML,
you can look at that.
Or search my video, you'll find the
episode on VRML.
So, anyway. So, Java is like huge
marketing. It's object-oriented
programming language. It's got garbage
collection. It's got virtual machine
supposed to replace, you know, it's got
garbage collection, virtual machine and
supposed to replace C++.
And with huge money thrown in to market
it. And Netscape is going to collaborate
with Sun Microsystem. Then, then what
you're going to do with JavaScript?
Well, well, let's change the name to
JavaScript. So, it's like
sounds like it's connected to it's like
the easier part of Java, you know, it's
like all together.
>> [laughter]
>> But, JavaScript has nothing to do with
Java whatsoever, the language design,
you know, JavaScript is like functional
programming nothing. So, but you have to
make it like, you know, looks like Java.
Okay, that's the
Um that's, you know, so anyway.
So, we are, you know, we are coding
TypeScript, which is a superset of
JavaScript, okay?
So, anyway, that's the history, okay?
That's the kind of the history. So, Java
is this
like
even in the beginning like it's written
in 10 days and kind of forced to look
like Java. So, you got It's a It's a
pain It's a It's a complete [ __ ] up,
okay?
Like complete [ __ ] up.
Uh I'm not sure what what what some
other language are comparable. There's
Pearl, there's PHP,
then there's a
the Python [ __ ] the Python [ __ ]
Uh then there's also Second Life
scripting language SLS also also is
worst [ __ ]
Um
you know, and PHP came from Pearl by a
teenager because he wanted to create a
pretty home page.
Anyway, so this a lot, you know, the
worst programming languages.
Uh Java is
JavaScript is one of them, okay? So,
JavaScript is pretty bad.
But,
it's here, okay? And he's here to stay,
you know, for
for the foreseeable future, you you
know, after 30 years it's still here.
And uh
you know, so I don't Do I like Java? I
really wanted to like JavaScript,
not
But, JavaScript I really wanted to like
it because at least it supports
functional programming far better than
Python.
Python, the [ __ ]
Python, the Python [ __ ]
The Python people. idiots they are.
Extreme.
They are you know, the Python Guido van
Rossum, the guy who created Python.
Uh if you watch my video, search for
Python. I have lots of, you know,
that you can easily find. My rant again
is Python. Why Python is a circus
language, okay? Search my YouTube.
You'll find some of them. I have more
than one. Okay, each one is 1 hour.
But
so I don't like Python, you know, it it
it
and and JavaScript supports Python.
Um I mean supports functional
programming far better than Python. And
Python has got this indentation [ __ ]
you know, the [ __ ] them scums. They
think you know, these idiots, you know,
indentation. You know, like I talked
about this many times, which the the the
forcing indentation to the into the
programming language basically means
your programming language
uh your programming language can can
never automate do automatic formatting,
okay?
That's essentially what it means.
Okay, so you can see
what you are seeing here is automatic
formatting, okay?
You see, but if you
make indentation part of your language,
you can never have this, okay?
So that's So I I despise Python in in so
many ways. That's why prefer JavaScript.
But
but JavaScript has got just so many
problems. You you know, you can't really
say JavaScript is better.
Um
you know, JavaScript has got too many
problems. So do I like it? No.
And you know, and and also it's sad they
could fix it.
But they they don't want to fix it
because they want they prefer to have
like backward compatibility.
I mean you
you could have a like a use strict, you
know, for example, you can for example,
we already have this use strict hack.
You could have one that says use
JS 2016.
And from now on, you know, from that,
you know, just add that. So it's kind of
like a new language. From that day that
from that year on
you you can write JavaScript that is
completely
uh good language, you know, without the
tremendous baggage in the past. You
could do that. But they refuse to the
Brendan Eich.
You know,
Brendan Eich guy
Eich is a funny character, you know, I
argued with him a little bit and he's a
he could you know, but but even though,
you know, you see,
I was saying that you should have
use for example, like
uh this use JS 2 you know, 2016 or even
you use JS, you know, 2000 26, okay?
Like create this
one time, okay? Then then you can forget
about backward compatibility because
from now on any new JavaScript code, if
you put, you know, use JavaScript new,
let's say use new JavaScript then
you don't have all the baggage
baggages of the past. Meanwhile, you
have 100%
backward compatibility.
Because all JavaScript code that has
ever written will still work.
All you need to do is for the JavaScript
community, you know, the the the the
idiots.
The the
Well, they are not idiots, but they are
like controlled by corporations. So they
So they are not likely to do anything
good, okay? Like that's
this situation happens with any
language
when it becomes big big and when you
have committees and organizations, you
know, they are not they they they
usually never get better, okay? They
just get worse.
So anyway, they could have that, you
know, if if JavaScript is like someone,
you know, like a language run by a one
single guy
actually like Python like Python, you
know, they could do that.
But they decided not to, you know, and
Brendan Eich I was trying to tell
Brendan Eich, you know, the
he didn't, you know, really think that
way, but and they did, you know,
it just and also even if he wanted to
I'm not sure he has the power because
it's like it's not his language anymore.
You know, back in 30 years ago, of
course, he can do whatever he wants.
But not not since like not since like
even 15 years ago. It's not his choice.
He He has no
you know, he he his opinion might have
bigger influence on how JavaScript
should be. You know, it has some weight,
but not much. I don't think so. Because
the the this controlled by the powers,
you know, by Google, you know, the big
corporations.
So anyway, JavaScript could have made
the change, but they didn't. So So what
we have today JavaScript is like
filled to the brim of all the worst
garbage crap. Means like blatant error
like mistake like like null is a object.
You know, the type of null is a object,
you know.
Like
you know,
all over and you don't have real array
real arrays like array is kind of like
object at some sometimes
sometimes not, you know, you have full
of this crap.
So that's a situation with JavaScript,
okay?
Okay, so I rambled, you know, so
as I usually do, I rambled and ranted
about JavaScript for like what? 10 10
minutes?
And so we've been talking for
uh an hour and 17 minutes. So that's
like 80 minutes.
And we even we haven't even started to
code what we wanted to do.
Uh we didn't even begin.
Yeah, that's a situation. That's a
uh that's the thing about
my live stream. One of the one of the
issues. Uh
You see, I I I want to I need to code
this, but if I do live stream, you know,
I never get things done.
Because to explain
you know, like I have to like I'm
starting to repeat again, you know,
because
either I explain or I don't. If I start
to explain, it takes 1 hour to explain
what I'm doing.
Uh so anyway, so we
So right now, do we uh
So you see, close that, close that,
close that, close that, go back here.
What is this page? Uh yeah, so we are
doing that. So we added this um
We added this float me
thing, okay? And we need to implement
it. So we need to start to
uh
Open so open the JavaScript file, the
TypeScript file. So we need to write
basically
Basically, we need to write such that
when float me is clicked
change
the UI
widget style to be fixed on the window,
okay? Can Can we actually code it? Yes.
Okay, so let's decide let's code it,
okay? Let's
push on. So
uh for the live stream, why not? 80
minutes so far, but we can we can
continue on and on.
Because I've been looking at, you know,
I've been thinking about what other
people do for live stream.
You don't have to worry about
Anyway, so
always a nice trip down computing memory
lane.
So that answers Luis' question. What do
you like about JavaScript? I don't like
it.
Uh
Maybe this one Unicode fullwidth char.
Why JavaScript sucks JavaScript?
Oh, did I Okay, so did I have a title
why JavaScript sucks? Let's go to
Salt Talk Show. Search for why
JavaScript sucks.
800 um
live streams, I think I've done.
Always a nice trip Yeah, so there it is.
So 2000 Okay, so why JavaScript sucks
that So there is one from year 2000.
That's one of my earliest live stream
like
pretty ugly. Let's see.
Yeah, Salt Talk Show 2020. There's no
episode number. So this is my first like
50 or so. Year
Year 2020.
That's Yeah, maybe my first
um
So what best programming keypad Unicode
Unix config what JavaScript property
sucks, okay.
I don't know if I'm doing a good job in
that video because that's my very early
one. So this one
Oh yeah, this one 2023
May 11th Unicode full width char why
JavaScript sucks JavaScript versus
typescript versus JS doc.
Um
Now what is what is JS doc? I don't even
remember what I was
So anyway, so this video 2023
that might be good. Okay, so there's
timestamp.
Um
So JavaScript data object versus object
object terminology JavaScript array
problems JavaScript object equality
problem JavaScript versus JS doc. Yeah,
okay.
Uh
typescript versus JS doc. Now what what
is JS doc? I don't remember.
Okay, yeah, maybe that video. Maybe
that's good.
I don't know. I don't remember.
So let's click on that. Let's see
is there a lot of
viewers or so that's 90 minutes 26 thumb
up.
Uh 1.3 thousand views.
Uh Luis says with the growing use of AI
will developers have to change the way
they write code to help agents or read
complex code base.
There'll be some changes for certain.
AI will become AI is already
tremendously helpful.
Uh there are many tools
um
you know, already kind of integrated
with um editors like VS code.
With AI and there's Claude. I never use
them though. Oh but I have used what I
do is I have asked
Quark
tremendous number of question everyday
uh
asking Quark many technical questions
about programming languages
and and things I want to solve. For
example
For example, there's this one.
You know, why is JSON has spec in RFC
and also in ECMA? Why do you have two
standards to specify JSON?
You know, the document exchange format.
So I asked you know, so AI give me a
good answer.
Which you know, this is a good question
because without AI usually then you
search for hours you may not get answer.
So AI
answered so many questions
for me tremendously useful.
Uh but
many other people they you know, they
they they they have tools integrated
like like
you just press a button it will reach
refactor the code for you of a project
of thousands of files things like that.
Uh and my impression so far is that it
never works out.
Uh in one shot. You always
you almost you you know, when when it
does that you know, touching hundreds of
files it creates a result that never
works.
You know, if you ask it to code a simple
toy program it will work in one shot in
many languages and including
and I also I've also asked very very
technical questions about Wolfram
language. It also got it correctly.
For example, this one I asked yesterday
about
Okay, you guys won't understand but it's
about like
you know, because Wolfram language is
esoteric. Anyway.
So it can answer all sort of esoteric
programming language questions or
technical questions or
um and uh solve toy uh problems you
know, it can create a code correctly in
one shot.
But if you ask it to write you know, a
lot of people are saying on Twitter they
will say, "Oh, I created this app uh of
game." Like you know, let's say create a
ping pong game in JavaScript. You know,
you can ask you know, create a ping pong
game in JavaScript.
It it will actually show you the code
but
but it usually doesn't work.
>> [clears throat]
>> You know, you have to
basically it requires for AI to work
writing code non-trivial project. It
always require a guy who is expert
at the code at that code. Maybe that
language or that you know, that domain.
Maybe [snorts] JavaScript maybe
Golang maybe be a C++. You need
like essential you need someone who is
expert. So in other words, you don't
need AI. If you got expert well expert
you know, you you need time.
>> [snorts]
>> So AI can create a code but you always
need the expert. You can't have it just
create a code. In other words, you
cannot fire programmers.
Like a lot this
grifters they are saying, "Oh, AI is
going to you know,
eliminate most programmers." Yeah,
that's true but they eliminate the idiot
programmers like the zoomers who don't
actually know how to stuff. They ask
stack overflow. You know, that's how
they do things. They they use NPM just
JavaScript download 1000 libraries.
You know, like how do you determine
number is odd or even? There's a library
for that one one line. You know, the the
the the
the zoomer idiots they don't know how to
code.
They will be gone
because of AI. You don't need them.
These idiot [ __ ] heads.
They are on Twitter everyday because you
know,
they they they they tell you, "Oh, I got
a project. I did this project this or
that JavaScript." You know, these idiots
zoomer generation.
Including some late millennial gen you
know, because they they are the people
they they you know, they watch videos
for programming tutorials. They they
don't know any other way. They watch
videos. They
they use stack overflow anytime they
have a question they go stack overflow.
Without stack overflow they don't know
how to do it. You know,
So that's a that's a generation.
They going to
be gone. Okay, they going to be removed
eliminated by AI.
But if you but AI so far not today
can't really create a non-trivial you
know, software project without like a
real expert.
So that is the state of AI.
Will that change? That we don't know.
Okay, nobody actually knows.
Yeah, vibe coding. I learned about the
vibe coding like uh last year.
Like what what what what is vibe coding?
What is it? Then I I asked Quark.
It it says, "Oh, the people you know,
they it's like you know, you can have a
drink you know, and just ask AI and have
have fun and create
What the [ __ ]
>> [laughter]
>> And and and it turns you know, so this
generation this this people like today's
people the zoomers [ __ ] extreme
idiots.
So vibe coding so this like this like
apparently I don't know but apparently
it's like it's a thing like
they are all vibe coding like and some
of them think that this is the future.
Like there there's no going to be code
vibe coding is is the way like some of
them like
it seems to me like that's the
what they are thinking.
These [ __ ] idiots you know, the
zoomer generation they are um
they
I think that's you know, that ties to
politics. I think that's the collapse of
USA.
Like they they are brain they they can't
think. Okay, they they are unable to
think.
Um
5 a.m. in my country and I got baited by
the thumbnail. Good luck.
>> [laughter]
>> You lucky you hit the you hit a esoteric
philosopher who talk about things you
will not be interested.
So where are you Xeno? So eight
5 a.m. So let's see um
What? Okay, so what what I want what I
want to do? I want to
launch the um
I want to launch the Microsoft clock.
What is my uh
Yeah.
Microsoft clock launch.
So what is
uh 5 a.m.? 5 a.m. that would be
Bengaluru. That's India.
Hello, India.
Uh
okay, so what we going to do now?
Okay, so we still need to code. Oh god.
You know, then I'm thinking actually I
try
maybe I should
uh just do offline, okay?
Yeah.
Yep.
Hello, my friend.
So, um
what am I going to do? So,
Pukansha, hello Pukansha. So, do I So,
should I quit this live stream?
Or should I actually continue to finish
the coding, okay? So, what is this? I
think I should continue uh finish the
coding, okay?
So, but uh
So, what is this? So, okay, it's not a
show. So,
So, we we need to
if I want to finish the coding, yeah,
continue, okay? So, but I need to take a
break first.
I'm 10 times more productive.
Ksaw, you are why tiling window manager
sucks article changed my life. Thank
you.
Yeah. Yeah, that was that's a that's a
old article by now. It's like 15 years
old.
And one of my
like popular
uh article.
I'm back after a long time. Okay, I
don't remember
you know, you guys. So, that's the
nature of live stream, so
you guys know me, but I can't remember
who you guys are.
And the other thing is, you know, the
condition of all the announce, you know,
if you guys actually used real name,
like real life, you know, like you are
John something, you are David something,
you are Louis something,
then the chances of actual communication
and establish, you know, some
recognition, you know,
I mean, it's it's it's hopeless for live
stream, you know, it's like you know,
because you have 100 people, 1,000
people watching you. I cannot know
everyone of you. But, however, if if
there's real name used,
then the chances of actual
knowing you guys is high much much
higher.
So, uh
yeah, but the but because but the deep
state, the YouTube, the [ __ ] the you
know, we got the in the situation. It's
hopeless.
Uh tiling window manager. Okay, so I
think I um
I either take a break or I stop the
stream.
Stop the live stream or I take a break
and continue to code this um
this this
I think I
stop the live stream.
Okay, I think yeah, I think I stop the
live stream because
uh
because
coding is kind of boring, you know,
coding on live stream.
Nobody really watches.
Uh
okay, bye guys.
We shut down in 2 minutes.
So, the tiling window manager, so it's
just search for
tiling windows manager. So, let's see if
you'll show my article.
Uh no.
But, you have to say should I use tiling
window manager? Actually, just search
for
tiling windows manager sucks, okay?
Let's just say
search for that.
Then, does it show my article?
Uh
no. [ __ ] Oh, there it is.
Why tiling window manager sucks, okay?
Now, does the Reddit show my um
article?
Does the Reddit show uh are those are
those um
Why tiling window manager sucks? Yeah,
that is my article 6 year ago, you know,
it's been posted few times.
So, you go there, why tiling window
manager, so that is my um
reason, okay? So, you can read about it.
So, this is written in 2012 about 14
years ago.
Uh anyway,
bye guys.
Uh closure,
I don't I don't know much about closure.
I coded closure for a year about 10
years ago, so I can't teach you closure.
Um let's see. Am I still going? Yeah, so
So, yeah, so I'm going to shut down and
uh what did I want to do? Yeah, shut
down
um
going to show this amazing
AI.
So, I can do a screenshot later. It's
going to be my YouTube thumbnail.
>> [laughter]
>> Amazing.
Bye, guys.