good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today's 2019 January 9th Thursday 5
o'clock in the afternoon San Francisco
time and today's topic is going to be :
and Unicode and then random Herman good
morning just in scarfy and good morning
port
do ro Louisville attack so just in Scott
by the mathematician who is spending 20
hours a day working on la tech and the
reading books and stuff good morning
Kathy great to see you
so okay today's : and unicode okay guys
go lion unicode and type your comments
in opinions and what and then your
thoughts in the chat chat box okay and
join this code you can find my discord
link in solid info homepage just go
there and join this code vibrant
discussions we have large photos and
great people here we have real people's
here and real people with real photos in
stuff very interesting things and we
have so many photos let me show you one
okay real life show you Alan the master
or snack snackers posted this his
kitchen his kitchen is a mess but he
have created a soda that he thinks
tastes flawless doesn't look like
something tastes flawless and there is
my food then there is something then
there is something then here is Alan
okay
the Eastern Buddha with his dungeon set
up this is a code dungeon lotus position
note the sea
in position that's well actually this
feat you know to be in the real
daughter's position this both of your
feet the palms must face up so this is
actually not the real lotus position so
so join this chord okay that's the point
good morning reaper and discord there
are lots of things lots of interesting
things going on and emily is found of
this drink this woman's drink okay this
this aloe vera this kind of plant you
know this friend today actually I mean
they are juicy but they do they actually
make you know edible juice and so this
is a bottle of sugar as far as I know
this is part of sugar good morning hey
Alan we were just showing your photo
your Buddha lotus position your dungeon
so and we have lunara's who lives in
this code climate below 30 cells is
thirty degrees in Nova Scotia okay this
you live here and at night there will be
bears coming out to get you that's
Halifax Nova Scotia in East in east side
of Canada I never imagined I would know
someone there because Fred you know from
a song you are so when okay so sometime
sorry you are vain glorious I am vain
glorious so vain okay so let's Frank
some music and you are Carly Simon there
is there it is
sexual anthropology in Carly Simon's so
you are so when sexual anthropology the
study of white men they like to study
this kind of
things sexual allergy anthology this and
that this and that and rights human
rights this that that that right right
right
and today you got a factor upstate there
it is a song very popular okay Carly
Simon she's very old now she is like
eighty probably is eighty something but
she is a queen back then and so she's
singing about a guy you are so vain and
yeah so when I was reading I when I was
listening to this song in 2006 I wrote
this page so these lyrics you dive into
the lyrics you understand you see this
blog is called human animals and their
songs so when you listen to a song you
type into the lyrics what they are
saying this is you know so if you are an
alien if you came from Mars then you
listen to these songs broadcasted on
radio you can understand humanity you
know like what what are they saying what
are they talking about all these songs
pop songs pop 10 top 10 top 40 you know
Rolling Stone whatever [ __ ] you know so
they have songs human animals have songs
we have songs and you know you know you
look into then you study the lyrics what
are they what are they saying all the
time you know you do study statistics on
them what what is the subject matter you
know what what are they saying and what
and you'd you you studied linguistics
from it because from these songs lyrics
you you can see there the addiction
their choice of words their their
spelling as well and and also the their
pronunciation especially the black
people's rap songs okay so let me let me
show you some black people rap songs can
stir gangsta rap
so gangsta so for example here we have
gangsta rap IceCube gangsta rap made me
do it okay you I didn't make him do it
you didn't make him do it he didn't do
it himself but cancer rap made him made
he to it okay so you study you type into
the lyrics what is he talking about what
other are they saying so this is called
human animals in their songs so when I
was doing cut you know listening to
Carly Simon so you have to I have to you
don't have to but I have to I have to
understand every word they they are
saying I have to know what it means and
so in the lyrics there it is Halifax let
me show you okay Nova Scotia not harlot
Halifax Nova Scotia you see well I hear
you went up to Saratoga and your house
your horse naturally won't you know a
horse gambling apparently then he says
then you flew your Learjet up to Nova
Scotia to see the total eclipse of the
Sun so this is some rich and powerful
guy where every girl adores and he's got
a Learjet now Learjet is probably a
brand name some fancy private jets um
you know jet so he he flew to Nova
Scotia by his Learjet to see the total
eclipse of the Sun how nice and there it
is Nova Scotia so that's so they then
then what you do you know you look up
well is Nova Scotia like what the [ __ ]
you look up Maps you know Nova Scotia
then you learn oh it's it's you know
it's some kind of code and isolated
place like Siberia you don't know what
what place is that and now I know be
we have a friend who lives in Nova
Scotia and he tells us photos in the
stories of Nova Scotia the people they
are in by the way the rent there is very
cheap
so guys move there if you are not a
social if you don't care about curbs
nightclubs or those kind of things you
move there to Nova Scotia and you will
have a peace and quiet life like this
peace and quiet life okay like like that
Nova Scotia great I think that place
suits me okay we digress so much oh wait
wait am I still functioning am I still
functioning check yes
okay Kathy loves curbing Kathy you have
to bring me you have to bring me to the
curb scenes you know I go to the clubs
in my life in my 50 years of life the
number of times I went to curb is about
maybe less than five when I go there you
get extremely nervous me why are you
also you see all these people and the
girls of course with their dress you
know they're there they're there their
tits and legs showing you know that's
what club is for clubs in dance clubs
you know different different kind of
clubs and guys you know guys guys you
know so you go to clubs then you see all
these people dressed up or you know what
they have they have a fund they they go
there to have fun that's what they do
okay so today actually let's get back to
the main topic shall we : so let's do :
then so I'm going to show you I'm going
to finish what we started yesterday nice
men always finish okay so we're going to
finish what we began yesterday so
then start command log mod and you can
see all my Emacs command shows up on the
left you see these powerful I hope I
just hold on the key P and it's goes all
the way up or s all the way down you see
powerful command this is fantastic
command one single key press not control
F or something control [ __ ]
so the idiotic Emacs so this is so
freaky so so so on D on this left window
you see all my commands right there so
I'm gonna show you okay and you see the
beginning of line or block so you see
let me tell you about this okay so why
is this command cuz a beginning of line
or block white why is that long a block
because this is this this command has
dual function do a function like do a
live lightsaber
you know because you press one key D you
for example okay let me show you okay so
let's see so my cursor is over here you
can see magnifier you can see you see my
cursor now you see my cursor is over
here I press one key it goes to the end
of line then I press that again it goes
to the end of paragraph I press it again
it goes to the end of paragraph I hold
it it just keep going down so you don't
you do not need page up and page down
keys anymore you know in Emacs the page
up page down is is idiotic
okay the the Emacs page up and page down
key you have meta V okay met Harvey for
pet aged the Emacs
Madhavi yeah so so it's idiotic okay
anyway so let's get back to the
let's see where are we
what is this page our talk show so this
is today and today's topics : continued
from yesterday and Unicode press random
okay that's that's let's let's do it
so I'm going to go to go line script
find/replace script so this is my goal
and find/replace script it has a total
of 186 lines and it has lots of features
it does find/replace
on all files in a directory or HTML
files or Java file or JavaScript files
you can specify a file suffix you can
specify a directory here and you can
specify a file suffix for example you
can see file name rejects you know that
rejects will filter out files you don't
want and you can also specify the
directories you want to skip such as
stop get you know you want to skip those
directories and then you have you have
multiple find/replace
pairs not just one so for example you
want to replace screen by princess you
want to replace King by Prince you know
you have multiple set of find/replace
pairs you can do it one shot just type
those pairs and run this script or do it
one shot on ten thousand hundred
thousand files and this is V Lynn :
and only 186 lines of code actually this
is not the right files actually the the
right file is this one okay so this one
so 160 160 lines of code it's even
smaller for some reason oh yeah because
this one doesn't have one of the feature
that oh it does I don't know so why is
this one actually smaller I forgot it's
interesting this this one does find and
replace multiple pairs but it actually
is 10
ten line ten lines less then the script
that just does find okay so here this is
the so this is script and this is the
URL you can actually go to it and you
can you can get it grab it for your own
use fantastic
so let me show you how you use it okay
but first of all let's copy the file
path and go to startup show today and
paste it so we have the proper link and
stuff for today and okay guys keep
talking and now I need to check my on my
health so there is the link check on my
health my health is good
seven people six people watching paucity
okay so goal and script you go there you
can grab it for your own use or you can
look at the script and learn :
okay get in-depth quick get into the
depth of goal and fantastic fantastic
language and now let's go back to the
let's go back to my script let me do a
demo let me show you what's going on
continue from yesterday : and unicode so
this script replace okay the face of it
so this script here is where you put a
file directory okay the directory to
search and found name regular expression
and write to file out shuo force you
know you can you know if you say that to
force you see it will report the you
know which file has changed where where
it find stuff and but it will not
actually write to it so it's very good
if you just want to try you know this
multiple pairs finally we place on on
thousands of files so you can also
specify backup or not and you can
specify a backup regular expression and
you can also wait let me find the right
is in my are we
is that right yeah find/replace squid
yeah so you can have these features and
you can say directory to skip and then
you have also this feature that allows
you to for example sometimes you don't
want just to change every file in a
directory even with regular expression
to filter it out because sometimes you
you have a list of files that they don't
have a pattern you know the file name
does not match a regular expression
pattern you know you are just given a
list of files you want to change in
those files only so in that case you can
put you know the list of file paths here
then it will just only do these files
then here we have the multiple payers
find/replace payers and we are going to
do a demo now okay so let's do a demo of
this so and this is going to be a real
life stuff so I'm going to find
something I actually want to change on
my website Mike's our JavaScript
in-depth tutorial so this is my website
it has thousands of files and right now
we are going to do multiple pairs of
Find and Replace on few hundred files
and I'm gonna show you what I want to
change so so this is a practical thing
because I use it every day for my
website
I do find replace almost basically every
day on seven thousand HTML files every
day that because my website is static
that's how I do change things so let's
read the comments very friendly and
civilized zone what zone the crubs Kathy
says Alan why are you sitting on the
floor though I remember you said it's
more comfortable yeah
that's Alan's thing you have to ask
that's Alan's thing
so finally face yeah so let me let's
find let's let's let's let me find out
what do I want to change here so
anyway I made a change here in my
tutorials you can see this you can see
these you see that shadow that green
thing highlight I added a shadow so it
stand out so this is fantastic guys so
you can see this is fantastic and
actually let me show you let me show you
the my unicode stuff okay today's topic
is unicode so I click on clothing you
see that green that so that that shows
that you are currently there and now
it's beautiful let's click on food you
have all these food ass war and you have
emoji and and you see anyway that's what
I want to show so back to the JavaScript
ok let's go back to JavaScript
JavaScript let's look at SVG ok SVG path
is the path you see that's highlighted
green fantastic let's go back to this go
back to what I want to change ok so let
me see JavaScript so I made a lot of
changes here yesterday let's sees date
ok here is one thing I want to change
let me show you so I let me explain what
I'm doing so I copied a URL copy the URL
go back to Emacs open the file I have a
command that you know just open whatever
file in the quick quick board the you
are incredible so this is the file okay
so I want to go to the top search for
nav bar so here is the nav bar you see
so showing browser again you see that
yellow thing back to JavaScript object
reference so that is the nav bar so
that's this one so I want to change that
okay I want to change that too
so let me show you okay open on you
another window go to the find/replace
script again now let's start to add the
find/replace pairs so find/replace pairs
so here I want the navbar okay and I
want to replace it by I want to replace
it by let me just show you okay so there
I want to replace by that okay so oh no
you see so this this line is what I want
to replace so cut it go back to the
find/replace so paste it here so there
these two lines find and replace spell
okay so that's one pair we are not done
yet
that's just one of the pair and we are
going to add more pairs okay
so copy the whole thing hey sit here so
that's so we have another new pair so
what is the other thing I want to change
okay so let's look javascript array how
to wait okay array how to and JavaScript
what's the other thing I want to change
we need to find another thing find
replace pair that to change on hundreds
of files so that we can demonstrate that
: script okay and what is the thing I
want to change let's see let me have a
look okay so hold on a second okay
yeah I know what to do but
map okay so this is getting this will be
a little bit complicated okay so are you
guys still there so okay so so this is
what I want to change okay let me show
you this is a gonna this is not a good
demo because this is this text is very
long
this text is thousands of characters you
know I'm thinking maybe we should do
this or find something more simpler like
one line or two lines let's do the let's
do the real thing okay let's just walk
on the real life walk instead of fine
instead of trying to find a some kind of
artificial example so open that you know
open this file this map so this page map
object I already opened it in the
browser in my Emacs here you see map map
object this is a page and now let's go
down to the bottom let's go down to the
bottom and you you see this block of
text that block of text corresponds to
this maybe magnify okay so you can see
it correspond to this navigation box
okay I want to change that okay so so
I'm going to change it so first of all
copy it okay go back to the goal-line
script so on the second pair I paste it
over there so you can see whips you can
see that's the block of text there okay
now what do you want to replace it by I
want to replace by let me show you okay
so I want to replace it by this block of
text the
this navigation box which is basically
the table of content contents for my
entire JavaScript so let me repeat I
want to replace this little navigation
box related to JavaScript map object by
by this giant navigation box which is
the entire JavaScript table of contents
page okay so I want to replace that so
let's let's do it okay so go to my
JavaScript block and that that big table
of content contents page is this one
okay it's this one
so copy it go back to the Golan and
we're gonna paste it in here you see the
replacement text so I'm gonna paste it
so you can see we have lots of text here
so you can see lots of text so but
basically we have two pairs find and
replace pairs this is the first one and
the second one is the you know that one
very big okay that's what we want to do
and now let's do it okay let's just do
it so let's go to the top wait
so let's now let's make sure the
directory is correct okay so and we are
going to do it now so hold on second
image let me show you
JavaScript okay go down map okay
remember we are changing two things one
thing is change the JavaScript object
reference and the other thing is change
the JavaScript map navigation box this
happens in multiple files for example if
I click here javascript map to Tokyo I
go down you see you see that box again
and if I click here
iteration iterate over map object at the
bottom you see this navigation box again
so this navigation box happens in about
one two three four five six seven seven
phases and the other thing the other
thing the navigation bar on the top left
that also happens in multiple places let
me show you so you see you see the
object reference so if I click on object
you see that JavaScript object reference
that needs to change that needs to go to
JavaScript in depth and you see this
array object you see that also needs to
change so we are going to render the :
and that will fix them all but before we
do so just in case even though it makes
a backup and all let's go to a shell and
let's go to Esau and directory up and
get status lets me make a git commit so
you see this all these files are changes
I made okay do I make sense old is this
boring
git add okay so I'm gonna get add them
all and get commit
okay so git commit every file in sorry
dot info and now I'm going to saw
interactive interactive a brief type
back for this brief delete or Emacs back
up
vennett so all backup files will be
deleted in the directory it's called a
primitive visit code a primitive east
revolution barefoot and minimal santos
okay so let's go back to so I've made a
git commit so now lets
to the find/replace in case we have a
major mistake I can always just get
revert you know you call the git
checkout command to revert everything so
how long have been talking 30 minutes
okay okay so let's render let's run
let's run this run it have a sip of
drink and it's done okay it's done so
you see all these files are changed you
see all these files
not many about about 30 javascript files
and if you go to the top you see this
bunch of thing you see this thing this
whole text those are those are the you
know the output is the header of the
output it's trying to make a report of
what is what this script is doing so
here over here this line that is trying
to tell you I mean that's just printing
out your Find and Replace pairs but they
becomes a long line because of this line
return you see because this line
returned you see because they I mean
that's the go syntax so that's not good
because this is this is unreadable what
we want is this let me show you okay
what we want I mean that's why I want to
edit this : script to fix these two so
that each line is a line not not by the
okay so here you see it should be like
that it should be like that
so this is our find and replace pairs
you see this is our first pair then then
then starting here this is our second
pair remember so yeah so that's what we
want to find modify that script but
anyway this this find replace motor
multiple pairs he stud now let's go back
to browser and let's refresh okay
see if he had made the change now look
at the top-left corner okay
refresh you see it's good now he says
back to JavaScript that's what we wanted
that's one of the pairs we changed good
now go back to JavaScript and scroll
down let's go to the map thing and see
if we change that you see the map see
map you see each other swim in depth
that's good fixed and let's go down you
see we no longer have the we no longer
have the map navigation box instead we
have these JavaScript basics this entire
table of contents so that's good so that
so mission accomplished
okay so that's the demo of the cola and
find we placed script okay so now what's
the next thing so actually there seems
to be a mistake here let me see let me
make let me take a quick look okay why
is this
what
wait a minute how did this [ __ ] we made
a mistake you see we we did change this
navigation bar you see but for some
reason I added de a Oh L there let's
screw the whole thing up so now let's go
back to our goal and script and let's
double check where did we add all our
G's here you see this line this Oh L
there the oil should not be there so
it's a mistake
[ __ ] okay so how are you gonna fix this
well one way is to revert every file by
their backup that will require some
shell script you know we have to write a
shell script so that for every file that
has a backup
we name it so that you know it doesn't
have the backup to replace the and we
can do that actually so so two ways to
fix our arrow one is to manually write a
shell script or with the Emacs using
Emacs 2 so that for every backup file
Davido original and rename the backup as
original so we are back to our original
condition the other way a faster way is
to simply do a git checkout remember we
made the backup I mean we we made a git
commit so we can simply do a git
checkout and that will get our new files
so which way should we do so let's
that's here that's here which way should
we use
yeah yeah let me know let me know what
do you think let's do that kind of okay
so we need to so guys say something
which way should we do it five people
okay so we are losing getting boring so
let me have a drink today's drink is
grape juice write a script Alan says
write a script okay let's do it
grape juice with Rockstar sugar free
accept natural sugar in a grape juice
so let's revert our changes
I'll find replaced we made a mistake so
usually you don't want these kind of
mistakes because then you have to spend
five minutes or so to correct the
potentially thousands of pages you you
know that find/replace did actually I
should write I should write a script
that just press a button it will just
revert you know we do and do you know
whatever the fine be placed but I
haven't done that so first of all we
move this Oh L so that next time we can
we we don't fall into that mistake
double check here yeah this seems good
okay okay so now let's click close then
okay so now let's go to the tired let me
show you how I do this okay I mean tired
in a directory and I press the tilde
sign to mark okay wait wait that's not
that's not we want okay
in tired now I press i press i press the
percentage sign and M that will call the
command mark regular expression so I'm
going to use a regular expression to
mark the files okay so I type quixote
oda okay twice you see all these backup
files are marked now all I have to do is
press a button okay watch what you do
command on the left window watch you the
command name up here so I press a button
you see that that command is called
sapphire saw copy file path so all these
marked files now I have a I have copied
their file path so let me show you
so I open a new buffer paste it you see
these are the files that that has
changed now all I have to do is to by
whatever means to rename these files so
without the Toyota Toyota so they'll be
placed or internal so how we do that
there are many ways ok so there are so
many ways you can I mean I can quickly
match you know create a shell script
here for example let me show you okay
first of all save this ok save this save
this file ok magnify so for example let
me show you what make a backup and let
me show you okay so I can do this you
see that so what this command do is move
movies renaming UNIX so it will just
move the file of this name with a Chioda
the backup name to the Ranger named so
that effectively you know does the
revert so so I have to do now is use
Emacs macro to to work on each and every
of this line let me show you okay so
they mean let's do it so let's do a
marker okay Emacs start mark hold on a
second so start mark hold on a second
okay so let me show you now now watch
carefully we're gonna start a macro so
start a macro then copy current line
then paste then delete delete then
enter enter then
move move up move up make it one line
then type MV space then go to the end
then go to here then go to here ok
that's it that's our marker now I'm
gonna stop mark oh ok now I'm going to
run the Marco on all these lines ok so
let's do it
select all the lines and meta x apply
marco to region lines okay do it
my Marco is a bit my Marco is not too
efficient so it's actually taking a
while wait is it actually running
okay maybe my Marco is wrong so it's
stuck it shouldn't take this long [ __ ]
the morning just change scarf I I think
my motto is [ __ ] up why don't you
write a new and do command for Emacs
and do is complicated and do is ok
my macro is not working yeah it's no
good stop yeah like my Marco is you see
my Marco is getting into a infinite
recursion [ __ ] look it's an infinite
recursion [ __ ] okay well we have a
backup so let's do that
okay we are back to our engine oh okay
let's do it again
okay um see you guys tomorrow
Wow ain't gonna do ma cross so start
mark well move
copy tastes diety read move
monkey maybe let me restart okay so
start macro move copy space paste delete
delete then right arrow and stop macro
okay now let's call the macro works now
let's apply macro to our lines then you
see it's done now let's show this in one
big you see now we have all these it's
done so now all we have to do is just to
run this file because all these these
are shell commands we need to do this
one as well so okay now I drop to I drop
to tired
rename the file shell and open it again
and just run it run it and they say
smash finished okay now let's go to
tired again let's go up and refresh
tired it's changed now it's reverted so
back to the browser now if we refresh
you see now it's back you see it says
JavaScript object reference again so
we've done that so now we just this is
taking too long we
started to take too long so now let's
render the cola and find replace again
so let's run it again run it
then back to browser refresh good
it says JavaScript in-depth and it has
the full navigation bar at the bottom so
that that that's the demo about this
goal and script but now you see remember
I said we need to make a change so that
it doesn't print the find/replace pairs
you know in one giant single line so all
we have to do is to go to the place
where it prints and modify it recursive
marcos why would you reach an apply to
marco go to so why would a region of
light Marco go to infinity well because
you know when you do a markup key Marco
which is recording bunch of keys for
example you start on a line then then
you move the cursor down to the next
line then eventually you do something
then you move back to the original line
okay so the the cruiser is back to the
line where you begin with so I think in
that case when you do a apply macro to
region lines that will get you a
recursive situation I think right you
know that doesn't happen often the X
actually I can't remember
I cannot remember I think this is the
first time I actually run into a
recursive mark oh yeah this is the first
time in my 20 years of Emacs using so
anyway let's go back to the : script and
let's make a change so that it prints
the find and rip
Paris each find replaced by a lying
itself instead of one single lie so if
the code is somewhere here they're
trained to find replace pairs so we need
to change that line in fact I have
already written the code somewhere so
let's just copy it somewhere so let me
see
train slice stream
[Music]
okay now we need to look at the print
syntax of : okay let's look at then we
are done we are done let's just look at
the print syntax of goal and the print
syntax so in our code we are doing print
percentage sign pound sign V and that
syntax means trained in colon syntax so
so you can see this line we have this
variable fr pairs that's the value of
that is a goal and slice slice is
basically just array smart array so it's
a colon slice and each element is is a
pair each element let's go let's go to
the top let me show you okay
so you can see here is how the pairs are
defined so each pair each pair is a each
pair is actually a structure fr pair so
so this is : a structure a structure
here is a struct
so a short is like a hash table but with
the fixed piece you know a fixed number
of keys so that's what stropped means in
colon and in C so in Cola and here we
have a we declared a type struct and the
stopped the key will be F s and RS so
this stroke has two keys FS means fine
string is means replace string and each
value is a string so this is dropped fr
pair is a struct like a hash table it
had you know a fixed hash table he has
two keys
F s and RS and their values are stream
so that's what this F R pair is now if
we go to the top then you see these FR
pairs so it's a slice which is a smart
vector so each element is the FR pair so
now go back to our print code so you can
see here we are trying to print this FR
pairs which is a slice and each element
is this pairs struct and we are using
the syntax % pound V that means printed
in colon syntax so when colon prints
this this this slice of stroke it will
use colon syntax that's why you see all
the backslash n backslash n you know
that's the colon syntax to represent new
line but we want to change that so it
doesn't print doesn't use the /n that's
why we are going back to the colon print
documentation and here are the syntax
okay so okay we so instead of it instead
instead of percent pound sign V we just
say percent V okay let's try it
can we run it again yes run it again run
it again
fantastic actually we success you see
now we run again because we already did
this before so there is actually no file
changed
no no file changed you know you will now
see it prints any fire but however it
still prints the you know the find and
replace space you used for example let
me let me magnify okay so you see the
header so this is encoding and marks are
fine output then you have the date this
script is run then the script name is
replaced
in this house in this directory then the
that we rejects theater is HTML and
right to file is true to backup is true
and and file list is none and then we
have find/replace pairs so it shows this
human readable printing of the
find/replace pairs that's what we want
wanted to do today and we are done
good morning Andrew so I think I think
that's the end of sauce talk show today
I hope you guys have a good day
and any other questions good morning
Sensa and come on in Justine and any any
other things so that's it for today
today is Thursday tomorrow is Friday
Friday Friday so we talked for 57
minutes good three more minutes we're
gonna shut down okay Andrew Andrew way
from Andrew D
and pour duro will you form again pour
duro so we did this thing actually it's
successful goal and tutorial okay so let
me copy that to my talk show and let me
copy that to my talk show page and copy
that and showing browser so we did :
find and replace script we did a demo of
that and that is fantastic and here is
the code you can grab actually we need
to again remember we made a change today
so we actually need to make a change
here as well but but I'll leave that to
you guys you know we need to make the
change on this line print so here's a
code you can get you can use so we
talked about that we did we did a demo
of that and and we also modified the
code to do what we want and we explained
a little bit what is : struct and you
know and what is colons go line : slice
a struct is just a fixed hash table or
in pythons jargon it's a fixed
dictionary it's basically just a list of
key value pairs but stropped is a fixed
data type that it that is you create a
fixed set of key value pairs you know
with predefined
keys and number of keys you know you
predefined it as a structure so that's
the struct data type in : and it's also
in it's also in racket you know the
scheme this racket it's also in C and
it's also in C first verse you don't
have that in Java you don't have that in
Python you don't have that in Ruby you
don't have that in Perl and we talked
about
javascript in-depth website so that's
that you know that's yeah that's it for
today and okay bye bye guys bye language
tutorial JavaScript so go by my
tutorials okay fantastic javascript
tutorials javascript in-depth and
actually yesterday and today i
restructured the table of contents so
now it's more coherent
I hope so you just become familiar with
this table of contents then you can go
navigate to anywhere by