Hello. Hello. I'm alive. Uh hello guys.
Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. We are going to do uh install
uh spell checker for Emacs running on
Windows. Um so, yep, that's so this is
for you guys who are using Emacs for you
guys extreme Emacs nerds. Okay. So,
Emacs is a great powerful text editor
for mostly for programmers but also good
for writers or anyone who wants to, you
know, manipulate text a lot.
So, okay, spell checking. So, this is
continuation from last talk show. So, we
did the last talk show. So, uh, two days
ago, three, uh, maybe a week ago,
episode 670,
make spellch checking in Emacs,
Microsoft Windows Great again. So, okay.
So, let's open the previous um, because
I need to So, let's open the previous
one. I need to check I need to get so
first of all so some of the tips for
spell checking
okay and some of the commands okay so so
what we going to do so we going to
install hunp spell okay so hunp spell do
I have it installed no I don't think so
let's turn on powershell
control scroll to make it large
okay and uh let's see gc CM Hunpel
Hunpel GCM means get command like which
is analogous to Unix which
uh yeah so is not installed but a spell
is but however my spell is old version
so where is it user being a spell okay
so we need to install hbell so hpel last
time we know if you are here Say hi if
you are watching uh
you know live. Say hi if you are
watching offline. Play at 1.5 speed
because I ramble. Hello Tamit. Meow.
Hello. Oh dude. Once you started you'll
never leave it. You'll never get a life
in human life. You mean Emacs? Yes.
Emacs is a dark hole.
uh I've been using since 1997
about 1999 I live in Emacs. Okay. So get
spell checking we're going to complete
this today. So on Windows it's not
installed. So if you are not sure, you
know, check out my previous video few
days ago. I talked about especially in
the beginning I talked about Richard
Stoman uh his abuse of the word free and
freedom from the free software
foundation and that explains why Emacs
on Windows for the Windows version of
Emacs spellchecking doesn't work. You
have to like ditto to get it to work. So
that's what we are going to do to ditto
something. So um so let's get that done.
Okay. So so this guy
uh very helpful. He's on Twitter. He
showed me he wrote a blog about how to
get it to work. So you can check out his
blog. I I haven't watched the video. But
let's just follow whatever he says.
Okay. Uh spell download. Okay. So you
got you got this page. Let's click. You
gota download hunbell easy ports. Okay.
Hunbell.
What the [ __ ] I understand you know the
source forge is is not very good
websites. Source forge is one of the
oldest opensource
software
repository. Okay. What? Like the oldest
since 1999
even something. Okay.
But but over the so so in 1999 or let's
say year 2000s there's no git yet git is
created sometimes around 2006
then there are several others eventually
git one then github was created
sometimes in 2008 or something wait 20
was it 2008 or something
uh no or maybe Jesus I don't even
remember now anyway so So, Source Forge
was the earliest since like the year
2000s. Uh, and there's another one
called Fresh Meat, you know, very very
juvenile name because they love these
kind of names because juvenile because
that's a Unix culture which became
Linux, you know, fresh meat. Do you guys
know fresh meat?
I'm not even sure the website is
available now. But um but you know fresh
meat was the earliest earliest
um let's see ripple
free code. Oh they renamed it to free
code I guess.
Fresh meat net 1997 to 2014. Yeah, they
shut down because Anyway, so let's so
let's let's not digress. Let's get the
So So we need to install Huntsbell. So
where is it? Okay. Hunsbell
um
C project
uh why is this website? Okay. So so let
hold on a second. So let's get unspel.
Okay. So I want to go to the previous
previous talk show. There's a link to
Hunpel.
Uh yeah. So there.
So HP spell.
So I'm just going to go slowly and
randomish. Okay. So this video is not
worth your time.
Uh what the [ __ ] What? How are they
arranged? They are not alphabetical. So
Jesus.
Uh
you know this this website is from
Ellie's you know Ellie Zeski.
He is one of the most senior old Emacs
Bast Emacs dev for for maybe 20 years or
more and he is actually his focus is on
Windows platform. So almost everything
of Windows Emacs is made by him, but
also he's a very cocky guy, you know,
he's like he, you know, he's very cocky.
Um, and kind of like a [ __ ] So a lot
of people have problem with him,
including me, you know, like every time
I I say something, he's gonna uh kind of
silly. Anyway, so Hunbell
Okay, there is hunbell. Let's uh so 1.3
132 uh so this is being so let's get
that okay so this is what from 2014
Jesus
uh
you know open source things are always
like
long outdated okay so there is hell
you know this is How I do things? I do
things slowly.
Now this, you know, this [ __ ]
idiotic. Oh, I already downloaded. You
just click. Okay. So, I already
downloaded. It's in download folder.
Okay. Go to download folder. Hell. So,
there's a duplicate dat. Okay. So, open
this. So, you got what? You got all
these directories. So
I have read this there's long kind of
documentation that you should put this
in uh all these programs should be in
the same directory whatever this you
download. Okay. So let's go to D drive.
Uh D drive bing.
I already created this. Uh oh, I already
downloaded. So this is So let's split
split. Let's see. HP spell 1323.
HP spell. Okay. So it's already there.
Open that. Delete that. Okay. Now we
don't need that that. So keep this. So I
already
did I already expand? Yes, I already
expanded. Okay, so HP spell is actually
installed.
Okay,
so copy the file path. Now go to the uh
PowerShell but the path is not there. So
you need to get the path. So,
so that means you
you you know you go to uh system
system. So, let's uh
you know, I want to go to click on the
system. Uh let me show you. So, click on
the system and go to the um environment
environment variables. Okay. But I don't
want to click there because I click
there it's going to show you show my
serial number for Windows whatever maybe
personal. So so is there any way to open
the environ environment variables
uh panel directly? Yes, I think so.
Okay. So let's show some tricks of
Windows
uh actually. So we can just open a
windows
folder viewer. This is called
technically file explorer and just type
environment
variable. Okay.
Does it work? No. [ __ ] idiots.
God, this this you know the windows
[ __ ] Windows, you know, they they
they go to the browser. Idi idiots.
Okay, so close settings. So I want Okay.
So let's do search setting actually.
Yeah. There. Edit the system environment
variables. Edit environment variables
for your account. So that one. Yeah,
that's what we want. So we got our
environment variables and what we want
to set is the path.
Okay. So this is like you know technical
and esoteric. You see environment
variables is global variable for
systemwide and you have that in Unix,
Linux and you also have that on Windows.
You also have that on the Mac of course
but however the Unix environment
variables in Unix and Windows are quite
different. Okay, they are not not the
same. They have different conventions.
they have different and but when so inv
environment variables in Unix and Linux
they are set up by your shell
uh you know I'm I'm kind of digressing
but um uh
actually I don't you know I'm on Windows
so I don't have bash so actually do I
have bash yeah bash history uh you know
you have dot bash or dot profile or dash
bash profile things like that. Okay, so
let's go to uh
I'm digressing all over. Okay, so you
you can check out my Linux tutorial.
Search for environment. Okay, I don't
have a so you know go to um search
environment.
So I got like tens of tutorials on
environment variables on in Wuam
language. How how do you set up
environment variable from within wam
language get their values and stuff and
why the environment variable system is
bad. Why? Because it's a global
variable.
This is old block from 2015.
2015 is a year when you have this p
panorama technology panorama uh videos.
So what is this? Uh okay that's a old
blog. So what are we doing?
Yeah why the environment variable system
is bad because it's just a global
variable. So avoid it as much as
possible. But the Unix people they don't
know. They don't know [ __ ] and the
Linux people, you know, every program
tells you, oh, you need to set up this
environment they wrote and stuff.
Extreme idiocy for like 40 years. It
began by the Unix idiots in 1970s.
Okay, the Unix and C idiots.
Anyway, so the main difference between
Windows environment variables and the
Unix ones is that on Windows, the
permanent ones are stored in Windows
registry. Okay, that's another huge
topic. But anyway, so
so let's see Windows and you can control
Windows environment variables from
PowerShell. So for example, this is a
tutorial uh that tells you all you need
to know about environment variables.
Okay, and you can start the environment
variable by just running this program
like Windows R.
uh and you can and and type this system
properties advanced you know and this is
a full path you can start it in
powershell and so on
so anyway so you got a full tutorial
then you can set it up using powershell
so you don't need
you know so you don't need to use this
um
close that wait where is my environment
variable windows it went somewhere
but but you can you can do it directly
in powershell so all these are tutorials
but um
but
but let's let's use um
let's use this
if I close that does that disappear no
But you see another annoying thing about
Windows is that this panel
does not have a corresponding icon.
The [ __ ] stupid Windows
Windows is idiotic all the way. So this
this window for environment variable,
they don't have a corresponding icon on
the taskbar.
So anyway, lots of digression. So let's
go back. So what is this? Uh uh Linux by
command line. Close it. What is this? Uh
Windows tips. Yeah, environment variable
tutorial. Anyway, let's just go set it.
So So you need to set the path. Okay. So
that is the one uh user variable. Yes.
Edit. Okay. So he and you see the
windows are tiny.
Even if you increase font systemwide,
the wind the the fonts here are still
tiny. There's no way no it's not
possible to enlarge it. You know that's
one of the extreme idiocy of Windows.
You know the Windows idiots they say oh
Windows 11 shiny did they fix this? No.
This is the actually critical because
for older people or for you know screen
size differs a lot. So sometimes you
have too small a font. You cannot read
it. You know this this font is too small
for me to read and right now I'm doing a
YouTube so I need larger font so you
guys can see but this it is not possible
to actually make make it larger. Well,
you can you can do something like um you
know something like you know like like
this kind of [ __ ] you know this you know
for for disabled you know who who's got
eyesight problems
but this is uncanny
stupid. So that's Windows and we stuck
with that because now how do you get rid
of this
uh
magnifier. Close that.
Anyway, so here is environment
variables. I want to edit the path. So
there and uh I want need to add the
unspel path there. Okay. So what is
this? Uh close. What is this wordy blog?
That's English. Okay. Unspel. So copy
the file path. Open it. paste it there
and uh
back slash to
uh wait that's slash so I need slash to
backslash
okay then you want to okay so then copy
that
actually so you want just that so the
path path.
Okay. So, what is this? Yeah, this is
the path. So, say new
new paste. Okay. And uh okay. So, let's
double check.
So, you want to modify the path
environment variable. So, now it's here.
Easy. We import bing.
Okay. I should have hunbell. Okay. Okay.
So say okay. Say okay.
So now if you do gcm get command
hunpbell
not found because you need to restart
powershell. You learned it the hard way.
Okay. Why? Because when when you start
powershell PowerShell reads the register
to get all the environment environment
variables.
So now if you say GCM let's magnify
control scroll up GCM unspel now
now it'll say there it is you see and
another window idiocy you see you you do
you do not see the path but however you
want if you want to see the path you
need to expand the window and call the
command again now you see the path you
see anyway so now we have Windows. I
mean, we have Huntsbell installed.
Fantastic.
Any comments?
No comments. That mask says, "Hi." Okay,
so we got Hale installed.
Fantastic. So, what we do next? Um,
so we got, you know, we got also Hzip
and some some other stuff. Okay.
Hi, I'm late. Uh, you integrate hunt
spell as a kind of fly checker in the
buffer. Yes, I'm basically just making
spellch checking work on Emacs in
Windows.
So, my alarm clock,
that's my alarm clock telling me to get
up and walk every hour.
Otherwise, you get ass rot for you
computer professional computer extreme
programmers.
Okay, let's get hun spell checking to
work. So, hunp spell is installed. The
path is set. However, in Emacs,
you you need to do what several more
things. Right now, even though it's set
up, but Emacs doesn't know the new
updated environment variable. So, you
actually need to restart Emacs. Okay,
press the button. No, not that button.
Oh, I did. I I pressed the two buttons.
Okay, so Okay, so here's a new Emacs.
Now set up the font to be 23 and this
one is old. Let's make it black.
Fantastic.
Fantastic theme.
Okay. So here is a new. So this one
knows I spell. This old one doesn't know
I spell. So let's make it different
color. So that um so what you do meta x
customize theme.
Okay. So it says
what theme do you want?
Uh let's say
I don't want I'm not color blind. Uh
luven buffer is read only. What the [ __ ]
there? Louven. Okay that is the old. So
you got a different color. So now this
one is the fresh new Emacs. That's our
main.
So this one got unspel path.
Okay. So what is next? So if you can you
try spell checking. Okay. Correct.
So press this key space 9.
You see it doesn't work because you you
need to set up. Right now it's using a
spell. Okay. So now
let's see what is this page to do. No, I
don't want to do. Okay. Save. Let's go
to talk show. Okay. Talk showing
browser. Fantastic. And uh let's just
paste the word there. Correct.
Okay. Where did it go? Let's paste it
above here. Showing browser. Correct.
Okay. So, there's a few more things to
do. You need to set up. So, this guy,
thanks to this guy. This guy is, what's
his name? But he's Emacs Elements.
Uh, he's also a YouTuber. So, you guys
check out his tutorial. So, I'm just
going to go to his website
and just steal his code. So, he's got
this bunch of code.
Let's just steal it.
The ways of the open source
code by steel.
Okay. Start uh emac this code. Paste it
there. Pop it out to its own windows. So
it says the only real option is hunel.
Okay. Aspel won't work according to him.
So I download it and he says uh add it
to exec add this directory. Okay add the
hpel location to the x to this variable.
That's a variable in emacs. You can
how do I know? Because I have a tutorial
about it. Search
execute
path. You see fairly complicated. you
know what's the difference between
execute path and environment variable
path and so on. So anyway you can check
out and also I have a tutorial about
environment variables within Emacs.
So you can set up envir environment
variables within Emacs without touching
the external shell environment variable
if you want. So anyway, so I got several
tutorials, but now
uh now what we doing? So close, close,
close. Okay, so he says,
okay, so let's see what um what is it we
need to do here. Okay, show show space.
Okay, let's clean the code a little bit.
Okay. So, wait. So, British spelling.
No, I don't care about Brits.
Do you care about the Brits? I don't
care about the Brits. Actually, you
know, before I thought Brit British
English is sound sounds so nice. Not not
today.
My preferred English
accent is California.
California hippies actually not true. So
anyway, American spelling. So So what is
this saying? I spell program name. Okay.
So that's a variable. Let's see what's
the value.
So right now I have it as hunel. I mean
as aspel that's incorrect. So I need to
change it. So let's go to D drive. Let's
go to hunbel directory again.
So, hunsel copy file path close close.
So, this is my hunbell path.
Okay, so
yep,
cut
paste. Okay, that's what what what I
want. And I spell local dictionary. So,
what is the value describe var?
Oh, I need to um I need to start, you
know. So, this this is old. Close that.
And now,
now exhaust dot command log. Okay. Now,
you can see everything every command
name and keystrokes I call it will show
up there.
Okay. for example
cut you see okay so now describe
variable I spell local dictionary
value is new so let's set that and now
what is this
I spell local dictionary a list stand
for association list okay so what does
this um
I don't know so describe variable
Let's see list of local or customized
dictionary definitions. Yeah. Okay. So,
[Music]
so what is this list? So, seems
why is it so complicated?
So, it's a association beast. Okay.
Wait, you're supposed to have a dot if
you want associ what
I think this is incorrect. That's you
know this is not association list.
Okay, I think I don't care about this
for now. And uh
don't run code you don't trust. Okay, in
this case I don't need I don't need
those. Okay. So then you say if
I spell
h spell dictionary a list. So if that
that's okay. So
oh this is another variable Jesus.
Now is that bu in
it is
so it is actually defined. I mean this
variable is part of Emacs
I spell hpel so it's specific to hpel
okay
so
set that to I spell local dictionary a
list oh so it's going to so now you
actually need to put this back
because it's you know the value of this
variable in yellow
is referring to the value of this
variable in pink. So that's why you need
that. Okay. Then hell default
dictionary. So describe variable is that
so that is also a predefined variable in
EMAC in ice very complex complicated
[ __ ] you know the in software the most
number one important thing is you don't
want comp complexity
you want the things to be as simple as
possible
so anyway you see to setting up set up a
spell checker Uh it is now fairly
complicated. [ __ ] Okay. So anyway, this
we need this uh default dictionary
check. Okay. So yeah. Okay. So I think
we all that's all these what we need.
Okay. So
before we do anything, let's check let's
check spell check and see if it works.
So space 9 is my key.
Okay. So it does not work because it
says a spell
version is not correct. Okay. But now
so by the way the command I call is uh
let me show you. Okay. So the command I
just called is I spell word. Okay.
Okay. So now I run that
and I run that. Okay. You can see Alask
six. That's how I run it. Okay, now I
eval that. Now I eval that. Now I eval
that. So now everything should be set
up. Now let's do spell checking again.
Space nine.
Oh, spelling is correct. Can you see?
Successful.
Fantastic. That is the beauty of coding
or today's effort.
is done.
Yeah, alarm clock is great because I set
it I set it up. Basically, you need to
get up, you know, get your fat ass up
from the seat,
you know, flying by the seat of your
pants. You need to get up every hour,
walk for a minute or two, for five
minutes, actually. at minimum 5 minutes
every two hours but actually you you
know just get up you know move about for
for you know uh for a minute or two that
would be good this is advice for you
long-term programmers because you're
going to you know be coding for 10 20 30
years I've been coding for 30 years and
for you severe nerds because average
coders they they don't sit all day you
know They talk, they on the phone, they
gonna do something, they going to go
meetings, you know, that's normal
average coders. They go go to a job and
they go home and they eat go out for
dinner, whatever. But for a extreme nerd
like a mad scientist like me, I sit in
my chair for like 10 hours a day like
literally.
So when you are severe case like that
you need all my setup and and because
because I I I found out the hard way if
you sit you have h back pain eye pain
damages your eye all sort of problems.
So every every hour or two every two
hours you need to actually go out look
far which is what I do. Okay. So anyway
I spell is working fantastic. Okay. Now
put the code back. Color it. Show in
browser. So this is what we did today.
So let's there's another thing we want
to test. Okay. So there's another thing.
Um where is this? Um
we need to check if fly spell works.
Okay. So open that. So there's a command
fly spell fly spell buffer. So it will
highlight all incorrect words. Okay. So
let's open Alice in Wonderland
down the rabbit hole. Okay. Copy the
path. Open that page. So there it is.
Alice was beginning to get very tired.
Beginning. Okay. So let's begin.
And no
not the thing. Let's make it wrong.
Okay. Now call the command meta x fly
spell
buffer. Okay. Do it.
Spell checking complete. Fantastic and
beautiful. Can you see those red
underlines? Ching ching ching.
Now spellch checking is working.
Fantastic.
Beautiful.
Okay, I think that's it. Thank you guys
for watching. Is it entertaining?
Uh, you know, so actually let's turn on
visual line mod so that it doesn't cut
the words like that. So Alice in
Wonderland down the rabbit hole so I can
actually screenshot of it
to prove that we did this successfully.
Okay, now just delete that. Save. Close.
Close. Showing browser. Go back here. Go
here. And press, press, press. Now
screenshot magically appears here.
Showing browser. There it is. A
documentation of what we did today. So,
thank you guys for watching and times
it's time to pay me. Go to kasari.info.
Go to the bottom. You can see my
Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal. So if
you
are working as a professional, pay me
$100.
Okay, thank you. So let's see what's a
comment. Fun idea. Uh yeah, so how does
ice spell determine the boundary of the
word?
Well, that's
that um
you know that is you know that is not
too much of
you know that's not too important
question because because in English
sometimes you have hyphen hyphenated
word for example
electronic mail
okay so which beca it became email then
which evolved into just email without
the hyphen.
Uh and but you also have like one time.
Okay, for example, let me show you just
a simple one-time payment
of
of $100
to kabi
and you will
become a good person.
Okay. So there's one times simple one
time that you know that one time is
actually one word. Is that true?
Uh I'm pretty sure but you can let's say
I spell it. Okay. So uh space 9
time is correct. So you can see so you
can see it says time is correct. So that
means it doesn't pick up the hyphen.
But what what if our uh cursor is here?
So I spell again space 9 it says one is
correct. So that means I spell ignore
kind of ignore hyphen the hyphen serves
as a boundary.
So but is there a way to change that?
Uh you can look into but that's not too
important you know.
You know I can I can look into by uh for
example by first of all um describe
function
I spell word. Okay then you can see the
documentation for I spell word and then
you can um you can read you know you can
read the whole thing. Maybe it'll tell
you you know um optional argument what
whatever spell
I spell dictionaries and stuff you know
you can just read it I spell region and
know then eventually you jump to the
source code and then you know you can
spend few hours to dig to see if it's
configurable how it determines the
boundary of the world
okay anyway I don't think I care, right?
Or you know. So anyway, successful.
Fantastic. Thank you guys for watching.
Bye.
We shut down in two minutes.
[Music]
Mhm.
down the rabbit hole. Close. Copy.
Uh, paste link. Close. And this is the
three days ago episode. And this is
execute path. Copy.
Paste.
Okay. And uh, next. Go back. Uh, close.
And this is this guy's documentation.
Fantastic. So this guy is Emacs
Elements. Okay, check out his check out
his you know blog which helped me today
very uh easily set up everything.
Raul Raul Camino are you are you here
Rau Camino?
I think sometimes he is here. Okay so
check out this guy. Uh then my todo then
Windows tips close that. Uh okay reopen.
There is Windows tutorial on environment
variables. Everything you need to know
about it.
Okay. Copy the link here. Linkify both.
Okay. And uh uh then there is you can uh
do in PowerShell
PowerShell
you know uh okay close that close that
Linux back command line. Okay.
Okay. Bye.