Oh going live okay now I've been talking
for five minutes while I'm not alive but
now I'm alive so good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today's 2019 November 26th six o
clock in the afternoon San Francisco
time okay so now we begin okay so wait
did I talk for five minutes in vain so
the Moni Emily and George and not Nobby
so what is today's topic today's topic
is going to be and then Maurice come on
intense so yeah I'm alive so today's
topic is going to be so you guys pick a
topic okay the topics is in the
description box so pick a topic let me
know what so it's gonna be either
keyboards we have lots of keyboards to
talk about oh it's going to be email
based I have a very interesting Emacs
Lisp commands Emacs commands related to
to doing image manipulation like resize
convert or scale yes scale resize the
size and quad I'm gonna show you several
commands how to do that in Emacs and we
are going to code eMac this eMac this
first tutorial I'm going to going to
show you live coding I should have done
all this in advance now I need to clean
my glasses
lots of work well so anyway so this is
just doesn't matter so so Emily says
Emacs and Emily says keyboards and
George says I'm only half an hour okay
so not in not most interest okay so
George is most most interested in
keyboards so it's just two key words
then
in then okay so I have I had been
talking in vain for five minutes
okay so keyboard it is so we got
fantastic wonderful keyboards and mostly
from this guy by happenstance okay so
let's go to Saudi keyboards okay we got
knots of interesting interesting
interesting facts and guitar hands look
so sorry blog okay so you guys have not
already join my discord okay vibrant
verdant communication and discussions on
all sort of topics in particular
keyboards you see we got this we got
vintage keyboards this this Zenith then
Zenith no this is synth
okay so we got anyway we got lots of
vintage keyboards we got lots of
keyboard nerds and keyboard experts here
and they have their personal photos you
know this is not just marketing photos
this is personal photos of a beautiful
cat okay so if you guys have not already
joined this cord okay my discord link is
everywhere sorry discord you can find my
discarding for example right there in my
Saudi keyboard blog and so on keyboard
we have this guy who first of all let me
show you this hello beautiful people's
video okay hello beautiful people he he
possesses this key Mouse device refresh
wait what what arrow arrow occurred how
the JavaScript is not long now refresh
okay so here is his video he did a video
today that's two hours long
basically in depth look at the key mouse
device now the keymod device it's a
keyboard and mouse together in one you
know so you might go check out his video
I have not done yet I only watched for
like five minutes so it's a long one so
check it out and so we have this guy so
one day two days two days ago I was
flaming this this keyboard okay I was
flaming the hell out of it on this
keyboard let me show you this one google
this gogo keyboard I said it's crap and
this guy heard it and he just you know
he went on discord and he said oh I
agree with your comments it's on the
spot then he began to show me his
keyboards his designs and lots of it so
so we have you know so and so he is a
keyboard maker you know he's one of the
keyboard maker he created a lot of
keyboards you know to it yourself kids
you can buy and you know when you are
and he sells them like he has a company
I guess sort of company and he sells
them and you can so you can buy so so
when you make a keyboard use you
actually get into lots of the design
stuff so anyway he started to show me
many of his keyboards and different
designs and you know very very
interesting but mostly he is interested
in you know keyboard with not many keys
let me show you okay so anyway so this
is a Google keyboard it's kind of
similar in shape to ago ago docks okay
so you can buy this one is 50 keys
and comes in varieties of key switches I
believe this key switches chalk piece
which I you know I don't know the
details yet but anyway you can go to his
website and find out so you know if you
like it go there buy his stuff and I got
a freebie you know he said he's going to
send me one of his keyboard so thank you
Chum now this guy okay I'm not sure
what's his real name or he said you know
but anyway he goes by the name Jim and
his website is chipboard start CA so
apparently he's in Canada and right now
he is attending apparently Tokyo is
having their yearly keyboard Meetup
so he is going to Tokyo attending the
Tokyo keyboard middle and oh my god and
you know so he's a keyboard maker and
you know when you have tons of photos
you know building and you know machinery
and you know so lots of photos and they
are fantastic so I'm going to talk about
some of his keyboards for example all
these are his keyboards you know they oh
he's fit photos and also when you are
making keyboards and some of them they
are internal like you don't see it much
on websites you know because they are
still experimenting for example this one
he explained to me you know you know
discussion why this is interesting so
this one for example this is coded it's
like a steno okay it's a steno
coded keyboard yeah so in fantastic
photos and many very interesting things
and and also when you are a keyboard
designer you also go out and buy all the
stuff you know that's in the market so
you can compare notes and he got this
thing this thing is $300 these three
track balls it's used for V
you're editing for you know video
editing see apparently is very
complicated thing the banana chip your
board which which one is that oh this
one that's the name of it oh maybe
that's the name you created I don't know
so anyway so he's got very interesting
photos and he showed me some of the very
interesting things you know for example
it here is his keyboards for sale you
have a stack of them literally a stack
you know you don't see these photos much
so that's fantastic and I'm grabbing his
photos to put on my website and put my
annotations commentaries so with some
kind of explanation you know typically
these designers they are nerds you know
there are things they they talk in
keyboard community jargons like you read
them you have no idea what they're
talking about you know by the way also
there's this keyboard this one this is
spectacular okay apparently they okay
this they mean well let me magnify okay
magnify shrink a little bit so
apparently they are ripping the
Microsoft trackball design now on the
right you see this this trackball they
made it apparently they 3d printed it or
something like that okay probably 3d
printed so they recreate it so this
model this is actually Microsoft very
popular is said it's said to be the best
trackball ever okay so and on Amazon you
can see people are saving it for $500 on
Amazon for the past ten years five
hundred dollars or three hundred dollars
so let's go to trackball okay so you can
see that's a Microsoft
trackball so trackball you go to check
ball history trackball history and you
go to let's see there it is
Microsoft trackball Explorer now many
you know I've been reading this for like
20 years so this is supposed to be the
best trackball design ever and over the
you know over the past 10 years make
Microsoft stopped making it because
according to Microsoft they said they
don't get much sales rather you made you
just make Mouse because mouse you have
hundred times more sales than trackball
it's an unfortunate fact because people
just adopt you know Mouse becomes the
universal device so this Microsoft
stopped making this about 15 years ago
in 2005 or so but when this but
trackball infuse yet enthusiasts
consider this one to be the best
typically almost universally because you
you see a lot of people who are willing
to spend $300 $500 for this brand new so
anyway so apparently they you know so
there we have it Microsoft trackball
Explorer and you can see this one on
Amazon $579 and this is 2019 okay so
you're going and you have videos okay so
it's hold on a second see if I'm still
good yes I'm still good okay so so
anyway so so they you know this guy jump
apparently they are recreating this you
know it's fantastic they are recreating
this trackball on the left is another
track war this one came out this year
2019 it this one is from Japan
but anyways yes so a lot of interesting
things so anyway how no second umekes
let me get ye okay so
comments okay so let me see I need to
okay so let's talk about his stuff so
he's got okay begin let's begin with
these oh go go go Kibo so you have this
keyboard but there is more okay so let's
go to do-it-yourself keyboards so he
apparently he is interested for some
reason he is interested in reducing the
number of keys on keyboard that's not my
thing you know I I don't like this 50
percent keyboards I think this sucks but
maybe I'll change my mind because on
these 50 percent keyboards you cannot
type you don't have a number row so
whenever you need to type a number you
have to use a code so and also if you
type Chinese basically about every 5 or
6 keystrokes you need to type a number 1
of 1 2 3 4 5 every about 6 keystrokes so
that may be a problem but however you
know I never tried this keyboard I will
have to see maybe you know maybe I just
because I haven't never tried it you
have to use code now let me let me get
into the the code thing so so you got
this go go then you got okay where is it
so let me go through the my blog okay
greetings
Oh greetings spot but you are not sleep
yet so we're talking about his keyboard
so let's go to let's talk about some of
you okay here here it is so this so you
can see let me open them okay this is
key reduction to the extreme crazy so
you begin with the gurgle 50 keys that's
not enough you don't have number rows so
okay then you know he used that then
then he started to do this one this one
is Georgie this one is called Georgie
keyboard now this one in particular is
designed for steno so you use it for
stay no if you don't know what steno is
you know you have to read this article I
talked about that few with videos back
anyway so this one is designed as a
stain of replacement so you can buy this
and you can try it but also you you can
also use use it as a standard keyboard
not using it as steno when you type
steno basically that means you have to
use a system a shorthand system that
types the phonetics with codes but
however you could also use this keyboard
as a normal keyboard but again you have
to do codes so if you like that you know
it's not expensive it's like fifty
dollars forty dollars very interesting
so but also I learned one new thing
completely new with this you know with
his stuff that is the key you know our
typical keyboard such as this one this
key switch you know Cherry MX red Brown
blue the pressure is about 50 grams or
40 grams Cherry MX red is 40 grams to
press it down to activate the key but on
this keyboard on this GOG it only takes
12 grams so that's amazing that's almost
like four times less pressure and
apparently someone you know there's a
video that you can even below you know
just by below to activate the key
blowing air to actively weigh the key so
that's so that would be a completely
total different experience when you use
this keyboard so so maybe they'll be
good you know I don't know and Emily
also has one of these you know
apparently so very interesting so this
one is a total of thirty keys total 15
for each hand but then you have this
extreme 10 keys total now so this one is
complete coded keyboard and there's a
precedent precedence which is this one
pad keyboard so you type letters by you
know like piano combination of keys and
it takes sometimes to learn here is the
cheat sheet so that's that that is that
that is his keyboards that's you know
that that's is that is some you know
he's some of the keyboards he does he
makes the one thing that's most
interesting to me is the 12 grams key
switch 12 grams pressure so that would
be your completely complete new
experience so we were you know I'll see
how that goes
yeah a sneeze would press a key down
like literally yes so I'm not sure you
know you have to try to see way so Emily
you have that one right I mean you have
this you have this GOG so what what do
you so that is also 12 grams right
so how does it feel
anyway so you know he's going to send me
one
thank you John very much and I'm going
to you know I'm going to have fun with
it
and maybe I like it I don't know for
sure but you know because you know I'm
also a keyboard nerds
so I'm going to start to play with it
I'm going to start to think about you
know how to remap design a key system
for Mike you know Emacs Sophocles and so
on and maybe something interesting will
come up and also the interesting thing
to note is that these are not expensive
at all like they are just $60 $70 you go
to his website and you can buy it and
apparently many of them are pretty old
okay I don't want to go this page this
is not a good landing page you want to
go to their product page okay so yeah
yeah I don't want to I don't want okay
let's go through Google let's go here
okay so you go to their website there so
all go to all products so here is a list
of their keyboards a sale you see only
$40 $40 this one $95 cheap comparatively
very cheap and it's fantastic because oh
this uses the qmk or was it qmt the
open-source software so you can
reprogram or the keys any way you want
almost
so for nerd this is wonderful but also
they also make let me mention okay they
also make this program about keypads
this is fantastic this for example this
one $75 that's cheap you know because if
you go Amazon if you go to Amazon you
buy a poem or Kiba keypad usually they
are more than $75 but with this one you
can you know with QM
you can you can program it in much more
flexible in quite a lot of ways and
another thing I noticed is that many of
his keyboards it's already pre-built so
you don't have to be ordered you just
buy it and come out you know you got
this no case though you don't have a
case if you want a case you can you can
3d print it yeah there are websites that
you know they have data about this case
for these keyboards he has shown he has
shown me shown shown the links in this
code so anyway so I think it's fantastic
now let me show you this one okay let me
show you this one so he's got this and
then we have then we have this butter
stick battle station so this is one of
the keyboard he makes one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten twenty
keys programmable keypad and then then
we have here a pair of station now let's
look at this so apparently some guy you
have this guy you know he's maybe a
gamer but he's he this is his Sparrow
station the his entire keyboard is just
his 20 keys now I don't know if this
this is for real but he's he mentioned
you know apparently there are people who
just is I don't think it's real I don't
think it's you know it's real you know
what they say daily drive you know I
don't know I'm not sure about that so
that's very interesting you know you you
have that so that's about that that's
the main thing I think how long I have
I've been talking again maybe how long
have I been talking let's see go back to
YouTube video what we okay 24 minutes
okay so I think today let's not do too
long we think it may be 40 minutes but
that's the main thing I want to cover
about his keyboards so it's fantastic
you guys check it out
and the go buy it okay and also you know
because you know he he is a keyboard
maker so he has contacts with other
keyboard makers and friends you know and
they you know he so he showed me a bunch
of things that's truly fantastic like
for example look at this one larboard
it's basically do it yourself version of
this thing this thing is called data
hand I talked about in my last few days
ago video but anyways someone is
recreating it 3d print it and this
machinery it's fantastic you know this
very complicated you know this this is
almost almost like steampunk thing yeah
so very interesting okay another thing
let me go I'm going to read the comments
okay but one more thing let me mention
one more thing is so there is another
keyboard designer who patrons me $5 a
month he likes me to present his
keyboard you know this one on my blog so
I started to do that but this is
incomplete this is just a draft so this
keyboard is this it's interesting is you
know to me this is very interesting
although it doesn't have number row so
I'm not sure
like it right off the bat but but it's
interesting because you got a knob now
this is novel this is a novelty I mean
this is a great design you don't see
this much okay so you got this knob knob
can be used for many things you can I
talked about this before you want a knob
okay you do want a knob on the keyboard
it's it can be useful backward forward
browser windows last window next window
previous tab book next tab back watch
our flow chart backward word-for-word
chart
forward backward page forward page you
know page download page up or mouse
wheel school or volume up/down all those
things you have backward and forward
versions for those kind of commands the
Rio is the best physical mechanism for
it
for examples imagine the sound volume
wheel you know many audio devices you
have a sound volume wheel but however on
computer keyboards usually you have a
key the key is a pen you know you don't
you hold it down the edge overshoot oh
you you have to keep pressing it it's no
good for so for anything that's kind of
especially for sound level you want a
knob okay that's a most suitable so so
they got a knob wheel here so that's
very interesting but also for back for
example I can show you so many things
you know I can show you so many things
about you know for example I can move my
chart forward backward right that's
typical you just hold down arrow keys or
up up arrow or down arrow but the thing
that most people have not thought of is
that you can actually use make a mouse
scroll wheel to do that and that that is
actually optimal it's better than
holding the arrow key I actually I have
showed that before but let me just show
it again okay
let me show you why let me show you an
application of the power of the wheel
okay the knob thing so let's go to Emacs
you go through practical Emacs then
actually you go to any setup in search
for mouse okay then here you have set
mouse buttons okay then you have okay
let me show you this command so so let's
copy that copy it and let's create a new
buffer paste it in Lodge
save it xx dot al a temp name then we
have two commands let's rewrite it okay
so let's say
for what okay let's just say right what
again it's sitting okay so right would
and for world would move closer to the
right okay so that's one command right
what okay and copy it and paste it in
leftward okay move closer to the left
okay then okay so we have these two
commands actually we don't need we don't
need those commands all we need is to
bind the mouse wheel to it so let's do
it
okay we just need to bind the mouse
wheel to it
so let's see so describe describe key
then I draw my mouse up so that command
is called wheel okay
so here is what we're gonna do that's
all we gonna do so so we're gonna global
set key wheel up then wheel up is
forward okay then we're down let's
describe cha
we are down is backward okay evaluate it
evaluate it now we are good to go now
let's look at my wheel you see it's
fantastic now especially because I have
a I have a spin wheel with the Logitech
mouse so you can see I you know it's
it's fantastic
forward would and also and also you can
make this you know if you find it too
small you can make this let's say 10
watts for World War 10 and back World
War 10 so let's let's change it so let's
actually remove actually leave those so
right word is here then left word okay
Eva buffer now I scroll up its okay I
scroll down
each time I scroll down it's 10 words to
the left you see 10 10 10 10 10 10 10 10
10 10 10 10
okay let's switch buffer okay now let's
see this one 10 10 let's let's go
through some other San talk show magnify
okay
scroll down well okay I got the
directions wrong but anyway you see each
time I scroll it's ten words so if I
spin it and see if I spin it it's going
to all the way up now I go down you see
now I go up so that's that's kind of a
demo of the power of the knob and you
can control it finally too and it can
use for moving tab too and you know
anyway so that that is very interesting
okay so actually let me be the comments
anyway so let me finish with this so
this is a great thing a great keyboard
this is called kiria
yeah key we are keyboard but however his
website is not well done I mean maybe
there's not much info there the ten
minutes I spent looking at it you know
you don't see many pictures and you know
so you can buy it but however you go to
his blog okay this guy toma spot he's
got a fantastic blog I only spent five
minutes yesterday so I don't know the
details yet but apparently he's got many
many interesting things going on in his
blog you know he also you know he's also
a keyboard maker so and he's got for
example he has a blog about steno
devices you know he's got I haven't read
it yet but I'm pretty sure it'd be very
interesting you know so you know he
showed several photos of the steno
device and oh yeah so very interesting
so check that out so that's I think
that's about it for today
you know several keyboard stuff so let's
see see the comments and and maybe
there'll be it
or today let's see stop these let's see
the comments
okay so Emily says that 12 grams key
switch is pretty good okay she says it's
really nice okay but okay yeah so I mean
I have to see for myself it means you
know so it's very light anyway so some
way out says I would design a tenting
holder stand for the for that cut of
wood yeah that would be good two words
per minutes may be useful to school
through layers especially when there are
few keys fuel keys screw through lay
layers no you easy using the mouse wheel
to scroll through layers I don't like
the layer thing okay that's yeah that's
my that's my opinion
yeah I mean my that's my own opinion I
never liked you know when you have less
keys then you need chords or lots of
modifiers and then you need layers
that's what layers you know they come
hand-in-hand so you have less keys then
you have lots of chords you know you
need modifiers and you need layers so
you layer these phone numbers layer that
for punctuation and things like that
but so far I am I don't like that idea
because I rather prefer you have a
hundred keys thousand keys you know
cockpit
power station everything you do is just
one single key press you know or knob
schnapps and quiescing you know like
that so you don't have to OH
to get this symbol I need to hold this
one or that one like control shift quick
front in that you have to memorize it
you know I I didn't like that I don't
like that but if you are just typing
English or you know it could be good I
don't know especially if you have you
know light you know special design so I
don't know for sure
like a mantra yes that yeah I really you
know I would love motrin I would love
the motrin one so let's see anything
else so maybe that's it for today that's
so that's wait for two minutes we're
gonna shut down so much wrong so much on
is great okay so let's look at this cord
and it's just look at did I miss
anything I want to talk about so so
check out this Q yeah okay so you just
go to my blog and you can find all the
links check out the key Mouse review bye
hello beautiful people
check out the G industries butter stick
battle station this this I highly
recommend actually even without knowing
even without having it I'm pretty sure I
we all love like love it super love it
this butter stick Emily also has one yes
I believe right I think I saw yeah yes
see I love it because this is this is
going to be a fantastic for programmable
keypad you know you can actually get two
of these and also you know even for the
this you know some of these suppose
suppose you know I don't like this
suppose he you know he sent it to me and
I tried it I don't like it but the thing
is with this it's it's it's going to be
a fantastic programmable keypad you know
if you don't like it you don't use it as
your main keyboard but but these things
is gonna be fantastic the most fantastic
keypad so so you can you know so you
have your main keyboard Kinesis or
Google Docs or motrin or whatever or
hacking keyboard oh happy hacking people
then you have this you know Inferno
somewhere use you know you have one pad
for browsers you know previous tab next
tab select all copy paste all that and
do then you can have another one for
Photoshop so this it's so I think this
yes I think it's great you know even
just for that purpose the original PC
keyboards better than the current layout
what do you mean they don't differ by
much anything else anything else we
shutting down in one more minute so
let's see so yeah go check out the key
Mouse video go check out this G industry
skies things and this photo is a
beautiful photo now who gave this photo
I forgot this I think it's okay fun
track very a very interesting guy
anyways this photo cat okay so let's go
back and also check out the queue yeah
oh yeah function keys on the left that
yeah I think that's better you know so
on some keyboards you have function two
rows of two columns of function keys on
the left okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching check this code
for the ultimate keyboard okay
and join join discord old Oh hand sighs
I need to mention so here we are we are
looking at we are looking at Emily's
hand okay and we're gonna measure it her
hand is about 22 centimeters okay
let's see if you can see it you know we
are talking about sizes so yeah so okay
so I'm gonna I'm going to show you my
hand size so my hand size if I stretch
it this is a ruler if I stretch it it's
like 20 centimeters you know from one
end to the other 20 centimeters but my
left hand is like 2021 for some a bit so
one centimeter larger so here's Emily's
hand she's her hand is on the a4 paper
basically her you know from fingertip to
fingertip
it's 22 centimeters for Emily okay so
that that's about that so you can go
measure your hand and why is this so
this is relevant to the this is relevant
to when you are using Kinesis okay so
make Kinesis because in Kinesis you have
you know you have the thumb keys and for
most people only one of the thumb keys
is is comfortable for the other thumb
keys you have to stretch that's that is
a case for me for Emily I think and for
some world oh okay so this code for
ultimate keyboard sölden and let's go
see that one last thing
okay so some way out
okay so ultimate keyboard let's see we
got food what is this food how big
feature rice with cheese I think but
let's look at the keyboard
uh emo girl okay so emo girl okay so
let's see magnify
okay so this is a point-of-sale keyboard
it's your keyboard some Weld yes I
believe this is this is point-of-sale
keyboards point-of-sale keyboards are
those type of keyboards where you go to
store the checkout that's what they use
you know for some small stores you buy
this keyboard usually they come with
credit card swipers like let me show you
so that's yours somewhere
point pony up sale keyboard let's see so
actually you can buy them on Amazon so
you got several for example this one
point-of-sale keyboards and some of them
also have credit card swipers and if you
look at them they have bunch of ports in
the back you know serial connectors and
whatnot
bunch of jacks and I have a friend on
Twitter he's got one of these and he be
mapped his keys so anyway
Oh fortune huh okay so that's
interesting
okay thank you guys for coming bye guys