hello guys so today I'm going to talk
about Emacs Lisp I'm going to code hello
guys good morning so today I'm going to
code a Emacs Lisp command that converts
English alphabet to run up a bit so okay
I'm I'm waiting for people to come in
but meanwhile let's change the title
Emacs peace write a command to convert
English to run okay Renick okay that is
my title here
okay it's not a talk show but rather
let's just say talk show doesn't matter
so I'm going to talk about yes so what
do you mean by your script let me show
you okay so here is unicode runic it's
very interesting now this is Asian
script it's used to write Germanic
Germanic languages it it is used between
year 150 to 15000 and the use for German
Germanic languages Germanic languages
includes English germany german dutch
afrikaans danish icelandic and so on so
basically each of these letters
correspond to a one of the English
letters so hi guys
glad to see you guys
alright so we're gonna cover so these
are runic alphabets these are ancient
you know it starts in around year on
year 150 so English was written in this
script actually before the Latin
alphabet replaced it so that seems to be
the case I don't know I don't know the
history but you can read Wikipedia so
anyway this in this runic script seems
there's a lot kicks are interested in it
for example we here have a keyboard with
a runic keycaps
very interesting so I'm going to just so
I'm I'm going to so what I mean by
converting English alphabet to that so
for example
let's copy this thing copy here okay
hold on a second new buffer paste
magnify magnify so for example this
character corresponds to F and so on for
each one of them so I'm going to write a
script so that I can for example just
highlight this paragraph press a button
and they all become runic okay but
before we do that let me turn on the key
log mod so start command log mod so in
this window you will see all the
commands I call in Emacs so whenever I
do something and you want to know what
command I'm calling just look at the
left panel okay yeah it's very useful so
let's start so actually I have written a
similar thing here so we gonna just
start by copying that that code where is
it skipped examples command examples
eMac these command examples let's see so
I have written one that converts English
alphabets through to gothic letters
let's see
Alysse miscellaneous search for gothic
gothic convert practically magnus
command examples Emacs text transform
under cruiser he should be here
so let's go to Emacs miscellaneous no
it's not here
okay so Emacs Emacs miscellaneous there
it is okay here you see these are gothic
letters or they call it black letter or
Frank Frank - so in this command you can
see let's try that so for example I'm
going to so copy this new buffer paste
it here magnify magnify and go to HTML
mod magnify okay so wait magnify and
remove the P tag so here's a bunch of
text actually that's too big okay now
I'm just selected call gothic there it
is now convert
Latin alphabet gothic enter so they are
so they became these gothic letters
these are actually unicode because you
can put your cursor there and the court
described cha so on here you can see it
says it says this is the unicode code
point 1 2 0 1 0 1 and the character name
is mathematical franked a small edge so
if you call the command again it will
convert back to english i think is that
true ok
no but let's look up let's call describe
function so when code interactively will
conquer my own tactics text selection if
any universal argument is called first
reverse direction so that means I press
control you first then I call the
command
then you see it converts back to english
so what I'm going to do is just
basically copy this I'm just going to
copy this code now this code is here
let's copy it create Anubhava paste it
save us xx convert yeah
that's just a temporary name so there we
have it and let's change the name
convert come Latin to run okay
okay so let's do that so if you if you
have any questions just type in a
comment so any comment just type it so
that I know where I'm going so first of
all let's this is all in one line and I
wanted to be in several lines so let's
to find angry face query replace replace
that by that yes replace all okay so
this way it's easier to see and magnify
the buffer and okay but before we do
anything we actually need to know how
how one is mapped to English letters so
let's go to Wikipedia run your neck so
Wikipedia magnify magnify magnify and
good
they are actually several runic
alphabets the early the earliest one is
this elder out of birth lock that's
that's what it's called so let's see if
I can find oh there it is so great I'm
just going to gonna copy this
okay copy it back to Emacs paste it here
okay so I'm I need to convert this
format to this map format here so the
trick is you know how we gonna do it
okay let's see now the window it's not
wide enough let's increase the window
size
oops
okay so you know we want to figure out
the most efficient way
you know just the efficient way to
change this into the the lisp format
let's see okay some of it is not so cut
that out
put it here and cut it out face it here
remove that remove that that's just F
now show space now change your tabs to
space query replace ctrl Q tab replace
by space yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes
yes yes okay something's wrong there
it's look good because we got one more
characters somewhere here so let's stop
them you know we are not going to do
this very accurately because you know
I'm mostly I'm just going to show you
how how to write the Emacs Lisp function
okay over here it seems everything is
got a corresponding character but why is
that why they don't match so let's see X
is mapped to G
XG p m and w so this p is w
then okay they don't match up mostly
just because the font ma are not mono
space that's right okay so now I have
you know we can you know what we can do
is that count cha count words so it
tells me there are 48 characters now go
to this line count words 47 characters
okay something's not right
oh I got a extra space here let's do it
again con words 47 con words 47 that's
good
so I'm we're going to turn these two
lines into this format okay so how do we
do that what is the efficient what what
is a efficient way I guess if you can go
to Oak mod and do a table transpose it's
problematic actually it's the actually
it's probably faster if I just type them
the most basic method okay there is
another so any suggestions
how did you pull how did you put all the
brackets on separate lines you just do a
query replace oh you have oh I did was
just replace the replace space by new
line so anyway so let's let me get back
to how do I convert a format oh my god I
thought this is going to be quick how
long have I been talking 15 minutes
already man
transposed to it oak transpose okay is
there some kind of transpose table
transpose sub ward transfer hangar okay
no you see if this is a matrix then we
can just transpose into this vertical
form but
okay let's do a keyboard Marco then yeah
let's do a keyboard Marco Marco :
maybe we have to do several tries so
let's make several copies back here and
[Music]
okay let's try this
so keyboard mark was so I'm going to do
first of all I'm going to remove all the
spaces space none because it's easier if
you don't have spaces okay then I'm
going to do start Marco start selection
move okay
stop create the split the window and new
buffer this way it's easier so I'm going
to do first of all copy this paste copy
paste okay so I'm going to start the
mark row select move to the right cut
switch buffer paste switch with a move
down start selection move to the right
cut that's a mistake okay yeah yeah okay
so let's redo okay it's kind so
everything we do start mark well start
selection move closer to the right cut
switch with a paste switch with a move
down start selection move closer to the
right cut switch with a paste enter new
line switch with a move kusa up stop
macro
okay we got a macro now let's hope it
works
magnify magnify magnify okay so let's
run the macro now watch the left panel
you will see the command I'm coding so
I'm going to yes that worked
Coyle again yes now I'm just going to do
this trick not watch don't don't don't
don't don't don't don't don't don't
don't don't don't and Duncan don't and
then it's out then it's fantastic
now what happened is that I was coding
now I don't know why is it not showing
on the Left panel but the command I was
calling was you know first of all I was
calling this command call as keyboard
macro so once I call that each time I
call this command it will you know do
why mark well then then the command
I was calling was was what repeat
okay yeah they are I was calling a
command that just the name of the
command is just repeat so what the
repeat command does is that it will just
repeat whatever the command you were
calling last time
however with with the extra such that
you can just press keep pressing the key
T in my case okay yeah so I just keep
pressing the key T you can see here does
it show okay I don't know okay anyway
name is summarized let me repeat it
repeat it one more time so I recorded a
macro then I was calling I was calling
the command coalesced keyboard macro
then I call the command named repeat and
call that command again again again you
know repeat repeat repeat
but however I'm not doing MX repeat I'm
just pressing that the key the key space
TT on my keyboard so you know after I
called the collapse macro command I just
press space T and just keep pressing
ttttt and that's how I do it
okay so let's cut the whole thing out
cut it out close it paste it here now we
just want to add the square bracket
that's easy so let's let's do a macro
again first of all copy it paste just in
case we make a mistake so start mark
well that
and stop macro so I'm just going to
select this whole thing then say apply
macro to region lines that's fantastic
we almost done okay so hold on second
cut it out we don't need this country
put it here just in case you know I'm
I'm putting those here save this file
just in case we need it back you know
redo something so now that is that we
need it to be in this format yeah so you
just okay so that's pretty easy so
select this narrow to region go to top
select that I actually it's just do this
okay then call rectangle replace
rectangle in just for the space put
double quote that and actually so so we
add that that we need to add the quote
in the back actually is just do this
they are not in mono space so that's
kind of a problem so penny anyway let's
just replace the end bracket replace
that by okay now we need to do another
replace this time we will need to do
query replace rejects okay double quote
any char
then we need to we need to start with a
left square bracket then a double coil
then this is he makes regular
expressions pimples so we're gonna do a
Braga's parenthesis and capture the one
character there then we gonna that's it
I think that's it so let's do that
replace it with replace with the first
capture there and had a square bracket
so I think that's it yes yes I we we
made a mistake because actually you need
another okay let's just do this thing
they face that by
this is taking longer than what should
be I'm just going to do it quickly
because I think we are taking too long
so anyway it's done it's done TV dad
copy it shrink space go go - here paste
it and go - we don't need that you don't
need that okay so there it is actually
this works shrink okay so that's good we
need to change this documentation we
don't care for now it's just for the
date and that's it I think that's it
actually let's just try it then
see you 24s keyboard mark oh yeah that
works I was using Co apply to apply mark
or two lines
oh yeah multiple curves cursors yeah no
I don't use it so so okay that's it
that's it let's run the command it's
just try to execute you know normally we
should change the variable name like
Latin to gothic and stuff but for now
it's just run the command so oops so you
need to indent it first then Eve Audi
fun that's it done so let's let's say
copy let's copy that new buffer paste
select or MX saw convert Latin to run
yes
no it didn't work oh the direction must
be reversed so control u MX yay so it
works that's great it works the first
time so there we have it
so now what should we do next
should we like title tidy up the whole
thing like you know the proper
documentation or should I you know start
to explain how the code works okay let's
let me explain how the code works yeah
so you know forget the documentation I
mean we can we can you know
change that after so first of all so
this command so this part I'm going to
go command to shrink them and Latin to
gothic so let's replace it by button to
run your Nick okay now it looks much
better now the whole thing is in shape
now okay so this command what does it do
it takes figure argument speaking end
and reverse direction P now in eMac base
when you have a name that ends in P
usually that means it's a predicate
meaning the value of that variable
function is just true or false true or
false
any Magnus when it's true a by
convention true is represented by the
symbol T like teddy bear T and force is
by convention Neil so anyway so it takes
the beginning picking end and you know
true false value begin means the
beginning of kusa position and similarly
for end and Kusum perceived position in
Emacs is just a integer and you can tell
what could who's a physician you are by
calling the command describe cha now
look at the left panel you see it says
that I'm this position is position 2 out
of 12 46 so if my cursor is you know for
example over here I call describe cha
and my position is 150 so you know kusa
position is an integer so you know
beginning and position you know that's
the argument to this function then it
starts with the interactive
this interactive here means that okay
first of all there's a if statement if
use region P that means if people have
the transient mark mod R meaning that
when you do a selection you will
highlight then use region P is true you
remember remember P for predicate it
returns true or false so this is a
function we can evaluate it so let's try
to evaluate it so I call eval last sex
you can see it's near beneath it you see
in the mini buffer it says Neil because
because I don't have any selection on
however if I for example selected then I
call eval region okay no okay well okay
so explain any email is output is in the
buffer messages so there's a command to
switch to messages buffer so let me call
that so that command is called view echo
area messages so now we can see you know
here's my message but for all the past
messages and now we go back here we
select the whole thing yeah we selected
and we call the command Evo region
okay it should return it should return
true but I don't know why it's not
returning true band
well anyway they did move on to the
important things so if there is a so
basically this pastor says if there is a
selection then you do this if there's no
selection you do this so when there is a
selection you do this now this part
returns a list list means we now return
a list and okay region beginning is a
function that returns the position of
the beginning of region like right here
you know where my cursor is and you know
it so it region beginning reach an end
and this is a built-in variable in eMac
this current prefix arc that the value
of this variable is
you know remember we caught control you
let me show you describe function okay
describe key control you you can see
over here control U is calling the
command universal argument which is a
mechanism to give arguments to the
command you are calling so in this
command in this command you know convert
Latin to run we wanted to be such that
if you press control you first if we
were to reverse converge direction you
see so how does a command know you I you
want to you whether you pressed control
you that is you know from this variable
current prefix arc you know the current
prefix arc the value is just the the
value is control you basically you know
control you has other options like you
can give it a numerical you can press
you know you can impress for example
control you
three then that means it has a argument
you know a value of three so anyway so
any anyway so this part you know if
there is a region then do this this just
returns a list that gives the beginning
position the end selection position and
whether control U is pressed and in this
list you know the if you use interactive
you know when you if you use interactive
and if it returns the list it will pass
the the list elements elements to your
functions arguments that's how you do it
you know it's a little bit complicated I
mean if you are if if this is your first
time doing eMac this I recommended that
you don't do it actually the whole thing
can be written like this
you know without yeah I would recommend
you don't do any of that just just do
this okay yeah just do this and actually
let me modify this let me show you how
let's wait so let begin oops
picking and by the way you notice that
at sign this at sign and this dollar
sign those are not necessary I'm using
them simply for my just for my very own
variable names so that I can easily
determine which variable name is the
came from the function parameter and
which variable name are local variables
so that's just my own personal
convention you don't have to do that
eMac list variable names or function
names allows almost any character oh
yeah basically almost any character you
can also use unicode character in fact
so anyway so I so so this is the version
this we can do it this way and so you
know we don't have to give it any
argument so interactive the what does
the interactive do is that it just lets
so that this function can be code by
pressing M X that's basically what what
the interactive does so for example if
you if you define a function without
interactive then when you press M X the
function we are not even show up you can
only call the function in Emacs Lisp
like for example if I you know say like
that you know so if you want it to be a
command you have to say that so let is a
way to to create local variables in
Emacs so you can see this lets structure
has two parts one part is this part the
other part is this part wait
the other part is what whatever the rest
of the last bracket which is basically
from here to you know to somewhere
somewhere here yeah so anyway I'm not
doing I don't think I'm doing a good job
like I'm you know unstructured am i
doing okay
hijack don't you
so keep the questions coming okay if you
anything you you want to ask just ask it
I am talking yeah okay so you know I'm
I'm a little bit I'm rambling a little
bit because I'm not sure actually I
should start from you know because I'm
assuming most of you guys have not coded
eMac this before but my explanation so
far are not basic things you know is
rather you know getting you know because
you don't even know how to write a
function stuff well but anyway so you
can you know you can be the code later
so I'm going to okay here's what I let's
do this first I'm going to copy this
copy it now go to my Emacs blog okay and
I'm going to paste this here so wait
where do I section okay I'm going to
paste it here so that he marries okay
color it showing browser so that after
the video you can see you know you can
just you know maybe study the code or
you can study oh yeah it's already here
you know this is converting to the
Frankfurt it's it's wonderful because
you're going to learn lots of things and
then you become powerful you know you
can write commands on the spot for
whatever your needs when using Emacs so
okay how long have I been talking 40
minutes maybe
minutes
okay so I'm going to so we have this
command working so that's great
actually let me clean up should we yeah
instead of explaining the details let
let me just clean it up for today
I have by the way I did another stream a
few days ago maybe last week that
teaches beginning beginners eMac this so
you might check that out so for this one
right now this command there's a problem
because the direct Direction is wrong so
so what I want to do is Latin to Roenick
the direction is wrong so okay so here
is a map use maps so what is this okay
use map so we need a method to reverse
this map here so you see here is a map
we want another map where each pair is
reversed order and that code is right
here wait no it's not there it's is
right here this so let's let me do this
copy that paste Latin to UNIX so this is
actually u unic to Latin okay and so
this so this is starting to runic wait
this is runic this is runic to Latin and
we want to reverse here so I'm going to
they're getting up paste it here and
basically I'm going to program it
programmatically reverse the pairs the
order in the page in a map so let's so
actually I need to let star let's star
means that for each variable it will be
when you say the variable the value will
be available for the next variable to
use so basically I'm going to route into
Latin
okay so I think that's it so unique to
Latin that's right and Latin to
which is the reverse here and use map is
this is a variable that tells us which
map to use so if reverse direction is
true then we want to use the map unique
to Latin okay there else use Latin to
runic that's right correct then now it's
much simpler so now save excursion save
restriction narrow to region and let
okay let's just give out the code and
let's select something let's see let's
select this paragraph paste it here
magnify
call
oh it did just for the lines we want to
select the whole thing and co-ed that's
great
selected koi okay now control u MX chord
okay
that's working that's great I think
that's it that's it's gonna that's gonna
be here today there are many refinement
we can do for example when you co it you
know if we'll just do the current line
because because this you see it checks
if there's a selection if there's no
selection it just does the first line
but actually what's better is that is
that he'll do the first paragraph I mean
whatever the paragraph you know between
blank blank lines so that if I call the
command now you'll just do the whole
thing so we can add that bye-bye
basically just change this line you know
so instead of line beginning position we
wanted to be the beginning position of
the paragraph and similarly for here
however Emacs do not have a you know
function that just returns the beginning
of paragraph because the meaning of
paragraph is different depending on a
major mod so I mean so that's one thing
we might to add you know automatically
do the whole thing on the paragraph
without needing users to select it the
other thing we can do is that
automatically determine which direction
to switch to you can check you can do
that by checking if there's any English
letters you know intersection if there
is no English letters then you know it's
run so you want to convert run to
English to Latin or you can just check
if it contains
any yearning characters but the problem
with that is that oftentimes your texts
may contain both for example this for
example this paragraph you know because
this is used for fun purposes you know
you want to maybe post on your in your
blog you know you part of it contains
you know English words in part of it
contains the you know the weird alphabet
so if you so there is no sure way to
automatically tell you know actually
which direction you want to go so that's
you know some of the extensions you can
you know you can try to add to it okay
so I think that's it for today thanks
for coming whoever you are still there
I'll see you next time bye