good morning my friends
welcome to another episode of some talk
show today is 2020
august 18th tuesday
two o'clock in the afternoon san
francisco time
and today we're gonna talk about emacs
uh
a little bit emacs workflow with
stuff like keys and we are going to look
at
the package projectile you know this
there is this fantastic
package projectile by the bats
bats more love something like that he's
in the
eastern europe you know he's a great
one of the big emacs this coder he
has written quite a few very popular
packages
so one of them is projectile which i
actually tried
a few years ago about five years ago i
tried it for a week
but it was too slow uh we'll have
another look today and now
you are going to watch my reactions
uh on on the projectile so
live chat okay so so my window is not
loading correctly i guess
um
we i'm not seeing the live chat thing
okay but yeah so let's let's start to do
let's start to do let me reload the
window so first of all the background
image
so today's background image is that that
college
flag you can see let me show you
so apparently someone probably a college
student
in usa created this emacs flag
this is typical college flag i guess for
football
for american football for the you know
the rambo so that is the background
image
for today okay so let's go back let's
start to
um do today's thing emacs college flag
and um
i want i need to fix the chat up so let
me reload okay
uh go back
go to it
excuse me for a second
go back here
[Applause]
okay is the chat back where's the chat
[ __ ] refresh six viewers good morning
guys
so comments okay i'm i can't i cannot
see comments the chat is not loading so
we're gonna start
um
oh there you are ratsu that's you from
scotland
hello good morning eric carson
hi where are you from eric
so okay so let's um let's do it
um i'm going to look at projectile let's
start with that okay
let's look at projectile so projectile
open a new window uh e-max
project tile
jh c t-i-l-e
okay um
github batsov projectile
so that is his uh so this is his
projectile package
and basically it's a package that allows
you to
easily navigate project directory
you know today these days you have
projects uh since about 10 years ago
projects becomes very popular you know
there's a
term project what it would you know
let me tell you a bit history about
software development
so so project means you know there's a
standard english meaning project you
know you have a project for something
for business or something
but in software
you started to have this project
terminology which
means basically it means well it means a
project
just like an english word but also it
refers to a specific directory
and all that all that projects directory
is
in in this directory and it's also
so it so it's a project
it's also a directory but also it
usually
um means it has a uh
the version control system typically git
you know git
or mercurial docs you know some several
others but today most popular is good
so a project means a directory a project
a directory and also
it means it's a version control there's
a version control system
running on that part on that directory
um
you know so so so that's what you know
so today about 10 years ago you started
to have this
concept of this software project
which means you know a directory and a
repository you know
all that all that together you call it a
project
and it also means when you start to code
some programs some software
you no longer just create a directory
and start to code it you
you almost always do you create this
project directory structure which has
you know several
subfolders subdirectories that's uh
that's a project it's this is kind of
annoying okay
because before it's a free form but now
it's a
anyway so so projectile
is for navigating files in your project
so you go to a project typically it
means there's a git uh
you know git git managed you know
repository then there are several files
and usually they have a structure
there's a certain structure depending on
different languages
javascript for example is the the one
most
associated with project directory
javascript
but also go land these days but also
ruby
back then uh so project
so often these days if you want to learn
a new language such as javascript or
or something you they always tell you
you know the basic tutorials they tell
you to create a project directory
which is kind of um okay anyway
so projectile this is the emacs package
that allows you to uh
navigate in search directories and i
look at
i looked at all the features you know i
don't use projectile
uh many of them you can do
very fast with uh
soft like keys system my system okay
so anyway let's let's start to install
it so let's
uh okay so on the right window is the
the pink window you can see all my emacs
command cores
uh using stuff like keys
let's do these packages i'm going to
install proj
projectile
okay list packages and let's
search for project tile
okay console projectile those are
projectile add-ons go projectile
grails projectile what a bunch of crap
oak projectile let's just search for
projectile
p-r-o-j-e-c-t-i-l-e
okay so you have 41 packages
that's all part of
i mean related add-on for the projectile
so here it is projectile
manage and navigate projects in emacs
easily you know it's funny why why
should you emacs already has a
fantastic system for for file management
for
you know navigating so in theory tech
you know in theory you don't need it
so let's uh let's install it
okay install it yes
mailpad uh not named for servers not
provided or not known what dev
what the [ __ ]
80 not name no servers provided or not
no what
what ah
yes install what no not no what
okay problem we run into a problem
already
so go to the messages buffer what's the
what is the error message
mailpad mailbox.net 80
not name no serve server name
provided or not no
this might relate to package initialize
let's see um let's go to my emacs
directory so
my go let's go to my emacs a brief go to
the directory
then go to the init okay
my emacs need init enlarge
um let's search for mailpad
okay i don't see any mailpad lines here
wait that's not right okay search
all directories for mailpad i mean
search all files in this directory for
mailpath so
in this directory dot el
okay so we found several uh mailpad so
it's in
emacs settings okay so in emacs settings
so magnify so this is the blog
require package add to list
mail power mailbox packages why is it
not
so let's open the directory
um we are having trouble finding that
site what doc
okay https let's try https
open it open the file wait is mailpop
down or what or did they change
uh url
software frustrations incredible
milkbox.net
website expired the account has expired
what
let's go to let's search for mailpad
good morning alan eric carson from
sweden wow
cool informatic good morning
so melpa melpa.org
what's going on
melpa.org but did they
so did they change the url
uh so let's see their init file so
getting started okay
let's copy okay so they did change the
url so i haven't installed the package
for
for a few months i guess the
so let's copy it paste it here
uh so this is the new url is here
melpa.org
no longer milk box you know milk box
there's a
the milk box
is um
let's go to my emacs uh tutorial okay
open open it my emacs tutorial magnify
you go to emacs init and you go
to install packages
so i need to update this url
so let me explain what's going on with
the milkbox.net
so so mailpad the e-max package system
began
uh in 2012.
there's a bit history you know in x
emacs in x
emacs they have a package system back in
but the gnu e max richard stollman
refused it
refused to have that feature because he
want tight control of the gnu
the whole emacs uh system he wants
tights control he is afraid that
once you have a package system you know
then there's going to be
a huge number of packages you know
and then you know it's then he will be
uh out outside of his control which is
happening today on male part you know
you have like twenty thousand
ten thousand or something packages and
there are not
many of many people they are there are
not
you know uh gnu emacs they are not
free software phonetics they are not
dedicated fans of richard stowman
so anyway in 1991 xemax
already has a package system but richard
stollman refused to do that
and uh up until 2012
2012 when packages you know you have so
many
by by 2000 by 2012 you have so many
languages they have uh
repo you know online report you know you
have npm
which is for the javascript python has
one java has one almost every language
has their
repo where is a you know centralized
collection of libraries
so eventually in 2012 emacs started to
have it
2012. you know to me it's like yesterday
to me it's
still like yesterday uh say so
melpah um let's see who wrote male part
i don't remember now so
but i wrote it here
okay yeah so i there's a so male part is
written by this guy
tom chumley tom tron me he's a
uh expert you know one of the top
experts of emac beast
and mama laid mama lady is another
ripper for
uh emacs and he's written by this guy
and melpa is by
mailpad the repository you know the
website is started by this guy
donald download frame
curtis but his online nickname is
melkman melkman so that's why you have
the mailbox.net
you know this is his uh you know website
is
expired so i need to uh update my
website
that is why male 1 repo had used to have
this url
i'm pretty sure it was working last year
but it changed
it when expired okay copy that to my to
my website
close that go to my talk show page
today's talk show and post it there
okay how to install packages
close it close it
then back to my back to my emacs
init let's change the url to the correct
url
okay then delete that then evaluate this
code
save it it's good close it
now list packages
hey good morning jeff troll uh
gdb maintainer i think troll me oh i see
i see i you know i know he he is a
he is a great uh lisp coder and beca
he has written some
project to speed up emacs i think he
also had a commonly
based emacs project uh he was working on
that for a while i think
yeah but he's an old timer yeah uh
i don't even free software foundation
are dedicated fine
fans of stoneman yeah he's so man
richard someone kind of um
he's he's getting old i mean he's old
now so anyway let's
uh try to install a projectile so at
least
this matching lines projectile okay
and which which one this one okay
projectile okay uh
this one yeah okay
enter install
install package yes
uh it it still says mailpad mailbox
postman
what the the url is not has not been
updated but
uh close that let's go back to my emacs
lisp in need file settings
add to list oh i need to so
the reason it's not updated because i
was using add to list i i need to use i
need to remove the old list
packages archive
and let's restart emacs that's the
easiest way
i can just set that list to nil and
then run that code your work without
needing to restart but
it's it's faster kind of it's easier
just to restart emacs
so okay so start command log mod
start command log mod so you can see all
my commands on the pink window
so list matching lines i mean uh
list packages let's install projectile
again
at least matching lines projectile okay
is it projectile
what oh here
okay enter
install it yes yay
finally package projectile is
you know there is this strange message
for mailpad uh
when i install some package it will say
package projectile is available obsolete
does anyone know what does that mean
you know available status available
opposite for mailpad
what does that mean
uh okay so let's so projectile is
installed
now how do i use it now i need to go to
a project
uh we i need a big project to look at
projectile because
menu i suppose projectile is useful
only if when you have a project that has
lots of files
and lots of nested directories
so let's see if i have a project
i don't think i have a project with huge
number of directories so
emacs well
uh projectile okay so we also need to
read
we also need to read the documentation
for projectile
okay i'm kind of lost here
so what do we gonna do
let's just go to soft like keys for now
okay
so this is my package it's only
one file actually only one single file
but let's just try some projectile
so i suppose you need to meta x
meta x projectile
mod do i like do i have to turn it on or
let's try projectile mod projectile mod
enabled
okay i think i need to read the
documentation i think
it's a minor mod yes this projectile is
a minor mod
and so what do you project
tile so let's do this okay
control h a for check
tile so that will list all commands with
the name projectile
projectile fine file projectile add
known project projectile ag
ag is mercury i think projectile browse
up uh dirty project projectile cache
buff of
current file clean up projectile diode
uh
yeah i think you know i this requires
one to read the documentation a little
bit so you know what
actually what to do with it what
commands to call
so why don't you use a linux distro
uh that's that question i can answer
that but i answered that
a few times
um so what are we doing now projectile
so
so does anyone use projectile uh
find files in so in this short demo you
can see
find files in a project switching
between implement
implement implementation and test
switching between projects you can
support my work
okay quick start the instructions that
follow are meant to get you from zero to
running projectile
in a minute okay installation
okay i guess many of you are not using
it um
those those with uh those with a job
are probably not reading not watching my
youtube
except jeff's
[Laughter]
projectile you know i think it's fairly
popular
for people in you know you work in a
company you have
a huge number of source code
wait wait where is my window okay here
um
i have to i have to read the
documentation then that's going to get
boring
building package manager is a
package okay installation basic usage
enable projectile mod okay
open a file in one of your projects and
type the command such as
cc control cpf okay
so i'm in a project directory yes wait
let's go to my emacs directory but so
because then there are tons of files
okay so in emacs directory this is also
a project
because you go up you can see uh it's
good
project it's a project directory so now
it says
control c p f so let's let's see what
let's see what command that that key
runs okay
describe key control c
p control c p
is not undefined okay let's try
projectile mod again
meta x projectile mod disabled okay
do it again enabled now
describe key control c p
ah control c p is not undef is not
defined
but it says control c p f what the [ __ ]
see the user manual for more details
yeah
okay let's do this again
let's see all the commands of projectile
now which one has the control cp
[Music]
f
yeah i i'm i'm running out of patience
with this
uh actually the problem is that i i
really need to read
the you know the basic usage
and type of command such as control cpf
yeah but but
uh but
yeah that's ctrl c pdf right
so close that back to
back to my project okay let's try again
projectile is on you can see in the mini
buffer
in the mod line so now
describe key control c
p it doesn't show okay let's just call
it
ctrl c ctrl h
so we can see all the commands starting
with ctrl
c and now let's
search for projectile
it's not there
okay so i'm back in my emacs blog i mean
my
talk show page it's just called
ctrl c p
control cp is not defined god
frustration
oh you have to you have to add the key
binding yourself
[Laughter]
you have to add the key binding yourself
so let's copy that
so okay so we need actually you need to
alternatively use the debian ni or blah
blah blah
finally add this to your emacs you need
file so okay
so apparently projectile is a collection
of uh commands
then but you need to add the keys
yourself so let's go to
star talk show i mean let's go to
star talk show um
showing browser okay you need to add
commands yourself so let's
um so what are you saying
define key meta
p wait not this is super
okay projectile command map that's the
key you want okay let's let's go define
a key
and let's you know let's do what they
tell us to do okay so
meanwhile i show you my workflow so i go
to my
uh using a bookmark go to my brief file
go to the directory
then go to let's say go to
miscellaneous okay
this is my miscellaneous emac list code
and at bottom
paste this key actually
save it close it open the keybinding
file
so here's my key binding setup
let's at the top let's just say that
and
ctrl c p okay so run it
okay save it back to
my close that closet
okay uh back to my
talk show page
and like
not sure what i'm doing so let's try try
the command
ctrl c p
wait what what
i thought i just did it
hang on a second ctrl c
p ctrl h
there it is i should have my keys so
so we got all these projectile commands
and keys let's try it again
ctrl c p
oh okay so ctrl c p is the prefix
of all a bunch of keys
is that right yeah so projectile command
map that's actually a key map you know
there's
one edlc in emacs in emacs
when you create a key map a key map is
basically
basically a table of con configuration
of shortcut keys okay
so you can create a key map but when you
create a key map
by convention the variable name for
key map is is dash
map not dash key map
so it's stash map you know that's just a
convention so
it should be a dash key map that's
better
because map could mean you know so many
things it's a table
for uh you know it's just a map you know
key value pairs for
so for so many things for example if
if if it actually says key map
then i would realize that this this is a
prefix key because it's a key map
so anyway so project tile has all these
commands let's try projectile diode okay
let's go back to my uh xory info page
so that is also a project then
ctrl c p capital d
projectile diode
it just goes to the diode i mean what's
the difference between
a normal diet command
you know i i don't think
i i think i'm doing this showing
projectile
many to flame it so
we look at the projectile source code
let's see what is
it doing function define projectile
diode okay open diode at the root of the
project oh it's
okay so it actually goes through the
router project let's try again
the talk show page ctrl c
p capital d oh yeah okay so it goes to
the root of the
of the project that's that's useful yeah
that's useful because
if you have a project sometimes you have
like five levels of nested directories
uh and you are in one of the nested
directories you want to go to the
root of the project directory so
so okay so this command is useful we
know that
now ctrl c p
control h now let's look at projectile
commands again
so projectile diet goes to the root of
directory um let's see what else to
you see i'm trying to find some you know
i'm trying to
evaluate this package
i'm trying to see what benefit
it may have
you know because first of all emacs is
already you know
it has styled has bookmarks has all that
it's supposed in theory you know it
already
does a great job of managing files
doesn't matter it's a project directory
or not
so what does projectile add to it
that that is the question um
and also i want to say you know i well
anyway so let's see
comments
okay so how long have been talking
35 minutes this is george good morning
george
ccpp and ccpf okay that's what
george says what he used ccpp
ccpp is
projectile switch project okay and ccpf
is uh hold on a second
go to talk show and let's paste it here
okay
and ccpf projectile find file
let's try them so projectile find file
let's just call by name
enter it okay so it takes
a few seconds to to respond
why because probably because i have
i have thousands i have literally
thousands of files
in this directory
so let's look at that documentation
projectile find file
okay projectile find file jump to a
projects file using completion
okay so so m e mike sardi
uh lee.info directory you can see
so here is my uh project root sally.info
and you can see a git you know this is a
project
but this is basically my website and it
has
like 20 000 files so it's kind of a
huge project 20 000
20 000 files and
uh but it does not have
that many nested directory uh
the dps is three or four levels nesting
directories so
so when you say projective find file
let's try it again
so put project find file let's say i
want to try to go to my golan
tutorial so goal line tutorial is in a
go land directory so
project project projectile find file
let's type golan
go lan oh okay so this is great
so you see it shows all my go land
directories and documents
if when i just type go so you can see
let me not magnify
okay so you can see all the gold line
yeah
okay so this is actually useful
yeah so thank you george
uh you know normally the way i do it
is for example so for so so if i want to
go my goal and
uh directory
i press three keys and i have my
bookmarks or book
bookmarks so i type geo
that is go land uh i press enter
and this is my golan tutorial
uh file you show in browser you see it's
golden
and if you want to go to the directory
you just press two keys
called dire jump so that's how you go to
the directory and
you know once you open the file then you
can you can
you can press three keys that's
uh i do find file so you can now you can
open
any file in this directory so that's
how i normally do it without um
so the the the thing
i mean the the disadvantage of this is
that
when whenever you work with a new
project or whenever you want to open a
file that
that that's frequently used you need
to add it to a bookmark
you know so there's one time work
for example let's go to let's go to my
let's go to our camel i don't remember i
have a camera i do have a camel
bookmark already so anyway let's
let's show my bookmark okay let's go to
let's
find the python so magnify
so i have three python bookmarks
that lets me easily go to there so for
example i press a key
type python and i have several choices
you can see python python 2 open it
showing browser python 2 website
close it so but now let's remove those
bookmarks
d for delete x for delete them
save it close bookmark
close close close now i want to open
python again
i type python it's not there okay so
it's not there
so but if i want to do it
so i have to add to a bookmark so let's
go to the directory python directory
about okay show in browser
back to emacs go to the diode
so here's the python directory so i need
to
let's say search for index okay so this
is the index file
open it showing browser back to emacs
i need to add this file to the bookmark
so
i have a shortcut key so he asked me
for a name let's say python okay
enter now it's done now close it
close it if i want to open it again now
i do a
bookmark okay now at python okay
python is already on top enter so it
opens that
file so but there is the step you need
to add to a bookmark
but with projectile let's go to bookmark
again
search for python magnify so here it is
deleted delete save close
now with projectile i don't have to do
that so i guess that's the
that's a that that's a big advantage
because once you
you know if you work in a company you
might have several projects going on
you know you don't want you know you
don't want to add a bookmark for every
project because some project you just
use it once uh you don't so let's try
projectile find file
okay then let's type python there it is
so i have all my python
let's say python list let's say python
dictionary i have a file
that's about python dictionary so i type
python
d-i-c-t yeah
okay then went to some other um
let's magnify it okay let's try it again
okay
so meta x
project tile find file let's magnify
pyt python
python dictionary okay so d-i-c-t
so i don't see that let's try
a r a that array
it's not there so maybe i need to put a
underscore
yeah so type the full name python
p y t h o n okay then
d i c t okay so now
it shows up uh still
it's very good python versus emac b log
string convention
okay that's interesting python 2 to
python 3 difference
python dictionary methods that's the one
i want
enter showing browser
okay that's that's uh very useful let's
try another
so projectile switch project why do you
need that
um projectile switch project isn't uh so
it's bound to
so projectile switch to a project we
have visited before
what what does that do i mean if you
want to
switch to a pr to a file that that
you already visited you can just
um call recent recent file so for
example
i just call it space ch
with soft like keys foreign ch so all
these files are
the files i just opened recently so you
have golan
you have um you know then you can press
the number to go to it let's say five
show in browser you know close it
back to emacs close it so
uh recent recent recent file that's very
uh useful
let's go to my emacs tutorial then you
can
if you you can see
so let me let me let let's try to use
the projectile feature
to locate my emacs website's
tutorial page on opening recent files
so it should be this one let me open it
okay so
emacs tutorial search for
so you go down file
open recently opened so
he this this is the tutorial this page
that shows you
talks about this feature so
my let's go to my emacs directory so
there it is
this is my emacs blog back to emacs so
this is a project
now let's call the projectile
find file okay now let's
type re
e magnify e n there it is fantastic
okay so actually i could use projectile
i could you know it's great so
so you guys go install projectile but
you know see you see now i find this
feature i'm going to steal it
so it's going to be part of satellite
keys
you know right so
so this feature where you call a command
that we are located
that will try to find all parents
directories
of all the parents parent directory chen
until it finds a parent directory that
has a
git dot git file
then in that directory it's considered
the root of the project
so so when you call the command it will
search all the way up the parent
parent directory until you find found a
root then in
all these directories it will try to
compile
a list of all files in this directory
then just show you you know then present
it to i do
i do is the interface that pops up the
you know list of choices
so this is actually easy to write it's
not difficult to write so
so you just go to you know you just go
to the parent directory until you find a
directory with a
dot git then list all files in those
directories
then show it on i do so it's not
difficult to implement
so actually i will consider i mean
seriously i will consider adding these
two
uh sapphire keys the command
what command shall it be
it could be part of the find file
command i do find
file or it could be
yeah this is a great feature okay so
anyway
so maybe i'll do it coding live coding
next time
and maybe that's it for today
okay anything else maybe that's it for
today let's see
projectile so so great so we
um let's see open last opened
yeah okay close that wait uh copy the
file path
close it show in browser
close it back to emacs close it close it
close it
and paste the link here show
linkify showing browser okay so that's
what today
we are what we've been done
and the command so let's pretty fine
let's make some predefications okay
uh wait show the pink window
add that add that then
add that then
add that showing browser so we
pretty fire them like that then also
do that like that so you hoover mouse
over
it should show it pops up a
tooltip that that is the documentation
the inline documentation for that
i don't have it here because you know
projectile is kind of new
i mean you need to
actually that's not the way i do it
but usually it's like that
okay let's write documentation for it
open a file in a project with
flex match okay
showing browser so that's projectile
find file
open the file in a project with flex
match
open a file in the
in a project of current
uh with flex match interface
then projectile switch project that one
i'm not sure what's the utility okay
so that's it so uh thank you guys for
watching
html modding action yeah uh
what else uh what else
i think that's it i have so many things
to talk about but
i need to like i need to stop somewhere
because otherwise it's infinite
uh anything else i wanna any any
questions you guys might have
so let me mention again okay so actually
let's go to my emacs blog
one last mission so there is so jeff is
here
i don't know if jeffy is still here but
jeff jeff
jeff runs the emacs meet up san
francisco okay so
you so there is one upcoming that is
online based so we all you know go go
online and
so you go to the website uh here
so let's copy it okay you go there and
make
uh register and make a reservation
because
there is a limit of 20 people
so you should go register it so let me
post
the link here
and maybe i'll see you guys there so
right now it's 16 people already so four
more spots
maybe we'll see you there there online
this is next week sometimes go to the
website
bye guys