good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 2021 may
5th and we are going to do
javascript coding okay we are going to
continue
uh the javascript coding
to create a diagram interactive
diagram compute calculation so let me
show you
uh so i did a video uh but i did
two two or three videos before working
on the interactive diagram so what's
interactive diagram
let me show you okay so search for
diagram
so you just go to uh
sally keyboard okay just go to saudi
keyboard
and you you pick you know just go to any
keyboard page
and go to the keyboard guide then go to
my blog
then then uh diagram so there it is
background work in progress
so you can see this okay so i need to
turn on javascript
refresh so you can see the background so
this is what we did
uh in last two or three videos uh coding
javascript
with svg scalable scalable graph
scalable vector graphics to create this
so for example
empty then you see
when you start to type and you
start to see the diagram
so so you can see right now there's a
for example if i just type t h t h t h t
h t h
you can see the th becomes the most
frequent and here is the
uh data so th occurs
zero point nineteen percent of the time
and ht occurs zero point uh
uh for example th space
th space th space th space th space
so anyway so that's a background so but
as you said you can see
this diagram is not so good uh it's not
done yet because
because when you type when you copy for
example let's copy the
entire page here and paste it here
you see when you have lots of text the
diagram gets jumbled up
so we need to truncate we have quite a
few things to do we have to truncate
uh the you know the you know after
you know we want to have the option to
show the top
20 bi-grams something like that and also
you can see the
data is you know you also need to
truncate
right now it's showing percentage for
example th
shows 0.06
uh times relative to all the
other diagrams now it's better to show
the count instead
like how how many times th occurred
so and also you see the label is no good
so
let's go go back here and
there they are them
they him he she
uh you know so so there are quite a few
things to do
and also you see the label for the
diagram they need to have a count
showing
uh beside the label so let's
let's continue doing coding that diagram
okay so
copy the url
go to talk show showing page uh go back
here open this file
show in page the here is the talk show
page and we are going to paste
here so that's today's spike i'm showing
browser diagram calculator okay so
we are going to start to code that
open that background calculator and here
is
the web page
now um
so you can kind of ignore all these
that's a google tracker the google
uh you know statistics uh so you
basically on this page uh
uh do i have to so if you don't know
what i'm doing
so check out the previous two videos
just go to
saudi youtube youtube saudi account then
today's date
then find the preview then find
the previous javascript uh
topics you will find those two
javascript diagrams we
we code it from scratch no other
libraries required
plain javascript okay no comments okay
two people watching that's just a bot
and z trump crazy
okay so i'm going to start to code
diagrams uh if
there's no people watching i'm just
going to code quickly so background
calculator so
here is the code
uh yeah i'm going to so yeah if you
don't know what i'm
you know we did the previous two or
three videos
explained all these details so first of
all what what do we need to do for
so first of all these percentage let's
get them into count instead okay so
so but first of all the the html file
let me show you the few important things
here so
the important things in the html is just
these three lines
the first line is the uh four lines okay
so
this one two three four these four lines
the first one
is the text area text area that's where
that's a
that's a box you type text the second
one is the svg display area which is
actually just the empty dive
uh that's you need that so that you can
tell javascript to
insert the svg graphics there
then then there is this show box showbox
is kind of the
the place you want to insert the data
you know the data how the number of
occurrences the count of currencies are
background
then the last one is the javascript code
of course
so yeah so remember
the text area then the display area
id then the show box id then the
javascript diagram
calculator okay let's open the
javascript now magnify
uh i mean full screen window so here is
the
explanation the documentation of what
this script is doing
okay then the first part uh is
we want to get those you know important
html elements text area
the show box and the display area we
want to grab it
then there's a bunch of functions string
two diagram okay so
this function takes a string and returns
a
javascript map object where
the keys are the diagram strings
you know th or ab or bc cd
then the the value is the
number of occurrences count
so that's one function uh string two
diagram
then we have salt map so it's a map
object and returns an array of entries
sorted by the values okay we need to
sort it because when you
display the diagram you want them sorted
okay so let's get familiar with what
functions we have in this javascript
page
so sort map we got that we covered that
then we have
uh map filter okay what does this do
returns a
new map where a function
f key value returns true uh what
yeah so you want to filter the map
uh given a function as a criteria
if the function the function takes two
arguments key and value of the map
and if it returns true that means that
element
stays in the map
okay so filter yeah why do you want to
filter
the map because in a diagram sometimes
you have
you know punctuations period space or
comma or question mark or exclamation
mark or you know all sort of thing
typically when you compute diagrams you
don't consider
you know punctuations or other or emoji
as part of the diagram you only usually
you are only concerned with
um the letters
the alphabets okay but we should have a
option
so that uh so that
people can click um
you know whether we want to have the
diagram just the letters or uh
or or including punctuation so we need
options so let's write down what we need
to do okay so let's
write down something we need to add
uh okay add a
option so that the
diagram is just letters
or
may include punctuation
and any other character such as space
okay um
that's one thing we need to do and
another thing we need to do is
add option
so that
only the top 20
diagram are included in the
chart okay yeah that's
two things we need to do so far and
let's continue to look at the code okay
uh map filter we need okay then
we have then we have a
function filter map takes a map
objects returns a map object
with keys that contain chart that's not
english letter
so this is this is a specific filter
function
for our diagram it filters out uh
any diagram that contains none letter
okay so let's rename it because this is
this is not a good name so filter map
let's rename it so okay go to top call
find and replace type in filter map
enter then replace it by
filter map letters only okay
do that do that do that okay
so we have this function defined here
and called here okay
filter map letters only now it
the function name explains itself
fantastic this
is one of the good thing you want to do
when you have
code when it comes to the naming of
functions
by just reading the name of the function
you understand what it does
okay filter map letters only um
let's see what else takes the map
objects returns a map object where keys
that contain char that's not english
letter
with only keys that that
uh uh wait
with with only keys that contain
contains only english letter okay that's
not so
well worded but let's let's leave it
let's not spend too too much time on
these uh filter map letters only then
the next function f compute
percentage okay given a diagram
map object return a map object
where the values are ratio of sum of
values okay
so technically this is not a percentage
because if you want percentage you need
to
multiply them by 100
okay so this compute percentage um
so where is it called it's called once
here okay
okay then let's see next
so so the next function is draw svg okay
so draw
svg is a bit big not too many lines
20 lines true svg
draw svg text takes a map
object and create a svg
a bar chart
and insert the svg element into the
display
svg display area element
okay so it just takes a map
object that's right
okay so that's this function we are
almost done we are basically done then
we have this update function uh which
caused all our functions before update
uh constant diagram
equals to f string to diagram okay
you take a string and convert it to
diagram and the string
came from the html implement
input element text area dot value
so that's a string
and you turn it to diagram so you got a
background map
object okay then
you take the background map
then you sort it then you filter it
and leaving only letter by grams then
you compute percentage
okay then you have the percent
percentage map okay then you draw svg
percentage map
okay there is something we want to fix
we want to change the draw svg to take
a should you be
percent i mean should should the
argument be a
map of bi-gram counts or should it be a
map of bi-gram
percentage
i should i think it should be just by
diagram count
so okay so so that's minor issues so you
know
this is about uh the code design of the
code function you know design of the
function should
should destroy svg function
take let's write it down
uh let's write it down okay
should should the function take function
argument the map of
diagram count or
map map of diagram percentage
it should be count
because that's better design
because count is more
common you know yeah so this is the
minor point we want to fix
okay uh
okay so so now let's go back to the draw
svg function
so we can see the joys vg function is
there
and and continue here the function
update
then we draw the svg then we
the show box is where the
you know the the textual data
is going to be inserted so show box
text content equals through json string
file
then percentage map okay so here
one of the thing we want to change is
not we don't want the percentage map we
want the count because the percent you
know
it's too too too many digits so let's
change it to
count
okay so before we uh count so we need to
also hold on a second
so let's copy that
filtered map
diagram map okay so we want a
constant constant name will be filtered
by gram map
and the value will be
this okay so we want just the letters of
the diagram
okay so copy that then
this part
let me show you
so it will be just that okay then
filtered then the sh then
when we want to insert the data it
should just be
filtered by gram map okay so now
i think we fixed one thing predefined
the code
and now we um predefined the code
now now this is actually a typescript
file you can see at the bottom it's a
typescript
uh and how can you tell also because
you see this thing that's a type
that's you know typescript is a superset
of javascript
so any javascript is also typescript
but however so typescript so what's a
superset you know it typescript
adds types you can declare types
in a javascript variable so here
you are looking at this html input
element that's a typescript thing
that says this text area is
of the type html input element
so that's uh so that's so this is
this is from typescript so because this
file is typescript
we need to compile it to javascript
otherwise the browser wouldn't
understand so let's compile okay
compile typescript compile file enter
great it says shell command succeeded
without
with no output now if we go to diode
you can see this is our typescript and
this is the javascript
and you can open the javascript
basically you can see
the code is basically the same except
you see
it removed it removed you know that
typescript thing so okay so anyway
so back to this file close close close
so you see now we go back to javascript
to the browser
refresh fantastic now let's magnify you
see
now we got the count instead of the huge
you know decimal numbers that's ratio
now this is fantastic
okay now now let's type a b a
b let's copy the a b space okay copy
paste paste paste paste paste paste
space paste paste
so a b becomes the most frequent okay
now we actually fixed one thing now
let's go back to the code
go to the top let's see what else we
need to do
okay we need to add two options add a
option so that only the top
200 top 20 background are included okay
let's do this one
add a option so that only the top two 20
diagrams are included okay
so we need to add option in the html
you know a checkbox so how do we do that
that's easy you go to sardi
javascript just search for javascript in
depth okay
hold on a second js in depth
you'll find my website
javascript in depth go there then you go
to dom
with dom is the document object model
which is the basically an api
in browser that
lets you code javascript and connect to
all the browsers elements such as the
window
such as the text box such as click
you know getting a click of move the
elements
anything you want you know that's how
web
applications are written javascript and
dom dom is kind of the api that controls
the browser
and by the way it's also how typescript
that that's how
also the atom editor
uh and
vs code microsoft vs code they are
written in this
api called electron which is uh
pretty good and electron is written
[Music]
using the google chrome's browser and
you know it's full it's just basically
written in javascript and dom
so dom is the all important thing when
you call javascript
so we are here where are we here because
we need to add a check box
so i'm going to show you how to add the
checkbox you see a checkbox
so here's how you write the uh checkbox
so married
no yes so you click you click on that
you can see the result
update as you click so okay
check box so here is the html code copy
it
uh copy it shrink back to the browser
close that go to the html file
so paste the text box uh check box here
so we have here the code
check box one uh let's rename it id
check box uh show top 20 okay so you
you'll say
show top 20 okay
type check box name show top 20
and value uh
value we don't care about value uh
what the value should be
okay i forgot okay value is optional if
omitted the default value is on
yeah we don't need the value check is
optional okay
so so by default it's checked we don't
need the value
delete the value
okay so that's a show check box
and uh let's put a label
for the uh
show top 20
so that's the label
show top 20 only so here we got that
and the result we don't need this result
box we don't need okay
now show in browser so you see we got
the check
box working now it does nothing because
we haven't done any javascript to it
now let's go to the javascript and do
something to it
okay so copy the id for this input box
that's what we need copy it
now open the javascript file and at the
top
over here we're going to add it here so
copy that
there it is so this line
we'll grab this checkbox element
that's right now but how do you know
that checkbox is checked or not
we go back to the checkbox tutorial
so here is the javascript that tells you
how to know if a checkbox is checked or
not
so copy the code back to javascript code
then then uh
then you go back to uh
go back to all the way to the bottom
then you
[Music]
uh first of all create an empty area
just paste it here okay paste
the paste our code here uh
so this part is what we are going to add
so we want to
we want to first of all add event
listener okay
so add event listener so
uh okay so what's the name of our
checkbox
show top 20 okay show top 20 add event
listener
then input input means whenever it
changed
that's right so you see we can see
example from the code here so here's the
checkbox at
event listener yeah so if
so the event name is input that means
whenever the checkbox
is changed then it will call this
function okay
now don't don't worry about the third
argument you can look up
you can look up the event listener if
you are interested
so show so this line showed
top 20 dot event listener
and blah blah blah this line means
whenever the check box is changed
it will call the function f update okay
so that means when it's whenever it's
changed uh close that
whenever it's changed constant torque
shot so whenever it's changed
it will redraw the svg basically
so okay so what else we
we need to do so about the check box
okay uh
okay
okay so when whenever now whenever the
checkbox is changed
it will redraw it but however our code
to redraw it
has not changed so right now it does
nothing
we need to add code
uh and we still don't know how to
know in javascript how do you how do you
know
whether the checkbox is checked right
now so far this line only
tells the javascript to run the update
code whenever it's changed
so how do you know it's checked so back
to the code here
uh color picker not color picker the
show check box
so how do you know it's checked here
okay
so here is the code that tells you
so here is the code okay so let's let me
simplify this so you can see
so here is a sample update function then
you have
showbox one text content
equals to check box one checked to
string okay
so how do you know it's checked simple
check checkbox start checked
it will return true or false okay
so this code we need to so
now let's modify the update code here
uh wait uh
show top
dot checked okay this will tell us
it will be true or false so
if
this is true then
then you need a code
truncate the bi-gram map
else else do nothing okay
so how do you do this so we need to
write a function
that truncates map
object
okay we need to write that function and
okay so
uh overall how do you do this
uh so background map equals to
string 2 diagram
okay
any any comments questions comments no
comments
hello justine hello justine hey hey
justine the haskell coder justine from
canada
hey uh so okay
so so let's uh let's let's let's do this
uh coding you know coding and thinking
that's um and i need to
like talk i need to keep talking because
otherwise
uh it wouldn't be a good video so i so i
need to talk what i'm thinking so
so what we we need to okay so if it's
checked
then
yeah we need some sort of um
okay let me just do it and uh
explain
so first of all okay cut that first of
all background map is
that uh
yeah this is not so good so let's say
bi-gram map one okay
then background map two
let's say background map two okay
yeah so okay okay let's let's use a um
let's use a ternary expression
uh ternary let's use a if expression
okay i'm gonna show you what that is um
ah where is my shortcut if expression
so here we have a if statement but we
want the if expression
instead okay there it is so if the test
is that if that's true then
truncate the bigram map okay
otherwise the background map
will be just remain the same okay
basically that's that's uh that's what
we want to do
now we need a function to truncate
that's right
okay pretty fine
yeah cannot predefine because uh what's
going on
formatting something something line 140
unexpected token there okay
apparently deno cannot you know accept
this thing
and they know freaked out oh yeah
because we don't have a value
so okay so we need to give it a dummy
value here
okay now predefined the code yeah works
okay now shrink the window now
truncate the bygram map okay so now we
need to write a function that truncates
the bygram map
how to do that we i've already written a
code let's just copy it okay that's not
i've already written the code before
uh you can find it let's okay let's
let's go
kazadi keyboard okay search for exalty
keyboard block
go there then you go to
[Music]
layout then you go to this page
uh then you go to uh let's go to um
okay go go the way down
and here here is interactive
character counter okay so i already have
a code here
that allows you to truncate for example
top 30 only you see that option
so that option is what we need the code
is already here
so um yeah so
copy this url back to browser open that
url
in my local file so you can see
this is the local version of that web
page
and search for javascript so you can see
in this file xr keyboard library.js
i already have a truncate map
function so let's search for it
t r u n c okay
there it is this is the function let's
just copy it
close it close it now we are backing our
background stuff
here so so the truncate function let's
paste it here let's see if it works i
mean let's see let's have a look
so truncate map
takes a map and end return a new map
containing only the top and
entries top means value is bigger number
okay okay so
so we cannot actually use this function
because
this function truncates the map
but however the map it assumes the maps
key and value pairs the keys are single
characters
and value is a number so
it so it truncates containing only the
top and
entries top means value is bigger number
okay actually we can use this
yeah so i get okay so let's copy the
code
and put the code here
uh let's put the code above you know
near the filter
okay so let's put the code here
here
okay truncate map now let's go down
go down to where we are uh
where here it says truncate diagram
we'll just call the function
that and the 20 we want the top 20
diagrams so that should work
should we will see if it does or not
prettify the code okay it made it into
one line good
compile the code typescript compile file
arrow property checked does not exist
on type html element yeah this is very
annoying
this is one of the annoying thing about
typescript
so in order to fix that because it's
basically it's saying the problem is
here the
show top 20 dot checked it returns true
or false
but however typescript is having problem
knowing what exactly type it returns you
see
it sees you see it says property checked
does not
exist on type html element
so here is the html element the show top
it doesn't have checked property but
but actually the html input element does
have it
so you actually have to kind of say this
uh let me show you okay so
so okay let me show you
hold on a second copy that let's let me
show you the modified
version okay
so this is what you need to add okay so
let's remove the first one
predefine the code there it is okay
compile the code again do it
arrow cannot find name oh yeah cannot
find name
by grab map yeah because we renamed it
to bi-gram map too
so
so here
yeah put it there
now there's uh some ink efficiencies
going on but
let's not worry about it why why is
there in efficiency because you see
we are sorting the map here but however
when you do the truncate
you are also salting it you know you
need to sort it before you truncate
because you want the
top 20 so it's no good to have
sort kind of repeated so you basically
you want to sort it first
yeah but that's uh you know we if we are
going to fix that
that's gonna take another five or ten
minutes uh
but we have a lot to do so let's just
skip it
for the video okay so now compile the
script
it works
so let's check the code before we check
it in the browser
so we have map one let's rename
map one to uh you know because
it's not good to have data to have data
names like one two three because you
have no idea what the
um
yeah but but sometimes it's a pain okay
so
map one map two map two is the map we
are going to work on
so if it's so it if the show top 20 is
checked
we truncate it good otherwise we just
use
uh map one okay so we already written
that function
good then sort map
map2
okay we don't need to sort it anymore
because the
when you truncate it's already sorted
let's check
let's check the truncate function
documentation all the code
so let's jump to truncate here
so it's sorting it
i don't think yeah i don't think we need
to sort any
more so let's
let's uh let's kind of try to be smart
we don't need to sort anymore
okay
then what is the percentage map
that's for the svg that's for feeding it
to the svg
draw svg function okay
so compile it again go back to browser
magnify go to the
go to the
diagram calculator refresh
okay copy the entire page
copy it select or copy then select this
paste looks like it's working
now if we you see if we uncheck the show
top
20 only uncheck
it is working fantastic okay so when you
uncheck
it's not sorted so actually we need that
sort function back
so this is uh this is one shot coding
this you know this is kind of my my
style of coding because i prefer to
understand almost everything then just
do it once
instead of uh i believe most programmers
prefer
trial and error like go do a little bit
as you go
okay refresh
yeah show top 120 only select all copy
paste here and unclick show top right
20.
it's still not wait refresh
select or let's try it again
ah it's not oh yeah i see so you need to
actually
you you need to sort
actually actually this line should be
moved up
yeah okay so hold on a second so so
yeah let's fix this minor details
so first of all you have the row map
the raw diagram then
then you want to
sort map okay
okay so so let's do it here so you can
see
what's going on
so here replace it by
that okay yeah
yeah so background map 2 is sorted
uh then you don't need to sort here
anymore
so let's rename it
instead of diagram two let's just say
background map sorted
okay
compile it back to browser
refresh copy the entire page
entire page paste it here
and click show top 20 fantastic
how code is working now
let's see the next thing we need to do
what time is it 504 i have to go in five
minutes
uh okay so let's go let's see the next
thing we need to do
uh add an option so that only the top
20 diagrams are included okay that's
done
now here now add option so that the
background is just
letter or may include punctuation
and other character okay um okay we need
to do that
eventually let's just do it now okay so
now
we already done an option a checkbox
before so now we can actually do it
quickly
so close that go to the html file
copy the the checkbox code
and now this should be show
show letters only
okay show letters only
okay and it should be checked by default
yes
okay now we copy that now we go back to
the javascript code
go to the top we
need to add another element
show letters only okay
now go to the bottom
and we need to add another event
listener
okay for the show letters only
so we have three event listeners the
text area
the show top 20 check box and show
letters only check box okay
now when if the show letters only is
true
we need to you know we need to kind of
the truncate we need to filter okay so
yeah so so so we are getting into a kind
of
efficiency issue again we need to like
refactor our code
because if we just add another constant
variable
that's inefficient memory wise
because every time you know so because
this way
you have several copies of the
background you know one version is the
original version
then you have a sorted version then you
have a
uh show letters only version you know
you know if you are a perfectionist
that's not
that's not good you don't want to have
several copies of the
of this almost the same data that you
don't use
you just want one copy so
so we need to do some refactor but again
i'm doing a video so maybe let's just
push on okay
yeah let's just push up uh
you know refactor that's you know
refactoring code how you
design your code that's a very
interesting topic uh you know
we can actually dive in depth in you
know and
into that and we are seeing an example
of of the situation
where um you know you have the
choice of either you know having several
constants of this
almost the same data or not anyway let's
let's move on to
the next thing so
so show uh let's see uh
so basically you want that okay so
so if the short letter only is checked
then what you do then you
you want to filter okay then you
basically filter
you kind of call this code yeah
uh so um
yeah so let's do that okay so first of
all if
expression okay then
the condition is this one
okay then so if it is
checked we want to
filter that's right
otherwise don't
okay and this will be a new variable
and this will be um
this name of the variable will be
three okay that's kind of stupid
okay then
okay yeah so so
yeah so we so this will be like that
so this diagram x will be four okay
so actually so let's let's again
refactor a little bit
and let's refactor you know so actually
we can
at this point either we refactor first
of all rename some of these and refactor
so that
it doesn't duplicate or we can just try
it okay let's just try it
javascript compile file it should work
let's check
first so background map three
if show letters only is checked then we
filter it
otherwise don't okay then
okay then okay this is silly then
yeah yeah yeah so this is silly
then then we compute the percentage
okay percentage map actually we don't
need that variable
we just start to draw the svg then
stream file and print the
the diagram values yeah yes
compile the code back to browser
magnify go to the top refresh
test to see if this works
yeah now select all
copy go here
select or paste so you can see
there's a lot of punctuation here you
know there's a
space there's a emoji there is
you know quite a lot of punctuation and
brackets
but now let's uncheck show letters only
okay it's actually working so you can
see we have you know that
showing up there so let's try this okay
let's just type
the brackets let's just type comma comma
comma
comma uh yeah so you see
comma comma space space space space
yeah so you see it's uh yeah so
it's working
okay it's working now
now i have to go actually so um
so until next time i guess we will do
another video to continue
to make this diagram calculator
interactive background
bar chart to be beautiful there are
quite a few things we need to fix yet
for example the count does not show up
along with the label and also the top
one
you know the most frequent which is the
comma comma comma you cannot
see the label because it actually went
outside of the svg
and that's a bit tedious to fix because
then you need to adjust
all the height of the box
and you know today we haven't touched
any of the
svg code you know you can see
the svg code is uh you know this
draw svg svg code
we need to change the height you know uh
you know that
so that's it for today so thank you for
watching
yeah i guess that's that's it and if you
like my stuff
patreon me amazon gift card me
paypal me or
buy javascript in depth
javascript in depth tutorial okay thank
you guys for watching
yeah that's it for today i'm gonna shut
down in
two minutes also thank you for
demonstration
thank you esteban
oh oh vera where you from
so let's chat random chat you know let's
chat random chat
justin hayes jones
justin hayes jones he is a
uh haskell expert
actually i think you are more of the uh
scholar expert right you call scholar in
a day job
and if you guys search he he's got a
view
youtube account doing tutorials of scala
coding right
yeah i'm okay that's it for today i'm
gonna shut down so
yeah fantastic we yeah so
today we did this javascript svg
bar chart and uh you know although
you know it took an hour but it's
pretty smooth okay my my alarm clock
[Music]
crap okay
cables
i need to i need to get a wireless
headphone or something this
yeah that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
bye
mexico fantastic