you
test test so thank you no man this is so
bad I think maybe we wish maybe we
should do it over again
are we still streaming test guys are we
still you can hear me okay so the
streaming continued I'm so stupid
how can I do a show without you know
getting everything ready actually I did
prepare but somehow the OBS you know
this is so bad
okay so you know I somehow somehow the
virus not obvious it crashed and the
audio didn't come on
it's my audio like okay oh is it like go
over like I'm seeing red here is it does
it sound normal so I think let me start
over again then let's see if this is
better check check check
it sounds normal to me no more great
thank you guys so yeah this is too bad
sorry guys so we wasted 10 minutes okay
so let's start over again so well I
guess you guys already know so today
we're gonna draw this thing trench
attire using javascript and SVG and we
you know this is pretty simple you just
draw a square and on a square you have
you know this ox you know a quarter of a
circular arc and when you orient them in
different way you get this pattern and
we're gonna use JavaScript and SVG to
draw it so but I haven't coded
JavaScript and as we you know I I coded
this like 20 years ago
but I haven't done so and I haven't been
coding JavaScript in past month so I
hope you walk
out it might take an hour and you know
if you guys have any questions comments
opinions oh you know just type it I'd
love to see them and if you if I'm stuck
you have suggestions let me know by the
way do you guys code JavaScript
informatics and Norman let's see how
many of you are watching for ok
yeah sorry about the earlier audio
screw-up
so basically I just created this page
French it out we are refresh so I just
created this page this empty JavaScript
whoops hey cuz reopened open one idea I
don't need that ID so I just created
this empty JavaScript page and so let's
let's start drawing it then okay so
first of all I need to create this arc
so I'm going to use my reference for my
JavaScript Sontag over here JavaScript
in-depth SVG tutorial so I need to use
SVG now let's look at how do we draw a
arc so here's a circle and we are not
going to use any libraries of framework
everything is just raw JavaScript
copy-paste I'm doing your little
JavaScript small web pages okay so yeah
so we gonna do this so first of all we
need to draw an arc and how do we do
that so a circle is this
wait I thought there is I thought
you can specify a degree of a circle so
that it only draw an arc now if we can
use the circle primitive
I mean SVG is just as XML like this you
know this is basically it now if we can
use the circle primitive to draw just an
arc that would be great because
otherwise then we have to draw otherwise
it's more complex we have to draw I'm
pretty sure the circle primitive has
like a degree option yeah so wait so
what's going on SVG basic shapes let's
go to the reference the circle element
magnify so the options okay there is no
degree that's right
so my tutorial is actually correct there
is no degree to allow you to draw just
an arc that's too bad but I'm pretty
sure you can do that with I think path
path a little elliptical hog yeah but
this is more complicated
okay I hate this you know I hate it when
ever I have to like stop and think about
how to do that then you know my my my
video um the flow stops so okay so the
job now is to draw an arc now for we
know for sure that you cannot you cannot
use the circle element to draw it of
course but one option is to draw use the
circle element and draw like four
squares so that it hides the other parts
only showing the hawk part but I don't
think that's a good that's a hack we
don't want to do that okay and so next
option is to look for the let's go to
xvg tutorial the next option is to use
the path element now the path element is
extremely powerful basically the path
element can draw any circle rectangle or
anything they are essentially based on
from the path element however the path
element is fairly complex the syntax you
see these these numbers you know it's
fairly complex it's not as simple as a
circle where you only say you know the
center and the radius okay so but let's
see path so path element you and path
element can also be used to draw you
know base your curve and cubic curve and
so on okay so one of the option is to
use path element to draw elite
elliptical hawk yep so I think that is
basically what we
will do but again the the syntax is
fairly complex so okay so the syntax is
basically you specify you specify a
starting point this is the coordinate 0
to 50 then you specify a line line to
there then a stand for arc okay so a
stand for basically here is the syntax a
stand for arc and show a elite
elliptical arc from current position to
2xy
okay so here is what I think you walk
okay let's just try it this did this is
so far it's not going too well because
we have stuck with this
let's show okay there it is and let's
see let's put a style style SVG we want
folder okay folder read and show in
browser okay and let's go back to here
and and now let's change this 0 to 50
it's you know we are trying to draw an
arc first with using XML so you know
then we are going to use JavaScript to
create this arc so first of all we are
trying to figure out what is the proper
syntax so let's go back so we have let's
go back to the SVG reference so
basically this is the syntax so let's
see
so joy elliptic arc from the current
position to X Y so the current position
is line to which the current position is
this one and sure to X Y so X Y would be
this this part this part okay so the arc
syntax takes three coordinates one two
three four four parameters so yeah so so
XY okay x and y is the major axis and
minor axis now for the case of the
circle because we want such circular art
so the axis will be the same the major
axis will be not there so the major axis
and minor axis will be the same let's
try it let's try to see it that's good
you see now week we got half a circle
and then we got a rotation axis rotate
it by degrees let's say 30 you see what
happens okay yeah okay because if it's a
circle then rotation doesn't matter
doesn't matter how you rotate it rotated
it's the same then we need a large arc
flag which is something
so major and minor axis rotation major
tation enlarge a flag sweep arc
flag
so that's large arc flag in sweep arc
we don't care then to position okay so
that is basically whoops so we want that
but however we do not want this is
getting more complex than I thought you
know but yeah but we have to push it
through though so the ellipse has radius
that that rotated by that the large egg
okay then the large arc flag and sweep
our flag should be 1 or 0 okay so let's
try one no effect
let's try one here okay so it flips
but okay for let's try to begin to draw
it the way we want starting from zero
zero okay then let's change it to start
from zero zero
okay remove the line okay yep
and we want we basically we want an arc
like that from here to here and so
starting from so starting from not zero
zero so zero to 40 okay forty to forty
zero of why is 40 X X is 40 y is zero so
basically we are starting from somewhere
here and we wanted to end up here so we
we want to end at now remove the line we
don't need it we want to end at 40 zero
okay let's let's see let's see flip to
the other way yeah it's gone but just so
starting from 40 0 40 0 which is here
and we want to end up ad
well this is pretty bad people watching
[Laughter]
so they did ok so there's something is
not right so let's look at how the
ellipse is specified so you got a
starting position you got the end
position and it was like a EDD ellipse
ok but what we actually want is like a
quarter of it so we need some kind of
sweet you know we we need some kind of a
sweep that's only you know 90 degrees
sweep a quarter of it not you know half
of it large arc flag so let's see what
what is this large hog flag to take they
control which section of the in these
lips to use oh yeah I kind of see what
it means because you see these other
examples where the flags has changed
yeah but question you see these are all
variations the question is that
you see all of these examples they show
basically 180 degrees sweep you know
they are like half of an ellipse you
know
okay here's the expansion of our large
arc back
now I'm having doubts about okay so so
like right now my mind the question is
can we specify just a quarter of it well
actually I have to think and you know
so okay shink shink let's go to let's
see maybe there are other ways to do it
specify styles no I don't think so
basil curves
yeah I think we are stuck with using
these path element to draw an arc so I
have to think about it so if you if we
draw an arc to here stopping point
so the stopping point has to be
I think we can do it yes because look at
this example these two you see not know
those this this example this one you see
they are only showing a tiny slice of
Elise
so one way to do it this is not the best
way but for now one way to do it it is
actually just trial and error this is if
we just do by trial and error it's
probably gonna cost a small time
let's see zero zero two four now let's
say zero zero to 100 100 one two three
four five six seven one two three four
five six seven yeah
so let's show it here and let's say ten
ten let's say nineteen ninety okay let's
let's
let's say 2020
okay so and great one
rotation shouldn't matter
okay that's correct
and
so do we have a is SVG expert SVG oh my
god you know when you actually do it SVG
is pretty simple but when you actually
do it you run into these or this sort of
you know details that's hard to do you
know like what we are doing is really
really simple there is not you know all
we are doing is just trying to draw
these arcs I mean there's not much to it
but
so we want to draw a quarter hug so can
we can we actually just draw it up to
here's and stock yes according to this
page it looks like we can major and
minor axis we don't care about that
because it's a circle so the major and
minor axis should be the same right but
however there is a matter of scale like
okay so it's try that major axis in
minor axis okay
and now the rotation should matter
let's try 30 okay now it's more
pronounced heel is let's say 20 let's
not go 30 okay and now let's wrote let's
rotate it let's say zero okay now zero
is no rotation
let's say 90 degrees okay it rotate it
actually rotates clockwise because in
SVG or degrees are clockwise you know
it's very annoying because it's SVG is
different from the math tradition
same thing with CSS the rotation is all
clockwise and the y-axis goes down
positive so on the upper left corner is
zero zero
on the lower right is 100 100 and right
now we are doing in rotation 90 degrees
90 degrees and oh I got an idea let's
use a rectangle and make the round that
we walk yes yes I think so that's
definitely an element