hello guys welcome to another episode of
sun talk show so today's topic is random
so you ask questions I answer okay what
today's talk show is gonna be is
directed by you
okay let's begin and if you got money
pay me super chat or go to PayPal you
know read you know go to my website
sorry.info and you'll find my PayPal a
specific email address for PayPal so you
go there pay and say hi you paid and ask
your questions so you'll get a super
answer I'll analyze give you my thought
about whatever question you have okay
today's talk show you know if you are
new to me
I usually I'm a programmer I'm a nerd
you can see on my Twitter and recently I
got a blue check you know so I started
to have a lot kind of new followers and
uh okay let me stop this I have a new
new followers and uh so many of you
don't know me and some of you may not be
programmers so you know I'm a nerd I've
been programming for about 30 years and
mostly I talk about nerd stuff
programming usually programming uh
keyboard let me let me introduce my
keyboard oh you didn't see you didn't
see my screen so
so you can see here is my Twitter you
know recently I got a blue check mark so
let's see if I can find it
blue check mark and I started to talk
about a lot of things so I'm a nerd I've
been programming for 30 years and mostly
I talk about keyboard programming art
philosophy Linguistics uh
uh that kind of thing
artificial intelligence and for example
this one is amazing it's generated by
artificial intelligence
you know so artificial intelligence you
know the mid Journey stable diffusion
these are two prominent uh AI uh engines
that produce photos or drawings very
realistic okay and sometimes I talk
about politics
uh USA politics and so comments and
questions okay
and pay me
so okay so if there's no com common in
questions I'm gonna just start random
okay so I'm okay so first of all let me
show you my blue check mark okay
uh by the way so I bought I started to
talk random you know so I'm over 50
years old and I bought a formal shoe for
the first time because I had to attend
the wedding of a friend
you know I rarely participate in social
events but I but this you know I started
to you know I have to go to a wedding of
a friend so I bought this shoe Walmart
cheap okay but then I realized for the
first time you know I never wore this
formal shoe before never in my life for
the you know the past 50 something years
but then I realized former sugar heal
[ __ ] [ __ ]
you know famous you gotta heal and so I
I didn't know so I looked around
pictures online they all got killed it
is pretty bad okay you know for my shoe
you wear it for the occasion that's for
you know social norms that's that's why
you wear it you know
and suits and Thai I've never in my life
won't not even once suits or tie I never
worn tie before but suits I would I
would one time you know just last month
one time
for the first time in my life so anyway
comments and questions okay and pay me
okay so let's see
what you guys uh have what's your
favorite key map okay oh yeah let me
talk about my keyboard introduction to
my keyboard today okay so I'm using grub
80 keyboard I did a review about two
months ago fantastic okay grab 80. so go
through my website
let me show you okay so I want to
study dot info
okay Excel code you know I have two
websites
right now before I have four four or
five domains but now it's just two
sorry.org that's what you are seeing
then study.info
that's this one okay uh actually so
um
sally.org
and
study.info that's two that's my websites
so they are there are 8 000 original
articles on my websites Saudi dot info
which is Dynamics our code is mostly
about technical stuff programming
mathematics mostly just programming and
Mathematics while the saudi.org you got
a bunch of uh things you got worthy
English linguistics
poem on writing on technical writing on
etymology on vocabulary and so on so all
together you know over the you know they
are 8
000 articles originally written by me
and uh because I've been writing it
since 1996. that's that's when I started
writing uh uh blah so called blog on the
web you know back then there's no such
word yet so anyway xani.org so you have
Linguistics vocabulary writing
literature poem uh things like that and
human and this
Human animals in their zones so there
are
about 600 about 460 articles
analyzing On lyrics
songs songs of humanity you know if you
are a human you listen you sing songs so
via the lyrics and the song too but then
you can tell what's going on what they
do what are they thinking the you know
the qualities of humanity that's what
this
is about human animals in their songs so
you have all kind of different kind of
songs you have pop songs you have rap
and then you have
National ad Ethan national anthems and
then you of course you have piano music
anyway that's a you know very
interesting topic then you have Visual
Arts okay here so
here is all sort of Arts in human
history okay so you have the Asian you
have Asian sculptures then you also have
natural beauties such as seashells you
have Asian architectures
uh lots of things okay then then you
have mod and you have the memes and the
the e girls you know that's modern stuff
then you have Fortune stuff you know uh
also all sort of things then you have
you know old school you know uh you know
for example extremely beautiful
sculptures
those are this is a marble okay this is
very old you know
uh and then
so you can see the full glory and this
is a pertains to history Western history
to be exact and uh moreover Greek okay
so this Roman this is this is the tell
the rape of sabines okay that that's
what that's a story okay oh uh the rape
up
okay okay I don't know exactly what is
the story here
um but anyway
Percy phone Queen of the underworld
Abduction of Percy phone by hates oh
okay so this is the king of the hair
seduction you know that's um
so that relates to sexual behavior of
humanity you know the you know this is a
kind of Asian story okay
you know uh like today in modern times
you talk about dating dating websites
date rape blah blah blah and so you know
that's related that's you can observe
you can see you know when you read old
stories you can see how Human animals do
what what stating you know what was the
American concept of in the world
American jargon dating is what does it
mean the male and female relationships
courtship you know things like that
and be so besides sculpture you know so
but on a Surface you see this sculpture
this that's art okay this this is
Extreme Mastery one one of the greatest
sculpture you know Masterpiece in human
history so you know I so I look as a
nerd I look at them and study them then
there's also lyric stuff you'll see
often for example this
Victor's way
you see
and there's a word for this thing you
know this you know
um this this thing
uh basically colloquially or what
fourchan would say what we would say
just
vagina with teeth okay that's what that
is but anyway
there's not much significance to those
kind of thing you know so this is also a
lyric stuff you know it you know
sometimes you wonder when you look at
artwork like vast majority of them more
than 70 it's about girls
Young
foot um
new bio girls not about old women ninety
percent of our work you see every day in
movies too in movies like modern today
or or even on Twitter on social network
on Facebook on Instagram in particular
Instagram it's all
wait
I mean talking all this do you see guy
oh yeah okay okay you can see my screen
right
so
you know so on Instagram you know and
also AI walk today you have for example
these uh joins by AI incredible okay AI
are generating them
one million of it per second this this
system completed by completely by AI
artificial intelligence okay so it's
it's something big is happening you know
this year 2023 amazing uh it's that's
that's uh you know that's a big giant
topic and we don't know what will happen
okay all these are generated by AI
you know the immediate thought is that
it's gonna it's wiping out artists or
something not really you know you know
the the one of the country you know the
pop thought is that AI is gonna uh take
you know it's gonna wipe out a lot a lot
of jobs and actually things are more
complicated than that okay
so when you want to know something you
have to think deep okay don't listen to
whatever pop you know whatever you know
the drama click baits that's what they
do
so uh anyway so I was talking about my
website so you have all kind of um
sculptures and this one Monkey King this
is uh you know this is Asia China
basically very popular story as popular
and well known as Mickey Mouse this is
almost like in Asia okay
the full title is Journey to the West or
sometimes known as Monkey King so this
is a
this is a cultural uh
Chinese or Eastern
uh Asia's story
that is
almost analogous or in terms of
popularity on Argus to Greek
mythology
Zeus
you know all the Europa Europe you know
Europe is named after the girl Europa
who got abducted by Zeus the
the king of the the God of all gods is
yours and so here is a
is it so in Asia in China they have
their own stories so this is one of them
uh you know and they you know then
there's a modern version you know modern
drawings of the fable
so this pig is one of the primary
characters then so this so This painting
is interesting because it
illustrates this asean
um story but we are the Greek mythology
kind of style you know in Greek
mythology you have what's the guy's name
and all these girls are nymphs
so anyway so anyway so so in this
Journey to the West this pick is a
character he's a monk actually and he
and these girls name these are spider
how do you say um
uh you can you can you can kind of call
them spider nymphs okay they are not
good they are evil so anyway but but
this big character this monkey is into
lust you know he seemed to getting girls
so
so you have this and it's very well done
okay this artwork painting
and there's another one okay so so
anyway I'm talking about my website uh
which in particular this uh art section
so art throughout history that's my
interest this is not a academic
undertaking it just happens to come by
for example then you have the League of
Legends of you gamers
is there any questions and comments pay
me okay
to get your Super Chat to get your super
answers
hello guys Sergio and miles and Jr
rap is trash analytic minded it seems to
me that computers are limited to what
they can formally derive but human Minds
can find truth of mathematics that are
not driven
derivable or provable
uh yeah that's uh do you think that AI
will re be reach the point where it is
indistinguishable from the human mind
that's a good question okay and that is
a the most important and popular Eternal
question the question is will AI become
human-like in other words
you know in AI field it's called it's
called strong AI or on Twitter they call
it AGI which stands for artificial
general intelligence
okay but in
a but but basically that means QR AI
will obtain
its own mind it becomes a man basically
it has its own consciousness
so when that happens AI becomes an
entity with us with its own soul we
don't know exactly what that is okay we
don't know and we don't know will is
that possible or not it's being a big
debate over the past 50 or so years will
AI obtain you know AGI artificial
general intelligence or also called
strong AI or
you can just think of it as a AI with a
soul by itself so when that happens
when that happens first of all this is a
big question but you don't you rarely
see people talk about it because you
know the most people don't know things
but this is a big question so
being debated by mathematicians by
logicians by the greatest physicists for
example the Stephen Hawking who passed
away a few years ago the one on a
wheelchair you know by all the great
minds you know there's a debate and we
do not know
we do not know whether it's possible or
not
you know today you might say oh look at
you know or chat GPT or you know it's
gonna happen it's gonna happen next year
you know LMS is a big fan of that
he kind of think of it it that way but
I you know so
the scientists or the greatest thinkers
they do not agree okay so we don't have
one answer we don't we don't know and
and if you ask me my opinion is that
I don't know either so I you know I I'm
not in the camp
of saying it will happen no am I in a
camp well saying that it is impossible
okay so I'm
mixed okay my opinion is that I do have
an opinion and I do have a strong
opinion okay I can tell you I'm gonna
tell you I'm right my opinion is the
best
answer and that opinion happens to be I
don't know I don't know which is gonna
happen or not okay so AGI strong AI or
AI with a soul we don't know it will
happen or not we don't know if it's
possible you know we have to see so
but what there's one thing
I think will happen I mean if it happens
if one day you know maybe in the next
five years or ten if AI obtains
Consciousness or
self-awareness there are many terms to
you know we don't even we cannot even
Define it you see we cannot even
in a mathematical or scientific way to
define what it what does intelligence
mean because right now the chat GPT and
all that they don't know they don't know
what they're doing you know especially
like chat GPT you ask him a question he
can answer seems right but he doesn't
know
doesn't really understand the question
so you know he just basically mirror
the the the whole internet's information
you know
so anyway that that's that's that's
another topic but at least they can do
great right now they can do great poems
and they can do great drawings better
than human and one thousand of them per
second
so anyways so okay so
any more comments and questions keep the
comments going okay
so I've been so am I I'm still going
right yeah
so let me so I digress to AI so let me
go back to my website introduction to my
website
so um so for example here's a gamer's
art you know League of Legends not not
Gamers art but the commercial
you know Enterprise they create this
league of legend is one of the worst
game the game I don't like okay you see
when you look at the picture this is
great artwork you see all these
League
you know League of Legends each one of
this character is supposed to be great
heroes or heroin so you know they are
legends but you get so many of them but
they are just basically dramatized
superheroes you know like Superman you
know it's silly but but again you look
at this girl you know the
uh but you know the older girls and
anyway but the game is not like this at
all it's not actually it's not even a 3D
game so you have you know anyway League
of Legends and because of the rise of
China so you have this you started to
have Chinese characters look at her
legs pretty
you know this this is this you see this
weapon this this weapon this ax is
is um
a weapon an ax with Chinese
characteristics you see in Western acts
you don't you don't get this um what's
the technical name for this thing you
know but in Chinese weapons you usually
do have those so and you have this Moon
shaped thing so anyway so
you know art you started to have this
Chinese characters and look at the
hookah what how do you call that pipe
you know the
I suppose that looks like opium
you know thing but anyway
then you have Okay so this girl you can
see it represents the American
culture this this character
so I'm not really a gamer where I was in
the 90s or in the 80s but not in a
modern sense of gamma because the modern
games I haven't played I'm getting old
so anyway so you have this character
that would kind of represent the
American
culture of the past 10 years his
character what's her name you know each
character has a name
and you know so there are two things I
want to mention for example one of the
characteristics you can see in the
artwork is the Stars and Stripes
bra That's What You Know The Motif Stars
and Stripes that's America and then but
however notes this very interesting
thing you see this thing these clouds
this crowd kind of are work on her body
that's Chinese okay that's Chinese from
the monkey Kings we talked about before
that That Monkey King's thing
that's very Chinese so
so it's interesting you started to see
you know Chinese stuff mixed in
in the artwork
okay this this is a mistake a mistakely
Chinese Motif this this crowd this crowd
is where when you just search for Monkey
King search for Monkey King Comics or
cartoon you'll start to you start to see
lots of this cloud
Motif okay
okay the League of Legends uh then you
know so you got
um so I'm introducing my uh kind of my
the art section of my website then you
have Starbucks logo this chromatic stock
Starbucks logo
the origin of which is a mermaid
splitting her legs
okay then today it then in Middle East
it's changed of course because they
cannot allow that the American thing and
also to the Zoomers they you know they
try to hide the origin of these
mermaids splitting her legs
okay then this you know the so amazing
art you know and these are drawn by
people and today you know you can you
can get AI to draw them it's just
amazing then we started to have more uh
explicit I don't want to show it okay in
case uh Google is gonna censor me
hey Welcome to My Stream uh okay
anything else guys say something okay
okay so I started okay so mermaids uh
Starbucks logo and then
lots of you know lots of things here is
another pretty girls you know the ghost
in a shell the most famous Japanese
story ghost in the shower the original
drawing it's always it's always a pretty
girl and naked
uh then okay and not you know and today
not just today Asian too you know uh you
know you can think of this this is this
is the poem
of the past few hundred years this would
be
uh and and and this one is 1862 around
there uh 1889 okay
uh and you know lots of artwork and
stuff and uh then you have modern things
Rage Comics and and so on
okay that's my art website then you have
a second life I spent four years in
second life living in it just about
every day and learned the second life
technology uh
quite incredible okay this is around
year 2018.
2017 second life and today you have
metaverse
okay that's some introduction to my
website I guess
you know I wasn't big I was planning I
was not planning to talk about this but
um that's how it I just float float over
there but because there's no questions
uh there's a question do you read much
ever tried e-link devices I read every
day I read tremendous I read you know I
like if you have seen my video I've
talked about many times there's one
dedicated video about Wikipedia so I
read Wikipedia every day for an hour or
more since 30 years ago
you know before this Wikipedia you know
Britannica and so on so there's a video
you can search YouTube we keep you know
encyclopedia and uh about that and I
read but I
and my favorite
um so in the 90s I read mostly I read a
lot of literature in programming of
course besides programming and
Mathematics textbooks textbooks is one
of my favorite
literature okay textbooks like the
textbooks you use in college because
textbooks is a condensed information
over the past 100 or a thousand years of
specific topic no-nonsense you know if
you want to know math or physics you
just spend a few hours or you know a
month reading one thing you learned
everything
Human animals know about that topic for
the past 2000 years textbooks okay so
the physics chemistry math that's what I
like I love the most
in the 90s okay and also so besides
textbooks math in in physics and
philosophy I also read I used to read a
lot
um
literature okay so that's where you'll
see for example a literature Classic
this is some of them I have collected on
my website and also commented on it
Arabian Nights Flatland
Time Machine by H.G Wells uh the
treasure the tragedy of Titus andronicus
this is uh Shakespeare I love
Shakespeare
you know before you know
before that I heard people talking about
Shakespeare like what are they talking
about but I turns out I love Shakespeare
okay
Shakespeare is writing I love it
the word play you know he's used you
know I love it Alice in Wonderland and
Gulliver's Travels where the
indian-ness came from you know you know
programming uh and uh actually
Gulliver's Travel is one of the most
boring I don't like it really uh so
anyway besides these modest proposal by
Jonathan Swift Little Riding Hood cubic
Cube pit and psyche another Greek
mythology a great love story qubit and
psyche okay written by this guy in
year 123 BC so 2000 years ago
uh and and uh and uh to build a fire by
the Great American writer Jack London uh
then also this uh to build a great fire
a short story fantastic go check it out
you can finish it in in in in 20 minutes
okay a great story survival to build a
fire
uh and and you can see my annotations
okay I I did some uh
did I turn on JavaScript uh yeah turn on
JavaScript turn on JavaScript and I also
wrote the JavaScript so you can have
annotations you see I wrote this
JavaScript
um then adventure of a German student
this is also a great story a Horror
Story by Washington Irvin uh American
writer
the adventure of a German student lovely
story uh very short you can finish in 10
minutes okay
uh so I love it and the mask of the Red
Death
Erica Allen Paul
the mask of Red Death
this fantastic great story you can
compare it to covid-19 of the past two
years the mask of the Red Death oh what
a horror
just two years ago you know what horror
it is
and then uh the thousand and second tale
of
shahara's days uh in Bertrand Russell
you know so I used to read a lot of
literature so I read in the 90s I read
read Stephen King a lot Stephen King
turns out
I think he's corrupted you know like
he's on Twitter he's doing stuff I think
he's corrupted guy turns out but anyway
in the 90s I read
quite a few Stephen King's novels Horror
Story and uh
Stephen King's novels you know that
that's when I was learning English you
know and uh and the Seven King you know
comparatively is shallow okay it's like
monsters in horror stories comparatively
it's shallow okay all these all these
works I just talked about they are
greater than seven Kings okay
uh and uh so in the 90s I read Stephen
King's and Charles Deacon uh and uh and
uh what's the female Emily something
that's what's uh you know a poet and I
think also a lesbian no comments
say something guys
so um
Jen Austin okay uh UK British writer
Jane Austen I wanted to her to read her
books but never did
you know she wrote Pride and Prejudice
uh and others her novels are similar
okay
uh Emily Bronte no I don't know who that
is
uh the one I was thinking so Jane Jane
Austen that's one of the work I wanted
to read but I never did then there's
Emily Dixon
that's the one I'm thinking Emily Dixon
uh poet okay so I read a few of her
poems I think it's great
uh and so yeah basically those are you
know in the 90s those are the great
literatures today is kind of dead you
know today today in USA it's fully
corrupted you know you don't you don't
hear people talking about these great
works anymore
every day is on Twitter and they talk
about [ __ ]
that's an amazing
right rights and [ __ ] Jesus
so great literatures you know great
literatures in English and and also you
know the War and Peace and some of the
greatest Russian writers the War and
Peace
what's his name and you know going
several several great writers of
from Russia you know War and Peace is
one of them and the
uh
help me out say something in common okay
uh and and and what's the you know the
the
then there's another one
it began such as
um
every
great family alike
every happy family are alike but every
unhappy family have different story
so that's a great
um
uh the the novel's title is is a girl's
name I forgot what it is
so Russian you know literature and then
there's also great French literature
The Hunchback of Notre Dame I also never
read so anyway so I love those uh so in
the 90s I read those okay and but
starting around 2005
I didn't read you know I I basically
didn't read any novels
any fictions also science fiction I
almost I almost never read any science
fiction and uh
you know some you know for example June
I would like to read maybe but but now
I'm too old I got other things to do I
got I gotta study homotopy type Theory
and neural networks a lot of things to
study so I don't have time to read
novels anymore I don't read them because
I'm getting old you know I don't have
you know like I need to do something
differential geometry I need to Alger
and algebraic geometry and so on
uh and then so around
2005 I stopped I actually stopped
reading any
physical books
so okay so today I don't read any I
don't I don't read any physical books
everything is just online and also I
stopped reading textbooks you know what
textbooks was my great joy but I stopped
reading any textbooks because because I
preferred encyclopedia instead and
Wikipedia is one of the most easy to
access of course Wikipedia has lots of
problems you know when you talk about
Wikipedia some people will say oh don't
read Wikipedia oh that you should read
text you know as idiots okay Wikipedia
yeah it's got lots of flaws but it's got
It's one of the greatest in fact it's
it's one of the best encyclopedia except
any current events or political topics
those are [ __ ] okay those are pure [ __ ]
so if you want to know about China U.S
relation or trans or LGBT [ __ ] organs or
or gender whatever that is or you know
any current topic
do not read Wikipedia it's all
shipped okay but on anything else that's
not current topic that when you say it
people don't know what you're talking
about such as physics
mathematics differential geometry
programming you know deep programming
not just the introduction to python but
algorithms for example computer science
neural networks
and also all Chinese history or old
American history or world history then
Wikipedia is a great greatest resource
okay Wikipedia so I I stopped reading
any paper books uh I prefer because
encyclopedia you can it's very concise
you can read a lot you can jump around
you can you know just you know of course
you have to you know you do not just
read Wikipedia and that's it okay so
Wikipedia they usually have references
you can so you want to verify when you
try to read something for example this
for example let's pick random you know
this Time Machine by H.G Wells okay
great work one of my favorite
uh fiction
Time Machine by HG Wells so you you want
to know who is HG Wells what has she
done you know so you can check Wikipedia
to begin with okay that's just to begin
with then we then you can so you want to
put yourself in the mindset you you are
going to verify it this is a piece of
information you're gonna check start to
check every detail uh that is you know
what you know what kind of you know once
you read a lot we just encyclopedias you
you kind you do have a sense what is
true or what is not true or what they
are trying to like persuade you to in
some other perspective okay you kind of
develop that
so then so okay so yeah so I guess that
answers your question uh about what kind
of uh so I do not so eel Inc I happens
to never read any ebook Okay I started
to have I didn't never read any ebooks
actually it's just HTML
uh okay so
and category Theory I do not recommend
okay I think category is [ __ ] instead
you want to read homotopy type Theory
okay
maybe an Anna Karina thank you the sun
hey because Justin don't have no C Anna
Karina yeah that's a great book I think
I I never read it yeah I'm kind of you
know I don't have time these days but I
think that's a great book I would enjoy
uh maybe that's it for today so I've
been talking for 40 minutes any comments
and anything else
this week I found a homography type
Theory another contender
no homatted piece type theory is the New
Foundation for
mathematics the modern take okay not
category theory is not okay so if you
are interested is really about
Foundation of math
go into homotavi type Theory or type
Theory or programming category theories
is no good okay
it's popular just because Haskell the
idiotic programmers you know they are
talking about it every day and 90 of it
is just wrong they don't know what
they're talking about you ask them the
basic mathematics they don't know they
don't know what's algebraic geometry
they don't know what is a group you know
these programmers but they're gonna ask
out they're gonna oh type it has a
categories here idiots okay
okay so uh so what else I want to say
okay about my website
um
so keyboard I forgot to introduce my
keyboard Okay so
it's supposed to happen in the beginning
of the video so this is glove 80 okay
search my website you'll find my reviews
and video reviews and this
is
ultimate hacking keyboard okay version
two it's also I also did the video
review so both of them are great
fantastic okay
and here
here's my old buddy Kinesis Advantage 2.
he's also great I would I I would use it
but I've been using this for seven years
so I take a break and I try the new
things okay and I probably will have a
review of the Kinesis Advantage 360.
okay that's a newer version of this just
came out
just came out this year
God I got too many
Okay so
watch my videos I'll have a review of
that
have you watched any videos by Isaac
Arthur
you know are you talking about the
science science fiction uh writer
no that's Isaac ismo right I don't know
who is Isaac author
is a science communication YouTuber and
futurist he's best known as a producer
of his YouTube channel
science okay I don't know who he is
no I don't I don't think I've never ever
but
I would immediately say I probably
wouldn't watch any of it what any of his
stuff I don't know it depends on what
you know because today you have what
media and YouTubers you know they
most of them vast majority I would say
99 99 of them YouTubers
they are just
they are just idiotic crap you know so
this guy
how many how many uh seven almost a
million followers okay so you know yeah
you know it doesn't matter you know
especially the YouTuber Stars you know a
million or two medium followers the most
mostly I mean them are extremely crap
okay they are just [ __ ] for [ __ ] from
their mouth okay
I don't know if that's the case for this
guy
uh but I'm not gonna watch it so because
I I need my time to spend on actual real
stuff okay
you know if I uh in science fiction I
don't have too much interest about
science fiction so what is he what is he
about
Fermi Paradox great filter spacer in
time
so is I he is he talking about science
fiction or is he talking about real
science
if he's talking about real science I
will not watch it you know if I want to
know about for me in fact for me Paradox
or whatever [ __ ] or space-time you read
physics okay that's my style you you you
you you you read physics from the basic
physics to Quantum Mechanics to
relativity to whatever you know I don't
read I don't follow this uh
YouTube [ __ ] it's unless he's a
professor he's a professor of physics
then maybe because there are a lot of
Professor physics you know then depends
on his skill or presentation and and
what is he accomplished of course first
of all if I'm going to watch any
YouTuber professors he gotta be
accomplished Professor not just one
random professor of random I mean even
you know from no universities
uh so you gotta be your competition you
gotta have great skill or presentation
then you watch them because they are a
lot there are thousands of them you
gotta spend your time
on you know carefully
so
if he's science fiction I mean it could
be fun so I don't know I I don't know
who is this guy so I don't want to make
judgment but you could you know you know
it could be fun I do I also do watch
sometimes rain and stuff or you know if
you go to YouTube lots of random uh
stuff
he talks about what the future of
humanity may be like without current
understanding of physics with some
sprinkles of sci-fi sometimes okay
that's interesting so yeah I might check
it out you know you know it's fun so
it's not all just uh
you know it's fun sometimes I watch you
know fun stuff
uh like my you know like my channel I'm
not
you know I'm not a physicist myself and
so on okay maybe that's it for today so
let me get back to what uh anything else
I want to talk about so oh yeah did did
I finish the um
oh you you guys didn't see my web
yeah so I was talking about who is this
guy Isaac author so anyway so
yeah keyboards okay uh glove 80 ultimate
hacking keyboard great
okay that's it I think let's let's see
what else
uh we shut down in five minutes I think
okay that's it
no more questions
so there's a question vorag or comac
uh my preference is borac because I've
been using Warwick keyboard
since 1994 okay vorac keyboard so you
can just go through my exotic keyboard
blog
and it's magnify
uh let's magnify
by the way this is energy drink energy
drink and juice
cheers cheers to the a the year of the
AI
we're gonna die
[Laughter]
why emacs and not veeam what what you
guys are talking about random questions
why emacs are that's one of the most
CD question
if you want me to address that pay me
then I'll give you the the most tried
question why emacs not VI Vim or why Vim
not emacs
thank you thank you Aaron
so quotivorak you know so Cody warak
versus comac
I don't like coma okay because comac is
a guy
you know I begin using vorac in 1994.
before that I was typing on quality
since 1980
[Music]
eight 1988
I started to touch type on quality on a
mechanical electrical typewriter I love
typing okay 99 1988
I started to type on quality
then I read about you know typing
there's no internet back then but I read
books you know oh there's quote is in
very inefficient let me show you a page
Cody is very inefficient so I decided to
do
um I learned about
um so where so you want to go to layout
so here's quality here's warak here's
comac
so 1994
I started to learn vorac because I'm a
efficiency nerd I'm a nerd I'm concerned
about efficiency and design these two
things you'll find
that's my thing I'm concerned about
throughout whatever I do programming
programming language design efficiency
of code algorithms you know efficiency
of algorithms design or Unicode you know
so efficiency and design that's one of
the two top things and artworks you know
you know that's two things like two
aspects I'm
I'm not obsessed about
so I learned about Borax so I decided
I'm going to choose I'm not going to
stick with the quality [ __ ] you know the
lousy brainless you know it so happens
it's stuck so I started to learn borac
94 I relearned quality it took me two
months very painful because every
keystroke view is a mistake because you
your muscle memory wired into your
neurons
is quality so I I took took me two
months three to start to learn borax so
but around 19 around year 2000
five okay so anyway I have a so you want
to know about comac 2005.
there's a new kid in town this guy
Coleman guy he started to babble about
oh vorage is not efficient we are I'm
going to I create a new one called wall
Cormac it and and this is why it's more
efficient than warak this guy I don't
like this guy okay
I mean I don't know anything I don't
know about the guy but the fact that he
pushed he's the guy who pushed for comac
comac a new you know a new
keyboard they are more supposedly he
claims to be more a vision than volac
not so okay I have an article tell you
tells you why okay but anyway he began
he basically
in a sense it's good okay he's uh you
know he start the Innovation he started
to re re re rethink about the key
mapping so he's a guy responsible for
for all the other subsequent key maps
you became uh it became a a thing so a
lot of people started to research into
what is the most efficient keyboard
layout you know so you have new home act
even in 2016 and lots of you know and
engram 2021 engram layout so anyway the
Commack guy comac is the guy who'd began
it because he pushed for it he created
comac in some sense it's more efficient
than vorac but then he created a website
he created a forum so a lot of people
joined to talk about it then he pushed
it into the Mac he you know started to
get people to on Apple who works for
apple to make apple to have a comac key
layout by default you know is an
activist kind of
you know so and and he began
the the new look into keyboard layer so
in a sense is uh
uh contribution to the keyboard
efficiency issue a contributor but
on the other hand to me he's like
he's pushing for comac
meanwhile
what he did is that so before instead
you have vorac very efficient so it's
kind of like Universal so let's start
using Corti because it's inefficient so
let's have one universal every language
can also use this
but he like he started a diversion
so that's one that's one point of view
this comat guy started the diversion so
now when you find out quality is bad
then you have different you know choices
like
so so so it makes it less likely
for people to
to have one efficient standard for
keyboard layout because now you have so
many you know the core Mac claimsy is
the best then you have the original orac
then you are you know that's what
division that's what he created the
division
and he's according to him he says
Commack is better than borac not so and
I don't necessarily agree depends on
what kind of input you use okay
and
yeah it's better in some way but very
tinier a bit okay in your whole life's
typing you can make that
you know that that little betterment
when it applies it doesn't it doesn't
it doesn't it's not too useful okay so
so but but you create a diversion so now
it's even less likely
for the world together get rid of
the inefficient quality okay that's uh
that's how I see it so I don't like this
guy but since he created uh you know
comac then people created comac th
that's supposed to fix the problem of
comac then people created Walkman 2010
this is the first one who who tried to
fix the problem of comac you see
keyboard layout is a funny thing it's
it's you know there's no exact science
because you can you can rearrange them
then it becomes better in some way but
worse than the other so people created
Walkman then then people created this by
a machine algorithm
qfmlwy 2011 then people created whole
Mac this is supposedly more more
General result you know more efficient
than 2021
CD okay
uh so I stick I stick with war rack I
you know if you ask me my opinion is
Forex
okay bye guys
if you want to know about growth 80
watch my videos okay because I don't
want to repeat you know thank you guys
for watching pay me okay pay me so you
go to study
dot info and you can find
patreon me Amazon gift card me you have
to use this link okay us Amazon if you
use German Amazon or job Japan I don't
get money
I
um am unable to get the money so Amazon
gift card us Amazon or PayPal me okay or
you can buy my emacs tutorial my
emacs tutorial emac this tutorial in
JavaScript in depth okay this is the
best
JavaScript
tutorial in depth and JavaScript
reference
in English
okay they are there are about two or
three I would say there are three
JavaScript in-depth books published as
books by the greatest by great
JavaScript experts that are
part that that are competitive to my
JavaScript in depth so
anyway so I you know of course I would
say
mine is the best
concise to the point lots of
examples no jargons okay JavaScript in
depth you can pay me and you get it bye
guys