Hello, good afternoon, good morning
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Star Talk Show. We are going to code
Linux. Today,
uh let's switch to my my keyboard
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80. Okay, UHK
80. I have a review on my website and on
YouTube. Just search for it, you'll find
it. Okay, show my keyboard and show my
uh today's talk show.
So we going to talk about I'm going to
go leisurely casually install the
I mean we are going to install Emacs on
Windows subsystem for Linux. Okay. I'm
going to like compile in like install a
bunch of programs. So it allows me to
compile Emacs and download Emacs and
compile. Let's see what you know you
know let's just go and see. So this is a
casual session. You're just going to
watch me install
uh Linux. Okay, I mean not install
install Emacs in WSL.
So, let me have this uh candy. By the
way, this this candy quit cigarette
nicotine candy. By the way, I quit
smoking. So, I've been smoking for more
than 10 years. Okay. For Yeah. For the
for for almost 15 years, I think.
But I quit this year. Amazing. I just
quit cold turkey and I don't feel a
thing. Amazing.
Uh so but I got this uh nicotine candy
for helping you quit smoking three years
ago. I never, you know, I I occasionally
took one, but I never. So it not because
of this I quit. I just quit cold turkey.
But now I feel occasionally,
you know, I feel energizing to eat this
this nicotine candy. By the way, I know
what you're going to say of you like
white man. You're going to say, "Oh,
don't take it. Don't don't don't do
that. You're going to be smoking again."
[laughter]
Nicotine. Okay. They make you, you know,
actually nicotine energizes you. I like
nicotine. I don't like wine. I don't
like beer. You know, most most uh guys
like that like they like beer. I don't
like beer at all. I don't like red wine
either.
I don't like their taste. I mean, they
they they don't taste good. And I don't
like how they feels. They make you
stupid basically. But not nicotine.
Cigarettes. Cigarettes good. Okay.
So, let's go casually. If you are here,
say hi. Okay. It's going to be boring.
Okay. This is for nerds and for special
nerds. Um you don't know what I'm doing.
Okay. So first well the first thing you
need to do is you um
you need to start a shell. Okay. So we
are on Windows and it's PowerShell. So
control magnify. Okay.
So WSL I already installed WSL. So to
run it you just run WSL. you'll start
Linux. Okay. Amazing. You know, the uh
WSR Windows Subsystem for Linux, it's
been around since um since like 15 years
ago, but I never installed it until two
month ago uh uh with people's
help. uh Reaper in my discord reaper and
few other people they help me um and but
anyway it's you know it's amazing
technology so here we are in Linux now
so you see my prompt is so long so um
how do you know use uh oh Jesus I forgot
my Unix commands
you name I believe that's yeah there you
So you name a let's see the full name of
my uh system. So this is uh
uh Linux XGPC that's my machine name
6.6.87 A7 that's a Linux kernel version
I think what was it Microsoft standard
WSL2 number one SMP so there's a
technicalities
they created WSL2 which is different
from WSL1
okay number one S snp uh what does that
means uh that means the um anyway you
see in order to install this you have to
Um, so I did a log a blog about the
installation process. So if you have not
done it yet, you might check it out.
Okay. So what you need to do is like
let's go to uh so here you are looking
at uh today's talk show. Go to install
Windows Subsystem for Linux. Okay. So I
installed it on April 19th.
And basically the steps you need to do
is you need to turn on the
virtualization mode called SVM mode.
Okay? And you need to do that in your
so-called BIOS or UEFI.
And typically you restart your machine
and you hold down the delete key, the
right word delete or sometimes F1, F2 or
F10. Okay. Then if you are using a MAI
Jesus uh I think eating this candy
makes me not talk well.
So maybe I shouldn't eat it now.
Nicotine candy.
Okay. So now, okay, I can talk. Better
better.
Am I talking better?
[laughter]
B better better or better better
uh better.
So in order to install WSL, you need to
have this virtualization mode on SVM
mode and you need to go to your BIOS.
Okay. Now if you are running a machine
your motherboard you know the the
motherboard and stuff you if you are
running MSI
uh click BIOS which is my my machine.
Okay my machine is this one.
[sighs] Uh okay let's magnify.
This is my machine. Biggest spending in
16 years. I I I I spent $1,000 for it.
Okay. So this machine is 16 gigabyte.
So I bought in 2020 partly because of
you guys donation. Okay, that was back
then.
So for $900, okay, and plus the monitor.
But anyway, this is my gaming machine.
Okay, so this is motherboard motherboard
is it's MSI machine. So you hold down
the right the delete key. Okay, that's a
delete key on the home and insert
delete, you know, over there. It's not
the backspace. Okay, you hold on that
key
when machine start up. Then you So I
have instructions here and photo. So you
can see the full detail, the full glory
of this uh this BIOS [ __ ] bootstrap.
Fairly complicated, you know. Well, it's
part of the
uh computer engineering. Okay, you have
to have this bootstrap
which I don't know much about. Uh okay.
So that's what you have to do. You have
to turn on the uh virtualization mode.
Okay. Then you run wsl-install.
Just run it. It's it's uh it's bundled.
Okay. You do it the first time. It will
prepare WSL. Then you have to reboot the
machine. Then do it again wsl--install.
So the second time it will install a
Linux. By default it will install Ubuntu
but however you can specify other DRO
like Debian or whatever but you know
just go with Ubuntu because because
that's the most like compatible. If you
really want uh running Linux, you know,
you
you you you you start your OS from
Linux, you know, you don't do this uh
subsystem in Windows.
So anyway, so you see we started. Okay.
So what we going to do now? So uh again,
I'm just like doing nothing. Okay. I
mean uh I mean well I'm supposed to
install Emacs. Okay. So press Ctrl D to
exit. Okay, that's classic. That's a
bash. Okay, so here's a all the
screenshots of the install installation
process. Okay, once you install it, you
see which I do. Then you got this
prompt. So uh let's say duh. So you see
I'm in this talk show directory which is
on my um
this is on my Windows disc.
NTFS
new technology file system from Windows.
Okay, close it.
But when you are on in Linux, they
your Windows um disk is mounted at slash
mnt
users and so on.
Uh and uh
anyway one one of the big tip is that if
you are
um
accessing
Windows disk from Linux is slow. Okay.
So you want to access uh so let's say cd
to my home directory. So pwd for path
current path that's home. So you can see
I forgot you know I mean so it's been
quite a while I I uh typed any uh Linux
command 10 10 years or 20 years.
So what what is the um
FD? Okay. So let's see uh DF. Okay. So
there is my disk.
So these are my Linux Linux disc. Okay.
So you need to enlarge this
use. So, so M and T those are from
Windows. Okay. So, anyway,
well,
so what is is uh how do you find out
what space available there?
Uh so, we got 4 gigabyte available or
something. Okay.
Okay. I don't remember my Linux Unix
stuff. Okay. On Solaris. So, so let's
see. I want to let's go to uh my Linux
tutorial which I've written this like 10
years ago and uh it's good for beginners
but not much today because you can just
ask AI uh and these are AI generated
actually because
this page okay uh because I was trying
it last year and I thought just ask AI
to generate this most commonly used
shell commands. Okay, let's enlarge
this. Wait.
Okay, we we we are like right now
direction list. We need to like go
somewhere. Okay.
Get system info you name a. Okay. So, so
find the Linux distro release name. Do
you have this command available? I
wonder.
LSP release. You do? Okay, Uben 2. Uh,
okay. So, what are we going to do? We
need to Okay, let's go to Emacs.
Wait, copy. Go to today's talk show and
uh Oh, yeah. So, I already have it
prepared there.
Uh, paste linkify show. So, let's go to
Emacs download.
Okay. Yeah, let's download Emacs in
uh
not Windows.
Do I want to install let's say
anyone here? If you are here, say hi.
Okay. Mac Linux. Okay. So, how to build
Emacs on Linux?
Uh or you can directly install via apt
cache. Uh wait, you know, with the
appget? No, I don't want to install with
appget. So, let's see. Do I have via
which emacs? No.
Which vim? Yes, it has a basic uh vim,
but that's not a full vim, I believe.
version that's actually uh
what the [ __ ] vim vim runtime default
vim what vim rc
okay
okay okay I don't care so let's uh so
what do I have um
bo emac from source code should I Yeah.
Okay. So,
sudo app get install build essentials.
Paste.
Now it's going to ask my password.
Jesus.
What's my password?
[laughter]
Okay. I need to hide it. Okay.
Hide. Hide please. Hide uh audio. No
video special. So we got several videos.
My face, my keyboard there. And uh what
is this? Display capture. Okay.
Okay. So, let's put them back.
So, you see it says, "Oh my god, Jesus."
Apt get install build essentials.
It's going to install all this [ __ ]
You see on Linux if you're going to
compile anything you need this build
essentials. Okay there's this package
build essentials which is includes all
the like GCC stuff
C compiler CPP the CPP [ __ ]
[snorts] Okay. Am I alive?
Okay. So let's see. Okay. And then
you're going to you're going to install
G++.
What? What is G++?
[laughter]
I I don't know what what is G++. Okay,
let's let's um let's
you know let's uh let's take our
pleasure and ask AI.
What is g++?
>> C++ is the gen new C++ compiler. It's
the standard tool used to compile C++
code on Linux and many other systems.
You run it like C++ main CP
program to turn your code into an
executable. It's part of GCC, the Genu
compiler collection.
>> Okay, so let's make it louder.
>> Sorry, I'm stuck in a soft voice today.
Can't actually make myself louder on my
end. Try adjusting the volume on your
device.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
Okay. G++ is a GNU C++ compiler.
What?
Wait. Well, isn't it just GCC?
I thought GNU compiler GCC already also
compiles C++.
>> Yeah, exactly. GCC is the whole
collection and C++ is just its C++ front
end. Same compiler suite, just different
command name. So it automatically links
the C++ standard library for you.
>> I see.
>> Yep, that's pretty much it.
>> Hello, mass. Oh, mass
moto. Massive muscles.
[laughter]
That keyboard is [ __ ] awesome.
Ultimate hacking keyboard. Okay. Search
on my YouTube, you'll find a lot of
reviews also my website. Uh can we can
we show it? Show it quickly. Okay.
Because I talked about this a thousand
times. You see you see my massive
keyboard collection. You see all
beautiful. So the one you are looking at
I'm using today is this ultimate hacking
keyboard 80
massive $500. Okay, it's uh elite
keyboard for elite coders.
Okay, that's about keyboard. Okay, we
Okay, let's go back to the uh where is
my uh like technicalities? This [ __ ]
Let's just say yes. Okay, whatever. Say
yes. Yes. Yes, please. [ __ ] me.
[laughter]
Wait, I haven't had a drink yet. So,
let's have the nicotine candy.
Oh, what?
What? Unable to fetch some archives.
Maybe run app get update or try. Oh,
[ __ ] App get I forgot that. I remember
reading about that. App get update.
Now you need the meta key. Is this meta?
Yes, that's meta. Meta,
[laughter]
my Linux expertise.
App get update. Is that right?
Okay, you idiotic Linux
Uben to [ __ ] You know, there's
something very insulting about Ubuntu,
let me tell you. Okay. uh fetching
fetched 17 megabytes. Okay, now let's do
the build essentials again. Do it.
mgabytes of additional required. Will
you accept?
Yes.
Okay. There's something offensive about
Ubuntu. You guys don't know. Okay. Even
Even your daddy don't know because I'm
too old.
But let me explain. Okay. So, uh let me
show you.
You see this is the origin of the social
justice warriors
origin. Okay. Yes. You know, do you know
why the logo looks like that? Do you
know like you zoomers? Nothing.
Hello SCP.
Are you in a VM or docker container? We
are installing
we are trying to compile emacs
in Linux in Windows WSL windows
subsystem for Linux. Okay, that's what
we do going to do in compile emacs. But
before we do that, we have to uh uh um
apt update uh apt get update apt get
install essentials. That's what it's
doing. Oh no, I need to run top. [ __ ]
You see in Linux, you need to run this
top [ __ ] [laughter]
These nerds getting excited top. [ __ ]
them. [ __ ] them, man. [ __ ] their mom.
Top. Uh, there's a better one. Uh, I
believe was it called Utah Jesus. I
forgot. It's not installed.
You see, let me finish the story about
Ubentu logo. Okay, but I bet you guys
don't know. Like, do you guys know
what this Ubuntu logo? Why is it look
like that? If you know, tell me. Okay,
you zoomers know nothing. And you late
Malaysian [ __ ]
Okay, but before we do that, let's um I
need to get this going. And I need to uh
what is it that uh let's stop that.
What is it I want? Oh yeah, the top.
Okay, so the top.
Oh, that's Linux. Let's go to Windows.
Oh god.
What?
Keyboard lock and close. Let's go to
Linux tutorial.
This is what Linux looks like.
>> [laughter]
>> Penguin with rabbit rabbit ears. And
penguin with moose
horns and frog head. And penguin with
elephant
nose.
Trump trunk trump trunk
the mutation. That's Linux. By the way,
this this is uh this image came from
Microsoft in year 2000. because the
Microsoft they are marking Linux you
know um so where is it I don't have a oh
[ __ ] okay let me show you guys okay
because this interesting
you are watching nothing you are wasting
your time that's why you guys are here
okay if you are here you are wasting
your time better go do something busy
okay get you know go learn Linux go
learn AI and stuff you are wasting time
with a crazy And
uh Microsoft hatred 2002. Microsoft
hatred FAQ. Microsoft hatred and God.
You know a lot of people hate Microsoft
like deep hatred by this Linux and Unix
people. Anyway, here here's the
Microsoft that year 2000. But can you
imagine
now after 25 years
Microsoft embraced Linux in Linux and
Microsoft became the biggest open-source
corporation and still the most nasty
evil
you see and the Linux the open source
[ __ ] they don't know they know
nothing [laughter]
they become you know they they they got
eaten alive by the this deep state with
cooperation with one 10,000 lawyers you
know this Microsoft open source the
biggest open source corporation
Microsoft and Google by lines of code
okay they are like the entire uh net
system is open source
and Google you know you know chrome like
the Linux [ __ ] oh I use chrome oh I
use firefox oh but I use is ice fox you
know is I use Wasel browser. [ __ ] it.
Anyway, after 25 years, they become
bigger and bigger. They become the
biggest massive evil corporation, Google
and Microsoft.
And we got the open source fanatics.
Kasan, why are you not using Linux, you
[ __ ]
You know, every day we live in fear like
we don't dare to use real names. Oh, you
can't oh you can't talk nasty about you
know uh some
you get you get banned you know we live
in fear and these people they say oh but
but open source but you need open source
[ __ ] it
25 years his history you know Google
began like do no evil and they removed
that
they are now do evil let's do evil
[ __ ] them.
Okay. And that that got me angry, you
know. So I wanted I wanted to say um I
wanted to um [clears throat]
uh Unix pestilence. This is my um 25
years old article because I was s admin
for Solaris and and and and uh HP unit
UX and and stuff. Anyway, let's go back
to um Linux by command line.
I want to show you guys this UTP. Okay,
the [ __ ] The Linux Unix
[ __ ]
Where is it?
[snorts]
[sighs]
Okay, I need to calm down. Maybe I
should have a drink. Is it time for a
drink yet?
um
text processing file permissions. Oh,
PSQ top hop
say this is a better one. This is like
this is the story of Unix. You know they
create [ __ ] and after a while people
realize it's [ __ ] They need to pile
[ __ ] on top of the [ __ ] That's why you
have htop because the top is [ __ ]
[laughter]
the entire Unix thing like like grab, F
grab, E grab then then then silver then
then then then they they you know 10 10
years ago they got the the the one
written in rust and today you have so
many shells you know because it's [ __ ]
it's a [ __ ] to begin with but you just
pile it another [ __ ] you know that's why
that's why the Linux is like the entire
you know entire complexity
By the way, by the way, did you know
that Linux truncate lines like for for
example if you started Apache server or
whatever long command name you know
pearl or something or Java serlet or you
know then you run it you know then it's
um
uh PS okay so oh loud
PS aux
that's a Solaris version of the
of the um
options for PS a u www.
Why ww? Because w is for wordy. So two w
means more wordy. Okay. And it is
supported by Linux as well. Can you see?
But the other HPUX you know there's two
branch of Unix you know one is called um
system 5 the other one is um what is it
AT&T you know so the other Unix support
PS-f
[snorts]
okay so now both are supported by um
merged like by Linux you know because
but you you you realize why the auwx
Why? Why they don't have a dash? Because
the Unix inconsistency,
[ __ ] it's a [ __ ] to begin with, you
know? So, it's all [ __ ] That's why.
Okay. Awx.
But when you learn if you run a long
program, you know, the path is long,
lots of options. The Unix silently
truncate your lines. So when you want to
grab you know you want to grab you know
you're like like ps uh ps something pass
it to uh grab I want to know if I um did
I run s server
you know it says you know not found but
actually because it truncated the line
you are trying to search.
Do you see do you guys know what I mean?
[ __ ] Unix. Okay. [ __ ] it. [ __ ] the C and
Unix and now Linux [ __ ]
But what can you do? They they are like,
"Oh, but we are the most powerful. We
are cockroaches. Every server run us,
you know, Google. They are 10 gazillion
billion server farms. They are all
running Linux. Of course, because it's
free like cigarettes given to children
free,
you know.
[ __ ] him.
Uh, you know, I I can't get not angry
when I talk started to talk about Linux,
you know. And I've done this rant like a
thousand times in the past videos, but
not in recent years. Anyway,
[sighs]
take a breath. And now, let's get back
to um
what what we doing. So we will did we
install correctly the build tools build
essentials I think so.
Okay.
Okay. So you and you need to install uh
Utop hop. Uh is it is it I don't think
you know I'm pretty sure it's not a not
available
[sighs and gasps]
edge top.
Okay. when I was you know running Linux
I mean when I was doing Unix you know
like I'm very aggressive about this you
know you should never use top always
just install edgetop because it's better
you know improvement like mo [laughter]
like mo you know you you should use um
like you know you have find and today
you have a better one FD okay you should
install that because it's better you
know the the Linux fox
Um,
okay. [sighs]
Okay. Okay. Let's go back to Emacs.
Okay. Emacs.
Let's go back to Emacs. And I haven't
talked about this story yet. Did you
guys know? Okay. Let's Let's read the
comments. Okay.
I like the drunken master. Well, I
didn't drink today. I didn't drink
today. Today is my natural crazy.
Windows is pretty good nowadays, but
Windows is nasty. Windows got deep
state. Windows got back doors like like
every day like like yesterday, you know,
it just started to install updates, you
know, and you can't stop it, you know,
whatever nasty things they they they
come to your machine like they press the
button, someone in the deep state press
the button and the update sends out to
millions of people and you know when
when and they decided, oh, this guy is
bad mouthing us. you know, they they
send the update and tomorrow I can't
start my computers anymore. That's the
problem with Windows. Okay.
So, I've been wanting to switch away
from Windows, but you you know you it's
it's not like I'm not like young guys
like you guys. You got all the time. Oh,
let's play, you know, Linux Dro and uh
switch. You can't easy switch. You know,
I need to back up. I need to change a
lot of things.
[sighs]
Uh, Linux sucks, but it runs great on
old hardware. That's what they say, you
know.
Okay. I don't like Mac because it's
locked down. That's kind of true. Kind
of. But, um,
uh, okay. Topping [ __ ] with more [ __ ]
That's true.
Mac OS container machines, Windows WSL
competitor. Oh, I didn't know Mac OS has
container machines, but Mac OS X is
Linux. I mean I mean it's a Unix.
Okay, we got this BRW
this guy. Okay, VR V lex, you know, like
a non a non coward and is making fun of
me. Okay, so nobody knows what Ubentu
logo came from. So let me tell you guys
okay the Ubenu logo
came from the utopian ideology where the
the world of different races
unite like the white men the black man
men the let's say Palestinians
you know that we all and the other group
okay we all unite and hug each other
that's the origin of the uban tool logo.
Okay. Ubenu is built by a guy I believe
a African black guy.
So we need to uh look at Ubenu uh logo
photo. Can you see the original photo of
that? I think they erase things so you
don't
you can find it now. You see the
original design of this logo. It's three
people of different races like a black
guy, a white guy, a yellow guy,
whatever, you know, hugging each other.
That's a ideology. Utopian, the utopian
nation like you must believe this
otherwise you must die. That's what they
say. That's how we got the deeply [ __ ]
up deep state today. The original nice,
you know, it's always, you know, the
intention is nice. The intention is
always nice but
but uh you see the world doesn't go by
good intentions usually good intentions
the ideology like the free software
foundation [ __ ] you up that's why we
have the deep state we live in fear we
don't dare to show our face we everyone
is a none you don't dare to talk about
things you know but you are happy but I
hack I hack Linux so that they cannot
not you know so so I don't have back
door that you know that's what you guys
are why are the you know the that's like
0.1%
0.001% 001% people like like you guys
and me but most people they you know
anyway
so let's find the photo because I'm
determined okay
logo origin
search Ubuntu logo origin photo
[laughter]
you see this one someone is trying to
make fun of it
but I want to see the original photo. So
it's like 25 years ago. So it's hard to
find now. You see they buried history.
You see this steep state they you know.
[sighs]
So let's go to
yeah Uben 2 logo engine photo. Okay.
Someone is making fun of it. Let's see.
This is Reddit. Do they actually show?
None of these are real. Okay. But there
is should be a original um
copy. Now we need to go to the deep
state website. Let's see if they will
show you. Okay.
Okay. AI overview. The Ubuntu logo
universally known as the circle of
friends represents three abstract
figures holding hands and leaning back
in a circle. The design is a direct
graphical translation of the South
African philosophical concept of Ubuntu
which loosely translates to humanity to
others.
H I am because we are okay. So
photographic or engine. Let's see. Um
there it is. Ask Ubuntu. Let's go to ask
Ubuntu.
Who Uben to you know uh Stack Overflow.
You know this is history because Stlack
Overflow is now dead killed by AI since
about two years ago. But we are looking
at Stack Overflow. It's dead. [laughter]
And someone you know some zoomer
some zoomer is asking who is the
designer of the Ubuntu logo 2017. Okay
like they don't know nothing.
There it is. Can you see? So this is the
origin
of the ideology
of the social justice warriors
that if you don't believe men and women
are different you should die.
That's what they say. Okay.
And the riots and burning people alive
and you know massive burning buildings.
That's that's that's from them. And and
the Ukraine war and the other war and
you know that's uh the name of it is
deep state.
[sighs] I wonder if I said too much
Google is going to cancel me.
Uh, I like you, uncle. You seem cool.
Thank you. Vega Bomb says, "What is your
refresh rate, Uncle?" What? What refresh
rate? My monitor.
Okay, that's a story. Okay, Ubenu logo.
Uh, that's what I want to tell you guys,
the story, the tale of the Ubuntu logo.
So, let's make a screenshot of this for
history purposes.
So, for you guys, young people, if you
didn't know this, now you remember one
day I watched this weird guy si and I
learned, oh, there's this concept. Okay,
now let me tell you why is this uh
nasty? Because this ideology never
works. Okay, ideally, sure. Why not? Of
course, I always loved, you know, I
don't have any problem with blacks. So
why do you know the but
in reality you see
when push comes to shove this just
doesn't work. You need practical you
need
practical thinking. You need to live in
peace
but not by ideology. Okay, that gives
you misery. That's what we have. Death
killing people. That's what this
result. Okay. The result of that.
Now, shall we go back to Emacs? Shall
we? Um, let's see. We want to look. So,
we solved that question. This is the
Unix pestilence. Okay. This book you you
guys should read the Unix pestilence.
Pestilence still true to this day. All
the details, the commands, the [ __ ] up
commands, you know, the the design,
no-brainer design, the Unix. Okay, no
brainer. Like everything is just [ __ ]
[ __ ] Just memorize it. Okay, that's
all that's all you want to do. Just
memorize it. Don't ask questions. Why is
it this way? Just just just do it. Just
just type what I say. [laughter]
Linux [ __ ]
Okay, now let's get back to Emacs. Let's
see. We were original intention is to
install Emacs. Now, where is Emacs?
Okay, you need to um build essentials.
We got did we? Let's see.
So I need to install a lot of programs
like Utop and and the tree a tree
command. So I don't think I have a tree
command. So which tree that shows
directory as a tree and uh but and and
uh uh which GCC
I got gccy
[laughter]
C and C++ [ __ ]
Okay, that's installed. Now I let's uh
install that's um
sudo app get build dependency emac 24. I
don't even have emac 24. Well, but does
that work? By now it's emac 30. You see
I wrote this in 2012.
So now it's emac uh 30. Can you like run
this? Let's see.
Emacs 30.
Can you do Can you do that? Oh, password
again. Okay.
Okay. Let's see what
what
you can see my keyboard. Okay. So, hold
on a second.
Uh that and uh that that
Okay, it says
you must put some describe source URIs
in your resource list. So this command
does not work any Oh [ __ ]
Okay, let's ask AI. Okay.
Uh
why don't I use Linux? Like I said
before, it takes time to switch. You I'm
old. I'm not like you guys younger
people who got older time. You can
switch around. For me to switch, I need
to back up. I need to then of course
install Linux. Then I need to put all my
systems back to Linux. You know, it's
lots of work.
Um
but but Microsoft is becoming very deep
state. So I really uh want to switch
Okay. Uh, so what?
Yes, your monitor. What?
My monitor refresh rate, it's pretty
good. But are you talking about the
update rate of the chat? There's like
five minute 5second delay. Okay. So
anyway, so this doesn't work. So let's
ask AI
copy.
I used to run
this. Okay.
But it doesn't work anymore.
Let's see what AI says.
Check. Video check. Audio check. It
says, okay, AI says, uh,
yes, that's expected. Emac 24 is
extremely old from 2014. and has been
removed from modern Ubuntu Debian. So
sudo Emacs build de dependency Emac 24
no longer works. Modern solution try
this. Um
oh okay. So you just drop the version
number.
So let's try sudo app get build
dependency sudo app get build
you know another thing about the this
apt is stupid name like apt like what
the [ __ ] does it mean apt
so let's do that
No.
Okay. So, here is a explicit list.
It says it says this. AI help me.
AI help me. I don't know nothing.
[laughter]
So you say it's got it. You are on a
recent Ubuntu likely 24.04 04 or newer
which uses the new deb 822 format.
The old resources that list this is
mostly a sub now. Now what the [ __ ] is
dev 822
quick fix recommend
cd sudo cp
sources list. Okay. Oh [ __ ]
alternative ways. Open software updates.
That's uh that's the GUI, right?
Okay.
What the [ __ ] is
Deb 822?
This is the way I work, you know? I need
to know everything.
So, what the [ __ ] is step 822? 822 is
the new structured format for APT source
list. Okay. Old style sources list
example. Okay. A22 style is what
key value stanza stanza my ass. You see
they they go waxing poetry
is Unix idiots.
The key value stanzas
[laughter]
why the change more readable and less
errorrone. Oh god [ __ ] That's basically
what your woven two sources files look
like. Oh [ __ ] Oh [ __ ]
I don't understand.
Oh, belex
says in Linux apt stand for advanced
package tool. Oh, that's right.
Command software manager used in Debian
based distribution. Yes, of course,
that's long ago. That's like 25 years
ago, you know, like
you guys don't know the story, but um
you know the the the beginning the
history of the app manager, it didn't
exist before. Okay, I lived through it.
So I watched the birth of these
so-called app managers. So the first
one, wait, can I even remember what's
the first one? But anyway, back then you
don't have these app managers. every
time you want to uh install Emacs or Vim
or whatever you download a source and
comp compile manually yourself for every
software okay there's no just type this
and install something app manager
there's no such thing
is not apt okay it's it's um I can't
remember what's the first one okay or
you go to some website they have
prepared binaries you download that okay
so there's no app managers then then it
began then there's so many versions you
know on the Mac I can tell you for
example on the Mac it began with think
which is a clone of something uh I don't
remember okay so but but can we um let's
let's see if I can have some let's say
if I have some historical document about
think
f i n Okay, there it is. Software
dependency complexity think. Anyway,
that's another article about something
else. But anyway, you on the Mac, you
begin with think, then you got then you
begin with um I believe it's a port.
Okay. Well, AI will answer. Okay.
Tell me tell me about the history of app
managers on the Mac. For example, it
begin with think then eventually you
have homebrew but there was another one
Mac port I believe. Is that right?
Yeah, you got the timeline mostly right.
Here's the short history. Think came
first started around 2000. It was based
on Debian's package manager. So it used
apt and dpkg. It was the original way to
install Unix software on early Macs. Mac
ports launched in 2002. Originally
called Darwin ports, it was modeled
after FreeBSD's port system. Many people
preferred it over Think because it
didn't mix Debian tools with Mac OS as
aggressively. Homebrew showed up much
later in 2009. It was designed
specifically for Mac OS, much simpler to
use and installed everything into USR
local instead of its own isolated
directory. That made it feel more
native. So the order is think Mac ports
homebrew. Homebrew quickly became the
most popular by far. Mac ports is still
actively maintained, but homebrew
dominates now. Think is basically dead.
Want me to compare how they work
differently under the hood?
>> Thank you. You are correct. Now, is it
true that the zoomers don't know
anything about it?
>> Yeah, pretty much. Most zoomers have
never heard of Think, Mac ports, or even
homebrew. For them, installing apps on a
Mac usually means going to the app store
or just downloading a DMG file and
dragging it to applications. The idea of
using a command line package manager to
install developer tools or Unix
software.
>> It's funny. Thank you. [ __ ] the
Zoomer idiots.
>> Hey, let's keep it chill. Not everyone
needs to know about package managers.
>> Okay, chill. Okay, chill. Now, tell me
about the history of app managers on on
Unix or Linux.
>> Here's the short version of Linux
package manager history. It all started
with DPKG in 1993 for Debian. That was
the first big one. Then in 1994, Red Hat
created RPM which became the other major
format. In 1998, Debian released AP on
top of DPKG. This is what made AP get
installed so easy and popular. A few
years later around 2001 2003, we got the
higher level tools young for Red Hat
based systems and Pac-Man for Arch
Linux. Then Ubuntu came out in 2004 and
made a later just apt the most widely
known in the 2010s we got newer ones
like zipper for susa dnf which replaced
young on fedora and flatpack and snap
for distributing desktop apps so
basically dpkg and rpm started it all
apt made it userfriendly and everything
else came after want me to go deeper on
any of these
>> no thank you
>> no problem let me know if you need
anything else
>> you see The open-source idiots,
[ __ ] they are in a war. You see,
because everyone wants to be uh you know
like I I I I need to be famous. I need
to create my own you know why you know
we are open source we can money we can
make money but I need to create
something by myself different from
others. That's why you got this, you
know, uh, apt, DP, KG, RPM, apt,
Pac-Man, and, uh, Red Hat, you know, the
RPM something, you know, [ __ ] So,
quite quite a [ __ ] up. This improvement,
but oh, but I disagree. I disagree with
your approach. I need to create my own.
That's the story of open source.
Okay. on the commercial world this
doesn't happen because in the commercial
world it's money based
you know on Linux you you can't make
money so you fight about about uh fame
you know but in commercial world it's
money based so whatever makes money you
don't just create you know uh uh
different things uh
if if you cannot make money you know you
can create different things but they
compete by by people who are willing to
pay. Okay.
So anyway, that's a history of the
appget. Okay. Uh so now let's um
maybe that's it for today. Maybe what do
you think? So well we haven't installed
Emacs. So uh so okay. So let's ask a new
question.
Check
next. I have a lot of people
recommending me Nyx like 15 years ago,
but I just never tried it. Okay, but
okay, here's a question. I want to know
what commands to run to be able to
compile Emacs on Linux.
To compile Emacs from source on Linux,
start by installing the build
dependencies on iuntu or Debian. Run
pseudoapp get build emacs or manually
install packages like build essential
autocomp text info lib gtk-3debit
and others for image support. Then clone
the repo with git clone
git/git.sb.gmu.org/eac.git.
Run cdo autogen.sh/configure
sh/configure
make and finally pseudoake install. Want
me to give you the full list of
recommended dev packages?
>> Yeah, shut the [ __ ] up. You know, we
went we ran that before. It doesn't
work. You see
[sighs and gasps]
God.
So or manually install packages like B
essential auto conf
uh auto confo
you can't manually do it because Emacs
require a lot of things if you you you
need a full list
uh then clone the repo with that then
you know so this is not a good answer
uh [ __ ]
yeah so we need to do It's um
Oh, [ __ ] We need to solve the deb 822
issue.
Okay.
Why don't you just install? What do you
mean just install? I can't, you know,
I'm I'm slow. I cannot just install. I
need to know like who wrote it. What's
the nature of the guy, you know, and uh
well I you know I'm on you know I'm
uh
maybe that's it for today. Okay so we
didn't so we need to solve I mean the
problem right now is this install Emacs
dependencies. Okay. So the AI says run
pseudo app get build dependency emacs.
That doesn't work because it says you
must put some dev source uris in your
source list.
Then sources list is absolute. You have
deb22
thing.
So you uh
Okay.
So I I suppose that's boring for you
guys. Uh let's see what to do. How long
have I been talking? One hour.
Okay. So how many people watching? Oh,
15. Oh god, thank you. I'm so popular.
So does does anyone of you Moedo don't
you know what is the command to install
Emacs dependencies like you you are the
Linux you are the open-source fanatic
you should know tell me how do I what
command to run to get all the Emacs
dependencies so I can start to build it
and Hang don't you know hang and this
BRV guy don't you know so anyone of you
know it. Type it. Okay. I need to run
the command that installs all Emacs
dependencies.
Just clone Emacs. What? What do you mean
clone Emacs?
Oh, then you'll tell me what I need.
Okay.
Well, okay. So, Okay. So, I need to
download Emacs now. Wait. And now what
is the command? I forgot.
Uh wait. So go to where? Uh so what are
we going
install? So I need to go to my Emacs
page. Okay. So let's
showing browser.
Uh how to be? So Emacs download. So, I
need to get
um I need to find what's the Emacs
to download. Okay.
Yeah, [ __ ] it. Let's just install the
default Emacs.
[laughter]
Let's let's just
app search Emacs please. Oh Jesus.
They have Emacs 21. Oh X Emacs. XE Emacs
is another story. That's the earliest
opensource split.
It's called Schism. Okay. You guys may
not know you you guys young people. It's
called
open source software schism.
That's the very first one fork uh of
Emacs XE Emacs big war for like over 10
years
uh but okay but uh okay so what is the
command what is the latest im oh god im
is so much so many of it oh Jesus the
alpa [ __ ] is also here
why why they put you know they they this
these people
They put alpas stuff in the apt
package manager
that spams the a the package manager.
They put all the library emacs library
stuff.
You see very confusing. and white. Um
Jesus
so common facilities
Emacen common common facilities for all
EMAC
portable library for Emacen
just give me the EMAC I don't want EMAC
libraries. I just want the Emacs. She
Jesus.
Emacs and my ass. By the way, this is
another thing you Zoomers don't know.
Okay, in the Unix community, they have a
knack for these
like supposedly proper English names.
So, when you want to call a Emac user,
you don't say Emacs user. That's stupid.
Okay, you have to say eaxen
that that indicates that you are a
insider. Okay, you are a hacker. When
you say you know when you talk to
people, oh I need you know I'm an Emac
or something Emac then people know oh
you are a hacker you know you are all
all kind.
If you say Emacs user they they think
you are stupid. [laughter]
So you you know you got Emacs and you
got quite a few uh quite a few but I
don't remember. So you can ask AI.
So shall we? No, let's not. Let's just
get this. Um
look look at this. They they put all the
uh Wait, that's X Emacs.
Ah Jesus.
Search Emacs 30. Can Can you do that?
No.
What the [ __ ]
You see they even put OG mod or mode
documentation in appgget. Why do they do
that?
You suppose like you once you install
Emacs then you can install the other
things but wait
uh [sighs]
clone and build. Okay. Okay. So, but
where is the uh
but I forgot what's the command to clone
um
the repo like I need to
oh g do I have git installed
which I don't think so
wait so you need this key
which get
oh I have git installed now that's
get okay get Chrome but I don't want the
I don't want the latest I mean I don't
want the you know dev version I I just
want the E okay let's try it
okay so
so Emacs so let's see download Emacs
binary wait Emacs from source code and
what is this page download okay so you
you want to build from source code click
on that but I want to build from the
repo. So you go here. Uh again this is
written in 2014. Okay but at least they
tell you the repo. Okay. So
there
get clone get clone now if that I you
know let's hope that URL is still good.
Get clone. Get clone it.
Oh [ __ ] I don't want to clone the
history. I forgot. I should say no
history
because otherwise it's huge.
Okay, I think maybe I should stop.
That's enough fun for the day.
Check discord.
Check discord. Uh where is my discord?
Check. Mo says check discord.
His majestity. Majesty. Mo says sudo app
update. That did I did that sudo app
install build essentials auto conf. egg
that I already did, I think. Let's just
let's just do whatever Mo says. Okay.
Uh let's move this here.
Okay. Wait until this finish.
So that is my Emacs clone from Ripple.
We are advanced technologist. You see
[laughter] very good.
We understand this incomprehensible
[ __ ]
but how long is this is going to take?
Oh, okay. So, that's uh one gigabyte,
right? K. What? This is
kilo.
What?
It's just one megabyte. Wait, one
gigabyte.
Uh, one gigabyte.
You know, when I started my computing
life around 1992,
a big hard drive is 40 megabyte. That's
uh, you know, if you are a rich man, you
buy the big hard drive, 40 megabytes.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I'm not familiar with this one
gigabyte [ __ ]
Jesus. One gigabyte [ __ ]
Okay. 1.5
giga or giga.
Now let's see what mo says.
Mo says you need to uh here.
Okay, that then sudo install lib
package. Oh god. Lip lib lib lib xpm.
That's a stupid image like textbased
image from the Unix idiots.
lip gtk
lip jpeg
lip gif lip t that's a old image format
lip ne
what what is this lip gut
okay then lip curses that's uh let's
magnify okay so can you guys see
wait where's my first.
Okay. So, magnify so that you guys can
see what Mo is saying. So, you you see
lip curses. That's um text textbased GUI
then li GCC JIT just in time
li J lip what lip Jansson I don't know
what the [ __ ] that is
then gu bing li tree sitter or tree
sitter that's advanced technology for
passing source code
Is it done? Okay. Says it's done. So now
let's follow GNU
most instructions. Okay. So uh wait. So
do we have already that? I think so.
Just make sure. Let's run it again.
Oh god. Jesus.
Okay. Yes.
Okay. So that is uh auto conf make GCC
text info. What why are they uh I
thought they are part of the dependency.
Why are there so many
pearl?
Are they installing pearl?
Jesus.
Hey, why why are they installing pearl?
Oh, Jesus.
Okay.
I don't understand.
I don't understand. But it's done. Next.
Next. Do this.
Do it.
Do you want to? Yes.
No. You got this
XZO,
a big virus.
[laughter]
Have you guys heard the story
uh XZXY?
um you know there's a big hacking story
that being hacked
by um so you can read that story by
going into Twitter
from my friend who told me well I know I
already know the story but he reminded
me yesterday
there is this
giant hack XZ
very interesting okay This this is deep
state hack to Linux. So someone
supposedly a Chinese name Jan
uh embedded a remote run uh virus like
allows you to control take over your
Linux machine remotely run any command
they want in bet. So they have the back
door installed in the uh XZ util which
is a compression.
Very interesting story. Okay. So XZ.
Yeah, that's right. So that's that. So
is it done yet? Is it done yet? Jesus.
Jesus. Okay, it's done now. Next.
Next.
Sudo app install. G leave GCC or Jesus.
Another bunch. Copy.
Okay. Thank you, Juan, for the cute cat.
Do it.
Yes or no? Yes. Okay. I don't know what
the [ __ ] they are doing to me,
but I can trust Mo and I verified is
good.
[laughter]
Okay. Okay. Are we going to finish
installing Emacs? I don't think so.
Okay, now I think all the dependency are
installed. Now CD, let's see the Oh my
god. Jesus, my Windows habit. It's not
the it's ls. Okay, [laughter]
so there we have Emacs
um
the Emacs clone report. Uh now
which make please make. Okay.
So I I guess I can start to build. Let's
see. Okay. So I don't remember.
I'm too old. I don't remember what what
make.
So see the autogen now. Is it autogen?
Do I still need to run the autogen?
I don't even know if it's there. Let's
see.
Uh,
I don't know what autogen does actually.
CDMAX
LS.
Do we have autogen? No, that hides the
dot file. Another Linux. [ __ ]
Do we have the autogen? No. You got the
clan.
Oh, there it is. Autogen. Okay.
Oh, you don't need to build from the
source. It's already done. What?
Which Emac
CD? What do you mean? It's It's not
done.
So, what do you mean it's done?
Now, you can run Emacs directly from the
command line. Oh, that's what you mean.
Oh, okay. Okay. So, let's run um
So, wait. So, where are we?
uh cde max
ls a l.
So there is I believe it's a bing
directory, right? I don't remember.
I'm too old.
Okay. So
yeah, that's right. You we we have to
build it. We only installed the uh you
know. So now I need to run the autogen.
Okay.
So
it's there. So autogen
confusion not work. You need the dot
autogen.
No,
you need
slash.
Wait, is it it um
dot slash autogen?
What the [ __ ]
Oh, is it? Uh, [ __ ] It's been too long.
Okay, so
uh yeah, dot slash dot. Wait.
Oh, there's no dot in front. So, autogen
there. Do it.
Now you can run config
config please.
Fantastic success.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. Fantastic.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
checking, checking, building and
checking and compiling and fax C and
[ __ ] C++. You see this is a this is one
of the damage from the C and C++
[ __ ] because they are com their
programming language C and C++ are so
convoluted it takes you know roundabout
to compile them.
the brainless from the Unix [ __ ]
Okay. Now you can continue to support
using configure with pop configure. You
might want to install GNU mail util. No,
I'm not going to install GNU mail. [ __ ]
Now I believe it's ready. Okay. So which
Emacs? No. Well, actually I need to say
install Emacs but
but I believe Emacs can run from this
directory now. So ls though there's a
bin directory I think is something like
that.
Did they create a bin directory or
something? This the content of the
directory. Okay. So Mo says if not C
then what? Oh, today you got options
rust and go. I would prefer goland.
Okay.
Yes, there is a build somewhere but uh I
forgot where I thought it's in a binding
and or did they um so you need to well
let's go refer to my
uh instruction make bootstrap that's
what we have to do make bootstrap please
[laughter]
[gasps]
science instruction is correct.
Okay. Okay.
Checking checking checking checking
checking this and checking that.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Checking debus. Checking.
Oh god. Emacs is big
big power machine. That's a master of
Well, so the question
Thanos says, "Isn't Go evil Google and
Russ deep state?"
Well, they are, but they are just
programming languages.
So you know
and if you want to avoid programming
languages from deep state then you don't
have programming languages you don't
have go you don't have rust you don't
have well in fact you don't have C and
C++ because
well well C and C++ you can rely on the
GNU compiler um But
anyway, it's almost done.
Okay, now it's been 1 hour and 28
minutes
of this live stream.
Okay, almost done. CC compiling.
Okay, come on. Come on. Finish it. I
need to go home and have breakfast.
Hang is the zoomer jet. You can tell by
the, you know, by the memes and cats
they post.
Zuma Jen. Look, look at this. What this?
This is the Zuma Jen's brand. That's
what you know that's their that's what
their brain are made of memes and stuff
and usually ugly like especially by
Huang. Huang likes to po post this ugly
[ __ ] They they call it memes, you know.
That's that's the that's their entire
brain is these things.
Is there a list that could do it? Yeah,
sure. You go back 30, 40 years ago, then
you run this machines, then you don't
have this G and G, you know, this GCC
C++ crap. Okay, this machine that's 40
years ago.
God is still doing Jesus. This taking
people, you know, I wish I can run. I
don't know how to do it, but I want to
have another terminal in WSL so I can
run top and see what are the processes.
Uh but I think like on Linux you can
press Ctrl Alt F1 or F2 or or one of the
you know so you can dive into the
virtual terminal and then you can have
several terminals but I'm not sure how
you you know if that can be done in the
WSL.
By the way, uh Mo, do you use WSL? Oh, I
don't think you do because you are on
Linux. You can use T-Max.
I never I never actually am a user of
T-Max, but
anyway, I don't think you can. I mean,
it's already running. So, you need to
run it before you do the compile.
[snorts]
So, anyway, it's uh Okay, now it's
building. It's compiling lisp code. You
see that those ELC those ELC are
uh bite compile lisp
uh lisp source code. EMAC lisp source
code. So they are now compiling the
emac lisp source code.
Okay.
Oh Jesus.
>> [sighs]
>> Almost almost done.
CET CET is a EMAC bisp package that is
designed to have um
advanced IDE features but it's so
complex that very few people use almost
nobody uses
okay now it's still building compiling
byte compile emac disp code
you see it's filling up the eacisp
directory with compiled emac of code.
So lots of emacs, you know, do
everything. You can you can run emails,
you can do music players, you can do
like you can you can you can control
your coffee machine from Emacs, you can
also remotely control Dodo from Emacs.
This package is [snorts]
Oh god.
See that is slow even with modern
hardware. Yeah, I never actually use it.
Yeah, nobody use it.
Playing games. That's right. Emax can
also play games. Let's, you know, let's
when it's after it's done, let's run the
Tetris. Okay. or there's a snake
building Emacs. These Emacs idiots,
they have to include games like Snake
and Tetris to demonstrate to show you
how advanced Emacs is.
But we can we can run here. So, let's
start Tetris. Okay,
Tetris. Let's begin again. Let's wait.
What is the key to flip? Oh, the Yeah.
Okay. So, down space to down. Okay. So,
just move that space. Wait, how do you
put it down?
Change. Switch. Switch. Okay. Oh god,
I'm in trouble.
Switch. Switch. Switch.
Oh god.
Okay, that's Tetris in Emacs. Okay, by
the way, all these are text.
Uh I don't remember what's the command.
So you can do this and to show all the
Tetris commands.
So right now it's still running. So you
can see wait did it stop?
Oh, when your cruiser is there and it
runs. See when your cursor is here,
expand the window so you can see all the
commands. So Tetris move down. What's
the way uh rotate? Okay. So what is the
key to push them down all the way?
I didn't see it there.
Oh, maybe there's not, but because it's
pretty basic. Okay, so anyway, there's a
demo of Tetris. Now let's go back to Oh
god, it's still building.
How long is this going to take?
Let's see the Windows process
CPU. It only uses one CPU.
That's why the other CPU is not filled.
Okay,
let's see processes. What?
Okay, this is the virtual machine.
This one is a virtual machine. 8%.
Okay, it's still running. Jesus. Now
close that.
Switch to Tetris.
Okay.
Still building. God, this is too slow.
Come on.
Make only uses one CPU by default.
Okay. Did didn't they improve like don't
they you know all these years didn't
they create a parallel um concurrent
make maybe they cannot because
you know because it is a C C++
sequential nature maybe
still running.
Let's see Discord. What's new in
Discord? Oh Jesus.
One's life.
Okay, we uh can't
ugly.
Oh god, it's still running. GNUS is a
email reader and also a news group
reader. Uh well, if you are young, you
don't know what's a news group. New news
group is the
is is like a group chat. It's like
today's Twitter but 40 years ago. It's
all text, you know. It's kind of wow.
It's not like it's like a forum, okay,
where you can post questions or talk to
people. uh news group. Okay, it's called
news group. It's like what's news today?
You know, today you go to Twitter.
What's news today? You go to Twitter.
You know, if I click it, you're going to
see lots of ugly news like war, you
know, that that's what I follow Twitter
for. So, you click here, it's my
profile. It's, you know, it's it's, you
know, oh, by the way, I discovered
the emoji from Google and from Apple,
the emoji font. For example, on Apple,
it's called Apple color emoji. If you
use Google on Linux, you typically use
Google's emoji font called Google Notto
emoji. Uh, Google notto color emoji.
There there are two versions, one for
color. Okay. Anyway, if you use the
color version on Mac and from Google and
Mac, they are actually bitmapped. Okay,
that's something I learned by asking AI.
So when you in so so the font actually
has many versions of different sizes,
but if you enlarge it beyond 160 pixels,
you'll get jagged pictures. You see, you
know, not clear fuzzy. they become fuzzy
because they are not
they are not in vector format they are
bitmapped so that's something new I
learned amazing you know this emoji are
actually bitmapped
uh you know but on the other hand if you
the Microsoft emoji they are not
bitmapped
it's still building okay so on the
Microsoft emoji let's see let's see my
Tetris. Okay, I'm dead.
Uh, okay. Let's do a screenshot of this.
So, this this is EMAC Tetris in Emacs
for oldtime. This is old news. This is
like everyone knows except young people,
you know, you guys don't know. But let's
go to uh Unicode, my Unicode blog, which
I talked about so frequently. So, you
can see
emoji. If you use emoji of Microsoft
emoji, these are Microsoft version. They
updated to become trans. So every emoji
reminds you of the trans [ __ ] like
crazy. You know this ugly.
But but anyway, the Microsoft emoji,
they use vector graphics. So they don't,
you know, they don't get um you see you
can enlarge. Let me show you this. Okay.
Bigger. Bigger. By the way, this is my
website. Just go to casardi.info
everything you want to know about unic
code. Okay. So anyway you are looking at
the Microsoft emoji font. Okay. They are
not bit map. You can enlarge it. Okay.
So let me show you.
Okay. But if you use Google's
emoji font let's see. Click here. So
this is Google version. Okay. Um
and you need to enlarge it more. uh
enlarge it more. So
wait, Google also have a vector version.
So actually this is using the vector
version. Yeah, Google also has a vector
version. Okay, so this is Yeah. So this
is using the vector version because you
don't see the jacked
lines. So this is good. Well, anyway, I
cannot demo Apple because I don't have
Apple's font. Um,
anyway, that's something interesting.
So, now let's just
make it uh
Okay, back to 30.
Okay, it's still building. Oh, Jesus.
How long does it take?
It's 2 hours now. We've been talking for
1 hour and 40 minutes. Okay.
Okay. Yeah, it's still building.
So, actually,
yeah, it's still building. Jesus,
why is it taking so long? God, this
building emac this this they are trying
to compile
all this emac this code by compile it.
Okay, almost done. Okay. Okay. I think
are you done yet?
Nazi entries. I don't know what that is.
Ctrl C and type
why do why do I want to type that make
JS M progue that's that's concurrent
it will continue from where you stopped
uh I don't want to risk it
so what is that uh make JS.
So let's ask AI. Okay. So let's ask AI
what is this thing?
Make dash J dollar sign M prog is a very
common way to speed up compilation by
running it multiple jobs in parallel.
Oh,
okay. But I don't want to try it. I
don't want to risk it because you never
know. You You try something you don't
know and you screw up. You have to redo
it. Now it's done
finally. I think that's it for today.
Okay. Now let's run. Um it's done. Okay.
So now
now LS-
Okay. Now, do we have a bing directory?
Where did you um
I don't remember where did it install.
So, now let's go back to my website.
Uh what's the last command?
Make bootstrapped. Oh, then I have to
make Jesus.
>> [laughter]
>> That was just make bootstrap. Now you
have to make Oh god. Oh then.
Did they create a binder? No.
Okay. Then when done.
Oh, the whole process will take about 20
minutes. When done, Emacs binary will be
at source. Okay. So, let's go to source.
So, my instruction written 10 years ago
is still good. Still good. Now, cd
source ls a l.
Uh, where is my emac here? So, my emac
is here somewhere.
There it is. So now let's run Emacs.
Okay. So wait
slash dot slash Emacs. Run it. Run it.
Success. So this is Emacs in WSL Windows
Subsystem for Linux. Okay. Now you want
you see. So now we want to magnify the
font. Control alt square. That works.
Okay. Now let's say meta x
version.
Okay. So it tells me I'm running emac
32. Oh Jesus even greater than my
current version. So my current version
is emac 30. Wow. So the ripple is emac
32.
So let's magnify more. Control port
magnify. So it becomes huge. Okay.
Okay. Now magnify more. This is the
first time I started a GUI
in WSL. Okay.
So now
now Tetris. Okay.
X
Tetris.
Fantastic.
Success. Okay, we installed Emacs.
Fantastic. That's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching and uh thank you
Mo for help and hang finally. Okay, bye
guys. Have a good day. I think that's
good.
Anything else? Let's see. Uh the final
check. So Unix we close that uh to close
close because our talk show that's
today's talk show. We installed Emacs
and compiled and all the trouble on WSL.
on Windows. So, yeah. Okay. Thank you
guys. Bye. Have fun. That was fun.
Bye. Bye.