Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. We are going to demonstrate and
show you Emacs lisp code uh doing
formatting code. So this is for you
programmers and EMAC coders. Fantastic
Emacs.
Uh okay, that's uh so if you are
watching this offline, play at 1.5 speed
or faster. If you are here, say hi. Love
to see your comments. Uh let's see.
So hello hello palash. So we're going to
do so I just updated this code format
source code. So for example let's go let
me demo first. Okay. So Emacs. So the
pink window shows all my command course
and the keystrokes for example. Uh you
can you can see my command call whatever
I do in EMAC. whatever command I call
for example delete that it shows up here
and the keystroke on the left uh I'm
using a vora keyboard layout and and I'm
using kasfly keys okay keys you can get
it for free it's the most efficient key
binding system in EMAC search for it
you'll find it keys okay more efficient
than vim you can watch a video okay so
let me demonstrate the what we're going
to So here is my CSS code. So showing
browser, this is my website. Uh close
that. Showing browser. This is today's
talk show. And go go up here. There's a
CSS. So this is my CSS file cascading
style sheet. Uh you know, close it. So
it's got about 1,000 lines of code. So
let's do something. You see, I got CSS
variables. Very fancy. So first of all
make a backup. Let's join them into one
line. And this body join them into one
line. Okay. Now press one key. Tap F.
Fantastic. They become formatted.
Beautiful. You see undo.
Redo. You see the difference? Undo. You
see we, you know this one single huge
line. Actually I like that. That's a
fantastic style formatting style. one
single line because then you can you can
compact your code but anyway that's
another story. So for example comp
compact this code so this is cascading
stylesheet now if you are a newbie you
don't know what is cascading stylesheet
you can check out kasadi.info info
visual CSS tutorial for for beginners
and as well for uh for those of you have
some experience. So CSS is a fundamental
technology for the web you need to as
well actually today for desktop for
everything when you need to write the
application you need CSS okay so that's
digression but anyway so here's a CSS
code for my website so you can like like
you can make the whole thing one line
let's see make it one line and does it
still work yes of course refresh you see
select a tutorial
uh an HTML tutorial, JavaScript in-depth
tutorial,
uh quote string, it still work. But if
you delete them, let's say for example,
delete this. Back to browser. Now, if I
refresh, uh I'm going to lose I'm going
going to lose the font family area. For
example, delete that. Back to browser.
Now refresh. Watch it carefully. Can you
see it? Yes. Refresh. You see that's CSS
undo. So okay now back to browser
refresh. Now back to my original now but
you see what I want to demo is this
formatting CSS code. So in Emacs I just
press a key press it. Fantastic. The
entire file is reformatted in a
beautiful way. Okay that is so save it.
Now let's do VS code. uh detect if I
there's any changes. No. Okay. There.
Anyway, so that is the um that is CSS
format. So where is the command? So
describe key press tab F. This is Kasan
EMAC system. Every major mod keys begin
with tab. Okay. So it's it's very
consistent. So you can see go to Kasan
CSS mod my own mod. So here is all my
mod now. Delete the backup now. Um
showing show show them big. Did delete
the backup. Yes. Okay. So CSS mod there.
And uh here is the command kasar CSS
format buffer. Uh go to the bottom.
There's 10,00 lines of code. Now back to
here. So format CSS buffer. And if you
want the code, it's free.
Go to this URL, open it. So you just
search for uh Emacs format CSS code on
kalei.info.
So you can grab the code
free and open source. Okay. Uh thanks to
me. So if you like, if it's beneficial
to you, donate. Don't forget. Let me
mention this. So this is the donation
time.
Go to the tops.info
and then you go to the bottom. Lots of
tutorials. Patreon me, Amazon gift card
me, PayPal me. If you work as a
professional,
uh, you know, pay me $100.
Okay. So, let's go back. That's your
sponsor. Okay. That's sponsorship now.
So, you can grab the code format CSS
code. Okay. So, now let's go back here.
We demonstrated formatting CSS cascading
stylesheet. Okay. Close. Close. Close.
That's CSS mod. You can get it. You
know, if you can pay me and get it.
Search for Emacs Kasaras CSS smart or
search for Kasar packages Emacs. You'll
find it. Okay. So, close course that.
So, that's demonstration of formatting
CSS. Just press a key. It will work.
Okay. Now, back to here. Now, Python.
What about Python? The most popular
language. Well, we can do that, too. So,
here's a code. So, let's demo Python.
Okay. So, for Python, we got, you know,
JavaScript. Uh, not JavaScript in depth,
Python.
We got so many. So, here's a script that
find replace multi-pairs of regular
expressions in a directory. Okay, the
code is here. You can grab it, too. So
this is like unique script but written
in Python. So we can uh can we run this?
Yes, of course.
Uh yeah. So copy that. Okay. Now
open that. Showing browser. That's this
page. Now search for pre. So this is
where the this code begin. Now okay. Now
go back here. Pop it out. So here's a
Python code. Now first of all let's demo
the formatting. Okay. So this this
script will change you know it does find
replace for all files in a directory.
Okay. And you can also specify a list of
files. So it will just find replace on
this on this list of files. And you can
specify do backup true or false. And uh
then you can also specify actually I
need to add a feature. So that allows
you to say you know write to file or
not.
And here is the pair a list of pairs of
regular expression. So regular
expression is a find pattern find text
pattern. Then you got a replacement
pattern whatever you want to replace. Um
so right now this code does not have a
option to to say you know just run it as
a test like write to file true or false
but my local I think my local version
does anyway so here's the code so let's
say I want to um you know so for Python
code you um
you know Python code is like hardcoded
it. So, how do you demonstrate a
formatting? Um,
you know, so we can let's try something
simple. Okay, let's not do that.
Let's try something simpler. So, okay,
let's just write a Python code on the
fly. Okay, actually we got several other
things to demo, so we need to go faster.
Okay. So, okay. So, let's uh let's just
quickly write some Python code. Uh
Python. Okay. Now, print for. Okay. Now,
press a key.
You see now it's nicely formatted. Now,
let's say variable x equals to uh
something. Okay. Now, uh print
xx. Okay. Now, this suppose like that.
Okay. Now, press a key. Nice formatting.
Nice. Let's say uh for example, now
let's make it, you know, something like
that. Something plus uh plus
one, two, three. Okay. Run it. Run the
code. Syntax error. Okay. So this cannot
be uh in two lines. Okay. So now run it.
Result is that fantastic. Correct. But I
want to format the code. So press the
key. Fantastic and beautiful. What if I
have extra lines there? Press a key.
Fantastic and beautiful. Press a key. So
by default it leaves two empty lines. So
that's demonstration of the formatting
Python. Now where's the code? Okay.
Describe key. Tap F. So you can see the
code is there. And uh here is the code.
Python format buffer. And you can open
this file show in browser. There's a
code. Okay. Um,
fantastic. That's automatically
formatting Python code. By the way, uh,
in order to uh, for this to work, you
require
you require the Python um, black.
There's a Python there's a program
called just black. So that does that
actually that's a program that does the
formatting. So the the Emacs command is
just a wrapper. It calls that command.
Similarly for CSS for CSS for formatting
CSS to work you need so now close that
close that I'll put it back the syntax
code showing browser for CSS code you
need to install deeno okay so it's all
specified in the you see this command
requires external command deeno
okay now let's demonstrate now what
about JavaScript same thing okay
JavaScript script. Um, yeah. Okay. Let's
go to JavaScript.
Uh, let's go to for JavaScript. Let's go
to uh let's go to JavaScript. Okay. So,
JavaScript
uh dome. Let's go to DOM. Let's go to
this page where you can see fancy
graphics.
Uh there's quite a few uh choices we can
pick. So web scripting example image
roll over. Okay, that's that's kind of
boring and small code. So let's do let's
so there's digital clock stopwatch fader
element two tips two tips. There it is.
This page shows you how to do that
and the snowing effect. So let's use
this one. So because this one you got
more code to format. Okay. So Jun. Okay.
So, copy the file path. Okay. Showing
browser. Close. Close. Close. Now, let's
paste that. Showing browser to today's
talk show. There it is. Falling snow
effect. Okay. Now, so open that falling
snow effect. Raining hearts. Okay. Now,
search for.js.
So, you can see the code is right there.
So, open it. So, so this is the file.
This is actually Typescript. So you can
see this is Typescript. It compiles to
JavaScript. So if I open the JavaScript
and delete it, you see it's gone. Now go
back here. Refresh. It stops working
because you just deleted the file. So
now open the TypeScript. Now press tab
C. Watch the pink window. Tap C.
Shell command succeed. Succeeded. So we
just we just called JavaScript
TypeScript compile file. Now drop into
directory. So
refresh. So you can see the JavaScript
file spring back to life. But now let's
open the TypeScript. Now let's you see
this this is um you know this is the
code. So let's
make it one line. Let's like do some
up and you know let's make it one
line. Let's make it one line. And this
this this uh this function random int.
Let's make it one line. Okay. Now press
a key.
Fantastic and beautiful. You see it
formats the entire code. So as opposed
to the normal C dler and C++ and Python
digital what they do is they read you
know style guide per style guide C code
guide you know C++ style guide you know
you
for for for for past 20 years they do
they do that then for each line oh you
got you gota tab indent you know I my
style my preferred style is three three
space another guy. My preferred style is
one tab,
you know. So, so you can see so each one
is different and each for each line. Oh,
I prefer to have a space here. You know,
this these idiots from Unix and Coders
for the past 30 years.
What changed? What changed all that is
goland in 2020 uh 2008 go language by
Rob Pike and other so they created auto
formatting concept which is in wufam
language since 1980 uh 199uh
6 1996 automatic formatting on the fly
anyway so what you do not want is this
this manual line by line this
indentation or whatever okay so So
anyway, so we made some changes. Press a
key. You see it format automatically
format the whole file in one single
consistent style. Now turn off the
spaces. Okay. Again, you can see all my
command codes there in the ping window.
So this file is actually 10,00 lines.
Okay. So for example, let's see, you
know, let's so this this uh let's this
this entire block of text make it one
line. Okay. Now tap C to compile it. So
now drop to JavaScript file. Open it. Go
to the button. Oh, when you compile it
actually format. Okay. But anyway, so we
will we we will format in TypeScript.
But but you can also format um
JavaScript. So right now here is
JavaScript. So let's go to uh for
example here make it one line. Okay. Now
go back to browser.
Okay. Now the file is saved JavaScript
file. Now go to the browser. Refresh.
You see it works beautiful. Now go back
here. JavaScript file. Press a key.
Format beautifully. Okay. So now go back
to browser. Refresh.
It works. Of course. Now back to Emacs
JavaScript file. Delete the thing. Go to
the TypeScript. Open. Format it. Compile
it. Back to browser. Refresh.
Everything still works.
Beautiful. So that's demonstration of
the automatic feature.
Okay. Close that. So where is that code?
So okay, so where's that uh code? So
open it. Uh
so open it. So describe key tab f. So
here is the code javascript mod and the
saw javascript format buffer and the URL
is here. Open and show in browser. So
you can grab the code. Okay.
So that is what we are doing. That's
what I'm demonstrating. Close. Close.
Raining hearts. Uh close. Okay. So what
about HTML? So right now we are in a
HTML file. So this is uh talk show today
showing browser. Okay. So what about
HTML? You can format two. So for
example, let's make it let's make it you
know HTML one line one line one line one
line one one line. Okay. So showing
browser is your works of course because
HTML is not white space significant. Now
if you want to format it let me show you
press the key. Oh
beautiful it's actually formatted with
indentation. You can see can you see
showing browser it works. Now what if
you don't want you know indentation is
kind of nasty in HTML. Usually you don't
want it because indentation because by
the nature of HTML syntax it's all
nested tree. So you are going to you are
going to end up with huge amount of
indentation because every element almost
every element is is nested very deep.
Okay. Like right now this is a very
small file. So I mean right now I'm
using one space for indentation. So you
can count. So there's one, two, three,
four. So that means this this element li
is actually four levels deep
in a tree. Okay. So when you have HTML
and if you do indent even minimal just
one space you have lots of indentation
that takes space. So so turn that uh
show white space off.
So you can so you can not have
indentation. So my command allows that.
For example, do it again. Do it again.
So now this formatted but no
indentation. So let's try this again.
Make it one line
format and no indentations. You see?
Fantastic. So where's the command? So
press describe key and uh tab f. So
there is a command html commands.el
part of the html mod. So here's the
function
and here's the website open show in
browser. So you can grab the code.
Actually I just updated the code
yesterday. I updated several of them.
Okay. Fantastic and beautiful. Close
that. Close that show today's talk show.
Okay. So we demonstrated CSS, Python,
JavaScript, HTML. Of course there's
Skolan.
Okay. So, so here is Goland. So, you can
grab the code. So, let's what about
let's demo some Goland formatting. Okay.
So, go let's see. So, I have a script
that does find and uh or grip. It does
find string in a directory. Okay. So,
this go line file. So, let's open that.
Okay. So, it's uh showing browser back
to Emacs. Search for pre. So, here is a
code. pop it out. So, here's the code.
Can we run it? Yes, I think so. Let's
try. So, right now, it's searching
searching my web directory.
Uh, let's just make it search uh um talk
shelter. Okay. So, let's paste that.
Delete that. Paste that. Just search for
talk shelter. Okay. Don't don't search
for my entire directory. So, okay. So
file name regular expression file name
extension. Well I mean this is regular
expression to uh filter out. So I want
all HTML files and the file list you can
you can give it a list of specific files
if you want. Uh otherwise you'll just do
the entire directory files in the
directory. So uh show character before
occurrence, show character after
occurrence and so on so on and on and
where is the find string uh yeah here.
So you what do you want to search? You
can search for Haskell. Let's just run
it. Run it. So this is scope language
running in Emacs and uh right now it's
finding all word Hascal in S talk show
directory. So, so done. Okay. So, this
is the result. Now, press a key uh to
show I have a special mark to show the
uh result. So, you can now jump to
occurrences. You can see go to the top
jump jump next occurrence. So, S talk
show this one 2019
uh January 10th. Press enter. Press
enter to open it. Wait, what? Uh okay.
So this this this
code is not being updated. So so I
cannot like jump to enter because I need
to change this this separator in order
to do that. Anyway,
so it shows this code is working. Okay,
that's what that's uh you know that's
what we are doing. It it's demonstrating
that this code is working. Now play it
back. Okay. But now let's demo demo the
formatting. Okay. So uh change that
actually undo. Let's uh yeah. So make it
one line. Now in go if you want to make
it one line you need a a semi semicolon.
Okay. So now press a key.
Uh
wait. Oh yeah. So in go if you want, you
know, if you want to put the one line,
you need a comma here.
Uh
okay. So you need the comma there. Okay.
So make it one line. Press
uh Okay. So then then you need a
semicolon. Okay. Now press a key to
format. It worked actually. Press a key
to format. Wait. Uh
uh go line seven character 29. Line
seven character 29. Expect semicolon
find comma. Okay. I think you need
semicolon here. I forgot. Let's go to
Goland tutorial.
So, Goland tutorial packages import.
Okay. Each line. Yeah. So, you need a
semicolon instead of comma. Okay. So,
so close that. So, comma replace by
semicolon that that that that. Okay.
Now, this is valid co valid code. So,
now press the key to format it. You see
it's beautiful.
So that demonstrate the auto formatting
of coland code and the code is here go
mod open it. So there it is kasago
format buffer and open that link showing
browser. So here's a code you can grab
it. So anyway that's demo of this uh gol
mod close close. Okay, now this uh put
it back
uh put it back syntax showing browser.
Okay, this is fine string in Golan.
Okay.
Okay, I think we demonstrated
uh lots of them. There's also PowerShell
and let's skip it. Okay, powers similar.
Okay, similar. Um but you need to
install this uh module PSS script
analyzer from Microsoft.
Okay.
The auto formatting in PowerShell is not
so great. Is not so great. Anyway,
so that's today's talk show. You got you
know um you got Yeah, that's what I want
to demonstrate.
uh and there's some technical detail for
those of you emac this coders because
uh it's some kind of art to write this
tutorial I mean to write this wrappers
for example uh let's format HTML code
right so for example uh format with
indentation right now we got formatted
how does it work so you can look at code
so describe key tap F. So there it is
HTML format buffer. Jump to the source
code. So you can see you know one of the
source code for that. So this let's copy
it. Make a new buffer. Paste it and then
make it emac mod. Okay. So you can see
it's um
it's it's uh just 40 lines of code
and uh you see you have a option no
indent because by default the deno will
always do indent. So if you don't want
indent you know if you say you know you
cannot do that for for example in deno
there's option indent width. So
basically it's calling the command demo
format. Then a bunch of options. So one
of the option is indent width. You can
say one or two or three but you cannot
say zero. If you say zero it, you know
it uh it's it returns the arrow. Okay.
So but I don't want indentation. How how
can I make it? So what I do is I pass
you know in my eac list this command I
add option no indent. So when no indent
is true you you basically manually uh
write emac this code to remove you know
remove the uh the tab or white space in
front of each new line. So it's a bit
involved because you it's not just
simply delete empty space in front of
each line. That won't that's not
correct. Okay. So you have to so so I'm
you know manually removing the indent in
this um this part of code. And also how
do you call the call the shell command?
This it's a bit tricky you know the
easiest way. Okay let me show you. So
here's some Emacs technicalities.
So in EMAC you can call a shell command.
That's how you call external internal
commands. Okay. So for example, let's go
to the simplest the simplest way to call
a shell command. External command is
just just by the name shell command
function. So this is familiar to
everyone. So once you call shell you can
just type you know ls d or whatever grab
you know like uh let's magnify
control scroll up
okay so cd
web sorry s
info
okay then go to emac for example emacs
directory okay so now you can do duh
it's going to be massive let's Try
again. Duh. You know you can in in in
Unix it's ls you know uh you can do grab
in Unix which whatever you know. So but
if you want to call shell command in
Emacs you can do so easily by this by
this shell command.
But it is not the best way. It is not
the most efficient way because whenever
you call a shell command it actually
start a shell. So it's slower and then
you also got a problem of escaping the
command. For example, if if the command
you want to type is long,
for example, I was searching for
lib gcc. So if you have a long command
and you have lot, you know, if you have
like apostrophe or quote in your file
name, then it become hell because then
you need to in EMAC you need to escape
it. then the in shell you know so
there's actually several levels so
especially if your command involves a
regular expression then it becomes
almost impossible
to
you know for example in EMAC you want to
call the grab command and you need to
pass a regular expression so Emac this
needs to pass that regular expression to
shell uh that's almost you know that's
almost impossible when your regular
expression becomes complicated.
So anyway, so coding shell command is
not always the best. So you have other
ways then you can start to call um
um you can start a external command or
process directly by core process
uh or by core process region or by um or
by start process so or by you know
there's few others and but basically
it's becomes a bit complic uh
complicated actually fairly complicated.
Anyway, I think that's it for today. Uh
so let's see the comments and I think
that's it for today. Let me get my tea.
How many people are watching? Five 10.
Fantastic. Say your comments now and uh
and that'll be it.
Juan Juan says you cannot format Python.
That is correct.
Actually, there's a technical details
about that. uh it is not 100% true
because in Python you could format it a
little bit
you know but um but
actually we have shown it okay so Emacs
close that so let's see what is this
yeah so here is a code for formatting
HTML let's close it we explained about
it so here's today's talk show and For
example, Python.
Let's see. Let's go to Python. So,
can you format code? Yes, you you can a
bit. You know, for example, you know,
this this is different from that. Okay.
So, you can press a key to format it. It
does format but not in the sense of
typical programming languages because
then you have lots of you know
it's not uh because in Python any line
return or space is actually significant
most of them. Okay. So, so in in Python
that's actually a disadvantage of Python
because it the way you format your code
is tied to the semantics of the program.
So it does not in other words it does
not allow you to format your code
arbitrarily.
That is a significant disadvantage
because
because that means there's no it is
basically impossible to auto format your
code. You always have to manually do it.
For example, if statement, you know, if
you are writing this manually, you know,
if uh okay, so if x, you know, minus
three, okay, you cannot just like, okay,
uh then three uh then else
then else um
fi uh five and press a button and it
automatically format that to into that.
You cannot do that. Okay. So in Python
you just have to for each each
everything you type you have to manually
you know type a return. Then here you
can press tab you know you can kind of
press tab to to say what how many levels
of indent you want you know but so
basically
you are doing line by line formatting
and the reason you know that Python
forces you to do that. So extremely
idiotic. Okay. And a lot idiot
programmers in the industry, you know,
lots of them, especially, you know, the
Zumas and the late Malay genen. So since
about 2008,
lots of programming languages they
follow the Python's way because they
think, oh look, you know, Python, you
know, it makes code so easy to read.
But these idiots don't know that if you
do this then it forces you to
to always manually kind of manually deal
with indentation. You cannot do it
automatically like we have shown in this
um
you know in CSS in in in JavaScript in
HTML you know you cannot
uh okay finally let me just show you a
woofam code you know let me show you the
wam automatic indentation in real time
like as you type okay not just that but
also format complicated uh math
expressions okay so wound language
language. There it is. Uh now let's go
to a woofer language code. So let's put
this back. Uh syntax code show in
browser. So go to talk show. Go to the
kasar code
wrame language and uh let's let's just
uh do something like this. Okay.
Beautiful code. Okay. So yeah. So simple
code like that. Copy it. Paste the code.
So let's magnify. Okay, magnify.
Okay, now wait before we do this, let me
show you. Okay, so delete that. Copy the
code over here. Let's make it um frame.
Okay, paste it.
Pop it up. Okay, it looks like that.
Let's make it one line. Okay, copy it.
Now back to Wuam language. Paste it. Can
you see that? Now do you see any tab or
space here? Do you see any indentation?
Let's let's uh turn on the uh white
space.
You see there's no indentation in this.
But however copy it, you paste it, it
became indented automatically.
and and and and what I mean by in real
time auto formatting in real time now
let's see let's adjust this window can
you see can you see the code the the the
automatic
automatic rendering with indentation at
the appropriate places
can you see that that's what I mean by
automatic
formatting on the fly you don't even
know you don't even have to know about
it. Okay. And there's no there is no um
no no tab like no no no tab like how
many indent how many tab versus space
the industrial code idiots like
the Python people python JavaScript
basically all of them. Okay. This
feature is available since 1996.
1996.
Okay. Goland format and and this deno
Golan they didn't come about until 2008.
Okay. And in Wuan language it's like on
the fly you don't you don't need to do
anything. Okay. And plus let me show you
something extra. Okay. First of all
let's run the code so you can see
actually you see you can see the power
of this thing.
Okay. This is called geometric
inversion. We did it live about two
years ago. You know, search for it,
you'll find it on YouTube. Okay. So,
Wuam language. Fantastic. But now, let
me let me show you something. Okay. Now,
I Let's uh O for title.
Okay. Something. Okay. Now, I put a
cursor here. Press shift controlN.
Can you see this fraction?
they format the code into type setting.
Now you see
and now if you try to
adjust uh the window size you can see
they still format the code on the fly
and the watch you know watch this
fraction they still format it in a
sensible way
and you see when when this coordinate
bounds array is long and when it doesn't
fit the window, it actually adds this
dot dot dot. You see that little nice
touch?
Okay, so this is how advanced Wufam
language is. That's why you have to pay
$2,000 for it.
There's a student version, you know,
today if you want, you know, you pay
like $200 a year or something.
Okay. And run the code. There it is.
Okay, so this is Wuir language automatic
for formatting. Okay, on the fly as you
type and not just not just plain text
but also like with fractions and
radicals and even nested you know and
you can see the square brackets. You can
see how it becomes large and you can see
how the syntax highlighting automatic
syntax highlighting. And if I click on
that for example click click click click
click click click click click click it
expands by semantic unit unit. It
expands my selection. Click
click by a semantic unit unit. Okay. For
example this transpose click. You see
now if I click on the fraction numerator
click click
click you see now it's all arguments you
see click click argument then the entire
if statement okay click click click
click now the outer arguments again
click click click click click click the
entire width statement width by the way
is is similar to the programming uh
lists let okay let but constant that's
what width means okay so you can see
this bracket is large uh wherever you
click it highlights the matching
brackets or braces you know
you see that is the power of wam
language that's why it's a magnitude
more advanced beyond
all these
uh all these dedling languages.
Okay, that's it. Um let's see. Showing
browser. Okay, that's it for today's
talk show.
My volume is low. Okay. Uh well, it's
too late.
Okay, bye guys.