hello welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we going going to
code advant of code in wfam language
okay we're going to finish it as fast as
possible maybe 40 minutes to an hour
this is my keyboard Kinesis 360 ultimate
hacking keyboard
glove 0 keyboard fantastic these are the
keyboard I recommend okay so let's let's
begin so uh Advent of code let's show
the
screen problem number seven so we did
number one two six and not not the part
two some of them uh we haven't done the
part two yet but I'm thinking I'm just
going to do all the Advent of code the
first part first then uh then let's do
the part two because part one the
problems are open to everyone you can
see the problem at the end of a code
2023 okay and uh okay so let's begin if
you are here say hi okay if you like my
stuff
donate okay so Advent of code let's
start wam language
begin
okay new panel 1 + one please show me
one + 1 equals to two
Okay and uh we need to magnify okay so
that's good let's
uh magnify the window okay so WF
language Advent of
code 2023 number seven day seven
can you share the link to your Discord
server I couldn't find ons.info okay go
to kali. info it's obvious or just
search for you can probably find it K
Google Kali
Google uh Kali Discord
okay uh yeah okay so well let me let me
just paste the link okay you seea
code uh and uhar blogs so many blogs on
Twitter on El musk X and uh there it is
Discord number six hello okay what
random code number day seven okay let's
begin now answer the question okay I'm
wondering you know I'm going to do there
are like V of code up to up to 17 or
something so I'm going to finish them
all okay but I'm going to do them like
one per week so I don't want to like
congest them all in one month you know
one per week so that we continuously
have some code exercise to do for the S
HW show so you know I'm wondering so one
one of the day I want to do a um you
know that that the mangen Zuma thing
like quiet you know like there's a word
like tickle your senses you just quietly
talk talking and make some
noises so do you like do you guys like
to see that not not today today I'm
going to talk uh and explain things but
you know I I'm guessing down the road
we're going to do one like that no
talking just like uh code okay Advent of
code day seven your all expenses paid
trip turns out to be one way five
minutes right in in an Airship can you
see
it uh let's see oh okay okay so you this
window needs to
be uh there
okay so your all expensive pay trip
turned out to be one way five minutes
riding an Airship at this is cool
Airship it drops you off at the edge of
vast desert and uh descends back to
island island did you bring the parts
you turn around to see an elf completely
covered in the white clothing wearing
goggles and riding a large camel did you
bring the pots she asked again louder
this time you aren't sure what parts
she's looking for you are here to figure
out why the sand
stopped the parts for the sand yes come
with me I'll show you she beckons you
onto the
camel after riding a bit across the
Sands of desert island you can see what
looks like very large rocks covering
half of the
Horizon the elf explains that the rocks
are all along the part of the desert
island that is directly above island
island making it hard to even get there
normally they use big machines to move
the rocks and filter the sand but the
machines have broken down because desert
island recently stopped receiving the
parts they need to fix the
machines
you have already assumed it'll be your
job to figure out why the part stopped
when she asked if you can help you agree
automatically because the journey will
take a few days she offers to teach you
the game of Camo
cards here here comes the payload Camo
cards is sort of similar to poer except
it's designed to be easier to play while
riding a
camo in cam cards you you get a list of
hands a list of hands and your goal is
to order them based on the strength of
each hand
okay a hand consists of five cards labed
one of AK
qjt 9876
54302 okay someone is knocking the door
hold on a second I got a um I got a be
back okay got some errand to
do so I'm back
uh so let's
see where was I so Advent of code so
camo so Camo
cards uh game of Camo cards so you got a
list of
hands your goal is to order them based
on the strength of the hands a hand
consists of five cards five cards each
one labeled one of them one of these uh
letters Also let's write it
down can you see yes
okay
okay something like that problem
description uh list of
hand
so so these are the
alphabets the relative strength of each
card follows this
order okay so a is better than k k is
better than Q okay a k q j okay a s s uh
king queen
Jack uh and T okay they got a t where a
is the highest of the two okay so yeah
so back to the problem so every hand is
is exactly one
type okay so there's no suits of clubs
and hearts and
stuff so let's copy let's copy the
problem Des uh
description so show in browser so every
hand is exactly one type from strongest
to weakest to
weakest weakest they are five of a kind
Jesus five of a kind okay so there's
more than one kind five of a
kind where all all five cards have the
same label okay four of a kind where all
four cards have the same label and one
card has a different label okay full
House where three cards have the same
label and the remaining two cards share
different
label share a different label okay three
of a kind where three cards have the
same label and the remaining two cards
are each different from any other cards
in the hand okay TT t98 three of a kind
Full House okay Full House three of a
kind two
pair where two cards share one label two
other cards share a second
label and the remaining cards has has a
third label okay two pair okay and one
pair where two cards share one label and
the other three cards have a different
label okay that's one single pair then a
high card where all cards labels are
distinct okay so every hand is exactly
one type from strongest to weakest they
are so every hand is exactly one of
these okay so one of each one of this is
called a type ordered from strongest to
weakest okay
okay okay
so so this is kind of odd because it
appears it doesn't covers all
possibilities for example what
[Music]
about what about flush right like 1 2 3
4 five they don't have that but anyway
so five of a kind four of a kind Full
House three of a
kind two pairs one pair and uh and
nothing okay hands are primarily ordered
based on
type for example every Full House is
stronger than three of a kind yes of
course if two hands have the same type a
second ordering rule takes effect start
by comparing the first card in each
hand start by comparing the first card
in each hand if these cards are
different the hands with a stronger
first card is considered
stronger okay so a second order okay
start by comparing first card is
something on my
mind okay so if these cards are so start
by comparing the first card in each hand
that's odd if these cards are
different the hand with a stronger first
card is considered
stronger okay if the first card in each
hand have the same label however they
move on to considering the second card
in each hand if they differ the hand
with the higher second card wins
otherwise continue with the third card
in each hand then the fourth okay that's
kind of odd I mean that's not
conventional uh ranking because they
simply compare the first card as opposed
to the rank of the you know four of a
kind four of a kind you might have
a s as as you know as the for of a kind
or you might have a king So in that case
the king should be
um High higher ranked but that's not the
case here they simply order by the card
number I mean by the first card and
second card and so on which makes the
problem kind of easier I
suppose because you just order them by
um by kind of alphabetical is that
right T okay T stand for 10 actually 10
9 876 5 4 32
okay
so so you so you got a least of oh God I
touched
my you got a list of
um hands your problem your job is just
order them okay so 3332 and 2 a a AA are
both for the kind but 3332 is stronger
because it's the first card because the
first card is stronger okay idiotic
similarly
77888 and
777 88 are both full house but
77888 is stronger right because the
third number eight is greater than seven
okay that's so far so
good to play cam cards you are given a
list of hands and they corresponding bit
oh God it's more complex so to play cam
cards you are given a list of hands okay
list of hands and they corresponding bid
so that's some kind of payload your
puzzle input okay let's copy the P
input so far so good am I doing
good
okay so this is the
input
and you have a weight attached to it for
each hand
okay so Co the corresponding bid okay
this example shows five hands each hand
is followed by its bit
amount each hand wins an amount equal to
its bit multiplied by its rank oh
multiplied by its rank where the weakest
hand gets rank one and the second
weakest hand gets rank
two okay so you order them so in this
case you got 1 two three four five five
hands so you order them by Rank and
uh multiply by the rank so basically the
multiplier is just ordinals like 1 2 3 4
five okay and so on okay so multiply by
the bit amount okay and so on up to the
strongest hand because there are five
hands in this example the strong
strongest hand will have rank five and
its bit will be multiplied by five okay
so the first step is to put the hands in
order so that's the first job rank them
by order of the
hands okay
so let's see
so some kind of explanation to confirm
that we understand the problem
correctly so KK 677 and KT jjt are both
two
pair okay their first card both have the
same label but the second card of this
is stronger K versus T
yeah
so so the first one is stronger so wait
they are two of a kind okay I mean both
two pair okay so KT
jjt gets rank two and K k6 77 gets rank
three okay the higher the rank means
they are more
Superior right okay so yeah so if you
want to maximize it you the bigger the
bit hopefully you have the better hand
for the bigger bit bits okay so now you
can determine the total winning of this
set of hands by adding up the result of
multiplying each hands bit with its rank
Okay blah blah blah so the total winning
in this example are that
okay so
now so here is the puzzle solution
um I mean the
the so 664 64 I mean
6440 is a solution to
this example
input okay you rank them then you m
multiply by the rank okay multiply the
bit by the rank and then you sum them up
okay so find the rank of every hand in
your set what are the total winnings
okay let's start to code this problem
it's already 24 minutes
okay say hi okay say hi so okay
let's see uh well I'm not going to check
so let's see the problem
so you get a Tex so let's start coding
wam language so you got
input
um okay so the input
is something like that
okay
um okay
so
so uh you first want to order
them okay you you first of all you split
the input by
um split by a new line
so well let's not let's let's do this
okay list of hands
equals to that okay so let's run it in
wam
language that's right so they are
strings so far and uh okay now the bit
the bits you need to turn them to number
eventually so okay so the first job is
to rank
them so how do you rank them
uh okay so you rank them basically you
want to sort it you want to sort it so
for example let me show you okay so for
each
line you know let's not do this so for
each of the input do we have uh
refresh yeah so we have the input here
so basically you're just going to order
this list okay trivial so the key of the
problem is finding the order ordering
function
okay uh and how do you going to order
them let's
see you want to so okay funy
so five of a
kind so this is basically Bally this is
the English description of the ordering
function five of a
kind five of a kind okay that's you know
that's a bit odd because there's more
than four kinds typically you a normal
card cards you only have four kinds so
you got five of a kind four of a
kind then you got full house which is
better than three of a Kind okay so
basically F three of a kind four of a
kind five of a kind kind and you got a
full house in
between then you got pair okay so the
first job we can organize the Sorting
problem determine which one is it is
by
sort so we can write a sorting function
okay so this is this
is not a trivial problem trivial in the
sense that you can code it right away
you have to think
about so as a
card a hand is a sequence of five
characters okay five characters you want
to
determine if they repeat you know like
five of a kind okay
so let's think about how do you approach
I mean I mean there are so many ways
so five of a
kind four of a kind three of a
kind okay so full house is also three of
a kind except that the other one the
other two numbers is a pair is the same
okay
so so so one of the key is you determine
how many if this sequence of five
characters they have
repetition okay
so then you have two pair which is like
two of a kind then one pair
is one of of a
Kind
yeah wait wait two pair is Two of a Kind
one pair is also two of a kind they
differ is that you have one of them is
two of two of
Kinds
okay and the the last one is all
distinct
okay
God so you want to yeah so you want to
sort them
uh you want to sort
them oh God this is not so
easy okay uh hold on a second I'll be
right
back
okay I'm
back so now we are into this salort
problem we need to sort this
thing not so
easy sort okay see yeah so you can sort
them you need a sorting function sorting
function is
that
so you
classify a
hand by this one two 3 four five six
seven seven
categories so you
classify this sequence of
five characters into one of these seven
categories one two 2 three four five six
seven okay seven
categories and how do these seven
categories
differ they differ
by so the repetition of a card okay all
of them the same then the second is four
of them the same these two are clear
examples no
ambiguity then you
have repetition of three characters in
that case it's either Full House or
three of a kind okay repetition of three
characters
okay let's let's write it
out given a hand a
sequence of
five
chars
they are one of the seven
types okay so one of the type is all
same
CHS that's called uh that's called five
of a
kind
okay five same characters four same
characters okay that's called four a
kind
then three same characters okay so in
the case of three same characters there
are two
cases one
is and a pair okay this is called Full
House right is that how they call it in
in card games full house okay okay
then no
pair
so this is called three of a
kind okay
then then you have the case
of two same
characters
okay and this is called two
pair then you have the case of two sem
characters
but one pair
okay okay so you can classify of them
into okay then the last one
is no CH are the
same it's called high
card okay so you have these cases and in
this particular ordering
so
so you
determine so there are seven types of
them
seven seven okay there are seven types
so each sequence of five characters
belongs to one of these
right and uh
then so you know basically what you want
to do is
sort sort by
okay so sort by is a wam language
function that that allows you to
sort uh by a particular function
okay like that okay so you want to sort
by list of hands and the second argument
is a
function okay something like like that
okay so this is basically what you want
to do and uh the key problem is to write
this
function so this function how we going
to write this function
um right you you saw this list of
hands right so you you saw this so you
got a list of ordered hands right so but
the key is writing this
function so this function we take x x is
one of this
string okay so but so first of all we
can
say we can say for example split string
by
space
okay then
something you you wait you split
it okay then you take the first
part okay so that gets
you that gets you just the sequence of
characters the hand okay then
then what you're going to do with that
so you know in fact we can just run this
so I can show you as we go so we run
this okay select all paste run it so you
can see if we do it this
way
so we got this
order this is simply alha alha numerical
order you see based on the first
character then the second character so
three comes first K comes second Q comes
fourth then T
right right so we have to fix this
ordering function
so so we get you so first of all we get
the first part the card
then so let's do this
okay the module
okay
hand hand string equals to that okay
then the expression so what you going to
do with that so the hand so okay so
then you know
so so what you're going to do with it so
you got a sequence of five characters so
you want to
[Music]
determine if it repeats and how how many
times first of
all uh let's see let's see the sord by
function so the sord by function
actually can take a sequence of
functions
fantastic this is ex this is the power
of wam language extremely useful so the
F first function we are simply
compare how
many
repetitions yeah let's do it the easy
way let's forget about efficiency let's
do it the most simplest way this is the
the highlight of wfam language because
it allows you to prototype and solve get
the answer as fast as
possible then you can worry about uh
efficiency and you know what data
structure to use and so on so so first
of all you need to know so you see sold
by you can have a bunch of function so
the first let's start to write some
function so one of the function is to
determine if
it's five same cards or not okay so
given a
string how
many repetition of a Char that's so you
want to write that function okay
so this is a string you want to
determine how many repetition in a in
the in the card I mean in the in the
sequence so once you know the
repetition basically you almost soled
it so here is zero same
chart okay so once you know the number
of repetition you almost started it then
you need
to yeah that's
right so the first job is to find the
function that Returns the repetition of
a string okay so let's
easy let's query
for any string
function and uh repeat okay
repeated string let's see what that is
repeated
string repeated string is an internal
symbol used for formatting okay that's
not what we
want so we have to think about it so
given a string we want to
find what is a
maximal repetition okay now we
you know in WF language the best way to
find the function is
to ask the most logical question you
want to find a way to ask the most
logical question once you got that then
then the function name is almost exactly
that so what we want to know is that
given a string we want to find the
maximon
character repetition okay so the words
are
occur
repeat something like that okay let's
see string take string string split
string Place string part string
match string
extract string con 10 string
cases search query
string okay so how so how do you find
the
the now in most other languages the
Primitive way to do this is that you can
use a hash table so you go through the
string C by character for each character
you push it into a hash table with that
character as a
key then you go on to the next character
if that character is already in in the
hash table in a dictionary you just add
one to the value if not then you create
a new key right once you
done you have a
dictionary
of keys and values the keys are the
other character in the string the value
is how many times they
occur okay so if you build this
dictionary if you can build this
dictionary then oh yeah that that's
obvious way to do it in most languages
once you build this dictionary then the
ranking becomes it's all softed the
ranking is simply the
maximum number the the maximum value in
this in this
dictionary okay if that's a tie for
example four house and three of a kind
then you find the second maximal value
in this in this
dictionary so in the case of Full House
the second highest value would be
two so and uh in a three of a kind the
second highest value is one so Full
House
wins right so once you build this this
dictionary the problem is solved the
ranking problem is solved oh okay
so so that tells us all we want is like
um in the WAN language you just need a
function that returns frequency
frequency is the word let's see f r e q
u okay
um you know there there is a
um
allow frequency range word frequency
character frequency let's see word
frequency give the frequency of word in
text okay so there is something like a
character
frequency okay so
we let's see
occur
let's see if there's any
uh
what
OC U okay there's
no occur in wam language so there is
Char okay so these are a bunch of
function names containing the word
character okay so we want the character
counts that's what we
want that's right okay fantastic this
gives us exactly what we want it returns
a
dictionary
okay character counts let's say let's
let's say uh let's say a given example
okay character count that
fantastic
exactly exactly so that's what that's
the function we want so the character
counts yeah so we
want so once we have this dictionary we
want to you you want to get a list of
the okay let's try
it let's say equals to that okay so x x
is a dictionary and let's see what
happens if you just sort
it okay if you just sort it it returns
it sorts by the
value right
so if you simply sort it it sorts by the
value of the
dictionary from minimal to maximum okay
so for example let's do this
uh so for example let's do sort
at
that okay but now let's say
5555 right
so then you just do
Max let's see what is Max Max versus max
value what's the difference max value
gives the maximum value of f with
respect to s
x okay maximum value applies a function
so that's not what we want you just want
Max
Max Returns the
maximum yeah of a
least okay so you can
see that's
it okay so we have a function so so now
we yeah character counts returns a
dictionary then you just return Max okay
wait character count then
sort okay that's basically that's almost
that's
it let's just try what happens here
okay so
now table
form
okay
so there it is you see the last one is
the highest
ranked exactly that's what how we want
it because the last one if we count by
the by the index of the least the last
one would be five the multiplier for
this one is five so you just 5 * 6 8
4 so here we have three of a kind and
here is also three of a kind now they oh
there's a trick so they they are equal I
mean they are both three of a kind and
now to determine their ranking you sld
by the first character right like the
the problem
description
so Q comes before T I mean q is Queen T
is 10 so Q should be
right Q should be at the bottom but
anyway so here's three of a kind three
of a kind then here's Two of a Kind this
is two
pairs okay so let's
see
okay so let's see let's try this okay so
let's try if we can do this
sort sort a
list 3 4
five
three now sort by default is uh is
what ascending or descending uh sort
code with three arguments okay so you
need okay so increase it SS from small
to large okay
so now
three Now by default it should
um okay so for example this
one 325 that's
correct it by default the sword will use
the first element in the list if that's
equal it will use the second element
automatic
ially so back to our problem we
can that's right we can that's right so
we can just yeah so this actually
works so we don't want to we don't want
Max we want to
sort
that's right so what if
we now let's try to sort again but this
time have bunch of
um so we don't care what the key is okay
so we don't care what the key is let's
just say k okay we only care about the
number
so uh okay almost done so
Sal increase okay so they
increase
okay can you reverse it you
can right you can just reverse
it so you want to do that okay so you
want
to okay how how you guys doing simple
first is a good
mentality hello Aris Aristocrat
coffee okay uh very
good very smooth so far so
now
you character counts G gives you a
dictionary then you you sort it
but you want to reverse okay so you
don't
want let's look up the
documentation there is a op option to
reverse
them instead of calling reverse yourself
because then it's less optimal I
suppose okay but where's the
option
oh there is no option for sort how funny
what am I
correct wow there's no option for sort
so the proper ways you simply revert
it
uh what about this order gives okay so
that gives
order uh what about sort
by oh wait there's Reverse sord
by interesting so there's also Reverse
sord by so we are using sord
by
Aries I'm surprised there is no sword
what do you mean there's no salort there
is salort there is
salort uh
okay we almost done just some of the
details so let me just concentrate
okay so we got we
got character counts which is a
dictionary okay character counts is a
dictionary okay then you sort it now you
don't want to you don't want to in Inc
incre order you want to you want them to
be in decrease order okay so instead of
sort you use reverse
sort it's interesting it doesn't have an
option for sort but rather it just have
a different function reverse
sort okay so instead of a sort you say
reverse
sort
okay so you use reverse sort so when you
sort them a dictionary the it basically
just sort by the value okay
so so we can try
uh okay so we
can try
this um okay so we need to
some what is
this so let's see let's say
four
three two okay so what happens if
you so
three let's say five okay then let's say
four and the second value so this and
this are the same now the second
value so this one let's say
four so this will come F this will come
first then this then this okay let's try
it oh we got a new
here uh
what oh we need to wait
what reverse
sort uh reverse
sord
reverse sort input is the least right so
input is the
least and uh
so why is
it oh because we are using key the same
key it combines them so we don't want
that
yeah and let's say a b c okay and
actually a
a
b
c
okay
so five comes first that's
right that's the
highest you know five in a kind then
when there's a tie four comes before
three that's what we want that's right
so this
works okay
so so back to here so we
so we get the
dictionary then we reverse
sord and we don't need to
Max that's right that's it okay I think
that's
it try
it
yeah let's see this should be correct oh
wait wait this is not
correct now this is actually
wrong so wait so you get a hand then you
get a DI
dictionary then you reverse s the
dictionary sold by this
function sort
by sort by reverse sort then you
want
okay now you want to turn a dictionary
to a list of its values
okay
so you want to turn a dictionary like
that to just values I believe that's
normalized okay so I believe
that's it
no that's
not normalize give the normalized vector
okay that's not
uh
standardize
no there is okay so let's go to my wol f
Language tutorial you can download for
free just search foram Language tutorial
you can go there download for free but
right now we are looking
for uh we are looking for how do you get
the values of a dictionary so dictionary
in wam language is called Association
okay Association
list uh and uh and then Association list
Association normal okay not normalize
normal
that's right so you want to apply this
normal to
here uh
okay so you
get q q q no that's still wrong yeah you
got a worse
so if you say Max actually that works
out yeah so
wait
okay very close you know we so here is a
solution basically just this function
but we need to trick this a
bit
so you can so this problem is
mostly solved by the sord by now the
sord by you can have one single function
that determines which you know element
is greater than the other or you can
have a sequence of
functions which are used in
turn if there's a tie
so for us now the problem is that we can
right now we have this one single
function that determines which come
first but our function currently doesn't
doesn't work for tie so we we so we need
to resolve the
tie so we can either continue to modify
this single function or we can create
create a separate
function uh but I think a single
function will
work however we failed uh because that's
why I'm doing all
this you know that's why I'm testing out
this this reverse sword and stuff I
think single function will
work
so we have to think about this okay
think is the best way so reverse
sorts wait why do you even need reverse
sword you don't even need reverse
sword you see
yeah you don't even need reverse
sort this Max will
do
but but then there's a tie okay so that
is why you need reverse
sort so let's see we got so many
confusing
now yeah so reverse sword gives you
these
then
you reverse sword in
normal so I don't understand why is
this
why is this not
working this I was thinking this should
be one shot solution this should do it
but
no
okay so let's think about sort
by
you see we can do this and
uh so we'll map this
function
to
okay
so wait why is it
still they shouldn't
be okay let's let's try more testing
here
so a
hand
oh this is
wrong why the normal we our normal is
wrong why is it not
work wait normal
works oh you don't want you don't want
the key you got to remove the key that's
why so we want we need to REM remove the
key
okay so let's go back to Association
list of uh get all keys there it is
Keys okay
so let's back to the one shot
solution reverse sorts then just
Keys
okay
uh no we don't want Keys we want values
okay values
so that's right say so let's look at
this
311 that's right that's what we want
values at reversal that's it okay so
here's our uh
uh here's our
solution
okay no it's not
right oh God what
something is wrong
here let's
try
this that's what we want
okay
[Music]
so that's what we want oh then there's a
length issue okay you see so you got
this versus this there's a length
issue then you just pad it okay
you just pad the
Leist yeah
okay for
example pad list n and X
okay P list by Z
zero uh
by five 1 2 3 4 five five
cards pad by zero that's what we want
pad right okay so this is the function
we
want so you just
add
pad
right that by zero okay so this is one
shot
solution
yeah no it's still wrong
God oh you forgot wait n yeah you forgot
to add
that's
right no it's still
wrong God what is
wrong
okay oh right you need to pad it before
you sort that's right so that's right so
you need to pad it
first okay so you need
[Music]
to you need
to get the values first then you pad it
then you applies the reverse sword okay
essentially it's one more
time no
God
okay so what is going
on oh wait you cannot no uh the order is
wrong okay
so so you get a dictionary first then
you then you need to reverse
sord
then you get uh
wait you get a dictionary like that then
you reverse sort so the so the biggest
value comes to the
front uh or you can apply the value get
just the
values right you just get the values
then you reverse sort them
wait you just you get the
values then then you pad
them then you reverse sort why can't
this
work that seems right
so see
so this is essentially the criteria for
the hand you have three of a kind then
you
have two of a
kind
yeah okay so then you just sort
by then you you just sld by this order
so oh God why is
it let's test this
okay okay let's let's trite it out
so
by let's see how it
does sold by that
did it sort it correctly yes 421 is the
best four of a kind then two of a kind
then 3 three then
32 that's right so this is the correct
sorting this is the correct sorting so
why is our
code doesn't
work reverse sord
get the
dictionary then reverse sort the values
of the
dictionary then get the
values then you pad okay
so
okay so you want
to that
okay this should be the answer but why
is it not
correct oh it is correct 555
wait
555 3 of a Kind QQQ is three of a
kind then
then JJ TT is two pairs then KK is one
pair this is correct but there's still
missing
something okay once we do that what if
they what if we have two full house okay
it's fantastic now now we just use
utilize the sord by second function so
so for example here is one
function you see now we just need the
list of functions so this is the first
function the second function is simply
to is simply to uh so them
by by alha you know by alha numerical
order of the string
so
yeah so the second function is just
um let's
see alphabetic
order
okay
[Music]
so so we want the function now that
given a
string well given two strings it
uh
alphabetic order okay that's what we
want but
uh alphabetic sort that's the function
we want so the elements of list
into alphabetical
order
okay alphabetic sord then you have lexo
lexical graphic sort what about
alphabetic order
close you know we already solved the
ranking
problem right now
we we have
solved the ranking problem of the seven
types of
hand right now the problem is that if
two hands have the same type you know
for for example both of them are four of
a kind how do you resolve that now
according to this problem Advent of code
you just you just SOL them by you rank
them by the first character then the
second character okay
so which is easy to do you know we
already have this you know several
functions alphabetic sort but the
but given our framework the way we
solved it we need to put that
into as a second function okay yeah the
second
function okay let's just let's just do
this okay so the second function is just
uh that's
right first chart
okay
let's see let's see if that
works I think
that's oh okay so you need uh this needs
to be a
function okay so
555 and QQQ which one is better
Q should be better than t Okay
so H yeah because our function here is
so you
get glad to see it working might help to
do some tdsd bugging is there a way to
step through the
execution
um
usually you don't do that in wolam
language okay um yeah but you can uh hea
juper says I have a question why is
pixel based scroll in emac so laggy on
Windows I don't know don't use that you
know some you know you know there's
people saying they want pixel based
score I never get exactly what's that
for why do you need that you know you
know you score by Char character that's
fine why do you need the pixel base you
know like there several packages over
the years trying to fix that I don't I
never get why you need that I don't
recommend it because it makes emac much
more complex to to kind of do that kind
of thing you know go with Native you
know whatever the native system
framework is the
best so emac
just by the way it is over the over the
over the past 30 40
years they don't natively support pixel
pixel scrore so don't do it you don't
need it when you know I don't get it
when do you why do you need the pixel
score like why why do you need the pixel
score by pixels I don't I don't
totally don't see the
need okay so yeah I don't know about
that
answer to that so anyway we are almost
solved the problem but we seems to be
stuck now it's 90
minutes uh we almost solved the problem
but now we so
actually the best way to solve the
problem is actually just think instead
of just like talking and trying and
stuff you just I just need to really
just think about this so so we are using
sort by now in W from language sort by
allows you to have a list of functions
if the first function comes out a number
that's a tie then you use a second
function right
so so right now we are using the second
function the first function simply gives
us the type of hand you know maybe Full
House or four a kind five a kind you
know that solves the problem but in case
there's a tie you know let's say both of
them are four of a kind what you going
to do I mean let's say both of them are
you know Full House what you going to do
I mean all you know three of a kind so
so that so then we use a second
function now according to Advent of a
code when there's a tie you should
simply go by the alphabetical you know
the lexical graphic order you compare
the first character
then the second character okay
so okay so we can do that you know we
use the list of functions and our second
function is simply return the the
sequence of characters
right but however here is a trick so you
you want
this this needs to be a
function but you need you need the sense
reverse first here because
[Music]
normally or let's not use reverse sord
here let's not use reverse
sord then we we have the same
order uh
wait so if you don't use reverse
sword then you got it wrong again what
QQQ now then you got a wrong why
set
um
where's the pad the pad is
here
yeah I'm getting tired the
it's three of a kind three of a
kind this is totally wrong
again oh you do need reverse sord here
let
see because that's about the yeah you do
need reverse
sord
oh yeah so
then
right then you just okay got
it yeah so so that's right so do we have
Reverse sord
by yeah we do Reverse sld by how
fantastic
so so actually a so we so it's not
totally lexical graphic sort because you
have the situation
where a is greater than k k is greater
than Q so they are not alphabetical at
all so right so alphabetically a would
be you know
first
then Q would come after J but it's not
the case here Q comes before J
so oh yeah so you the order is
um so you have so you need to write the
function now the problem okay okay we we
know what's a problem it's not
alphabetical at all we need to write a
function some kind of ordering
representation
that that represents this specific order
a comes before k k comes before q q
comes before J J comes before T okay and
first of all based on first character if
there's a tie then second character Okay
so
we need a function to represent this
order
so so okay yeah got another
problem
yeah yeah so our function works so far
the problem is this part we need to fix
this part okay for example we let's
delete
that okay if we don't do that
then and then we got this
you know so far it's pretty good three
of a kind three of a
kind three of a
kind two pairs one pair and and random
right we got a solution but the problem
is now there's a tie you see this 555
three a kind and QQQ three kind
so in this case Q comes before
T that's
correct
okay but what what if uh what if we you
know what if our
problem has another pair such
that such that for example let's
add uh for example let's add another
pair so Q q q let's say kk let's say uh
KKK okay then let's say another pair IJ
a AA okay a
AA on j4 okay
so let's add this thing you
know so for example if we have a this
input
this input then then uh
we list of hands then we apply our list
of
hands okay so we can
see this is three of a
kind a AA three of a kind KK K three of
a kind
QQQ but according to the problem which
one comes first a comes
first then K and then Q okay that works
out okay so let's just change the input
a
bit so let's put Q here okay so
now
copy you
see now this is our
sorted
solution but you see the order is not
correct when there's a tie so a should
be first then K then Q okay so right now
our problem is just create a second
sorting function now and and the problem
is to
represent a function that represent the
ranking of a sequence of five characters
such
that the the first character is by this
order so how do you represent
that
so so let's say A Single Character you
know forget about the sequence of
characters let just say a representation
of order of one single
character and uh you want to you want
them to be ranked like that so if it's a
digit then it's very easy okay the
larger
digit uh
wins okay
so but if it's not a digit
then so a single so so we can you know
we can hard code it but let's think
about the interesting problem how do you
represent an order
by this particular thing I need to go to
the
bathroom H we are almost done but you
know of cold always always gets more
complex almost two hours now and I need
to go to the
bathroom how many people watching
five
eight so far am I doing good do I make
sense so you need
um find a function let's say a single
character that represents
um I don't want to continue I I I I need
to uh go to the bathroom and and uh walk
let let me take a break then let me just
go to the
bathroom
e
I'm back now I forgot my
[Music]
glasses
okay okay
so it's back to the problem so the
problem right now is this okay let me
let's write it out because when you
write things out you give
you better thoughts
okay
a function the problem is to have a
function that
represents an
ordering okay ordering of this nature
okay
so given two
CHS the by the above okay so that that
is the that is a problem we write we
need to have a function that kind of do
this
so so so the function uh might
be
F you
know f um Char one Char
2 okay so the problem is to have a
function F chart one chart two that
represent an
ordering like
this so for
example if the function is
given uh a and
uh let's say let's try something
interesting uh JQ okay
J
Q it should return in this order okay so
how do you want to
represent I mean if J
is it should uh so JQ it should
return
less something like that so because J is
less than Q now how do you want to it's
a bit confusing
because greater or less so let's see if
this order Q is greater than J okay
so so let's rename the
function greater
okay so
if okay so we re we name our function
greater so greater
JQ returns
force greater
QJ return
true okay we want a function like that
uh okay and how do you do
that so this function takes uh two
arguments each one is a single
character
uh okay so let's see four
people uh so how do you
represent order okay so we have sort
function we have
sort sort by reverse sord and Reverse
sord by let's look at sord
okay
so takes ordering function P okay
so
[Music]
so takes an ordering function P okay
so so we want so this is our
problem but however to use this function
in in our s by
algorithm in the way we work work on
this
problem is that we
need the function
to
okay so
actually we can we can have a hash
table okay so here is what we
do we simply have a hash table that
returns
uh
a is let's
say something like that okay so
9 and 10 J becomes 11 that's right oh
God this is so simple now 12 13 a is
just 14 fantastic so we want
that okay so we want a function we want
a
function that turns a
CH into a number okay so something like
that and uh the 987 they return
themselves okay
so so yeah we want a function that
Returns the character so so first of all
given a
string uh let me just type it out so
because when I type it out I
know we get clarity of thinking so we
got a sequence of characters we want to
turn it into a sequence of numbers by
this hash algorithm okay so let's encode
this hash algorithm
okay now emx power Marco keyboard
Marco record Mar
delete that that that that
okay and uh done okay then we
do that uh
okay there it
is okay
so this is what we want
okay we we we want this okay so this is
going to be a
hashtable a dictionary okay so and uh
the these are
the uh
wait
okay let me do
this
wait okay so record hash record the key
Mar
again
now
fantastic okay we turn those characters
into a
number this is our hash
table uh
sort table okay s table equals
to now this is Association so the way
you do Association a hash table in wam
language
is
right what did we
do okay so
table
Association
okay so this is how you do
Association in wam language okay so
let's go back to here so table this is
a Association yeah okay so some of this
is
wrong because you got the the arrow
incorrect wam doesn't like the
that so you need to have that
yeah so this is our
association and uh let's see what what
happens if you s
them yeah you so them by number by the
value correct I mean the syntax is
correct okay so now this is our
association table
okay um okay let's remove that let
Association table let's move it here
somewhere this is uh test stuff okay so
and now we don't need
this okay so let me just quickly code
this so so you can understand what I'm
doing so this
function does this okay so now
we so we have a
function so we need this function to be
part of the sort by now the sort by is
the second argument is the list of
functions if the first function is a
tie you know then you use the second
function so the second function will be
the second function will be you get the
hand so this is a hand
then then it's it's it's a um it's a
sequence of five characters it's a
string then you say string to list okay
um split
string
okay let's
say okay you want to turn a string into
a a characters
so what is that
function let's see
characters gives a list of characters in
string so that's what you want so not
not split string okay so
you want that for example that turn a
list of charact a string to a list of
characters each one is a string of
Single Character okay so that's a
function so
[Music]
you so that's right so you basically
just do it here okay
okay once you got that list of single
characters then you remap them into by
this dictionary okay by this table so
you so for each
character how do you do it uh okay so I
don't know so let's look up the my wfam
language
Association you have Association
you have a character you want to return
the key so so let's see what you do so
let's see sort table and
uh a let's see
what does that work Works
fantastic okay let's say you have J
works now what if you have lowercase j
it doesn't work okay so you make sure
you have got a case match okay so this
is how you get
um get a single character to their
ordering value okay so this is how you
get a single character to the ordering
value now we need to turn this I mean
this is a hardcoded case so we need to
turn this into applying this to the hand
of sequence of characters so what you do
is
[Music]
you okay so you need to write a function
so let me show you so this this this
would
be function let's
say
ch ch okay so that gives you a number
that represent this characters ordering
function okay so so you have this
function now you want to apply it
to to a list of characters okay this
function you want to map it to a list of
characters which is
this okay this let me show you okay so
for example let's
try so this part is just uh
hand for
example
QQQ 33
Okay uh did it work
no
uh
what oh fun uh wait function this is
repeated
wait yeah so
C
oh okay so wait
so
let's say QQ
q33
okay that's
right that's
right so so this is a function
so okay so we got that function we just
need to put it here okay the second
function is going to
be this
okay copy
that and that's it that's our code let's
let's evaluate the whole thing that's
our solution to this problem I
think please part expression X cannot be
used as part specification we got uh we
got a
um oh yeah so we got a yeah so you need
a function here so um yes that's right
so use
something
uh that's right so we need
this
yeah and let's it's getting very complex
here but I'm not sure you know what I'm
doing but I know what I'm
doing okay so
anyway that should be the
solution
fantastic it is correct you see a AA
three of a kind then KKK three of a kind
QQQ three of a kind but they got ordered
correctly a comes last because it's
heaviest then AK king queen then 555
then KK 77 two pairs then
JJ and
TT uh JJ and TT two pairs KK and 77 two
pairs but which one is ordered first I
mean i j k k is greater than 10 so K
comes first
correct and the last one is nothing
random you know no no pirs and nothing
so but here we have to double check the
KK versus KT what is the original KK
versus versus the ktk
so KK versus
KT which one comes
first
well so KK versus KT KK comes KK is
heavier which is
correct yeah so we actually we reorder
this two you see 28
220 it becomes 220 and 28 that's correct
so this is this is correct what we have
to do now is
we we just uh multiply
them uh all we have to do is like this
okay let's
see um
what yeah we we don't want okay so let's
remove the table form okay so we want
that
uh map index
it okay we map a function to the list of
ordered hand
and uh what function we want want map it
to we okay so
we map function yeah so we map index
so okay very easy okay so let's do it
here because I have competions map index
I mean because emac is more efficient to
manipulate and stuff
so
okay so we want to map a function to
that and the function is going to be two
arguments uh and the second argument is
the
index
right okay so the second argument is the
so and what does it do exactly you you
want to multiply the index by
the by the bit number okay by the bit
the second part okay
so so why is the index
okay so what you do is
you
index
times
um index the first part of it remove the
Leist okay so you get the index which is
the
rank times the bit so the bid is is you
need to split
string and get the second and turn
number to string okay
so so
so string
split
X by default is split by yspace okay
then okay so you can just say that at X
then then you want to take the second
part okay let's do it this way okay then
take the second part
then that second part is the
bit number then you want to turn that to
expression
okay
so okay that turns a string to a
number and uh and that's it I think and
you just sum okay then you just sum okay
so let's try it that's
it then then you just sum it now this
sum is too high okay
total okay now this is too high because
we actually changed our input so now
let's let's revert the input to whatever
is original
problem Oh God QQ qja a so QQ QJ a so
you don't have this a
AA so that's right so this is the input
now okay do that do that do that and do
that okay let's try it again again
fresh uh and what we got map
indexed table
form uh
what
almost
done wa this is this is
incorrect
so list of ordered
hands okay so use string
split
[Music]
then then you take the the second part
should be
that and uh and two
expression let's just try
this for
example this should return 28 okay
that's correct now
now it returned the 28 then you take the
index one multiply
them nothing wrong with that that should
be so why does it return
that oh because you don't want the table
form yeah
stupid yeah you don't want the table
form let's re evaluate that's
it so you got this numbers 1 2 3 4
five now what you do you add them
together
oh correct we got the
solution
6440 okay we got the solution
so now let's clean up the code okay so
let's just clean up the code so here
this is the code okay so we uh let's
remove the remove all the
uh okay so and uh and just say
total
okay okay this is our solution let's try
one more time
and fact you don't want table form
here okay let's try one more
time perfect
now what you know now let's get our own
solution I mean
the
uh to play please identify yourself I
want to ah God I forgot to log in to
GitHub do I am I still logged into
GitHub sign to GitHub okay so I need to
stop I forgot to log into GitHub
how many people are watching four I need
to complete this shall we yeah let's
complete it okay so let me let me log in
to
GitHub this is tricky because I need to
stop
the stream okay hold on a second and I
need my
phone I hope the I can I'll be back
okay
okay I think I'm back am I back let's
check is my
streaming
back if you are here concurrent views
now two people can you see
me yeah I think I'm back okay now we
logged in to GitHub now let's get our
personal input okay
huge okay so let's let's see okay let's
open okay let's save this input let's
just say that okay so this is our
personal
input a file 1,000 lines okay so now we
just
say
um
read read string I
believe yeah read
string input equals to that okay this is
our input and read string let's see the
documentation uh what okay not
you need to put the cluer here let's see
read string file okay so that's it
so that's it that's a solution let's see
if that
works this this is a solution we can
make it much shorter one single line
okay but let's
WR H
okay H we don't want uh okay scroll
back SC scroll down this is our number
five 250
957 639 that'sand of a
code
submit that's the right answer of
course okay so now let's summarize since
we did all this trouble to get this
let's just summarize
okay
summarize and clean the code okay
so so
we so okay
so don't we don't need this big chunk of
output okay so that's our
solution yeah this this is
already
what two
hours 2 hours and 30 minutes but here's
a solution so can you do it in one line
yeah sure but okay let me do it in one
line
okay okay so let's let's do it in one
line let's clean up so um map indexed um
so
hold on a second hold on a
second
you know I'm just very sloy
trying to get this done but I'm not
doing a good
job uh but okay but here is a single
line solution
okay here is the single line
solution
okay
yeah it can be shorter much better but
anyway so so where is it starting here
okay there it
is and uh all these can be
shortened uh let's
see so many ways to shorten it yeah but
um let's not worry about it but anyway
okay here's the final solution and we
got it solved okay that's Advent of code
that's that's okay so anyway so this
this is advent of code day
seven uh part one we solve the problem
and that's it for today thank you guys
for watching here is uh one single line
solution and uh of course this part can
be uh this part can be moved somewhere
here so it you actually get one single
line here
input
uh so let's
see yeah so just move this input to here
okay one single line solution Advent of
code day 7 2023 that's it for today uh
kind of long but it's I mean it's
interesting problem uh and okay so if
you like my
stuff buy my stuff okay pay me you know
go to sad. info code
kinfo and uh go to to the bottom you can
patreon me you can Amazon gift card me
you can PayPal me you can buy my emac
tutorial you can buy my um emac and emac
this tutorial and JavaScript in depth um
okay and so uh that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
bye