good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show so let me wait
for people to come on Sam Sann talk show
and let's put today's date in stuff into
the title property so today I think I'm
going to talk about two topics let's put
that two topics one is JavaScript
JavaScript iterators iterable generators
generate a function the whole shebang
you know the the whole so I'm thinking
of I'm giving you a lecture like you
know a tutorial that teach you about the
whole thing it's very complex the
JavaScript iterators iterable the way
that there are concepts and the way they
are implemented the mechanism in
JavaScript is extremely complex ok so
you have let me show you the so in first
of all you you have JavaScript interface
the interface defines defines iterable
interface then you have iterator in
interface then you have iterator result
interface yeah anyway it's very complex
it's the the the the also the
programming concept of these things
iterable iterators generators they are
no good basically they are what I would
call a side-effect of computer
engineering ok
so anybody here so hi guys so let me
know what you want me to not talk about
today so one topic is JavaScript
tutorial a lecture on JavaScript
iterators and in the interface so that
is that the other thing we might talk
about is YouTube stuff you
basically a commentary on today's
YouTube society the millennial
generation maybe some politics I mean I
mean it's all related you know and it's
pretty bad today you know it's it's
pretty bad and also it's very
interesting I mean the YouTube stuff you
know they are billions in billions I
don't know what what number exactly but
it's such a numbers such that if you
watch all your time you know all your
wake time watching YouTube you cannot
watch it you know you cannot watch maybe
even half of it you know in your
lifetime so these tremendous things
happening in YouTube and also the
important things from my perspective you
know my kind of perception of the world
the style you know the thing that makes
my talk so interesting is that I want to
say that so the YouTube I mean the
YouTube they the way there are tons of
YouTube videos they represent they are
they are kind of a era a new era in
society I mean that's you know society
is changing you know all the time it's
changing imperceptibly because you know
if you know you live every day you don't
see a change but however if you look at
you know in ten years period you can see
things are changing and today in this
past decade they are changing very fast
and you know like you know if we if you
look at the past hundred years or 200
years that's history yummy I mean you
observe you see how things change how
how perceptions how the society how the
morality ethics the general sense of
morality and the behavior the attitude
the mentality you know everything you
know it changes and also including
social structure
and of course also countries you know
come and go giant huge corporations come
and go they switch hands usually you
know I got after you know a few decades
and also corporations you know powerful
powerhouses governments they also come
and go but anyway about YouTube you know
YouTube is one of the technology you
know most of us are programmers so we
are engineers you know we are we these
are things that interests us you know
programming and related software and
technology so YouTube the today's
YouTube it's kind of I would say okay I
would say it's kind of a maybe it's it's
like a turning point you know how people
behave and and like for example you know
you it used to be you watch TV you know
where the TV the mega-corporations
you know they you know you have cable
you have you know these giant if you
base basically three or four giant
corporations that broadcasting this
isn't you know it's called broadcasting
companies so they create programs you
know maybe news maybe entertainment you
know they produce shows you know for you
to watch but but that era is good you
know because I think I'd you know I
don't have a TV since year 2000 so I
don't you know I haven't been watching
TV for for like 20 years
the only thing I watch these this you
know so I don't want you know I have not
been watching any TV programs for 20
years and but I do watch you know videos
usually you know like 10 years ago in mm
I I went you know I I maybe go went DVD
movie so by DVD movie so CD you know
before VCD you know v CD was never
popular in USA but it was popular in
China and Taiwan anyway I haven't
watched much v CD but mostly
it's you know I watch DVD you know
sometimes I watch movies and but for the
past ten years I basically have not been
doing that and the only video I watch is
YouTube and I used to like it because I
don't like programmed I don't like
anything that's let's prepare that's you
know I prefer to watch natural things
like people and YouTube was made by
people you know you watch other people
just like in real life you talk to
people you talk to people of different
you know may be from different countries
you know they and people when you talk
you know you are not prepared like from
a script you know which is on the other
hand it's usually the case from
broadcasting companies it's carefully
prepared program that they maximize you
know they have all sort of statistics
they want to maximize viewership you
know and so they have ads and so on so
they make money that that's the bottom
line
anyway in general I don't I don't I
don't like you know so I don't like
watching TV at all it's kind of it's
some sort of brainwashing it because
what you are is what you see and what
you know it's like they say what you are
is what you eat you know because if you
eat healthy food you are healthy or be
healthy if you eat junk food all day it
does things to your body so in the same
way as an allergy what do you see what
you watch who are your friends that
heavily influences or makes who you are
you know how you think about things how
how you view things and in fact in you
know in the large part this is this is
what culture means you know if you are
born in America in USA your thoughts and
your perceptions of the world your
ethics or morality so American you know
justice rights and every things like
that but if you were born in Asia that's
you your view of the world is entirely
different from our
America or if you were born in let's say
Russia or Middle East countries you know
or India so anyway so who you are is
like much of it is influenced by what do
you know what book helps you read you
know what what do you have seen you know
what kind of news every day you know
it's not like it's not like oh I have
read this or this this book specifically
no but rather most of the things you
that that makes who you are are the
things that you see every day like your
life you know you just they small you
know by micro micro units everything you
see everything you touch that makes who
you are what you know what what you
think about things you know so so I you
know anyway so I I don't like you know
watching TV I always prefer to watch
youtube videos because YouTube you know
at least let's say 10 years ago it was
all by people when you watch YouTube
it's just people it's just people you
know talking and you know talking about
maybe some interesting topics or some
natural footage about animals you know
see animals because they they are divers
or you know it's made by people but it
has changed the nature also has changed
you know you know there are a lot more
and more people making YouTube it's
almost like everyone now because as long
as you have a phone and everyone has the
phone now and you can you know you can
start to make videos on YouTube but the
nature kind of also changed the youtubes
stuff because you know as small people
making videos and actually these days
more people are making videos because of
money you know not because they happens
to you know make a video about something
they of their interests or you know they
have opinion about but mostly a lot you
know it's like in the past five years
maybe that's the right frame of time in
five five in a five you know in the in
the past five years you have a surge of
people like you know go on YouTube
making videos and they are so the nature
of YouTube videos most is it has changed
somewhat so it's no longer it's less
about you know just people average
people talking but rather it becomes
more of kind of a semi-professional okay
who you know everyone wants to start to
make a living from YouTube because you
have seen if you paid attention you know
you have seen a lot of people become
very wealthy you know rich by just
making YouTube videos that's all they
have to do like you can quit your job
you just start to talk talk on YouTube
but also because of these money money
money element you know that also changed
significantly I would say to a
significant degree the nature of videos
we see on YouTube because these days you
see a lot youtubers you know they make
money although they are still individual
but they are their content has become
it's almost their content has become
just like the TV just like what TV was
showing you know 10 or 20 years ago
it's all very scripted and lame you know
there's no arranging ideas there's no no
it's it's all smooth and pretty you know
its own its you know the in other words
it is kind of like it's all fake you
know because they you know just like me
okay I mean for example you know I if I
want to make my videos popular you know
there's a lot metrics you know YouTube
provides you you know when did people
watch which video people liked you know
watch them all and how many subscribers
subscribers you got because of this
video and so on so there are this all
measurements they tried to help you you
know be get popular they want to help
you to become popular because the more
popular you are the more popular YouTube
will be the more money they will make so
if I make a video and my goal is to make
money so I start to you know so I check
all these statistics in psychology
there's lots of turns of health you know
so-called help you know some provided by
YouTube some provided by third party
that this CEO you know industry
industries they you know they basically
there goes you know how to get more
followers you know the top ten tips to
get more followers or get more or how to
become rich by you know making videos on
YouTube so so you do this you know so
each of us you know you tend up of
course you want to be popular and make
more money so you tend to follow these
things and so but the result the result
of your video it it became like what TV
programs is like 20 years ago or 10
years ago we so what so what what what
does it become
it becomes like everything is smooth you
know there's no swearing you know
everything is nice and smooth and yeah
you know it's everything is Lynn you
know it's like because the one of the
reason what one of the way to become
popular is that you just focus on things
everyone agrees this is so there is no
unique opinions anymore there is no
anything that might be considered
offensive to some people so you you
cease to become truthful I mean you see
it ceases to become natural so it's it
it doesn't is when you watch which lots
of YouTube a lot of people they are not
behaving in a normal you know average
you know it's not like average people on
a streak anymore
it's rather they it's you know in a
sense it's like all fake hegemon him no
man
so Norman says making money on YouTube
seems similar to music writing odd
almost all money is captured by a very
tiny percentage yeah that is true too
yeah that is true too but but in
comparison anyway that's another subject
and you know I maybe I'll talk about
that so what I'm saying is that YouTube
has become you know it has become almost
just like TV for example on YouTube
there are a lot people for example one
of those you know there are thousands of
areas you know so what one of the things
people do is reviewing keyboards right
so anyway so so I mean you start to see
you know logos like 3d logos and you
know like when you start to watch a
video the first 5 seconds is a logo and
music just like you know movies and TV
those you know produce on TV because
logo they kind of like it's a brand you
know they do so they kind of want to
spread their brand so this is so this is
a negative thing it's rather a bad thing
because you stop seeing people you start
to see all these rather fake things ok
that's that's one of the negative aspect
of it but the other thing I want to say
is at YouTube so today you know YouTube
I think there is a some kind of a
turning point you might say not not a
sharp point but but in the past 5 years
you know there's a change in society via
YouTube so one of the thing I want to
mention is that you know before before
there is a video you know video is a
very complicated technology it's not
easy to do it's in fact it's the
extremely very extremely complicated
technology you know we don't have that
you know we begin to have you know
the videos in in 1990s you know the
first company that made it big is
Apple's QuickTime and by the way back
then so in 1990s a video is like
stamp-sized a video like 320 pixels by
you know 200 pixels that's that's a
quality video and lasting lasting for
like five seconds
I know because because one of the
subject that pushes pushes technology as
you know is PN you know I don't want to
mention a word because people Google
YouTube start to ban people you know
they say PN is the pusher of technology
which is true you know if you observed
at least in the past 20 years
but it goes longer than that before that
you know bit you know for example video
cassette tapes they the technology of
video because cassette tapes they are
all pushed by the PA industry anyway so
so yeah I was so so I was saying video
technology is rather very complicated
and difficult to do
it's rather so we would call it advanced
so starting in 1990 s of course before
1990s we have you know you have TV and
broadcasting and video tapes that is
also video but that's a different
technology that's kind of that's film
you know that's before the software
based you know digital video anyway so
video is a very complex technology and
so only so in 2000s we begin to have
phones you know because you most mostly
due to Apple you know and that every
phone Scott camera so but now another 10
years everyone has a phone and the phone
can you know for us you know powerful
computers you know everyone can make a
video but still video is you know video
is like 10 times hundred times
the file size of a image file so anyway
the video is not is how to do so so my
point let's get back so what I was
saying so before video you know we have
the technology to communicate is writing
now you know as you know writing has
been with us you know for thousands of
years and then we have printing printers
you know the Gruben good Gutenberg you
know hotels Gutenberg printing press you
know that's a huge leap of technology
that advances humanity you know because
printing massive printing you you you
start to have these you know kind of
publications so everyone can read stuff
and every kind every everyone can get
educated you know learn things from the
past thousands of years you can print
you know books you know thousand copies
before that you have to copy by manually
you know writing it out
so anyway writing and reading is one is
our is the technology of communication
that we are used to you know that's how
it helps us you know pass knowledge from
generations to generation via writing we
can learn and understand history like a
thousand ago that today you can still
read I mean I can most Chinese can still
read like you know Chinese books that's
written 2,000 years ago and I you know I
have examples but anyway so and then so
so so you know writing is incredible but
however notice that writing is rather
unnatural because for example when you
study your country usually there's a
statistics about literacy you know like
literacy rate of the country you know
for example China you know in knighting
z-- let's say nineteen fifties the
literacy you know percentages maybe
sixty percent or something I don't know
and some Africa and Africa countries for
example today they don't have much
literacy literacy and in fact you know
and you know solely literacy is a big
thing so so what does that mean because
because to learn reading and writing is
actually it's a learning process I mean
it's not like you just pony and learn it
on the other hand language speaking you
know and listening that's kind of
natural you know when you are born you
learn it you know you can talk to people
you can do things communicate but not
writing and reading that so we if you
learned writing and reading you are
considered educated you know it is you
know let's say a hundred years ago
because the writing and reading is a
it's a learned process it's not you know
it just it's not a natural thing that
happens so what I'm saying is that so
you know so if you look at reading and
writing you know it's it's not a natural
thing that happens to animals okay for
example talks you know dogs cats wolf
lions they cannot you know they don't
have language that they don't have
written language but they can
communicate via sound you know because
that is natural you know
woof can howl you know lion can go or
dogs can walk and that's you know that
that they communicate and dolphins and
whales and so on you know and same thing
with humans but reading and writing zetz
that is something different that's that
takes kind of artificial kind of
learning to do but however videos now
look at videos the video communication
it doesn't require you know it's not
like it bypasses reading and writing
when you watch a video you are watching
another human animal you know like me
talking so you don't need to have
literacy and stuff you know whatever I
say you can understand you know we are
communicating well this one way you
so I have you know two-way video chat
like you know Google you know help so
anyway so so VD in the video format is a
communication format that even though
from the perspective of software you
know in technology it's really very
complicated to create you know you have
all these codec formats and you know it
takes huge amount of disk space very
complicated but however the video format
the video of vedyam as a medium as a
communication method it's actually idiot
it is actually natural i mean that's the
thing that's a difference between video
videos and compared to writing so what
I'm thinking when you know when I look
at YouTube I want to observe the
observed the search of amount of number
people making youtubes you know the
commercialization aspect aside let's
look at just look at the communication
aspect of human human communication in
society yeah idiot it is actually some
kind of incredible like it's a
revolution I mean it's an evolution it's
it's it's very significant and also the
other thing I noticed is that you know
when you learn a programming language
like I write programming language
tutorials I don't like to you watch
videos so so so I guys say something ok
I'll comment you know keep keep the
comment coming so why why write a
tutorial you know before there's a video
era you know YouTube you know you just
read and write programming languages you
learn you learn how to do it by reading
you know books or websites or
documentation that's fairly efficient I
mean compared to watching someone
teaching you a new language via video
it's rather more efficient because
video another thing about video
communication as a method of
communication is that video is very time
consuming you know you like my videos is
like Oh an hour every day you know you
don't have time you know you watch few
people then your day is good you know
you don't have you don't have time to do
work or any other things so video the
other thing is it's very time consuming
to watch but anyway so letting
programming languages I noticed you know
in the past few years a lot people they
actually prefer learning a programming
language via video so at first you know
I I just you know laugh it off you know
I think maybe stupid stupid people but
actually thinking about it that's not
the whole story because video as I said
you know it is a natural medium natural
way we we learn things communicate like
you learned from your dad from your mom
when you are small you watch what they
do you watch how they do you know you
just see it you know even even though
it's not a lecture you just you know you
you see you see your mom and dad or your
you know adults to things you learn it
you know that's how you learn so
watching video so I noticed a lot you
know there's a lot tutorial websites
they have you know they have they sell
their videos you know like you buy this
tutorial then you can watch you know
five hours to study Python for example
and actually a lot people it's very
popular that that kind of thing so I'm
so I'm so I'm thinking you know actually
the reason it's not these popular not
because you know at least partly because
you know video is actually the natural
medium and okay so now here's my point
okay so here's my point is is that so so
I have seen you know the YouTube how the
number of videos on YouTube is searching
it's like I am feeding you know
especially in the past
two or three years there's a search you
know a wave of people starting to make
videos because I've seen for my Emacs
circles even people who never you know
these kick programmers who would never
do a video before they are starting like
they are starting to do some videos
including myself you know I I only
started to video like half a years ago
so because so why are we starting to do
because I know I I think you know so all
these we you know we see news every day
there we we all noticed there is this
search and and also there's a money the
lure of money you know once you know
because we see a lot you tube stars you
know they can just make a living by in
many cases they make huge amount of
money like millions million dollars you
know years something like that so so
this incredible amount of videos on
YouTube so so that's some of my thoughts
you know let me let me make a summary of
what I've said so far so one is that
there is a surge of you number of videos
and YouTube video makers on YouTube okay
there's a search of number people making
YouTube's
making videos today one two videos are
actually more natural as far as
communication goes human communication
is actually more natural medium than
reading and writing reading and writing
is actually if you is in some technical
sense it's actually unnatural it's
artificial okay it's not because you can
look at other animals so video is
actually the more more natural medium
for communication 3 ok 3 the the the way
I see how the incredible number of
videos on YouTube in elsewhere as well I
mean the point is the the vast quantity
of the video
your format is that I'm I'm thinking you
know it's it's a kind of a turning point
of society that you know if you study
society as you know long term like as a
history I think there's a some kind of
change going on like you know pop for
example a possible consequence is that
number books on you know the way we we
you know website so the the
communication by text is kind of we
might we might say declining okay
relatively at least relative to videos
it's absolutely declining because of
course video there are so many videos
and many of this video youtubers they
don't they don't write and they cannot
write they are unable to write an essay
it is true you know maybe most of them
or significant portion like majority
they they are not writer so I mean they
are content creators but they are unable
they don't have the ability to actually
write an essay okay but they can course
they can make video so anyway so few so
so so I'm seeing some kind of a social
change as a from the perspective of long
term let's say historian you know
observer you know with respect to the
changing in society long term so I'm
seeing this is kind of a change I mean
so let me let me let me address that
because I am Not sure I express my idea
I'm saying that there is a change in
society that's happening you know partly
due to video that possibly you know so
so what's the point so the point is
possibly in in the future we are
starting to see that that people in
general
they you know reading books is is
becoming you know a past it's not going
away for sure but it's kind of you know
become less of a primary way we
communicate to you know to broadcast our
opinions to other people
I think that's happening and also
remember because writing and and reading
is acquired skill you know it's actually
a skill you know they have you have
turns a book sound writing styles and
grandma I mean it's a skill you have to
practice supposed to video you know you
can just anyone can has ability to talk
so video is actually the more more the
more popular medium so and any massive
numbers we are talking about a magnitude
more than writing it's happening so
that's what I'm thinking is happening so
there's a major isn't some kind of shift
I don't know exactly what it is
you know of course I'm just you know
giving out my observations so I'm but
socially I'm thinking there is a massive
kind of some kind of shift of something
happening because of the quantity you
know because of the video becoming you
becoming practical you know like
everyone's got a phone and everyone can
start to make a video a channel of
themselves I mean this is opposed to
opposed to ten years ago I mean ten
years ago of course you have video
bloggers you know V bloggers of course
so you have bloggers then you start to
have deeply bloggers you know which are
typically tech savvy take savvy people
like us you know programmers we start to
make videos you know short short clips
about something you know but not but
today is today stiff situation is
stiffened it's in this video massive
amount of videos on YouTube they are not
made by you know
some tech-savvy you know tech head so
they are just by every people you know
average people so yeah so this these are
things happening about YouTube that's I
found quite interesting and also I
wanted to so since we are talking about
video today I you know I might as well
continue the subject because I was
looking you know I started to I started
to watch youtube videos seriously like
everyday you know starting in 2016 you
know you know in the beginning
I'm watch mostly the political ones
commentary because you know as you know
there is a rise of social just justice
so suddenly you see these ideas about
you know trans or LGBTQ you know some
some of them you know patriarchy some of
the incredibly you know art concepts you
know so I started to watch YouTube video
starting in 2016
late 2016 I almost watch it every day
before that I just watch you know I
happens to watch something interesting
about some programming lectures or
something but beginning around to late
2016 I started to watch almost every day
and in the first one year or two is
mostly political commentators you know
talk about the strange kind of very
strange the rise of social just just is
you know tell people okay but but
starting about half a year ago I started
to watch more and and also this is how I
observe this just it seems like YouTube
is like tremendous there's a tremendous
amount of videos and so I started to
watch or different things different
things on YouTube yeah and and so I I
gathered at least kind of of some of the
things I watch let's go to
so I gonna show you this is this is this
is my periodic dosage which is asian my
asian blogs this block began this is my
original block it began in 2000
let's see human animals archive he began
in 2006 okay and you know in 2006 I was
reading Wikipedia everyday I mean I'm
still really like one hour of Wikipedia
almost every day you know I've been
doing so anyway so this this is my
original block it began in 2006 and and
then of five or ten years ago I started
to split them out so now I have a Emacs
blog artist art blog about art oriented
stuff visual arts they are blog about
linguistics literature writing related
stuff programming blog and the math
block you know I have like several blogs
but anyway so today this blog periodic
passage is mostly random and mostly
political stuff in many of them I was
offensive okay so if you're gonna read
it it's offensive
you know so this is my blob of this
block in this is written in 2006 and you
can read it you know that's when the
word blog became you know when the word
blog was invented around 2003 or so okay
they became popular so I say you know
what about once upon a time there was
Tyree and similar war logs journals
travelogue and such forth in our info
age it is called blogs by inept
computing geeks okay as I despise I
smeared you know the computer
programmers I'd like I despised
especially the elite hacker you know the
UNIX philosophy types so so I say you
know to keep in sync with humanity of
fashionable business and nomenclature
novelty mine is called periodic passage
this periodic is spent on to inform the
informed and educate the educated and
all things in social things and
ethological if ethological things that's
just my blurb okay that's kind of
dramatic that you know that's what
blurbs is for you know in books you know
when you buy a book a printed book you
know you know covers phone in packs
usually they have a you know some quotes
those are called the the the proper term
for those are called
I think the proper term is blurbs I
blogged about it but I forgot where but
in well I know where I mean in my
English blog okay
but I've but in one of the article in
one of the other I forgot where but
anyway so there is a word for that you
know in a book in a back or front you
know you have these blurbs the purpose
of the blurbs is of course for it's
mostly for marketing marketing reasons
you know you read these blurbs it kinds
of convey your style what this book is
about whether you want to buy the book
things like that so this is my my blog
you know
so you you read it and you see oh is
this the guy I want to read all these is
what kind of you know I'm not gonna
not gonna read it you know he kind of
kind of gives you the style of the you
know my stuff but anyway so this this is
my uh you know blog periodic passage
that's what I call it so I collected a
bunch of you know you youtubes I've been
watching so and also the number of their
followers but anyway let's
go read the comments take a break hey
David Capello great to see you again let
me read the comments
so live stream coding seems to be a
chain but I never found it helpful for
learning yeah you know video is
extremely time consuming and a spade
especially live stream coding you know
in a live stream coding you don't learn
things you know except you watch the
people struggle and you know I mean
typically that's the case unless it's
very you know very prepared on you you
know so but interactions is good you can
ask someone why they code a certain way
yeah yeah I mean the the good point is
you know it's visual it's natural and
you know it's like what did you know
it's like how they say why the rush I
mean today we are in this digital you
know AI age where everyone is rushing
like we don't have time we need to you
know mastered programming language X in
you know in a week on the other hand you
know you might ask yourself why the rush
you know just take your time to be you
know watch videos or whatever you know
yeah you know all the technology you
know they on my hand it seems to benefit
us but on the other hand we seems to
work more hours you know that life gets
more more pressure and less happiness I
mean that is true you know you you there
are lots of studies on that measures
happiness across you know of every
country you know there's happiness index
you know by these organizations you know
III check them out every few years so
and if you look at society and in
particular USA you know you look at our
situation society it doesn't seems we
are getting happier and better it seems
you know the you know politics and it's
getting worse you know the richer gets
richer the poor becomes poor
there's huge amount of anger there's
injustice happening every day you know
so David cavero says hikes are here
listening to you why our programming
okay that is multitasking and good luck
if you can actually do that so what do
you think about YouTube video
recommendation algorithm I think it's
it's pretty bad of course confirmation
bias fake news spread yeah so YouTube's
algorithms yeah you know YouTube they do
that of course first of all YouTube
wants to make money that's all they want
you all these speaking companies they
they want to do all they can to make
money and you know but they always say
you know positive things like oh we help
you to find the videos you are
interested but that's not true that I
mean the the fact they are saying those
things in the and even down to the the
word choices the styling of the writing
style it's all crafted you know by
psychologists you know they have like
the hope department of psychologists
psychologists working for them you know
the warning style everything is is is
created it's written took such that with
the ultimate result of you using their
product more that's that's what it is
and YouTube algorithms well there's so
many aspects to comment about that yeah
put down on one hand I mean the at least
one of the at least the past positive
thing about that is you do find videos
that that are interesting to you that
otherwise you know would not come by as
easy you know because I go to YouTube
you see a lot of you know the it's it's
really annoying to because because I
have subscribed you know to let's say
about maybe 20 people okay so those are
people I'm interested
oh I want to observe at least let's say
so I mean I got a list here you can
check them out I was planning to talk
through them but maybe I won't get into
that you know because you know he's got
so many to talk but anyway so I got
these things I got let's say I got 20
people you know beginning like two years
ago I start to follow and watch you know
especially in the past six months I
start to really check out YouTube you
know what are there so I got twenty you
know I subscribed to I followed twenty
people and then you know that I want to
watch their things but every time you I
go to youtube you got this you know you
got these tons of videos like
recommendations turns it's like they are
trying to bury you okay and but it is
true like half of them you know at least
oh let's say let's say you know twenty
percent at least this half you know
something like that I find it
interesting but the thing is I don't
have time you know I already got 20
peoples
I subscribe to some of them put out
videos every day then I go to youtube
you got these 50 more videos and and 50
most you know people creating videos
like what's going on you know it's like
of course YouTube want to do that so
they get you know they get you know
they'll be happy if you spend all your
time just watching video on YouTube but
that's an issue I mean so they create
all these recommendations so it's like
so what I'm saying so is it so this
situation it's like they you know
YouTube is doing that Google is doing
that because they want money but it's
like inhuman it's inhuman because these
kind of things because all these little
things they do they change you like they
change your person but that's why you
know we have society where you know even
though technology is growing expands
exponentially you know we are trying to
get to Mars
Mars you know we have rockets flying
every day but on the other hand you know
people get depressed is is kind of you
know people get depressed in anger and
just you know if you use Twitter you
know it's like Oh anger this is I think
so so this YouTube you know thing it's
this cycle example okay so it's not like
YouTube decided they want to make you
unhappy but but rather all these
companies they want to make money so
they create these things and also
algorithmic you know control things so
that on the surface it seems to like it
me it's min to help you or whatever you
know pleasing oh we are helping to
change the world we are trying to get
other information to people but actually
that's not the true nature of their goal
their goal is simply to make money more
money and it has a impact to people you
know because this is deployed you know
this is influencing you know me you know
like PD literally billions of people
around the world if it is you know it is
YouTube Twitter you know Facebook
everything website you go to they are
all doing that so it is changing you
changing you the person it's like doing
things to your brain you know so that's
you know that's what I happen to you
know right that's my comment about the
recommendation algorithm also the other
thing people when people mention that
recommendation of this algorithm is that
they say you know they say that I don't
know if it's true or not you you know if
you just keep following recommendations
it tends to get into the fringe you know
you start to see your UFO stuff oh you
know like dramatic like we are we as
human animals we are attracted to drop
drama you know that's just psychology
because dramatic things like people
crying or people
you know dead or something happened
accident or a big explosions that
attract us that that gets us attention
because because that is important
because you know suppose there's no
taking up technology when we peep when
we hear some girl crying you know or
shouting for help we that kid attention
because with this emergency we go there
and you know help or find out what's
going on or maybe a lion you know he's
attacking us so we run you know oh you
know things like that drama gets our
attention and because of the
commercialization everyone tries to make
money quick baits you know quick big is
based on drama so every video you know
they have dramatic titles and pictures
half of them is like half-naked girls of
you know wardrobe accidents and things
like that then other half is like about
in injustice or some war or explosions
you know anger you know anger gets our
attention so so you click and all you fo
you know US government is trying to hide
you know this is this is the real photo
of us so things like that
so you click click click follow directly
recommendation you eventually is it said
I haven't tried but I beat I suppose
it's true you get into the fringe okay
including fringe in pilot political
opponent of you you know basically fake
news you know they just lie so that is
also I suppose that's true I can you
know I can understand see how it is true
I don't know for sure but III pretty I'm
pretty sure it's true so that is also a
bad part and you know YouTube algorithm
these algorithms they supposedly you
know they are the intention is that they
use algorithms which is efficient way to
help them do their job you know help
Google these companies you know do their
job actually there's many issues because
right now we don't the AI we know is
sanctuary is not there yet so AI makes a
lot of mistakes but also the deeper
question is we actually don't know what
AI is we don't know you know we don't
actually like right now we don't know we
don't understand what is good and bad
you know the we can not but by that I
mean by that I mean that we cannot
algorithmically or mathematically or in
some scientifically scientific way
define you know in a precise way what is
good what is bad we can we cannot do
that because we don't even know what is
consciousness so you know you know in
the AI is subject as you might know you
know we don't know we you know
scientists you know mathematician so you
know they we don't have one theory that
everyone agrees so we don't know what's
going on going on so these algorithms
you know is in their initial stage so
they are doing these recommendations you
know and Google is trying to trick it
then so today our palette you know the
the political situation the word
stability stability stability is getting
worse you know as you know if you you
know if you observed words you know
what's going on so you know you have
more Wars more kind of violence and you
know and a lot of people you know at
least there's this information from you
know we know there's some people we you
know we some people believe I believe it
too you know that it's due to this
technology companies Google Facebook you
know Twitter they become you know
massive control of information and
because of their selfish reasons they
they are creating this problem they are
creating the wall you know they are
creating all this situation I would say
you know they they are significant
reason to blame you know they do they
have a significant responsibility
so so yeah that's that about these
algorithms so the newest ace took a deep
dive into outright culture okay oh
that's taken yeah let's try to know I'd
you know you know you know these days
Google are pending people so I'm not
ready to be banned yet okay all right I
just read that out so take a look
took a deep dive into culture on YouTube
and never came before hey I'm kidding
but then again still here okay I took
about the fact you know because I have
been very careful you know I already
said this I try to because Google I mean
if you know I suppose if you follow me
you know the situation you know you are
at least somewhat familiar they are a
lot of political you know have factions
you know and very including violence and
they are you know since the shape that's
just incredible you know I couldn't
possibly believe you know ten years ago
it is in USA you know freedoms of speech
is like the fundamental thing American
thing you know but today it's like we
have you know it's almost like you know
politically you know it's a fashionable
to to actually do not want freedom of
speech you know is this incredible so in
the end and we begin we begin to have
these censorship among these big
companies you know these serious
censorship and yes in many cases it's
just blatant you know some so much fake
news churned out by these big named
corporations like CNN you know MSNBC or
you know New York Times they are
churning out play blatant I mean it's
not like on the borderline I mean it's
just patently false false
you know things they are churning out
and
other political reasons because you know
so so it's it's really sad and
incredible to see so you know as for
myself
you know I start to make videos and I I
have been tried to be careful you know
I'm not sure you know on one hand that's
what really I want to talk about you
know I've been you know I mean I've been
communicating of that aspect too you
know you almost have my videos I want to
bring it out because that's that's
affecting every every one of us but
meanwhile you know this censorship going
on you know you just have to you gotta
be careful you know you cannot just jump
into hot water and you're you know
you'll be wipe out immediately so I also
want to be careful we have not to be you
know not to be banned you know you it
could happen any day you know I don't I
don't know it could happen you know so
so if YouTube you know if you Google
start to do that then you know Google
and still you know I'm living on Google
ads it's a sad thing you know I'm I'm
you know I'm living in poverty below
poverty okay it's like in USA you have
this if you make this some amount of
money you are poverty now of the people
in poverty the amount of money are
making Oh Isis my sister knows my food
it's like you know the the the the 10
percent at the bottom of poverty you
know II it's it's a topic you know it's
a sensitive topic you know he's you know
so anyway so you know if Google banned
me you know it's it's it's pretty bad
you know it's it's like I'm dumb
thankful you know so I'm kind of
thinking you know I mean a situation
there is this book flatland
okay let's by the way comments posting
them okay let's talk about it and maybe
that's it you know we I've been talking
for an hour now we have eight people so
for
your comments out there so we can talk
about it and that's almost is it's
almost like that's the conclusion of
today's talk for today you know that's
we covered the topic about videos you
know the videos in the relations to
society society instance something like
that but anyway there is this this
fiction flatland it's very popular yeah
you know some of you have read you know
so I highly recommended yeah be careful
on YouTube we need your videos thank you
David
so so there's these frictions
technically is classified as science
fiction the name is flatland enrollments
of many dimensions it's written like two
hundred years ago it's incredible but
you know I'm thinking this is his
character in this book a square okay so
he has seen the vision because he lives
in a two-dimensional flat land that's
his universe that's his people okay but
he has a revelation because he has been
touched by a 3d character 3d being like
us you know so he has seen the
three-dimensional world
okay for for for a brief moment then he
is back to his you know two-dimensional
world and then but in his word you know
every like every thousand years this
happens you know some three dimensional
beings comes to his world and select a
person to reveal the true nature of the
world which is three-dimensional okay so
every year in in their country you know
in their flatland you have this kind of
strange phenomenon every thousand years
because every thousand years in their
history you know they have thousand
years of history it's recorded every
thousand years there's one guy who is
and who says you know preposterous
things hey who is a nutjob you know so
they Joe them you know because because
he's talking about crazy things that's
disruption disrupting the social
structure you know the churches churches
you know whatever you know they are
social structure because you know you
have a nutjob talking about three
dimensional things every thousand years
so but this author these squares so he
became the he became the guy you know
who who got you know got the gospel of
three dimensions then he's thrown back
to the 2d world and he's thinking you
know okay I gotta be careful
I gotta be cover I gotta be careful oh
you know that's not to not to be not to
spread this kind of you know
three-dimensional things thing things
but meanwhile he he has seen it you know
he has seen the truth you know the truth
the three-dimensional things we are
actually there is a freedom you know
third dimension it's not just a flat so
he's you know so he's on the other hand
he won't really want to try to you know
to really tell people you know like
really I have seen it it's right there
you know let me convince you they are me
so you know instead of North West you
know east south there is another thing
it's called up and down but eventually
he failed so he got you know so you have
to read the story so he's I'm feeling
I'm feeling like that you know hey Scott
flatland yeah so so let me my eyes are
dry
my eyes are getting bad over the past
few years really a few years back yeah
is flatland written by a written by an
English schoolmaster yes
Edwin this Edwin guy Edwin Abbott kind
of kind of fascinating
Edwin and theology Thea theology Chien
theologian yeah yeah I've read that too
I've you know so I started to read this
back in 2005 in 1993 and I read it you
know I read it like three times over you
know in different years four times
almost so I have actually so I wrote
this up you know I put it on a website
and actually there is a annotation you
know I actually made annotations of it
actually not much though because some of
them annotations so anyway I think
that's almost it today for today's topic
so we got eight people watching so maybe
so if you are watching you know make
some comments and maybe you know we talk
five more minutes or ten more minutes in
that beer today
but originally I was thinking actually I
have a list of these people on YouTube
by follow let's go to so yeah and I know
and I want to make comments you know so
I want to make comments about some of
them what kind of it you know the nature
you know what kind of people what kind
of videos are they making you know and I
mean there are so many interesting
things to talk about about these people
so so again so make make your comments
okay and that's and then you know in
five or 10 minutes that that would be it
for today's video
let's see okay so so one that the most
popular guy on on YouTube is this
pew die pie yeah this this guy he's just
nickname is PewDiePie and he's got 95
million followers
okay now you did not remember that he is
the most I think he right now is the
second most popular but let's just say
the most the the guy was the most number
of followers
now that is more than any pop star you
know the you know girls follow pop stars
you know so what what are some today's
pop stars you know the you have Nicki
Minaj which is you know her you know
today's generation look at these you
know it's like so so what she is a
singer you know one of the most popular
so so you have this you know parsing
singers today very popular but but no
but on YouTube this guy PewDiePie is
like a few times more popular than than
any any movie star any any movie star
any single star or any means anyone any
politician any you know president of any
country so you got is PewDiePie it's
incredible
so so I began you know as I said I start
to watch more videos especially in the
past six six month since I'm beginning
to make video so I'd look you know I go
watch his videos what what it is about I
you know I go to Wikipedia study you
know read about what where he came from
what what does he do you know how you
know it so he is so he is like he's a
camera okay that's how he became popular
he just play games they are quite a lot
cameras on YouTube they become hugely
popular so he's one of them you know he
just make you know in the beginning he
make playing game you know they just
play games people watch that's it
and so I watched you know like five of
his videos you know and I watched other
gamers but anyway of his video
as I watched like six maybe six of them
in the past you know made in the past
two years a year or maybe last week okay
you watch them there's nothing there's
nothing on it you know it's like it's
like no content
there's no no content no opinions that
were in any sort
it's not even comedy okay technically
people like him is classified as a
comedian but it's not comic like you go
to uni you know you go to his channel
he's just talking about you know about
memes about you know random things about
you know that's not even it's not like
for a professional comedian you know you
have for example you have materials to
talk about maybe you are a political
commentator like like the like the you
know they are quite a few number of them
you know they read today's news
politicians what's going on they make
you know witty your commentaries about
the news but that's not pewdiepie I do
also there are other kind of comedians
you you prepare scripts you know
stand-up comedians and you know you make
jokes you know some of them are funny
but that's not that's not what this
PewDiePie do you know you look at video
this video is really it's truly rather
it's just no content and but also he's a
handsome guy by the way most people who
are popular handsomeness or how pretty
you look is actually a significant
factor okay the charisma is actually
sick significant because I know because
I've studied psychology I study
marketing in this kind of things it's
one of my thing obsession
yeah so one another thing he does is
like you know me like reviewing mean
stuff and you know means you know what
that means means are just like this
quema type of people they create images
that are nonsense
sico and they some of them are so-called
extremely popular
you know viral you know it's a another
word in in in their group viral you know
something our social media becomes very
widely spread
sometimes it's fake you know sometimes
it's like mostly dramatic things like in
nonsensical dramatic you might say
stupid things you know there's no okay
so in other words there is no value with
respect to let's say knowledge or
education or scholarship or there's
nothing like that this is no like no
value okay so so somehow so so he is the
most popular so no 95 millions more than
pop singers you know even movie stars
and pop scene singers sing singers for
example they they have you know maybe
you are old generation you think today's
Saint singers are crap you know in many
ways that's true but singers at least
they have the you know you must have the
ability to sing which is not which is a
you know it's a skill you know you have
to sing but this cutie pie you know so
it's not this is like few times more
popular and singer so there's no there's
no there is no value in their content so
is it's so what how should you look at
this situation it's kind of so I mean if
you want me for example I like to I
prefer the way I look at things I like
to see them in terms of history okay I
want to I like you know it just so
happens I like to see them as long-term
history kind of what's going on kind of
a way so the way I see that this this
content list you know in some sense
content valueless thing created by this
PewDiePie but yet yet
it's you have the most foully followers
and viewership so I don't know what to
make it's kind of sad you know I feel so
that's today's generation that's you
know what what do you call millennial
generation that's you know a lot of
people blame the millennial generation
and and I could you know you could say
this is one example of what they are
doing and what they what they think how
they perceive things what they do with
their time you know content Leslie
things so what are they they go haha
it's that's that that's that's what it
is just like what I'm doing now okay you
know you you laugh at face you show
funny things that's what they do so and
they are quite a lot like him and then
anyway so that's one of the one of the
thing okay he's the most popular
youtuber okay so and there are other
there are other other people some of
these are political commentators
fighting the social justice stuff and
shoe our head okay sure our head is
another very interesting character she
is also she is the in the same group as
the pewdiepie okay she's a girl and
she's not exactly pretty okay but she
you know she put on makeups but she is
also classified you know technically as
a comedian and she is small focused okay
her content is kind of different from
PewDiePie okay PewDiePie's content is
most is up a political it's not like
siding with any political camps like
today we have you know at least in USA
you have the you know you might say
conservative versus the extreme it
becomes the Democratic switch is
becomes extremely bro because their
their topics is about you know feminism
in translating stuff you know like
everyday and immigration oh yeah I might
say you know summarizes social justice
kind of thing it which is very different
from Democrats let's say twenty years
ago
but anyway so PewDiePie he's not his
videos content is like a political a
political which is like is not
associated with either groups but in
recent months he's been smeared you know
people call him you know people want to
smear him but anyway anyway
Chiron head she won't had this girl I
knew her like since ten years ago I've
heard I've seen her videos heard videos
is rather more focused her videos is
rather more the anti social justice
people okay so her videos and many of
them actually are funny I find her funny
so I've watched she heard we shoe on
head videos you know some of them
actually at least she has put effort to
make her videos funny now I don't really
know what PewDiePie do because I've
watched then you know at the front of
five videos i watch this no not even
effort to put into creating a video like
maybe because he's already so popular he
doesn't need to you know he just show up
there with his pretty face and he just
and automatically these people will talk
about you know whatever he is doing but
at least she won't had you can see
there's some preparation required to do
her videos there's scrapings
you know you have to edit your videos
and you know there's audio clips you
know you have to you know mixing you
know
so anyway sure on here it was you know
one medium followers you know you know
these people when you have like
even just a few hundred thousand
followers you know have a median you get
to you make a living out of you know
just creating the youtubes more more
than programmers you know even even you
know programmers even if you you spent
like five years study you work at Google
they make more money than you and anyway
lastly greens also popular anyway so
maybe that's it for today so you know
this another actually there's some quite
interesting because okay this is a shoe
on head okay this also you know
incredible this this girl okay actually
to actually talk up about this I should
go to their YouTube so you can see them
you know you can see their videos anyway
I'm also getting tired so Scott says I
think PewDiePie the issue is that there
is a context that Nouveau viewers aren't
getting and getting unless you've been
familiar with the cultural references
yeah that's true I mean you have to be
your camera you have to be like a team
you know teenage kind of or early
twenties you know you grew up when you
grew up there's already YouTube so you
grew up with these kind of things you
you know what's the website you know the
new fashionable website and stuff anyway
so some of these actually maybe I should
do another video I'm thinking maybe you
know I'm starting to maybe even do two
videos a day so maybe in five more hours
so in six you know hours maybe I do you
know the problem with my videos is that
I don't have a schedule so it's like
just whenever I feel like I announce it
two hours two hours beforehand but
there's no vide schedule so people don't
know so only people just happens to see
it you know
I'm live so people get on so there's no
no
schedule or no topic and that kind of
you know you get less people interested
you know in the topic to be on it so
anyway there's some other interesting
things very interesting because you have
this Chinese girl okay this girl this
this is in Chinese anyway she she has a
YouTube channel if you search copy-paste
this you'll find it I should show you
but I am tired I'm gonna close down in a
minute okay I just want to mention this
she so this Chinese girl she make videos
it's incredible I mean she okay let me
let me go show you
she's got four million followers that's
a lot you know you make you formed four
million followers that means you are a
million you are a millionaire you know
you make few millions a year so I said
well she began in Chinese you know over
China at Chinese social networks and
video websites but she started to have a
YouTube channel and this four million
followers you know and and that means
basically that pretty much means you
know she and whoever her production is
very rich now and her video excuse me
her videos is like you can see let's go
to videos basically you have this
ruh-roh girl in China like in Inglewood
row area and she make you know her video
is like oh this tranquil beautiful
scenery it's like you know ruh-roh a
very pretty girl in very remote rural
place in China and she prepared food she
make Pam bamboo she cut you know cut
bamboo
to make furniture you know she prepare
food by going going into the forest and
the kind of food she makes they are
exotic I mean they are not they are not
the type of food you would any I mean
even a Chinese Ruegger
I don't imagine it's like very exotic
traditional Chinese food you know it
takes skill like learning you know to
actually know how to make them you know
some of them are truly exotic like you
blow you have to blow you have to
prepare a chicken then you have to blow
the chicken up so that the air inside is
for certain purposes and so on and you
know she and she you know here's a video
she makes a chair or bed out of bamboo
from ground up like you have to go to
the forest to cut cut up bamboos and you
know I watched this video and I'm so um
fascinated by it because first of all
this is not I mean this is not a natural
video I mean there's a production I
think I'm pretty sure it I mean in a
sense it's fake okay there's a
production team behind her you know like
your v-- camera main directors or maybe
you know something like that it's
definitely not you know someone her
family members just you know make the
video real-time then
but however on the other hand it all
looks like it all appears to be like
very natural in rural so there's many
interesting things going on I'm not sure
quite sure what you know I haven't done
research you know like sometimes often
you know often like when I do my wise
you know go on with my daily lives you
know suddenly I start to do research you
know I start to dig into this person
where she came from
you know what's her Chinese channels and
you know because I read Chinese I can
then go and further find out you know
what how is this video made these years
a like a production or company maybe
maybe possibly even a powerful you know
cooperation behind her making these
videos I don't know
so I haven't done any research but also
you also notice you know it's fate so
it's very strange you also noted this
video okay she's talking to the camera
to us you know so this video is actually
more kind of like more on the spot you
know so she's actually saying that
telling us that you know I'm me and I'm
just making videos you know for you know
what you know - because I love my
country and whatever but it's it's very
strange II I mean it definitely this
videos are you know it's not like it is
it seems professionally made but however
it's totally amateur in in in the way
you know so I don't know what to make of
it
so I don't know so yeah but I'm just you
know I the way I perceive things I just
you know find it fascinating her I want
to dig you know I want to dig out more
and also just the videos themselves they
are they are truly beautiful because all
these sceneries you know this winter
sceneries you know on the surface it
looks like you know it's natural it's
like somewhere in China ago just go out
out of her home you know and walk for
half an hour and then you just start to
you know take video videos that seems to
be the case but however these sceneries
just - they are too beautiful to be true
you know it's you know winter in summer
and all these flowers is just incredible
so yeah I don't know but but even I mean
even a professional production some of
these just not you cannot even I don't
know how you know yeah so I don't know
so it's fascinating so so I'm saying you
know if if I
these videos are very attractive you
know I can because I don't you know but
a lot of people you know she's got 40
million followers
I suppose you know more more of it half
of it more than half of it is just
average American no you know who don't
don't speak Chinese but just by the
video quality itself you know it's very
soothing and beautiful you know you when
you watch this beautiful girl do her
things everyday cooking and make you
know fruits and pick foods and it's just
beautiful it's amazing so it's one of
the this is by the way this is it's more
than one
okay I've noticed I've found out you
know it's not just her there are other
girls okay similar you know apparently
it seems to me apparently
you know they people discovered okay
this is the way to make money
apparently so there are other girls who
are doing similar things and I haven't
found out exactly there are different
persons by the way but they are doing
very almost you know identical since
very similar things and you know so it's
I don't know what's going on so anyway
that's it for today so Scott says it
helps that I have three teenage boys to
decode it for me
okay yes God I've seen photos of your
kids children they are incredible they
are beautiful so yeah so you have a lot
children that know what's going on and
the other thing I want to mention is
that you know girls you know they are
fascinating okay because then we have
these videos by some of these guys who
are making makeup videos and what's
their name they mean let me just quickly
point out James Charles and Jeffrey star
they are guys okay so they got 16
million followers and you can why is 40
million followers they are guys okay
well
his neck like 19 years old the other one
is more ugly and older but all they do
is make up videos you know the makeup
products girls love them
incredible 16 million followers
so so they have you know they are very
rich you know they they are millionaires
they are they have tens of millions
incredible anyway that's it for today so
thank you guys for coming
some how many people I've got nine
people yeah I'm getting tired seeing
here talking for 90 minutes too so thank
you guys for watching if you like my
videos you know subscribe and thumbs up
in and do my paypal okay do my patreon
stuff so by the way David Camaro if you
are here one day I really like to see
your opinion about why you like C++ so
much and by the way Scott - Scott you
are also a low-level what I would
consider low-level programmers you know
programming see you know know a lot of
details about C and you know the
hardware stuff you know the optimization
those kind of things are far into me
okay so I love to have you guys I don't
know how to do it yet you know because I
have to get a way to set up so people
can maybe joining me as a you know video
or maybe just audio when you anyway I
like to talk to you guys so what David
you know tell tell us why you like C++
so much because I I know you I know you
are very you you have like a kind of a
like a rant like you insist you know see
Christmas is the best language something
like that okay I just don't see it you
know I think C and C++ is the worst okay
so I like you to talk about why you why
you why you somehow you know find C++ is
the almost like not just the
frak you but somehow you use I think you
also find it it should be you know
somehow it's a pace or something and
yeah also Scott your opinions about
c-plus first yeah
OC yeah you know yeah so but I don't
know how to do it you know I you know I
can contact you guys from Twitter but I
don't have idea I you know I use
something I you know I don't have a plan
so but anyway I just want to throw it
out so I so I have to you know let's let
the idea sit there so maybe we will come
up with something so power L says are
that's two backs our next video you can
talk about personal personal life or
that advice okay what about that you
have to tell me though because because
like for example what okay that's it for
today thank you guys for watching I'll
see you next time bye