good morning welcome
to another episode of talk show welcome
to another episode of star talk show
today is 2020 july 18th
noon san francisco time and today is
saturday and we are going to talk about
several things about keyboards let me
stop that
okay so several things about keyboards
i'm going to show you
um google keyboard
and i'm going to show you the logitech
g604 mouse okay
and let me show you okay several things
uh let me show it here
and say hi okay come here people come
come you know type type um in the chat
box
so we are going to shall we begin
so i started to um you know i haven't
been talking about keyboard for a while
let me show you my keyboard block okay
so i've been working on keyboard block
every day of course
and we haven't been talking about it for
a while and there are
a lot news and update um
and in the past few days i've been
updating a lot of my old pages you know
right now i have like a few hundred
pages on keyboard let's see article
index
so you see this is my article index
let's see how many
pages about 700 pages on keyboard mouse
input devices and so on
let's go back okay so let's go back and
let's go to
my keyboard blog and in the past few
days i've been up
updating lots of old pages uh let me
show you
some of them okay you know i've been
writing a lot about keyboards
that some of these are old pages
let me show you
i'm just going to show some of them
because most of these are not
interesting uh things and i haven't been
i actually don't have it
hey yo so so you guys so i'm alive right
i'm
alive and well so we have eric
gonzalez gonzalez hello and
jay gone hello jagen uh the lisp
expert and channing stefan i haven't
seen you before first time
great welcome so i'm gonna talk about
keywords
and yeah let's start okay so i've been
updating lots of these old pages
you know these are not great pages
mostly i just
read amazon reviews about them so this
one is logitech g703
mouse i do not recommend you know if you
want to see what i recommend just go to
the mouse section
you know mouse section and i have
categorized what i do recommend
and what is my judgment what is my
principle basically i've written it out
here
i tell you uh which mouse i prefer and
i'm not
a gamer in the modern sense uh
in the sense that i don't play modern
you know 3d games and so on but i'm a
big nerd gaming note my mouse
recommendations are mostly for
programmers or heavy
heavy computer users browsers uh
programmers photoshop
and you know that kind of thing
okay hold on a second let me get some
issues with the
okay so yeah so so let me just quickly
go over so
these are some of the old pages not
interesting i'm going to show you
show you interesting things okay uh oh
this this page is
interesting you know we have so many
diverse devices
for example we have so many different
mouses mouse and trackball and pen
uh you know as you have seen
wait so many different shape and
uh of mouse you know the weird shape
five buttons twelve buttons twenty
buttons
and you know a joystick on the mouse and
and this one and ergonomic mouse and
also this contour roller bar
and there's this space navigator then we
have the drawing tablet
of course so all these devices and also
uh trackball you know a trackball is
even more diverse you know
uh thumb operated trackball versus you
know finger operated
trackball and different trackball size
and some of them has a
ring for square wheel fascinating
so all these devices and pen tablet and
touchscreen and so on and also things
like this
they you know you want to know so which
one is the most efficient you know gamer
gamers talk about it all the time like
some say some claim
that trackball is actually the preferred
instrument to play first-person shooters
you know the diverse ideas
so let's put it to scientific tests you
know
and that the way to do that one of the
ways via this game also
i've actually never played it but i've
surveyed you know i collected
information on this page
about also players their video for
example this guy is a weird guy
he uses a trackball to play also and
very good you know beats
most of us i guess if you haven't played
it before
he uses a trackball so you can watch
this video you can see
on the corner of the screen he's using
these uh
stupid youtube ads okay you know he's
using the mouse
i mean the trackball to play osu so we
have
trackball users then we have pen tablet
you know drawing tablet users
uh which you can buy cheap and then you
have
touch screen uh users you know this is
obviously the most efficient for this
game
but however you see you cannot do this
with uh
first person shooters because the very
nature of touching
you know that doesn't work in first
person shooters then you have trackpad
you know operation then you have uh
a you know game controller uh like such
as
a ps3 controller then you have mouse
so you can actually so this is a kind of
a scientific way then then you have the
pen
tablet the scientific way to determine
which
device is actually the most efficient
uh with respect to get to the point as
fast as possible
and and and you know clicking and and
dragging
and so on so that's an interesting page
okay so let me get on to the main topic
today we want to talk about
so these are some of the old devices uh
for example this
nostromo was a product from belkin
and then about five years ago
seven years ago razer bought it so razer
bought it
slapped on their logo razer is a bad
company you know i don't recommend razer
product
at all because razer they've they they
actually
um this is what i think okay i don't
know if it's actually
uh i haven't really tried to verify it
they
you know they they they want to force
you to in
use the cloud you know so-called cloud
that is other people
their computers store all your
customization in their
uh cloud so you need to you need to
install their software
intrusive software you know into your
computer
then you need to register a account then
you need to
you know customize your keys and store
that information in their computer
so why because that way they they have
data about you they can sell it they
make more money
and and they market it as you know oh
the greatest the latest technology cloud
where you can
have different profiles depending on
what games you are on
that's all kind of because you
know
gamers are in general ignorant so they
bought into that so actually
in this way they actually save memory
you know they don't have to have
internal memory as much as anymore
because they it's all cloud
so it requires you to have internet
constantly
and they constantly monitor what app you
are launching when you launch it things
like that
so i do not recommend razer product at
all
so especially they have this uh uh razer
oh weaver this is the worst device you
know you are first so
so don't buy razer okay so again some of
the other uh old pages razer black widow
this
is also no good comparatively you know
if you are a gamer you might you might
think oh this is the greatest no
there are much better ones so anyway i
want to talk about
okay this one this over ob touch is a
special
special input device oh my friend's dog
coco come here
go go shut up
go go go go shut up okay let me show you
my dog okay
am i doing okay okay we're gonna start
to talk about google keyboards how long
has been talking already let's see
google okay 10 minutes 11 not so bad
we're gonna start to talk about google
keyboards and
and uh hold on a second
okay use my dog use my dog
you go look
this is my friend's dog
okay can you see it
hmm
good morning alan good morning elk cook
and uh
danielle and
okay so i'm going to show you
close that this is another old page
because that
yeah interesting devices so this one is
the uh
3d space navigator it's a it has an
interesting history
let's see am i still on
it has an interesting history let me
show you okay so
normally the device it looks like this
okay or not
here so where is it let me go to it
so space navigator 3d this is the uh
common version okay so it basically it's
just like a joystick
but you can also push it down and pull
it up
and twist it and that's it you know it's
basically just like a joystick
you can pull up push down or twist it
uh i don't think that's that's uh you
know i don't think it's that great but
many
3d modeling software users such as
blender
allen uses uh might like it you know and
this is also great for google earth if
you pre like you know to play with
google earth this is a great device
and this is the history of that device
it was
in the beginning it actually was
developed or used at nasa
you know the space you know this
the space organization they use this um
it looks like that 3d connection but
eventually
the voice becomes redundant they just
become
a knob so actually let me see if i can
find
i have another page of history about it
somewhere showing
um showing a even a older device let me
show you okay
since these are interesting so you go to
trackball history uh
trackball history trackball controller
uh i forgot where that is actually not
trackball history
uh trackball controller no
mouse history actually anyway somewhere
on my page i forgot where
i want to talk about let's go back to
talk about
the interesting things okay this mouse
we're gonna talk about
and google keyboard yes let's let's do
google keyboard
let's see so am i doing okay so
great uh
streaming task say idiotic
okay the proper time to say
idiocy is about these
normal pc keyboards these are all
idiotic
you know this especially the 40 plank
the happy hacking this one this one is
the most expensive
350 happy hacking keyboard it just
came out about three months ago this is
the most
idiotic keyboard possible
[Laughter]
okay and and and well
let's go back to our topic because
otherwise it's gonna be endless we're
gonna talk about this keyboard okay i'm
going to show you
um i'm going to show you let's see if i
can
show you my keyboard
now i don't want to show some
okay so here is google keyboard
you see this is fantastic let me let me
explain okay
so this keyboard doesn't have a case i
mean you you buy it you can either do it
yourself
or you can uh buy it pre-built this is
like the full
pre-built actually they also have a
version that comes with the case and
pre-pre-built
so um you buy it and you build it your
you know you can build yourself do it
yourself or
you buy the complete one so that
that's it you know it's very simple that
that's all
there it is so you got you know the
connections between these two
then you have the usb cable you know
connecting to the usb
so google keyboard the guy is
actually he gave it to me for review so
i'm going to plug it in
okay let me put plug it in
so i can actually show you typing on it
and i come to love it but but however
there are several major
problems okay with this keyboard and
let's
show okay now now i'm going to show you
some typing on
with this let's go back
okay so now you see the keyboard and now
you i go to the screen um
this is gonna be a bit hard let's see
i'm holding it with my mouse
okay this is gonna
be a problem let's see if i can do it
ah this is pretty bad but anyway i'm
gonna just show you
so this is my right hand this is not
good
okay so emacs i mean emacs look at my
emacs screen okay so now
now wait magnify magnify magnify
oops cancel uh let's magnify
one more time so now
i am typing on the google
keyboard and this
is actually a 40
percent weight percent 40
keyboard one problem
shall we say is that
40 keyboard
um well basically you have a problem
when you want to type symbols
so if you want to type symbols such as
the percentage sign
or number there is no direct key
on the keyboard for it because you see
there is only
three rows you know you know for example
i put my
hand on the um on the home row there are
only three rows there's no numbers
so if you want to enter numbers you have
to hit one of these modifiers
or if you want to hit symbol keys
such as percentage sign dollar sign
and so on
okay this my uh
let me adjust this so you actually see
more of me
so okay so so what what do i want to
talk about it so
um 40 keyboard so i'm going to go
over okay i'm gonna tell you all about
this
google so i have a video demo actually
it doesn't play in in firefox uh
keyword blog okay google
okay uh opening chrome
open link in chrome airplay so you go to
my website you'll see the video
so here is a video of actually this guy
this guy actually types on it so well i
just showed you typing demo so he
is a great guy he sent send me one for
review
um and then then you have google heavy
which is
come with a box um case
okay the layout so there's a default
layout okay
now the default layout in my opinion is
not
optimal i mean it's pretty good but
you know for those for those of us who
are very into
uh key mappings and you know we want the
utmost efficiency for
emacs users or vim users or whatever you
do
you usually want your own layout so i
have actually created a layout
i designed it you know spent as a week
after you know
the first version then second version
came out with this layout and i'm really
really happy with it with this layout i
find that
i can efficient efficiently operate on
this keyboard and i really love it
so this is a 40 keyboard i never liked
the concept of 40 keyboards
but but i think it's
okay um for me to use it
no i wouldn't say long term i mean i
wouldn't say
for becoming my main board because well
because
not because 40 because there are several
issues with google okay i'll tell you
about it
in a moment there are several issues but
i wouldn't mind you know
i enjoy using this 40 keyboard even
including typing symbols you know one of
the most
uh great thing i discovered is that the
embedded you know square
shaped square shaped number layout look
at look at here over here
so you see this is extremely uh uh
efficient to type as uh instead of you
know the
typical top row numbers so the square
numbers you do want that that's
far more easier um and faster
so anyway so i could you know uh i if
you use
any type of gmk software you know any
kind of a dm
do-it-yourself keyboard i recommend you
such as ergo docs okay i recommend you
give my layout a try
you know try something similar with my
layout because i
i think it's pretty efficient you know i
think it's very good
uh the layout you know the design of the
layout
it's a it's kind of a big science now
first of all there's a later layout you
know the layout you know for example
qwerty
uh vorack i'm using and some people you
know alan
you know some allen uses qwerty but he
he doesn't believe in cody he used i
mean he used waraq but he
went back to qwerty sometimes
you know some of you use comac such as
emily uh
and and some of you use you know many
other type of layout those are letter
layout okay
i mean the arrangement of letters now
letter layout is one thing
but when you use the 40 keyboard they
are
something more significant that is the
shortcut layout
for example where do you place your
windows key
where do you press old key or command
key you know uh or the
control key where do you place them you
know
there's a big science which which way
you know which way is more efficient
or whether should it be toggle key or
should it be you know
a normal modifier like hold it down
press some other key
uh leave you know lift off and lift and
leave the
modifier you know it could either be a
toggle
or it could be a one-time shift or it
could be a standard modifier
you know there are many ways so in the
their position so
this is a great science um of key
mapping
that have not been studied much for
example you go to online
website you'll see tons of uh pages
about
layout quality versus full rack versus
coremag
which one is more efficient yeah but we
are over that
let me show you the layout okay so
layout
so here's the page about layout all kind
of layout
you know so you have quality you have
work you have programmers work
you know i'm sure many of you are
familiar you have cormac
then you have chroma dh you have workman
you have acid
and so on so these are all later layouts
and
terms of people you know we have nerds
we
already studied it to death i mean
but the more interesting thing is the
modified the shortcuts layout so i
have lots of uh pages that talks about
this aspect keyboard shortcut design you
know the shortcut layout such as in
emacs or vim which command should should
be bound to what key you know that's
that's shortcut layout or photoshop
photoshop you have hundreds
uh hundreds of shortcuts where do should
you place them
things like that but but with a
do-it-yourself keyboard you
you have even more issue because on a
normal pc keyboard
you know the windows key alt control
they are kind of fixed
at most the nerds will say oh you should
put control on the
caps lock position that's that's all
they said nothing else no
no no new idea no thinking but on the on
on new keyboards such as google keyboard
or google docs or you know
you have much more variety i mean for
example on the google should the control
key be on the traditional caps lock
position
or should it be one of the thumb you
know which should it be or should it be
a toggle or should it be what you know
and also for example if you look at all
entirety of all possible shortcuts keys
that comes in windows 10 for example
there
are about 50 or maybe 100 you know we're
talking about
operating system shortcuts then there's
a question you know should
you know so so normally you have windows
key
control key and the old key right
and they on windows each one have
specific
specific uses and shortcuts with them
but if you are going to redesign the
entire thing you know it's an open
question like for example
should you actually have three modifiers
or is three too many you know maybe you
should two is enough
you know so the other modifier is a
extra key spot you can use for something
else
such as a function key or extra function
key
you know so there's a and then should
you use key sequences such as you know
old
uh old e
c that is you know for example you know
key sequences versus modifier so this so
there's a lot a huge
unexplored area about shortcut
keybinding
layout okay so so anyway so on the
ergo keyboard i mean on the google
keyboard i have designed my own
kind of so you might you might try to
use it and this
layout is also optimized for soft light
keys i'm using if you are emacs user
software keys for example right now i'm
typing on logo keep
google keyboard okay i i
continuously rambled a lot is there any
questions so far
how good how how can you program on one
of these
then um what do you mean
so let me show you okay so google
keyboard you know
it uses these um
okay i guess jagen you are uh you are
not
uh are you into keyboard community
because
okay so if you are uh using one of these
do-it-yourself keyboard one of the most
popular software
is this qmk okay qmk is uh
the most powerful or almost the most
powerful software it's
open source for controlling uh key maps
and uh layout and shortcut layout you
know it
basically any aspect of keyboard so and
there are many
novel concepts that doesn't exist that
doesn't exist
in gaming keyboards for example you go
buy the most
expensive logitech gaming keyboard or or
cooler master or razer their
programmability is
actually much more inferior than than
the qmk because for example let me tell
you an example you have
you on the qmk keyboard you could have
you could have a a single
uh single use shift key
for example normally what the way you
press shift key is you hold it down
press the letter release letter then
release the shift okay that's a standard
but you could have a single press shift
key that's kind of like a sticky key
in operating system feature where you
you press the shift key
um release it you don't have to hold it
release it
then the next letter key is going to be
shifted
so so that's a single use shift
and you you could also have single use
modifier you know the such as control so
anyway so that's
and and these are built-in firmware you
know use the you use the qmk
to set the key into the memory on your
keyboard
so that's so qmk is a great uh software
i wouldn't say it's the greatest because
i know there's a
keyboard i o for example this keyboard
keyboard i o uh wait not here
keyboard i o they have their own version
of
keyboard software which is also the
greatest i
okay so yeah their version is also
open source i believe it's called
collido okay it's on github collido
uh so this is kind of in competition
in a sense in competition with qmk their
software i know
because i know the guy who who wrote the
collider software at least in part
you know he he he helped
so so that is also the greatest uh key
binding
software versus qmk
and also let me also tell you that
there is this one okay there is this one
ultimate hacking keyboard
which i have uh you have seen it before
i've showed it
a few times let me see if i can show it
um
so let me show you again okay so let me
show you
so you see i have my kinesis and this is
this is ultimate hacking keyboard right
now i'm using it as a keypad
you see pad 2. i'm using as a macro
keypad you know all shortcuts here for
example this key
is switched to last window for example
let me press it see
one key press instead of you know
holding alt
tab you know all tab is no good you and
then you have to wait and watch
which one we know you want you know this
is one single key press
and let me show you for example these
two keys this is
next window previous window you see
and for example i go here this key close
it
i want to reopen it reopen last
you see oh actually you are not seeing
the oh
actually yeah so actually you you
you missed my windows so anyway this is
a
switch to last window and and okay and
and go back to browser and this is the
previous window
previous tab next tab and so i have so
many
uh shortcuts
so let me get back to
okay so i've been talking a lot so um so
let me answer the questions okay so
google keyboard we're
talking non-stop this i haven't finished
the review yet
let me let me finish the review about
google i mean some criticisms
go keyboard so i showed you my layout
and i told you about the qmk great great
software and i was going to say the
ultimate hacking keyboard
they also have the greatest uh the most
easy to use and the most powerful
software i showed it before let me show
you
uh here you you uhk agent the most
easy to use pharma you know in terms of
ease to use is
far more better magnitude better than
qmk
qmk is actually hard to use because you
have to go to their website
then you have to do something on the
website then you have to download a
firmware you just generate it then you
have to download the firmware upgrade
you know the flasher then you have to
you know
put the firmware into your keyboard
that's tedious you have to be a nerd you
know you have to study qmmk
carefully on the other hand if you buy
the ultimate hacking keyboard you come
with this software the most
the most intuitive you don't have to
read you know and the most powerful is
yeah i would i would even claim as you
know
as powerful or even better than qmk
but anyway i'm giving you several uh
right now three examples of the most the
greatest
uh for uh
key mapping and firmware so one of them
is qmk this is most popular for
for for you open source fans okay qmk
and then ultimate hacking keyboard is a
great it's over
by the way it's also open source on
their website okay i have links
oh
i have links to it then the other great
uh software is the uh kaleidoscope i
believe
from the keyboard io
okay also open source so three of these
these three are the greatest
uh software uh for keyboard
for writing to keyboard firmware okay so
let's go back to google let me finish
up talking about google so google um we
talked about my layout then we talked
about
okay so that one i want to show you
there there are some
flaws of google which can be fixed okay
problem of google okay let me show you
okay so let me see what
comments you guys have comments okay
common questions i'm gonna
i'm going to read it
okay so yeah common in questions okay
comment
right now because i'm going to read it
soon so i'm going to show you google
what other problems okay
so you see these key caps are all flat
they are not you know the top you know
it's all flat this is no good
one of the problem i often have is that
i don't know
you know sometimes my fingers are on the
top row sometimes uh
one column left to the left you know and
i type and
it's a mistake so there is no
uh you know homing tit you know they you
know there's a
little thing on the key there's none
here
so it's all flat so this is no good
not make sure you want to um you want to
you you want to have keys with spherical
top let me show you okay so you go to
um you go to key history
let me show you no you go to key design
and you go to keyboard profile so so you
can see here are various keyboard
profiles okay let me put this
back oh god so many so
so i'm so busy talking and and
i want to keyboard profiles okay so you
look at
so these are some of the designs of
keyboard profiles
and one of them the most simple one is
is that let me show you here
um is like this every key looks exactly
the same
identical but anyway you see some of the
keys they have what's called spherical
top
so those little dents are actually
important you know
because when your fingers are on the
keys you can you can know you can know
you you can feel you are at the center
of the key
whereas if you are using this flat
goggle
you don't know by feel you know whether
you are in the center so it's
easy to move you know it's easy to place
your finger at the wrong
column or key so so one of the thing i
think it you need to do to fix google is
that you want to get a keycap
uh where is it then let's go back to
google
you want to get a keycap that's uh
that's a spherical top okay
uh yeah then
then you want to get you know spherical
top like this guy actually i think he's
this guy you see
you see you want to get a keycap with a
spherical top
and then you want to have a uh you know
homing guide for
for j and f on the js so so that you can
you can without looking you can put your
fingers on the right position
those are critical because oftentimes i
i put my fingers in the wrong column
it's hard to feel them
so that's one thing then then
the goggle doesn't have a case you see
at the bottom it's just a pcb that's no
good
because you put this this is super light
okay it's tiny
you put in a bag they hitch you know
they hit your clothes
and it's prompt to damage you see all
these uh
you see this usb uh plug it's prone to
prone to damage you see very
fragile so you do want the case
um so if you buy google i recommend you
actually
seriously consider that also the
the one i have is 50 grams okay
now let me talk about the switch the
goggle keyboard the switch here you see
is called uh chalk from china
from kyle okay kyle chuck key switch
they are very good they are very
low profile you know um let's see if i
can press
press it you see i don't know if you can
see it
but low profile and and linear
which is good but uh it's 50 grams the
one i got is 50 grams 50
you don't want 50 grams especially for
40 keyboard
because 40 percent keyboard means that
you have to press modifiers
all the time you know the thumbs
modifiers all the time
so you want you want a light um
you want a light key switch
so i would recommend you know 40 grams
or less
you know this guy they are crazy
actually they have key
they have key switches that's only like
12 grams i think
only 12 grams so it's feather light so
you like you can actually blow it
and to make it activate so he's talking
about you know how
great 12 grams are which i don't know
i haven't used yet you know the lightest
i've used is just 40 grams cherry mx red
so but i'm going to i think he's going
to send me a uh
a google play plex well let me show you
google play
you know you go to his website okay go
to his website
gboards that's his company he's in
canada
so he sells so here is a new model
googleplex
it's you know it's even less keys you
know it cuts down two rows it's
like 12 18 key less than google
so he's um so i think he's going to send
me google
plex and with a key switch that's much
lighter i forgot which
30 grams or something so i'm going to
tell you i'm going to do a review
and tell you how that feels so so you
don't want 50 grams okay if you go you
get anything like google you want
uh you you you want a lighter switch
so be sure to choose you know on his
website choose uh
something less than 40 grams less than
50 grams
so that's it my review so google
keyboard
40 and with my layout i think it's
it's fantastic okay and then
you do want a case definitely you you
need a case
to cover it then you you you want a
keycaps that's spherical top and you
want
um you want a homing key on the j
and f and you want a
less than 50 grams key
resistance 40 gram is good 40 grams or
less
okay that's what i have to say about
google keyboard
okay i'm going to uh read the comments
and review okay so i actually talked for
very long actually 41 minutes
i need to do review of my other things i
haven't done yet
okay so questions okay so questions
um
how can you program on one of these okay
so when you want to customize shortcuts
assuming quality standard hundred
percent
how do you know which key would be most
comfortable
ergonomic do you have recommendations
uh okay uh yeah i have a i have an
answer on that question
so this question came from joe de nino
okay so you go to my website
okay you go to my just search for saudi
keyboard okay
then you go to uh
you go to key binding okay so on this
section
let me magnify on this section it's all
about the science and art of key binding
how to choose which keys go where okay
now yeah key binding
notice like i said before it's different
from letter layout so
you have quality vorack those are letter
layout then you have a key binding
layout that's an entirely different
thing
because the it's more complex so
on this page you go to um
you go to this i believe here okay let
me see
uh
yeah so you go to here emax versus
stream compute
compute keybinding efficiency now on
this page i tell you
how do you determine which
sort of key binding is more efficient i
i give you
our line and this this issue is actually
fairly complex because it
in order to actually optimize it you
have to do linear programming which is a
you know computer science if you know
what i mean
there's a topic there's a subject called
linear programming you can go to
wikipedia and read about it so it's
actually very complex
it's much more complex than trying to
compute
which letter layout is the most optimal
so anyway you have the key binding okay
so so go to keybinding go to this page
compute keybinding efficiency i'll give
you a guide
about how how do you actually determine
uh which key binding is more efficient
for example
for example let's say a quality layout
on a normal pc keyboard
is ctrl t more efficient
or is it for example f
f8 let's say the f8 key you know on one
hand f8 is further away
but it's all but it's one single key
press you know you just move your hand
one single key press
on the other hand control t you know
it's
you know you have to press ctrl
depending you have to hold down control
and press t
but it's you don't have to move your
hand so much but which one is more
efficient so that's a question you have
to determine
and also it depends on your keyboard for
example if i'm using google
then control key is obviously some
somewhere on my thumb so it's easier but
on a normal standard pc keyboard
it's on a corner it's hard to press so
you have to use the palm technique
or maybe you you mapped to the caps lock
in that case it's easier but then you
are abusing your pinky you you might get
pinky problems
so there are a lot of issues but anyway
i give you an outline
in this page um you know i'm talking
about
which one is more efficient okay so
that's
i hope that answers that question does
that make sense
uh joe joe nino
now let me drink my energy drink
actually i have a
kind of jamba juice here
so nubu ku
ku says what is a keyboard called
that was in the thumbnail before the
stream
went live okay that is this google
keyboard
wait wait no oh oh no that's that's um
wait i know what you're talking about
actually i should i'm going to change
the thumbnail to google
but the one you are talking about let me
show you that's
that's that's this one okay it's a
do-it-yourself keyboard from china
i have it here somewhere okay here
okay let me magnify there so it's just a
random keyboard on
um on on a chinese website someone
created
it with full details on how they
designed it and stuff
and by the way this volume wheel uh
is becoming popular among do-it-yourself
community we begin to see
quite a few of it and volume wheel by
the way let me tell you what volume
volume wheel the knob or wheel kind of
thing is a great
feature on keyboard you do want that
okay so i have a page that's a survey of
of
all kind of volume volume wheel designs
for example this
is a dash 4 and this is common in
logitech
and then you have the dell which is also
you know this type of knob is common in
stereo you know
then you have this flat disk design uh
you know the so you have also a design
you know you actually you do want a
volume wheel volume i talked about this
before volume wheel
is great for many type of control for
example sound volume
sound level up and down that you want
that because that is the most efficient
way
uh to control to to increase and
decrease
for example you can you can control in a
very in in very uh fine precision
how fast you want to the volume to go up
or down and physical because you can
it how fast it goes up depends on how
fast you twist
the wheel as opposed to on a typical
keyboard you have the
buttons you know buttons for increasing
volume for example on the mac
keyboard stupid apple mac keyboard you
know
you press the button to increase the
volume that's no good because then you
have to
you have to repeat it and sometimes you
if you hold it down it overshoots
then you have to you know rev that's no
good so volume queer
it's not just for sound it's also for
controlling any type of motion for
example squatting
mouse wheel for example scrolling you
can find it fine tune
exactly how much you want you know and
also you can control the speed you know
so you want about volume feel i talked
about this
and also for uh things like tab okay
for example okay i'm going to
show you okay for example tab tab
is also one of the things you want the
volume here too
for example i could if i wanted to to
con
to um to set my mouse wheel to
to to uh switch the tabs right now
you are seeing you see i'm using a
shortcut
you know previous tab next tab you know
but if you have a volume wheel
especially clicky one you know
like click click clicky one you
it's it's actually more sufficient so
ideally
for a power station you actually do want
several volume wheels you want
you want four or five volume wheels one
is for previous tab next tab
another wheel click wheel for
next window previous window okay another
wheel for
cruiser forward backward another wheel
for cruiser forward backward by word
okay when you are doing a lot of editing
so actually
you want four or five million wheels and
some of them you want to be clicky type
some of them
you want to be spin for example i showed
you the logitech
spin wheel there's a video on my
website you can see um let me go to a
long page
so you can see you see my
okay here so let me go to
okay so you see uh wait
so right now it's clicky i don't want to
click here i press this button now it's
spin
okay you see you see how it's spinning
you so so for some kind of command you
wanted to spin
for some kind of command the optimal
physical wheel is a
clicky wheel
so actually i talked a lot there
actually there are several topics we
haven't
uh i wanted to talk about but we
we we so today it's all about keyboards
we talked about a lot about keyboard
issues
keyboarding issues and um
so let's see what you guys saying okay
so what's the next
any uh more questions type it right now
it's a good time
okay let me have a sip of my power drink
what do you think of speech-based text
input
okay that is pretty good as that is good
of
if the content of your
typing is speech oriented for example
for example right now talking or talking
to your mom
or chat that's good but speech
speech based input as ever
as of today is not so good if you are
going to write poetry
or if you're going to write uh technical
documentation
or if you are going to program you know
to do programming
because the current technology of speech
recognition
is you know machine learning based
basically based on statistics
so they they have lots of data that's
oriented towards common speech for
example good morning goodbye
how you doing today if i say that you
know google google knows on youtube you
go to youtube
you know you click on you know show show
um
caption you know you know you'll show
what i'm talking about
but it's not so good for programming if
you are going to
program they don't understand what you
are you know doing
so yeah but however there are people who
i have a video i mean i have a page you
know search for
sally search for xally emacs using voice
to type faster than keyboard okay there
are people who did that
uh let me show you okay uh
okay so so new page
wait what am i doing okay so yeah so
search for
xrd
using voice type faster
okay something like that
using voice to code faster than keyboard
so there's this guy this is five years
ago
seven years ago he actually created a
system
a voice recognition system that is
designed
for programming so when you watch his
video he do things like uh
the fall back you know things like that
he utter
these chirps to control you know to tell
the computer
move the cruiser backward one word or
forward one word to beginning of line
uh insert parenthesis insert you know
brackets
and insert the for loop you know things
like that so he
very efficient so but this system is not
common yet you know if
you know what i mean by common is what's
available on iphone on google you know
you know siri okay google you know those
are
already there but if you want to use
these you have to buy
for example he's he's actually using you
have to buy the dragon
uh voice software then you have to do
lots of customization you have to be a
nut
anyway so you go read that article you
can see
um so next question thank you guys i
wonder if you have
any personal preferences yourself i'm
for you familiar with your pages about
computing personal efficiency
okay what do you mean by personal
preferences about key binding
about shortcut layout design yeah of
course i have my
uh opinions i have for example if you
are a emac user
you might try my uh my system
some fly keys okay you know that that is
my that is my result
of my like 15 years of study on key
binding and
experimenting on key binding so stuff
like keys
it's for emacs um you know you might try
it
try it it's a model it's a model
like vim but the key choices is based on
frequency of the command and the ease of
finger positions
so that's stuff like keys i have a
tutorial on there
okay so that's about that and of course
otherwise
outside of my i mean i have tons of
shortcuts but
but that's another topic because you
know i'm gonna talk about that for one
hour
but basically in the past few years i
started to
uh let me tell you guys okay so i
recommend i highly recommend
that you buy a keyboard uh let me show
you okay you buy a keyboard that
um you buy
a programmable keyboard with onboard
memory
okay so i have a list here
so this is a bunch of programmable
keyboards with onboard memory i
recommend them
you know if you like ergonomic ones or
there's a pc
you know one piece pc flat ones so you
you want
a keyboard with onboard memory
programmable one
so in in the past three years i started
to
exclusively always use a programmable
keyboard
because before that before that i use
the operating
operating system to remap keys for
example on the mac you have
you have for example let me show you my
articles
you go to software on the mac
you typically use you use carabiner
elements okay this is the most powerful
um operating system based
key map software okay on windows on
windows you use
auto hard key okay that's the most
powerful key remap software on windows
and on the mac on the on linux you have
a bunch of
crap okay you have x mode map you have
quite a few others
uh i have i have you know 10 10
20 articles tutorials on them you know
what they do
how to do them how to remap keys how to
make your
uh control to caps things like that yeah
you know
so these are operating system based
key remapping software and they are no
good they are inferior because they
always always have glitches and they
always have issues for example
for example on windows for example
the windows l key for locking a window
that key you cannot reprogram it with
any of this software you cannot
reprogram it
unless you actually dive deep you'll be
you know i'm not going to go into
details yes
and similarly on the mac for example on
the mac there are certain keys you
cannot be bind
for example um
um there are certain keys you cannot be
bind with the
max system-wide um
uh um key binding um
system for example let me show you okay
there's carabiners there's also
um you know
there are many ways okay i'm not going
to go into them today about
you know because it's a different topic
but but what i'm saying go back to what
i'm saying i'm saying is that
for the past five years i started to
rely
exclusively on programmable keyboard you
want to program the firmware
you don't want the keyboard to send a
signal to your operating system
then another layer in operating system
tries to change that key to something
else because there's always problems
okay so but just just spend just go put
down two hundred dollars three hundred
dollars
for a programmable keyboard okay
so that's that and go go to my website
and use
you know buy it from me for my amazon
links okay
uh okay that's it for today i
i i talked about quite a lot of things
okay uh
also x mode map requires x or exactly
that's one of the
problems you know glitches with these
software-based
um key remapping software you know on
linux
you can use x mode map to remap software
but
that only works if you are running in
x11
so sometimes when you boot to you know
if you put to a single user mod
or boot screen you need to change your
disk
configuration or something then all of a
sudden
your key doesn't work anymore because
you know you you were used to x mob
x map under x11 but one day you know
your key stop working and you oh my god
i realized oh i was because i was using
xml map
then you have to start to look at your
keys you know always this is glitches
like that same thing with the auto hard
key
and also another advantage of keyboard
firmware you know programmable keyboard
is that you take the keyboard anywhere
to your work
to your friend's place plug it in
doesn't matter what operating system mac
or windows it works
okay on the other hand if you use you
know the
operating system based way you take
you bought a new computer or you take it
to work you have to
you have to spend hours to reconfigure
you know on that on that computer to
install software or whatever you know
so it's so so no good
okay actually uh how long have we been
talking
one hour i think okay one hour so that's
that's a long one so three more minutes
okay guys
i'm gonna wrap up three more minutes
so these smiles we haven't talked about
today
i'll do it next time i have it here
i was going to tell you you know i was
going to give you a review but
in short i record i highly recommend it
okay
i do recommend this one uh
and i was going to talk about that you
know i wanted to talk about several
things okay let me show
let me see
uh where are we so
google keyboard we talked about fully
and many related issues typing tutorial
okay
let's skip that qmk
okay my tutorial about qmk uh
then okay one last thing okay let me
show you so i discovered this keyboard
this
is the best okay this one if you are
you know one of those who wants a pc
keyboard you know you don't want split
keyboard you don't touch type or
something
you don't want ergonomic keyboard you
think they are weird you think they are
expensive
you know you you just want a normal pc
keyboard okay
then i recommend this one okay this
from this actually is from china apple
maker that's the brand name
and this model name is nice plume okay
you just
go to my website sally uh keyboard
nice broom you go to my website read my
review
i think this is a one of the greatest uh
you know one of the greatest um model
you know for for for those of you who
are just who wants a flat
pc keyboard they have several models by
the way they have so
that you you know you have the full uh
sized one or you have the
you know 10 keyless compact ones
anyway why is it so great i you know
because
many reasons first of all it's
programmable okay
in comparison to other for example among
keyboard nerds
you know they like happy hacking
keyboard for
i have all of them shown here uh
actually here
you know among keyboard nerds you you
like happy hacking
or you like fioco or you like real force
or you like you know leopold you know
for example
here's a real force here's a deal port
and here's happy hacking they are very
expensive they are like
200 300
and but they they they are crap
okay they are crap in my opinion they
are the worst ship
extremely uh expensive
and not programmable imagine not
programmable
no onboard memory but these nuts you
know they just like these
happy hacking and leopold and you know
and real force
you know these are the classic high
quality
keyboards even in two year 2000s because
you know
beginning around year 2013
the mechanical keyboard became popular
you know then we started to have lots of
gaming keyboards
that's mechanical then people start to
talk about mechanical keyboards
everyone is on the trend you know but
these
leopold reaffirms they are the classic
very expensive high quality ones
they talk about keycaps you know
top and toe for you know key switches
anyway
so these are the classic greatest
keyboards that
the keyboard nerds admire especially
especially the happy hacking
but but they are no good okay in terms
of
functionality that's the that's what i'm
concerned about the most
functionality efficiency operational
efficiency and functionality
pure functionality i don't care about
looks i don't care
you know many notes they talk about
whether you can twist the keyboard you
know they like to twist it
they like to you know they like thick
keycaps the crap
you know they they like heavy you know
many of these nuts when they
do keyboard review they'll say oh this
is heavy this is great
you don't want heavy you know look at
space you know look at the spaceships
you you want you want material science
you want the
material that is the hardest possible
and also the lightest possible
that's science okay you don't want heavy
you know i mean for example
i i show you many of the nerds
they they custom build certain apple you
know keyboard that's
the whole thing is metal like it weighs
five kilograms literally let me show you
um literally let me
let me show you okay keyboards history
um
uh we we go to yeah we go to normal
keyboards
then we go to apple keyboards let's say
apple keyboard history okay then you
have this one okay this macintosh
uh m01 this is
you know one of the classic many of the
keyboard nerds admire okay
they spend a few hundred dollars to buy
to buy this keyboard then there is this
extreme keyboard nuts who creates a
duplicate now this one the entire thing
is made of metal okay
a weights literally like a break brick
okay i i know because this this photo is
my wait this photo is not mine but i
went to the
uh keyboard meetup so i actually seen it
you know actually seeing it somewhat you
know they make this
they three kilograms this thing weights
three kilograms and these nuts just love
it okay
not that's not for me so i i care about
efficiency you know operational
efficiency and
also the mapping the shortcut mapping
and so on you know
what is the utmost efficient the least
finger movements
possible things like that many of these
issues
uh these traditional keyboard nerds they
don't consider at
all it's like outside of their thinking
for example you go to
geek hack gig hack.org
is the classic keyboard nerds
forum and also then there's a desk
authority
just search for desk authority it's like
one word they made up you know that
those those websites are the
keyboard nerds they go to they talk
about
they talk talk about electronics of
keyboards you know the adreno chips or
whatever
the soldiering the the the key
cap technology you know what kind of
plastic
the key switch technology they did they
are into that okay they
you know in depth you know they are
nerds you know they talk about that in
depth
but but you see these people they
they usually there are certain aspects
about keyboards that they never
ever look into such as key binding
efficiency
you will you will never see see them
talk about it you know the the concept
doesn't exist in their mind
you know also you talk to the emacs
people the vim people
they they every day they'll tell you oh
emacs is great or even it's great or
model this like that
but they never actually spent 10 minutes
to think about the issue
what what issue issue the scientific
measurement
of shortcut mapping which
way is more efficient you know things
like that i think about
you know uh anyway uh so what was the
question i was
uh digressing into um
okay x mode map okay uh intimate
idiotic people he thinks one one okay
mission complete
okay that's it for today uh 17 people
still watching
how long have been talking
108 okay we don't we don't mind we don't
mind talking for long
long videos okay as long as we are doing
good
um yes i think that's it for today
um okay summary okay go to my website
if you are in usa you buy from amazon
buy from my website let's so i'm going
to
see uh wait go back uh whether
we what am i going to talk about
okay so
so yeah i was talking about this uh nice
plume okay i think this is a great one
okay that's it that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
subscribe buy my tutorials emacs
tutorials in javascript in depth
and bye guys
enjoying discord okay fantastic
people
okay join this code sorry disco let's
see
let me go close the goodbye take care
you