good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is July 31st year 2019 and now
it's 6 o clock in the afternoon San
Francisco time and today we have a goal
we are going to talk about Emacs the
greatest editor on earth and I'm going
to do some live coding of Emacs Lisp and
also explain how it works you know so
you are going to learn some Emacs Lisp
and feel free as usual feel free to ask
me questions you know anything related
to Emacs and right now I have zero
person watching so let's talk about some
random Emacs things so that maybe you
know when people will come so I went so
there's a Emacs conference Emacs me wait
ok there is a Emacs conference 2019 good
morning guys
say hi okay so we gonna talk about Emacs
today and some light coating of Emacs
Lisp feel free to ask questions you know
just type it so we're going to you know
so there's a Emacs conference 2019 so
check check it it out check it out and
this phone interesting Hayes
justin hays Jones good evening good
evening where are you where are you from
like what city what state what country
so Emacs conference 2019
looks like is this is a this is a
virtual conference meaning that
everything is taking place online so you
know check it check it out and someone
emailed me you know asking me whether
I'm going to do a presentation you know
X conference I'm not sure but since
someone asked you know maybe I have to
check I have to get to check out what's
a date you know what's the schedule
oh hi from hi to Vancouver I lived in
Vancouver Canada for half a year around
1986 then I lived there then I moved to
a Montreal Canada and I lived there for
three years
good morning king herring in king
herring so the this Emax conference is a
virtual online one so you know check it
out
but what date is it so let's see em
excellent conference is a MF Kampf is
the conference about the joy of Emacs mi
crisp and memoir memorizing sequences we
are putting things together for Emacs
comp 2018 and we need your help to make
Emacs conference amazing see our call
for proposals okay let's check Co for
proposals get involved and help spread
the word yes indeed help spread the word
Def Con so King herring says are you
going to Def Con I guess not because you
need a car you need a wizard and Def Con
is about what is about hack is about
encryptions related yeah because I don't
have a car and you know I don't have
money to go you know I haven't been you
know going out for me for decades so
anyway so this eMac eMac some friend
this year we are holding Emacs humph
as a online conference we haven't fully
decided on the details in the need and
the needed infrastructure yet but using
as much as free software as possible and
ideally only free software for this is a
priority for us yes because it's part of
the you know the Emacs
political situation you know the free
software foundation so if you know you
should support for free software as
opposed to open source you know free
software foundations idea of free
software so so free software and C
planning page if you would like to get
involved okay let's have a look at that
and they have handout on IRC IRC free
not net okay so let's see Co for
proposals called Co for proposals
they're gonna important dates CFP openko
for proposal opens July 29th
okay so July to August 31st that's your
chance to submit proposals for talk
speaker notifications schedule published
October 1st okay so the Emacs conference
2019 is November 2nd oh that's you know
that's near the holidays so lighting
talks standard talk extended talks so
maybe I'll give you know I'm thinking
maybe I'll you know I could give a talk
lighting talk 10 minutes old or standard
top 20 minutes and you know I might talk
about stuff like keys which is the key
binding I'm using it seems what you you
know people will like that you know so
maybe that yeah so check it yeah so you
know check it out so let's see King
Harry and says Las Vegas it's a security
conference right okay mostly black hat
you know those Def Con those kind of
those kind of you know encryption
security conferences they go over my
head you know like like sometimes you
read about them
they they so called hackers you know the
serious hackers they you know yeah yeah
I you know it'd be nice to go but you
know you know in Las Vegas so it's gonna
cost you know a few hundred dollars to
go so also oh by the way is there anyone
from mountain view area if you are
interested we could go together you know
I pay you know a half of the share of
the you know ticket or whatever so yeah
if you are if anyone is interested in
that you know going with me then we
could do that you know I just go there
to see actually because I have never
been so so sorry
you are also Kassar you are some form of
wizard demigod thank you so Justine says
it's neat that it's online last time he
was in London I think and I couldn't
make it okay so you could really do a
talk yes definitely do a talk okay yeah
okay thank you for in the encouragement
because I wasn't sure because usually
you know you can say I'm kind of weird
I'm of you know like when I do a talk
I'm afraid it's not going well let's see
am i doing okay here let's see okay my
face and voice yes okay like sometimes I
you know the the voice went off and I
didn't know for a long time so let's go
back to the okay so we are but we are
going to start to do live coding you
know let's talk about Emacs and Emacs
this stuff so King Harry sa C++ for
Emacs is kind of lackluster I wish I
were better any suggestions
what do you mean see first press for
Emacs is lackluster if actually if you
consider all languages Emacs would be
best for C and C++ actually yeah that's
a strong point of Emacs as far as I know
because yeah I'm pretty sure of that
you know because so what what what is
Emacs not good for typically Java you
know if you are a Java code Emacs has
you know lots of problems of course some
people really some people have different
opinions they say oh you just need so
this package and this this you know
fairly complicated configuration then
Emacs will be great for Java but but the
typical opinion is Emacs if you coding
Emacs I mean if you code in Java you
probably better off with some other data
that's you know that's a common opinion
but for C++ I think that's one of the
Emacs strong point but however I don't
have any answers because I don't code C
or C++ I don't know them at all the best
thing I've done is hello would it would
be hard-pressed for me to to to write a
HelloWorld in C right now but you know
this is one thing entry ID you know I
don't like C at all but okay let's let's
focus on Emacs it's not you know because
I'm going to start to talk you know half
an hour about C and C you know stuff so
in so King Harry is you know in San Jose
oh it's next week so you are going to
the DEF CON so autocomplete an error
message and stuff I see irony mod and
it's alright but it's hard to configure
and works with clan only yeah QT creator
is really comfy yeah I don't know
anything about c-plus
hello brother z lk y okay
justine says i use emacs for this Elise
Ruby and closure yeah those are good
I've done more or less or all those and
it's Emacs is is great but I would use
what your visual code for sleepers Percy
okay oh that's interesting
so King herring says okay different
response they expected I thought you
would rant about how see first Percy
scrap yeah I was about to but you know
today you know let's focus on Emacs this
you know Emacs stuff okay so let's let's
let's let's do that then okay so this
Emacs conference it's good to go let me
mention another thing so there's a Emacs
meet up San Francisco
okay so you just go you know search for
Emacs meet up sand San Francisco okay
I've been going there like five times
also in the past two years and it's
fantastic so if you live in Bay Area
it's good thing you meet Emacs people
and Jeff draw this guy he organized it
with help of other people and he's a
great guy you know he's very great guy
and he's a very a smooth guy you know
he'd eat talk in a gentle way and in a
organized manner you know and he's by
the way he's a see first first coder
okay so if you have the cheapest first
questions may be asked him and he also
he has also done talks about tsipras
first I think he you know with Emacs of
course I think he's been doing his
simplest first for like 10 years or 20
years or more you know you know so he's
tsipras was expert
and so I went there actually last week
when the July 24th you know and I met
John Wiggly John Wiggly he's a guy who
is the current maintainer of Emacs and
he's also of course he's a Emacs least
expert and he is also he's also a
Haskell expert and he is also a compiler
expert as far as I know he's been
working on compilers as his job for like
10 or 20 years
so John Wiggly I met him you know he's
giving a talk about oak mod and several
other people as well and yeah another
guy was you know another guy is this
kitchen I think his name is John kitchen
wait something kitchen okay I'm sorry
like kitchen you know like that's his
last name
he is a chemist professor at Cana CMU
you know which is a you know one of the
top university but anyway he I think
that C's anyway he also he's also a
expert oak mod and you know he wrote
this scientific computing package sigh
let's let's look okay let's
junk kitchen okay that's his name I
believe let's see
jankoji musician Emacs okay let's see
okay yeah this is him okay J this is him
John kitchen so he yeah that's him
I met him once once you know and I you
know he and and I and so he's one of the
big Emacs least expert and also he this
is a huge package he he showed me one
time sign max okay it's a you know tens
of thousand or tens of thousands lines
Omo and you know if you are a oke mod
user and if you are a professor or if
you do scientific publishing this is a
good thing to look into okay so let's
see let's see the comments
do you do some Python the jungle I never
did the jungle but I do code Python just
for my own things for you know many
years
you know so yeah so I have a it's nits -
a plug okay so I have a python tutorial
yeah let's do plugs you know support
sorry so I have a pad on a yeah I
started to learn Python in 2005 you know
I it was a Perl code in a web dev you
know we do e-commerce you know I I
called it Perl for like four years every
day for eight hours a day then I
switched to Python and you know but
mostly doing my you know almost on
scripts so anyway you know for you guys
interested in languages I have mini
tutorial some languages I would HIGHLY
you know some of them are very good I
would say you know well you know yeah
it's related good the good ones are
JavaScript in depth and Emacs Lisp you
can check them out
Python is okay and Golan is also pretty
good you know Python : my tutorials are
good for beginners but javascript my
JavaScript tutorial is rather very much
in depth you know more in depth then you
know III would create more in depth in
you know in in a printed book you by
Andy Mac sleep please and typically you
know my you know Emacs list tutorial you
know because they are actually not many
you know eMac these tutorials out there
you know this almost doesn't exist so
anyway so well let's get let's get back
and focus on Emacs that's what we're
gonna do today let's see how do I been
going five people okay
so okay I am Kumi dev seems much smaller
in Vancouver
justin hays honestly I haven't been to
many meetups okay oh yeah King hearings
since you are inside say yeah you should
definitely John kitchens YouTube videos
on AG mod was was what opened my eyes to
oak oh yeah it's great hey Dan so please
share your website here a friend
recommended your videos please share
your website here what do you mean you
mean the URL okay I'll post it okay
let's let's do Emacs it's let's start
okay this so there is the that's not
enough about that so let's let's go to
top there's something I want to do on
the left window you can see all the
Emacs commands I call so when you see
I'm doing something you are not sure
what it is you can see the command names
here and for my commands you know they
start with saw and typically they are
also on my website you just search the
name you'll find it okay so there are
two things I want to do so I have this
sign new page commands let me show you
the code okay so let's call describe
function is a new page and you can see
here's the documentation for the
function you just create a new new new
file new new file for my blog you know
on my website and you can go to the link
you know that shows the source code so
by the way this is a great way to go to
jump to any fire any Emacs list file for
example I I don't remember you know
which file is this command in so you
know typically whenever you have some
Emacs this file you can just call this
scrap function and you know given the
name
and you'll show the documentation with a
link to the source code so this is a one
efficient way like a bookmark you know
one efficient way to open open any Emacs
Lisp file so here's a code so what this
code does is basically oh my god it's
longer than I expected so what what this
code does is basically let me show you
what it does okay so if I go to my Emacs
blog you know and let's say section so I
create a new section and I say something
okay make a paragraph showing browser
you see there's something now I want to
create a you know I have lots of files
in my Emacs website you know lots of
them so so if I want to create a new
file so what do you do
let's see how to XYZ okay so in browser
how to XY Z you know how to do something
you know tired or whatever windows or
whatever I want to create a new file so
typically that is tedious you know you
have to create a new buffer save it how
to XYZ okay dot HTML and make it
underlined okay then you have to insert
the HTML you know template then you need
title then you need you know footers and
you know navigation bar like you know
it's very tedious so typically what I do
is let's delete that okay
delete a file so typically what I do is
I go to the directory and open you know
open like like copy let's see let's
let's go here somewhere you know copy
your file for example this file
Emacs command so you can see I
I copy it then I say something takes
something X Y Z dot html' okay now I
just create copied a new file then I
open it
showing browser you know this is the old
page I changed the name like I don't
need that anymore
then change the title something X Y Z
okay I have lots of commands that help
me do that so so that and also all that
I don't need delete them okay
and showing browser so these kind of
give me a you know kind of a new
template then I start to type you know
so today I want to do XYZ and this is
how to do it okay so I started to put
content so I copy the file path close it
close it you know I in here I you know
paste the file path link if I delete
that make a paragraph showing browser so
you see something X Y Z that's how I
create a new file showing browser then
you know then I can start to write about
that page that's tedious so what I have
so let's open that delete it so instead
of doing that I just say something X Y Z
okay I just type that in call saw new
page that's a command you know press
Enter
it's done it automatic it automatically
create the file I can open it show in
browser you see with every templates and
you know the Google tracker you know
Google and you know so it does that all
for me by the way you can use a Emacs
Marco for that
you know if you don't want to cody max
lease that much but typically if you
want it to be faster with remote control
fine control it's better to write impact
lease code so anyway so I have that
command that's why it does so let's look
at the code again it's our new page okay
describe function go to the file and
here's a code okay you see first of all
it we have a direct to your map of
directories like if if my the current
file is on this directory then use this
file name as template because I have
several websites and each website they
have different templates you know so
typically the template is based on the
current directory like you know you can
copy a file in that directory then that
that template would be good for that
directory so first of all we have a map
of directory you know depending on which
directory you are in you you know then
use a particular file as the template
now basically this code just just do
what we did before to create a new file
it essentially copy you know copy you
know for example if I am on for example
if I'm on Emacs my Emacs directory it
will just copy this file you know Emacs
logo file then removes you know the the
content of that file then you know it
becomes empty like that okay so actually
I should so what am i doing so yeah so
what but what do we need to do today so
there's a issue I like to fix or modify
for example sometimes let's say you know
some
for example Emacs so you for example I
have a text here and I want to create a
new page you know you new file based on
that name but you notice there's a slash
there now slash is no good because it's
a directory separator if I caucus a new
page it will start to trying to find the
directory over there you know something
you know but it doesn't exist so that's
no good
so basically I like to modify the
command so that whenever you see a slash
or comma or or any any kind of question
mark or you know like that remove them
you know remove them just make it just
make them like that instead you know so
that's that's what I like to do modify
the code so let's go back to the code
oops I did something wrong
do I want to save no oh yeah I tried to
hike change you see that's a problem
that is a problem we just talked about
because I just called
I just caught a new page on this line
and what it's going to do is is trying
to create a file name with all these you
know characters you know with these you
know that's no good when that happens
it's confusing because you don't know
you know sometimes creates random file
names in your directory and you is hard
to find them you know so that that is
what we are trying to fix so let's go
through back to the code and let's see
how we gonna fix it let's narrow to
region narrow to rejoin is a great
command so you only see the part you are
interested so let's let me read some
comments
I follow that github so a friend
recommended your videos please share
your insight okay so see what did you do
to underline the space spaces in the
file name okay yeah that's a convene
very convenient command so you know
remember to check out the left panel
because that shows all the command for
example something okay something this or
that okay we are in eMac list let's go
back to let's cook of Anubhava okay
something this nab okay I want to
suppose I want that to be a file name so
you want underscore so I can press the
key you see they'd be all become
underscore or I can press the key again
they all become - so that command is
called there you see saw psycho -
underscore space you know that's very
convenient so I press it again then it
becomes all spaces again so if you just
search that name you'll find you know
the code my website very convenient so
close that so we need to modify these
let me read the comments again so how
would you suggest mapping an Elise
program to a Firefox web extension like
I want to be able to categorize my
browser tabs and then save it in Emacs I
have a project that saves my tabs into
Jason so how how do you suggest mapping
and Elise program to a Firefox web
extension I don't know how how that
would be done but I know who I know who
would have the answer for that there is
this great Emacs and Emacs list
expert his name is Christopher
Wellington I think and his website is no
program okay
let's search for it no program is his
website and he has written packages that
that deal that interacts that connects
Emacs with browser Firefox you know in
JavaScript or things like that
so that when you code Emacs when you
code JavaScript in Emacs the Firefox we
wrote automatically update something
like that and you can also call fire you
know you are calling the JavaScript
engine from the Firefox you know
JavaScript engine from Emacs so he he
has that package I forgot the name but
anyway you can go to his github let's go
to his github it's you know it's you
know he's a very advanced coder you know
he code this usually when you code the
extensions like that it's fairly
complicated advanced so so the mod is
SKU amount okay you know I actually
haven't tried it so skewered live web
development within Emacs so you might
check it out so I'm pretty sure he would
know the answer to your question and
also he's famous for L feat alpha'd is a
RSS feeder in Emacs so you in Emacs you
can read all the blogs blog blog as you
follow you know within Emacs which is
very good application by itself you know
L feed so he's that guy he I think he
code mostly in C or C prospers I mean he
is that type of guy you know you know
low-level kind of guy yeah so you know
you might check it out
as far as you know grabbing Firefox tabs
I looked into that one time because I
also have the need you know for example
I have so many tags you know tabs right
now like 20 tabs I want to look you know
I have I want to get a list of all the
links you know of the tabs so one time
you know this is like five years ago I
looked into
so apparently Firefox preferences there
was you know there's there used to be
like bookmarks I think you know
something but anyway as us go they
changed everything to binary so these
days I don't think you actually have a
file for books mugs or things like that
everything is like binary in a database
you know SQL they use SQLite so you have
to I think that's what you have to look
into which is gets complicated so you
know so you have to look into api's for
Firefox SQLite and things like that then
it takes the Jason yeah I don't know how
to do that so thank you thank you
nice another follow I already have the
Firefox tabs grabber okay so you already
have the Firefox
tab grabber and basic transition to oak
mod okay so you already have that so how
do you do that let's look at Kenny
malloc we keep Phi
so Kenny Malik we keep fine
oh this this this doesn't have a readme
so okay by the way is that your is that
your is this your project but this
project needs a readme because anyway so
so let's go back to the Sonia page so
let's I think we finished doing modify
this and I'll be it for today because
it's okay 36 minutes let's see if we can
do that so what we need to do is we need
to do some kind of find replace okay so
so in this code let's see so the current
path is spot file name so so let's
refresh on what we need to do so we need
to grab the current the line cursor is
at then we need to replace any slash by
our space let's say that's what we need
to do so let's look at a code so
directory path temp file name so which
line is it so file name directory so
this this is the current directory okay
so so this path is the current directory
this this curve F path is the the path
of the current
buffer the file is the koozai zone so so
cur file path is the path of the kusa
the koozai zone so so this is just a
directory of that then temp file name is
okay Tim foul name it tries to look up
the path map you see it tries to look up
into this map so so the temp file name
is actually just a file name like that
okay so this is how you look up you know
this map is actually called associated
beast okay so if you don't know now
associated least okay so not here let's
go back to let's go back to my Emacs
blog
okay so Emacs blog so associated list is
one of the Emacs P odine data structure
which is also in any least common lisp
or scheme this and associated file list
associated list is is basically a like
key value pairs it's like a hash table
but a little bit different so you can
see a tutorial my tutorial here
Association B's yeah that's the name
associate Association B's it is actually
just at least okay but each item is a
pair so anyway you can read that if you
are if you don't know let's go back to
our code let's try to finish that code
okay so this is actually this is the
Association list and temp name is how we
get you know the value you know from a
key okay so okay so far so good but
actually we don't have the current line
yet what we want is you know the line
the cruiser is that
so that would be these I think no that
would be wait when is that
so once you see once we find that
variable you know the it contains you
should contains the value of the current
line the kusa is that once we find that
then we can just do find replace on that
string then everything is solved so the
task now is to find that line where the
where the heck is that dying so if I
exist
oh here okay we got screwed up you see
so we have here all these are local
variables you know from the left that is
how you specify local variables so here
we have a bunch of local variables this
is one of them and here is the value
then here's another one of the local
variable and here's the value and so we
have a bunch of them and also here p1 is
the beginning position of the cursor the
line beginning position of the cursor I
I overlooked because you see you see how
these are colored in tark doing and both
but this p1 is not because those colored
in dark green because they start with a
dollar sign you know that's just my own
convention you know you don't have to
have dollar sign you know you don't need
that but because the p1 doesn't start
that so so that's why it's not colored
you know I'm using my own saw Emacs this
mod so those are not color that's why I
didn't I fail to look you know look into
them so so actually the line we are
interested is is this this variable file
name base ok so why don't we do some
find replace and make them into a dollar
sign in front so change that change that
there it is you see now it's green and
also let's change that okay so let's
change the f path let's add a dollar
sign change no change change
change no change okay now you see now
it's all green so the the variable we
are interested is this you see so what
the code is doing is if first of all it
finds p1 and p2 p1 and p2 are like
position like position kusa position 1
in post whose a position - they are the
line beginning and line end position ok
then you say you know you extract the
line you make that into a string you
know and we want to name it title 1 so
let's let's add a top dollar sign here
dollar sign title 1 ok so we change with
so that's the string though so the
current line is saved to the variable
title 1 ok then we transform the title 1
by removing and is any any sequence of
spaces by an underscore and name that
file name base you see that's the
interesting part that's what we want so
what we have to do is actually we we
repeat that that's all we have to do so
let's see let's do that ok so this is
the line of interest so we actually want
to do that again we want to replace any
backslash by a underscore ok so actually
here is what we want okay enemy okay
hold on a second let me make it clear so
you can actually see clearly what is
going on okay
so originally originally we have this
line now the new line should be I'm
gonna show you how how the new line
should be the new line should be piece
okay okay so this is how the new line
should be so so this is you see this is
the old line one second so let me make
the code more legible okay so here is
the old code here is the new code wait
this is not right yet yeah so here is so
this is a new code so what the code does
is first of all first of all you know
you know take the title replace the
backslash by a underscore okay that's
that then we down case it then we do
okay so we we do the replacement again
so yeah so first of all bleep we replace
sequence of space by underscore we down
case it then we replace any backslash I
mean / by under school we don't need to
down case anymore so actually so so yeah
so so that that is what we want so
actually comment that up so actually we
just quickly fix this so we did the fix
so now we eval
I'm going to read the comments okay so
let's finish this first
I'm going to eval eval this Tiffany
Vodafone go back to the code go back to
the go back to my Emacs okay so go back
to my my blog okay
programming block so okay now let's try
it some slash thing ABC okay
now let's cook some new page it should
walk ish it should the expected result
is that you will create a file named
that okay let's try it it's a new page
yay it looks like it did so open the
file view in browser yes success so good
we finish that part so yeah that's you
know that's good so so that commands a
new page is a new page let's describe
function you know so we we did that so
let's change the version date July 31st
okay so that's actually done and this is
actually in my Emacs in it so we can
just get status ok many changes let's
upload it so you you can see it on my
github get had okay git add whatever
actually wait I don't want to I don't
want to add bunch of these temp stuff so
let's just say git commit you know add
existing then let's say the comment will
be something okay yeah so now it's on my
github you know you it's updated oh yeah
so that's that's good for that that's
good then you know I'm glad we I did you
know we focus on that you know
okay let me read the comments lots of
comments its magnify you know when you
get old you have to magnify things so
lots of comments let's see so after
reading the comments and you know answer
some questions I think that'll be it for
today that's faith 50 minutes
[Music]
okay King Harry's so King hairiness has
this project which which graphs the
order tabs in the browser then put them
into a Jason I believe okay then you
know that's what it does so that's
interesting so you might check out how
it does that you know I haven't get into
you know the browser extension how it
works so anyway so so yeah so you know
put that with me
so like wherever I go to a github page
the first thing I mean if you want your
project to be popular you need a lead me
because I you know people don't have
time to look into details like you know
I just want to read me
and also preferably with a screenshot
you know like oh so you know like the
first thing you want to do is like what
does what these two you know what this
project do you know you know like some
you know hackers you know we tend to
like you know begin with you know how
fancy it is like how esoteric oh this is
going to do this ABC esoteric things but
for most people vast majority when you
when they go to your website they don't
understand what's going on you know they
they first of all they just want to know
what these two you know and explain in
the most basic way paths possible you
know so anyway that that's if you want
your project to be popular you know but
oftentimes it may not be necessary
because you know this is just for
yourself or something like that well
anyway so I actually live stream to me
making the thing oh so so what's your
youtube you know put you know type it
yeah link it you basically so you
basically have to move to you have to
manually load the web extension the ramp
HD bug
then you use cop he type info yeah that
I would be interested to look into
because you know the web extension stuff
you know Firefox you know they also
changed over the years and Google has
their chrome stuff which is which is
different and I believe Firefox started
to migrate into Google Chrome's
architecture
so I'm not going to read out the details
i I wouldn't know it's good or bad okay
so
so sit saw doctrines in my image in
terminal hog mud so X doctrine says
inline images in terminal augment what
do you mean so I guess how do you do in
our images in Hawk mod I would I don't
know of hand because I am NOT a heavy
user of oak mod I have you know I don't
use it that much actually because
everything I do is you know like a lot
Emacs
people use oak mod for everything but
for me the analogous is HTML you know
everything I do is in HTML so if I want
to embed the image it's annoying you
know manual HTML for example if I have a
path of an image for example let me show
you so this is a path to an image I can
show in Emacs and I can just call
command and it you know it becomes you
know linker fight you know in the image
and you know so I've been doing this
since you know 1995 manually coding HTML
so I'm familiar with HTML much more in
CSS and stuff ok show that ok so I think
that's it for today so any other
questions or interesting things you know
originally I have another thing you know
anything interest you know any questions
about the code about oops that bad thing
there about you know this code or email
is code or actually today I was there is
another
tcp/ip tutorial so actually go to San
talk show there is another thing I want
to do which is right is a modify my code
update a atom timestamp but let's do
that another day yeah let's do that
another day so let's see so any so
anything else
so Sid says I said I arrived very late
to the stream we are tried to catch the
next from the beginning yeah because I
don't have like I don't have a fixed
schedule so people don't know why I'm
going to come it's problematic you know
I don't know how to fix that because my
sleeping schedule changes all the time
so how do you host where your web blog
blog it's very easy I'm kind of old
school so what I have is let me show you
okay so if I go to my programming blog
go to my Emacs blog wait what is this
Emacs blog showing browser okay so open
that so we just tried that delete the
whole file we don't need so now it's
done and yeah okay so that is gone so
this is another file delete it and
remove that line remove that line okay
and show in browser so we have this
empty so let's say something okay
something today's date okay showing
browser so I just updated my Emacs blog
entry then I just go through shell a
shell then I call this command this is
very convenient command this is called
saw interactive a brief so what does I
do you know like when you have a brief
for example right arrow okay
r4 right arrow
you know I have lots of real briefs I
did a talk about the briefs you know few
months ago so anyway so that's a brief
but some briefs cause a complicated
shell command for example this one
but when you have lots of these shell
commands when you have hundreds a brief
you forgot you know what is what exactly
is abbreviation you see for example I
have this a sink and I have variations
of asking to different servers but you
forgot you know with a brief the problem
is you forgot you know which breathe you
know what is the exact abbreviation to
to expand to that so so what do you do
you can go to the brief for example I
can go to my brief you know I have a
bookmark
I go to my Emacs Sabri then you can look
up you know like hundreds of Maya briefs
if for example I have many unicorn emoji
I you know I go to my brief I'll - if I
forgot what a brief is what a emoji I go
to my brief file but the brief file is
like you know 500 lines it's tedious
it's your tedious to find out which are
brief what you know it's tedious step so
I created this interactive a brief so
you call the command then it you show it
shows all the possible briefs you have
you know so for example give give to mp4
then you see this is a linux command to
convert you know give to mp4 let's try
another one let's see SSH let's see what
is that okay so that is you know when I
want to SSH to my my server
let's see you know so this command is
called interactive abri so I can show
you so remember the trick to open list
file you code this wave function then
you have the you know documentation then
you can jump to the file
you see so this is the this is actually
the command it's actually pretty short
and it's actually described in this
Emacs my Emacs page so you can see the
source code you know if you want to use
that it's very convenient so anyway so
the way I do my web server is that my
I'm old school so I have a my web server
is you know you're just asking to it so
I call this a sink
you know correct type the password then
just our sink to it now you go through
my Emacs blog okay go to my Emacs blog
and you see it there
you know it's updated something okay so
that's that's that's that's what that is
so I used to have bash command for a
sink but now I use github pages oh yeah
so you know the modern days you can use
github you know you can just use git
sink you know like use git to update
your github and your github I suppose it
functions as a blog right oh you can use
you know you know the modern ways you
can have you know what's that there's
that tool let's go to my blog okay let's
go to for example there is a way
interactive green clothes you can go
this there is the what's a tour that
bundles everything it's it's like it
bundles everything all the libraries you
need in a in a standalone box I have
kind of a darker yeah so today you have
so many options you know the technology
advancement I haven't really used darker
but I looked into a little bit yeah you
know so you know when you have a new
project you make a dock then you talk it
up you know everything is like you know
bundled up so anyway that's that's it
for today I'm getting hungry and I'm
going to go to each so thank thank you
guys for watching I'll see you next time
but okay so if you like my stuff you
know support me go to my Emax website
you can buy my Emacs tutorial you know
there are links somewhere you can buy my
Emacs tutorial or where are the links
okay
anyway you find the link on my website
you know or use my patreon you know or
PayPal
so thank thank you guys for watching
by