hi a friend want me um requested that
that I do a um review of the truly
ergonomic keyboard that's this
one uh and uh actually I have two of
them
here and and and here uh one of them the
difference is that besides the blank key
that's that's not much of a difference
but the two are different models what
what the major difference is that one of
them is got um you see the side it's the
keyboard is totally symmetric let's
see uh okay here you see these two
keys compared
to this model which they have um you
know two keys instead of one um so this
one actually has more keys otherwise
they are um they are
identical uh but actually I like this
one better because um when you press the
key this key it's actually easier see
when I want to press that key I I I just
uh hold on my pum you know usually for
me that one is control so for example
Let's do let's do some you know for emx
uh use you can um you know I hold down
the key by
just pressing the Palm down um okay so
so anyway let me show you the box so the
box is not you know it's like just the
normal box you know truly ergonomic
keyboard
um um it's all dusty so I've been using
the keyboard for for five months now so
this is the
cover so let me put the Box away
uh this is a nice cover oh and it comes
with a uh Palm rest it's all very
dusty I don't use the Palm rest because
I don't like the Palm rest but by
default it comes with a palm rest so let
me let me put it
on hold on
second so let me use this one to
demonstrate because it's got keys and
you can see
better uh of the key labels I actually
prefer um keyboard with labels on I
don't like the blank keys
because because the blank Keys um you
know even I use vorak so I don't I don't
actually use the labels there but the
blank Keys um when you want to um set
Keys it's painful because you can't see
which keys are what I I change Keys all
the time like like every week so
anyway so let me put this
um oh so this so here's the back side of
the keyboard uh it's pretty heavy it's
like actually oh it's plugged in hold
on so let me unplug
it it's pretty heavy you
see um so so anyway
yeah it won't go in now because I need
to take off the
screw
um yeah what I have to do you see there
are five screws here one two three four
five 6 seven eight actually eight of
them uh or something like that nine of
them and you you have to so you know
it's um you have to take the screw out
and this comes into two pieces then you
um clamp them onto this
um you know you you clamp them then you
put the screw back on see here
the you know one two three four four
screws those are like holes so
that so that the big holes here um The
Columns I mean the bumps
here yeah here here and here and in the
middle so they they snug in so when when
it's when it's there it's very studdy
it's quite studdy um so anyway I'm not
going to put that on so once so and it
comes with the cover you
know covers like that and fits well
uh okay so that's the cover that's
the
um the
distress so let's see what else I want
to
cover I just close my windows by
MN okay so the the Box the cover and the
okay let me show you some
typing let's
see I want I want you to see closer
anyway so I I want to see this keyboard
I think this is a great keyboard I
really like it I've been using this
keyboard for five months
now um so I use it I'm a heavy emac user
so I have all the key settings you know
set for myself um different from the
default dmax keys and I mean the it's
got mechanical
Keys uh it's it's it's actually not much
louder than the traditional um keyboard
yeah let me show you the size so okay so
this is a traditional keyboard this one
is Apple Apple's keyboard from from 19
uh from
2005 around there so that's Apple
keyboard uh you can see Apple
keyboard and uh so you see it's it's
like it's like half the size I mean I
mean to that
there so so that that's the Apple
keyboard and uh and this this got it
it's not
too uh it's not that
allowed and uh let me show you the key
press you know it's mechanical keys so
it's much easy it's it's actually easier
to press than than rber Dome um and you
can feel it it's fantastic
uh the key switch they use is called
Cherry Cherry Brown uh it's one of the
most popular for typing
keyboards um okay let me show you the
special keys you know it's a very nice
design it's symmetric and you can see
the most frequently used Enter key and
the uh backspace it's it's at at the
bottom and they've got two uh uh space
Keys you can there's a dip switch in the
back sure you see here that's a that's
there are five dip switches so one of
them you can switch it so that so that
the
um the the left space key becomes the
menu key which I actually um do that
because uh for emac purposes um you can
read read about it on my blog so so
anyway so I want when I want to call
emac command I just press that one time
like the left space press it one time
and two letters like one command another
command another command another command
like say open calculator you know that
open shell that um you know whatever so
and uh yeah so you have enter back space
and that's tab that's really good too
instead of using pink keys on the side
um
and this is delete key forward delete
and this is the Windows
key or super on on Linux I don't use
that much actually um so and
the that's a page keys on the on the
right page uh Up Down Home
end oh and notice that they have on both
side they have the um shift here and
control down there so it's it's
different from the normal keyboard this
key is actually much easier to press
that's why they put the shift here but
for programmers you might want to put
control here instead and put shift here
for me I put old here uh so for me the
the bottom one is um control on the
other keyboard where this two is one key
so oh and they got this
um print screen on let me show
you let me plug it
[Music]
in so so this
key is the number
lock number lock on and uh the other one
is cap
lock I know you can read the labels but
anyway so with a number lock on the
these Keys becomes numbers so it lets
you easily type numbers and that's uh C
lock I don't use them actually but it's
the number lock is convenient when you
sometimes you want to do heavy data
input data entry you know numbers like
calculators um so anyway um that's
basically it let's
see enter control number log yeah so
well thank you thank you for
watching
um bye