good morning guys so I'm kind of early
I'm three minutes early I'm three
minutes early
well I'm going to so so what I'm going
to talk about today is the most
efficient way to operate your computer
and what keyboard you need what Mouse
you need or any other kind of input
device you know I'm talking about
basically I'm going to give you a tour
of my way of operating the computer so
what do you mean by operating operating
the computer now especially on Linux you
have so many desktop window management
systems window managers so-called window
managers and you know the Linux
phonetics
they they you know they are very
fanatical about their window managers
you know do you have virtual spaces you
have tiling windows systems they're
disabled one stable of them there's
commonly spaced one you know I forgot
the name but there's a one before that
it's called rat poison now that guy is a
common lisp programming and also he's a
Emacs user I've chatted to him a few
times since like 10 years ago and he is
also on Twitter but anyway so you know
you know on window Linux you have many
tiding tiling windows tiling window
managers and you know the point about
all that is efficiency especially Linux
fans are you know love to talk about it
you know ephesians efficiency meaning in
general they don't like to use the mouse
and you know you press a key the window
is get arranged in a certain way and so
on on the mac you pretty much don't have
any choice you just you know because Mac
because Apple wants you
oh don't want you did Oh with you know
that their UI they think their UI is the
best but but anyway still you have many
options you know the way you operate the
computer I'm talking I'm talking about
the most efficient way okay I'm talking
about the most efficient way that means
if you have one way and that is writing
a competition you want to find which way
is the most efficient now we cannot
define you know we're gonna give
somewhere rough definition about what
mean what how do you measure of fish
efficiency and basically that's you
mention number of keystrokes to do
certain things in and there are the
aspects we we may get into that you know
on Windows usually you just use the
Windows system but again there's so many
different ways of shortcuts and keyboard
and you can buy you know for example
okay one of the thing that illustrate
why the whole efficiency issue is gaming
you know especially like multi massive
multiplayer online gaming you know they
have you know they have so many like
when you play and I actually never fade
those massive what I play play online
gaming you know but basically you have
you know you know game you have so many
keys like you know this key changes
weapon that keys you know build building
or something that key switch your gods
or whatever you know you have so many
shortcuts so you know the gaming
industry I mean the gamers those gamers
MMO gamers you know they have you can
buy a mouse that has like 20 buttons let
me show you so actually I have one of
that Mouse you know it's it's somewhere
down there maybe maybe I'll show it but
anyway so so there's one people watching
you know if you have a question you know
just type it tap it here so you know if
you have a question tab it here you know
and answer it so your question your
comment comments kind of guide me where
I'm going
to go but mostly today I'm going to be
focused on what's the most efficient way
to operate yeah I'm going to give you a
tool of how I operate my system and also
but basically the fun part will be on
keyboards like how do you avoid it's
also related to avoiding repetitive
strain injury you know I have you know
hand pen so I can I recommend what's
what are the most important things you
can do to avoid that and and and related
stuff you know I I'm not prepared you
know I you know I try to so this is a
free talk so I'm just you know let's see
where the way where it is heading so let
me let me start to tell you
keyboard system yeah so I have an
article that became hugely popular it
has been on reddit a couple of times and
it has been on Hacker News a kebab times
so let's go such it not here let's do it
brave brave browser brave browser is a
great browser it's created by the same
guy who created JavaScript Brendan Eich
or something Brenda ik and anyway so
it's such folks are the Saudi tiding
windows
there it is whitening windows whitening
window managers sucks now this is hugely
popular it's you know I used to have
comments on my bra oh my you know blog
on my website like if you go all the way
down then I used to have use the disgust
comments and on this article they are
like over a hundred you know hundred
over a hundred of comments but
eventually I had to remove discuss
because you know disgust started to
charge you I mean they started to force
ads you know ugly ads like how to lose
fat quickly you know and usually you
know a bunch of image ads and usually
with you know skimpy clad women you know
and you know how to lose weight or how
to you know it's it's it's bad do read
ads so I have to remove that oh I have
to pay like ten dollars a month
something like that so but after
removing the ads you know I think so I
don't I mean removing the disgust so I
don't have comments on my site anymore
but you can see there's a whole lot of
discussion and you can see reddit
okay this thread now this is it's beyond
rate on radio the Unrated a few times so
this on this story someone mentioned
actually this is a good tip so anyway so
let's go back to the hi guys
excellent yeah okay so let's yeah so let
me you know I'm going I'm going to try
to be more focus today so I'm just going
to talk about my you know system my the
way I operate computers and keyboard
recommendations and stuff but again you
know just you know keep the comments you
know ask me questions so you know I know
where to what to talk so anyway white
white tiling window manager sucks okay
so let's see you know window manager
actually sucks you know telling Indus
manager it's it's not efficient and it's
well basically let me tell you let me
just tell you why okay so trading
windows manager the concept is that you
know when you have multiple windows like
right now you look at my desktop I have
several windows and you can see you know
they have you know gaps like this space
and this space is like you know gaps so
to a nerd it seems inefficient you know
what you know wouldn't be great if every
window is tired you know like side by
side like this one but actually that's
not good because if you are basically
when you have a tiny windows like that
you know if your windows are laid out
like that basically that's a table
you know that's a table format and what
happens is that your window is is are
forced into particular shapes and
positions then you get funky things like
you know you look at this scratched
clock and look at this wrapping of the
text and look at this
no-ho-ho so basically the white space
between windows they move into your
windows basically but however tiling
windows is still useful but not because
windows are tired no that's not because
of that but because tiling windows they
usually have a lab elaborate keyboard
shortcut system and they you know they
create this keyboard shortcut system so
that it allows you to easily create more
keyboard shortcuts to you know tire your
windows or float them or or switch to
another virtual space so it's actually
the keyboard shortcut system that allows
you to create new keyboards and you know
and with the commands too
position your windows that is actually
the reason most people you know are
crazy about turning windows but it's not
because the windows are tired itself so
that's my opinion and but even with that
okay even you know if you survey if you
just for example if I'm God you know I
can I can look at I you know is suppose
I already know I can I know that all the
use of users of Linux typing Windows
users what their key bindings are you
know what they do so I can immediately
do a statistical analysis you know which
which key I use the most often which
command are used most often and you know
so if if we have that information then I
can tell you it's no good because what
what do you mean it's no good because
when you want to do is because it's the
the keyboard shortcut is not efficient
you know you know you look at the the
key locks of all these people and
basically they have lots of keys that
are not efficient keys for example let
me give you example you know right now I
have a window I want to full screen it
you know because this window here is too
small for you to see so I press one
button one single button it's full
screen I press it again it's back you
know but if you now if you look at those
you know go ask your co-workers or
roommate or whatever who are using
Carrie windows you have slim what's your
key for full screen chances is not one
key one single key actually actually
that's not true because I'm on Windows
by default the f11 is full screen but
it's not on a Mac but well but let me
give you another example for example I
want to switch to my last window so what
I do I press one key one key you see
I've been back to Emacs one key back to
the
tearing windows now this you know again
remember it's one single key there's no
control there's no old control whatever
meta one single key so that's my that's
my point
so instead of so so let me summarize
turning windows the fact that window
windows are tired is it's no good
basically you know you don't want that
unless all your windows are text
terminals but that's you know that's not
usually a case because when you you want
to browse web pages and in web pages you
know you have pictures you know you you
know also programming language
documentation so image you know
illustration of tree relations or
whatever or math things so so your
windows you know unless all your windows
are text terminals which is not usually
the case you so basically that the the
concept the concept of tiling is not
that useful now the keyboard shortcuts
of all those tiling window users are
inefficient so that's basically the two
points I want to say about our turning
windows now so what what is the better
system okay I on this page I give you
some tips about the best system there
are a few things you want to do let's
see let's see the comments you know let
me check if I'm going in the right
direction what people are saying it's
actually - your blog
could mean something okay which mean
which Linux distro do I use okay right
now I'm on a Mac but I few years ago I
was using Linux for three or four years
like four years and I was just using
Ubuntu and you know this simply because
it's easiest most common and I haven't
tried others actually by the way my
first Linux installation is in nineteen
nineteen ninety eight
that's MK Linux only on another video I
talked about that you know so so I'm not
a I'm not a Linux newbie and in fact I
was using I was a UNIX Solaris at the
mean for you know during the 2000s for
four years
UNIX is much more complex is in harder
than Linux so anyway so which key are
using to do that it's Mac T Ford
No okay so okay the key to to go full
screen on a Mac by default is ctrl ctrl
command F I think let me try that and
show command F yeah but I I just have a
single key to do that okay let me
okay so so I'm going to give you a few
tips you want about the most efficient
system how you switch windows okay here
are few tubes actually um you know
before we talk about these you know you
can read it you know just on this URL
you can just read it off yourself but
let me talk about keyboard first okay so
what is the most important thing let me
cover this what is the most important
thing to be one the most efficient in
operating your computer doesn't matter
if it's Windows or Mac or Linux so what
is the most efficient what what do you
need to do that's what I'm gonna talk
about okay so so what what can you do to
make you know using computer the most
efficient most efficient meaning the
least amount of keystrokes okay
scientifically like if you run a key lot
go ahead you know go go and install a
key lock so you actually have the solid
data when you talk about you know which
Keys you press you know most people like
Emacs users they say oh you should you
know put your caps lock to control oh
that's the best way oh oh you know some
other people say oh you should do this
tab that yeah you know that's all
first of all install key dogs
so you actually have solid data then
count how many keystrokes you typed and
also if you can count you know with when
when you do a shortcut how many
keystroke that involves basically the
most used command command you know to
operate your computer you have you know
you have all the commands you using a
day now the top ten you know top ten or
30 are the most used those commands you
want them to have the most easy easy
keys now so what does easy key means for
example control let's say control Q
compare to
let's say compared to control K now
obviously control K is easier because
control K is well let's say let's say
compared to spacebar okay is control QE
0 space bar obviously space bar because
he just pressed you know it's usually
you have a big space bar so that that
tells you you know that's how you
measure which key is easier which which
shortcut keys are easier so so you can
you know you want to go for example to
to come to measure you know which key
combination better you know so this can
be done scientifically and so basically
you know the question is given any two
shortcuts you know control T versus
command T or ctrl T versus option T f
versus f9 you know just one single key
which is which is more efficient you
know f1 is just one single key but it's
a bit further you know you have to move
your hand but anyway so I'm getting a
bit lost so so I was talking about how
you so I was so the first thing is you
want to measure what are the top you
know most you want to get a ranking of
all the commands the ones you use the
most often that's one thing the other
thing is you want to assign the the most
used command you want to give them the
most simple key okay then the third
thing is how do you judge which key is
simpler now that's a bit detailed we can
talk about later I have a lot articles
on my site but but basically you know
obviously control T is better than
control option T you know command H is
better than command control something
you know and and indexfinger keys are
better than and pinky keys home row keys
are better than you know the keys below
oh the number keys so that I mean that's
a general idea you know you can figure
out the details again you know I have
like huge you know hundreds of articles
about all these details you can read and
also you can find out how to how to
actually create those shortcuts on your
system so on this page okay so this is
URL let me go through the other page so
just such folks are keyboard so you go
to my keyboard blog sorry dot info
keyboard and you go to on the left there
is key how-to so here you can I tell you
how to set up keys on Microsoft Windows
and on Linux in on a Mac ok so so far we
covered the problems of tiling windows
and we covered what do you actually want
to do I mean what what is the better
things to do with regards to shortcuts
in commands okay we we covered that the
next thing I'm going to talk about is
about keyboard okay so the question is
let's go back up one level so the
question is so what can you do to make
your to increase your efficiency and
reduce repetitive strain injury for your
hands you know maybe you are young and
you don't you don't think you ever get
into that problem you know I on the
computer keyboard for 16 years I don't
have a problem at all you know I was
very athletic and but after 16 years
when I was using a laptop for two years
exclusively laptop I started to have
feel you know I feel some funny you know
tingling and sensations that that is in
2006 and that's where I started to use
Microsoft economic keyboard so you know
you might think you don't have a problem
you know maybe you are right but
people get older you know you get out
and one day and some and sometimes you
know right now you you don't have much
that need for typing intensively but you
know if you look at data entry clock
crooks data entry crooks so what does
data entry clerk me those are people who
type out they did the sole job is typing
you know people talk and they type you
know they sit and type over their data
entry either from speech or they look at
something and they have to type actually
that data entry clerk is not a job
anymore I mean they are replaced but
they are pretty much replaced by
computation by you know voice
recognition systems but but still you
know if you are writer you know if you
write novels if you are heavy bloggers
or if you are a gamer in some kind of
adventure you know game where you have
to chat a lot you know like I was in
Second Life
I built in second life virtual world for
like four years and you know high tech
chat to people all day like role-playing
you know you have to pretend what
happens so anyway so I'm saying one day
you know maybe you're you you you switch
to a new job and and there's a new
project and you know maybe it's a
startup and you know your team needs to
finish this so you started to code like
60 hours a week you know that that is
when you start to feel hand problems and
that's kind of late I mean it's better
better never than late you know that is
when you have problems so you want to
you want to be prepared you want to know
what you know there are people a lot of
people because I write about keyboarding
and hand injury so a lot of people
contact me and it's also on reddit and
hacker news like every month there are
people are talking about how they how
they had hand pain how they visit
doctors you know when that happens to
you that's kind of late you know you
don't want so you want
to be prepared and often what they say
is that once you have that it's kind of
it's not going to go away completely you
know it's kind of so anyway so better to
preventive you know they say preventive
measures is the best medicine they
animated medicine so anyway so how to
increase your efficiency so okay so
there are two things I want to say to
increase your efficiency and prevent RSI
they are related okay they are related
they are not exactly the same but they
are related so so how do you okay how do
you do that now the answer involves two
things one get a better keyboard to use
a efficient shortcut system
okay now the efficient choker system we
already covered previously a little bit
you know about you know how you assign
commands you know you want to find out
which command you use most most often
and and how you choose shoot shortcuts
and you want to map the shortcuts to eat
the most easy shortcuts to the most
frequently used commands and also if you
are using Emacs of course if you know
Emacs user there are two things you want
to do one is use two options one use the
Evo mod okay use Evo mod or use soft
like keys or there's another option use
a go Emacs
mod okay there are three things let me
show you just so you can see you know
you can go to the website and look after
the talk
so some fly keys so if you are Emacs
user you want to check this one out and
also the other options are and it's got
the other options is a go Emacs mod I
have a link here and the other option is
eva mod okay use one of these and
nothing else
well i'm is let me get this this is
important you must use one of these okay
just nothing not any others one of these
sophocles even 100 go Emacs mud you know
pick one you know try them and you know
see which one you like the most
pick one then possibly if you like you
can try you can you can use other key
binding add-ons but if you want my
opinion okay I'm giving you you know I'm
telling you this is the mode is this is
concerning about the most efficiency I'm
not talking about you know I don't yeah
I don't care what you say I'm talking
about first of all you have to measure
how many keys you actually type okay
most programmers they don't type much
then there's data entry clerks they at
the other end you know or similar like
novel writers okay they type ten times
more than you then you average
programmers you want to listen if you
are concerned about keyboard shortcuts
and efficiency stuff you want to listen
the data entry clerk the novel writers
you know the writers those people not
the programmers the typical they give
you typical garbage like you know swap
your control key you know caps knock or
whatever so anyway if you are Emacs user
use this one one of these soft like he's
eeeevil mod and over in my hobo Emacs
mod now okay so let's go back so i said
there are two things important why is
inc you know increased efficiency in
your shortcut system the other one is
keyboards now you might think funny how
you know what do you mean keyboard after
the keyboard is actually more
important and then then the shortcut
system if you can only choose one you
must actually you should do to both of
them but if you to begin with actually
get a better keyboard now if you are
using laptop that's a worst that because
of laptop I began to have repetitive
strain injuries it's always with my left
hand starting in 2006 and since 2006
it's like every three years I have some
kind of problem it's new problem you
know it takes a month to take a month or
two to find out you know exactly why am
I having another problem you know it's
almost like every three years I have
some kind of new problem and every time
it happens you panic because if you are
a programmer you know typing is your job
you know if once you yo you got you know
repetitive strain injury you peep you
kind of done for you know it affects
your career it's pretty serious so you
are oh you have to take vacations and
you know you come back from vacation and
it's pain again so so what I'm saying
yeah so don't you know if you are using
normal laptop stop that
you know never type on laptop more than
you know five minutes you know just get
kid you know you know be serious about
it try not to use you know laptop again
you know what I say you may not think
it's important it also again depends on
how much you actually typed you know
because every people is different you
know nobody you don't think of other
people like you just live you know you
live in a city or you do whatever your
lifestyle you don't you don't see other
people but maybe in fact you actually do
not type that much you know you are
programmer and you you know you go you
go to your day job you know you type
maybe for a little bit you know you you
read the dark and type and you you go to
meetings you talk to people you eat
lunch you you know you actually don't
type that much and to you it seems oh
it's a great idea to swap your
caps lock to control you know you should
do everyone should do this but on the
other hand you know those other people
who writes a lot who write documentation
programming and who code you know 60
hours a day in startups or like me right
you know five blogs when those people
try your method you get paid I mean if
you suddenly have to type the what you
know the amount day type you get pain
within your month you you you get you
know you go visit doctor you your career
career is done for so that's a that's
the thing so you know just you know just
be aware that you know this is a lot
happens throughout people you can see it
on reddit or hacker news you know it's
just such four Emacs han pin or Emacs
repetitive strain injury and not
necessary Emacs being people also get
that you know it comes up like every
month now you know and you can see the
horror stories because it never happened
to most people you know you know like
for example if your mom you know your
mom does not type much but you know it's
fine you know what's wrong with why do
that you know there's no need for a
konami keyboard you know that laptop is
perfectly fine so so it really depends
on how much you really type so if you
maybe you don't need you know to worry
about things because you know not you
know you don't have to actually you know
the actual typing is not that much so
again remember get the key log now again
I have a sorry key log have a page that
lists a bunch of keyboard key log
utilities sorry info
and not that okay let's go to Saudi
keyboard
so you go to my blog and you go to
typing now this section is all about
typing typing habits repetitive strain
injury and there's a link on key log
keyloggers
let's search for it log ok it's not yeah
so I got all these tips basically what
I'm talking about today you know they
are all in these articles I'm just
giving you a live presentation because
sometimes when people read articles you
don't have the context you know you
don't see the expression you don't see
you know the feedback so video is
advantageous advantages in that regard
so I have a other code that least the
key log tools what is where is it and
let's see key binding such for log no
typing key how to search for log ok key
logging and security so it's you know
keyboard shortcut inlay our tutorial
yeah so it's in key how-to and you
scroll down you can see key logging list
of keylogging software so you can try up
one of these you know that actually lock
your keys so you actually know you know
how many keys you type and if you are
using Emacs I highly recommend you know
get this one if you are using Emacs you
know X key freak because that we are
measured let me show you for example
let's see key freak show you know I have
it installed so you see so this is my
result this is this this is result for
about three month or something like that
but I have also resolved
for a year to two years it's also a my
my site somewhere here you know but
anyway so the what this does is that at
least all the commands you used or all
of them so this is a command this is the
no no command and they are ordered by
frequency so I use this command the most
self insert command
what does I mean that that means just
just typing like when you insert letters
in symbols just typing so so so at my
actual actual typing is only 20%
so that means 75% of typing is actually
shortcuts not not inserting stuff you
know actually if you have a program the
majority of keystrokes are not data
entry you know they are not inserting
keys or you know writing stuff they are
actually like moving forward delete
words backward page of switch buffers
copy and paste things like that so
anyway I also have a report let's see
Emacs let's see sorry
UNIX key frequency actually command
frequency
okay this is oh do you want the new one
you know here here is a report about
different people a bunch of people
statistics on what command they use the
most you know in Emacs so these are four
Emacs people so anyway let me go back to
the so I was talking about keyboard yeah
let's go back to keyboard so I've been
talking for 37 minutes that's another 20
minutes we should we can finish it
okay so let's go to keyboard so keyboard
is the most important things you want to
begin with okay so what what is my
recommendation what is my recommendation
so let's go through there my keyboard
hog so I have two recommendations one is
get a keyboard get a mechanical key
keyboard okay that's the first thing now
if you are starting out you know just do
it do it just you can just do that they
are pretty cheap like $40 you can you
know get $40 don't get lower don't don't
get cheaper than that $40 is pretty
cheap you know usually they are made in
China you can go to Amazon and you know
just search for mechanical keyboard so
there are a lot of them like like here
you can see these are pretty cheap like
this one 40 $40 $40 this is more
expensive but but if you are starting
out you know if you are young and you
know get get one of these you know $50
that's all you need okay so first thing
get a mechanical keyboard now the other
equally important thing is you want the
ergonomic keyboard so basically you want
to pee you want a keyboard that's
basically two sections one for left hand
one for right hand and also you want the
tenting like so that when you type they
are like the middle is higher so again I
have lots of reviews some of these are
very expensive usually they are like
most of them are above 200 you know like
200 above 100 okay some of them are 300
something so and in this one for example
this is 500 and this one
so $500 anyway if you go top best urban
ami keyboard 2019 so I have a list a
selection I think those are good again
you know if you are starting out you
know you don't have any pain you are
young you don't want to spend you know a
few hundred dollars just just get a you
know just begin with a normal you know
fifty dollars mechanical keyboard you
know is $50 you can throw it away next
year or two years after so but if you
are adventurous if you you know you
don't mind spending a few bucks you know
most programmers you make money so don't
worry about keyboards then you can try
you know then you want to get one of
these and and if you actually have hand
pen or if you actually type a lot you
absolutely must get one of these
absolute you know this is like no but
maybe no yeah absolutely you know you
either you go to see a doctor
you know your career you get one
of these so so I'm not going to go into
details like which one is better I mean
most people want to know which one is
the best you know that actually depends
I mean there's no one answer like right
now I use this one Kinesis advantage you
can see you see that's that's Canisius
advantage that's what I mean
and the middle one I use I use a mark or
keyboard as a function key so I press
this key my whole window is enlarged
you know I for example I press this key
well it's it's each he does something
shortcuts
it's but it's one single key there's no
no control option command something
so anyway back to organ Ammi keyboard so
there's no one answer for everything for
example if you need portable and you
know this is good this is okay if you
really wanted cheap this is your best
option Microsoft sculpt that's you know
you can buy that too to begin with so
there are many choices you know you can
look at you know best 2009 here I give
some selections and and you can read
about their pros and cons you know you
know if you want it portable how much
you want to spend things like that they
are all mechanical by the way except
except the Microsoft economic which is
like $80 or something the cheapest okay
so that's keyboard so let me summarize
so to increase your efficiency and to
reduce repetitive strain injury there
are two things you want to do one is get
a get a good keyboard because actually
keyboard is the thing you touch every
day every minute it's the key it is the
key board that actually causes pain or
order efficiency is involved it is the
keyboard so get a get a good keyboard to
use a efficient shortcut system you know
and and if you are using Emacs use one
of one of Sophocles Eva mod organ ami a
go Emacs smart okay and in choosing a
keyboard you know if you have young if
you are young and you are you know you
are beginner you don't have problems you
don't type that much just get a
mechanical keyboard you know just a
normal mechanical $50 keyboard now if
you don't mind spend a bit more or if
you actually type a lot or you already
have discomfort in your arms
get one of the ergonomic keyboard okay
so I think that's basically I want to
cover today that's kind of like the
summary of this whole thing hundred
articles so again if you have a question
you asked question then let me mention
one more thing let me mention one more
thing for one more thing about keyboard
okay so another thing about keyboard is
programming programmable keypads yeah
you know I I can talk a lot about
keyboards you know like when you buy a
keyboard you actually want it to be
programmable I mean so there are so many
features about keyboards you know I can
talk about some of them are important
it's for example I was saying you know
if you are beginner if this is your
first time you know you just spent fifty
dollars and get a cheap one you know
like this one optical switch is good
this one tomoko is cheap and it works
fine you know if you want a brand name
you know go for see a master key
that's from Coolermaster it's well known
Unicom it's that's the classical creaky
very loud some people like it so you
know of all these they are also good
they have different features like this
one is program programmable this this
one is on-the-fly programmable so is
this one but not this one not happy
hacking so they have different features
and by the way I don't recommend happy
hacking you know I don't it's you don't
buy that period and this is very
expensive having happy hacking is like
$250
it's the worst it doesn't have arrow
keys it doesn't have function keys that
means every time you need to press arrow
keys you have to hold down of FN key and
press another key with your pinkie so in
terms of efficiency and in terms of hand
comfort happy hacking is the actually
the worst and it's it's also you know
$250 it and it's not programmable it's
not on the fly program but it's also
it's it's the worst in so many aspects
however happy hacking is well known in a
keyboard hackers community because you
know it has certain Prestage but anyway
it's worst in my opinion so yeah so I'm
talking about keepo oh yeah the other
thing I want to mention is you you want
to get a programmer program a keypad
well first of all your keyboard should
be programmable you you want to get that
you don't get that if you spend $50 like
this one it's not programmable okay
maybe it's a little bit but you know
it's not so a programmable key keyboard
is very good because for example you
want to you know we talked about you
want to the most efficient shortcut
system now how do you create a shortcut
you know different operating systems
they have different ways and they have
tools like you can install that allows
you to create shortcuts but however they
do not work as well compared to actual
program or programmable keyboard you
know they have lots of issues like
sometimes it doesn't work sometimes you
need if you know if you are in Windows
and if you are running West edit for
example the registry edit and if that is
running in route mod or privilege mod
then your keyboard
you know if you are using autohotkey it
doesn't work your shortcut doesn't work
anymore
and also on Linux for example when you
start Linux in a console your shortcut
doesn't work if you are using you know
you know some of the Linux tools to
remap keys same thing for the Mac you
know on the Mac is a bit better you know
I'm running Cairo by now you know but
anyway but if you have a keyboard that's
programmable you know that's better
because it sends whatever keys you
programmed directly to the operating
system instead of instead of the upper
end instead of the upper end hinge
system you know do something to your
keys to change it so anyway yeah
programmable keyboard is great now once
you get programmable keyboard next the
next step is you know a programmable
keypad is really useful yeah
programmable keypad so I have some
options here now this this one is fancy
you know it's got screens you don't you
don't actually need it it's it's nice
though I mean but it's not as far as
efficiency goes you don't actually it's
not required but anyway I have some
options okay so let me go back to the
let's see some questions you guys have
so I think that's basically covered what
I want to talk about today Commack yeah
kamek kamek is great it's it's a
alternative layout evil man and he's my
own custom and command mod for another
text editor yeah that's that's that's
good I mean yeah that's also a good
point is James hacking James asking says
avoid wrist rest type like a piano
player that's a good point because
actually when you type your hand is
supposed to you should float not you
know your hand should float not resting
on a wrist pad so you know you can you
know so so if you look at Canisius you
know it's see you know it's curved you
know if I put my hand here you see my
it's curved see if you can see that my
camera my camera is pretty lousy so
sorry about that
so you see it's the keys are like below
the the rest here so when you use this
keyboard you know my hand is actually
like my hand is not like that but
actually just like my wrist my wrist and
my arm is in one straight line you know
that so that's why they they designed
the keyboard that way but when you
actually type on a flat keyboard you
should you should not rest your hand on
the pad but also that depends on whether
you touch type and also so actually
there's a lot of details anyway about
all these issues yes split and also need
linear I'd really like yes like you know
that's Momo
most people you know like when you use
one of these fancy keyboards it takes
sometimes to learn them actually yeah
usually if you never used any of these
it will usually take one month one month
for you to be fluent for this one you
know this Microsoft economics scoped
it's easy to adapt you can you know you
can get used to this one in one week but
but for the others like the author
linear you know this one is also very
easy to adapt this ultimate hacking
keyboard but for also linear and you
know yes so some of them actually takes
some time to to learn
type speed okay so I guess that's the
last thing I'm gonna five so I've been
talking for 53 minutes
I don't type that for a fast let's uh
let's go to types to speed but what the
hell you know let's just do it
type speak now if I in practice you know
if I know I said is that a particular
site or is that oh are you talking about
the Linux Linux tool
hell okay well I'm not on Linux right
now so so but anyway let's go through a
type let's go to a website and let's do
that I don't write like right now I'm a
Mac now that software is probably
available on a Mac too but you know
let's just use a website typing how to
touch type no I want to have in-game in
typing tests so here is a bunch of great
typing tutorial websites and typing
speed test site so my average you know
when if I'm typing every day a lot my
average I mean the best is usually 90
words per minute that's about as high as
I go maybe 95 you know if I actually
practice I mean you know if I actually
really want to try to be very fast then
I passed
if I practice every day you know maybe
I'll get to 100 but that's about it
but also note that different websites
they measure differently so on one web
website you might be 70 word per minute
ah another website you might be nightly
they may differ you know it depends on a
lot on the word used you know which site
it is but right now if I you know try to
compete it's probably gonna be 70 or 60
so but anyway it's let's see let's go to
one of the site timing games typing type
racer and also if you are using a
keyboard like right now I'm using
Kinesis it's actually slower for speed
typing
into a typing race oh so
Hey
what
jeez what is this you have to type
the word Italy followed by space
what oh you you mean I have to correct
it it it so you must be correct
that had in China and then brought here
in fact to eat a 33 word for a
minute
that's a screw up it's that guy I want
revenge so let's do one more so
nice again
I'm just not and I for you quite a
eighty-two word per minute yay okay okay
that's it
and you know so my my normal speed is
around 90 you know so you know if I
practice a few rounds I get to 90 okay
that's it
any more questions thanks for watching
subscribe to my channel donate money
well actually you know if you enjoyed my
articles about keyboard you know about
keyboard or if you enjoyed my Emacs
stuff or my programming stuff give me a
few bucks you know you know donate
they'll be helpful so any more questions
I
I think that's it for today so
so thanks thanks for watching I'll see
you guys next time
yeah I have brew installed but then I
don't want to install that program you
know I don't need it I don't you know I
tried to not inst you know I don't want
to install I tried to be minimal I don't
want to install anyway so see you guys
bye