Guys, welcome to another episode of Sand
Talk Show.
Uh we are going to code CSS cascading
style sheet. Okay.
So, let's begin.
Uh Sand
Talk Show
open the talk show page and Sand Talk
Show that page Emacs Lisp add width and
height to all thumbnails. No, that's not
the one. So, the today's talk show page
is this.
>> [snorts]
>> Episode 790 CSS pie chart grids
uh and spinner animation and some
others, okay?
And I'm just going to do it uh for fun.
I'm just you're going to watch me live
coding and that's about it.
But meanwhile I code, you can talk to me
and ask me questions, okay?
Now, I'm
uh well, okay. So, anyway, so let me
just do it.
So, let's see.
Am I ready? Okay. Now, I have a little
sip of
booze. Okay, so this is uh guava
cocktail. So, it's a guava juice with
one shot of vodka.
Very good. Smell good.
I discovered that I like vodka.
I like Well, I don't actually like booze
any of that because um
alcohol gets you stupid, okay? But
anyway, among them, I don't I don't like
beer at all. They taste bad and red wine
I like I hate red wine. It tastes
bitter. Like what what's It doesn't
taste good red wine and beer, okay? They
both are sucks. But vodka is like
uh odorless um, um, like almost
odorless, okay? Vodka.
And I I discovered vodka, actually red
wine, you have some like after effects,
you what they drinkers call,
whatever, what's the name? But vodka
less, okay? Vodka in the China Erguotou
is very good. That's Chinese baijiu.
And so vodka
and I like a margarita, okay?
And I like pina colada.
So let me tell you guys about the CSS,
okay? So I've been doing tremendous time
uh,
in the past month on CSS.
Uh, as you know, my last two videos,
live stream is about CSS, okay? So
anyway, [snorts] let me show you
something fun quickly. Uh, video check,
audio check.
Yeah. Is it good, everyone? Is it good?
Uh, if you are here, comments, okay?
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Okay, so CSS.
Well, let's let me just start code,
okay? Cuz nobody is here. So I want to
do some this coding for myself. I want
to do, you see, I got this, uh,
pad.
That's my screenshot notes.
So let's see, use PyCharm, okay? So let
let me do this, okay? So let's go to CSS
index, okay? The pink window show all my
command codes and the the keystroke I
type, the commands on the right, the
keystroke on the left, all the keystroke
I type, okay? You'll see.
It will show there dynamically
in real time, okay? And I'm using Emacs,
I'm using Safely Keys.
Safely Keys, okay? That Safely Keys and
I'm using a Dvorak keyboard layout,
okay? Dvorak keyboard layout. So, you
open this is the source code. So, search
for Wait, undo. Go to the top. Search
for d v o r a k Dvorak keyboard layout.
Okay? That looks like that.
Meanwhile, QWERTY, do we have QWERTY
here? No, because this is a translation
table. Uh
from QWERTY to others. So, you don't
need QWERTY, but do do we have QWERTY?
No, but we got AZERTY, which is very
similar to QWERTY, okay? So, anyway,
that's digression. I mean, that that's
introduction. So, Visual CSS, massive
work on it in the past uh month, okay?
So, for example, yesterday, I discovered
2 days ago uh also, I discovered conic
gradient.
Amazing. You see? So, with pure CSS, you
can create this kind of
sweeping gradient, okay? And among which
is how you generate the spinner
animation. Fantastic, okay?
Now,
so, on my homepage, I want to make
changes. So, Visual CSS, okay? Fantastic
CSS animation, okay?
Now, if you are here, say hi, okay?
Okay, so, let's go to the top this page
and here is the Here is all the CSS um
code
uh
7 kilobytes just for this file uh
backup. So, these are the CSS code for
for this Visual CSS
index page, okay? That's Visual uh So,
what I want to do is
Leave it, okay? Now, open a new window,
not too big.
Okay, I need to do this quickly. Need to
get this done, okay? So, that's a CSS
file. Now, go back, close, go back,
okay? Now, I want you to use pie chart,
okay? So, let's go to the conic
gradient. Open the file. So, this
conic gradient instead of like that, I
want to show a pie chart.
Actually, pie chart, I should create a
new page for pie chart.
Yeah, let's create a new page for pie
chart, okay?
So, [snorts]
copy.
Go to
JavaScript blog. That's where I add my
new stuff, web dev blog.
Content include JavaScript, CSS, HTML,
okay? So, create the new section, paste
the link, linkify it. Now, copy paste
the line, so we have a new line of the
same link. Now, you want to say pie
chart.
So, we want a new page for pie chart
because pie chart is very common.
Uh what?
Paste, okay? So, pie chart,
okay?
CSS pie chart, that's what we want,
okay? Now, open that, copy, close.
Go here, open [snorts] it empty, paste,
close, and copy this
title and call command. You can see in
the pink window call the command to
update the title and H1. Now, show this
page in browser, you say says pie chart,
okay?
Now, just go up. Now, we want to delete
everything.
>> [sighs]
>> Browser support. Delete, delete, delete,
delete, delete, delete, delete.
Delete. Delete. Okay, so do we delete
delete delete delete delete delete
delete delete delete delete delete.
Magnify all delete delete delete delete
delete delete. Okay, showing browser.
Okay, that's almost done. Delete. Okay.
Fantastic. Update today's state there
and remove the original date time there.
So
date created today. Okay, now this is a
pie chart page. I mean the this is a new
page which is empty, okay?
Now you want to add a pie chart to here
as an example. So
copy the file path. Now go to this one
of these uh
So can you see uh if I enlarge it might
be better. So spinner animation and
paste it here. Linkify delete the URL.
And okay and
press press press press press. So that
will update this topic box to all
these four pages.
Okay, so now we just added pie chart,
okay? By now currently empty, okay? Now
you just close that and and go to here,
search for
p i e.
Okay, pie chart there. Example. Cut it.
Close.
Open the pie chart, go to top, go to go
to go to go to here, paste, showing
browser.
Does it work? Yes.
Now why does it work? Because uh
because I thought oh yeah, so we did uh
we created this whole thing, okay? Mhm.
Okay, hold on a So, this is Oh, okay.
So,
let's do this.
Wait, I don't want to do this. I don't
want So, this attribute is very
interesting.
Hey brother, Aluma. Hello, howdy.
This attribute is very interesting
because
I just learned it actually yesterday.
So, you got this
So, this CSS property, let me show you,
okay? Do you see this attribute?
CSS property, what does it do? It allows
you to that function attr will
get the
value of any attribute of HTML element.
So, for example, a link href attribute,
width of a image, the width and height
attribute. In fact, any attribute of
HTML
element.
So, you can get the content.
Then,
you can use this after, you know, this
after so-called pseudo pseudo element to
add that
as text. So,
So, for example, it's useful for
example, let's go to attribute. So, go
cssly.info.
cssly just search for cssly web dev
blog, you'll find it, my web dev blog.
Okay, and you go to So, I just updated I
just created um
this yesterday, so somewhere there's
attribute, okay? So, did we
I must be few
What?
Okay, so, add multiple
gradients.
Wait, I got a call.
Okay, I got a call I got to take. Okay,
hold on a second.
I'll be right back in few minutes.
Hello guys. I got to go. Sorry.
>> [laughter]
>> I got to go. I got to go pick up my
wife. Um
So, this is
great. Okay, so well, I got to I got to
go. So, I forgot.
Uh but what we going to do about this?
Uh yeah, so
hold on. So, let me finish this pie
chart. Okay, let me finish this page.
Five 5 more minutes.
So, we going to do pie chart. At least
you can you know, let me show you how
how is the pie chart done? Okay? So,
this is the property you want.
You see what we have before. Oh, wait.
Wait. Can we undo? Let me show you the
attribute.
Yeah, you see this attribute this you
see this attribute. What it allows me to
do is that it will close it, okay? So,
you can see I got a
div here, and the div is the class
circle box.
And it's got a style.
And the style says background image, and
the value for background image is a
conic gradient. And the value of that,
the argument for the conic gradient
gradient is red degree, yellow degree,
green degree degree, then blue degree
degree. Then when you show in your
browser, you can see you got a pie
chart.
Okay, but you see there's a magic, you
see? Now, that's a div, you see? That's
a div.
Block, right? There's no text, there's
no inner text. But magically, the inner
text
shows here, the style, the entire style
text. How is that done? That's done
automatically by So, if you scroll up,
scroll up, you can see there is this
style section.
And we pop it out in my Emacs magic
sa-html.
Sa- html sa-css mode, you see? This CSS
that you got this circle box after.
That means insert this text
after that circle box class, okay? And
what do you want to insert? You want to
insert the attribute value of the style
attribute.
If
it doesn't exist, like if it's like
there's no style attribute, insert empty
string, okay? Like don't do an-
anything. So, actually we don't need it,
you know? Like it doesn't, you know? If
there's none, do insert nothing, okay?
So,
you see magic. So, this CSS
automatically, so let's go to circle
box, let's highlight it, okay? You all
the year, then I'll go down, go down, go
go go go down, down, down, down. See
see? You see this div circle box style.
You see, it the CSS
attribute automatically grabs this text
and insert into the div. That's why when
you're showing HTML, you can see the
code. Fantastic.
But anyway, when when the code is long,
it doesn't work. Also, there's another
issue. When you do it this way, you
cannot copy the text. You see, anything
inserted by the by the um
by the before and after pseudo element,
that's those are called pseudo elements,
okay, if you don't know actually. So, I
got to go
Uh what time is it?
Yeah, okay, so Okay, five five five more
minutes. Okay, so you got pseudo
elements. You go to visual CSS Society.
Uh
selectors Uh okay, well, then you can
see a bunch of
You can see the explanation of pseudo
class and pseudo elements. Okay, so the
the Uh so, this pseudo class function
selector. So, you got pseudo class
selector and pseudo elements selector.
Pseudo elements selector are like
They are not exactly elements, but they
are like seems to be, you know,
elements. For example, the first letter
of a element or the first [snorts] line,
CSS can, you know, like pick the first
letter or first line or the or before
Before is what we use to allow you to
insert content. Like Q, capital Q, huge
Q. Question, how are you? Q, you know,
like question answer. Usually in English
tradition of printing, you will see this
huge Q.
Very common, but you don't actually have
to
type the Q because it you can use this
trick of before to automatically insert
to all the class.
You know, so you have like bunch of
questions, Q and Q QA QA, question and
answer, okay? So, that's So, that's
before and you can also do it for after.
For example, for after you can ask you
can insert a parenthesis before and
after any
element.
So, that's called this So, So, this are
called pseudo element because they looks
like an element, but actually they don't
exist. So, it's pseudo elements. Then
CSS you also got pseudo class, okay?
Anyway,
So, we used that trick to
to have, you see, to have this
the actual style code for to illustrate
to, you know, how do you do a pie chart,
okay? That's a basically the heart of it
is this background image conic gradient,
okay? But there's issues. Issues is that
you cannot copy this, you know, inserted
pseudo elements.
So, that's not so good because when you
have a tutorial, people see it, people
want to be able to copy and paste,
right? So, so, so, so, that's why I, you
know, let's not do that. And also this
So, instead of the embedded style,
So, let me show you.
Pop it out and delete this whole style
and move this to this style
here, okay? Now,
prettify the code so you can see make
the whole thing one line. Press a key.
See the pink window will show what
command I just called. You see, so undo
let me undo. Watch the pink window,
okay? Undo. Now, press my key this key
here. Can you see my finger? That's
actually tab, okay? Because of my
fantastic programmable keyboard, this is
ultimate hacking keyboard, too. I press
this key twice because I'm using CSS
CSS mode, okay? Press twice, it will
call a command to format the buffer.
Okay.
And, you know, automatically. Okay, now
you close it, it will move that CSS file
inside back to this HTML file. Now, if
you show in browser, fantastic.
>> [snorts]
>> So, now you copy the entire style style
block block
create a CSS code block here, paste it
and remove the style tag. Press press
press. You see? Fantastic and beautiful.
Now, show in browser so people can see
the code.
This code creates this pie chart.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Now press press press
show in browser, you now have syntax
colored version. Okay, I got to go. So,
got to go pick up my wife. It's good
food. Um
nice. Didn't know about styling pseudo
elements. Yeah, so uh
yeah, so you can actually style pseudo
elements. Very interesting. Okay. Thank
you for watching. Bye, guys. I got to
go. Bye, guys.