good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sod talk
show today is September 10th
Theo Clark p.m. san francisco time
Tuesday okay so now I am Alive this is
my second try and its success so c'mon
easy trunk good morn in bathroom you
good morning Justin and what we are
today's topics B so guys type a topic
and meanwhile let me close my door okay
type a topic and we can do technical
which is programming JavaScript
Emacs emag bees or Golan or we can do
non-technical but I'm thinking not
non-technical because we talk about we
we did a rant about you know open source
and stuff to yesterday and I think the
day before so what topics number six
let's see number six now this is like
JavaScript typescript SVG write a
function product okay let's do that
let me close my door
okay so I'm alive check and like six
people watching great fantastic so
bathroom you says topic number six which
is JavaScript typescript SVG Dom writing
a function Plata okay
so let's get the window here so you can
see so okay so here and this window over
here and that should do
and on the Left window you can see all
my Emacs commands such as moving cursor
and so on and
okay topic number six
javascript typescript and
Charles gave typescript okay so writing
a function prata
so okay so let's go to this is today's
talk show page and let's go to sorrow
okay go to here this directory and go to
tests 2018 index okay and copy the URL
open the buffer show it okay so you know
I'm thinking what to do like like what
how shall we do this so I've been trying
to work on this project for a long time
this you know on and off for a year now
so this is written in 2008 it always
already does that but it has problems so
for example you can see so here is the
code there are two plots those are you
know I you you just call the function
parametric plot and parametric plot
which element to attach to and here's a
function so X and the function is sine x
squared yeah so and from 0 to 7 that is
the first fraud and the second prod is
sine times sine x times pi
good-morning DeYoung great to see you
DeYoung grade you see you on Twitter
and and I get to see you off her face
greetings greetings so you know you know
what's the difference between parametric
plot and normal plot this you know if
you have not done calculus you may not
know but it's so simple you know
normally when you plot X ok let me
explain this like normally you you press
something like sine X ray
basically y equals two sine X so
parametric plot is instead of that you
have you have this so x equals to a
function t okay and y equals to a
function so so as T goes and T goes from
zero to ten for example so you plot is
you evaluate functions F and G and T
from zero you get the pair of numbers
you product XY when T is zero point one
you get pair of numbers and that's XY
you know then you plot it and you can
see and the normal plot with respect to
parametric plot would be like this let
me show you okay so the normal plot x
equals normal plot in terms of
parametric plot it's just like this x
equals two x so x doesn't change you
know x is just you know you know zero
one two three four you know just going a
linear align basically
yeah x equals 2x yes
yeah wait let me change the time so this
is a normal plot so per parametric plot
is just more general and so you can use
it to plot you know normal curves
okay so I I did this project you know
and and you can plot this but there are
many things to fix
okay but I'm thinking what are we going
to do today are we going to okay so hold
on a second let me go back so so go go
back to the so this is a file right this
this is the file that does the does the
two parts and
so this is the code and but you need the
libraries the library is this one go to
the bottom is 500 lines and there are a
lot problems I need to fix they are
quite a few problems because when you
when you start to learn SVG you know
prod JavaScript and all that you know
the the thing are with the details you
know it's the difficulty are always with
the details because theoretically you
understand how to do it you know how to
draw a circle in line so but the details
there's a lot of details and I have a
lot of things to fix on these for
example the font size the you know
plotting the axis with labels that's
that's one of the most difficult part I
actually you know partying the labels in
axis that's most but one of the
difficult part so Dion says can say how
long tonight but I have a question
bizarre you have info on writing passes
in Lycia Maglis where you do a show
sometime about it if you know about it
actually I don't have info about writing
a parcel in emag this yeah right now my
understanding of pasa is very limited I
so I have not actually written a pasa
it's one of my project to do you know so
many things to do like in learning Julia
okay so but writing a pasa is one of the
thing I want to do after you are able to
write a parser okay let me show you that
saw compiler tutorial okay so here's a
basic tutorial about writing a how
compiler works it's not actually about
how to write a compiler but how the
outline of compiler so basically you
have the parsing steps then you have
generating code step so so parser is
very interesting and and I haven't got
you know I do not have full
understanding on how to do it exactly
how to write it I mean the point is you
have to be able to write the parcel for
a programming language it's it's it's
it's a bit involved okay so because
normally you like parser when a
programmer says pasa there are so many
different meanings for example if you
write a regular expression to extract
emails in a HTML file you can call it
passing you know no more you just say oh
I I'm gonna pass this HTML to get all
the email addresses that's passing but
oh you you read a UNIX config file UNIX
config file is usually like x equals to
3 you know window size equals to 6 9 9
you know that's kind of like UNIX config
file you want to get the value and said
you know set it to variable that's also
passing but this I mean these are all
passing but that's that's not what
passing means with respect to compiler
with respect to programming language
Parsa okay so in programming language
passing means it means your program
needs to read a grammar file
you know formal grammar basically
Packers no form so you might read this
page you have to so so you have to you
know you have to learn the formal
grammar then your your program is going
to read the formal grammar and then be
able to pass any text any sequence of a
text and turn that into a tree a syntax
tree structure then that's passing okay
once you after that after that then you
do the semantic code generation like
compiling that's a compiling part I mean
that that's the code generation you
you spit out C code you spit out
assembly code or whatever oh you know
that's two parts to two parts to
compiler passing and code generation so
passing is very interesting and
inscribed detail study you know you
might study you know at least half a
year to a year or two to begin to write
a parser and there is tremendous
theoretical aspect to it like
theoretical computer science because
parsing or since it's actually the
formal language you're dealing with from
formal language so you that's that's
when you're dealing with lambda calculus
and all that so parcel so actually I
don't really know about pastas that much
and I have not written a tutorial about
it so so I do not know and obviously I
do not have a email based tutorial about
parsing yeah so yeah I will not be able
to do a passing you know for tutorial
video but you know what what I can do is
like I grope like I you know do it live
and you know I you know I kind of like
learning with it with you guys together
that's right actually it you know I
don't know enough about parsing to
actually do that QDI yes party so okay
so I actually so let's let's go back to
JavaScript and okay so I need to figure
out what we what is the plan to write a
write write a tutorial about plotting
curves let's I think the best thing for
you for fold for the audience is
actually to start from the beginning I
mean the alternative is just to follow
the alternatives just to okay you guys
make a choice the FIR
choice is I'm going to start from
scratch I'm going to start from scratch
and write this so this way you will
learn from scratch how to create this
from scratch it will be one hour okay
that's one one way that's choice one the
second choice is I'm going to explain my
library so these five hundred lines of
library I mean I'm going to use my
library to you know basically I'm going
to see I'm going to explain this code
you see I'm calling my library it's so
simple just one line and then you can
plot it and I'm going to explain that
I'm going to explain the library code
how it works so this is choice too
so number one or number two guys type it
so the answer is fair enough
thanks for the link or the same it's
something I definitely won't get into
yeah so yeah great to see you on Twitter
today
do your spot remember to save so what's
going on but remember to save some
chicks for the rest of us oh you gotta
go okay okay Z trans guys see Tron crazy
and bad so which which option Prada cops
from scratch or explain the library you
know my library about plotting curves
yeah so you know type type he answered
let's see you know type type the answer
like let me know what you guys prefer
Experion library okay so okay let's do
that then so I got Elise Elise I got
this log function or these are SVG
and logistic map I haven't done that yet
geometric inversion that's not done yet
okay so explain the library so okay so
you see this is our SVG it's not bitmap
meaning so because you can see you can
actually select you know select text in
it and because it's SVG so it's like
scalable it's it's smooth all the way
you know what one thing interesting
about parting is that you see all these
starts each time this word up happens
that means there is a point then you
just cut connect point to point to
create lines now you see when there is
when when the curve turns very sharp
there are a lot of points this is
actually this is this is called adaptive
sampling this is what you need to do
because otherwise when you product curve
you will see you know you'll see kinks
so the tech technique is that you
measure you know you plot a bunch of
points of the function you know you prod
lots of points on the function then you
measure the angle you know so this is
one point here let me show you so this
one you know there's one point here at
one point here and another point here so
you have like that right okay so suppose
there are three points then you want to
measure the angle you know between two
two lines if if if the angle is like
flat then that's good
if the angle is greater you know then
some decrease you know not not very flat
then you want to add another point you
know in between that's how you get it to
be smooth you see you see even for this
one this is not so smooth you see here
you see this point there's kind of King
you can see so if you remove the points
if you remove all the red dots
you know here you know people will see
kind of a kink kink that's not what you
want and they are a lot quite quite a
lot other issues for example for his
example there are some master curves
that that just goes infinitely
infinitely non smooth like there are
some examples maybe I should not show it
because we need to focus on the
JavaScript anyway so there are some code
badly pathological curves you know math
mathematician created because they need
to study you know when you study
calculus you need to study smoothness of
the curve differentiability and so on so
there are some monster curves so-called
monster curves that that when it gets
near zero it just go you know up and
down the more closer to zero it goes
more wild you know up down so it becomes
infinitely you know as it approaches
zero it becomes infinitely dense
actually that's interesting monster
curve so I am just let me just talk
randomly then they explained the library
a little bit curved monsters monster
curves Wikipedia space-filling curves ok
space-filling curves is one of the
example of pathological curves let's not
get into that
ok so let's explain library ok let's do
it thank thank you for the reminder
ok the library ok so the library is you
know it's only 500 lines but there are a
lot of functions and a you know we
cannot act we cannot explain them or if
we have to kind of explain
you know actually I think it's actually
better if we just start from scratch
because well if we start from scratch
basically you that's what this library
do you basically you see all the basic
fundamentals of what this library is
because if I otherwise if I just jump to
the library it's a lot of you know
rather boring technical details like for
example you know let's let's let's begin
okay let's let's give some flavor then
maybe we can switch you know if you see
it that's better so for example first of
all you have a bunch of function first
of all okay define constants
okay I'm defining some constants so I
can just write cosine instead of
assigned our costs okay so those are
constants now F range is a function that
just generates array like from 1 to 10
or 1 to 100 with from with increment 0.1
so you need this frequency because when
you want to do a plot you want to say X
from you know 0 to 1 or 0 to 10 you want
to you know have an array so f wrench
that's the range function like the range
in Python okay and then you have split
array speed array is like so you have
one array but you wanted to become
nested sub arrays in other words you say
partition mathematicians code partition
so one over it a way you wanted to
become several nested arrays you know
like there are certain points you want
to cut off why do you want to why do I
need this function because because when
you plot a curve let's say from X to 10
now for some functions some value X will
become infinity you know hey
that happens for example if you say you
know so many functions that happens egg
X becomes the Infinity or you you have
divided by zero so you know those are
bad points you don't want actually so
the so these are technical details about
plotting curve when you start to write
this and when you plot you know for this
you know textbook examples they are so
nice you know they are so just nice you
know 0 to 1 you know 0 to 10 everything
is nice but in real life given a
function it's likely you're just go to
infinity you know any anywhere go to
infinity or you have divided by 0 so you
need to handle that because otherwise
you know the JavaScript they becomes a
nun
you got a numbered na and not a number
because either you are dividing by 0 or
it went to infinity you got infinity and
you cannot plot infinity you know for
example Y becomes infinity
you cannot plot it so you have to so
when that happens you have to actually
you know you have to know which point
that happens you cannot always know
which point that happens unless you do
symbolic mathematics you know so so
there's a lot of issues so you you you
don't know which which point that
happens but but however because you are
computing a function at its many values
you kind of know which which value
becomes very large you know like it
becomes 1 followed by you know the
maximum number representable by
javascript you know the 16 bits or 32
bits float you know so you want to
capture you want to find those numbers
then for example when when when Y goes
to infinity at X equal to 0 for example
you want to find that that payer points
and you want to
you know they are a lot the question is
open there are a lot of ways to handle
it you you could replace it just by you
know just leave it be as long as it's
not infinity just leave that value P so
you you you you are going to have a line
that shoot up or in the case of
parametric party the the line can shoot
into any direction you know like because
you have a huge value of X Y so the
lines goes you know in direction then so
act yeah so you're actually you have
lots of problems but anyway let's go
back to the library so f range is a
range function like python range so this
function split split array it I use this
function to you know to whenever there
is a value of infinity you split you
remove that point and split it into two
arrays this is called partition in a
math okay yes so split array function so
far it's very simple to understand so
all these functions are very simple to
understand this start product of two
vectors that's all these functions are
math or these functions are math
functions that that for for example
vector dot product you take it takes two
vectors one vector then the second
vector then you return this value which
is the dot product now this is useful to
find out when you want to find out the
angle between between two lines two to
two vectors so oh these are math so so
he this is a vector length this is the
unit vector unit vector is like so if
you have a vector you know a vector is
just a pair of numbers like egg XY let's
say X is 3 y is 4 so the pair of number
three four is a vector so what does that
mean it just means
you know it just means before it's a
point so a vector you think of it as a
arrow from zero to that point so that's
a vector basically a line a line segment
ordered a directed line segment so
that's a vector so what's a unit vector
unit vector is a vector in the same
direction but you want the length of the
vector to be 1 so that's unit unit
vector
usually in math you call this
normalization you know why do you want
the vector to be length of one because
because in many ways that solves that
makes a lot of problems simpler so when
you have a vector you want you often you
want to you know shorten the length so
the length is one so this is how you do
it so this function you know it it takes
a vector which is a way of two numbers
then it returns it returns ok I'm using
ok here is function on notation here is
functional programming let me show you
okay make a backup let me show you what
this is doing ok so so so this function
takes argument this argument is a pair
of numbers ok now the body of the
function is this this one two parts so
it's made of made up of one function
evaluated at this value so pattern of MU
you know yesterday we were talking about
functioning function return' of function
so here is actually an example we found
it so the way we the way I define this
function inside you first of all you
create this function then you evaluate
it right away by by by giving it that
argument so let me show you another way
to write this XI am i doing good like
right now we are not explaining anything
about prodding at all so you know if you
like to skip this weekend you know like
just type okay that type tell me what
whether I'm doing good or bad or what
what else you wanna know so so right now
I'm going to be write this function in a
normal or more normal way so no normal
way to write this is like this okay okay
so that's that TD equals to that and TT
okay here here is a alternative way to
write this function so you you first of
all assign you know assign this this can
be constant actually so you assign a
value of this expression then you map
the vector you apply map to the vector
remember the vector is the input of two
array of two numbers you map each
element by X / TT
so this is actually very simple and
actually we can write it this way we
don't even need that so this is how you
do it so okay so actually we don't need
even return either so we can do it this
way so there here is another way to
write it
now you might you might think okay so
why do you write this so complicated way
why don't you just write it this way
because because for efficiency reasons
okay anyway let's not get into that for
efficiency reasons
keeping explaining okay so wait okay so
let's do it
because this is actually difficult to
understand unit vector let me just
explain what it is it's simpler if I
just type in for example a vector you
have XY okay let's say a B okay that's a
vector so what is a unit vector unit
vector is this value okay this value a
square root a squared plus B squared
okay a eight divided by square root a
square plus B Square and the second
argument the second component is P P
divided by square root a squared + B
squared you see so this square root a
power a squared plus two squared
happens twice so this is the math
definition okay but when you want to
code you don't want you don't want this
square root appearing twice because
depending on the language some you know
the compiler is not smart enough the you
know you will actually compute these
twice so you don't want it so the best
thing to do is to compute compute
computer square root assigned to a value
then you know you put a value here and
here you know that that's the thing with
translating math formula to premiere
language there are all these efficiency
issue issues now some compilers you know
today some compilers are smart enough
that when it sees when it sees a
expression repeated you know you just
compute it once but but but you cannot
rely on that that does not always happen
so that that is why you wanna do this
you know what I'm doing so actually yeah
so you know Chuck of hi choked up okay
so anyway that's that's a function about
no more vectors you know you like you
can't go this math concept you can look
up Wikipedia you can look up unit vector
you'll see it you know vector length
length dot product this is third product
you of all find it now in Wikipedia so
this this one computes vector angle it's
not getting into it
so this is vector addition oh these are
simple okay then vector subtraction
scalar multiplication with a vector then
here's a matrix multiplication with the
vector okay now this is a rotation
matrix why do you need this because you
want a point and you want to rotate it
around the origin by by alpha by angle
alpha so you want to rotate it you know
then you need use rotation matrix that's
how you do it so these are linear
algebra then you want to rotate a point
okay so then you want to then you have
Radian to degree degree to Radian and
this one okay this is another technical
detail this is get get curve mean
minimum and maximum so basically this is
you have a bunch of points you know lots
of pair of points you want to find you
want basically you want to find a
boundary so so what why is this useful
so you can find out you can find out
what range to plot you know like from 0
to 10 or 0 to a thousand and why why is
may be from negative 10 billion to
negative 10 you know you need to find
out the plot range basically you need
basically you know another interesting
thing is that what do you need to do
this because for example in this
textbook you know school textbook
examples they are all nice you know you
just start from 0 to 10 you know
whatever but in real life a function
they can go from negative 1 billion to
you know to to whatever you know same
thing with Y so it's unpredictable so
you you can you know so you plot a lots
of points you need to and you you want
it to be automatic you see this is
critical feature very useful this is a
difference between good software and bad
software you know you want you want this
feature to be automatic in fact to write
a curve plotting involves you know
somewhat AI artificial intelligence you
know and this is a good example
like what what range you know what range
to plot because in real life the points
can be anywhere okay so you why do you
want it to be automatic because if it's
not automatic it is almost impossible
for a user to find you know to find out
where where is the where is the actual
curve because you know you know for
science cosine we know you know those
are pretty examples this is so simple
you know it's just centered on our
ancient but in real life it could be
anywhere and it is actually impossible
impossible unless you already know you
have you know symbolic analysis of the
front function you know like textbook
functions sine cosine you know log you
know those those or polynomially be a
but in real life if you are a scientist
you're doing working for NASA you know
you have complicated function you don't
know where it goes so you want and so if
you don't know that it's impossible to
go by trial and error because if you if
you arrange you know let's say if you
try a neck x equals to negative one
thousand two one thousand it may show no
point because it may not be there but
even if it shows some points the you
know all the points this is like little
you have then you have to you have to
duel you have to spend like hours to
find out where the point actually are so
you want a you want a feature that
automatically in some smart way to find
out where is an interesting part of the
plot and this is not trivial okay
because the way I do it here you see
this is a dumb dumb guys way to do it
you know the simple way the simplest
this way is simply to find the minimal X
the maximum X the minimum y the maximum
Y and that that is your you know border
okay but that's no good because for some
for some curves you know they they all
the interesting parts are concentrated
in your area but but far far far where
you might have one point here over there
so that happens so then this is no good
you know you you know so you see what I
mean so that so that so this this is a
problem so this is my solution my simple
solution you know my beginners first try
you know just just find the maxima and
minima but that's not good but if you
really want to do this
you need to have basically you need to
do some statistics so basically you have
a bunch of points you want to find out
the distribution some kind of
statistical distribution then you find
out then you know maybe all the points
actually concentrated over here or if
they are kind of equally distributed
then then this minimum maximum works you
know so for example this is rather
equally this distributed you know all
over the place so that's you know that's
interesting aspect so this is the red
curve minimum maximum that's okay and
this now this is one of the this is the
most actually difficult this function is
most involved at points so it takes one
two three four five five parameters one
two three four four parameters then the
function is like that so what does it do
so like I we explained before you have
adaptive sampling you see basically when
when a curve pens you want more points
over there so it's smooth
I wonder if I should should show example
to actually try to remove the dots so
you can see the difference so you see
why am i plotting the red dots this is
this is actually your debugging plot so
I can actually see you know where are my
points my dots because otherwise you
don't see them you'll see your curve you
don't know where the dots so this is
kind of a debugging part and similarly
you want to try different curves so for
this curve this is equiangular spyro
this curve has a property that all the
angles doesn't matter which point on the
curve you can pick any point on the
curve it has the same angle okay so
that's a special property of this curve
so when you when you want to test your
adaptive something you know algorithm on
curve you can you can try it on these so
on this one you can see walks you know
so it's you know it's working well and
and of course you also want to try this
um you know on this curve so why do I
proud is to because this one you got
more sharp turn very sharp turn that's
why I use this curve you know and this
this this one is typical sign you know
you have very smooth turn so anyway so
so what so this is about adaptive
sampling you know when the when the
curve turns small you want more points
there and and the heart of that
algorithm is this one at point so what
does that do is that okay you have
sequence of points each each point is a
pair of numbers you have a sequence of
them like a list array array of them so
you want to measure the angle between
points you know like every two points
forms a lie every two points forms a lie
so so at each point you actually have an
angle you want to measure that angle if
that angle is is is is you know it's not
flat it's not like 180 degrees then you
want to add another point in between
like on the left or on the right you
know you want to add another point you
know from the function you know so that
that is what this function do you know
given array and given you know the
maximum angle you want this this okay
the first argument is points its array
of points the second second argument is
a function you know it is a function
that the parametric function that pass
the curve okay because you need a
function because you need to call the
function when you want a new point so
the third argument is the max angle you
can you know it's you can it's like an
option you can specify then the fourth
argument is because because level that
is how many times you want to do this
you know so this is getting taken
technical detail because why why because
recursive level because there are many
approaches to how you generate new
points so the way my approach is using
recursion that is you know given a bunch
of points I do it one shot then I got
you know they I got more points this you
know then I can do I can do you know
because you know do it one more time so
how many times I want to recurse you
know so the more recursion the more
smooth my curve will be but you don't
want you don't want to you know you want
you don't want too much because you
don't want you don't want a million
points because that's gonna crash the
browser or sort of slow down your
program you want just the right number
so that you know it doesn't kinks like
this doesn't happen you don't see sharp
pins that doesn't happen
so that is why
this function is about so so far so good
bathroom you and all you guys eat wrong
crazy and how many people are watching
seven okay so say something guys let me
know how am i doing so so that's what
this function about add points so let's
jump to the next so far so good okay
great so next next function we have this
translate string and scale string okay
what basically what those are you know
when you do this kind of thing often
times you want to scale the whole thing
you know magnify or shrink it or you
want to rotate the whole thing or you
want to translate in math you go
translate which means move move the
whole thing you know up or down or to
you know to to somewhere that's
mathematical operation that's part of
group theory you know the whole oh these
are called isometry that that's some
tech jargon so okay look up isometry
look up you know anyway so you want so
you won't do that now SVG has a way to
do that okay now so we're getting into
starting to get into SVG so let's let's
go to SVG okay now remember to do this
you need to know JavaScript you need to
know Tom because tom ties everything
together Dom is basically the browser
controlling you know how you generate
those these things then you need to know
SVG SVG is the actual the actual okay
here's my you see here here's my another
JavaScript app to generate a arc very
difficult in SVG anyway so this is this
is my SVG tutorial so SVG
when you do SVG first of all let me show
you a little bit what SVG looks like
because because all of these you know
all this partying SVG let me show you
okay yeah so this is let me show you
part of the explanation so let's show
the source code open that open that open
that
so let's magnify so you see all these
you see all that I mean okay you see you
see this path element you see this gg's
for grouping so first of all you first
of all in my source code i have a type
ID equals to as SVG plant one okay then
everything below it you know everything
inside it is generated by JavaScript so
this is the actual output of the
JavaScript so you see so you got a group
then you got a group then you got path
so this path this one is actually some
points there you know some segments so
this is another segment so let's go down
you see so you got lots of Oh actually
shows there you see oh those are the
vertical lines those are the background
vertical grid you see so the the browser
actually shows shows shows it you see so
those are the better go with hope code
great then you have okay then you have
let's see okay then you have this these
are the path you know this this is the
blue lines the actual curve you know so
you got thousands of points probably a
thousand or two then you have these are
texts okay so these are the labels so
what you see there is the SVG SVG is XML
okay it's just like a key
it's just like HTML so so your job when
you when you write this part in software
your job is simply to generate those
elements you know it sounds simple
you know actually so you can actually
use Python or whatever the language to
create this and show and and just
showing browser your work so you yohko
is actually just to generate these
elements this SVG elements so let's see
so this so these are texts these are the
vertical the y axis labels then what are
these these are the thoughts okay let's
show okay so you can see thoughts are
circles
first okay now now it's just okay so you
see you can see in a browser over here
it shows the circle label I mean those
are just the dots lots of dots okay so
that's the SVG that's so that's you know
what all these code are going doing so
back to this function so SVG so back to
SVG so you see what SVG is like and SVG
has a feature that is let's go to SVG
SVG has a feature that allows you to do
transformations coordinate
transformation let's see
yeah so you see this translate scale
reflect rotate the way you use it is
like these for example here is SVG we
say you know SVG tagged with and hate
then you create a rectangle
you know the x equals to 0 y equals to 0
that's a coordinate rectangle and color
gray okay that's the first rectangle
there and this this is another rectangle
with the same coordinate you see X 0 y 0
but however you have this this string
this attribute it says transform equals
true you know a string the string says
translate you know 20 40 so this is how
you use how the SVG translate works you
know so so you have this bunch of
functions translate scale reflect your
Tait but they need to be a string you
see because this is not a programming
language exactly so so these functions
actually inside the string then you say
transform equals to that string this is
one of the very annoying thing about
about CSS and SVG and XML you you know
because when you do things inside the
string that's extremely extreme pain in
the ass so anyway but but that's how SVG
is you know you yeah so the here is
aligned that's what you have to say same
thing for when you want to scale
something you know so if you want to use
this in your JavaScript you know again
there are many ways to do it
like if you want to move a graph there
are many ways you can you can directly
use JavaScript to you know to to
translate the points directly or you can
add to your SVG this
attribute you know transform equals to
something and it seems that using this
way you know using SVG is actually
faster because SVG you know SVG
so-called decorative you know decorative
language okay so and because it's
implemented in browser browser has you
know optimization to death you know so
when you do this you know when you
specify SVG you know transform something
it's faster than you you know we then
you actually you know do computation on
on thousands of points in JavaScript so
that's why I have this to function
you know because generating a strange
the pain so I have a function that that
generates the string the translate
string for you you see this is a string
translate okay so okay okay I is it
wrong goodnight
so okay so I think I think this is kind
of boring
am i right z tron crazy or any any other
guys watching six people watching okay
so so the next function the next
function is creating a SVG element so we
are actually starting to get into SVG so
what this function do this function
actually just create this this element
like you know like like this SVG with
hate view box XY you know things like
that and basically you use this thing
you use this building function to create
a SVG element so you say document dot
create element yes
and you know a bunch of things that's
how you create a SVG element so so this
function just created our SVG element
with you know with attribute like like
with and hate like that okay so I'm not
sure this is saying this is going well
so fast what do you say so we have we
have creating SVG element yeah because
this you know because this code this
code is real life code and real life
code you have a huge amount of things
you know you are not interested you know
as for for beginners and also this is
written in typescript so you got all
these incomprehensible kind of crap you
know so I think actually to learn so
Beckerman says it's interesting to see
yeah okay so yeah so I guess it's
interesting to see real live code once
in a while you know because I mean like
I'm thinking like right now after this
you wouldn't be you know you have you
wouldn't be able to start to write one
you know right where the SVG but however
if we start the beginning you you you
would know after you know what our you
would know you can start to write you
know from scratch you can start to do it
but not from explaining this code
because because when I explain these
things I'm explaining their concept what
they do but but but I don't explain the
code you know like you don't you don't
see the code what what you know because
it's fairly complicated it because it is
real-life stuff you
it gots lots of you know error-checking
and lots of other type things but if we
start from scratch you know it will be
very simple you you see what the whole
thing I mean you see kind of the whole
kind of architecture and actually I have
an example here so if you want to learn
SVG you know the basic just you know
like if you want to begin to write write
this SVG you can buy by reading
just one page by reading this page
scripting SVG so here we have a SVG of a
red circle and the entire code is just
these ten line 10 lines 10 lines also 15
lines and this entire code kind of
capture I mean kind of represent the
whole I mean all this complexity kind of
that's the bottom line so that you know
this is the foundation you know to draw
a circle you can see how to use
JavaScript Dom to create SVG images and
and this is the fundamental so this you
learn first first of all you need to
create a HTML element that's that's so
you can tell JavaScript where to insert
the SVG then in your code you generate a
SVG element then you generate you know
you add width and hate attribute then
this five lines is how you generate a
circle you know SVG element and in fact
every other STD SVG SVG element is the
same you know they are just different
like you have rectangle you have path
you have you know
things but basically the code is the
same that you know how you generate a
SVG element then you set set the
attribute like the center of the circle
the radius you know for rectangle we
basically it's a corner you know of the
rectangle and with and hate means like
that you know you create a SVG element
then you set attribute that's how you do
it then you attach the SVG element you
just created into the SVG you know tag
then you attach that to the ID to the
you know HTML place so meaning that you
insert it so that's how you get this
image so it's you know this is the
outline and all these code are doing
that you know all this code basically
for example let's see we explained one
of the code this code this this code
create SVG this code is it's basically
this single line you know it just it
just create a SVG tag but why do I have
so much code here because I mean because
this is the library so it's for
convenience the SVG tag you have the
pram you have the attribute with hate
you also have optional attribute called
view box that's how you specify user
coordinates okay so so if you do it raw
then you're gonna read it like this you
know first of all first you create a SVG
element then you set attribute which set
attribute hate set attribute view box
then you know four values stream things
like that but that's this is
inconvenient you know this is tedious so
you have this one single function with
you know so the way you use it for
example let me show you where
use it so search for these go down there
it is so you look at this line this is
how I create a SVG so you just call
create SVG no no no no means the first
argument is the parent meaning where do
you want to attach this as VG element to
you know for example in this page we
need to attach it to the dive you know
like where do you want to insert it into
HTML so so the s the first argument is
the parent because here I don't want to
attach anywhere so I say no and second
third argument is the width and hate I
don't want any so I say no now remember
no is different from with equal to zero
or something because when you say no you
do not even have the width or hate
attribute at all you know those are
different so anyway so I say no no then
then I give a array of four elements
here you have X min Y mean X with Y
width that's the view parks attribute
that specifies the user coordinate
because if you do not specify user
coordinate then it's just the pixels you
know for example for example in this in
this in this part you know from from
from the left folder to the right border
there are maybe 800 pixels so if you do
not specify user coordinate then your
coordinate coordinate is going to be
you're gonna work with from 0 to 800 and
when you plot a sine you have to
translate you know your coordinate into
the pixel coordinate so that's a pain so
you can SVG you can specify a user
coordinate by what's called a view box
you know I have a tutorial here you can
read you know the view box view box unit
you use a codon so anyway so you see so
I call this function it's kind of nice
you know everything they are just one
line instead of otherwise otherwise I
would have to say otherwise it's gonna
going to be like ten lines you know
otherwise you know it's going to be like
this create as SVG element then sit
attribute say attributes say attribute
then a paint child you know it's kind of
like that so that is why so that so you
see now you see this function so let's
go back to the definition you know so
that's the that that's a function
okay that's function so then here we
have another function so hold on hold on
a second let's take a break let's see
let's take a break and see where are we
going so sabatham you says maybe you can
focus on like 20 complicated lines and
explain them in far more detail okay
then yeah maybe there let's do that
forbidden says it's like how level it's
like lonely about UI code describing
elements yes okay so great thank you
guys for the comments so okay bathroom
you says maybe focus on something and go
in in depth okay so okay so let me think
what I want to do okay so anyway so far
so good so actually the rest is not much
all the almost all the rest of them is
about generating SVG elements let me
show you okay yeah we go through this
so you see so we have a function that
generates as you've seen we have this
function created vgm element that's the
first one that creates a SVG tag then
you have this function this function
generates a okay
so this function generates elliptical
curve which I kind of showed a little
bit there
why because let me show you now SVG is
kind of it's not you know all these
standards Tom it's very they got lots of
problems lots of you know extremely
weird you know it's just sucks yeah you
know like if you know math or if you
know programming I mean either either
either camp if you know math you know
how to specify a lisp their parameters
and so on if you know programming you
know you know how to write a function
and so on but when it comes to Tom and
scg doesn't matter which which group you
are you find lots of incredibly like you
like you find like why would somebody
like what the why would somebody
create something like this like like
like because every time you want to use
it it's very tedious not just tedious
but it's like it's very bad badly
designed you'll find that a lot in DOM
and SVG just like UNIX okay just like
the UNIX shell and oh and you know it
and many programming languages you know
as a programmer you swear all day like
what did what are they thinking why is
it this way
there are a lot reasons you know so
spacing mostly yeah because social
reasons you know it didn't happen that
way and in its most specifically SVG it
turns out I looked into I study the
detail you know I try to trace wise in
this way like who who
designed it I mean is it's you know we
tend to think okay someone you know who
is a great coder who designed it
something like that they become standard
no typically that's not the case
typically it's either committee or
nobody cares okay
like SVG is like that it's like
something like nobody really know nobody
really cares but it so happens you know
you have this standard and you know
seems like people say oh this is the
standard we need but nobody care about
it you know commercial organizations
like Apple and flash any particular
fashion
they do their thing you know they don't
give a about SVG they care about
their design you know Apple has you know
Apple invented canvas okay Apple and an
apple is you know anyway canvas that's
Apple summation then you know the the
the the flash you know the macro media
back then
Adobe fast you know they take care they
have they have ActionScript basically is
like ActionScript is basically like
JavaScript you know but for their stuff
you know fash to code fash so so forth
for like ten years flashes everywhere
you know and it's it's fantastic you
know you can create Cox you know other
clocks are we done if you flash per
those games you know to 2d games
everywhere but SVG is like you know SVG
is actually very old beginning around
year 2000 you know 1999 something like
that but it is it's like it's like SVG
is like someone you know like every
program says oh yeah we need this we
need this but actually nobody nobody
cares you know they just like most
programmers yeah open-source so you know
that they don't actually have you know
like like if they if something went bad
it doesn't matter anything to you
nothing happens to you that is when all
the bad things have
like like when you buy something you
have to pay right then you carefully
choose Oh which which computer should I
buy what memory you know you you you
spend the time to research but if you
are professor you are telling students
to buy textbooks you don't care you just
care what book is good for you you don't
care how much it is that is why the
textbooks becomes you know to $300 today
anyway so SVG's like that SVG you know
every you know programmers and the big
companies you know say oh yeah we need
this but nobody gives gives a so so
you know it turns out you know people
just like people who don't really know
things they just created from scratch
lots of bad designs and in particular
you should go read there is a woman who
participated without pay okay
this happens a lot in programming in
lots of this standard so she she is not
expert but she became a expert you know
because she started to study SVG so she
became an expert and she participated in
the standard process and she also wrote
wrote SVG books SVG - okay it's a
fantastic blog you should go read it
okay so this is this girl I forgot the
name I can look for it but I forgot that
moment anyway it's a woman who has
written at least two SVG books published
in the past three years okay go to
Amazon you'll find it
SVG books published in the past three
years she has written at least two of
them as co-author at least she is also
participated in the SVG 2 standard which
which I think came out within the past
few years
ok fine her name then find her blog she
written a blog about SVG to standard
like her that she tells you the
experience how it all happened
you read it then you realize it's like a
it's like very bad okay it's like
extremely bad so so anyway back to the
topic so my point you know we were so
that that is about why SVG sucks so bad
and and similarly for many other
technologies DOM and XML so anyway so
let me be the comments a little bit so
it's like huh so forbidden 303 forbidden
we are you from what country or city
more important is the concept of
coordinate systems okay I think maybe we
explain that because that's that's
important so have you ever played with
blender 3d I tried I tried ten years ago
exactly ten years ago like 2008 2009
when I was in second life and I didn't
go anywhere so I tried it you know for
two three days it's I didn't go anywhere
it has a Python interface
you mean blender 3d okay when the 3d it
has a reputation of being extremely hard
to learn on the other hand there are
many other CAD systems open source of
you know CAD systems that has much more
intuitive you know more intuitive than
blender 3d so bottom you says my my
internet was down for the past 20
minutes oh my god I don't know why but
at least I'm back online
okay okay so you you missed you missed a
big rant on SVG okay I don't know if you
caught that so forbidden says the
convolution programming languages drove
me to lisps okay Scotland
Oh Scotland ah very interesting
cool it's much better now okay so how
long I been talking I I'm thinking maybe
that's like it oh my god one hour and 16
minutes yeah so let me go but you know
not this not much to the to this package
you know the devil is in the details
that's that's that's the thing when you
start to write I mean on the surface you
know creating SVG is just like you know
just like you know just like these you
know that's the outline that's a button
but the details is so many details
anyway and when you write a protein
software there's a whole term houghton
of issues you need to solve like
adaptive something and also the
automatic automatic range you know you
know you know that that's a lot of
problem to sell to to to solve then you
have to deal with asymptotes you know
like for example in this I wrote down
some of the problems I encounter and
solutions some I have several solutions
already some I do not you know some of
these you know you take days take it you
know took me days to actually find a
solution for example one is scalable
canvas size problem I mean this is a big
problem okay now I know the solution the
problem is you see when you okay let me
show you actually the camera size
problem okay you can you guys see it oh
you guys cannot see it part of it
part of it side hidden okay so anyway so
when you plot you know why out functions
you have situation like this it becomes
a thin strip oh you have situation like
this you know it becomes a vertical
strip
depending on the function you know on
the other hand you see on my hand you
you want it to be automatic range so you
got these problems and how you solve it
is it's it's hard okay the and this is
why in the early days on Linux many DVD
players they cannot you know they cannot
find to find find the aspect
ratio like when you watch DVD on on
Linux of you know in in the early days
you know this this they squash the
picture so you know that's funny you
know and I realized so that is actually
a problem because this is not it's
somewhat complicated you to actually
solve this problem it's somewhat
complicated so I spent days to actually
you know solve this find out exactly
what's going on like you do an analysis
on what exactly that is the problem what
is it you want to do you know and find
out what exactly this is problem why it
happens and so on and what is a desired
result when this happened so desired
result when that happens then you have
to find out how how to implement those
solutions do you I mean I mean is it is
this a coordinate problem in SVG or is
it with and hate problem aspect ratio
and how do you do a square ratio in SVG
you know SVG has aspect ratios you know
like and and also you know it's fairly
complex because also in a browser it's
not just SVG because the SVG has to go
into into a browser when you don't
specify width and hate it actually
creates automatically create a you know
a area so lots of complexities are
involved then you also go with SVG
standard usually oftentimes it's not
clear
like what like you you think you are
within the standard you know the spec
SVG
Veck but it's not clear and yeah and
it's not clear because it is not really
good you know badly written because
nobody cares about it so anyway that
that's one of the problem the s aspect
ratio and with hate problem the other
problem is auto proud range problem this
we talked about already because you do
want a automatic range finder but it's
not easy anyway we talked about that and
adoptive adoptive sampling problem we
talked about and we have a solution
that's pretty good you know that is you
product so the curve do not have kinks
you know do not Bend sharply then you
have asymptote problem you see this is a
puppet okay look at this fat you see
that part that is a hyperbola you see
you see a dot over here you see kind of
like goes like that and goes like it's
very ugly let me show you a hyperbola
okay sorry
so this these are schoolbook curves you
know you learn these curves in
precalculus hyperbola is this you know
this kind of is kind of two of them like
shaped curve so let me show you some you
know that's some of the ways to generate
hyperbola okay and here's more hyperbola
hyperbola is a family of curves that
means there are many of them but they
are well defined anyway I'm not let's
not go into it but anyway all these the
white curves here are hyperbola they
have hyperbola like any conic sections
like a league a lisp and parabola
they have special optic properties for
example if you shoot away
I forgot what oh yeah okay so so you if
you have a hyperbola here suppose they
are mirrors suppose they are like yes me
Rose won't like one-way mirrors or
something like that
so if you have two light points here the
you shoot array laser think of it as a
laser you should a laser ray and it will
refract it will refract and in fact if
your light source is is at this precise
point then doesn't matter which
direction you shoot away all the Rays
will refract into this exact point okay
and and vice versa so you can shoot rays
from here or here but they so every
parabola has two point code focus
associated with it that that's a beauty
of math you know you have all these
special properties anyway so that's
hyperbola and these two points are
called its focus and focus and so we
seen one property that is up to
poverty then there are other you know
lots of other properties for example
this is a Peter poverty so if you okay
there's a lot to explain so if so if you
have a hyperbola let me explain this way
if you have a hyperbola okay then you
draw a circle that that is in the middle
of the you know centered on the center
of the hyperbola then this this thing
happens okay okay so once you have a
middle then you draw a line from one of
the focus to any point on the on a
circle any okay any point on a circle
then you draw a line perpendicular to it
so you see we draw a line to any point
of the circle and then we immediately
draw a line perpendicular to that now
this perpendicular line is a tangent to
the parabola at some point you see what
I mean so it's tangent so you see so you
can also shoot a right here you know
anyway that that that this this this
this property is called Peto
okay anyway so so there are so many many
many many interesting properties okay
now what why why am i mentioning
hyperbola because when you plot
hyperbola remember we are trying to plot
it right we are trying to for example we
are trying to plot a hyperbola and I
failed you know I wrote my program it
works on sign it works on you know
equiangular triangle so let's do hi
problem it failed why because when you
use a specific parametric formula for
example if you use this formula to
prepare Umbra then there are many
formulas by the way but anyway
if you use one formula what will
happening is that the point we are you
know we start at T equals to zero okay
so 0 then 1 2 3 4 and so on you know so
the point will start here then we're the
point will go there here here here you
know you'll go up up the hyperbola and
then the point will go into infinity
okay you wish he will shoot to infinity
then it will come back from the opposite
direction of infinity it will come back
here so you'll come back here here here
here
then then up to infinity again then come
back from the other direction okay so
when you when when you prod it you got a
problems I'm not showing it here but
basically this is called asymptotes
asymptotes okay so so that's another
problem you have to deal with when you
write a curve plotting function
asymptotes P is basically a lie that
happens for example if you have this is
actually a hyperbola and you have this
axis that's actually the same thought
the this graph the red lines are the
equations of 1 over X and 1 over X is
actually a hyperbola okay it's just kind
of rotated by anyway when you try to
play part 1 over X you have another
problem which is the divide by 0 problem
so so I need to fix that you Mike let's
let's show you some actual example let's
start to let's do that
I mean it's this to some parting and and
let's and that's it for today
what is his unit vector
save okay let's go back to okay that's
just product let's create a another one
so okay so for trout fall and it's open
it let's create a new prod at the top
here and this will insert at to plot for
and let's say let's just plot 1 over X
okay 1 1 divided by X let's let's say
from zero point 1 let's say zero point
zero one to seven
okay now go to browser refresh there we
have it a problem this is another
problem it's a long long page you see oh
my god this is God you see so when you
do these lots of these happens okay so
this it's not so let's try 0 1 okay go
back to browser refresh okay now that's
better
back to Emacs 0.2 let's say okay seven
browser refresh okay so you see we are
we got the x over 100 X let's do some
let's do some fun fun thing for today
let's just say math dot SCI okay this
lets do random let's see what we can do
x equals two
cause size zero to seven okay sine
cosine this is gonna be a circle and
pretty sure there it is sine cosine you
see the labels the the axis labels is
another very very difficult thing to do
because on one hand you see you don't
want them to overlap but however when
the scale is very small let's say from
zero to 0.1 you know you want to pry
something that from zero to 0.1 so so in
between all the numbers is zero point
something something like a factor you
know so you don't have you know then you
cannot you know when you write the
numbers they overlap so how do you solve
that there is no simple answer is quite
you know it involves a I it involves
elementary a I that is you you need to
figure out some smart way you know some
heuristics so that your label stone
overlap you know maybe use slant the
labels you know and the most difficult
part is that you want to make all this
automatic you know you don't want users
to you know oh no you know I see overlap
then I try to adjust you know so they
don't overlap that doesn't work because
then you're gonna adjust it ten twenty
times it's very time wasting so if you
want a good software you you need to
have these automatic so they don't do
things like that you you know you want a
automatic labeling system so the label
generated they don't overlap and also
they just make sense for you you know
without you self you know have to
specify you know where you want the
label of course that's optional you can
do that you want to provide you want to
let users to specify at which point they
want war labels that would be good but
meanwhile you want automatic labeling
system and the key things is that you
wanted to be you know you want you
wanted to
smart you know makes sense the labels
make sense so let's try sine x times
let's let's try something saying
something like that okay let's try it
/ - okay let's see what happens oh let's
let's nest it let's nest sign okay first
of all constant sign math sign okay okay
so what what is pi so let's see okay
okay so we got the function here and
let's say sine X oops something wrong
let's say science
and maybe and see what see zero so what
what what
any comments am I still going okay we're
gonna shut down we're gonna shut down in
two minutes something like that
so last words put your last words and
we're gonna shut down in two minutes
so let's see what's the error console
uncaught syntax error identifier sign
has already already been been declared
oh of course
yeah so identify sign has already been
declared oh oh okay right yeah so we are
we we don't need any parts there it is
what is this okay let's go back to one
way we can do is shrink it shrink
doesn't look so another way to solve
this is actually create a we need to
actually specify a user code and I mean
we need to specify a width and hate but
let's not do it now so let's sign sign
let's see what happens
why is it not going oh yeah so if you
have sign inside that doesn't work
because everything is just going to be
one
okay Oh No okay so we got figure eight
no no let's see yeah that's not good
okay we're gonna we get some kind of
leisure leisure leisure drew something
called digital so let's let's square
let's put square root into the equation
first x times math dot square root okay
X square root is spelled wrong I think
okay anyway that's that should be it
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it for today yeah that's it for today
any last questions protests post-it and
buy bathroom you buy forbidden
and whoever is here by have you done any
four-year serious series now actually I
have not studied Fourier series Fourier
series it's one of the things that it's
you know people talk about that often
but I actually never studied Fourier
series much okay bye guys