good morning welcome to another episode
of XR talk show today is 2000 19th 2019
October 19th
Saturday 10 o'clock a.m. San Francisco
time Oh
today's Saturday nice in my life yes I'm
alive good morning George George isn't
it 3 o'clock in morning it's pretty
early for you let's pop this out and I
do have some topics some random topics
so we're gonna talk about and that let's
see what parts say good morning but far
says how can a new Linux distribution be
created that is exactly according to
your dreams that you would actually use
it rather than Mac OS ok basically what
is your dream GNU Linux a Linux
distribution you will look ok that's
several questions let me answer that
George says any comments on 2020
election oh yeah yes of course I have a
lot comments about that politics but so
far tulsi gabbard
seems best yes I agree how would how
would yang box change your life young
bucks that idea I don't I don't I'm not
much for bar says ok employees Ryan will
start a new one if he would follow a
couple of simple rules other people
based bashing fresh what bashing free
[ __ ] no I understand how hard some
people's life are okay
some people have it rough good morning
good morning League
of noobs 1 a.m. Australia
tempers you know it's interesting that
Perth was in Australia Perth is on the
west side of Australia on the lower let
lower left corner Perth has have the
same time as China Bolivia not because
if you look at Earth is actually below
China kind of so we don't see your
desktop Oh indeed let's switch back
great thank you for that comment great
comments I always correct me in my
livestream ok there so there we are
so my English is pretty bad anyways
sorry for that League of New says I have
nothing wrong with what you are saying I
just hope that people are reasonable and
not as horse ok uh legal news ok so so
let's begin let's begin at the beginning
well it's begin with maths books real
projective plane this is projective
geometry we talked about few days ago
projective geometry real projective
plane this is this one is by Jo by
godness stupid camera HSM coxster is a
very well-known geometers he lived up to
100 years old he died about 10 years ago
real projective plane Pascal's theorem
ok projective geometry in fact I have an
article about that sorry
projective geometry ok I can see that
this we are going on into a talk chain I
will be talking nonstop for
our projective thing because whenever I
have a topic I mean I started to talk
about something Danes gonna be nonstop
with multitudes of recursive digressions
and great software oh let's not remember
let's not forget that link great
software for plane geometry God and
let's look at projective illusion and
harmonic conjugacy you see guys this
harmonic controversy that is a theory in
projective geometry and quite a few
quadrilateral and quadrilateral to
triangle theorem this is the most
important theorem in projective geometry
well it's not the most okay it's not the
fundamental theorem of projective
geometry but it is the it is a
foundation theory the sagas - triangle
theorem is fascinating projective
projective geometry and by the way when
you go study math in college in
institutionalized education system
universities you go there you study math
you are math major after four years you
got a degree bachelor's degree and you
would know nothing about projective
geometry you know basically nothing
because it's not a subject they teach in
general you know it's just it's like
programming languages no most most of
you guys know about you'll come up relax
but [ __ ] let's see check check
no it should it should be fine I think
it should it I think it's fine oh it's
it's lagging I know why it's lagging
because I was opening or the webpages
it's loading that's why it must be why
so let me know if that happen
again yeah it must be you know I'm
opening pages so is that so I was saying
so if you know in you know it's like
programming languages if you study
computer science in college most college
you know maybe they teach Java they
teach Python but they would never teach
Lisp okay so it does not work but it
does not mean this has no merit in fact
it's you know oh you know list so so so
math is like it's like computers you
know so some subject in math they don't
really teaching universities and one
such example is projective geometry okay
I'm gonna talk about that a bit more and
showing and I'm going to show you my
pages I have actually quite a lot pages
to talk about and this book now let's go
back to the this book the history of
mathematics by car Bo you see this is a
thick one this is a thick one this
projective geometry is the thing one
hardcover and this this history of math
is a thick one so these books mostly I
read in 1990s you know I am a math but
I'm a math phonetic I dive I live in
math I dive into I have to read it every
day a dream I dream of math and geometry
every day in the 1990s you know when you
think about something this you know for
programmers some of you might also have
this experience like you dream about
some bug you want to solve or how to
code something because when you think
about something dream basically reflects
what's what what you are thinking what's
on your mind so if you do something
every day you think about it when you
are dreaming and an end
sometimes actually some solutions come
to you in dreams and we have many
anecdotes about that for physics you
know great discovery discover your
physics listen some some stories like
that
League of noobs says I think about
coding problems while sleeping yes
indeed and this book now this is another
book now this this one you know actually
I have quite a few history of math books
so I studied a lot history of math you
know like I mentioned you know
programming syntax notation is extremely
important in fact it's the most
important thing of a programming
language the syntax okay not the
semantics of whether the [ __ ] syntax is
the most important thing in programming
languages okay and one reason we can see
that we is from the history of math
notations okay I talked about that in
previous videos just such folks are the
math YouTube channel and this book is an
interesting one this this one is the
stupid cap the language of the party
okay it's got this pretty girl you're
naked
oh well lovely suite by Alexander lo an
MD okay medical something doctor and
he's a psychologist or psychiatrist I
think he's some what we all know but
notice this is the old book this is this
book is written in I think 1960s or
something the language of the body okay
so you can find it on Amazon 1958 it's
published in 1958 and do you know why am
i reading this book because
the personality disorder as you know you
know some of you see have seen my videos
you know some of you have watched many
of my video spot right and button League
of Nations - and oh we got a Chinese
here George's wife here oh good morning
Miao means sure nice to meet you
George's wife here he is always your
loyalty guests everybody every day I can
always listen to your voice every day
and it sounds interesting because you
have a Taiwanese accent yes oh you can
tell it's so familiar for me ha enjoy
so Taiwanese accent do you me - speak
Chinese or do you mean you can tell for
my English so George George are you are
you Chinese or are you why this person
did he did he marry you easy lacasa
League of Nations League of Nations so
what what are we okay so I was talking
about this book so this book is you know
see he's a psychology psychiatry
psychologist old-fashioned 1958 remember
and when you read the book you know
1960s book the reading style especially
he's a classic psychologist you know he
write a style he described the human
behavior and you know body of the
language okay I'm reading this book by
the way I bought this book like back in
1997 because I was researching what is
wrong with me by the way that is a
common question among young people
because when young yeah this happens
often to young people because when you
are young when you are a young link
as a matter if you are a human animal if
you are a cup or if you are a puppy or
if you are a [ __ ] kitten kitten is a
redwood then the you know young or if
you are a young turtle you know you die
you know the chances of you dying is
high because you don't know you don't
have experience in life and they are
petted predators I in you the moment you
are born you know when you when you have
turtles turtles sea turtles they hatch
on the beach so when they hatch I think
they dug a hole in the sand then a bunch
of them hatches you know then you have
like 100 or something little turtles
crawling out and you know one thing very
interesting that is a turtle we all know
which way is the sea we ho they will
come out you know you have hundreds of
them little turtles tiny turtles and
they are just ahead to the sea but when
the moment that happens the egos or
whatever birds you know they are
swooping down and get you know and eat
you so actually there is another book I
want to show related to this one so
anyway I was saying when you are young
this this is true for basically all
animals when you are young
you are the most vulnerable not just
physically but also psychologically so
young people usually have the question
oh what's wrong with me oh I'm different
oh you know you feel sad or depressed or
things like that well you'll get over
you know especially especially this is
when parents and a good parent is
critical you know when you have have a
good parent that's critical when you do
not have a good parent or a single
parent which is common every day today
by the social justice [ __ ] social
justice can [ __ ] they they created
this situation an American Democratic
Party they've made the American black
people like 50 percent or 60 percent
they don't have a dad okay it's all just
mom in taking government
we're fail because if you have a dad you
do not qualify okay so so so it creates
the situation where the guys just leave
you know did you oh the women just get
divorced so they can you know it doesn't
matter to me I can just take government
money so they the American Left
Democratic Party created the situation
where American blacks like sixty percent
or something or even higher we are don't
have a parent they are just mom single
parent and when that happens you know
you're missing a parent or you have a
bad parent you create problems you know
the father young so that is one and
actually let me show let me pick up the
other book I want to show
can you see it okay now it's very dusty
it's very dusty so I have to brush it
off
the betrayal of the body now pay
attention to this cover okay
look closely closely at a girl and
observe okay look you know tell me what
do you think of her you know you see
that girl observe the betrayal of the
body okay now observe the girls and let
me know like like put out put your
psychoanalysis abilities on this face
I'll be right back
there is the brush and I'm going to
brush it right off because it's or dust
or dust okay let's see comments okay
comments comments comments
I mean tiwa I'm a Taiwanese and he is a
local Aussie great fantastic
meow means show miss OH
Xiao Qi I can tell you're Taiwanese
accent from your English by the way oh
that's interesting
hmm yeah I guess yeah I guess
Quinta good morning Quinn back to Russia
so that betrayal of the body is also
written by the same guy Alexander Lowen
okay now I read I pick up this book
first then I picked up his other book
the language of the body you know why
why did I found how did I find this book
and again this is written in 1960s
betrayal of the body let me tell you
what this body 1967 okay
this book is written one year before I
was born
now remember I did a video on schizoid
personality disorder
so in a nightie when I was 20s you know
basically throughout my 20s and teens I
always have you know you got problems
like psychological problems which is
which is actually true for me because
well my family and stuff my background
so you wonder oh maybe I'm depressed
because I you know maybe maybe I have
depression or maybe I have something but
eventually now I'm you know I'm 50 51
basically when you get older when you
become you know 30 when you win when you
are 40 for example you you don't have
these problems anymore because you know
you have experience you know what how
things are you know you
you I mean so even if you have
personality disorders like these
disorders or whatever you pretty much
get okay get over it
so what we so what I'm going to say oh
this one okay
I'm gonna talk about that what am I
going to say yeah so I was going to say
today's talk show yeah so I did a video
YouTube video personality disorder
especially schizoid I have like two two
or three videos about schizoid you just
go to my youtube channel and search for
schizoid
okay that's spelled let's see sorry s CH
IC o---- ID schizoid okay you'll find it
and there's article I we I did a video
talking about that okay you don't find
you have to click on YouTube okay turn
script you see the idiotic DuckDuckGo do
not cannot allow you to if you have
JavaScript off you cannot just click it
you have to retype the whole thing if
you want to search images or videos now
you can search videos so I did a videos
schizoid in meeting and skis over there
it is ski so it again ski so it's four
videos whose title contains the word ski
so so eventually I'm you know I'm mostly
I would say ok I have never seen a
shrink before but I was saying ski so a
personality which basically means a
loner so in 1990s you know I was reading
this book I discuss I want to know
what's going on you know I want to know
am I wrong in some way you know so I
found this book then the language of
body by the same guy and his writing is
very interesting because he
the betrayal of body okay let's talk let
me show you this book betrayal of the
body you see this girl so what is what
is your impression have you found the
impression yet she is a schizoid like
like the prototypical the stereotypical
picture or illustration of a schizoid
personality so-called disorder it's a
disorder when your personality is so
extreme that you cannot function in
society such as you cannot find a job
you cannot have relationships you know
things like that and schizoid
personality disorder is one of the
disorders you know you know each one of
us have these personalities but when it
becomes extreme then you call it
disorder like you have antisocial you
have bipolar you have you know bipolar
is many active-passive you have many
many things you have histrionic which is
a person who likes to be dramatic all
the time
green deck says who is your favorite
Western philosophers that would be
Bertrand Russell he's not just my
favorite philosopher but he is my idol
even now I mean even um you know if I
pick the top one person I respect in
Western society in english-speaking you
know English author that would be
Bertrand Russell Bertrand Russell is
also the greatest the one of the great
greatest mathematician logician okay
that's how you spell his name
sorry Bertrand Russell I have quite a
few articles of him and okay yeah one of
his book is history of philosophy I know
a history of the Western for us
I think something like that one of his
book but I have not read that one
so here are two a few articles I have on
Bertrand Russell there are more but what
desires what yes so there are three
articles I recommend you read them okay
we got a lot to talk about
and he also you know he said one of the
great mathematician and he's well he's
he's known as you know if you go to
encyclopedia he's known as one of the
great logician and he's one of the great
philosopher he created the school of
philosophy called analytic philosophy
which means which means you study you
approach philosophy from kind of a
scientific methodology okay analytic
philosophy also also he's he's known as
the positive logic season you know
that's a movement positive logic system
no I actually it's a called logical
positivism okay logical positivism
that's once you can look up Wikipedia
okay
Rochambeau wrote John Purcell great
logician great philosopher and he's also
known as the great peace activist you
know so throughout his life he's he
advocate for disarm nuclear weapons you
know no war and for that he went to jail
he went to jail bye-bye-bye United
States of Americans put him tune in jail
and he is also anti God
well anti-christian you know anti
religion he's a you know like today you
have several popular guys who is anti
religion you know they talk on YouTube
you know where our talk atheist you know
for example was a young guy the the
do you guys remember the name that
Harris Harrison the the Atheist who has
a background of new road science what's
his name you know he's one of the most
popular atheist code so-called modern
8/8 atheist you know begin around in
2000's guys type it what's his name help
me out okay we we digressed so much well
anyway Bertrand Russell okay that's
that's my favorite author so he's my
favorite author so I have here are
several of his articles for example this
one knowledge okay not not that one weed
let's talk about the other one which are
talkin yeah richard token is one of them
but he's not the first one but however
if you search okay if you search his
name the other guys will come up
actually I have a link here let me just
show you
so Bertrand Russell wrote in 1927 why I
am NOT a Christian okay and okay so he
gave Minnie and when you read this are
Co not what this other another guy had
hairy skank
ham Harris okay anyway at the bottom of
this article you'll find Sam Harris yeah
that guy young Sam Harris is a one-trick
pony
okay Sam Harris sauce judgment Sam
Harris is a one-trick pony he doesn't
know much Richard Dawkins and
Christopher Hitchens which died a few
years ago
so this free person they they kind of
started the movement modern I think
there's a name New Atheism yeah I think
it's got called New Atheism around you
know beginning in mm
they began and you know and it's you
know it's it's it's it's it's sad to say
that actually part of these atheist
movement became today's social justice
[ __ ] that's what they became half of
them you know so by the way so you know
if you are religious that's great okay I
support Regis people and you don't know
you don't know Sam Harris he talks about
a wide variety of different subjects
with different approaches actually
docking is comparatively more of an OTP
than Sam Harris OTP stand for what
one-trick pony
okay and they are they are oh maybe I
don't know what's Richard token I
Richard Dawkins is a biologist I think
but anyway I've watched Sam Harris
I've watched he talk and he's debate and
he's personality agua I watched quite a
few of his videos like like ten over the
over the past say five years he he's
well he well he's you know he's academic
very you know knowledgeable you know
probably better than me and well at
least he's got more reputation than me
you know he's got certificate to prove
we have that he knows things unlike me I
don't have a certificate and I don't
have money to prove it
so that's that's a sad thing so anyway
but I watched him I don't think he well
he's suddenly intelligent and you know
but but I don't you know I don't find
him that much interesting for me okay
but how for example as an example Jordan
Pederson I respect that
Gai far more than sam harris sam harris
tone oh [ __ ] it's one-trick pony and
also sam harris has this personality sam
harris is has this personality he is
very competitive he is highly
competitive like me okay I mean I'm
talking about a personality trait like
if you say something immediately he's
gonna try I mean like he's gonna just
he's gonna just trying to counter it
like by reflexively you know try to
counter it any any way he's you know
he's it's kind of it's a it's kind of a
personality flaw I would say he's highly
competitive you know always always in
you know in a argumentative you know way
no I disagree look look look but you
have to you know it's not like each
person's opinion well anyway what I'm
gonna say well so about that well you
can't be too sure
anyway that's just my opinion about Sam
Harris
okay so anyway Bertrand Russell wrote
this Holika why I'm not a Christian okay
so you can read it and then he also
wrote this Arco has religion made useful
contributions to civilization so for
example one thing religious people say
is that okay maybe God doesn't exist or
we can approve it but this religion is
good in that they they created a
morality that helps us helped society to
to be to phosphor you know the actually
that's I think is kind of true but
however Bertrand Russell here says
he just heat up oh he just heat up his
region hee-hee do not believe there's
any good in religion okay now I can tell
you what I think okay in regards to
religion let's say ten years ago I would
believe exactly the same as Bertrand
Russell would believe that it really has
no value in modern society historically
yeah sure because you know we don't have
science yet but in modern society you
know I believed that it's possible that
religion doesn't really have any
significance like that like I would
imagine that we could leave a society
without religion at all and be be
prosperous okay that this is ten years
ago but today I don't think that's the
case I don't think that's necessarily
the case maybe maybe in the future okay
again before anything else let me say
you know these kind of questions nobody
knows the answer
you know Bertrand Russell yeah he knows
a lot but he doesn't know I mean he
doesn't know the answer to the universe
no does anyone else know does Jordan
Peterson know the Sam Harris no nobody
okay doesn't matter how how big they are
how how what a scholar how many awards
they they they they want it's all
[ __ ] okay nobody know the answer
about these kind of questions about for
example about whether religion whether
had you know whether religion will have
important or will religion be helpful in
modern society going on words you know
questions like that nobody really knows
the answer
so I'm but I'm telling you my opinion so
I was saying back then ten years ago I
would say you know I don't think
religion needs to be around but now I'm
more of a pinion that
I'm more of a opinion that we don't know
actually I would follow another great
person I admire I idolize is Camille
Paglia okay now I also have several
articles about Camille Paglia
pakiya okay watch this one
wait hold on a second I need to open the
link in a new tab okay there we go
and another article another article
another article and another 2min
yakisoba is just show 5 sorry
on Camille Paglia Camille Paglia is one
of the person in english-speaking word I
greatly admire so I would say so far it
would be she is one of them still alive
she's you can watch lots of her videos
on YouTube and and Bertrand Russell and
I would I think I would also put Jordan
Pederson in my beast as my top top
persons in Western society that I admire
okay now these are none I mean I'm not
we are not talking about computer
science science-u no we are not talking
about scientists then it's a different
thing like mathematicians then then this
it's different so we are talking about
general scholars you know general
scholars or people you admire you know
not including mathematicians because he
met I have a lot others so Camille
Paglia she is well she call herself a
feminist but she's a feminist of the
1980s era something like that okay she's
the second wave first wave okay so she
she she's great okay she and she's also
anti today's social justice [ __ ] and
today's feminism [ __ ] okay those are
[ __ ] those are anyone who believed them
yeah there are either scumbags or they
are ignorant young people okay you can
try to teach them you could try that's
what you need to do what you should
to try okay not not not just beat em up
that's not the way to go you can try to
you know young people teach them so
Camille Paglia I admire very much
and so I have quite a few articles about
him some of them are funny come you of
Hagley Elena don't now I have JavaScript
awful let's turn on JavaScript so the
video shows or at least you can see the
screenshot
okay that's Camille Paglia
Lena Dunham Lena Dunham is a social
justice scumbag whatever they did they
don't have a brain they they don't have
a brain and they are sinister and they
are me the meaning of the word me that's
what some of these social justice
activists are me that that they would
they are the type of a person who would
beat you up who would kill you just just
for their you know just for they again
so they get you know they get more
famous or more money that's these social
justice can people are and the things
they talk about that the things they
talk about that's their means you know
to to to get themselves ahead so here is
Camille Paglia and there is more Camille
Paglia on gender pronounce gender
pronouns I am a dragon king from now on
you should call me Your Dragon King okay
I'm a dragon king you know what I mean
what King means you know a question what
does the universe have so few comments
children here have you watched
Peterson's debate with zizek no you can
you can say you don't agree with sam
harris but you can say he's one trick
pony that's plain wrong you know yeah
but you have to I think
it's not feign wrong okay you might say
you know you might say you might
reconsider you see first first of all
you are younger than me you are trying
to years younger than me right so I read
stuff 20 years more than you so how
could you say that's plain wrong oh you
are just plain wrong is that's like us
like oh I don't know nothing you know
you have you know you could say at least
you know I think I disagree and I think
from you know like say something like
say something about your experience like
oh I watched this video that so I don't
think he's a one-trick pony and also
also you know one trick pony's kind of
you know I'm just making fun of him
right yeah I mean of course he know
other things of course he he has a
degree he is a PhD in neuroscience right
but this is a talk show I gotta do some
show so anyway so what questions does
the universe have so what meerkat good
morning meerkat allow me to reboot the
better to draw you with because
livestream doesn't walk in to install
Jen - you need to be food and recompile
Gentoo Linux that's a story of Lena's
good morning Kathy oh I'm keen on
getting back to project geometry oh my
god I've been I mean digressing so much
okay let's get back to that I forgot
where what is the point I started to
digress - Oh Bertrand Russell because
there's a question so anyways here's
some videos and Camille Paglia okay let
me let me put it into my today's talk
show page then let's get on to
projective geometry actually I'm not but
okay so um I am going to talk something
about projective geometry but it would
not be
technical because that's you know that's
a heavy topic that's what you go to
university you you go to university to
math professors then they teach you
projective geometry but as usual I can
talk about it like I tell you what it is
about and things like that interesting
things you know in the talk show ok and
here is another article so we talked
about Bertrand Russell right so let me
show you so we talked about Bertrand
Russell curse sad face it here why I am
a Christian why I am NOT a Christian and
has religion made useful contributions
to civilization
and ok here's another article math
prizes and Noble ignore bility Nobel
Prize is a [ __ ] Western brainwashing
scheme ok Nobel especially the nobel
peace peace peace price okay why I'm now
going to talk about it in detail but
let's just read you can go to week you
can go to read Wikipedia okay there is
one article that discuss how the
controversies in Nobel Nobel Prizes
become hell this has become I don't know
maybe it's not so be it become a weapon
for we can rightly you know we can
rightfully say it's a weapon for western
white people for white people it's a
propaganda weapon of white people they
for in particular the Nobel Peace Prize
they give that to whoever wants you know
whoever benefit benefits the Western
society Polly political it's via P it
became a political thing
but where there is a philosopher who
created the existential ISM his name is
his name is Paul something or something
I I have quoted here I didn't quote it
here it must be another article I forgot
but anyway it's it's you can read about
it
we can talk about it on another day okay
here's another article from Bertrand
Russell what what desires are
politically important by Bertrand
Russell now this article is not about
religion and it's very interesting and
it's what I tried to follow as well oh
you could say he well he wrote it before
I you know is it's about when you study
things you have to study the motives not
just statistics statistics doesn't tell
you much but rather you want to look
into the mode motives of why people what
what they do for example you can say
Harry Henry Clinton or Trump or you know
whoever politicians you study you look
at their history and why they do things
you know you study you look at their
nature okay as as as the serial serial
killer Hannibal Lecter would say you
look at people's nature okay that's this
article is about what desires are
politically important and this this
article is actually Bertrand Russell's
Nobel lecture you know he won't a Nobel
Prize not for peace but for literature
this is kind of strange okay the proper
award to Bertrand Russell would be
should be peace because he is one of the
prominent peace activists however he
also has done great things in philosophy
in in mathematics okay but Nobel Prize
does not have a math category that's a
way unknown thing you know people say
because the guy Alfred Nobel I think
because a guy one time a mathematician
cheated his wife so he hate he hates
math you know that's a that's a that's a
law you know we don't know if it's true
or not it's it's it's probably false
okay there's a weekly PD article about
talking about it why Nobel Prize to not
have a math category so anyway so Nobel
Prize there's no math category so anyway
Bertrand Russell if he should want any
Nobel Prize it should be peace but
however he got a literature Nobel Prize
so when you get a Nobel Prize you have 1
million dollars and you also give a
speech like you have acceptance speech
and this is he's I think I think this is
the one so he's talked about this what
desires are politically important ok so
that's about that so close that ok this
arco is one of my network word
anthropology which we talked about for
19 minutes yesterday so it's about
trolls you know online trolls or online
etiquette of behaviors or Amanda
programmer hacker culture you know so
many people call me a troll there's a
exile trope Chris Isidro is a you know
this they kill me for 10 years and but
so here is article where I judge what
does it mean so you know like if you see
my especially my old articles I out you
hear me say [ __ ] units [ __ ] UNIX people
you know fact Linux [ __ ]
[ __ ] Richard Stallman you know you you
see me [ __ ] [ __ ] Larry Ward the creator
of ok you see me say that often and and
too many people in particular
white people [ __ ] the white people this
especially today social justice
type of people so to them you know they
see me swearing and AD people they see
oh my god this this guy is just askin
you know he's they think I'm just askin
you know [ __ ] yourself you are a Western
you know you have your Western you you
have your kind of in a Bubo opinion okay
that's that's your view of the world
okay that's that's not for example
that's not the whole entire Asian people
asean people have more people in the
world and then you then you white people
okay but the white people well because
I'm American I live in America so and so
the people what I see every day is white
Americans people so they they are
opinion and also because USA is the most
powerful country in a world for the past
50 years for what does I mean for
example USA United States of America we
okay I'm a member of it we have the most
nuclear power than anyone else on earth
then all of you combined I have where I
have more nuclear weapons than you
nuclear bombs okay all of the of the all
the world combined I have more chemical
weapons than all of you I have more
biological weapons than all of you
combined okay so shut you better shut
the [ __ ] up
I you USA we so these white people you
know so their opinion we are our
opinions the white you know American
American leaded you know and European
that especially in particular the United
Kingdom we are presence you know we are
the same seed we are the same you know
they are literally we are literally the
same because USA came from Britain
because USA our traitor a Britain but
when traitors become big we have our own
country you know we disagree with you
anymore but originally you know these
the same people you know most most
reason and more more you know you know
more less so
so white people so that's why
white people he's actually very
applicable there ton the term invented
you know popularized by social justice
can but also the white people the the
you know it's racial you know the the
white people's idea that the the the
Western ideas you know I used to love
the Western ideas because I hate the
eastern fuzzy Taoism know that Buddhism
philosophy you know it's all fuzzy it's
like it doesn't mean anything you can me
you can you can you read you know the
Buddhism or Taoist you know mantra or
whatever they say you have 1 million
interpretations you each wasn't see
different thing to say yeah so I don't I
don't like I'm a rebel okay I'm a rebel
kind of a guy so I don't like well since
I was a teen I don't like the eastern I
follow the Western logic the Greek
philosophy but anyway today I see the
Western says that you know the Western
thoughts philosophies kind of have lots
of problems so today I'm kind of more
I'm kind of I don't you know I value
it's not it's it's it's more like this
it's not like Western is better than
Eastern or otherwise you know this is
you want you want diversity of thought
okay diversity of thought not diversity
of the social justice can [ __ ] heads
skin skin color and colorful hats
different colors of hats
so so yeah that's about the philosophy
you know Eastern philosophy Western
philosophy so anyway back to we know
they call me a troll so how do I judge
people I judge by the score I give to
people is by it can be summarized by
this formula love first knowledge
divided by this rip respectfulness okay
so you if you have great knowledge and
if you have great love love he's here
means generic love means you know you
are a good human animal
so if you have that then you are great
divided by this red disrespectfulness
that means like how much [ __ ] you say
how much despite you have against other
people like how much [ __ ] are you so
if you are big giant [ __ ] doesn't you
know if you have great knowledge and if
you are a good person but however your
[ __ ]
this is is greater it's like a dinosaur
then then your total score in my eyes
would be still low you know you see you
see how this formula works out so that
that is how I judge people so because
and by the way so this philosophy love
and knowledge is from I borrowed I read
it from I first read it from I learned
from Bertrand Russell Bertrand Russell
said somewhere here somewhere I forgot
where okay here the last part let me
recite it so he says the good life is
one inspired by love and guided by
knowledge knowledge and love are both
indefinitely extensible therefore
however good a life may be a better life
can be imagined neither love with our
knowledge no knowledge with our love can
produce a good life omit in the Middle
Ages when pestilence appeared in our
country holy men advised the population
to assemble in churches and pray for
deliverance the result was that the
infection spread with extraordinary
rapidity rapidity among the crowded
masses of supplicants this was an
example of love without knowledge
because they don't understand virus you
know they don't understand bacteria back
then and he continues the late war
afforded an example of knowledge without
love
which is for example nuclear
proliferation knowledge without love I
just want to bomb you like the social
justice can are doing they want to
eliminate people who they disagree with
so in each case the result was death on
a large scale
indeed note he says the result was death
on a large scale
so either case love without knowledge or
love with our knowledge that is the case
of the social justice can purportedly to
do and knowledge without love that would
be that would be the example of USA
maybe you know USA control the words we
do that knowledge and love okay so
actually so let's go back to back to
back to back to back to Twitter okay we
don't care about Twitter back to
projective geometry okay we don't have a
chance to talk about that today but we
gonna open oh did I just close my weight
who is my
hold on second I had a lot projective
geometry or there okay so projective
geometry projective geometry in the
1980s are considered the the most
general branch of geometry
so during 1980s 1980 nineteen nineteen
fifty let's say projective geometry is
thriving so it is intro to real
projective so it is the you know it was
you know during the 1980s 1800s 1800 he
was the hot topic the popular topic
everyone you know mathematicians study
and so so we learned a lot about it but
today it's kind of fell apart so it was
considered the most generalized geometry
but late later on we developed topology
which kind of took over however the two
subjects are different topology and
projective projective geometry their
nature are entirely different okay so
what what are we going to say about
projective geometry projective geometry
is extremely elegant okay it's very
elegant and is but it's not a popular
topic so but anyway in the 1990s
airplane just flew by very loud in the
1990s I was in armored Yamaha with
projective geometry you know I was
studying math so projective with
geometry was very interesting to me
because it's kind of like it's a pure
geometry it's a pure math okay it's a
branch of pure very pure math and it
it's very extremely elegant so you know
maybe you guys like to studied
study yet but but it's you know it's
it's you you don't you don't learn you
don't learn about it very much for
example if you ask mathematicians today
you ask them first put perspective 'ti
they don't know what the [ __ ] that is
professional mathematicians even so for
examples here are some of the okay let
me show you some I'm not sure what to
talk about actually so maybe it's time
to take a break and have a sip of my
drink and let's see the comments
harmonic conjugacy projective geometry
is great fun okay
it's it's very easy okay you don't need
you don't need any calculus you don't
need sine cosine you don't even need to
understand trigonometry you can start to
learn projective geometry okay
but however on the other hand you could
also say projective geometry is rather
advanced okay so you need a bachelor's
math degree majoring in math to to
actually study projective geometry yeah
that is true so on one hand you can you
can start to study projective geometry
you don't need calculus no algebra No
you know you can just you know you you
are a high school student you can start
to learn projective geometry but however
that's what I did you know that's what I
was doing in the 1990s however there is
a problem you don't really get somewhere
that's important okay like like what I
mean by that you could study it and you
could for example the book I just showed
the book I just showed you can stop you
again you know you can buy it it's
actually expensive I don't recommend it
you know because you know you you buy
this book on Amazon it's like $100 and
that book is written so that you don't
need calculus and in fact that's how you
study projective geometry there are many
approaches again he met there are many
approaches so one approach is is called
synthetic geometry which do not require
any calculus or abstract algebra like
group Theory field rings things like
that so you can study projective
geometry like this guy did you know the
author hsm Cox the coxster
he's very well known you can find his
name on Amazon on Wikipedia ok HSM
coxster he's a well-known geometers he
study pure geometry mostly synthetic
bison effect synthetic geometry
I think synthetic methods meaning you
don't need the whole package of calculus
or modern algebra you don't need you
know the jargons field means groups you
know supreme and you know matrix space
vector space you don't need all that
your anthropology you know topology
topology cause space you don't need that
you don't need say theory ok you don't
need that though all those baggage that
is the modern power of math so you study
you know you go to that's what you do if
you study if you major in math that's
that's a ladder you kind but anyway it's
an HSM coxster he usually does synthetic
geometry so you can learn it without all
that but however you know you can do
this like for over a year and you will
know a lot you will know you know quick
actually quite a lot more than more than
a professional mathematician about this
subject projective geometry but however
it would not be actually useful in
modern society as a mathematician or
anything else even though you know a lot
about this subject but even though you
know if you are a genius you know you
you you even if you invented new theorem
like your name is gonna be part of
history like there's a theorem
you know let's say male cats theorem in
projective geometry so you study like
two years you know
without calculus or that you you could
piece so so depth in depth that you have
a theorem in history books you know
named after you but however however if
you do not follow you know the modern
math like abstract algebra calculus you
have to know that topology if you do not
know any of that you're you are kind of
going nowhere because that's how things
are because anyway I'm not sure I'm
making sense and so anyway it's very
interesting projective geometry dis
Argos to try and go theorem so I
actually I tried to understand this
proof it's it's fascinating it's
fantastic
this proof this August to triangle
theorem this this this this theorem is
critical okay you can actually so let's
look at Wikipedia
you know this theorem theorem has is
fundamental because it set apart the
Sunburst
theorem okay it let's see okay now like
I said before you see I have I have
shown I have shown several you know
illustrations in projective geometry you
see all you see is like you know a bunch
of lines and triangles so that's what
I'm saying that's that's why I'm saying
you can approach projective geometry
you know without all the trigonometry
calculus you know those things you know
he's just lies he's basically just lines
and figures you know that's that's all
but however however whatever what what
am I trying to say however any anyway I
forgot what's my point
so anyways on Wikipedia you can see you
know they talk about the sagas theorem
you know again you see just lines end
points but however you see if you read
you you if you read Wikipedia you know
you can see you know Wikipedia is
general you know they are not
approaching projective geometry purely
from the synthetic geometry point of
view you see all the things you we see
so far these lines and figures they
those are approaching you know the study
or method of studying projective
geometry from a axiomatic synthetic
geometry point of view so that's why you
see you know just lines and figures in
the plane but however Wikipedia is
general so when they Wikipedia discuss
something like this August theorem they
don't live in they don't limit
themselves in this point of view they
will talk about in the whole context of
math so here you will see the importance
of projective geometry I mean the this
this particular theorem so for example
projective versus affine space itself
duality okay proof proof of this August
theorem you know this Wikipedia Arco is
very small you know that's why you know
I'm telling you that projective geometry
is not a popular topic you know it
should it should be actually issued a
lot it should be a lot more but they
don't talk about much
so three-dimensional proof okay so to it
dimensional truth relations to Pappas
theorem okay they don't talk about much
but okay so yeah they don't they don't
really yea they don't really talk about
their religious relations to other
things but however you can see that if
you click on projective geometry then
it's huge
okay this projective geometry you can
see the magnitude of the weight of
projective geometry in math then you
started to see how they you know they
talk about okay overview oh my god what
is this growth measure and the polar
vortices based on the work of Laurence
Edwards I don't understand what it is in
projective geometry you have this polar
I don't understand okay this is okay I
don't know what that is so history and
history and okay and description and
configuration you know projective
geometry you have this configurations
final plan plane and then you have
duality which is a critical concept then
you have axioms of projective geometry
okay we started to talk about various
action axiomatic approach so these
axioms are all axiomatic approach then
you have they don't they don't well I
was hoping they'd talk about something
more anyway so projective geometry for
example in crypto analysis you know in
number theory crypto analysis in queer
today you have you know cryptocurrency
Bitcoin they are based on crypto
analysis and I know that I've heard I
don't I don't know how it works but
projective geometry is used in those
theorems to create things anyway so I
don't know too much about it so let's
stop on that so kathyface
says interesting I thought projective
geometry is heavily related to topology
and linear algebra yeah no I don't think
it's related to not much to topology at
all yeah I am pretty sure that is true
and linear algebra yeah I can't you know
I can say much about I don't know this
subject to well to say to say I need to
study
oh my god so ok so that's about that
let's let me read the comments then
that's I think perhaps that is it and
today how long I have have I been
talking one hour and 10 minutes and
today but ask me the question to address
which I did not address but we can
address it another day and that is you
know that's a common topic we're gonna
talk about often so what we saw what the
question is what is my idea of new Linux
what is my ideal distro ok first of all
well maybe this is not answering your
question but first of all I don't want
to know I don't want Linux okay I don't
want kunu I don't want Linux and I know
and I don't like I don't want the named
gnu/linux okay just Linux [ __ ] no goo no
Emacs yeah Emacs good no Emacs minutes
the proper the you know what so what I
mean by that
so Richard Stallman in his opinion he
says we should call Linux by calling it
new Linux because important part of it
is new you know his projects such as
the shell the bash shell the compiler
CCCP you know see new GC no compiler
connection GCC you know i son you know
many to us in linux is from new project
so in his opinion we should correct new
linux because linux is truly really
technically should be just the kernel
that's his opinion in my point of view
that is incorrect
I mean it's correct technically okay but
all things considered how we use
language human how human use languages
if you studied instinct with sticks you
study you know you study all things
philosophy linguistics literature you
study all things you study the naming of
things you study the science of jargons
you study the committee the the you know
iso standards they have actually they
have actually standards for naming of
things also you know you have sent us
standards for classification of math
categories you know do you have made
name is the important thing
you know so you study you know you
import what point of view then Richard
Stallman's opinion about Coney Linux
Linux is incorrect I don't think that's
valid you should the part you should
just call it Linux ok yes it's true we
should give credit to no but however it
just should be just called Linux when
should you call it lacunae Linux when
you want to when you when marketing is
involved and when you are you know a
member of the free software foundation
and you know you want to do marketing
then you call it good new Linux ok you
should just be called Linux so first of
all I don't want to know I don't want
Linux
I don't want the name to be goon or
Linux either so what I want was my idea
what
according to my dreams that that you
would actually use rather than Mac OS
okay so so I don't have you know well
ideally I want the system that's you
know that's for people and it's good you
know it it can it can be proprietary but
but we can trust it good people you know
no lying no devious tactics no beating
other people no you know no underhand
tactics no things like that you if you
have a group of people that's hard to
come back that's so that will almost
never happen things like that so but in
practice and I mean if we can see the
reality then what is my preferred ideal
OS suppose I can you know put in some
idealization into it like you know Linux
like what distro would it be what is
just so what is your dream
no Linux what is your dream Linux distro
okay so that I haven't explored Linux
distro so basically the only one I have
real experience for four years is Ubuntu
okay we went to his based Debian Linux
okay and but the other one I installed
like in 1998 is MK Linux which is my
first Linux I installed it I used it for
a few days that's it so anyway so what
what is my idea so basically I will say
the Linux people you want to first of
all so we so which what so which this
tree distribution I want I don't know
okay because I don't really have
experience maybe our our clinics would
be great because I wanted to be clean
and kind of minimal no no baggage no no
pile of [ __ ] okay just one thing and do
it well okay
there's a ng n IX Oh Nix was it called
Nix or something n IX okay
Knicks Linux I think I heard good things
about it
Nix OS okay so it's based on pretty much
functional programming ideas about
managing packages so I heard good things
for my friends and if I have time I
would try this
okay Nix Nix and I like the our clinics
our clinics oh you know our clinics they
have a website and that's the best Linux
documentation because when I was using
Linux about five years ago for four
years I you know about three years ago
so I was using you know I you know I was
looking to all kind of problems and ugly
notes they always have the best
explanation if they truly the best about
everything in Linux okay they tell you
the actual technical details I mean feet
clearly unlike unlike for example Stack
Overflow which they call it you know
open to one or something or other faces
you know typically when you search Linux
problems you find you know 20 articles
night 80% of them are ten years old or
five years old and you have to dig after
you read for ten minutes
oh this one is ten years old god you
know [ __ ] Linux so anyway I don't know
much about Linux distro so I think I
heard that Nix Linux is great and all
but and also I can say that our clinics
has the best Linux information so that's
about that and the other thing about
Linux I want to say is that I want the
Linux people ok Linux you guys minutes
phonetics get rid of the fanatism
ok get rid of
any open-source ideology you know [ __ ]
open-source [ __ ] open-source [ __ ] free
free software foundation do that first
of all do that ok then you will be
better so so if you [ __ ] you open-source
what then what do you do so watch what
you do you follow what what what kind of
you should follow you know just follow
follow good things study for example if
you are creating or Linux software study
languages study you know technology
study then the kernel your Linux kernel
or something you know know your stuff
you know you study okay a lot Linux
people already do that great also yeah
okay so here's the important thing study
things outside of programming okay
that's so important because vast
majority or the programmers at Google
and all the basically all the Linux
phonetics [ __ ] they don't know
nothing about about literature history
philosophy you know linguistics or other
things you that's that's the thing
because when you lack knowledge about
you know go go read literature and and
don't read [ __ ] science fiction I
know because all the programmers they
yeah they read they read a lot I read
science fiction that's basically the
only thing they read science fiction
okay so I'm saying what I'm saying is
that you want to study all the other
things okay literature because that that
truly enriches you your your thinking
that truly enrich your thinking okay
then then when you actually called Linux
when you write a program software GUI
when it comes to decisions decisions or
what license should you choose you
actually make better decisions okay as
opposed to the vast majority of
programmers the tech heads the you know
the the UNIX philosophy [ __ ] heads and
the Linux phonetics [ __ ] heads open
source [ __ ] they don't have this
they are just tech heads you know and
and they have of course they have 1
million
some politics on what license should be
an open source how great attract them
they don't have no nothing that's that
is why when they code they are to I this
sucks in every way they don't know how
to do things and they fight you know
they fight each with each other Linux
you this it's fractured then you're
10,000 district history and everyone is
different everyone is like have their
own like a philosophy or opinions or
[ __ ] eco goin nowhere wait there is one
place Linux is going go into Google and
Facebook empires evil empires that's
what you [ __ ] doing Linux and open
source phonetics okay but but so that is
my opinion about my dream OS okay I
think I should stop every video should
have ten minutes rent so I actually so
there is another question I think that
why don't you
we don't okay so well German book you
read a German book huh which one it's
one of the absolute highest German book
published in Germany ah
which one I forgot this is your cam
output bags okay it's Bella okay I
forgot which one is that
Oh cat so meow cat okay that's the point
of Jen - okay male cat I know you are a
fan of Jen - are you
are you still on Jen - and are you still
Jen - fan everyone have their own
disease saw everyone live stream cuz
free software foundation for one hour
youngji Quran Zika hands
what is so wrong with councils in this
okay I did a video on that so yeah I did
too video and video on that you know
check it out you know just go to my
channel search for lease you'll find
several so we can talk about so me or
Cass says I'm not a gentle fan but I
still use it no you are a gentle fan
teach you how to chain to phonetic as
far as I know what do you mean you are
the gentle chin to fat like gentoos I
saw I don't know anything about it but I
learned from you you told me that gentle
is the one that wear it you know the the
the the fame of Gentoo is that you
compiled in the you know in the
beginning you choose what package to
compile something like that okay you
don't care about them okay yeah milk
assays unbend milk assays actually I'm
banned from gin to IRC for over 10 years
ahead
no you are penny multiple places like me
okay so that's it for today so what is a
cuz I like you're open to looks I like
your Ubuntu looks what Fame is that what
which what I'm a Mac OS my friend Robert
Robert Robert E Robert Lee Sora's among
Mac OS ok thank you guys for coming
ok so I think there's no more questions
then then that is it for today and I'm
gonna shut down in one minute
Thomas Thomas
Curtis says what do you think about qub
s qu BES I don't know what is that la
casa Thank You a casa good have a good
day guys Kathy let's look what is
q.u.b.e s cubies cubies OS Oh another OS
a reasonable a reasonably secure
operating system they have a Wikipedia
let's go there
OpenBSD is greater than Linux my open
PSD you know the BSD is kind of dead you
know Linux just took over cubes OS is a
secure security focused desktop
operating system that aims to provide
security through isolation okay yeah I
don't know operating system technology
much in fact you know I will be
hard-pressed I don't know much about it
at all so I don't know the operating
system technology you know I don't know
how it works so when they when people
talk about for example when people are
talking about you know open you know BSD
versus Linux to me it's just the same
it's the same thing it's a it's just you
next every unix is the same so solaris
you know so I've used you know I see Sam
in Solaris for four years 1998 to 2002
you know so I've used hp-ux you know
that's that's UNIX from HP I have used
IREX which is from Silicon Graphics UNIX
I have used there is also a IX from from
IBM I've never used there's also a /ux
that's Apple's UNIX real you know not
many people know it I've never you
it apples 8ux okay
a /ux that's a proper way morphology
apples so irx a iooks you know you know
so yeah anyway I'm shutting down so
sorry
ax HP u ux i Rex you know I love these
names you know I used to lots of
articles my articles contains them it's
such and see what we find
AIX vs. Solaris vs. HP us UX versus I
Rex how old is this article what age is
this article this must be
mm early 2000s Ars Technica ah that's
just that's a forum discussion I thought
it had co because nobody nobody even
know what those are anymore the UNIX
pestilence okay so that's it for today
thank you guys for coming
if you like my stuff go to it goes hooks
you know my website and go through my
homepage and you'll find my patreon in
PayPal so support me thank you guys
okay bye guys