welcome to another episode of s talk
show start wolam
language Advent of code day two the
shortest Solution on
Earth let's
begin let's start wolfan
language and magnify the window let's
say
three shift enter to run it shift enter
three that's good
now Advent of code day two so here is
the shortest Solution on
Earth paste it that's a code run
it uh
what what
oh you forgot to add the
input so start again select all so here
is the
input it's let magnify the lines okay
and uh shift
enter the answer is eight fantastic
shortest Solution on earth now V of two
problem day two problem two
copy paste okay so here's the input and
here's a solution run
it
2286 86 fantastic the shortest Solution
on Earth in wolam language hello welcome
to another day ofar talk show how are
you guys
so today's job is to explain these
shortest Solutions of Advent of code day
two uh then we are going to I'm going to
work on day three live I haven't coded
yet I read I read the question but I
haven't coded yet okay so let's go over
day two on day two last week I started
to do it live and screwed up you know
end up one hour didn't do nothing but
then I uh finished so in the Advent of
code everyday solution I'm going to code
in wolam language is going to be the
short shortest possible okay uh let's
magnify the uh font can we magnify the
font let's just do it this way okay
so so Advent of code so what is the
problem Advent of code day
two the first problem is that you got a
bunch of lines like these uh can you you
see uh okay so let me let me do
something here here here can you see oh
yeah so you need
to yeah okay
so so what is the problem day two day
two problem one so you got a bunch of
lines like that let's go here okay so
you got a text input a bunch of lines
and some are blue some are red you know
for each line you have a game number
then three blue four red and so on so
each line describe a game and each
semicolon field shows a draw of colored
balls okay so like that and given info
that there are a total of 12 red balls
13 green and 14 blue in other words we
have some kind of hash table like that
so 12 red 13 green 14 blue and for each
game so for each line if any of the
number is greater than the possible Max
cross that cross out that
line for the reen re for the remaining
games sum up the game number so the
input is a bunch of lines each line has
a bunch of blue red number you know one
red two green six blue two green and uh
if any of these colored number BS is
greater than the given
number for red green blue you cross that
line out then for the rest of lines you
add their game number okay that is the
solution so the solution for Advent of
code day two part one is this okay so
let's copy it and let me show you how
that
works okay so where do we do it okay so
let's do it here uh hello and say hi uh
good night all uh hello I managed to get
solution that day uh modify your initial
code fantastic yeah I'm so late I'm I'm
kind of anyway let's continue the
explanation of day two's code okay uh so
what is this S Talk Show so um then
after
today after I explain the solution for
day two I'm going to start day three and
uh I should you know it's day three it's
it's going to be one single line two
within let's say 200 characters one
single line of no more than 200
characters in fact like like I said
everyday's Advent of code in W language
is one single line I would say no more
than 300 characters okay so anyway so
here is the uh day two problem one so
you got a bunch of lines and the Run
this code so let me explain this code
okay so for example I can run it now uh
run
it eight right you see the problem
solution is eight now if I run with my
own input now you see this read string
and this file path now if we open that
file path you can
see uh there are a total of 100 number
lines red green blue and so we are going
to do the input my personal input and
it so the solution is
2512 so I I you know obviously I passed
so that is the day two part one so now
let's explain how this single line of
code works okay now how many characters
are
there the region has one line one
sentence sentence 25 words and 170
characters fantastic okay now let me
let's explain how this code works okay
now uh let me just do something so that
it's more
readable uh string cases okay
so uh
okay so let me just
uh reformat the code and and do
something so it's in the most readable
form okay uh so let's put that uh
so
uh okay so let's
do x max let's x max so let's move this
out so this defines this defines a
dictionary Okay so so green 12 uh green
13 red 12 blue 14 this is a dictionary
so here Max we move
it uh you know we just embedded that
constant into our code that's uh so that
shortens you know the shortens that
shortens the variable name and that okay
so let me let me finish uh I'm going to
explain the code how it
works so I need to add some spaces so
that um
um yeah so that it all makes better
sense now okay so put it
here
uh okay
so so the algorithm is this so for each
line you have this green red Blue paired
with a number so you want to pass it so
that you if if any one of these pair
number green number Red a number and a
color is more than this given Red Green
table then you remove that line or re
you know ignore that line so so what you
have so what you do is you first of all
you do string cases okay string cases
return uh for example string
cases yeah you don't even uh wait you
have to split yeah so first of all you
split the string into a list right so
then
you pass
each list item each list item is one of
these line okay
then then for each line you use a string
pattern to
check the pattern the pattern is to find
the number number and pair so one green
is a pattern three red is a pattern so
you want to capture those patterns okay
so the way you do that
is you you use string cases okay so oh
God when you start to explain it it's
going to take half an hour string cases
okay so string cases is take a string
okay obviously first of all Tes a string
let's say
uh AB B CD EFG and uh takes a pattern
let's say a okay so takes a pattern a so
that will return all occurrences of this
pattern so in this case it's just one
one thing uh in fact we don't need uh we
don't need
this this list okay so let's do again so
it's one thing a right so if you say now
if if you say regular expression let's
see oh my God if I'm going to explain
this is actually going to take half hour
so regular expression DOT stand for any
character right so if you do that you
got all this bunch of characters you got
a is a is a is a match B is a match and
the space empty space is a match C is a
match so let's try another example okay
so let's say B something d
uh D 88 e 99 okay some number now we
want to regular expression we want to
find all cases string cases all cases
that start with a letter Then followed
by a sequence of numbers okay so in that
case so start with the letter so that
would be uh square bracket A to Z okay
or back slash back
slash uh W I think yeah we can do that
anyway so A to Z Then followed by uh 0
to9 or back slash back SL D okay so and
one or more so plus means one or more so
if you run that you see you got the all
the cases occurrences b 2 A3 so string
cases you know that extract substrings
by a pattern okay now in wam language
you have uh it to specify a string
pattern there are two ways one is the
normal regular expression everyone is
familiar with every programming language
has it Java python Ruby go Lang PHP
regular expression Asian old okay but in
from language you have
another uh syntax to specify a string
pattern equal power with regular
expression but much more um much more
readable okay that is called string
expression okay so let's do this the
same thing with the string expression
syntax okay so let's do
that string expression okay uh
expr so I'm kind of going um okay so
what do you want to match the first of
all is a
letter uh letter character okay this
symbol you see wam language is a
symbolic language just like this
everything is a symbol in this case this
letter character is a
symbol and it stands for basically A to
Z or capital letter you know depending
on if you ignore case or not but
basically A to Z okay so you want that
begin with that then you want to to
follow by digit okay digit character
um okay another symbol that send for all
digits okay and you want it to occur
more than once okay so uh in that case
the syntax
is is uh is underscore underscore okay
that I think so let's try it okay right
it there it is
wait uh digit character uh wait we got
it wrong this e99 FG am I going am I
doing good am I like can you guys see
it check check my
status okay say hi if you are watching
okay so and ask me questions if if if
it's not clear so we almost got it so
the lat
character um okay some some syntax so
you have to look up basically basically
you have to look up the string
expression syntax here so let's
do okay at this rate I cannot start day
three every time you know it seems so
simple to explain to but once you
actually start to explain it takes half
an hour or even an hour oh good
fantastic okay so we are looking at the
documentation for string expression
which is a alternative to regular
expression okay which is uh in fact
easier to read so now we are you know
doing the same thing with regular
expression and string expression but
except the string expression we got
something wrong that's why we got
different answer so letter character why
does it repeat so let's check the
syntax
uh one or more characters
so and why is this digit character not
uh so hold on a second so let let's
magnify
this so you are looking at the string
expression
syntax digit character 0 to9 and uh
letter character is just a letter
right uh and for this example we
want so there's one single letter
character but why does it return a b 2
A3
uh one single letter character so let's
look
again string any single character
substitute one or more characters in a
subring of one or more okay so pattern
so you you have
to okay so I think what happened is that
this oh yeah I know so this the letter
character is not just one single
character it's actually more than one so
if we do it
again oh now wait now it's one single
character
okay
so oh okay
so so digit character must be one or
more so
[Music]
um ah yeah I got it wrong so it should
be dot dot okay not not underscore
underscore stand for anything so so
digit so letter character is just single
one and digit character we want one or
more so one or more is dot dot okay
let's do it fantastic now the answer is
is exactly the same as our regular
expression okay now let's remove our
eror so there
so great thing okay string expression is
a alternative alternative syntax to
regular expression but kind of more
readable and compatible with the wolf
language because the entire wam language
is a pattern matching system symbolic
pattern matching you hear about patter
matching all the time from hascal from
meta language from okamo you know these
functional languages they pattern
matching is
um structure
structural and uh type system patter
maging you you know hasc for example but
the wolf and pattern magine is symbolic
pattern matching in other words it's
syntactical pattern matching okay so uh
it's different so anyway so string
expression is alternative syntax to
regular expression and the Syntax for
string expression is compatible with
wm's symbolic pattern matching syntax so
anyway so that's about that so now let's
go back so when when we call string
cases now there's more uh Advanced use
for string cas cases what if you have
multiple string okay you can you usually
in other languages you use a map you
create create a Lambda and map map it to
a bunch of strings but in wam language
you can put a string you uh you don't
have to use a map you can just put a
list of strings here so for example I
create a list of string so another item
so let's say
x62 and uh do it you see you got
x62 so let's try another uh TT H 22 you
see so you don't even have to map so
that is why in our solution we call
string cases okay we call string cases
string cases takes two
arguments so here's one argument here's
the second argument two argument the
first argument is the split string of
the entire
input so each each string is a line so
the second part is now the second part
is the heart of the solution the second
part okay now we explain explained so
far here we are using string expression
to extract strings
now you can um you can use you can
actually do replacement so for
example uh for example okay so let me
show
example so whenever uh what happened
undo okay so whenever you see let's say
whenever you see a digit
character okay you want to replace it
by let's say replace it by x capital x
okay so
given given two strings this you know
this one and this one whenever you see a
digit character replaced by capital x
okay do it see
fantastic uh wait why does it replace a
and b uh something is not right
uh let's try it again now let's try a
simpler
let's just say whenever you see T
replaced by capital
x uh okay
so I'm not sure what's going on exactly
actually H what's going
on what's going on with my keyboard
oh
[Music]
okay so whenever you see
T replaced by
x uh and uh this is not what I
expect oh yeah right so it you know
first of all it find the match then
whenever there's a match does that it's
not
a it's not a simple replacement so so
when you do this let's see let's try
again so for example when you do this
um you see when we do this when we do
this one it returns this right now of
this
result then we can say for example let's
copy that okay let's let uh let's remove
it okay so exact the same input now out
of this result you replace it by X for
example so you see you got a two list
the first one is three items the second
one is two items exactly and because you
say whenever you found this pattern you
replace them by X so that's why you get
that now the the more interesting thing
it becomes interesting when you have a
captured pattern so you want to capture
let's
say whenever you see letter and digit
just remove the letter okay so for
example
x62 will become
62 H22 will become just 22 okay so let's
say we want to do that so you give a
name so you give a name to the string
expression so the way you give a name
you can say x uh you can say x colon
okay so now this x is a name for
whatever pattern that follows you see so
in regular expression normally you
capture groups and uh they are the name
is numbered so you have the first
capture one two three and so on and you
can also give a name but in wam string
expression syntax it's much simpler you
just start with x colon okay then
whatever pattern
so so in this case uh what we want we uh
actually I haven't done this H to
explain this okay so let me try to do
this then
okay so let's look at the
um yeah okay so I guess you have to do
fix
order uh
okay so fixed
order letter character and digit okay
so we have a pattern named X and uh
the wait uh actually that's not we want
so let's move the letter character
out
so string expression the first pattern
is the first pattern is letter character
okay then followed by a named pattern
and this named pattern is
simply yeah okay so I know what to
do the name pattern is
simply digit character dot dot dot dot
means one or more okay now
now now uh now we are missing a
bracket
uh no
wait yeah we need the
bracket yeah so string
expression start with the letter
character then the second pattern is a
digit character but we give a name X now
we want to replace whenever you found
this pattern string expression you want
to replace it by by by um
X that is the digit character okay so
let's do it run it there it is
fantastic okay so that
explains another feature of the string
cases
function which means once you captured
some group you you can some pattern you
can actually do replacement okay and
this is what we are doing okay so um so
this is
the let me show you this pattern okay so
so let me show
you uh okay okay so this code is very TS
uh so so what what what what we are
trying to capture here is a number
string followed by one of the red green
blue okay so that's what this is so let
me copy
it paste it here you see that's a
pattern but now let's do input form
let's see okay so actually let's
do full
form and that's um let let me just
do control shift
n okay let me do this okay
string
expression okay then D we want to
capture a number
string okay we want the first pattern is
a number string that means
any like 3.5 that's a number
string okay then followed
by Then followed by another capture we
capture it by the name color okay and
this color would be all three parts
either red string or green
string or blue string okay so that is
the
that is the the pattern for
this for
the pairs of numbers I mean a number and
a
color okay and we capture them so the
number will become D the color string
will become
C and uh and what what's with this TAA
thing now those taoda is just the short
short Syntax for the string expression
you know because when you use this form
it's easier kind of easier to read but
it's longer so you have the short syntax
how do I explain the short syntax okay
so let me the short syntax is like
this so string expression you have ABC
you know a b CDE e FG can be many
arguments right now the show Syntax for
that is just a t
b c okay these two are equivalent now
let me show you why it is so let's say
equal parentheses paste true you see so
this is just a short Syntax for the
string expression so I'm using this
one but the full syntax is just
that okay so that's this part that's the
part this that's this this part so we
captured basically the number and color
okay now we use the
replacement feature like we showed
before uh this replacement feature we
replace it by two expression that turns
a number into
a that turns a string into a number so D
you see this D is a
is a number right so we turn that into
an actual number a string to number now
if that number is greater than x max at
C so xmax is here so so what is c c is
one of these color string so when you
when you say okay so let me do it here
so when you say x
Max uh so let me show you what that is
okay so in wam language another shortcut
is this when you have F at F bracket X
that can actually be
written as F at X okay that's always
true now the F and the X can be any
arbitary complex expression can be like
1,000 lines of code okay so this is kind
of the syntactical shortcut any of the F
and X can be any you know expression
so what we have here Max at
C so so this x max at C that is actually
just x
max bracket C equivalent okay so but
what is the xmax bracket C that is the
this dictionary so basically and C is a
color right so so basically it gives me
mean if it's green it you know the
result is 13 so what we are having here
is that two expression if this number is
greater
than Max I mean if it's greater than one
of these number is it true or not if it
is true then return true otherwise
return false okay so after this string
cases what we got is uh is a bunch of
true and false let me show you
uh okay so we haven't defined xmax
that's why so copy xmax so let's put
xmax
here okay run it so you see you each
line becomes just true and false true
and false okay now your job is just
merge all this true and false if there's
one of them is true if there's one
single true that means that line
that means that that line contains a
number B that's greater than the given
okay
so so whenever there's a line that
contains true eliminate this line okay
so how do you do that you can just say
all uh so let me go let's do a example
so
[Music]
uh paste Okay so you
know so all so we we can do all
um or okay you use that
because there is no true so that's why
the result is is false now what is that
add add well that add add is apply okay
that's a short Syntax for apply so
another short syntax is whenever you
have F list okay
that can be written
as uh F at at list okay let's replace
list by X you know it's symbolic so it
can be anything okay that's another
short syntax Universal it doesn't matter
in what statement or it you know
Universal okay
so so this so now what you want to do is
you want to apply this
all to each of the list of
bins okay and you the way you do that is
you can just say all add at
at this is this is getting complex yeah
so let let me just show you okay so you
do that so you got that each one of
these true and false means if any of
these list
contains a true it should return true
okay so the first one is false the
second one is false the third one is
true because this line actually contains
one true okay so that means the game
number three should be removed because
game number three contains one of the
color 20 red that is impossible okay
because they are a maximum of 12
red okay so now you just got so so this
true means re remove that that um that
line so but how do we know which line
that is well this is index number three
so this is first item second item third
item so we want to map a function to
this index but we also get the index
okay so let me show you how to do that
uh map index let me just show you a
example okay so let's say uh AB
C okay so basically it applies F to a
list but it gives a function two
arguments the first argument is is what
whatever in the list the second argument
is the
index of that list okay so map index is
one of the map
function that can map but also give you
the index information
right uh so that is that so so that is
why you see this map index and uh what
is this function if Okay so this
function this function just means now
this fun this this line is a shortcut
for let me write the full form of this
this uh the the the easier to understand
way of what what this is okay so the
easier way to write this I mean the
intuitive way to write this is this way
if x then zero otherwise y okay that's a
function this function takes two things
X and Y now so given so you know so if x
is
true return zero if x is false return y
so we apply map index to the to the list
and use this function so this
function is our function here so you see
this function so that means we apply to
this
list when it
is
true for example this line game three
this is true and just return zero okay
so this this element becomes
zero
otherwise give it the the second element
the second so the the index of this
array so what you get is so for example
let's run
it with this
input
uh okay yeah you need to map okay so
okay so okay so you need to map okay so
let's write it map okay map takes two
arguments the first one is a function
the second one is a
list
okay uh oh
well oh wait wait not map map
indexed right yeah so let's try so there
it is so you see then you sumon them
up um that then then that you sumon them
up because this one means game one this
two means game two uh and game three G
four is zero g five is five so you add
them together is eight
the toy input for day two part one
solution is eight I believe so we can
check uh God so many whaty am I doing
good am I
like uh so let's see day two day two
problem number one it
says uh
okay problem number one the total input
solution is eight
correct okay so that is how this line is
seem seems so short
um you see this line is equivalent to
this
line okay I hope that I hope I explained
it um you know when I when I when I
thought about doing this live stream to
explain this code I thought oh 10
minutes but how long have I been 43
minutes oh God and then then we need to
expand the code for part two um that
will take 10 or 20 minutes then we don't
have time to do day three so what shall
we do uh continue to explain day two
will start to do day three I think I
should continue to
do explain the day two then then do
another video for day three so that each
video is more focused on a
topic uh that's kind of sad because I'm
itchy to
demonstrate the wolf and Power on the
day three the day three is a bit more
comple complicated because it in I don't
know if you guys have read it you know
it involves
checking adjacent lines um but day three
can be solved in one single line just
like this nor more than this number of
characters okay day three part one okay
let's see what you guys are
saying if you are watching say something
okay Valley hello Valley hello lunita zi
very interesting I never had to work
with regular expression in academics so
this is useful knowledge okay uh regular
expression is vastly useful you know if
you are in if you work in a job in you
you almost have to use it every day
especially if you unless unless your job
is very specialized you know maybe do
doing computer uh GPU or computer
Graphics but in general if you do web
especially web programming web dev you
you have to use regular expression every
day okay so it's uh great to master so w
so let's see let's read the next
uh wam solution are very different from
other languages where almost everything
are for Loops inside four Loops yes
exactly explanations in Notebook
interface much Clear fantastic something
fantastic guys okay let's let's go on
explain the
um day
two uh day two part two okay the
question the the day two problem two
question okay same input but now for
each line sum the max of sum the max of
each
color then take their product then sum
result for all lines for example this
line three blue four red one red two
green six blue two green okay the max of
each color is six blue four red two
green
okay six blue because there's three blue
and there
is six blue oh wait sum the max of each
color okay so among the draws the max is
you know you you got three blue and six
blue six blue is bigger so you got six
blue then among the red you have four
red and uh one red so the bigger one is
four red check then for the green the
bigger is two green now six BL six BL
four red two green
you time them together so the product is
six 4 * 2 is 8 6 * 8 is
48 okay so for this
line the answer is 48 and uh uh then
then and for each line you have to add
them you add all them of them
together okay so for for the sample
input the product for each lines are 48
12 uh
1560 630 and 36 and their sum is 2286
okay and this is done by this single
line okay so let's let's let's let's
just run it
just
uh okay right eight what oh that's the
wait what oh that's the first that's the
first solution the second solution here
okay paste it right 2286 check now how
does it work it's almost almost the same
okay so we take the string cases just
like before string cases take two
arguments so the first argument we split
the split the string of the input so we
got a list of lines list of strings the
second argument is a the second argument
to the string cases is a
pattern and with the replacement rule
okay so the pattern is the same like
before we grab the pairs of a number and
the color okay and we name them d and c
d is a number c is a color okay once we
got this pair this D and C
we replacement rule we change them to C
becomes true expression D so that means
we change them to the expression uh let
me show you what that is okay so that is
just
um H okay so so two expression you know
here is for example let's
say let's say eight okay so
that's this is a rule so we want to
change it to the color
name c is a color name and uh kind of a
rule that means uh change it to
the associated number okay so what you
get is let me show you what you get
okay you get the
list like that okay this is the first
line it's a list so blue is a string
blue becomes three red becomes four so
basically it just transform
this you know it just transform this
text into this structured syntax you see
blue three check for red check red one
check two green check you see okay so
once you have this structured pattern
then what you do is okay so then you
just then you just sort them okay let me
show you okay let me let's sort sort the
result
okay you see before we had blue blue
three red four red one now we sort it it
it not sort the out Le the the the items
but also sorts the inner items wait did
it
um oh yeah you need to map to so we need
to map too actually we need to map okay
so what does that mean so whenever you
see
F slash add X that
is exactly the same as map FX okay in
wolam language okay symbolic so wolam
language is a lot of the syntactical
transformation okay so instead of
writing this you know cumbersome you
have to type map bracket you know like
list next you just do slash at okay so
we are doing sort slash add that means
map sort to this list okay let's do it
okay now so you see before so so before
it's blue three red four red one green
two now it's blue three blue six you see
because blue got sorted together then
green because B before G then red is
last because R is you know after G right
so now we got them sorted now all we
have to do is to convert each
this each one of these list into a what
python calls a
dictionary you know or or Ruby calls
hash table or Java course
map okay so remember when you have a
hash table the the easiest uh Jon is
dictionary okay when you have a
dictionary the the latter key P
overrides the first so now why do we s
them because when we s them you see it's
you know the bigger number comes after
so if we turn this into a hash
table then you got blue six because blue
three is
overridden uh and green doesn't change
because 2 two and red is got you got red
six red four okay so let's uh
let's copy that let let me show you how
do you turn this thing into a hash table
okay hash
table in wfam language is called
Association okay so given that line you
evaluated it so you got that hash table
okay so each line is now just becomes a
hash table so you know each line becomes
a hash table and then what you do
you see you sort you turn it into hash
table then you just multiply each one of
them together so let me show you
okay uh so for uh so for example we got
yeah so we got
this we got this okay now we turn this
into
Association turn them into a hash
table
map okay fantastic beautiful now
we sum so for each one of these
Association
we we want to ignore the key we just
want to S uh not sum product okay
product the numbers so we can
do
apply
times uh apply times at this input
then we want to apply it at level one I
think let's
see yeah okay let me just show you you
know so you got a product for each
line you know so what does this level
one means
well in short any expression is a tree
so level one
this uh brais one just
means uh apply it to the depth one so in
Unix jargon you know when you Traverse
the directory you have depth depth first
directory sub directory is depth two and
so
on similarly in any nested syntax they
form a tree then you can talk about
depth or level so the word using wam
language is level level one okay so
anyway so that you get just a bunch of
these numbers then once you have that
you just
total okay so the solution for the toi
input is
2286 is that
correct yes it is okay so I hope that
explained uh
it does that make sense you guys how
many people watching
three seven okay nine good not too bad
okay does that make
sense okay now we talked for 56 minutes
shall
we um I think that's
it or I can try to start to do day three
but I don't
think uh I don't think it's good
because I think it's simple but if I
actually do it it's going to then it's
going to be at least 30
minutes if I focus on it but usually I
going to talk about it then it's 40
minutes then it's not
done okay
no okay thank you guys thank you for
watching hope you like it pay me if you
like it okay go to my website s. info
you see my PayPal and
patreon okay last five minutes question
and answers any
questions do you think you are you
impressed by the power of wolam language
okay one single lines of code less than
200 characters okay let's let's let's
let's count the characters let how
many 170 characters okay that's for the
part two wait is this is this
uh where are we so what is this yeah so
this is today's talk show I just demoed
some of the
code but we can go to okay color it so
let's see yeah okay let's let me just
talk random for a while talk random
about things
okay so
we if yeah so we so uh talk random so
let me show you some other neat features
of wolam language okay so let's
see yeah so in the past few days instead
of working on Advent of code I worked a
lot on my wolam Language
tutorial in
particular uh in particular okay hold on
a second let's see I wonder like what
can you see here yeah so I worked a lot
on the wolam language in particular on
the association data structure so if you
just search
forar wam Language tutorial so you know
I have a whole tutorial so there's a
Association data structure section
Association
is python dictionary or hash table okay
and uh tremendous so I worked on it for
a few few days then I worked on regular
expression so because the Advent of code
requires a lot regular regular
expression and what's
fascinating of WFAN Lang language that
stand out is that you know you got this
this string expression which is
alternative pattern string pattern for
analogus to regular expression we you
know we just showed a lot of that power
today
you
see uh so can you actually can you do
this in regular expression yes you can
should we try actually you know so we
can represent this you can see this
string expression syntax we can
represent that in regular expression
which which is not uh hard at all so in
fact for example this line in regular
expression would
be uh r e i e g
e
regular expression okay so in regular
expression first of all you want the
number
string so a number string is Dash uh uh
back slash back slash D that stand for
digit one or
more now in wam language you need to
back slash just like lisp because in wam
language the string pattern for regular
expression is not special string there's
no special regular expression string you
just have one single string data type
and in string data type the back slash
is escape so when you want to when you
want to have back slash D which stand
for
digits you need back SLB SL D okay so
anyway so so now we have a a digit
followed by space then a color a color
is okay a uh
parenthesis red or green or glue okay
now we need to capture this so in order
to capture we need parent so parent
parent
and actually that will work but now so
so this this line is actually kind
similar to that okay but the issue is is
that now the capture pattern is
represented
by in wolam language dollar sign one
dollar sign two okay that represent this
captured pattern okay that's anyway
that's about regular expression and uh
string expression do you know why so you
you see when doing the the Advent of
code my goal is basically to show off
wolam language right you have a problem
programming problem there's a lot things
you have to think about efficiency of
code readability of code maintenance
maintainability of the code you don't
want cryptic you know you don't want you
know cryptic thing uh unless you are
playing programming golf you know when
you are doing programming competition
program like Pearl golf then the
crypticity is what you need you know
that that's the first price similarly
before Advent of code you see Advent of
code is kind of you know the internet
you know phun programming but there is
no measure of efficiency of your code
there's no measure of your quality of
your gener generality of your code they
don't care you know they all they care
is like show me the
answer right like I talked before about
the vent of code which is I mean that
that's that's the purpose right it
doesn't need need to say how efficient
you know suppose you know suppose this
number of lines is a
billion I'll bet most of this Advent of
code 95% of the Advent of code solution
will break because they can they'll run
for days so you have to care about
efficiency and then you also have to
care you know so anyway when when in
general when you solve a problem there's
a lot concerns but for the vent of codee
uh you know for me I I choose to the you
know the most dramatic solution the
shortest seems to be the best approach
because that's that's what people see
right uh yes wam language can also
understand natural languages but I
haven't um ex like what uh I haven't
really explored that there's a lot AI
building you know machine learning
building like one single line equals to
10,000 lines of python libraries one
single function name you know right I
have to show you another I have to show
that another day uh jman says uh does
that pink window counts the key
strokes uh the pink window uh the pink
window you see here that is all my uh
how do I uh okay so let's try to move
that
here it it counts the you know all my
the every command I do okay for example
I move down I move up or down by
paragraph or I go to the top of the
buffer uh can you see it actually
no okay so
let's okay so if I go to the bottom of
the buffer you can see end of buffer
right now if I go to the top you'll see
beginning of a buffer now if I just
press this key which cause uh which
cause s end of line or block because
that's what the command do either move
to the end of
line for example I do it or if it's
already in the end of line it'll just
move to the next paragraph or block of
code or I can move up so every
keystroke and their corres corresponding
command are logged in emac because
that's how emac Works eemax doesn't you
know in essence the gist of emac is that
O8 chaos is your keystroke because every
keystroke eventually correspond to one
command and that command will do
whatever you know including inserting
characters for example new buffer you
see I call I just called new buffer I
I press U because I'm using softly key
so that means command mod
activate Okay or actually uh that means
you see U Is insert mod activate Okay so
youu then I can type
ABC so you see when you type ABC that
actually calls
insert command insert character okay
it's not shown here you see it's not
shown here
because I filtered it out because
otherwise when you type something then
then this pink window will just insert
insert 10,000 times you know so so
that's why the pink window doesn't show
that but but basically it records all
your
commands uh if you want to see the code
for the pink window that removes you
know fter that I can show you uh not
here okay I can show you let's go to my
init okay Kasa init uh I want to go
[Music]
to uh okay command log mod go to
packages okay so let's adjust the
window uh log and
wait okay it's not here it's in my under
my other here okay there it is command
log mod it's WR by someone else so I
modified a little bit Command Mod Dot
command log
mod. so you can see the filter where is
my uh there it is so you
see command log command exceptions so I
added Mouse track region Mouse set point
because otherwise every time you click
every time you click you'll say click
you know code you know or every time you
you know you know so oh there it is you
see self insert
command so if I common this out then
this part of
code and
now I open a new buffer switch to insert
mod start typing and typing some more
and now you can
see you see this start typing and typing
some more it become when they and they
are actually calling this self insert
command you see 33 times why 33 because
there
are 33
characters you see
okay okay uh that's it yeah I was I
wanted to show you uh one more thing
about wolam language so I been uh it's
fun thing okay so that's
um yeah transliteration you know you can
actually transliterate Chinese
so um close that close that go back toam
language go down paste it so you can see
transliterate these are Chinese
characters and I can type some more
Chinese let's see windows
Chinese input let's
say G
uh Gan means today okay now let's switch
back to us keyboard and enter okay now
remember this last part is pronounced
Jin I just typed okay now shift enter
you
see G you see
it can transliterate
Chinese fantastic and you can type
Japanese you know Japanese too uh and
actually I found out that uh chat gbt
can also do it because I just tried it
here okay that's it uh that's it for
today thank you guys by pay me okay
donate me thank you I reading stepan
Wan's blog he uses a key loger yes
commercial not wolf language to record
keystroke yes he you know he
recorded uh lots of things in one of his
blog about four years ago bye
guys can you try speak with that input
that's very interesting let's try
that
say something English okay let's try try
English first say something
English okay let's let's let me
um adjust the
audio say something
English okay now let's try this
Chinese
no it
doesn't interestes so wait so does it so
let's see let's look up options can you
actually maybe not because then you
require
uh produces sound using your computer's
operating
system uh spoken stram gives text for
speech generated by
speak gives text oh wow oh well that's a
very interesting thing
so so you say spoken
stram so let's see how it transliterate
the
English
it doesn't that's
not but anyway is there option for
Chinese I don't think
so okay bye
guys