good morning everyone
yeah who suffer from the years of
maternity comes a fear therapeutic
session of melodious Nastase commences
on YouTube right now
today's 2019 December 23rd Monday 11
o'clock in the morning San Francisco
time welcome everyone and today we don't
have a topic and the topic is going to
be random okay good morning Justine
Justine scarf I and Matt Matthew change
your name is that is that your real name
or nickname and good morning Freddy mad
Freddy from Germany good Moni magpie
from Nicaragua and Justine scoff I where
you from and Justine scoff I send me a
email interesting email by the way do I
know you do we know each other just in
scarf eye and can I tell people what you
send me because that's an interesting
email with photos good morning Alan
shinza shinta who are the surveys a
woman and jin-sang jin-sang ching chong
ching ching Zhang Jie so today I don't
have a topic and then is going to be
random but I'm thinking the first 20
minutes or so I'm going to talk about
number systems numbers system space five
space 6 base 7 base 1000 ok we're gonna
talk about number systems how that works
that is called positional system Arabic
numerals that's what we use array big
number system Pizitz a in a category of
positional system ok so yes nickname so
so just change
Scarface so you see her there
okay so let's talk about things now
someone bought this keyboard now is that
is this one suitable to your test taste
Allen
so this one is wireless mechanical
keyboard some nameless brand okay will
also fire velocity fire something
something 87 keys
pinky 10 keyless what a idiotic jargon
from the keyboards 10 keyless the proper
name is compact okay compact compact and
with white LED and quiet Brown Cherry MX
switches acquired brown switches nuts
necessarily Cherry MX so this one and if
you like it you can go and buy oh it's
only forty six dollars chief chief guys
cheap so you buy it you go to
Casali keyboard blog okay
sorry keyboards such it and you'll find
my keyboard blog and you buy it right
away so i'm going to paste the link here
and you can find you know my amazon so
so let me pop this window out and we're
gonna talk about sundry topics diversity
very interesting so there it is the
keyboard and okay so and keyboard you
know keyboard once we talk about
keyboards it's gonna be nonstop for 10
hours but let's stop not today maybe not
today because we got so many other
topics okay so that's that is about that
keyboard and someone bought a Korean
vocabulary book okay so those of you who
are learning vocabulary learning a
foreign language the language of the
people you don't know then you learned
you you perhaps this is a good book I
don't know but actually Alan can suggest
us quite a few books on languages
because Alan is a certified
expert in linguistics you know meaning
he's got a degree post graduate degree
at least you know he's the studying
masters or PhD something so Alan so so
this book if you want to buy that book
you go to you go to what the English the
wordiness of English English the
verbosity the you know the the years of
the English okay you go to what English
the lure of vocabulary the depth of
literature the question of style the
logic of linguistics the years of
English and the cue by writing that is
what you should do
that's English you take geek on
languages and linguistics and from the
haughty emotions of lexicon statistic
concerns decipherment of grammar and
idioms linguistic karate literature and
logic allottee that is what this is all
is about and if so if you want to learn
Korean by book no money
no pain no gain okay pay and you get as
suppose through the open source you
never get anything instead you got
Google and Facebook Google main Google
guys Google Linux yeah Linux and all its
fantastic free software foundation and
you got Google and Facebook who watches
your bedroom photos every minute of it
okay so that's that is that that is that
those about those things you buy and
what is the next thing okay so I bought
this yesterday thanks to you guys
donations okay this is a this is you
know hard drive external hard drive to
Tetra by its terabytes two terabytes
okay and it's it's very small it's
smaller than your phone
and actually lighter than your phone
about half half the weight of an iPhone
or something and I protein plug it in
and it works fantastic by the way they
you know on this on this hard drive they
give me a secure code secure code and a
reset code what are those do you guys
know see QR code and reset code okay let
me see if I can show you okay no no no
ii c QR code and reset code what what
what what does does this that mean you
know it's got this secure code and reset
code do you guys know what that means
tell me okay I teach you something you
teach me something quid pro quo
okay that's about that and shall we get
into start to talk about the number
systems so you know once you go to the
were the English blog then you find a
motor tude of interesting things so many
interesting things okay diphthong you
guys know what is a diphthong diphthong
diphthong and noise noise this is the
term of the crash hacker noise
something-something oh that's noise okay
let's see let's see the comments what
you guys are talking about and we have
quite a lot of things to talk about
depending on where we want where we want
to go and this this is you know the USB
cables they are becoming so many
varieties is confusing USB to USB three
mini USB plug mini something female-male
and you know it's it's it's a wonder the
social justice have not replaced the
term for female and male cables yet
you know they are policing the
programming language master/slave you
know that sort of thing and they I don't
think they say push to replace the male
and female cable thing yet
male and female
how fitting okay so let's see the
comments okay so you look like a Cookie
Monster oh do I do I look like a Cookie
Monster Cookie Monster nickname okay
in blue shirt you don't eat cookies very
strange
I met I think ten key is good to have
especially if you do things like blender
yes indeed yeah but if you you know if
you you know so I talked about this
before if you find where is that we open
last closed one key press okay so so so
if you yeah
so the problem to solve with this
compact keyboard is that you you can buy
a programmable keypad and that that's
gonna be fantastic because you can
program your firmware I talked about
this quite a few times in my in my blog
okay he might so for example you go to
my keyboard blog you go to keypads then
you'll find a list of the best
programmable keypads so if you don't
have the ten you know if you don't have
a full-size keyboard then you can just
get one of these and it's programmable
well it's fantastic and some of these
they got displaced on the keys and it
turns out they are not too expensive
like hundred fifty dollars I mean
relatively not too expensive so you you
buy a programmable keypad okay it's a
good companion even even with even with
my Kinesis you see I have a
keep hat in the middle but however this
one is not programmable so I programmed
via the upper knee system so you know I
got 1,000 things to say about keyboard
if that's a topic we want to go to
because then I'm gonna tell you
besides programmable keypads then I'm
going to tell you about what if you are
a cheapo you don't have money to buy a
programmable keypad well in that case
you buy a go to the best numeric keypad
so you get one of these numerical
keypads they are not programmable but
they are much cheaper the programmable
ones are like 50 60 70 dollars okay this
one's 150 or something and this one 70
dollars something this is 70 80 dollars
okay
40 dollars something like that so those
are programmable meaning that you can
program the keys in the firmware so when
you press a key the the keyboard since
the signal directly to the OS so there
you so you know the advantage of that is
that you don't have also the problems
like oh it doesn't work in this app or
the OS 8 8 8 8 your keyboard sync no
because for example on the Mac the Mac
you know people they like to control
things they don't let you to have you
know num lock key for example things
like that so they they rewire in the Mac
OS deep down to change your keys so your
app never see the key you pressed it
becomes something else so it's a problem
so the programmable key ports solves
that problem
because the keyboard sends the signal
whatever you wanted to send directly to
the OS so but if you are a cheapo you
don't yeah oh I don't I'm a student I'm
a post doc I'm a I'm a you know I'm a
student then you buy one of these you
just buy a numeric keypad $20 $10 there
there is there are some even $5 ones so
you buy this then you program
the operating system then I have an
article on that how to program number
keypad as function keys you see so you
can you can do this by operating system
on in Microsoft Word
I mean Microsoft Windows you use
autohotkey on Linux you use a bunch of
things
ok Linux is the most complex in the
universe in its it's not just complex ok
it's it's the the worst you're
gonna with spend hours into it and there
are multiple ways depending on your
distribution even within your
distribution there are multiple ways and
multiple programs you you you you you
you app manager you know you download it
try it doesn't work oh it didn't work
didn't this this this this that this
that then you go to stack overflow and
the messages you see are ten years old
tutorials in answers ten years old but I
have a guide well written on how to do
that
on Linux okay so you can read you know
this is it's it's it's it's an entire
set of articles ten 20 articles how do
you bind keys on Linux so anyway we are
talking about programming the numerical
keypad
we are the tools in operating system so
you have Microsoft solutions you just
use autohotkey okay I know some of you
I've encountered a lot people they all
say oh other hotkey is too much too
bloated they just want something well if
you are into key binding I mean if you
are into efficiency if you're gonna dive
into this just use autohotkey don't use
any other just one single program
autohotkey for Windows okay and that is
what Ripper uses Ripper Ripper in our
group he has written he told me he has
written like a thousand lines or ten
thousand lines of our hotkey that's
something so Microsoft Windows
used auto hockey on and Linux
it's you got bunch of you know torso GUI
and stuff and you and on the Mac it's
the most simple of them all it you know
and I have an article on that but it's
not get into it anyways on the Mac you
just use carabiner okay that's the one
pretty much they are quite a few others
that's very useful and very powerful you
have for example let me show you okay so
first of all you have operating system
basics building by the operating system
that allows you to swap caps lock
control option command keys things like
that single that's if that's what you
want to do if you want to get more
complex like Marcos and stuff then
carabiner okay if you want to okay then
then there's a keyboard shortcut for
launching apps and so on this is
building in Mac but it's got problems
it's not as powerful
it's got credit quite a few problems I'm
not going to go into detail you know of
these things I've been taking on them
for for the past 15 years okay so I know
the stuff okay yeah you can ignore your
own opinions okay yeah I know you have a
pinion you know it take my opinion
supplant it with my opinion so anyway
I'm on programmable key
keyboards yeah so be you know besides
using these solutions the best is just
actually get a programmable keyboard
that is you program the keys in a
firmware not via the operating system
okay then on the Mac you have app
launches and you have several great
tools okay
Hamlet spoon I heard it's very good
Alfred
I heard is very good but I haven't used
them keyboard maestro is classic it's
like 15 15 20 years old but they charge
you they like $30 you know so I you have
and USB overdrive is also very good and
which actually unlike the other the USB
overdrive they they allows you to
intercept the USB signals okay so you
can have used this app it's pretty good
but I don't use it now because I try to
you know these days I try to not use any
of these autohotkey or or or or the
Linux X X Mart map I don't I don't I try
to avoid them at all because okay
there's a lot to go into I can tell you
why in detail that's gonna be another 10
or 20 minutes
but anyway so on the Mac you you have
okay so you have then you have these
keyboard tools Carolina you know it
tells you the event tell you tells you
what key you are pressing now which one
is it let me see okay so carabiner
launch Event Viewer so you're gonna buy
this okay actually so do I have a link
yeah I do but it's yeah I'm gonna get
out of my pen my tablet came with my
tablet here and I haven't I need to read
the comments but I haven't done so yet
so you see my tablet you can see there
it is okay anyway so back to so I was
telling you about how you should get a
programmable keypad and but if you are
if you don't want to spend that much
money you get a numeric keypad and then
you program it by operating system then
I'll show you how to okay all this is in
my it
sorry max having saw
keyboard
Blagh you will find it in this keypad
section okay okay let me read the
comments then let's see where we go and
check we talked for 20 minutes okay he's
a blue switches but not loud and it's
blue switches but not loud okay so
required so I think
Tinky so I have recently got a nice
mechanical keyboard from habit okay yeah
they sent me a keyboard by the way I
kind of reviewed it a month ago habit
check the low profile yes low profile
king thin switches which is right here
okay do I have a photo or I need to take
a personal photo but oh yeah there it is
so it's right there this one thing the
key of everything okay oh that there is
my photo but it's not oh this is not a
good photo okay so but anyway you see
it's a very thing keyboard use this
I think this switch is called chocolate
switch or something
so that's habit and I have to say it's
my first keyboard read like okay Freddie
Freddie Freeman I like 10 keyless raise
a black window a black widow
yeah Razer BlackWidow racer is no good
okay don't buy racer macca pie magpie
don't buy racer okay return it racer is
a worst possible their product they
abuse you know they their audience is
the gamers basically ignorant gamers
gamers who you know teenagers who
idolize you know the gaming stars so
they want oh you
you need to play games you want to be
the champion and so therefore you need
to get this keyboard and so on you know
lots of marketing jargons this in that
race and their keyboard and you know
it's the worst okay I mean the they
force you to use their internet you know
software otherwise your keyboard won't
walk like they say they would say okay
here for example let me show you never
buy razor
never buy razor razor anything okay why
because they they are keyboard they
first of all their price is much higher
than competitors than Logitech then
Coolermaster all the other game game
game II makers where their price is
higher and the worst thing is that they
force you to you know they say oh we
this keyboard is programmable in blah
blah blah but however you need to have
their driver running otherwise all your
program of program that the keys you
program does not work you have to have
the driver on the computer you are using
so in other words you you you program
your keys you take it to work doesn't
work nothing works your program keys
nothing work this you know that's razor
they've actually they force it wasn't
like that but they intentionally made it
that way so that why so that you they
it's not only require that you use their
that that a razor driver is present but
also they require you to have a internet
account to their cloud to talk to their
server so they have all your data why do
they do that because they can they sell
your data they get mass amount of data
you know and they can sell it and and
also they remove for example they they
could they remove memory in the keypad
for example so that is they save money
they remove the memory memory you know
the the physical memory you know keypads
they save money so they require you
that's why they require you to have a
driver software present so they saved to
your hard disk you know
your key settings or they save it to the
crowd that's what I do
so Raisa is the worst possible
never buy Raisa and that the end and
that's not just not that's not all and
and from the for example from keyboard
experts point of view for those people
who knows key switches who knows
let's see design okay Keith keep key
switch their quality what type they are
you know a tracer is just no good okay
Allen says I bought that book must have
left oh my god so Allen bought this book
this Korean book wait
so Allen okay so Korean vocabulary book
a topic now since Alan bought it I have
to pay attention because this must be a
good book and you know reasonably good
book because Alan bah so this is Korean
vocabulary book a topic based approach
okay so he says the Korean vocabulary
book contains more than 3000 words and
phrases which are grouped by topic to
make it easier for you to to pick what
you what to learn first on top of that
the index in the second half of the book
provides you with a basic Korean English
as well as English Korean dictionary oh
okay so guys buy this book increase your
knowledge increase your communication
skills to people you don't know foreign
people and be multicultural okay you
need to be multicultural in modern
society okay so with my Amazon code okay
Alan stop doing don't do that okay when
people start to do that I gonna get into
trouble
yeah don't do that I mean if I have a
link to some product that's good if you
want to buy something that's not there
that's okay don't you know don't push
for it thank you though
yeah because um it's it's part of the
Hamazon rule you know they're gonna ban
you so that's okay actually not with the
so Freddie says that's okay actually not
with the considering if this keyboard 20
euro okay 20 euro above my budget what
so masses can you shortly
elaborate on polymorphism on in
functional programming languages yes
indeed I'm an expert on that yeah indeed
so let me talk about polymorphism the
entire do read history and detail of
polymorphism and all the you know the
all the ignorance and babbling among
programmers on polymorphism okay so let
me read the comments first the magpie
says I see so yeah I I want to okay so
what mister is on a small black box in
sauce hands oh this no it's just my
backup okay it's mostly my the most
important backup for me is my website
well I used to be a pack rat you know
you sometimes you run into people they
okay let me let me tell you Stefan
Wolfram
log ok personal log let me talk about
this guy which I talked about quite a
few times now this article the personal
edit the personal analytics of my life
this is stefan Wolfram guys he is the
creator of Mathematica the greatest
programming language ever and you know
he he coded it you know thirty years ago
he code it it was written in C so
Mathematica today as far as I know it is
ten years twenty years ago
it's written in C C++ and Mathematica
Mathematica is basically in the family
of Lisp languages so they share many
characteristics in fact Mathematica is a
B's they share many characteristics
including how they are implemented so
typically in a lisp language it's
implemented in c and this okay the core
is in c or sometimes c plus a little bit
then then the rest of it like 80% is is
lisp the language itself same with
Mathematica the core is in C I think
they they they they may have moved to
Silver Spur I mean this is 20 years ago
so they have grown a lot so I don't know
what they are doing now but anyway so
the core is in C or C++ but the rest 80%
is in Mathematica itself so seven wolf
I'm created that and he also is the
creator of Mathematica I mean the
Wolfram Alpha kind of the algorithmic
artificial intelligence which is you
know anyway so he he wrote a blog and
his blog is usually very long like 40
pages okay each one of his blog is 30
pages and this guy is a nut job is
extreme okay he is the extreme him
anyways he is extreme I mean he's a
great programmer he is a great
entrepreneur
you know he so he he's one of the best
programmer
we can say that genius sort of he's
actually a certified genius because when
he was 17 or so he got a PhD from
Cambridge or 15 or something like that
then when he was 18 or 19 he got mug
author award which is MacArthur Genius
award literally the title is MacArthur
Genius award I think that's a title so
he's a certified genius so he's good you
know he he program he's one of the best
programmer and is back then he still do
programming okay
unlike the Richard Stallman the
richest woman who have not coded any
line of code for for 15 years but he's
like Richard Stallman Issaquah it's a
it's a it's kind of a what worthless
almost worthless today and and now he
got kicked out by social justice
warriors just like that just pictures
like that and he's like oh I'm okay with
it the Richard Stallman you know
doesn't know how to code and no idea no
he doesn't understand economics he does
doesn't understand how society works oh
he got the Richard Stallman all he got
is that when he happened to have this
idea kind of communist idea about free
software foundation and he just pushed
for it that that's that's what happens
that's you know some people you know you
look at history quite a few people are
like that they don't they they they
haven't got anything but they happens to
have you know they they they they
believe you know they all they have is a
strong belief in his in certain idea and
they push for it that's Richard Stallman
and he made history it literally made
history so that's Richard Stallman but
he is ignorant about about anything so
anyway back to Stephan Wolfram so he's a
great program he also you know he's he's
also a great businessman
he made Mathematica and he when this
company become very successful and and
noticed this is something interesting he
most companies most entrepreneurs when
their company's big they sell it in the
American capitalism system you sell it
it becomes so-called public company
which means it belongs to everyone
ok so but then then the company in the
way company functions is that buy stocks
you know whoever you can own you can own
a piece of Microsoft you can own a piece
of this you can own a piece of Google
you can own a piece of Facebook and the
owners decide what to do you know you
hire CEOs then you can fire them that's
most entrepreneurs you know once they
got money they sell it you know that's
most people do but Stephan Wolfram again
he's an unusual he's kind of freakish
he's my type ok I like him so he he
doesn't sell he I'm not you know he's
not going to sell the wolf and research
to the become a public company you know
because he want he is a he has got he's
got a vision you know he disguise got a
vision for Humanity I mean not in a bad
way not nothing like you know like he's
gonna be a task fader to control
everything
no but he anyway he's he's one of the
person who's got a vision for how things
should be and the way he like the way
things are like me okay hey you know so
he's got a vision and he you know and
he's able to to to execute that vision
so he runs wolf on research and he
wanted ty to be controlled like every
detail he has full control of it you
know as opposed to it becomes a public
company that you know like usually here
in USA at least when you have a public
company things go bad since the things
go
Souths like google becomes so evil you
know because money basically public
companies money money is controlling
things and and and not in a precise way
it's like all kind of complexities you
know your once your company becomes
public it becomes like you know it
becomes like you know a leafy notion it
goes you know in some way random be but
he tightly control his company he wants
you know everything to be the way he
wants you know so anyway back to his
blog he wrote this article you know he's
this arc of my put the personal
analytics of my life and this article is
one of the many you know he's got lots
of blogs each one you take you take
hours to read it in detail okay and you
read this one so he is so what is he
doing
what do you see talking about in this
blog he said he log his personal life
for example we keyboard warriors we lock
our keystrokes like I tell you guys to
lock your keystrokes so after 10 years
you actually know how many's keystrokes
you actually type not the typical
typical typical programmers saying oh I
think I think you should remap caps lock
to control idiots
okay those typical Emacs hackers or
whatever mean attackers idiot so so you
you want to lock your keystrokes okay
but not just that he you also lock log
for example today you have fitbit's
watch it locks you know what time you
went to bed you know what's your
heartbeat you know you can have a log of
it for 10 years you know you can you can
know precisely the three years ago how
many days ago at a particular time
what's your heartbeat you can know that
today with technology so this guy Stefan
Wolfram he does that he log his life by
technology okay this is before now
remember this is before the era of
phones you know phones came about 10
years ago let's say 15 years ago then
you started to have you know iPhone then
they watch then you can lock your things
so key locks for example key locks today
is very popular you go to my website
you'll find an article where I list all
the software for keylogging ok for
example over here
typing habits repetitive strain injury
key locks
ok so somewhere here okay so you just
search for log okay so it's not here
actually it's in the software section so
for you you search for lock ok there is
a several articles key logging and
security so this of keylogging software
and today it's popular you know you
download those you can lock your keys
but remember this guy stefan wolf and
he's you know before this is popular
he's doing these kind of things so you
read is he you read his blog you see all
the kind of things he log about and he
make a plot of it you know for example
this is his sleeping time since 1990
okay guys from 1990 to 2012
this is his sleeping schedule so as far
as sleeping goes he's pretty normal cuz
he sleeps doing let's see 12 12 to night
kind of 12 you know midnight he begin to
sleep around midnight then around 2002
he sleep around 9:00 a.m.
no wait what is this anyway that that
you know you you you have to read it in
detail so he sleep in time and he's what
is his average by month steady outgoing
emails okay then you can see his email
log he measured analyze it statistics
his email since 1990 you know he can see
his email count how many email he got
per day things like that oh how many
emails he sent per day then you got his
distribution of email per day okay then
you got his monthly distinct email
recipient okay so then you got you know
he got lots of logs this is you know 20
pages
here's his keystrokes okay he he locked
his keys rocks since 2002 so he locked a
lot of that so why am I talking about
him because I was going to say I used to
do this okay I'm that type of guy I used
to do this similar to him so I have I
have my hard disk these are used to have
all the emails I sent you know since
since 1991 all the emails all the
communications I talked you know our new
school song forums it's all logged okay
but life went bad around 2012 I don't
have money I was about to go homeless so
oh he's lost oh he's lost no it's just a
mess so I don't have a backup for ten
years but now I'm starting to get a bit
better so I know I have kid this so I
was yeah so I was saying you know so the
most important thing here right now it's
just my website mine is my 7,000 pages
website but I used to have for example
all my emails emails in the past 30
years they kind of half of them are gone
gone somewhere I don't know like like
like this is pretty bad you know like
about seven to eight years ago I it's
really bad like I don't have $10 $20 to
buy a USB Drive so that's a situation I
anyway so that that's Stefan Wolfe I'm
okay yep and we are going to talk about
Polly movie
I don't know if Matt is here yet Matt
are you still here yet
polymorphism so I'm going to explain
what that is polymorphism okay so I let
me start to explain then but but but
then but then I have a lot of comments
here am I missing something so let me
see what the comments addressed to me so
did you ever use the automation tool or
Mac OS Apple script
no well I did I use I did use it for a
little bit
around 1999 - lets say yeah well anyway
around 1997 - 19 - 2 - mm let's say
let's say so Apple script is a
automation tool okay so in fact you can
see it they have this icon let me show
you
however it's never actually much used
okay wait did I today did they even
remove the icon do you guys see it I
don't see it okay I guess it's so it's
so outdated I'm in it's it's it's so
unpopular they removed the icon yeah I
don't see it they have I come for the
Apple script thing should I show let's
let's try to show it okay
I'm tree and I don't want to show it so
Apple script is a script for automation
it's based on the there's underlying
engine anyway that technology never went
far ok never and I always wanted to know
it more but I I did have several scripts
back then I use it every day but that
technology never went they never become
very popular the apples web automation -
it's
pretty cool but he never took off so any
comments to me any question to me okay
say put my name to it
so here is one Freddie says did you know
Twitter implemented donation donation
buttons with bad coins oh they did
Twitter oh really Wow
I have to look into that thank you I
didn't know okay so if you want to talk
to me put my name to it orange so I can
see it okay now let me talk let me tell
you about polymorphism now polymorphism
it's a job and it's a idiotic jargon
okay
pretty more fearsome you know I
could start to show you code because if
I should start to show you code it's
gonna be more clear but but right now
the language is I have coal and coal and
JavaScript Python they don't really have
polymorphism okay so let me tell you
what it is okay pody when you write a
function let's see let's let's let me
give you an example okay okay so let me
give you an example what what
polymorphism me so let's say you want of
to write a function first okay
define first okay so a B let's say you
want to do that okay and then you see
then if the a and B are numbers then you
do something you you can say return
okay so let's let's let's try javascript
in okay and let's let's say that okay so
let's say if if you are defining a
function a plus B if a and B are numbers
then you do that return a plus B right
now but however you also want this
function to work on vectors okay for
example if a if a are B okay so for
example if they are a and B are vectors
away then two vector addition
okay so in this case you're gonna be you
know a zero so so use for example the
results is gonna be something like that
right you see so you guys see what I
mean so you want this function to you
know the function is called first but
you want it to work on numbers as well
as vectors so instead of sewing as
opposed to as as as opposed to writing a
separate function you see what I mean so
why do you want to just one function
because the empress' can be mink and the
arguments can be numbers B or numbers or
they can be complex numbers or they can
be vectors or they can be matrices you
know different data you know but the
idea is the same you want to add them
together first a function now so this is
a common need this is a common problem
occurrence where you want to write a
function that but with different data
types you know makes sense so so how the
one solution one solution which now
today we have this idiotic name
polymorphism it extreme idiotic name
what why does this name came from
because they came from the imperative
upper object-oriented FLAC those
language those people C C++ Java those
they created this this job and
polymorphism let me tell you what that
what what that is okay a polymorphism is
basically is a function it's a language
feature okay let me write it down let's
be clear okay this is the precise
meaning not not nothing else if you read
let's say if you go to Wikipedia I say
something else
it is wrong okay but I know it's correct
because I've read Wikipedia multiple
times polymorphism is a language feature
okay this is important it is a language
feature this is important this is
critter critical thing it is just a
language feature it's a
programming language feature in a
programming language okay so
polymorphism is a language feature where
a function can have different behavior
depending on the type of argument okay
that's what it means
polymorphism is a language feature this
is the most important parts it's not
it's not about some math idea like you
know or functional programming or it's a
mathematical concept it's a hey
Polly movies emits just a programming
language feature where a function can
have different behavior depending on the
type of argument so so that allows us to
do things like that you know first April
you know first a B can work on numbers
you know and or you can work on vectors
or you can work on complex numbers okay
so if a and B are complex numbers in any
way you get idea oh it okay so let me
just write it out all the a and B can be
complex numbers or the a and B can be
matrices Oh a and B can be tree
arbitrary tree in that case you have to
define what first means you know you
want to add two trees three trees just
means nested array okay nested list so
anyway so the the problem is that you
want to write a function that can work
on any different type of object or
object or type depending on the language
you know object or type or shape or
whatever so they because you know so it
can work on any of these type data type
so if you have a language that allows
you to easily do this then you say that
language supports the feature
polymorphism okay that's
that's that's it now if you have a
language that does not have polymorphism
feature you can do it yourself and this
is called ad hoc polymorphism okay let
me write it down if a programming
language does not let you define a
function that has different behavior
depending on argument then we say this
language to not have the feature of
polymorphism but you can always write it
yourself and this is called ad hoc
polymorphism and in fact JavaScript do
this all the time so what do you do you
write a function like the type like
before like that and you just check so
you know you check the type of a and B
so if they are numbers then you do
something you know you put a condition
like your switch statement like if if
else if else if else you know so if a
and B are vectors then you do then you
return this if a and B are complex
numbers you do something if it's
matrices you do something else
so so in essence you are creating your
function does you know that's what you
want but you are doing it manually
because you are checking you know you
are doing all these if statements so
this is so that if you are doing that
that is called
ad hoc polymorphism anyway
so that that is the basic meaning of
polymorphism you know that that's the
main that's a meaning of polymer VESA a
polymorphism is a language feature where
a function can have different behavior
depending on the type of argument now
now let me add I can give you some
examples now exactly how polymorphism
works
depends on language like I said it's a
language feature so in Haskell there's
one way you know kammo it's another way
in Mathematica it's another way okay in
in JavaScript JavaScript doesn't doesn't
really have polymorphism but you can
like try you can you can you know you
basically do you do this ad hoc
polymorphism you can kind of make it
work so again let me emphasize it's a
language feature okay
polymorphism is a language feature so
there is no like precise definition on
how it should be because each language
we are doing it differently but it's
gent it's a general idea about a
language feature that allows you to do
this easily in a language so each
language will be they will use different
mechanisms to do it okay to the point
like sometimes you know of you guys you
know talking about programming languages
sometimes you can see you know that the
term can become loose because if you are
doing your P then you can think oh I'm
just going to do this or that way which
kind of achieves the same behavior a
polymorphism but not really you know for
example of polymorphism again let me say
it again it's a language feature okay
which means it's not necessary and also
it's not a mathematical concept you know
it's not a math concept at all it's just
a feature it's just the extra
convenience it's a convenience okay so
if you don't have that feature you can
either do it this way you know just
manually code it or you can simply write
different functions for different types
you know you have a plus for vector
first for matrices
first of all trees first of all complex
numbers things like that and and then
you can also have used object-oriented
programming you know so you have a
object that's plus then you know dot
method you know depending on what that
method so so you see so it gets fuzzy
then then anything is polymorphic
polymorphism now you know like your mum
programmers these idiots you know at
least people these people will say oh we
have a multi dispatch or things things
like that it gets gets fuzzy okay anyway
so that's about polymorphism and I think
that's it for today so let me paste
whatever I talked about here and that's
it for today do I make sense to I am I
like is this too much rent or not enough
so seven people watching so I am about
that I'm done today so that's about
polymorphism and actually let me show
you article okay so let me show you a
article you go to polymorphism syntax
OOP computer science let's search for
color okay okay not it's not here it's
you go to a semantic nude oh there it is
Hopi you know again the word
polymorphism is a extreme idiotic jargon
and where it came from it is it came
from it's created by this Hopi idiots
because their language cannot do it so
so it becomes you see here's a history
okay here's how that word arose and
becomes a jargon like everyone is like
oh holy movies on this or that idiots
this Opie idiots okay so polymorphism
you know it came from the Opie people
because why because in function of who I
mean typically all function of
programming languages can do it it's
like it's an it's not an issue you just
do it naturally but in the Opie
languages the crowd the C C++ these
facts they don't have that so so it's
like it's a problem now it's a problem
so they are trying to find a way to do
it so they they have a chargon for it
this is
you know when they can do it they call
it oh this is polymorphism okay
so this article programming language
polymorphism dispatch and the town of
Poli tinting and here I have a example
in what JavaScript and a bunch of other
things okay so that's it for today yep
good thank you guys for watching and
that's it so let me just post this link
so you guys can read my rent yeah and
okay let's talk random let's talk random
chat for three minutes no more no more
than three oh five no more than five for
sure
and let's shut up okay and and let me
just read some random comments let's see
what do you what what you guys are
talking
so I see yeah honestly 65% Kiawah
because even with TTL
what mysteries are in small back no
Sonia we will not know what I activated
fire vote today oh yeah I have used fire
file vote
fire fire vote is a Mac OS feature where
they encrypt your disk you know and I've
used it for like four years
this is around a god I don't even
remember
ok maybe around 2004 to 2008 you know
and so back then I was on a Mac Mac
laptop I book you know one of the
low-end iBook so is slows down a lot but
today's probably much better especially
with fast drive fire fire vote yeah you
know the the one issue with encryption
is that you have the danger of losing
all your data once you if you forgot
your password or things like that
Oh password is like a hell today the
password issue their software probably
use it for encryption or for secure so
let me talk let me talk let me let me
mention something about polymorphism
against okay so hold on a second so let
me so you see if I show this in browser
it's gonna be one bunch of text not
formatted so I need to format it so add
a parenthesis I mean add a paragraph
there and end and add a code block there
and add a paragraph and add a code block
then show in browser now it's pretty
you don't need a PCB and soldier it and
stuff X script in in X script good
morning
it's almost the same as you have oh you
mean my hard drive yeah this is good
I'm not buying Raisa anymore okay so
there's a mountain of off-brand cheap
Chinese pads and mice which do exactly
the same but ant Maktub Aunt Martha and
need well you know the Chinese ones
yes they are a lot of Chinese skin pads
and stuff but usually they are not in
good quality because I have yeah usually
it depends okay but usually the very
cheaper cheap ones the Chinese made
gamepads you have lots of them you have
20 butter mouse you know the cheap ones
they are pretty bad quality so
Yahweh spot wait do bot they but what's
up for parts
Hey bye guys