good morning guys welcome to another
episode of talk show
today we are going to code wufang
language live
so this is mostly going to be me working
on my wolfram language
package
and probably is going to be boring for
you
unless you are interested in wufang
language which is the fantastic
good you know my favorite language
um
and uh yeah so
i'm going to
you know this is a wufam language coding
session uh for myself you know working
on my packages and in in this one hour
or so
i'm going to um
you know as i work i'm going to explain
some things about wolfram language and
and that's it but first of all let me
give you a short introduction
so if you just search for some woofing
language tutorial you can see my
tutorial and i've done several videos
about it like over 10 20 videos in the
past year uh introduction and you can
get it for free download for free and uh
then you can learn the language you know
language basics and uh and wufam
language you know families research
website they have
like a million pages of documentation
so
okay so
okay so let's uh so
i'm just going to work on my we'll film
uh
language now okay so this today's talk
show uh language tutorial um
so you know where to get it for free and
explain the note notebook format okay
first of all let me explain the notebook
the wolfram language notebook format
okay
okay so so let's okay so you know uh you
start woofing language desktop a new
notebook and let's say three plus two
three plus seven okay enter ten and
let's magnify
so you got a big um
so this is a notebook now a notebook is
just like um
let me show you okay so if i save this
file
save okay untitled
let's save in desktop okay untitled
one save now let's go to desktop
so you can see refresh here is the file
now you can open the file
you see wufang language is um the
notebook you know this is a notebook
file
you know the raw it's basically
essentially just ascii you know just
text files
and the content of the file is just pure
wolfram language
code okay so for example this thing
this
this uh parenthesis
parenthesis
uh star
something let's say common okay that's a
kind of nested syntax for comments so
you can delete that so first of all they
have a bunch of comments they tell you
what's what's the content type wolfram
notebook file uh wolfram research
website created by wolfram desktop
that's the that's the
software i'm using
uh you know it's kind of confusing you
have woofum
so you have
let's see download for free
uh download for free wolfram engine by
mathematica and what's the difference
between wolfram language mathematica or
from engine or from script you know it's
a bit confusing so
but essentially they are all the same
they are you know wolfram research they
pretty much have just one main product
you know that's
that was called mathematica but
now they call it wufam language not
referring to the language you know the
language is just like a lisp okay let's
get back so
essentially it's just one thing okay one
thing
but this page explains
who from language will find engine
wolfram language refers to the language
like javascript pearl python ruby refers
to the language you know syntax and so
on
and wolfram engine is the software that
actually do the computation uh you might
think of it as a compiler you know
that's a wolfram engine you know as you
as you know when you type three plus
seven
it sends
you know the notebook sends this text
expression to the wolfram engine the
wolfram engine
do compilation do passing compilation
whatever return the result result and
send it back to the
notebook and the
notebook displays 10.
so that's what wolfram engine is
and the wolfram scripts woofing script
is just woofing language where you run
it in share so let me show you
uh okay i you know i have you know i
have it all set up for example let's say
three
let's okay let's save this file xx dot
uh
[Music]
wls okay so you can see here is the file
xx wrw
that's one of the extension file name
extension for for wufam language
so let's see let's say let's do
something more okay let's do three plus
uh four okay
and i can run it
you know i'm using uh
saufa mod
opening output file permission denied
what
let's see
seven so you can see that you see the
result is seven let's do something more
fancy okay
expand
x squared x
squared times y
let's magnify
plus
z
third power okay
let's say square root of
z
plus y okay let's say something like
that
z uh let's not let's say x plus y
okay then square the whole thing
by
four okay
now let's remove that
and run this
run it
okay so you can see the answer in the
mini buffer so here is a result and you
can do the same thing in a notebook
let's do it here
you see fantastic and you can you know
let's copy the copy it and you can press
ctrl shift n
to make it
you know a two-dimensional format
mathematical type setting evaluate you
know same answer so that's
the notebook
and what i'm doing here in emacs because
i have a sao woofing mod okay let me
show you
uh
there some wolf and mod so you can go to
the source code so this is a
emac list major mod i wrote for for the
wolfram language
you can get it
you can get it it's free
it's sponsored by wufan research you
know so it allows you to code wufang
language in emacs
and uh it's on github so you can you
know so i have an introduction video you
it's on github you can get it there
on github
okay
so that's how i run uh let's let's not
close it so okay so close that
okay let's show it and close that
reopen close
close
okay so
here's the e-max buffer and it contains
wufang language code
and i can run it run
you see the result is in the mini buffer
can you magnify the mini buffer
mini buffer is hard to magnify
yeah so it you know it's better just to
open the
messages buffer so to see the results so
you can see there is a result
okay close it so
so i was talking about wolf language you
know that's that's wufam language
and that's wufam language that's wufam
language
ufam engine is what computes these
things and you can actually get the um
yeah
you can you can get uh for example i can
show you where is the actual wolfram uh
engine
file path
so
gcm gcm is powershell it stands for get
commands
okay getting complex let's say let me
let me show you okay so
powershell
help gcm
gcm is the alias for get command okay so
i can type gcm gcm
ufram
okay ufam script executable so you can
see it's an application and does it show
the path no
so you uh
let's do
format list fl is a shortcut fpl is a
powershell ads to
for to the command format list
so git command will find language so you
can see it's located here you know see
i'm on windows so it's on c program
files wolfram research who from script
so let's go to that uh directory so you
know so i can show you some of the
wolfram language
uh compilers and executable
so let's paste the path here let's okay
let's
you know one of the problem of the
powershell i don't like is that it
output this readable format but however
it's not so useful if you are coding
because it
you know you have to reconnect the lines
so anyway here's the file path so let's
go to the directory actually so let's go
to the directory
so you can see here's the wolfram
language
of script directory go up a directory
so you can see c program files i don't
know if you can see that
okay
so program files will from desktop
that's a product they send it to me and
wolfram script is free
uh
so you know that's the executable so
close that go to the ufam desktop and
version 12.2
open
uh then you have you know from desktop
executable ufm.exe so let me tell you
what these are okay
it's a bit confusing actually you don't
need to know so but basically the
wolfram desktop
the wolfram desktop you are seeing
that's
that's what runs the notebook you know
that's the application for example let's
open it let's try to open it you know
open it
there it is
and i can now open a new notebook you
know that's a wolfram desktop close that
uh
i want to make sure i only want have one
instance running yeah okay so that's a
wolfram desktop
and this is just a config file and woven
dot exe that's um
you know these two are similar basically
they these these are the actual kernel
the compilers that computes wufang
language so
in notebook when you press enter when
you press shift enter to do some
computation it actually sends the
expression to the wolfram to this woofam
kernel
so it it works kind of like a server
client uh model so the notebook is a
client
since the expression to the server the
the kernel the the kernel the wolfram
kernel can be local on my machine or it
can be far away you know 10 000 miles
or it can be a super computer you know
machine farm you know things like that
and the the wolfram kernel returns a
result and it's displayed in notebook
and similarly in emacs for example we've
done
uh with language you know for example we
have done let's comment this out
common itself for example we have done
this computation
you know it's doing similar things it
sends the expression to the kernel and
kernel replies and emacs receive it and
display the result
okay so let's go back to the
to the directory
yeah okay so that's woofam kernel and
wufram script is i haven't showed
wolfham script woofam script is the
ufam script is the the front end that
allows you to
do firm language in a terminal so for
example let's let me show you
so wolfen
you know let's start it you know it's
just like any python python you know uh
command line interface so for example
let's
let's um
for example let's
let's send this expression to it
paste
do it you know so it you know that's the
wolfram
script
so wolfham script is the command line
interface
ulfram notebook is the graphical
and you can also run it in emacs i'm
using saufa mod
okay
so that's about
that's about the difference is what's
you know the wolfram language from
engineer from scripture from notebook
you know what you know kind of uh a bit
confusing and wolfram player is
basically just a free
notebook like application that allows
you to see you know if you downloaded
some woofing notebook file online and
you don't have wufang language installed
you know you then you can download fun
player just to see you know product
to see it but you cannot actually
compute it so wolfram player is kind of
like um
kind of marking in tool okay not
recommended you know you rather you know
i recommend you just download wufang
language
get the engine free get the wolfram
script free and if you want the
graphical user interface it you know it
can show fantastic graphics
you can download you know from github
it's open source download the
julia so did i mention it here
yeah so uh jupiter not julia so jupiter
you download jupiter you know you run
the jupyter notebook then you can
you know so that's another interface to
firm language you know you run the
notebook in the jupyter
you know
in a jupyter notebook
software
and whenever you want to do some
computation you know wolfen language
expression
you press enter it sends the expression
to the wolfram kernel you know the
woofer engine like we talked about
before and send it back to the uh
jupiter notebook and you can display the
graphics you can rotate it i believe
so anyway that's uh introduction to uh
you know these
things okay
and
and now
now i want to talk about the notebook i
want to show you what is the notebook
file format made up okay so you can see
here's a notebook
let's um let's save it okay let's
let's open a new one
three plus seven okay three plus uh two
um
okay
five let's save this as
xx dot mb
test notebook okay
okay
now we go to
go to the directory so there is the test
notebook so open it so like i said
before all these are just simply from
language expressions you know these are
wolfram language syntax so all these are
comments you know these are comments you
can delete it
you can actually delete it you know the
cash id
internal cash information
uh you know notebook data position you
know those are cash you know
any comment you see in this file
is wolfram language
you know no nothing extra it's just pure
wufang language
so you know when you see your comment
you can actually just delete it so let
me close the notebook
close it okay and let's edit the
notebook let's do like surgery you know
some
like programming engineering you know
software called this is surgery you know
we
we edit we modify the notebook directly
by just using language okay so it says
beginning of notebook content deleted
and then end of a notebook content
deleted internal cache information
deleted sale tag you know
those are cash for
for whether the sales are closed or not
you know things like that
so we can also delete it delete it so
here
you are actually seeing the raw uh
wolfram language for the
for for the simple the you know for the
most simple computation three plus two
okay let me explain how this uh is you
know it's kind of confusing but let me
explain your understand
so you can see the notebook
that this notebook is a function okay so
that's a function
notebook
yeah so that's just a function like that
and the notebook takes uh what
it takes two arguments so you can see
the first argument is this part you know
it's just one
kerdi bracket that's the first argument
then it takes several more arguments
rest
arguments you know so it says window
size you know window size is you know
it's the window size
not important information so window size
window margin
magnifi magnification 1.4 because we
magnified you know we magnified the
notebook
then front end version you know 1.2.2
for microsoft windows 16 64 bits
style definition default
you know style definition that you know
notebook is so it's like
you can use
kind of like css thing to control the
look you know you can have headers
subheadings you know sex subsections and
so on i'm gonna go over okay
then expression you know expression uidu
id is a universal identification that
you know they just give a random number
for for this particular notebook so let
me so let's modify this notebook okay so
first of all notebook then this window
size we don't care okay so remove all
that
so now
the first argument is the actual real
content of the notebook so let me let me
dissect how this uh works okay this cell
this this cell group is very annoying so
you can see
so this is the first argument and and
this argument is at least
how do i know because at least you know
that
curly braces that's a syntax for a list
so this list has only one element
yeah only one element cell
now you see it's all nested just like
this you know this is woofing language
is just this okay it's wonderful you
know
it's just a a lisp so it's all
nested so you so this
so this
notebook takes one argument the first
argument okay so you cannot have extra
comma here so you need to remove that so
one argument at least and this list
consists of just one element cell
so one single cell so what is a cell
cell is this
this thing so if you
type that you know it creates this
that's a cell
okay so this so that notebook has only
one cell not this one but the one we
just closed
uh can we be open let's see control
shift tab
uh we're gonna reopen later okay
actually we can actually let's reopen
now so save this file
go back you know go back to the uh you
see we reduce the file size by a lot and
open it
you see there is there is our notebook
again so but let's delete it it's um
you know again let's work on
let's modify the
you know the the source code the raw uh
content of the notebook
you know i'm i'm get you know so and you
can also program the notebook you can
generate the notebook
programmatically you know you can
generate lot you know lots of notebook
so anyway cell
so this list has one element and that
element is a cell and this cell has how
many elements uh two elements okay so
this cell is another function
uh it takes two arguments here so let's
say
oh just one argument so you see
this cell is just one argument and that
argument is the cell group data you know
it gets a bit tedious
the cell group data takes two arguments
so the first argument is at least again
the second argument is open
so what does open mean open means you
know if you have a cell here
that's open this is close you see you
can expand it that's open close open
close
you know this one close open you know
just just like oak mod you know you have
hierarchy of headers header heading one
heading two subheading three heading sub
heading four you can expand them
or you know open them or close them
similar you know very similar for
example let me show you
so heading let's see heading
one okay heading one
heading two
heading three so you create a cell you
select it you go to the
format
and you can go to um
style
so you can see you can choose title old
one
then it becomes that
then
o2
is the
subtitle let's uh
yeah o2 subtitle all three is chapter so
you know they they give different names
but you can think of it just heading one
head into heading three
so let's see let's make this all three
so the way they named it is
old one is titled uh
old one is title o2 is subtitle o3 is
chapter 04 is section
title subtitle chapter section
subsection so
so let's
hold three let's see all three
then this is four
then
heading five
old five let's do old five
so you can see
so now you have them you know because i
we we we set their style so you have
heading one heading two you know they
are they become a hierarchy so you can
collapse the whole thing
you can class collapse any um
you know root of the tree
so it's kind of it's you know it's just
like oak mod but but let me go back here
to explain okay so so this cell group
data you have open
then
then you have you know the set the first
argument is at least
here the second argument is just open
meaning the cell is open okay so you
have cell group data then you have
actually started to have a cell
okay cell takes
okay two arguments so you have the first
one is the box
the second one is uh box data
uh so it gets complex it gets tedious so
let me just simply explain what are
these you don't need this okay this
so what are these box data let me
explain okay so
when you have something simple like a
number
then
then then you're gonna have for example
let me show
for example we can create an entire new
notebook let's do it
by you know we're gonna
we're gonna manually create an entire
new notebook you know like that okay so
let's um
so first of all switch it to um
wufang language mod sao from language
mod
then
completion notebook okay so notebook is
represent the notebook then you have a
cell so let's create a cell
then in this cell let's say three plus
four plus five okay
so that's it that's that's uh that's
that's one notebook so we can save it
test2 test2.nb
okay so you can see here is our file
test2.nb
so that's that's it
now let's open this file so you know
let's open in desktop test2
open it
okay i got the syntax wrong that's why
it's not showing so let's modify it
uh i think this should be strings no
they shouldn't be strings
and
let's let's say
cell group let's just do whatever the
other thing is doing
let's see
cell cell group data
this is
complicated
and let's just do a put them into a
string let's see what
happens
okay save it
open it
okay it's not showing okay so
close it it's
it's okay so
okay so maybe you need cell uh you
notebook okay notebook you know book oh
yeah you need the list i said i suppose
let's see
let's look at the documentation okay
wolfram language notebook documentation
the notebook function
refresh
yeah so you see notebook the syntax you
need at least that's why we got it wrong
so you
gotta have a list here and put the cell
there okay save it
open it
fantastic
you can see
345 there you see we
essentially we manually created a
notebook
you know so close it so
the main point i want to make here is
that the the notebook format is just
you know the content of the notebook is
just pure ascii test test test
text okay pure ascii text
and the content is purely woofing
language
expressions nothing else you know you
don't have binary you know
special format or you know maybe
backslash you know maybe backslash for
both you don't have nothing like that
the
you know the whole thing syntax is the
notebook syntax is just wolfram language
okay
now in wolfram language you have things
like this you know notebook cell that
represent you know this
this kind you know this
thing
and when you
evaluate this in a
um
i mean when you open this
upframe expression in a notebook then it
format them nicely and also you can
actually run this code
you know i can actually run this code
right now but before we do that let's um
let's make sure my syntax is correct
okay so notebook
the notebook requires one argument of a
list okay and then inside the list each
element is a cell so what exactly should
the cell be
notebook file contains explicit notebook
expressions written out in a textual
form you can manipulate open notebooks
in the front end using standard commands
in the front end using the open
inspector and so on okay so
so okay let's look at the cell
function
so you see it says cell is a low level
representation of a cell inside a
wolfram system notebook
okay so contents and style okay so we
need a style so
okay what uh
so we need a style here
because otherwise when we you know
because otherwise we open a notebook
it's kind uh it's you know it's
can can we actually evaluate this you
cannot you see so
you see normally you press shift return
to evaluate but this is what's called
inactive cell inactive cell is just for
representation you cannot actually
evaluate so in other words
you have tags
to represent which part is the
expression that actually
is hot you know like code for example in
in oakmod
you know you have certain text that
to signify this part is actual code so
when you run it part of the
org mod
uh section we are actually running some
code
in the same way wolfen language has that
so you have you see this cell
represent represents a cell
but however you need
you need uh you need to say style you
know like indicate whether it's um
active you know expression or not so
so what is the um
let's see what is the
uh what is the syntax for the
i don't know so let's
so what we can do is we can let's say
options
so we want to see all the options for
the function cell okay
okay oh god sale has a thousand options
what the hell
geez geez
you see the sale
it's funny because cell is
it's a function but it's i mean it's
it's a represent representational
function
you know
so let me show you this um
yeah this this is interesting because
the the
connection between language and lisp
gets into lots of interesting things and
also html and xml
so let's see
sunday html5
so i have an article
yeah and i don't know where is this html
tutorial
so go to my website saudi
code
and click on search
and type
html6 not five right that's right
html6 okay
so this is the article html json xml
simplified so
so you can see
you know list is just list
this
list syntax is nested list and html and
xml is also nested so in some sense they
are the same you know they are just
nesting you know nested syntax
so in the same way wolfen language is
the same
now in lisp
you know in this usually when you have
um
you know let me i i explain part of it
here
so for example there are there are many
formats existing
in scheme list
yeah in particular in scheme racket they
use lisp
expression to represent html so this is
how you represent
um
h1 header
you see so
if you represent
html in this in this way
you'll see that this h1
you know this h1 technically is a
function but this function actually
doesn't do any computation
except that when you have a program that
renders this
you know
this thing for example a browser then h1
became meaningful
what it means is that the you know
whatever
inside the h1 should be represented
rendered in certain way you know because
h1 is a header so this is how you
represent
html in lisp syntax
okay and this is actually part of the
standard it's called scheme
um
you know did i mention you know it's
just it's a standard it's like
it's like very popular among the skin
phonetics
you know the the associated word is like
semantic
web you know if you search for semantic
web
and this
semantic web list you'll find you know
the
lots of standard documentations and
proposals
uh from the mostly the scheme this
community
uh especially during the year 2000s
lots of it because that's that's the
time when the semantic web idea is very
hot
so anyway
but if you represent html in this this
you know in this syntax
you'll see that some functions they
don't have a
like you know some functions such as h1
they don't have a like computational
purpose
rather they have you know so they are
inert in some way so if you run this in
this you know compile it doesn't do
nothing it just returned itself
but if you
use some application like a browser
or pdf you know to to
to load this document then h1 is
meaningful it it means that the
following expression should be
involved in in larger font and so on
because it's a header
so the point here is that
you have some functions that's inert in
actually that happens in this
right now too for example let's um
so we have emac this
so we have cons you know
cons let's say three
four okay
cons is a
data structure it's a fundamental data
structure in this
but the cons doesn't do anything i mean
it doesn't actually
compute it just represent a structure
so in the same way
if you represent htm
ml in this you know you have this kind
of thing you know it represents
structure by the way these these are
alternatives you know there are
different syntax for
uh different proposals to represent xml
in this
so this is one of them
and this is another one you know they
have competing proposals
to represent xml in this
so but my point i want to make is that
you some functions you you'll have some
functions that's rather in earth such as
the cons
in the same way here
so
that brings up to the wolfram language
so this notebook that's a function but
it doesn't do anything that's a point
okay that's a point i'm making
this cell is a function but it actually
doesn't do anything
it only represents some some format some
structure
but if you
open this thing you know open this thing
in
uh
let's save it
uh oh permission deny because i have
this open
close it
you know on windows if you have some
thing open you cannot modify it until
that's closed
so now
saved okay now if i open
there it is okay so
so actually it gives me an error so we
can see
an improperly formatted directive with
head symbol
was encountered error occur cell on line
three
yeah it's it's telling me that this is
oh there you see i got the style you see
the style this is your own syntax
so let's do it again
close it
so now we can open this file open
open it
and what output error information denied
what
did we
opening our profile permission denied
oh
oh yeah we are opening a wrong file
jesus what
test 2
untitled one
so anyway let's save this okay save this
save this
and back to
ah that's why i see yeah never mind
what what what was going on was that i
have auto save in emacs so that it's
trying it's actually trying to save this
file
you know because we opened it before but
i just closed it but anyway so
no so let's open it let's go to untitled
close that
yeah so we open this file and
you know so let's close it so we get rid
of that error
okay so
let's open this again
there it is okay
now
now i want to add a style
i'm not sure what is the format because
because we just tried the option cell
and there are
like a thousand options
so let's cheat and let's look at
let's just look at the other notebook
what is the
so let's cheat and let's see what
what
style it's using expression id
cell box data raw
this robux you know
so anyway so you see what you are seeing
here is the content of this notebook now
it's getting too too big okay let's
let's close this
what's going on
yeah
don't save
close it
and
because i have auto save
okay finally
so now let's
close this
thing
now let's just save that okay
let's close these two
close
make them simpler save it
now open it
right
oh untitled there
so
[Music]
so there is one cell
oh there there okay so now i got it
so now what you need to do
not style but um what what is it input
okay so that's what you need
so
this cell needs two arguments the first
argument is the expression the second
argument is what type of cell like we
mentioned before active or inactive or
whatever so input
make it
a input cell so that's when you want to
evaluate something
and this you don't need to be a string
yeah so
save it so remove that you cannot have a
hand in parentheses
you cannot have you know trading commas
in from language
so there it is okay
so let's uh save it okay
open this file
okay arrow
arrow okay i think i need
why is it arrow i think i need uh
improperly formatted directive
with head symbol is encountered
line three okay
improperly
yeah okay
so let's
let's make this
i think it needs to be a string then
okay save it
let's close that close that close that
okay
open it
there it is fantastic you can see wufang
language
let's see yeah so
so
so this
let's make a backup so this
is what it looks like over there
uh i want to
so let's let me show you something uh
here okay so let's
delete this
and delete this let's just save this and
okay and let's say three plus four here
okay and evaluate it okay so this is uh
kind of hierarchy
so save this
now let's open untitled
okay so it looks like that so you can
see
it's a notebook
then you got a bunch of sales so this is
oh yeah okay this is one giant cell
okay so the notebook so
the notebook so that they
oh yeah so they created one giant cell
to hold all these things so you can see
the heading one here this one
is this part
so heading one
then title
yeah title is the style of this heading
then you know cell change time you know
it records when you make change to it
so because it has a
stepwise backup systems you know you can
like mini software today you can revert
to specific date you modified it
uh
okay so the details are a bit tedious
but basically that's you know that
that's what i'm trying to tell you
so in summary a notebook
content
is just
text file ascii test text file of
wolfram expressions and you are looking
at the content so these expressions are
just wolfen language and wolfen language
has many functions that's
like these
cons or like how you represent
html
in
this syntax you have many functions
that's
not for computational purposes but
rather they represent a
structure
or particular formatting of expressions
so
for example this notebook and cell okay
okay so then
what i want to show you is that
okay what i want to show you is this
part okay so
input let's say
did we uh
okay so i want to have some fancy thing
let's do that okay
so let's
paste that here
okay let's make a several copies of it
now i want to show you
some formats okay for the first one
ctrl shift r
means raw okay that means don't format
you know anything just um
ctrl shift r
and wait ctrl shift r okay
uh
then this one
control shift i for standard input what
why is it
you can just shift ah
i don't know why it adds a space there
ctrl shift r
and it adds a space
mindset
ctrl shift i
it shouldn't add a space ctrl shift n
okay i haven't
wow a lot comment wow thank you guys
and thank you ofamio i haven't seen the
comments i think that's it for today i
was gonna work on
my wolfram language and
so i'm going to read comments
you can read the wolfram language
notebook in emacs with that mod yes of
course you you you mean the wolfram
language mod kassaw from language mod
yes that's your that's what you are
seeing here
uh latest wolfram version i have to talk
to them because i don't you know i
realized i have the version 12.
right now they are on version 13.
so i need to talk to them to you know to
get me the latest version but it should
be the same by the way you know the
wolfen language basically you can expect
10 years
without any change any code you know
compatibility
uh you can read and write wolfram
language notebook in e-max with that mod
opening clubhouse shaped 10 iq points
what
so german says is it possible to run a
program like a keystroke counter
outside mathematica while writing a web
or docs
yeah of course i mean you have you know
you have
how long have i been talking
50 minutes i think that's it for today
so
you know i was going to work on
my packages but
explain explaining the notebook format
took took an hour
uh but it's a good thing because i
wanted to explain this for a while um
but
you know there's a there's a major point
i want to get to i want to show you some
of the difference between
uh let's see
let's try it again okay let's
ctrl shift
r
ctrl shift i
ctrl shift n
this is a major part i want to show you
show you guys okay so let's do it again
close that
so new
save
test three mb okay so i'm gonna show you
this
three plus one 3 plus 1 okay let's make
some copies of these
three copies okay wait
let's say 3 plus x squared okay
copy copy and the first one
ctrl shift
r let me show you what that is okay you
go to the cell
and you can say convert to basically you
specify what kind of representation or
style okay so you have
ctrl shift r for raw input form that
means represent this expression
in plain ascii no
no fancy rendering nothing just plain
the most basic wolfram language
expression that's this raw input form
okay so ctrl shift r then you also have
ctrl shift i for input form that's
that's that's um that's also ascii but
less raw
raw is the most you know the most simple
then you have the input form then you
have the standard form ctrl shift n
okay so let me let me show you one by
one
ctrl shift r
so that's the raw
input form the first one
ctrl shift i so the second one is input
form
then the third one is let's to control
shift
n that's a standard form so that's why
you you started to see
this expression you know the raised
so let me let me
let me
also type some text
o7
this is raw input form okay
this is
input form
then all seven
this is
standard form
and
let's just say standard form okay so now
save this now let's open them in
uh raw let's see what they are so test
three
so you can see
so you can see here it says this is raw
input from text
then you have the cell
you can see cell
3 plus x squared input okay
blah blah blah then you have this
so this input form that's the first one
this uh this is
this is raw input form okay that's this
one that's what this one okay
raw input form so you can see
the expression is here
you know very the most simple possible
okay
then
let's look at the second one the input
form
uh this one okay so
so go down so you see it says this is
input form then then you you started to
see you see notice this box data
this box data then you have row box
then your box is a list your box is a
list of many elements you have you know
a string three
then a string empty space then a string
plus in an empty space
then another row box
uh you know three blah blah blah you
know that's input
so that's the second one
okay that's this one but you know they
look the same but you might wonder so
what why what's with this raw box
and so on because
it allows you to you see when i click
it's
syntax aware you know it's it
because of these raw boxes
i can click and select by semantic unit
you know
for example click
twice three times four times you know
but here i cannot do it you know it's
just
it's just like the whole thing
you can see this when you have more
complicated expressions uh anyway so so
let's get let's go on to look at the um
the standard form there it gets more
complex okay
so you go down and you can see standard
form
then you can see
you know box data roblox
superscript box
oh still pretty simple okay so this is
this is actually what you want
anyway so that
this
that's what i'm trying to do is to
explain what are these raw box
and box data are for
they are essentially you know like tech
you know la tech tech they represent you
know they kind of capture the position
you know for example roblox is just a
box of things
it's
it doesn't represent any computation it
it's it's trying to
it's trying to represent the position of
things that's why you have these rule
box so in other words
you are trying to
have a format that specify
arbitrarily complicated
expressions like that
in a nested syntax
and also represent the position that so
that's why you have this row roblox and
superscript box things
but
but my point the point i want to make is
that if you want the things to be the
most simple possible just make them
raw input form
but you miss a lot you miss a lot
features for example
for example this is the input form
this is the input form this is the
standard form i can click on that and
and subsequently depending on where my
crews are
subsequently expand the expression
by semantic unit for example i can click
on that then i got the whole thing oh if
i click start here with the plus sign
see
so this is a standard form this is the
the most normal now over here is the
input form i can also do that you can
see
i can start here
or i can start here or i can start here
but
over here it's the
raw input form you don't have that you
just
you know you just select the whole line
okay that's uh anyway so that's it
oh so how do you filter an array to
exclude numbers less than 50 that's the
most simple okay so let me answer
that's a good question that's that's the
most simple
so let's do a let's do a random uh
random integer okay random integer
uh let's say
let's say 10 okay
10 of
them uh random integer under 100 okay
from from 1 to 100 or 0 to 100 so we got
10 of them so now let's say that
2x uh x
you know one thing i don't like is the
wolfram
notebook doesn't have good
text editing abilities
that's why i you know working emacs
so okay so x is this bunch of numbers so
you want to filter out so
you can do it in many ways you can
so when you have at least this this is a
huge topic you know
so when you have a list you can filter
by a function
or by a pattern
yeah in general so basically the the
cases is
is is by a pattern okay so uh not case
cases
yeah so so we if you want to do it by a
pattern then you just say
cases
x then give a pattern so the pattern
should be
you know in this case pattern is not
suitable it's more suitable if you give
a function but however you can represent
the function in a bio pattern so the way
the way you do that is
you can represent the function by your
pattern
uh
yeah okay so i haven't
so i need to look up the patterns syntax
yeah okay let's just do select okay
let's first of all let's do select um
select is allow is what allows you to
filter the by a function okay so select
x then we just write the function
uh
say x
uh the function will be
argument less than 50 true okay
then
that okay that should do it there there
it is
so if it's so this is a function you
know this is a function shortcut
so it uh yeah it removes elements beyond
you know more than 50.
and
the full syntax for that you can another
way to write this is is like this
more understandable function
so function argument let's say x
let's say let's use some other symbols
so
uh y
less than 50.
you know this is another way to do it
same result
but you can also use cases so
the
so
if you so the difference is that if you
use select you use a function to filter
out so the function returns true
it stays it returns force the item is
removed or you can use cases cases you
give a user pattern if the pattern match
the element states
so
if we want to use a pattern
we need a pattern to represent any
number that's less than 50. now this is
you know this is generally not
represented by a pattern
you know because
a number less than 50 that's you know
that's
but however the pattern allows you to
represent a function by a pattern but i
don't i don't remember the syntax of
hand
but i believe it's like this okay
so you just say anything let's just try
it okay so you just say anything
and
and question mark
then followed by the function i think
that's how you do it let's just try okay
do it
no
uh
so what is so we need to look at the
patterns okay we should be able to do
quick quickly
you know there's so many like so many
different ways to do this
okay i think that's it
pattern matching functions rules and
patterns uh unimaginable functions
so what is the
what what is the way to represent god i
forgot let's see let's try that
patterns in transformation rules there
okay so here's a summary of the patterns
uh we want yeah so
so yeah that is the function
oh yeah so the function needs to return
true or false
so why why is uh why is this not correct
maybe we need a parenthesis no
i know
oh you need a parenthesis that's why
okay
here it is
so here is how you represent
a function
by a pattern
you know this you know
so this expression means it's a pattern
okay
it's a pattern the underscore means a
pattern okay
the underscore means a pattern followed
by a question mark so that means
this pattern
underscore it means anything okay so
it'll match anything
except
only only if this function returns true
so
you know so it's quite flexible
cases yeah okay so
okay okay thank you guys
bye guys
right guys i i you know i rambled over
this hour
uh trying to explain the notebook format
but it's not a good one okay bye guys