hello guys welcome to another episode of
excel talk show today we are going to
review
the ultimate hacking keyboard too
you know in the screen you are seeing
all my keyboards well not all but you
know most of my favorite ones but today
we are going to review this keyboard
ultimate hacking keyboard version 2 okay
fantastic so let me show you what these
keyboards are this is exposed fantastic
one all these all these are my favorite
exposed keyboard okay fantastic
Xbox keyboard every time I use it it's
just a joy pure joy
this is kinesis Advantage 2 you have
seen in my videos for the past seven
years I've been using this as my main
for the past seven years
I I would still use it but now I got so
many other choices so you know I take a
break from that
bodies are fantastic and this is a glove
80 keyboard glove 80. I did a review
about an hour uh long about two months
ago okay this is my current main
keyboard okay fantastic
this is Bluetooth
okay this is the only Bluetooth among
the choices you've seen here
and now okay so and now this is the
ultimate hacking keyboard version one
and this is what we are going to review
in depth today ottoman hacking keyboard
version 2.
okay
so version 2 the difference the major
difference is that the version two so
let me start this so the major
difference is that in version 2 you have
bike backlight backlight
okay backlight and quite a few other
improvements I'm gonna show you and
explain okay
backlight and the backlight is
functional backlight because you know
typically okay let's stop that stop stop
that
typically the backlight is you know you
see how they are colored
almost every other keyboard their
backlight is decorative
the purpose of that is decorative but
this one is different it's functional
coloring so white is the normal input of
a numerics
CN is operating system modifier Keys
such as control Windows old shift
and Xiang is Ultimate hacking keyboards
modifier Keys okay and and also when you
can you can see if I press this function
key down
uh
we see that you see the active Keys have
different color okay so those are key
markers those blue are key markers and
if I press the function down you can see
the red red or switching layers so
anyway orange colored that means special
modifier keys for the ultimate hacking
keyboard version 2. the version one do
not have
uh
backlight
okay so now so let me set up where I
wanna okay so also my hacking keyboard
too okay so let's go over let me go over
my notes and and cover each one of the
features okay so let me go over the
notes uh
see ottoman so first of all it's a split
keyboard
so okay okay so split keyboard by the
way I got this um
I got these modules you have to buy them
separately they are attached by magnet
so this is fantastic I'm gonna cover
them in detail okay in fact I have two
other modules so all these are modules
so this is a trackpoint module
trackpoint like the IBM
ThinkPad most famous there and here is a
track pad module okay I'm gonna go into
detail about each one of them which one
should you get and this is the left hand
the only left hand module this is uh
three extra keys plus a
mode plus a multi-directional tiny
trackball this is for scroll
multi-directional scroll and plus two
other
little Point uh
buttons okay left click and right click
and you can program any of this key or
the button to do anything to do anything
else okay and here is a trackball module
this is the best actually click click
okay so the modules so let me go over
the keyboard okay so first of all it's a
split keyboard
why is this split what's a what's a
what's the purpose so that you can tend
it this way or you can tilt it the
normal way traditional way or you can
tear it this way or a more ergonomic
tier this is called negative till you
know you can tear this way so multiple
ways so to connect them you just simply
snap them in okay it's solid okay it's
very very well built solid okay
okay so since I connected them I I don't
need to
pop up the legs so I can
so I want them to so actually this is
not good because
because now if I connect them you see
you have the legs in the middle and but
you don't have the legs on the side but
the legs are easily removable so let me
show you all you have to do is twist it
and lift it
okay so you see so twist it and lift it
and this is the leg very good design
and let's see if you can focus it
yeah you cannot focus so anyway so you
just
and see click them in
click them in
and push them in and twist to lock once
it's locked you can you know pop pop up
the legs
up or down
okay so so anyway the point here is that
they are
they can be split so once you split I
want the legs up
so you got tinting you know tinting
split keyboard and extremely portable so
you can just put them together or you
can just you know drop the legs and put
them in your backpack
so that's the point about split keyboard
okay and then next let's see USB
connections so this is USB wired and you
got
um
let's see
let's see so you got this
USBC to USBC and they include a
a plug so that you can connect to USB a
on your computer
over this side is USBC okay
so let's see what's next feed so we
already talked about feet fantastic
feature you know just twist and uh lock
and so feet is great
backlight we talked about backlight
functional lighting okay uh fantastic
and let's see what what's the next topic
uh functionality so you you can turn it
off if you want to you know via the
software I'm going to show you in a
moment I'm gonna show you my screen so
if you have comments and questions
posted okay let's see
comments and questions guys
so key switches you know you have
multiple choices of key switches I'm
gonna talk about that later you can just
go check their website so for me because
I have repetitive strain injury for like
10 years so I need very light switch so
I'm the one I have is
is uh
silent pink those are made by Kyle Kyle
box switch silent pink 35 grams
activation Force okay that's what I have
okay now let's talk about modules so
each one you have to buy them separately
you know if you want to you know so this
so uh let me let me let me tell you
about them so these modules you know
each one is like 60 or something so one
for left hand for the right hand you
have three choices
track point trackball and the track pad
trackball is the best Okay so let's just
connect it
snapped it in just slide it in
Okay so
so you there you have it so now so if I
move this so you can see can you see my
can you can you see my cool so you
cannot okay but now you can so you see
this is the track point
uh
track point and and you have the scope
wheel on the left hand so let's go here
so you can scroll
I don't know if you can see it can you
see it yeah okay so you can scroll with
this or
so let's focus on the trackball module
first so the right hand side so you have
left click
you have left click you have the right
click okay then
so it functions as say trackball then
you can hold down the modifier then it
functions say scroll wheel
so you know very nice so I would say so
of all the uh the pointer modules so
this or the left hand key cluster
modules I would say
so the pointer module they are not a
replacement for
you know these modules they are not
replacement not a complete replacement
for mouse or for a track travel okay
because suppose you work on with the
computer eight hours a day you maybe use
Photoshop or you maybe you do CAD you
know AutoCAD or drawing
three-dimensional modeling software
or even if you are a programmer in you
know if you work a long day you want a
mouse okay you want a mouse or trackball
uh you know a full-sized Mouse because
this this this tiny
it's not good for a long time okay but
however they are tiny so you can you
know it's very portable with this
keyboard you can just clip it in and
remove it easily
okay let me show you the trackpoint so
track wall is the best in my opinion
the checkpoint uh is very sensitive you
know but you know typically and pretty
small so
I wouldn't you know I would recommend
the trackboard the most so also the
track point you can scroll by two finger
slide okay
by two fingers slide but it's not very
good because you can also magnify by uh
let me show you my screen okay maybe I
should show you my screen
so you can see my operation with the
track
pad so you can see first of all it
functions like a mouse you know and then
you can
you can you can do this to magnify so
let me show you you see magnify Mac can
you magnify you see it magnifies then
you can shrink by pinch them in
or you can use two fingers to swipe them
up and down and in that case it's gonna
be square okay
uh but sometimes you know when you
scroll it it instead it magnifies it so
it's not so you know it track four is
better than okay so anyway if you want
to right click you double you click you
You tab it with two fingers okay like
that okay
you tap it with two fingers okay so
that's
do it again so you see that's the right
click so that's a track point you know
there's no buttons on it on it or
anything so it's just
it's just a pure
I mean trackpad okay all these are very
light you know they are they weighed 30
grams or something
then you have the IBM you know the IBM
made it famous the track Point okay I
don't so again my favorite is the
trackpad so let me show you the track
point so
click so you can see one finger so you
can see the trackpoint got a problem
checkpoint is like a joystick okay so
sometimes you overshoot then you have to
move back uh you know things like that
so you've got two buttons here
left click and right click
and again just like every every other
module if you hold the modifier key then
the function as a scroll okay so let's
let's uh
Okay so
so anyway so that's the track point
click okay
so track more track point so let's uh so
I want to use the trackball so let's put
the trackball here
okay so you can you know right thumb is
treble and the left thumb is the scroll
wheel and also you have left click and
right click here so they are duplicated
duplicated and you can program them to
do anything else so let's see let me
show you about that okay
so I want to show
oh yeah and the display also you can see
you know this display they you they can
display any any letters or numbers you
want so let's switch to Quality so you
can see qwr is for Quality then I have
SAR key map uh then you have the quality
for mag by default they have quality for
PC for Mac comac for PC for mac and
volac for PC for Mac so by default they
come with six key maps already
programmed but you can program anything
you want you can program this so I want
to go to
xsa
so also when you hold down function key
so you can see so let me hold on you see
the function light shows up you can you
can see if I hold down
function you see the tiny function like
so also if you hold down modifier that
we also light up okay so you see mod
and if you turn on if you switch on the
software if you
open the software let's see ultimate
hacking agent uhk agent uh
then
then okay so
so I got a problem here because right
now I have two ultimate hacking keyboard
plugin you see I got uh God
so you got so I got the ultimate hacking
keyboard one automatic hacking keyboard
two I got two of them plugged in so that
means
the the software can only do one at a
time so let me unplug the
the first one
so the ultimate hacking version one
unplug okay
so now
now let me show you the software
ultimate hacking agent
so you can see this is the
this is the software okay so
um
so here's the software and this software
is also open source it's on GitHub and
this is the best of them all so I've you
know I have so many ergonomic keyboards
fancy ergonomic keyboard this is the
best of them all I would say Okay of all
the programmable keyboards
software this is the best of them all
the most easy to use okay you you I
never read any manual you don't have to
read you know you just open it
and you know what you can program the
key to do anything you want okay so so
now let me try let me show you a feature
okay so let me see for example you just
click this key and and you can program
let's see can you see it yeah so you can
program any key you want letter keys or
number keys or punctuation or interspace
tab or Escape access backscape insert
you know and so on and function keys F1
to f24 or page of page down arrow keys
or multimedia Keys anything so you can
say I want this key to be pause then
it's pause then you just click the remap
and your
set the key to the firmware so the
keyboard has 32k memory building so it's
great so once you program it programmed
it you don't need
you know you don't need to have the
software running all the time unlike the
gaming keyboards many of the gaming
keyboards especially made by you know
that
um
snake brand you know three snakes uh
what's the name you know they require
you you to have the internet connection
and so so anyway 32
kilobytes of memory building so
everything you program is within the
keyboard so you can just unplug it and
put in a bag and go to work or go to
anywhere and re-plug it and you have all
your keyboard markers so let me show you
some of the layers so for example right
now so you know
so you have three so you have I have
three key maps I deleted the default you
know by default you also have a quote
Mac to call Mac for one for PC one for
Mac I deleted them you don't need them
so I don't need them so you right now I
have three uh
keymats in you know for gamers that
means profile so it's a set of set of
settings so three key maps so for the
key map for example let's change the
name
let's say XXX okay so you can see I
change that to x axis so watch uh look
at the uh
look at the word here okay so I go back
here and I click this button save to
keyboard
okay then it revert to qwr Quality
because that's the default you can you
can make the default do
to be any key map you want but now I
swap I switch to
my layout now you you can see it says
XXX
triple X fantastic
so this is my key map so let's see so
let me show you one feature okay so one
of the features is that you can set it
any of this key can be dual function so
that means one of the key for example
spacebar can be both space key and
control key so when you hold this key
and press another key that key becomes
control
so you don't have to go you know move
your hand to the to the side to press
Ctrl or Windows key or the old key or
the Mac command key
you can just hold space and press on the
key and this so This is called Dual
Purpose key okay and and this
functionality can be programmed on any
of this key so
one of the things people do is that you
can make your home row Keys you know AS
ASDF
jkl
semicolon you get you can make your own
home row keys to become modifier Keys
dual function so let's let's do that
okay so let's say I want the d
I want the d here to be also shift okay
so when I hold down this key and press
another key it becomes shift so let me
show you how to do that okay so I'm
using a variac layout so let's go back
here
so I mean so I all I have to do is click
this one and right now it says e I'm
using a verac layout so you can see
secondary row let's say I want okay so
click on that let's say left shift
okay
okay now let's say let's click remap key
then now let's say
save to keyboard okay done now if I go
to
okay now if I go to emacs
so
now watch my okay so watch my
so I'm gonna press this key and see if
you can see it I'm gonna press this key
then let's say I press this key okay so
that will enter a capital D okay
so hold it down it becomes shift and
press that D you can see
oh uh can you see it here there it is so
let me try again
okay so let me do that again so
hold down this key and press that so you
can you can see it's all capital letters
now
so that key becomes shift can you see it
yes
okay so do a function so you can also
make that key you know you can make any
other key to be control or old or things
like that so this is uh
you know this is quite useful Dual
Purpose keys
any questions and comments what keyboard
do you prefer uh what keyboard do you
prefer ultimate hacking keyboard version
2 or girl of 80. well for that question
I would prefer glove 80. now this is
personal okay
well because girl of 80 you know it's
got curved and uh that's why I prefer it
and also it's because
it's got you know in this in my case I
got a special
key switch that's 35 grams this is
lighter than this one so I'm I need to
have it lighter so anyway the point
about here is that you know different
preferences so I was you know this
ultimate hacking keyboard
could be
I could use for my main I wouldn't you
know I would not have a problem
this can be my main okay now the only
thing I do not like about this this is
this is one of those 60 keyboard
okay let's go back here so this is one
of those 60 keyboard meaning that it
only got 60 something Keys okay now the
the glove 80 so let me show you the girl
of 80. so you see the girl of 80s got uh
80 keys also you know 20 more keys
and it's it you know and it's more
ergonomic so if you ask you know so
if you ask me you know this one you know
you you also have to consider price this
one is like close to 400 this one too
the uh 300 something fairly expensive if
especially if you add those okay
so anyway I I
right now this is my man but you know
there are many other issues for example
this one is Bluetooth
but in general I want wired I want wired
keyboard for my desktop okay I also need
Bluetooth when I'm away when I'm you
know lying in bed because I'm using a
Surface tablet you know you don't have
many plugs you only have one USB so you
don't want to plug and unplug every
every hour because I take that tablet I
walk around so I need a Bluetooth so
this would be perfect you know but I
only have one of these so anyway so it
depends on you if you have to go a lot
you know go to work you want Bluetooth
for my desktop I I want wired okay so I
would
rather want wired but you know but that
one is
you know curved in you know many other
details
so anything uh so let's see anything
else
so uh let's see anything else yeah let
me show you the feet okay
so let me so they got this
feed
this I mean not feed the wrist pad the
high quality respect the wrist pad
together is almost as heavy as a
keyboard so I I did a unbox the other
day about two weeks ago so here is the
very high quality luxurious Deluxe
wooden
piece pad okay and it's extremely easy
to attach
okay let me show you
wait where did my uh
where's the screws oh here okay so
without screws I cannot attach them
so let me attach them I don't use I
don't like in general you know
personally I don't use respect because I
think the best risk is bad Towers okay
this is you know bath Towers two dollars
each and you can third you know you can
throw them in your washer and wash it
and it's the most comfortable thick you
know that is like these you know the
most comfortable you can have you know
you can have them higher however you
want as opposed to this and also it's a
good I believe you know I'm pretty sure
you know I it's a good
typing practice that you don't rest your
wrist on the wrist pad okay you should
leave them when you type a lot when you
start to type a lot for an hour you
so anyway let me let me let me show you
so this but this is this is the most
high quality thing okay so let me attach
it very extremely easy to attach no
screwdriver needed okay so let me show
you
uh and so you got this four screwdrivers
okay so you can see you just
okay so you just
twist it you know they got this flip you
can just twist it in and flip them okay
so let's attach it
okay in order to attach I need to remove
this feed twist and lift off okay then
you have this and then you just position
them here
I need to wear my glasses because I'm
getting old so I need my reading glasses
in order to see
uh wait is this the left hand or right
hand
oh yeah so this is the left hand okay so
you you put them there yeah
now you you know because
the problem I have now is that if I
I might press some Key by accident
accident
then I'm going to
screw up my video
sorry so anyway so you you
yeah okay should I turn off the keyboard
now there's no
okay so let's just try this hopefully I
didn't press any key
okay
so now you just twist it in
fantastic
okay one more screw
done
so done fantastic so you see solid
so yeah you know then you just flip it
down
there it is then you reattach the feet
now you before it was here now you are
just attach it there
so let's
all you can take out the feet if you
want if you want it flat
so push it in twist there it is okay
there it is
now you've got you got
you know these solid wooden
wrist pad okay
fantastic okay and and you can attach
the other side so I think that's it uh
let's see what else I want to review
so I talked about display and
programmability of the keyboard
Beauty so yeah okay so that's it for the
review anything else any comments any
questions that would be it we close down
in one minute
okay so before we go let me show you my
website so you can see you know we the
review you know I have everything on my
website just search for Sally keyboard
so you can see you know all the photos
and detailed explanations if you like my
videos pay me okay uh
you know the great photos and you can
see all the keyboard you know many of
the keyboard we we I showed you today
any any anything else any comments okay
so
thank you
okay we shutting down let's see what
else anything else
we shut down
let's see
okay let me take off the
let me take off the wrist pads since I
don't use it
so
twist the feet and lift it
first of all first step is Twist the
feet and lift the feet
then unscrew
so they you know they they send me the
ultimate hacking keyboard as a gift
but otherwise this video is not
sponsored so this is my own opinion so
like I said before I could use this
keyboard as my main but I have so many
keyboards so you know
okay the feed is back fantastic
thank you guys for watching bye guys
okay