hello guys good morning welcome to
another episode of K talk show K talk
show K talk
show how are you guys so we are going to
code emac L today and maybe random okay
I've got so many things to do so
many so many things to do so chat okay
chat and give give me money okay PayPal
and
patreon okay so many things to do so
shall we begin with uh emac L coding
directly or shall we like talk random
because I got so many topics you know
the SVG you know so onar Discord we have
a lot of discussions
about CSS pixel what does a pixel mean
you know it's not what you think it
means you know the definition of a pixel
and SVG versus canvas and and and lots
of things and a fantastic Indian movie
okay I've been listening to it for for 3
hours yesterday and research this is
Hindi language can you see
it you see so this movie okay fantastic
this CL clip I've been listening to it
for three hours so anyway let's begin
coding emac list shall we uh okay yeah
because usually you know
when uh let's start emac list okay uh on
my emac list on my emac blog there's a
lot updates you can go read it okay Kasa
emac blog so you see usually I'm doing
live stream because it's something for
me it's not just entertainment for you
guys but something actually I need to do
for working on my website so lots of
commands I need to do uh what I want to
do is write a command that moves a file
in a website to another okay basically
this is what I want to
do okay
so uh okay so let's so I'm using soft
flag keys if you don't know uh let me
show you quickly s FL Keys here's a
source code 4,000 lines of code go to
the top and uh here's a URL open it
showing browser emac Sly Keys it's a
model key binding system for emx and you
can read the details you can learn
there's a dedicated video and uh and
what does it mean keybinding system like
this okay so basically you don't have to
press control or meta or all keys
anymore most most of the time 90% 99% of
those keys you don't have to press
anymore that's s like keys and on the
pink window you can see all my emac
command Calles and uh you see as I as I
type them all the emac command course
and the keystrokes okay command names on
the right keystrokes on the left I'm
using aora keyboard of course if you go
to my keyboard website s keyboard blog
and you go
to
there layout there it
is keyboard layout design ergonomic
keyboard layout so you can see all the
possible keyboard layout all the
efficient quy warak KAC comac DH Workman
okay so I am using the vorak you can see
the heat map and you can see the quality
is
sucks okay so so are we ready to code
ready Sly keys okay close close ready to
code today's talk show page let's see
what you guys are saying oh Bey
Beaver six hello hello hello hello hello
okay hello okay let's begin so I want to
for
example uh let me show you so you go
to okay let me let me let me show you my
stuff
okay JavaScript uh what's what's going
on
yeah oh I did I press a key by mistake
what is this okay so I'm in a browser
JavaScript in
depth okay that's the best JavaScript
tutorial ever in English language
doesn't matter it's a printed book or
not okay JavaScript in depth so in this
directory so let's go to it JavaScript
okay so you can see this directory has 9
,900 files so they include they include
my blocks web D blocks they include CSS
files for example let's open it okay
this is Javascript code CSS SPX sizing
so box sizing is one of the CSS stuff so
anyway in this directory you have CSS
you
have you have JavaScript you have HTML 5
for example HTML 5 video audio tutorial
this is how you can embed a video or
audio in um file in
your in your uh in HTML page you know I
noticed recently Firefox is having
problem playing
some video files okay it shows finally
it's stuck yeah fire fire Firefox
recently in the past month or so start
started to have this
problem it's stuck but anyway okay
digression so let let's show this in
okay so there it is let's see let's try
it again yeah okay now it's
smooth okay anyway so in this directory
you have CSS tutorials you have HTML
tutorials then you have JavaScript
tutorials let's open one of them showing
browser this is Javascript map object
which is essentially a hash table or
python dictionary it's different from
object okay it's different from object
it's new since about 200 15 because it's
different from the object object because
the object object it's a key value
pair collection of however it's not a
good one because Javas script suck so
badly because you cannot get the number
of items you know how sucky is it is
when you have a hash table or a
dictionary and you cannot get the number
of items and if you made a mistake it
goes to the parent object you know
inheritance you know it search search a
key in in your parent chain so idiotic
therefore JavaScript in 2015 have the
map object it's new so anyway that's an
example so now go back to the directory
so you have CSS tutorial you have HTML
tutorial you have JavaScript tutorial
All in One Directory okay
because this directory is created
sometimes like almost 15 years ago 15
years ago okay let's go toar JavaScript
blog okay
open web dev blog and let's go to web de
blog I archive and go to all the way to
the bottom so this blog began in
2010 this this dedicated URL began in 20
but actually my my webd blog began you
know begins you know in in my other
blogs you know after a few years I
separate them to into specific topics so
2010 is the year I began this
dedicated blog that's all blogging
related to CSS HTML JavaScript okay and
also web browsers you know web browser
change and Google Shenanigans like
Google search issues they censorship and
basically all related on web stuff okay
so this is s web dev
blog okay and recently we have you know
howar is a CSS pixel very complicated
that's a different topic anyway back to
my topic so I was saying you know when
you do a website you know over 10 years
over 20 years that's a very interesting
question it's a very interesting
phenomenon by the way you know most of
you guys are young guys you know maybe
10 maybe 20 something maybe in college
and maybe you are thinking of blogging
you know then all of a sudden you became
a old fought like me I've been blogging
for 25 25 years technically speaking
1997 that's when I began okay okay let
me just talk you know so this my
earliest first project is this
mathematics this is cited by over a
thousand University math departments
okay on curves you know important when
you study calculus and be Beyond anyway
so this is my first project in
1997 1997 okay CSS is not invented yet
1997 there's no C
CSS and there's barely JavaScript
JavaScript just began nobody is going to
use it because it's idiotic considered
by programmers it's for non programmers
to do something pretty you know anyway
so 19 1997 that's when I began writing
blog okay or or you know blog is not a
word at that time the word blog became
invented in
I don't know 2000 after 2000 after year
2000 okay so
anyway so I'm you I'm old
so the thing interesting about blogging
is that when you get old you know after
10 years 20 years you have like a
thousand blog entries you know you you
can see what happens in the world or
what happens to you depending on your
nature the nature of your blog what kind
of things you blog about you block about
your personal stuff your personal views
or you block about programming languages
or mathematics mathematics never change
okay all these are still good all this
the mathematics doesn't change you know
for example hyper hyperbola but of
course they got replaced by
Wikipedia Wikipedia began around 2002
okay and they saw your nice information
that doesn't exist anywhere 2002 okay
they copy it they rephrase it they put
you know let's let's go to conic section
okay conic section the
most uh well-known kind of thing in in
calculus in algebra in in in you know if
you are a colleges college student or
High School Stu high school student you
study uh what they call it analytic
geometry uh anyway yeah analy anyway
this belongs to analytic geometry or
anyway so so Wikipedia they copy part of
your information they'll rephrase it and
at the bottom they'll say reference you
know but usually typically after five
years that's gone because people addit
addit you know people come and go you
know your arranging you know five years
ago you know they got information from
you but after so many edit you know
basically your link get removed that's
what happened in fact the my first
awareness of the Wikipedia thing there's
exist some thing called Wikipedia
started by this guy lots of controversy
my first aware I first became aware of
the Wikipedia is around 2003 because
they linked to my conic sections page
this page you know with a reference you
know you know
information you know reference from Sali
that's that's my first um awareness of
Wikipedia but anyway
so so if you blog you know then if you
continue most people don't continue okay
don't think about you're going to blog
and you're gonna make money and also
you're not going to make a dime okay you
you'll make a dollar or two1 dollar a
month a dollar uh a week me all all a
day
okay anyway so after many you know 10
years 20 years of blogging you have so
many thousand Pages you can have kind of
look back and lots of links are dead and
you can see kind
of your evolution of your thinking or or
even a document
documentation of what happened on the
internet for the past 20 years which I
kind of have okay so anyway
my yeah so I'm okay I'm not going to
show it because otherwise we're going to
talk about this nonstop okay so let's
see
so let's go back to code iMac Le okay so
I was saying that so when you block you
have files in a directory and after you
know after 10 years 20 years they
become you
know they are not as structured as you
used think because things come and go
new ideas new CPU new operating system
and you might have changed from Mac to
Windows due to many reasons or Linux and
change back and so on and maybe you lost
your drive and so the file structure and
you got more topic to add you know in
the beginning maybe you are blogging
JavaScript then you started to blog some
CSS and you know so your direct
directory structure is not going to be
very nice you know that's why for almost
all major corporation website you
usually you often you have dead links
dead dead links you know because they
they have to reorganize their their
directory structure you know put you
know proper you know and the Personnel
the programmer come and go you know you
you got fired they hired new people or
things like that or you quit so lots and
companies got bought out
and you know so lots of change so
basically what I'm what I want to do is
that in this directory JavaScript
directory which contains CSS and HTML
and JavaScript I want
to okay let's go up to the Parent
Directory I want to create a new
directory okay so here is a c JavaScript
directory I want to create let's say CSS
okay so create a new directory and let's
go back to the JavaScript
directory I want to
move okay I want to move all these CSS
files into this CSS directory so
separate them reorganize them you cannot
simply move them okay because for
example let's let's show this example
CSS 2D transformation showing
browser okay so CSS this this is kind of
by by now it's old this is like new in
2013 okay so you can actually GE do
geometric transformation of text or
images okay so this is a tutorial right
now let's say I want to let's say I move
this file move in emac diet very
convenient okay so now I moved into this
directory open it show browser okay now
but all your links are now you
see now you see the panel okay I want to
check how do you change color color
syntax click file not found okay so you
cannot simply just move it you have to
CH you have you move it you have to
change all your links inside this HTML
all of them
okay and that's not okay and all other
files that links to this
page the link are also broken so you
also need to you you need to go to your
entire directory structure find all
links that links to this particular
directory file and move it and and and
and and change the link in each one of
them so change all the links
so here summary of what you need to do
okay this seems trivial you know if you
never coded this as a programmer usually
you
underestimate the the humongous of the
task you know you might say oh it's one
hour actually I did this in
2010 or
2011 I separated Kali org kali.org into
kinfo and several other
domains and so I need to do this and I
end end up spending one month actually
more than a month to write a script to
to do this to to to separate these
domains you know and I started to move
them and after 10 years around
2020 I move moved all of them my
different domains back into just two now
kali.org and.info
okay this is my main page Sali or
kali.org
and then kali. info okay now I only I
just these two are my main domains so
you see I used to have a wordy English
domain Anda Arts C music domaina Visual
Arts and second life you know different
domains I move them all back so now it's
just k.org
and.info kinfo is technical stuff
mathematics emac programming JavaScript
other programming languages and so on
Technical and unic
code okay and uh and keyboard and or is
a bunch of other things non technical
Humanity songs and music English grammar
style literature you know comments
thoughts uh Arts okay let's open each
one of them in Second Life explore
coration and politics okay I'm not
showing here I'm not going to show it
but anyway there is that too so here's
wordy English it's literature vocabulary
and all that style logic
Linguistics and uh here is collection of
songs
you the anthropology and ethology and
ethn e the anthropology and ethology and
ethnology and
sexuality you look into them
via the music the songs that human sings
about you know there's a lot to look
into that a lot you know you look at in
fact you look at the songs of let's say
different culture you know most of you
guys are American of course we speak
English but you can but but you can look
at Chinese or Russian songs but let's
say just English maybe pop songs or
maybe may it be blue jazz or whatever
you can look at you know you look at the
lyrics you look at what are they singing
what are they saying what kind of thing
what are they saying over the past 100
years over the past 200 years over the
past 500 years or a thousand years you
look at what they seeing you know that's
part of humanity you know so that's
that's the my blog
okay uh so it has so far about 460 songs
of all kind of All
Sorts uh and and there's Arts okay arts
in humanity from
today's from today's memes you know the
Zuma memes
[Music]
edsc which are these you know the the
most beautiful is a Duma girl okay
anyway these are memes okay memes in the
past about 20 years and this is the most
idiotic this is today today's Zuma
okay the most idiotic is this
today's Zuma thing this what Jack or
whatever Jack you
know and before that is the uh is the
Rage Comic that's much better it's it's
much better okay today is is just like
de brainless you know today you got this
into this situation this you got this
brainless
things Rage Comic actually has some you
know contains information cultural
information reflect the thoughts and so
on you know Rage Comic anyway so anyway
what I'm saying is that so these are you
know in the past 20 years the art of the
past 20 years but of course then you can
go to Asian stuff you know these are
Asian classic Western this is Western
okay remember it's western western is
not the entire Earth okay to the most
American they think it's the ENT entire
Earth but then even more Asian the Greek
stuff the Greek stuff the Greek stuff is
the best stuff I love
them okay anyway that's a lot of
digression so what what I was saying was
that you know so let's get back to the
main topic okay so I have cad.org
and.info that's my main thing okay so I
was talking
about you know I need to move
directories so I mean I need to
reorganize my directory structure so you
cannot simply just move the file you
have to do two things okay one is that
you do move the file
and change all the link all the links
within this file because otherwise they
don't work okay so you have to change
all the links in this file now what does
a link mean well typically it's the you
know a HF but that's not all okay you
know when you actually do this a lot
complexities for example here's a CSS
file so it's the tag is not anchor is
not a so you have to also do that and
you also to have to do uh let's see do I
have a image no but I do have it here
okay so the link doesn't
work but so anyway so you also have to
change image embedded image you know so
quite a few so you need to change all
links in this P page that you are moving
that's one thing the second thing is
that you need to go through your entire
uh domain okay so let's show you let's
see so we are in power Shell let's show
some power shell okay magnify so
the okay so uh okay magnify you need
to you know this is a characteristic of
power shell I don't like that it it it
kind of truncate
your long lines so anyway so the
recursive file and let's limit it to
HTML filter okay that ending
HTML
so you see it's endless it's about so
let's see
measure let's see how many files 8,000
files in
cinfo 8,000 h HTML files of course you
have JPEG files 5,000 JPEG files you
have PNG
files okay also 5,000 PNG files oh and
uh you also you might have JP EEG
depending on the spelling you know let's
see I have zero because I normalized all
the jpeg file names into just jpg not
you know but you also have you know I
started to
use web P files so I have eight web P
files
anyway so back to the original topic so
I was talking
about why do I need to restructure the
directory and what does it involve so
you have to go
through all files in your
directory that links to the file that
you are moving and for each of the link
you have to change them okay so this is
not a trivial task now this task is
belongs to the category the field of
text
processing and emac is the best tool not
Pearl not python not whatever emac if
you are going to do emac I mean if you
are going to do text processing emac is
FAS Superior than all the others Pearl
python bash power shell okay because
emac has the buffer concept which allows
you to you know which a buffer is kind
of like
a
glorified
string okay so in this huge giant string
it can be one
megabyte long you
know you can you you have the concept of
a CER which is is like the current index
of your position you can get a position
you can copy part of the string move
part of the string to other part you
know that's what buffer is and you can
manipulate it programate
programmatically this is this is emac
disp okay no other language is better
than this for text processing not even
go land not even not anything okay not
even not wolam language neither if you
want to do text
processing emac list is the best
language okay this is a kind of
information few people know not not
rightly
um no okay so anyway back to this so we
are going to write this command let's
look at the commment and let's see what
what what you guys are saying any
questions
so hey S I don't have bucks to spend 200
ergonomic keyboard so I'm stuck with
Island switch laptop keyboard to make it
more comfortable to type I've moved
standard positions keys on Roll upward
that's no good okay that's no good you
don't have money you know go out run buy
a $40 China Cheapo mechanical keyboard
right now you know you going to
you typing on laptop you're going to
have you're going to become a
within a year if you type too much and
you know you are like me I did this for
10 years so you are thinking okay I
don't have money to spend for even $40 I
I don't have but I'm just going to
create a way I'm very creative I'm going
to spend 100 hours you know to to to
change this coding you know to to remap
keys no that's no good okay you spend
huge amount of time and it do does it
does you no good it doesn't help much it
help like maybe
1% go out run buy the cheapest Chinese
chipot like $30 you can buy it I'm sure
you have $30 okay just do that okay do
not you know do not you know do do this
you know like move your standard
position you know that's crap
the first thing you need to do if you
are concerned about ergonomic or if you
have hand pen okay the first thing after
that then use S flag keys I mean well
yes or evil mod if you want
that okay s so you have a question this
also allows me to pump press control key
but I I still think how how should I
configure modifier Keys okay forget
about that it's very complex I myself
I'm the master okay I'm the master of
the key binding the ergonomic of key
binding all those information but I can
tell you like after 20 years the first
most important thing is you go out
immediately you don't have money okay do
it right now go out immediately spend
$30 on Amazon or wherever you are in
Europe you know buy the Chinese Cheapo
the Chinese now they are massive they
they massively produce the cheapest
thing and actually you you won't break
okay just go out buy a Chinese chipo $30
you want mechanical key switches okay
and you want linear switch no blue not
the blue clicky switch not the brown you
know go to Amazon right
away okay s keyboard board okay s
keyboard you click on the normal
keyboard section these are all expensive
okay you can buy this
one okay you want a linear switch okay
okay this key is kind of more expensive
like $70 or even up to 150 they are kind
you
know you can buy it you know it's I can
recommend it's not bad but just buy a
cheapo okay if you don't have money this
one is actually uh $50 or something H
Amazon fmrg LX okay let's
um okay so this one is 60 yeah maybe a
bit expensive but there are tons okay
you see there are tons you know you just
like this 25 25 bucks 28 works okay make
sure you get you know me real mechanical
switch and linear okay
so that's the first thing you need to do
I'm talking a lot about this because
it's the most important after my 20
years experience okay don't forget about
your I'm going to change control this
that forget that about that just do this
okay now the second
thing is just use Sly Keys okay that's
also important so you don't you don't
actually have to press control at all oh
I have thought about this I've been I've
been like changing my key every week
every week like Change Control to this
or swap you know change the position of
control and caps lock or control and all
which one is better on Windows what
happens if you do this on window on the
Mac what if you want a universal way so
it works both on Windows and and Linux
okay so first thing to do go out
buy a mechanical keyboard if you don't
have money buy the cheap one if you have
money buy the one I have I recommend it
many times
okay like uh like the you know
the uh okay I can recommend glove 0 this
is my favorite okay Glo 80 and uh K KES
360 I'm using right now and also the
ultimate hacking I'm currently using as
a marro it's fantastic and Al I can
recommend the expose s
okay if you have money buy this okay if
you don't buy the Chinese chipo okay
that's first thing after that then two
things then then you need to do one
thing switch to Stu like ke if you are
using emac or or use the Vim Evo mod
okay so that that's your question that
is my answer to that
question now I'm absolute okay listen my
advice is not okay you know what you are
doing is pretty good but maybe you can
also do this no that's not my answer my
answer is that stop that okay
that's wasting your time and that's not
going to help you at all and don't think
about oh I'm just going to switch to vak
vak is more efficient I'm going to
switch to coac it's even more efficient
than crap
okay go out buy a mechanical chip when
mechanical switch linear light switch
first thing the second
thing
is stop using Control Alt you know that
those keys okay and that you can do on
emac use Sly keys or you can try the Evo
mod you know of course I recommend sof
Keys uh but you know know Evo mod is
also
okay another thing is is that you can
turn on sticky keys okay I have all this
information on my website on on the you
know on on how to on touch typing issues
um uh typing issues also on software
issues what software can you switch keys
in on the Mac on the windows on Linux
and the entire you know tens of articles
on emac key reming how do you do that
and so on but
anyway anyway
so uh okay so I digress so much are we
still going to code emac this I hope so
let's
see laptop keyboard is the worst okay
that's the worst that's what got me RI
back in 2005 I have full documentation
detail details in my blog just search
for S RSI you know you will find a 10 uh
more than 10 articles about
it so that's the my answer to Rusty okay
next Jen how are you uh long time uh
audience can I find a job after reading
every word of JavaScript in depth yes of
course you will JavaScript is a one of
the most popular language are you in
China J I think you are in China yes
you'll find a job for
sure what makes emac special okay I'm
going to skip that question because
that's just that's just uh too that's
too frequently Asked question
okay another question why don't you like
multi-display workflow
H I have article on that did you did you
read the article and then you have the
question or are you just asking out of
the blue
because uh I want to go back to code
okay because we already talked for 50
minutes something like that already 40
minutes and we haven't start coding yet
okay let's let's go back let's start
coding okay you guys you like my stuff
pay me okay PayPal or
patreon ch ch thank you Ben thank you
Ben
fantastic any questions you have
Ben so let's go let's let's start to
work on uh work on
um coding emx because that's what I want
to do so let's move this back
okay okay
so so coding on emx oh my
God okay
so what was the page we are talking
about make
sure
okay so we just move
that transformation yeah so we are
talking about CSS
transformation not SVG
transformation so CS transformation make
sure yeah it's back you see
now now all the link
works okay my CSS tutorial you can also
read it visual CSS
okay
so okay so let's start to code
this good to see you hope you are doing
well and yeah thank you you must be a
old reader of me so you know my history
thank
you uh so
okay now uh you need to uh change of
mindset so now we're going to start to
code okay so remove this so what is this
keyboard blog close web dat blog
okay close close JavaScript map object
tutorial okay
so HTML video okay
so I don't want want close that close
that so okay back to talk show so back
to
code okay let's just write it
out
suppose you need to move the
file named x.
HTML
to let's say
why okay let's say we are not changing
the file name so you are just moving a
file to a different
directory and of course you need to make
sure the file doesn't already exist in
the new directory you want to move to so
lots of details lots
of if you make a mistake when doing this
kind of move you screw up your site okay
you might have deleted some files so
when you do this is your you of course
you want the backup first and and get
commit and things like that
so two things you need to do uh change
all links in the file x.
HTML okay so
that so they still
work
okay
to
go through all
files in your
domain check every
file that has link to x.
HTML change all the links okay that's
the two things you need to
do okay so you know this this will take
more than one hour but let me just code
the outline how do you do this like
General okay General concept how many
people are watching am I doing good am I
still good
seven okay so let me tell you what to do
okay so uh let's let's just try one of
these uh 2D
transform
so okay
so so hold on a second I want to wait
let's just do it okay so yeah 2D
transform refresh copy the path back to
emac so let's
say let's say I want to move this file
okay let's do a demo let's complete just
moving one page because usually when you
want to move like you have several you
know I want to move all these you know
CSS files to a new
directory so but I'm just going to code
so it works for one file then you know
you can work out the details later so
close that so what I want to do is okay
so suppose this is you know this is a
file you need to move okay and uh okay
so let's suppose let's just be
exact okay we want to move uh not
that we want to move this file
path to the
the
Okay so
so how so what so how do you do so first
of all so of course we need to change
all links in the file
okay so you so how do you change the
link
okay for
example uh find
all HTML Tex that contains
a
link examples okay that's one
example okay another
example
uh okay uh we don't need the rest of it
okay that's another example
HF okay another example let's
say you know sometimes they don't have
dot dot and sometimes they have this
form and sometimes they have you know
fairly fairly complex when you actually
do this for example sometimes they have
this form okay let me just write it
out
okay so here are some of the examples of
variations and also images okay so
actually this file doesn't contain any
image so let's try another file with a
image so we can
illustrate uh CSS
selectors uh color Okay so let's find a
page that contains image okay so Box
model border outline margin and padding
box
sizing box Shadow layout okay so we have
let's let's see this one okay this one
is a tutorial on how do
you uh overlay text over image so you
see this this is text and the background
is image so let's copy that
open
it search for image so for example here
is the image tag image tag contains link
to a image you see so you so here is
another example of
a a link to you need to
check and this is not all you see so
when you actually do this it's fairly
complex fairly complex oh my God and
also when
you when you actually trying to find
what's the full path of these of one of
these links it's very very very complex
you have you know you have the relative
link relative path then you have full
path then you have domain
path very complex okay um and the domain
path some of them point to your own
website for example this one so I can
open it showing browser you see that's a
emac
command and but you know so so the file
path for this is
actually this okay correspond to that
file path so so anyway so
so so okay let's let's narrow down the
analysis okay so first of all is all the
different HTML tag
that contains a link reference okay so
and these are examples uh the second
example for each link path there are
many variations for example so let's so
this is actually we want to do them
here
okay so these are examples of the
variations of the file path
itself God we going to this is going to
be
endless so there's a question from Ben
good to see you uh Ben says it seems you
don't use the Palm rests with the glove
0 very often any reason yeah I I thought
I told I spoke about reasons many times
because you know did you watch my video
for glove 0 review so if you go to my
glove 0 keyboard review page you know I
have full detailed reviews and photos
and there's a video one hour
alone about the whole thing thing and
there's like five minutes of it talking
about Palm rest in general I don't use
Palm rest okay it's not good that you
rest your palm when you actually need to
type a lot like for example when you
need to type continuously for let's say
5 minutes or more you don't you do not
rest your pal on the pal rest doesn't
matter how good it
is you you you want to you know lift
your palm up like vertical and hit the
keys like a hammer like the way you do
playing piano okay
that's that is
a kind of common touch typing advice
okay do not rest your pal on the pal
rest you know if you're just going to
type a sloppy maybe you are tired that's
fine but in my in my past you know 10
years
experience when you actually need to
start to typee a lot like like for
example writing a blog or code you know
do not rest on the pal rest because in
the past 10 years my experience
experience sometimes in argument with
people online you know I too lazy to
raise my palm and after 30 minutes not
it's not feeling good okay so that is uh
why okay so let's go back to coding okay
uh so how do you solve this issue so we
have we we have outlined some of the
issues about changing link so I have
discovered one of the best way is that
to change the link first of all
um oh my God this is tedious this is I'm
not sure I can finish it in
another
you know it will need at least 30 more
minutes because okay so so I'm G to go
as far as we can okay let me just
quickly so the first thing you need to
solve you know remember the first thing
we need to solve is to change all links
in that file okay and we have all these
different TXS for link and and for the
file path we have all this very
Creations so the easiest way to
normalize all these different links is
first of all by changing name or to file
path so you don't want this you don't
want this fully qualified domain if you
see that you have to write a command to
check if that domain name is your own
website if it is then change this path
to the actual file path for example open
that that is this
page copy the file path you can see
that's a command name close it paste the
file path here make common so when you
see this you want to have a command that
change them all to the full file path so
all of these becomes full file path that
is when it becomes very easy for you to
compare if two links are pointing to the
same file because otherwise you know all
these index actually may be different
files depending on which of the
link they are embedded in which file and
and depending on that file directory so
each of these even the same name they
don't they don't they don't point to the
same file so the first job is that you
want to convert all these variations of
path or URL in into a actual file path
okay and in order to do that you have to
deal with uh relative links so you need
to know you know you get a file path you
know the value of hrf then you need to
know the
directory this link of the file is
located so you have to resolve the
relative link to a full path
okay so anyway let me Demo a command so
I already you know like I said I already
wrote this command 10 years ago now I
just need to uh rewrite them so let me
show you okay so for
example for example showing browser you
know CSS 2D transformation so at the at
the bottom you'll see a lot of links and
those are here okay
so so you want to so how do you convert
them to for example I already have a
command so let me show you
okay uh this block okay so let's
try control w
h okay uh wait control WT you see each
of these relative link becomes
this this another complex this is not
exactly a file path this is a full file
path of in h in url
format you see you have the file colon
slash slash slash triple slash and you
have the drive letter this format is
this is a URL format and and that format
is actually what the
browser uh the browser URL field shows
okay so but anyway this is kind of like
a full path okay so so that command I
just called is uh
um let's see where is
it there it is HTML local links to full
path
okay and I have another command that
turns a full path like that back into
relative path so let me do it so the key
is tap w h you see now they are back to
um relative path let me show you the
complexity okay so for example let's
copy this
one so you see this one is a relative
path but however you can make it into a
domain so let me show
you you see these two are actually
equivalent because you know equivalent
as far as user is concerned let me show
you you see if I click that it just go
to my
website so what I'm talking uh so yeah
so let's try the command
to turn them into relative links okay so
do that do that and do that you see okay
it skips the domain uh yeah in my case
it skip the domain but anyway so that's
some of the
complexity okay so I think maybe that's
it for today I mean yeah because to
actually code this uh it take an
hour so I lost people okay so seven
people watching it that's about it I
think anything
else
does does my explanation of the Palm
rest work Ben so you know actually I do
have you know if you just search for
Palm
rest uh kadi keyboard
search Palm rest so I I have an article
on best Palm
rest let's open some of them it's
interesting how to PR okay so these are
you know so base pump rest is the tower
okay I have it here can you guys
see you see so let me open
that you see bath
Tower so actually you know it should be
thicker it should be like that
actually so you
see you know I have it like that but one
more fold
because the kesis physic is high so
actually now it's too high but
anyway this is the best pum rest okay
it's cheap bath Towers you know a dollar
or two you buy at Walmart you don't need
the expensive luxury Elite $10 each
ones you know just buy the cheap one and
you can fold it and if it's 30 just
store them to the wash machine
right you know $2 each as opposed to if
you actually buy the Palm rest you know
Palm rest on Amazon they are $5 or $10
they have fancy robust it's not good you
know the the issue with the tower is
that it doesn't look professional that's
the thing you know if so if you at at a
work in the office you probably don't
want this because your coworker is going
to see what the is this
guy but this is actually the most
practical the cheapest the most
comfortable the most fitting the most
efficient and the most
economic okay bath
Tower but even with bath Tower when you
type a lot I recommend you don't don't
rest on it okay don't rest your hand on
the on the palm
rest okay then
uh okay that's it so I bought a can SP
on your review
fantastic oh you're going to switch to
callac DH okay I don't y that's not
bad
uh okay bye guys bye guys coffee and I'm
done today so we did some we we didn't
really do coding but that's okay
because a lot of people you know when
you start to Cod stuff uh a lot of
people you alienate a lot of people CH
thank
you thank you master
Mater okay that's it anything else okay
anything else so let's see so here is
what we talked about we we we B
basically talked
about blogging
personal blog you know what what happens
when you blogged for 20 years you know
or half of your life happen most of my
life and uh the issues when you blog for
a long duration for 20 years the dead
links and change of structure and you
know what happens to other
corporations you know happens to them
all the
time and uh what what is the things you
need to do in order to restructure your
website you know the
issues why two glasses that's also
talked about in the past five videos
okay one is NE cited this one is old old
man's reading glass okay of course I if
I'm not too lazy I should get one you
know nice glass but yeah I need to do
that but I just
I just have not done that yet cuz I'm
kind of lazy all I'm interested is
coding and n and about technology about
mathematics you
know and I also have contact lenses but
contact lenses is not is less
comfortable okay thank you guys
bye