Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Exot Talk Show. We
are going to code F. So what I'm going
to do today is to
uh write F functional programming
language tutorial. Write my tutorial. So
uh it's going to be
exploration.
Um, so I'm going
to, you know, if you want to learn F,
you can, there's a great tutorial, okay?
You can just go to Microsoft F and read
about it. That would be very efficient
way to learn F or I presume there's
quite a few videos teaching F. Okay? So,
if you want a nononsense tutorial, you
can go learn from those resources. But
what I'm going to do is I'm going to do
like several things. I'm going to write
my tutorials in F in Emacs. So you can
learn some you know and chat. Okay. So
you can learn some uh functional
programming, learn something about F and
also about my Emacs workflow. Um how I
write my tutorials and the things like
that randomish. Okay. If you are here,
say hi. Love to see your comments. Post
in the chat. Hi, Sprinkle Night. Spring
night, where are you from? Uh, if you're
not here, watch at 1.5 speed and uh skip
around because I ramble. Okay, so let's
start quickly. So, the F, the most great
thing is about this F tutorial. Okay,
did we? Uh, yeah. So, there it is.
Microsoft, that's the greatest F
tutorial. So, turn on JavaScript.
Refresh. Uh, okay. Not not install.
Okay. I don't want to not install. So,
this
Flearn.microsoft.com that's the best F
tutorial. So, I have I started to write
a little bit. So, you got file name
extension the one of the most important.
You got comments. uh one of the most
important and you
got core string that's most important
okay so let me start to uh work on that
so first of all I want to make a panel
for the rest you know for each one of
these so let's do that
Okay. So, uh what we got? Install file
name, extension, comments, uh uh quote,
string, string
escape. Uh if you want introduction of
my keyboards in every of my live stream,
I have introduction about my keyboards
and my Emac setup. I'm using Sfly keys
and I'm using VA keyboard layout. Okay.
So,
um so first of all, I want to make the C
uh panel. So install file name extension
common string string escape. Okay. So
let's do
that. Okay.
So create a panel. Uh yeah. So that is
the original copy. Make a copy and
linky. Make a list and move all these
list into here.
And uh so F
install file name extension comments and
quote string. Okay.
Um yeah and remove
the
that okay. So we going to replace all
files of that
string replaced
by this new thing. Yeah. something like
that. Okay. So that's
right. Uh not yet. So
overview F.
Um let's see. Comment this. So those
are so something like that in the
beginning. Okay. something like that. Uh
install open. Uh okay. So you got you
got make sure the HTML is correct. Yeah.
Okay.
So find replace that by that of this
directory. All HTML files. Make changes
to files. Yes. Make a backup. Yes. Oh,
nothing. Uh, no
change. There's no change because uh
because I don't have it now.
Okay. Okay. So, let's uh so I need to do
another thing. So, for every
uh here is what I do. Where is the main?
So, this is after main. Okay. So, go to
replace
findreplace.go. So this is a go program.
You can find it here on my website. You
can this is find replace in golan. Okay.
Uh so if you want it just search for
golan golan script to find replace multi
pair of regular expression in directory.
You'll find that script. So but what we
going to do is we're going to use
it. So we going to find okay. So what we
going to do is we going to find all the
men. So
uh these files
uh well we need to find um now let's not
use golan. Let's just use emacs. Okay.
So
call co call co call co call co call co
call find replace
text. Okay. Find
men and what you want to replace by I
want to replace by
men new line. New line and
that. Okay.
[Music]
Uh yeah, there there's some issue that
doesn't let you. Let's just do it. Okay.
Do it.
Okay. So you got several um you got all
these files changed. Showing browser.
Now you got a duplicate here. So delete
that. Showing browser. There it is. So
install file name extension comments
course string string escape. That's
good. And uh then we don't need this.
Okay. So show
Okay. So start at
install. Hello based. Hello Jang. How do
you build your site? Hugo. No.
That is a frequently asked question
which I have answered a thousand times.
I write HTML manually raw since
[Music]
1995. Okay. So in
beginning 1995 I type that that that uh
that then
something then you know, I type it each
tag name slashp
uh then quote that's how I write it in
Microsoft word with some Microsoft
uh shortcuts abbreviation templates you
know so starting in 19 about 1995 I 1996
I write HTML manually in
1998 I started to use
Emacs okay then then use whatever emac
power you know like you you um you have
abbreviation but I didn't use
abbreviation until like uh 200 um 8 or
something so after 10 years I using
Emacs I started to use Emacs a brief
which is one of the most powerful
feature of
Emacs so if you want to know how to use
it there you know just search my
tutorial Emacs a brief
hard. Okay. So, so basically I started
to write HTML rows raw tag by tag every
character by character since
1996. Then in
Emacs since
1998 and ever since I write HTML raw. So
today I have about 10,000 HTML pages on
my website. you can you know 10,000
pages tutorial linguistics philosophy
whatever and how how do I write them
like what I'm doing right now okay so
close close so that's what I'm doing
today writing a
tutorial manually okay and this
way so by now I have so many things I
have
um some HTML mod. Okay, so you know
there's about like
15,000 lines of code. Uh well about
maybe n 9,000 lines of code HTML mod. So
I can so even I write HTML raw but if
you count my keystrokes it's more
efficient then if you use Hugo
or Emacs or mod or whatever okay more
efficient and I got more control as
well. God I closed the window by
mistake. So I you know I uh you can you
know I talked about this in my past live
stream so many times. So hello blue
three. Blue three is a emac list packer
writing a thesis about Emacs list. Do
you use WordPress to build your website?
No. I don't use nothing of that or
Squarespace. Is that a troll? because I
think you know what I'm I do you know so
manually.
Okay. So let's go back to F. So F. So
what um Okay. So let's
um
install. So if you want an introduction
to F and the history of F meta language
or camel uh how it relates to Hascal
watch my previous video about a week ago
or four days ago something. Okay. So one
hour I talked about that. So um you know
to write a tutorial so there's a lot
um you know so so for example I have uh
golan tutorial wrame language emac this
powershell python ruby rubies my ruby is
not very good uh so I'm just showing you
some of the good ones. Okay. So you see
my Python tutorial. You got you know
Python install uh overview Python 2,
Python 3. What's the difference? Source
code encoding. It should be UTF8 or
should it be UTF-16 or whatever uh
depending on the language. Okay. So then
you got help. How do you get help? How
do you print the current version which
is one of the most important common
thing when you learn a new language? may
be PHP, NodeJS, JavaScript. Then know
you always want to know what what is the
current language? What what am I using?
What do I have? You know, so print
version, how do you find the current
version? Uh and then the uh another
thing common in all languages, how do
you find help? You know, in many almost
all languages, you have building help.
Uh for example, Py you know, Python or
man pages, Unix or uh you know or
d-help.
So how do they have built-in help or if
they don't have like interactive uh doc
string for functions how do you you know
sometimes it's website for example for
PHP it's website uh which is very good
because you can always find what do you
need so you know you cover building help
then one one of the most common is how
do you do comments in every language
then you start to get technical that is
uh that is a string string. How do you
code them? How do you create create a
string and how do you deal with unic
code? Then sometimes regular expression,
then you start with arithmetics,
operations, motor, divide. How do you do
uh mod or modulo or remainder of a
diversion or how do you do assignment?
This gets very
complex uh quickly in different
languages because sometimes you can
assign multiple variables at in one shot
and their syntax is kind of different.
Sometimes you have dstructure assignment
uh things like that. So then you know
after the help and common then you start
to have the basic common technical
uh aspect of the language usually that
that are string arithmetics number
boolean boolean type. How do you do if
uh true and false and what what what
does true mean? What expression return
true? You know what express you know
depending on the language. So then you
have conditional if then else or switch
statement or if else expression which is
different from statement then you have
loop then you have started to get really
complex data structures list dictionary
sets sequence type JSON for example in
Python they you know all these are
considered sequence type that's kind of
the Python's quark in lisp you have lisp
quark in wuam language you have the you
know like how do they organize the
different data types you know hasht
dictionary and how do they call it
uh for example hasht sometimes also
known as dictionary or sometimes known
as map uh and sometimes known as key
list uh and sometimes known as
associative list you know in depending
on the language. So then you started to
get into how do you define a function?
How do you define a class? Then the next
level of complexity is module. How do
you write a module? How do you take a
bunch of functions put into a file like
modularization? You know, then then you
got miscellaneous daytime. uh how how to
benchmark, how to how to how to test the
various speed differences between
different constructs because usually
almost always for doing the same thing
you can write different ways like while
loop for loop for each map function you
know so which one is better you know
which one is faster so usually the today
programming languages has a timing uh
library building. So you know so that's
the basic the module and basically
that's it and then regular expression is
part of the string processing then you
have topics like how how do you read and
write a file so these are and unic code
how do you deal with unic code so these
are the
common elements of writing a programming
tutorial okay so uh in this example I'm
showing my Python tutorial similarly for
Ruby but my Ruby tutorial is not very
good. I spent one month to learn it.
It's not very good. Uh so PowerShell so
PowerShell very good. So in PowerShell
in the case of PowerShell you have two
sections. you have how to. So this is
just like how to list directories, how
to list directories of file names of
certain uh file name extension, how to
exit, how to print, how to access
building help, you know, how to do name
completion in
terminal, you know. So you know, so here
is
PowerShell. Uh so for example, CD uh web
then
info then you can you know list these
directories and so on. So you got this
because PowerShell is a shell which is
allows you to have interactive use. So
most of the time you are using it
interactively. So you this list alias
you know powers has the alias concept
then how to navigate directory how to
list directory how to list um this
directories how to uh you know the like
how to show it as a tree how to show
only empty directories how to show
directories with directory size or this
directory only if their content is more
than 10 megabyte things like that then
you have list files how to So you got a
bunch of how to for interactively use of
PowerShell which is special in shell
languages because you don't have that in
in Python in you know you don't do that
in in you know
Python.
Uh but then you got the PowerShell in
depth section. So this section is more
like treating PowerShell like a
programming language like Python. Then
you got the same thing kind kind of
concepts like file name extension, how
to do
comments, what are the different types,
objects and types in the language, how
do you find them? Then how do you deal
with path? Path is in PowerShell is the
critical concept. You know, do you
should you quote with single quote or
double quote? How uh which quote has
file name expansion like implicit
expansion things like that?
So that's PowerShell. Then you got like
how exactly the path expansion works.
For example, you can have dollar sign
embedded variable names or you can have
this t symbol for standing for home. You
can have also dot and dot dot
or wild cards.
So when you look into it, it's somewhat
complicated because you know which one
which kind of expansion goes first. You
know if you want to know the detail and
how do
you see exactly what some what some uh
path expand to. So that's how you uh you
can use this function resolve path.
It'll show you what it actually expand
to. So you got file path issues. Then
you got pipe issues which is a kind of a
special construct in PowerShell. uh
which is similar to in other words you
can view it as a postfix notation of
functional programming okay that's what
this pipe came from in uh from you know
unique shell which came from functional
programming postfix notation I have like
10 articles about that so then then you
got you know like then you got the
things like number how do you input a
binary number then you got the same
thing as arithmetics Then you got how to
quote strings different way to quote
strings what they mean how to quote like
huge you know 10 you know 10,000 lines
of text you know called um called here
string or here doc it originated from
pearl you know called and php here
string here doc so this is all about
coding string then you got things like
um you know string variables assignment
ment, booleans, conditionals, data
structure, loop, input, output, then how
to write a function, how to deal with
errors, then how how do you say
profiles? So this is PowerShell. So
again, PowerShell Python, you see you
can see how they how uh the structure of
a tutorial for these different
languages. Then my Goland tutorial is
similar, you know. So in Goland in the
case of a Goland you have to deal with
compilation. So you have compilation how
to compile source code encoding how to
print the current version. What does
package mean in Goland? That's one of
the first thing important because you
because every Goland file is a package.
You have to have that as the first line.
So that's why it's you know in the
beginning introductory section. Then you
have comments how to print. Then the the
the significance of the semicolon in
Goland which is important you need to
know. Then uh source code format which
is also kind of important in Golan
because then you can format you don't
need to worry about it. Auto
format then it covers topics like the
other programming languages.
string run. Run is a special type. Run
is a character type actually. So in
Golan you have that. Then type and
values. Golan is a very type um you know
it's a typed language. So you have to
deal with types. Then you have
conditional loop data structure and
function and read write a file. Uh I
don't have a coverage for module but
anyway. So this is Golan
tutorial. Then I have JavaScript in
depth. Okay. Then I have wam language
kind of in depth. Uh so that's my
tutorials. Then I got emacisp. Then
eacisp is like um you know that I've
been working on this the longest like 15
years. So I got all these tutorials.
Okay. So programming language
tutorials and uh go back to here. So
what so what are we doing is today is
just to write a F tutorial. So what I'm
doing is to um what I was doing is to
explain the structure of writing a
programming language. Okay. The
structure of writing a programming
language tutorial.
So
the
truck of
writing a programming language
tutorial. Okay, that's what we have
covered and that's kind of the
explanation what of what I'm doing here.
So, we started with install file name
extension. We need to have like source
code encoding. What is the expected
source code encoding? Uh then we got um
how do you get uh help either inline
help
or or how do you find the function you
need? How do you you know things like
that? So I need to add a new page. Then
you got the basics like comments and
quote string.
Okay. Jesus 38 people watching.
That's that's I got the most popular
people
watching. When will you go to China?
Maybe. Maybe, you
know, maybe I'll go to China. Um, I
don't
know. I never been. Okay. So, do you use
WordPress? No. Blue law. Janice says,
"What are your thoughts on Kinesis
Advantage 2 versus 80? Why do you prefer
GR?" Okay, I talked about that a million
times. In fact, I have like five or 10
live stream videos about that. So you
need to go back to last year or
something you know like you know so
uh so just check okay s talk show year
2025 you know I anyway I mean I talked
to that almost every video so let's go F
I use net and car as a lot and never did
F it looks um blue says it looks good it
looks cool
test. Let's see. Let's see. Let's the C
comments. Okay. Since I started F,
converting C code to F is one of my
favorite task.
Fantastic. Uh interup with C is very
good. Yes. Yeah. Because the they all
based on net. Very good. Uh I assume
it's nice for delegating certain tasks
for functions too that might be
cumbersome to write otherwise
uh okay anyway let me go back to uh what
I want to do I'm doing this you see if
you want to learn F you don't have to
write a tutorial in I actually these
days because F the tutorial is fantastic
the official F tutorial clear
professional right written
professionally written
uh for example let's get started uh
install F I already you know I read a
lot of these already so you you you
start with um you know literal so what
are literal then you have like what are
strings what are the different ways to
quote strings what's the difference what
are all the escape sequences you know I
already read a lot of
these.
So these days, you know, tutorials are
getting so much better as opposed to
like 10 or 10 years ago or 20 years ago.
But you know, and because since 15 years
ago, there's tons of pajit, you know,
the Indian
idiots, a lot of uh people from India,
they are massively producing these, you
know, shallow websites. Okay.
No offense to Indian but but that is
technically true. A lot of Indian you
know they are doing scams or creating
lots of these tutorials like like they
they don't have experience they just
like copy and paste and you know
massive. So you got tutorial point you
got lots of these big commercial like
tutorial websites for beginners like
they they only like they they they they
covered the like for beginners. You got
so many of them starting about 2010.
Okay. The first one is the you know the
first one is what's what
um I forgot what's what's the first one
but anyway was technology progresses.
You got this open source you know
tutorials this uh you know and and many
ac
uh something called academy. Yeah, the
the KN Academy that that's kind of one
of the first KN Academy something okay
it became very popular you know oh you
can learn trigonometry you can learn
programming you can learn you know uh in
video so there's a ton videos I don't
need to actually write one because the
the the the F one is very good but I'm
writing one because that's my habit it
and also when I write so also it's my
habit to write down things as I learn
and the and also the advantage is that I
have my own notes so I can read I can
see exactly the way I understand
something okay and
uh so I mean so my tutorial like all the
all my tutorials like they are not you
know
They some of them I spent 10 years 20
years but they are not people don't read
them you know people just go to like uh
stack overflow or the pajit site
tutorial point you know that's what
that's most traffic go there okay and
even today stack overflow has been
killed by AI so today you just a ask AI
bot you can ask AI bot write a tutorial
Python you just like you can ask any
question. So I don't need to write a
tutorial but it's just my habit. So you
know so I'm going to continue my own
tradition and style but also my style of
tutorial has a particular style because
my style is to the point no extraneous
use of jargon. No unnecessary use of
jargon. Okay? So I don't talk in terms
of jargon. Oh, by the way, this is a a
pointer that is you know I talk I talk I
I tell you exactly when you type this
what what is the
consequence you know whatever you type
in terms of the programming language
okay what it returns things like that so
concrete no nonsense no jargon no
unnecessary use of jargon okay that's
critical because jarens actually somes
times are necess necessary. But however,
for example, on the other extreme in
Unix man pages by the Unix and
by the Python Python to uh programming
language documentation and tutorial
idiots. They are full of jarens
unnecessarily. So also that is true in
Hascar tutorial by this you know very
smart functional programming hottheads
you know filled with
unnecessary use of
jarens. So and so the consequence of
that is incomprehensible. Okay. So
another characteristics of my t tutorial
is that there's always examples for
every concept
uh for every concept you'll see example
uh you know for example let's say
comments so you got this comments you
got this comments you got block comments
then there's example to it uh so
comments you know then you know data
structure let variable declaration
exactly so there's no nonsense Okay,
every concept has a example. No
nonsense, no jargon and no story
storytelling. Like a lot of a tutorial
they will start. Oh, by the way, I began
programming 10 years ago and I
encountered this language. At first I
thought how how it compares to
C++ these Oh, what one day I
travel to the land of sarin land and I
see a beautiful tree and it reminds me
that like the python philosophy. Uh then
I started to thinking uh that's what
function function means these idiots.
Okay. So that that's a different you
know there are many different styles of
programming tutorial.
So another reason I write then is
because I enjoy it. So you know because
when you write you um think about
things. Okay. I kind of rambled over
about tutorial style and about the
structure of programming language
tutorial. Uh about the different styles
of tutorial about my particular style of
tutorial you can which you can see in a
lot of my tutorial page introduction for
example Java JavaScript in depth. So my
tutorial is written in the most simple
way you can
understand you know it doesn't require
to be you to be a open source fanatic or
to be a elite hacker like the Python
Pythonic or the pearl
or the Unix and C
They want you to be elite
because whatever they write they they
need to use like obstruuse ways to talk
about something so that they are peers
they they will think they are you know
superior and including lisp lisp
people. So my tutorial is the most
simple you can understand standalone
examples you can run for every
concept you know. So every every example
you see in my
tutorial when there's an example you can
run this right away. You don't need oh
oh but you need to add or import
something there you know every example
is
independent you you can run you can run
in what you know in whatever language
okay written in a code style no ninja no
zen no joke every sentence counts okay
so this is like you can say it's a
mathematician there's no one single
sentence that's redundant Okay. No one
word that's
redundant and no talking about oh this
is ninja. Oh let's do some kang or
lisp. Let's do some taii and
taoism. Okay. No z no nothing. No
framework no library no design patterns.
No extran extraneous jarens. No fad. you
know many some some tutorials they will
they will talk in terms of design
patterns. Okay. So in JavaScript if you
want to do a function in a factory
factory pattern this is what you do.
Okay. Factory pattern. What the
does that mean? That's what they do. So
and and and for my JavaScript in depth.
This is in depth. Okay. for my
JavaScript not but not for my Golan uh
you know not for my Python so my Python
and Golan is
like reasonable for beginners okay but
my JavaScript is in depth more in depth
than any professional book
printed selling on Amazon the top ranked
seller okay my JavaScript tutorial is
more in-depth and more correct than
any in English language
counting or printed
books. Okay, that that's okay. That's
the summary. That's summary and
advertisement for my JavaScript
tutorial. Uh now let's go back to
um so I talked for 40 minutes already.
Uh so let's talk let's what do we do
now? So I kind of randed all over and uh
I actually didn't write any tutorial.
So let's let's go back to
right back to F tutorial. Let's you know
start to actually write
some. So again this is just a random
okay this is just my random talk and
exploration. Okay let's write the quote
string
chapter. Okay open it. So uh update so
the work in work in progress uh okay
let's leave it so
um yeah so I need to
read string so f string
um yeah let's just start to write some
string okay so what do we do I have here
so let's see uh so I got that run
sum. Okay, so we got it. So cross string
uh what are the different ways to quote?
Let's
see. String type represent uh immutable
text. Okay, so uni code characters.
Okay, sequence of unic code characters.
String is an alias for
system.stream.net. Okay. So that is also
uh you know so they it's a alias to the
system string inn net. Okay
remarks. Okay. So this is the important
part single lit. Okay. So single string
literal are delimited by the quotation
mark character. Okay. Then the
backslash inside it has special meaning
certain backslash known as escape
sequence. Right? Okay. So those are the
escape
sequence inside
the quotation
mark. Okay. Then uh important the ddd.
Okay. Ignore that. Uh
uh important d escape is decimal
notation. That's right. And uh okay,
verbatim string. Okay, so you got the at
sign. So let's
see how do I
um start to organize it. Okay, so you
need a print. Uh you need a core string,
you need another page for printing
because printing is the most elementary
thing you need to do in a program for
programing language. So I need a
different page for print. Uh and
uh okay so you got
um so you got verbatim string start with
at sign okay
so okay so let's write let's start to
write you know
uh writing a tutorial is not so easy and
it's kind of tedious so you just have to
write and write quotential mark
string. So let's just say that uh so
that's a chapter I mean that's a section
then
verbaton
verbatim I don't have a shortcut for
that did I spell it correctly you know
one thing I don't have in Emacs on
Windows is the spell checker uh on
Windows it's kind of difficult to get
that to work verbatim uh stream okay so
verbatim stream is a new section
Um let's begin just by some examples.
Okay.
So a a backslash n bb. Okay.
Now run it. Okay. Tab r is undefined. I
need in emac in my f mod. I need a fun.
I need a emac command to run the current
block or region. Okay, I don't have that
command. So let's write write one. Right
now I have this command which runs the
whole file which works. Okay, so you see
it returns
literally. So this is a verbatim string
syntax corette. So we added a section uh
quotation mark string. So you need to
add some
explanation. String can be quoted
by okay by by that character
uh
in inside you have escape.
um backslash has special meaning. Okay,
that's kind
of then you need a section about the
backslash sequence. Okay. So, uh so this
is a example but however you didn't show
any example of backslash we need to show
an example aa uh line
one back
slashn then let's say line
two okay run
it
fantastic okay so now copy that now
comments
Now what is the comment of F# is that
back slash slash slash let's see check
my tutorial correct you also got block
comment okay do we have block comments
no let me add it okay to um so anyway
one thing at a time so here is example
of backslash sequence verbatim string
okay so verbatim string
If ad
sign. So what is the unic code uh name
for ad sign? The technical official name
is commercial ad.
The
quotation
mark the string is
literal.
Okay. Back
slash has no
special. Okay.
Fantastic. Fantastic. So this is a
little
progress. Okay. Uh yeah. So now let's
digress a little bit. So you know
there's a lot to do then. Now let's
digress. We want to code emacisp. Let's
do that a little bit. So
um so describe
function f mod. So there it is my f mod.
So
multitasking writing a f tutorial and
write improve my f mod which is here.
Okay. So what I want to do uh I want to
add a brief comments. Okay. So this is
typically what I
have now in F mod you have comments.
Okay.
So okay let's see that evaluate. Make a
backup. Go back here. Uh close that. Go
back here. What what do we
have? Show in browser. Okay. Uh talk
show. Okay. So let's uh com uh learning
notes Emacs a brief programming tutorial
index. Okay. Uh we we also talk about
the programming language documentation
style the structure of writing a
programming language and uh we also talk
about
um style of technical
technical
documentation. Okay, we t we talked
about that uh technical documentation or
also known as technical writing. Donald
Guth has
written an essay about how to do
technical writing. It was a popular t
topic back in 1990s. you'll see a
tutorial about how to write techni
technical documentation that you know so
back in the 90 90s it's common to have
how to write you know you have to teach
people how to write a essay and so on
but and then part of that is technical
writing which you have different style
so writing has different styles you have
creative writing style you have
journalism style then you know then you
have
writing a technical documentation style
they have different styles. Then even
within technical documentation you also
have different styles. Okay. So we
talked about that. So uh but let me
reference to um to my website because um
that has
that
subject. Okay. Hacker code. Why Python
doc sucks? Why Python sucks? Compliment
perving this syntax soup. Semantic soup.
Jarens of tech software industry. Doc
for dummies. This section collection of
essays uh related to technical writing
and programming language documentation.
Okay. So let's copy that. Make a list.
There it is. Doc for dummies.
So, so you have which programming
language has best documentation. That's
one article. And then you got how to
judge the quality programming language
documentation. How to judge the
quality of programming language
documentation. Oh, I I missed a
of Yeah, I missed. Okay, let's fix it.
So, go to that page showing browser back
to Emacs. How to judge? Search for J U D
E Judge Doom. So you want to rename this
article for every link in the 10,000
pages that links to the article. You
want to rename all. So I got a
function do it HTML rename links all.
Okay. How to judge the quality
of a programming language doc. Okay.
Enter. So that will take 30 seconds.
That will go through 10,000. There.
There it is. Because the
um if you run this for the first time,
it takes some time to load 10,000 20,000
files. But if you already run it before,
it all the files are in memory like
right now. So that takes just two
seconds. This is emac this code. Okay.
So close that. Okay. That's the how to
judge the quality of a programming
language doc. Okay. That should be yeah
that let's leave it. Okay. So that's one
article. Close that. Close that. Then
which programming language is easier to
learn? Programming language
documentation styles. That's what we
talked about today. Okay. So that that
is kind of more elaborate than what I
did
ext. Okay. Programming language
documentation styles. So here I gave a
more of a
comprehensive documentation about
different styles in programming language
documentation or in technical writing.
Okay. Then you got doc by dermis. Each
is a case example. Which language has
best dog Unix, Python, Pearl, hacker
idiocies? You see here I document some
of the extreme idiocy of these
idiots like the Unix man page for
example. These are funny. Okay, the Unix
man page. Unix man page man. App get try
it, you know. Try try try to verify if I
was telling the
truth. By the way, am I like live and uh
alive and kicking? Everything is
fine. You know, sometimes like I've been
talking for um one hour and my voice is
muted. Okay. 15 views. 15
viewers.
Uh so, programming language
documentation styles. Uh yeah. So, uh
but go back doc for dummies. So uh Unix
Python you know man appget get then you
have a section remove the remove option
remove is identical to install except
that packages are removed instead of
installed that is from the Linux
documentation man aptget 2010 I mean
2011 okay so what does this mean it
means it's like kicking kicking ing is
identical to kissing except that
receiver is kicked instead of
kissed. This is
a this is showing the idiocy exposing
the idiocy of the Linux Unix
via a analogy.
Okay, so that's a example from Unix.
Then you got example from uh wufam. So
why is wam documentation superb uh you
know so I explain then you got the
idiocy of the Unix man
page you know they start with that then
you got the python edioscy you got pro
idioscy you know so anyway that's some
of that so now let's get back to the
topic of of the uh writing this okay so
copy that back to
um back to okay back to here. Now pop
this out. Run it. Okay, that's the
output. Good. Now let's do a comment.
CM.
Fantastic. So now I can have this
comment. The uh this is a comment. Okay.
Now fantastic. Okay. But however, cm
space it doesn't it didn't move the
cursor back to where it's supposed to be
here. Okay, let's fix
that back to emac.
So, in order to get it back, you need to
add a
um uh you need uh so I forgot. So let me
check the my other
um so this let's check emac this mod uh
yeah hook okay ab hook do I have that
here hook there it is f hook okay so
this function just move after expansion
of a brief it moves the cruiser back to
this cruiser character from unic code
okay so that character is called black
vertical rectangle which represent a
cruiser. Okay, nicely. So copy that. So
you want to go to a brief. So by the way
if you are wondering what are you doing
s this is emac this seems technical and
advanced you can go to eac this tutorial
create the major mod scroll down then
you go to the syntax table uh not there
you got uh create a hook text properties
function template okay that tells you
everything you need to know about this a
brief expansion and template exam
expansion so that you can for example in
you know so you can have templates type
a few characters expands okay so if you
that this is about writing emac list
writing a major mod okay if you are
coding a major mod so that's what I'm
doing so you need to add that
so we are creating a a brief so let's
you know for example
Um some some some
tea. So a brief
table. Yeah. So a brief table a brief
properties we need to the brief
hook. A brief hook. So that is explained
here. Okay.
Oh, so you see that's what I'm um do you
need a uh let's see do you need a quote
no okay so anyway eval evaluate it now
go back to now pop this out now type cm
enter fantastic you see my cursor went
back there fantastic so that's one thing
done color it showing browser so I
improved
my my uh F mod. Okay, backup. So, we got
comments. So, where are we? So, I think
maybe that's it for today. Uh
[Music]
uh yeah, maybe that's it for today.
Hello, good evening sir. Please stop
insulting
India.
Uh I use for trend. Um I bought 360 and
was
disappointed. Uh returning to advantage
too. Oh interesting. And honestly doubt
glove could compete with it neither
either but probably we all are different
and therefore value different features.
Oh that's interesting. Okay. Uh yeah so
in general I would
consider Okay, let's digress a bit.
Okay. So let's go back to glove 80. So
the ergonomic keyboards. So we talking
about these three keyboards. Glove 80,
fantastic and beautiful. Then then you
got Kinesis
360. Both of them came out about two or
three years ago. Okay. Then you got this
more classic Kinesis advantage 2 which
came out 10 years ago in
2016. Okay. So what you are saying is
that you actually prefer this advantage
too. Okay. In my opinion, no 360 is
definitely better.
Um yeah, I would say in general because
for several reasons it it it's
got you know any anyway but you know but
but the advantage too is like one single
piece and it's light one single piece.
So that's nice. I like
that the Kinesis 360 is is heavy, you
know, they are made of some kind of
metal quite heavy uh like more than one
kilograms. I think I got the details
somewhere here. Okay. So, but it's heavy
and two pieces. So, every time you use
it, you got to connect then just, you
know, fiddle with the positions. Uh
yeah. Um and then it doesn't have
function keys, you know. So, but the
advantage to got this tiny function keys
which makes them
useless. So, anyway, so different people
have different preferences. You if you
want to compare, I have a comparison
page um which is uh comparison page
there. Kinesis advantages keyboard.
Okay. So wait that all these are Kinesis
then dish surface keyboards.
Uh so I got a comparison some page
compare these two not listed here. Uh oh
there. Okay. Glove 80 versus Kinesis 360
there. Click it. So you can see the
comparison between these three and uh
and you got a table comparing the
features. Okay.
Anyway, so we talked about for one hour.
I think that's
it. So we were doing um So let me copy
that. Copy. Close. Okay. Close. Go back
to
uh talk show
uh
paste. Okay, we talked about that. And
now what what else I want to do? Emac
this. No.
Uh we want so we will write in the
documentation for course string. Uh
there's a lot to do though. So there's a
verbatim
string but there's more uh there's also
triple corded
string. Uh then there is yeah then you
start to talk about indexing.
Um yeah so there's a lot to do. Okay. So
and why is this common page not syntax
colored? Let's open it. Let's syntax
color it show in browser. Oh, looks
better because when I had this page, I
don't have my F mod kind of ready yet.
So, okay, that's it, guys. Bye,
guys. If you like my stuff, go to
kasari.info, okay? Scroll all the way to
the bottom and pay me. Pay me.
I think that's it. Let me get
tea. Oh
god. Okay.
So there's a lot to write though.
Um, you know, like the issue with doing
live stream is that when you do when you
know when I do live stream, you can't
really work on your
stuff. If you just if you know for me
for example, I need to write this
tutorial, right? And I've been prepared
because I've been reading this F
documentation in past months.
So if I just you know so this is what I
want I need to do for myself. So I'm you
know if I just work on it it's much
faster. I don't have to explain
anything. I just go to emac go to you
know just read and you know do but if I
do live
stream it becomes something something
else because I need I kind of need to
explain what are you doing for example
adding this panel. What? What are you
doing? Like if I do not
explain Oh, I got a string escape escape
sequences here. So if I do not
explain, then it's like you have no idea
what I'm doing. It's kind of boring. You
just see me, you know, it's kind of
boring. that which defeats the purpose
of live stream, you know, because live
stream is supposed to be, you know,
either having fun, you know, either you
enjoy what I'm talking about or chat or
seeing some oh interesting or dramatic
stuff, right? Seeing my what what what
color themes are you using? Oh, you
Emacs, what what template are you using?
You know, that's dramatic. So, that
makes live stream fun.
But then I talked about the writing
style, the documentation
style. But then but I mean the issue is
then I'm not actually writing you know
I'm not actually the the the goal is to
actually write a tutorial. So today we
just like added one
single block of
text. Uh and that's not good writing
neither because you see for string
quoting. Let me let me just continue
this
explanation. When when it comes to
string quoting in in a programming
language, there are many issues and this
is actually quite important and fair
some somewhat complex
because when you quote string, you have
several issues. Do you
allow empty line in your string? For
example, JavaScript, it doesn't until
until like 15 years later, it created
template string. Then you can have
like new lines in your string. So you
know, do you allow new line? And what
about escape sequence? If you do not
allow new line, then you need some kind
of escape sequence. But sometimes you
don't
want, you know, escape sequence because
that's nasty. You want literal verbatim
string. So how do you design it? Some
languages use you know use single quote
or double quote. In Python you have
triple quote which actually you have
that in F as
well. Some of them add a something in
front which is in F and F also you can
have a dollar sign for expandable like
interpreted string. So that a string you
can have variable inside. So you got
several issues. You
got you got do you can you allow any
character in your string? What
characters are allowed such as new line
character? Do you allow it? Do you allow
new characters in your string? Things
like that. Do and do you allow escape
sequences? By the way, it's not a good
feature. You should ban escape sequence
sequence should be banned. Okay. It
began by the C C and Unix
They created this backslash
something escape sequence which makes
passing stream extremely complex
extreme. Okay. What you should do is you
have you should have like variation of
the quotation or the so-called here dock
or here string.
Okay, that will do it. That will that
will be much better. Okay, so the C
poisoned the programming
industry. Well, so they they have this
backslash. So anyway, do you allow what
characters do you allow? Do you allow
new line character and how do you quote
if your string contains whatever the
quotation mark then how do you include
that character? Okay, that's the issue
then. Okay. Then escape
sequences within escape sequence you got
complicated issues about unic code
because unic code you you got UTF 16
characters then you got UTF 32
characters by
historical
historical typically they became then
you have two syntax to include uni to
have escape sequence for unic code.
Typically one is four digits, the other
one is six digits. So that happens in
eacisp in JavaScript that happens also
in I believe in
Python. I have a documentation for each
one of these you know and and you know
and more. So you got this escape
sequence then the string then you got
the string template
issue because often times you want some
variables or expression inside the
string. You want them to be able to
evaluate. So what syntax do you design
for the language to allow that?
Different languages they have different
ways. One typical example is is you just
include a dollar sign variable name. But
that doesn't work for expression. So
later on people invented dollar sign
curly braces then expression inside.
Okay, that's another issue. How do you
have expand expandable string or string
template? The another issue is how do
you have um formatting? For example,
let's say you have
1.3456, but you want all decimals to be
just two decimals. Okay? You don't want
you want to truncate the rest of it. So,
you need format.
Then formatting you know then the issue
is how do you design your programming
language string to have that feature
formatting of decimal characters or
hexadimal or binary digits or or
sometimes you need pad padding you know
you want empty space or you want zero in
front of a
number. So that's the issue. So, so
different language you have different um
ways to do it and again one of the
common way is like the from the C
format. Okay, that this C and Unix
again they poisoned the design
of programming languages. this
format you know from print you know like
sprint and print this from the C
C and and Unix that
is the worst design the most inflexible
the most ad hoc you have to memorize
like each what like what what is this
this pound sign or whatever it means
okay and not flexible not extensible and
you just like Everything is just ad hoc
you know just like just remember it okay
just do it C and Unix
created that
um so anyway that's about the designing
of string
syntax in programming languages and uh
their
complexities and that is why writing you
know this chapter about
string is not you know it's not so um
trivial. So for example, let's look at
Python, you know, you
got Python is one of the worst design.
You got, you know, quote, but quote can
be double quote or the single quote, but
then you you can also have triple quote.
Okay, then then you got, you know, Pon
is the
worst. Okay, that's it. That's it. We
closing down for real. We shut down in
20 seconds.
By the way, lisp languages including
Mathematica, they got also the worst
string because in lisp you only have
just just the quotation mark string.
So, so it makes it very difficult when
you have regular expression or when you
have when you want some when when your
text include quotation mark. So you got
you have to escape everything. Then you
got the tooth toothpick syndrome you
know like
incomprehensible you know so and hard to
process like so this is the
worst the best is here do dark okay so
the best is actually here do dark for
example
powershell you know so this mechanism
allows you to have arbitrary text
without conflict without um collision of
characters
inside you know here do so here do comes
in varieties of designs in powershell in
PHP in pearl
originally
they originally they came from pearl
okay so let's go to
pearl pearl
uh string do Do I have a
um do I have a
uh here or do dark? Okay. I think Pearl
is the first I I don't think Pearl is
exactly the first who created this
concept. But however, Pearl is the one
responsible for first massively
spreading this design, this syntax
design, which solves the problem of
including arbitrary text like very long
text, you know, even 10,000 pages like
entire book. So, you can quote it
by so-called here do that's what Pearl
Pearl originally calls it. Okay. So
basically you allow you you can have
like random characters as the delimiter.
So that solves the problem because you
know when you have a sequence of random
English letters the chances it happens
in a text is is like astron astronomical
you know the chances is less
than you win a lottery. Okay. So, so
pearl created this kind of made this
popular. So, this here dark string
syntax move uh they became they moved to
PHP because PHP is derived from pearl
and then they they also came to uh
PowerShell. Uh what is the origin of
heark string? Uh I'm not sure. I think
it's some kind of Unix tool. Okay, let's
ask
Gork what's the origin of the here dark
string in here dark do string concept in
programming
languages let's see let's see the power
of G's
history let's magnify so you can
The here do for short for here document
string concept in programming languages
originates from the Unix shell scripting
particularly the boon shell. Oh from bon
shell introduced in 1977. Okay. Boon
shell which bash came from. Bash is
derived
of b. By the way, bash stand for bone
again shell. Okay, that's a idiom.
That's a very interesting idiom because
originally in Unix you have the bone
shell. And what does the bone stand for?
That's the the guy's name. Okay, you
know, Stefan Boon. I I'm not sure how
you pronounce it. I suppose it's just
bone. Stefan Bong. Okay. 1977.
But it's full of you know it's it's full
of uh bad design you know it's like Unix
you know Unix is always full of so
they they try to improve it you know so
the story of Unix is simply piled
on top of other you know like you
start with oh it doesn't work this
way it's got problems let's let's pile
another on top of it to cover it up
oh then but had got problem let's let's
cover let's cover pile another on
top of it that is the fundamental
history of Unix okay including C for
example C you got C then you got C++
then you got D then you got Java then
you got C sharp each one is trying to
cover up the before you know that's
the story that's the damage of Unix and
CH
Unix shell. Same thing. Boom sha then uh
bash. Okay. Now
I I'm not sure if there's another
version before bash. But anyway, bon sha
you got then you got se shell. You got
kong sha k sh. You got um se shell con
shell. You got uh zshell. Okay. They all
try to fix it. And then you
got bash which is b again sha you know
that's a idiom from the American white
people because then it's comes here
comes Christianity okay born
again so but anyway it says the idea was
inspired by earlier systems like mortex
okay which used similar mechanisms for
embedding Multi-line. Oh, okay. So, it
came from actually
Motics. Okay, that's it. Bye, guys.